<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02709434</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LW Fatigue study</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02709434</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Fatigue Management in Quiescent IBD</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Efficacy of a Structured Psychoeducational Inflammatory Bowel Disease Group on the Control of Fatigue in an Adult Outpatient Setting for Patients With Objectively Quiescent Disease.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Fatigue is a very frequently reported symptom in patients with inflammatory bowel disease&#xD;
      (IBD), whether it is Crohn's disease (CD) or ulcerative colitis (UC). Sometimes the fatigue&#xD;
      may be easily explained by other symptoms or tests which show that the disease is active. For&#xD;
      example patients may be anaemic (have a low blood count) which can in itself lead to a&#xD;
      feeling of being tired all the time. Treatment of the disease can make some of these patients&#xD;
      feel less fatigued.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, 4 or 5 out of every 10 patients with IBD which is felt to be in remission (ie not&#xD;
      active disease) report fatigue. This can have far-reaching implications for patients in their&#xD;
      everyday lives, with issues around work or school, close relationships, travel and leisure&#xD;
      being profoundly affected. The CCUK funded research on fatigue and IBD, led by Professor&#xD;
      Christine Norton and Wladzia Czuber-Dochan at King's College London, has identified fatigue&#xD;
      as being a significant issue facing patients and has also highlighted that few doctors offer&#xD;
      help and support beyond treating the disease itself when active. This is partly because&#xD;
      fatigue itself has been difficult to measure and so any study designed to treat fatigue would&#xD;
      be limited by being unable to quantify any improvement in a meaningful way.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fortunately the King's College group have developed a 'fatigue score' which is a simple&#xD;
      questionnaire that is able to quantify the severity of fatigue. The aim of our study is to&#xD;
      assess the effect of a structured support and educational programme on the levels of fatigue&#xD;
      in patients with inactive IBD who report moderate or severe levels of fatigue. A secondary&#xD;
      component of our study is to see if there are any associations between fatigue levels and&#xD;
      disease activity or other parameters such as quality of life, anxiety or symptoms of&#xD;
      overlapping irritable bowel syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be approached in the out-patient or telephone clinics and the study will be&#xD;
      explained with written information and any questions will be answered. If they agree to being&#xD;
      involved they will be asked to complete the fatigue and a number of other questionnaires in&#xD;
      addition to having the standard assessment of symptoms, blood tests and a stool specimen.&#xD;
      Patients with active disease will be excluded from the subsequent group interventions but the&#xD;
      data they have provided to this point will still be helpful in our understanding of fatigue&#xD;
      in IBD. Patients identified as being in remission following the initial assessments will be&#xD;
      offered the opportunity to be involved in the next stage of the study. The stool samples will&#xD;
      also be analysed for the microbiome ie which bacteria are present as some studies suggest&#xD;
      that patients with IBD may have a reduced diversity of bacteria in their intestines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Half of this group will be randomised to active intervention and half will act as a control&#xD;
      group for the rest of the study. The active intervention will involve completion of activity&#xD;
      diaries over the following two weeks and then analysis of the diaries and agreement on&#xD;
      behaviour changes designed to help fatigue. This will be supported by written information and&#xD;
      three, monthly small group sessions to reinforce and support these changes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the study all patients will again complete the fatigue and quality of life&#xD;
      questionnaires and have their disease activity assessed by symptom scores, blood and stool&#xD;
      tests. The baseline results and the final results will be analysed to see if there is any&#xD;
      improvement in fatigue in the group undergoing the programme of support and behaviour change.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is only a small pilot study but if it demonstrates that the intervention is feasible and&#xD;
      may help with fatigue then a larger study will be performed to try and confirm our initial&#xD;
      findings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our ultimate aim is to find a simple intervention to empower patients to deal with the&#xD;
      difficult task of living with IBD and the fatigue that this can bring.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      41%- 48% of patients with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), which is in remission, experience&#xD;
      fatigue (1). Fatigue is associated with significant physical, emotional, psychological and&#xD;
      social consequences (2). This can have wide-reaching implications for patients in their&#xD;
      everyday lives, with issues around work productivity, academic achievement, close&#xD;
      relationships, travel and leisure being profoundly affected. Based on data from the CCUK&#xD;
      national lottery-funded research on fatigue, although 68% of responding IBD treating&#xD;
      professionals felt that fatigue was adequately treatable less than half offer anything over&#xD;
      and above checking the haemoglobin level and treat if low, with only around one third&#xD;
      offering lifestyle related advice on diet, exercise and sleep (3). The CCUK funded research&#xD;
      on fatigue and IBD led by Professor Christine Norton and Wladzia Czuber-Dochan has not only&#xD;
      identified fatigue as a significant issue facing patients but has also developed an objective&#xD;
      fatigue score to quantify it. Leading on from this the King's College team has studied the&#xD;
      role of diet and exercise in fatigue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims of the proposed investigation&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our study aims to address two key questions:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Do patients with active IBD have higher fatigue scores than patients with inactive&#xD;
           disease? This question will be addressed as we will be screening a selection of patients&#xD;
           coming to the specialist IBD clinic. Some will have active disease when assessed and so&#xD;
           will be excluded from further interventional study. Others with inactive disease will be&#xD;
           recruited to the study, but we will be able to compare fatigue scores in both the active&#xD;
           and inactive disease groups. In addition we will explore any association between fatigue&#xD;
           scores and anxiety/depression, somatisation scores, quality of life, overlapping IBS&#xD;
           symptoms and the faecal microbiome.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Can the intervention of planned behavioural change improve the symptoms of fatigue in&#xD;
           patients with inflammatory bowel disease in remission?&#xD;
&#xD;
      We believe our study complements the existing work on fatigue by offering a structured&#xD;
      psychoeducational intervention centred around a self-management booklet and group-work. The&#xD;
      primary outcome of the study is to assess fatigue in an IBD remission cohort. The study will&#xD;
      be undertaken by Lisa Warren under the supervision of Dr Anthony O'Connor and Dr John Hamlin&#xD;
      with input from Debbie Pullen (mental health nurse specialist) and Anna Errington&#xD;
      (occupational therapist, department of liason psychiatry).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary outcomes for a larger study that could cascade from this pilot would be to assess&#xD;
      if there is a decreased risk of flare and an improved quality of life in patients in whom&#xD;
      fatigue is adequately managed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Detailed plan of investigation and methodology&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients being screened for this study will be required to give informed consent. In&#xD;
      order to recruit the proposed study numbers for the active intervention we estimate that we&#xD;
      will have to screen approximately 100 patients. A large number of patients may be excluded&#xD;
      from the active intervention study as baseline clinical and laboratory investigations,&#xD;
      completed as part of their standard disease assessment, will suggest they have active&#xD;
      disease. However data collected on these patients will still provide valuable information&#xD;
      about fatigue in patients with IBD, such as any association between fatigue score and&#xD;
      severity of active disease, or other parameters such as somatisation score (as assessed by&#xD;
      PHQ15 form), quality of life (SIBDQ &amp; SF36), overlapping IBD symptoms (Rome III criteria), or&#xD;
      anxiety and depression (HAD score).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients identified as being in remission will be offered the opportunity to be involved in&#xD;
      the psychoeducational interventional study. The study will be explained with written&#xD;
      information and any questions will be answered. If they agree to being involved they will be&#xD;
      asked to complete the fatigue questionnaire in addition to questionnaires addressing&#xD;
      anxiety/depression (HAD), somatisation (PHQ15), overlapping irritable bowel syndrome symptoms&#xD;
      (Rome III), and quality of life (SIBDQ &amp; SF36). In addition, patients will have the standard&#xD;
      assessment of disease activity with symptoms, blood tests, and stool specimens. The stool&#xD;
      sample will be sent for faecal calprotectin measurement which is a non-invasive and sensitive&#xD;
      marker of bowel inflammation. The stool samples will then also be stored for future&#xD;
      assessment of the faecal microbiome (the different bacteria in the intestine) in order to&#xD;
      examine any association between this and disease activity, fatigue scores, or the other&#xD;
      parameters assessed with the questionnares.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with active inflammation based on symptoms, blood tests, or stool calprotectin level&#xD;
      will be excluded from the subsequent psychological intervention aspect of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Those with inactive disease will be randomized, by concealed envelopes, in to two groups. The&#xD;
      first group will act as the control and continue current management. The active intervention&#xD;
      group will complete activity diaries over the following two weeks. The active intervention&#xD;
      will be an analysis of the activity diaries and agreement on behaviour changes designed to&#xD;
      help fatigue. This will be supported by written information and three, monthly small group&#xD;
      sessions to reinforce and support these changes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the study all patients will again complete the fatigue and other questionnaires&#xD;
      outlined above and they will have their disease activity assessed by symptom scores, blood&#xD;
      and stool tests. The baseline results and the final results will be analysed to see if there&#xD;
      is any improvement in fatigue in the group undergoing the programme of support and behaviour&#xD;
      change.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is only a small pilot study but, if it demonstrates that the intervention is feasible&#xD;
      and may help with fatigue, then a larger study will be performed to try and confirm our&#xD;
      initial findings. Our data will also help inform IBD specialists and their patients about&#xD;
      factors which may play a role in the common symptom of fatigue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our ultimate aim is to find a simple intervention to empower patients to deal with the&#xD;
      difficult task of living with IBD and the fatigue that this can bring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our active intervention study group will be patients with inactive disease only, in order to&#xD;
      avoid confounding factors. Those patients with inactive disease will all complete activity&#xD;
      diaries and half of these will be randomised to the active intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As there are no proven interventions to treat IBD-related fatigue we do not forsee ethical&#xD;
      problems relating to the other half of patients being randomised to no intervention, other&#xD;
      than their existing treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The psychoeducational intervention of behaviour changes centred around a self-management&#xD;
      booklet will be made by our IBD clinical nurse specialist, with support from the mental&#xD;
      health team who are trained in these interventions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants :&#xD;
&#xD;
      We plan to recruit 20 IBD patients, 10 with Ulcerative Colitis (UC) and 10 with Crohn's&#xD;
      Disease (CD) with disease in remission for the active intervention arm and 20 IBD patients in&#xD;
      remission for the control group. Remission for CD will be defined as Harvey-Bradshaw Index&#xD;
      (HBI) &lt;5 and C-reactive protein (CRP) &lt;5. For UC it will be defined as partial Mayo score ≤2&#xD;
      and CRP &lt;5. For both groups a faecal calprotectin (FC) of &gt; 250ug/g will be regarded as&#xD;
      indicating active disease and will exclude patients from the study. Patients will also be&#xD;
      excluded if they are anaemic (Hb &lt;14g/dL for males, 11.5g/dL for females). In the CD arm&#xD;
      patients will be assessed for Vitamin B12 and Vitamin D status and excluded if B12 is less&#xD;
      than 300 pmol/l or Vitamin D less than 30 ng/mL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interventions :&#xD;
&#xD;
      We intend to commence recruitment in January 2016 via our twice-weekly IBD out-patient&#xD;
      clinics in addition to nurse-led telephone clinics. We aim to complete recruitment within 3&#xD;
      months with the interventions scheduled to begin in February.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At week zero the patients will be provided with information leaflets about the study and the&#xD;
      process will be explained and questions answered. Those patients giving informed consent will&#xD;
      be screened for baseline measurements including the CCUK fatigue score, in addition to&#xD;
      completing the other questionnaires outlined in the methodology above. Baseline blood and&#xD;
      stool samples will be taken to assess disease activity. Patients deemed to have active&#xD;
      disease will be excluded from the rest of the study and their medical management optimised in&#xD;
      line with local and national guidelines. Those patients meeting the inclusion criteria will&#xD;
      be provided with activity diaries and asked to complete them over the following 4 weeks. All&#xD;
      patients will have their baseline data analysed to study any association between fatigue&#xD;
      scores and disease activity (as measured by HBI/Mayo score, CRP, FC), quality of life (as&#xD;
      measured by SF36 &amp; S-IBDQ), anxiety and depression (HAD) or somatisation (PHQ15).&#xD;
&#xD;
      After excluding patients with active disease we will randomise the study population into two&#xD;
      groups. Randomisation will be by allocation from concealed envelopes by a physician not&#xD;
      involved in the study. The nature of the study itself means that it will not be blinded. As&#xD;
      this is a pilot study and there is no existing data on the effect of this intervention on&#xD;
      fatigue we have not performed a power calculation for study population size. The active group&#xD;
      will have analysis of their activity diary and agree behaviour changes. This group will have&#xD;
      three subsequent visits taking place on a monthly basis until week 20, consisting of small&#xD;
      group work of 4 patients per session to reinforce behaviour changes. At week 20, the patients&#xD;
      will come for a 6th and final visit at which response will be assessed. This will involve&#xD;
      disease assessment with clinical indices, repeat blod and stool samples and completion of the&#xD;
      same questionnaires as baseline. The control group will have standard medical management but&#xD;
      will also be reviewed at week 20 and undergo the same assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Comparators :&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age, sex and disease matched controls will be identified from our IBD clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcomes :&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the sixth visit (week 20) Fatigue score (and other questionnaires as outlined above), CRP,&#xD;
      FC and HBI or partial Mayo Score will be obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Timetable&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential application of results, including benefits for people living with IBD&#xD;
&#xD;
      We feel that patients with fatigue when in remission currently do not have sufficient access&#xD;
      to interventions designed specifically to manage fatigue as a symptom. In the CCUK fatigue&#xD;
      study there was a clear message from professionals that they wished to have a greater array&#xD;
      of evidence based interventions to offer patients under such circumstances. We believe our&#xD;
      intervention, which offers supported non-pharmacologic self-management, will be empowering&#xD;
      and worthwhile. We feel that this work would complement the sterling work undertaken by CCUK&#xD;
      on fatigue in IBD in recent years. Interest has been expressed throughout the Yorkshire and&#xD;
      Humber Royal College of Nursing IBD Network in using the booklet and method should it prove&#xD;
      effective.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dissemination intentions&#xD;
&#xD;
      We expect to publish our findings in abstract form and are hopeful that this pilot study will&#xD;
      enable us to assess the feasibility of commencing an MSc or PhD project in facilitating group&#xD;
      work for fatigue management in our IBD cohort. Dr Hamlin has been in conversation with&#xD;
      Wladzia Czuber-Dochan from King's College and their group has discussed our proposal. They&#xD;
      feel that this is an interesting project with no conflict with their existing studies. They&#xD;
      also expressed an interest in collaborating with us on future studies should this pilot study&#xD;
      provide some interesting preliminary data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Key references&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Van Langenberg DR and Gibson PR, 2010: Systematic review; fatigue in inflammatory bowel&#xD;
           disease. Alimentary Pharmacol Therapy July 2010;32(2) 131-143&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Gasche C et al, 2004: Iron, anaemia and inflammatory bowel disease. Gut August 2004;&#xD;
           53(8) 1190-1197&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. CCUK Fatigue in IBD study http://www.fatigueinibd.co.uk/research/outcomes/&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>December 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fatigue score</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Fatigue</condition>
  <condition>Inflammatory Bowel Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with quiescent IBD who are randomized to receive the active intervention of the psychoeducational programme</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Randomized to standard care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Psychoeducational programme</intervention_name>
    <description>Activity diary analysis and a structured programme of intervention</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard care</intervention_name>
    <description>Usual IBD management</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patiets with IBD in clinical and biochemical remission with no other obvious&#xD;
             identifiable explanation for their fatigue&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active inflammation based on symptoms, blood tests, or stool&#xD;
             calprotectin level will be excluded from the subsequent psychological intervention&#xD;
             aspect of the study. Patients unable to give informed consent or who are unable to&#xD;
             understand and follow the intervention will be excluded&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 11, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 11, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 16, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 11, 2016</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 11, 2016</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 16, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Intestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

