<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02701023</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>16-000080</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02701023</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Compassionate Use of MitoGel in Upper Tract Urothelial Carcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Individual Patient Expanded Access - MitoGel for Upper Urinary Tract Urothelial Carcinoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>UroGen Pharma Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to evaluate the feasibility, safety, and efficacy of MitoGel in the&#xD;
      treatment of UTUC in a human subject with low-grade UTUC which is endoscopically unresectable&#xD;
      or rapidly recurring, and in whom nephrectomy would likely result in the need for permanent&#xD;
      hemodialysis. The study drug would be obtained under the single patient access program&#xD;
      approved by the FDA. The patient would then undergo instillation of MitoGel into the affected&#xD;
      kidney. The catheter would be left indwelling in the ureter and would be externalized. The&#xD;
      ureteral and urethral catheters would remain indwelling for the duration of the 6 treatments,&#xD;
      which would occur twice weekly for 3 weeks or once weekly for 6 weeks. Following the final&#xD;
      instillation, the catheters would be removed. The patient would then undergo ureteroscopic&#xD;
      evaluation at 3 months following the final instillation of MitoGel. The total duration of&#xD;
      study would be 3 months. The total number of study patients is 1.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Upper urinary tract urothelial carcinoma (UTUC) is a rare malignant neoplasm arising from the&#xD;
      urothelial lining of the renal collecting system and ureters. The current treatment paradigm&#xD;
      for UTUC involves endoscopic resection, when technically feasible and oncologically sound, or&#xD;
      complete resection of the kidney and ureter (nephroureterectomy) in cases in which&#xD;
      organ-sparing treatment is not feasible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Both organ-sparing and complete resection options present significant technical and clinical&#xD;
      challenges. For patients with bilateral disease, an anatomic or functionally solitary kidney,&#xD;
      or significant underlying medicorenal disease, treatment with nephroureterectomy would result&#xD;
      dialysis dependence, a state which carries with it a significant risk of 5-year mortality in&#xD;
      the often elderly and co-morbid patient population affected by UTUC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MitoGel is a novel investigational product composed of RTGel, a unique hydrogel polymer which&#xD;
      exists as liquid at cold temperatures and a viscous gel at body temperatures, and Mitomycin&#xD;
      C, a clinically proven safe and effective treatment for urothelial carcinoma in the bladder.&#xD;
      MitoGel can be instilled into the upper urinary tract as a cold liquid, where it solidifies&#xD;
      to a gel upon warming to body temperature. The agent remains in the upper tract for a period&#xD;
      of 4-6 hours, resulting in sustained contact between the tissues and Mitomycin C. Preclinical&#xD;
      studies of MitoGel in the Yorkshire swine have demonstrated that both single and serial&#xD;
      instillations into the pelvicalyceal system via both retrograde and antegrade approaches are&#xD;
      safe, with no observable adverse clinical, laboratory, or histological effects. For these&#xD;
      reasons, MitoGel has generated interest as a treatment for UTUC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For patients with UTUC in whom nephroureterectomy would result in dialysis dependence, and in&#xD;
      whom the disease is difficult to manage endoscopically, there is no currently available means&#xD;
      to effectively deliver adjuvant chemotherapy to the upper tracts. These patients are thus&#xD;
      either condemned to treatment with complete resection of their kidney and resultant&#xD;
      hemodialysis, or risk progression of disease to an incurable and unmanageable state. MitoGel&#xD;
      represents a promising treatment option for patients who have no other therapeutic options.&#xD;
      For these reasons, MitoGel has been granted Orphan Designation Status by the FDA. While&#xD;
      clinical trials of MitoGel are currently being planned, no trials are open to date.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to evaluate the feasibility, safety, and efficacy of MitoGel in the&#xD;
      treatment of UTUC in a human subject with low-grade UTUC which is endoscopically unresectable&#xD;
      or rapidly recurring, and in whom nephrectomy would likely result in the need for permanent&#xD;
      hemodialysis. The study drug would be obtained under the single patient access program&#xD;
      approved by the FDA. The patient would then undergo instillation of MitoGel into the affected&#xD;
      kidney. The catheter would be left indwelling in the ureter and would be externalized through&#xD;
      a urethral catheter. The ureteral and urethral catheters would remain indwelling for the&#xD;
      duration of the 6 treatments, which would occur twice weekly for 3 weeks. Following the final&#xD;
      instillation, the catheters would be removed. The patient would then undergo ureteroscopic&#xD;
      evaluation at 3 months following the final instillation of MitoGel. The total duration of&#xD;
      study would be 3 months. The total number of study patients is 1.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>No longer available</overall_status>
  <study_type>Expanded Access</study_type>
  <condition>Urothelial Carcinoma Ureteral Location</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MitoGel</intervention_name>
    <description>The patient would then undergo instillation of MitoGel into the affected kidney. The catheter would be left indwelling in the ureter and would be externalized through a urethral catheter. The ureteral and urethral catheters would remain indwelling for the duration of the 6 treatments, which would occur twice weekly for 3 weeks. Following the final instillation, the catheters would be removed. The patient would then undergo ureteroscopic evaluation at 3 months following the final instillation of MitoGel. The total duration of study would be 3 months.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Therapy to be utilized as part of the FDA Compassionate use IND&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed low grade upper tract urothelial carcinoma which is&#xD;
             high-volume and difficult to control using standard ablative therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anatomically solitary kidney or renal insufficiency significant enough such that&#xD;
             nephroureterectomy would result in dialysis dependence&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to consent and participate in a single-patient expanded access use under an&#xD;
             FDA IND agreement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to maintain an indwelling foley catheter for a period of 3 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypersensitivity to mitomycin C or any of the other drug components&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently participating in or has participated in a study of an investigational&#xD;
             agent or using an investigational device within 4 weeks of the first dose of treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an active urinary tract infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is unable to tolerate the treatments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Demonstrates progressively worsening renal dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known additional malignancy that is progressing or requires active treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is pregnant or breastfeeding, or expecting to conceive or father children within the&#xD;
             projected duration of the trial&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>76 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>77 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCLA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90024</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 2, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 2, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 7, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 12, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 12, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 14, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Transitional Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

