<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01060085</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D0842</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01060085</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Digital Breast Tomosynthesis Versus Contrast Enhanced Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) for Breast Cancer Staging</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Comparison of the Diagnostic Accuracy of Adjunctive Digital Breast Tomosynthesis Versus Adjunctive Contrast Enhanced Breast Magnetic Resonance Imaging in the Preoperative Assessment of Breast Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hologic, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this study is to compare the diagnostic accuracy of Digital Breast&#xD;
      Tomosynthesis (DBT) versus that of Contrast Enhanced Magnetic Resonance Imaging (CEMRI) in&#xD;
      determining the size of breast cancer preoperatively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Comparing the operating characteristics of each combined imaging protocol with respect&#xD;
           to the reference standard, i.e. histopathologic assessment, of additional non-index&#xD;
           lesions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Comparison of re-excision rates based on estimated disease extent from adjunctive CEMRI&#xD;
           vs. adjunctive DBT.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Evaluation of patient satisfaction with regard to the adjunctive modality (DBT vs.&#xD;
           CEMRI).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      STUDY OVERVIEW&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects are enrolled within 4 weeks of the date of diagnosis of biopsy proven ductal&#xD;
      carcinoma in-situ (DCIS) or Invasive Breast Cancer. Approximately 50 subjects will be&#xD;
      enrolled. In addition to Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center's (DHMC)current standard imaging&#xD;
      practice, i.e. bilateral mammography with or without sonography and bilateral CEMRI, all&#xD;
      subjects will undergo bilateral DBT within four weeks of CEMRI and prior to surgical&#xD;
      treatment. Usual clinical practice, i.e. interpretation of current standard imaging&#xD;
      (Mammography, Sonography and CEMRI), and clinical assessment based on physical exam as well,&#xD;
      as discussion with the patient and breast surgeon of record, will dictate local treatment,&#xD;
      i.e. surgical excision only, breast conservation therapy (BCT) or mastectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any routine diagnostic examinations completed as part of the subject's standard of care&#xD;
      imaging will be read and interpreted as part of the patient's standard of care. There will be&#xD;
      no delays in reading or interpretation of the routine care images.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blinded reads of the DBT and CEMRI images will be conducted, with the patient's mammography&#xD;
      +/- sonography available for reference. The interpreting radiologists (&quot;readers&quot;) will&#xD;
      evaluate tumor size and extent of disease, along with the presence or absence of&#xD;
      multi-focality or contralateral disease. The two imaging paradigms will be compared in the&#xD;
      estimation of breast cancer extent using the gold-standard histologic result.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DBT mammography may provide new or different information about the index lesion than standard&#xD;
      imaging, but this will not alter clinical management. However, if DBT detects an additional&#xD;
      abnormality separate from the index lesion either in the ipsilateral or contralateral breast,&#xD;
      it will be evaluated further with standard imaging technology (e.g. diagnostic mammography&#xD;
      and or sonography) targeted to this site to assess the level of suspicion for malignancy and&#xD;
      potential need for biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PROCEDURES&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tomosynthesis Acquisition&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study participants shown to have DCIS or invasive breast cancer by fine needle aspiration&#xD;
      cytology and/or core needle biopsy, and who have signed informed consent, will undergo a&#xD;
      bilateral DBT mammogram within 4 weeks of CEMRI (prior to surgical treatment). The DBT&#xD;
      mammogram includes a 2D acquisition and a 3D acquisition, under the same compression in both&#xD;
      the standard craniocaudal (CC) and mediolateral (MLO) projections. In the rare instance that&#xD;
      the index malignancy is not included on a view due to a chest wall location, a single repeat&#xD;
      view of the involved (i.e. cancerous) breast will be performed in an attempt to image the&#xD;
      malignancy on the combined DBT mammogram. For each view, the subject will be positioned and&#xD;
      compressed as for standard mammographic imaging. The patient will remain under compression&#xD;
      for no more than 15 seconds. During the compression, a 3D dataset (about a 4 second exposure)&#xD;
      and a 2D dataset (about a 2 second exposure) will be acquired. Once the subject is positioned&#xD;
      and compressed, the technologist will activate the motion of the x-ray tube to move to the&#xD;
      starting position of -7.5 degrees. The technologist will then start the tomosynthesis 3D&#xD;
      acquisition, which is completed at +7.5 degrees (an arc of 15 degrees). The x-ray tube then&#xD;
      by design moves back to the center and automatically acquires the 2D dataset. At the&#xD;
      conclusion of image acquisition, the compression is automatically released.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Radiologic Technologist registered for radiography and mammography will perform the&#xD;
      tomosynthesis study. The technologist performing the DBT exam has been trained in the use and&#xD;
      operation of the DBT imaging system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Device Description&#xD;
&#xD;
      A DBT system similar to the commercially available product ('Selenia Dimensions', Hologic,&#xD;
      Inc., Danbury CT) will be used for the data collection. The 'Selenia Dimensions' 2D/3D&#xD;
      digital mammography system has been approved by the FDA for screening and diagnostic breast&#xD;
      imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The breast tomosynthesis system is a digital mammography system (Hologic, Inc, Danbury, CT)&#xD;
      that is capable of producing standard two-dimensional images and a three-dimensional&#xD;
      tomosynthesis mammogram. The 2D and 3D tomographic datasets are acquired under the same&#xD;
      compression. The breast tomosynthesis system employs a tungsten target anode with&#xD;
      interchangeable rhodium, silver, and aluminum x-ray filters. The filtration material is&#xD;
      chosen based on breast thickness and exam protocol and, along with the tungsten target,&#xD;
      minimizes x-ray dose while maximizing image content. The three-dimensional tomosynthesis&#xD;
      x-ray imaging technology involves acquiring images of a stationary compressed breast, at&#xD;
      multiple angles during a short-scan. The individual images are then reconstructed into a&#xD;
      series of thin high-resolution slices that are displayed individually or in a dynamic cine&#xD;
      mode. When in combination mode, the system acquires both the 3D dataset and then the 2D&#xD;
      standard mammographic image. The dose for a single combination 2D/3D acquisition for the&#xD;
      &quot;average breast&quot; i.e. compressed breast thickness of 4.5 cm, 50% fat, 50% glandular&#xD;
      composition is approximately 2.45 mGy, less than the FDA limit for a single mammogram image&#xD;
      (3 mGy) for the same breast thickness and composition.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The DBT system will only be used for subjects who have signed the Informed Consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Quality Control&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Hologic Tomosynthesis Digital Mammography System (DBT) will be checked by a qualified&#xD;
      medical physicist prior to any testing or imaging of subjects to assure the system is&#xD;
      operating correctly with optimum image quality. A Study Technologist will review images,&#xD;
      obtain phantom images and check system operation on a periodic basis to assure that optimum&#xD;
      image quality is maintained. The quality control procedures described in the systems'&#xD;
      operator manuals will be used throughout the trial. If there is any noticeable degradation in&#xD;
      image quality, a Hologic engineer will be called immediately to recalibrate or repair the&#xD;
      system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CEMRI&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each subject will undergo bilateral CEMRI as part of usual clinical practice, not because of&#xD;
      their participation in the study. Subjects who are unable to undergo contrast enhanced MRI&#xD;
      due to contraindications to MRI or gadolinium based intravenous contrast are not eligible for&#xD;
      study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Image Interpretation&#xD;
&#xD;
      The DBT images will be evaluated by a Mammography Quality Standards Act certified&#xD;
      radiologist. There will be two readers for each subject: one reader will interpret DBT&#xD;
      (blinded to results of CEMRI), while the second reader will interpret CEMRI (blinded to&#xD;
      results of DBT). Each reader interprets the adjunct exam (i.e. DBT or CEMRI) unblinded to&#xD;
      conventional imaging (i.e. mammography +/- sonography) and completes the appropriate rating&#xD;
      instrument.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Size Determination&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Readers will estimate the maximal in plane diameter in at least two imaging planes of&#xD;
      the index malignant lesion. For DBT, maximal diameters should be measured in the CC and MLO&#xD;
      projections. For CEMRI, maximal diameters should be measured in axial and sagittal&#xD;
      projections. Readers will also report on and diagram the location of additional lesions that&#xD;
      are not considered definitely benign.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Histological Interpretation&#xD;
&#xD;
      The specimen (lumpectomy or mastectomy) is sequentially sectioned into 5 mm slices and the&#xD;
      number of slices is recorded in the gross description. Targeted sections are taken of both&#xD;
      lumpectomies and mastectomies by sampling lesions identified by imaging (per usual clinical&#xD;
      protocol). Such lesions are submitted as appropriate along with 1-2 sections of a surrounding&#xD;
      cuff of normal appearing parenchyma in each appropriate direction. The distance between&#xD;
      multiple lesions is measured, and in such cases a single section of intervening tissue is&#xD;
      submitted for histologic examination. Incidental lesions identified on gross exam are sampled&#xD;
      as appropriate. The histopathologic specimen is viewed by a pathologist with 3-20 years of&#xD;
      experience in breast pathology. Invasive disease is graded according to the Nottingham Bloom&#xD;
      Scarff Richardson system. DCIS is graded according to a modified Van Nuys system, including&#xD;
      the nuclear grade, the presence or absence of necrosis, and the pattern of growth. The number&#xD;
      of consecutive slides containing DCIS will be multiplied by the approximate thickness of each&#xD;
      tissue section (5mm) in order to determine the histopathologic size.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tumor size will be determined by gross examination of the pathology specimen when visible on&#xD;
      gross examination. Tumor size estimate in this case will reflect an aggregate of invasive and&#xD;
      non-invasive, i.e. DCIS, components.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If no gross lesion is seen, the measurement of tumor size will be determined by the&#xD;
      microscopic measurement of the lesion. Since the 2 components are intermingled, the size&#xD;
      reported represents an aggregate size.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to the gross exam measurement, if a lesion is substantially composed of DCIS,&#xD;
      (i.e. extensive intraductal component present) by microscopic examination, we will specify&#xD;
      the size of both the invasive component (by microscopic exam) as well as a measurement of the&#xD;
      DCIS component (by microscopic exam) and provide an aggregate size of both invasive and DCIS&#xD;
      components).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In cases of invasive cancer with an extensive component of DCIS treated with mastectomy or a&#xD;
      very wide local excision, standard pathologic sampling of the lesion may not allow for&#xD;
      accurate microscopic size estimate of the lesion. In these select cases the pathologist will&#xD;
      indicate the type of growth pattern of the DCIS component as either &quot;mass-like&quot; or &quot;non&#xD;
      mass-like&quot;.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison between the accuracy of DBT vs. CEMRI using two measurements: 1. Maximal diameter estimate by imaging modality and 2. Maximal diameter based on histopathology gold standard.</measure>
    <time_frame>surgical pathology results completed</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>True positives, true negatives, false positives and false negatives for: 1. Multi-focality defined as additional discrete discontinuous tumor foci that are at least 2.5 cm separate from the index lesion. 2. Contralateral disease: presence/absence</measure>
    <time_frame>surgical pathology results completed</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Predicted re-excision rates based on size estimates from each imaging paradigm</measure>
    <time_frame>surgical pathology results completed</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction survey for DBT and CEMRI imaging</measure>
    <time_frame>patient completion of DBT and CEMRI imaging</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">51</enrollment>
  <condition>Ductal Carcinoma In Situ</condition>
  <condition>Invasive Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Breast Cancer</arm_group_label>
    <description>Women shown to have DCIS or invasive breast cancer by fine needle aspiration cytology and/or core needle biopsy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Women who have histologically proven, non-inflammatory, breast cancer.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is female of any race and ethnicity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is at least 30 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has histologically proven DCIS or invasive breast carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is able to undergo CEMRI at DHMC-Lebanon&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are pregnant or think they may be pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are breast-feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have significant existing breast trauma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects unable or unwilling to undergo informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute contraindication to CEMRI, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. presence of implanted electrical device (pacemaker or neurostimulator),aneurysm&#xD;
                  clip, or metallic foreign body in or near the eyes&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. life threatening allergy to gadolinium contrast&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CEMRI performed at institution other than DHMC Lebanon&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing neoadjuvant therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with maximum tumor diameter &gt;5cm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients presenting with Inflammatory Breast Cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with gross axillary lymphadenopathy on clinical exam or by imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Maximum breast size limitation: i.e. breast size that exceeds the size of the large&#xD;
             format image receptor (24cm x 29cm) on any view&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Steven P Poplack, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lebanon</city>
        <state>New Hampshire</state>
        <zip>03756</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 29, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 1, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 2, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 20, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 20, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 23, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma in Situ</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Ductal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Intraductal, Noninfiltrating</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

