<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02842905</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H15-01282</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02842905</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Examining the Impact of Physician Influence on Hearing Aid User Satisfaction and Retention</brief_title>
  <official_title>Examining the Impact of Physician Influence on Hearing Aid User Satisfaction and Retention</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of British Columbia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>NexGen Hearing</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of British Columbia</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Most of us will experience some degree of hearing loss as we get older. It can affect one or&#xD;
      both ears and without treatment causes difficulty with following conversations in the home or&#xD;
      workplace. Audiologists are trained to diagnose and treat hearing loss and tinnitus problems.&#xD;
      They also dispense, and fit hearing aids. Physicians do not provide or fit hearing aids&#xD;
      directly, however they diagnose hearing loss and can recommend hearing aids amongst other&#xD;
      treatments for hearing loss. It is undecided whether consulting with a physician in addition&#xD;
      to an audiologist will improve user's satisfaction with hearing aids, compared to consulting&#xD;
      with an audiologist alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether physician involvement (in addition to an&#xD;
      audiologist) in the hearing aid fitting process improves users' satisfaction with hearing&#xD;
      aids. The study utilizes questionnaires to assess satisfaction with hearing aids.&#xD;
      Furthermore, participants decision to keep the purchased hearing aids will be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will take place in the clinics of family doctors, Otolaryngology (Ear) surgeons and&#xD;
      audiologists. A hearing aid suitable for the needs of the participant will be fitted by an&#xD;
      audiologist. In the first 21days after the fitting, participants will attend follow-up visits&#xD;
      with the audiologists for adjustments to the hearing aids to best meet their specific&#xD;
      listening needs. After 21 days, eligible participants will be allocated to either the Control&#xD;
      or Test groups. Participants in both groups will be asked to describe the change in their&#xD;
      hearing performance related to the use of hearing aids to their audiologist(Control) or&#xD;
      Physician (Test) at a follow-up visit. At the study's final visit, participants will be asked&#xD;
      to complete a satisfaction-based questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The time taken to fit a hearing aid varies depending on the individual needs of the patient.&#xD;
      It is estimated that at most 10 visits will be required over 90 days to complete the hearing&#xD;
      aid fitting and study processes. These visits will be of 30 minutes duration on average,&#xD;
      except for the initial and final visits which lasts for 45 minutes. A patient will spend a&#xD;
      maximum of 330 minutes to complete the hearing aid fitting process, but only 25 minutes of&#xD;
      this time will be specifically related to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is intended to determine the satisfaction with hearing aids and consultations with&#xD;
      health professionals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Description of study design This study seeks to determine if additional patient benefit is&#xD;
      derived from involving the referring physician in the hearing aid fitting process using the&#xD;
      Client Oriented Scale of Improvement (COSI) process. The COSI process is a well-known&#xD;
      methodology that consists of two consecutive phases: Phase I is completed by the client with&#xD;
      the Audiologist either at the time of initial hearing aid fitting or within 21 days&#xD;
      thereafter. The patient is asked to list any specific listening environment/situations in&#xD;
      which he/she would like to improve his/her hearing with the assistance of wearing hearing&#xD;
      aids; Phase II occurs within days 22 to 76 from the day the hearing aid device is fitted and&#xD;
      is also normally completed by the patient and the Audiologist. In this phase, the patient&#xD;
      indicates any degree of change in the specific listening environment/situations he/she had&#xD;
      previously listed (wearing the hearing aid).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two methods will be used for study purposes to assess patient satisfaction with hearing aid&#xD;
      use 77 to 90 days post fitting: (1) the validated SADL questionnaire described previously&#xD;
      will be completed by the patient and (2) the number of hearing aids returned up to 90 days&#xD;
      post initial fitting will be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will consist of two groups: a control group and a test group. Both groups will&#xD;
      undergo Phase I of the COSI process with the fitting Audiologist. Patients in the control&#xD;
      group will undergo Phase II of the COSI process as part of their follow up with the&#xD;
      audiologist, whereas those in the test group will complete Phase II of the COSI process in a&#xD;
      scheduled visit with their referring physician before further follow-up with the audiologist.&#xD;
      Participants will be recruited from the investigating audiologists' clinics in Vancouver. The&#xD;
      study involvement time for each participant will extend over a period of 90 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Routine Clinical Practice A complete hearing aid fitting takes place over the course of&#xD;
      several clinic visits each on average 30-45 minutes in duration. These include the initial&#xD;
      hearing test and consultation, actual fitting, and any subsequent post-fitting adjustments.&#xD;
      During hearing evaluation and post-fitting follow-up sessions, a COSI questionnaire is used&#xD;
      by audiologists as part of routine clinical practice to guide optimal hearing aid adjustment&#xD;
      to meet the patient's listening needs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Time schedule The time taken to fit a hearing aid varies depending on the needs of the&#xD;
      patient. Very often clients over the age of 55 have problems with dexterity, memory and other&#xD;
      health impairments that extend the length of individual consultations. Some patients require&#xD;
      more clinic consultations than others. Anecdotally it is estimated that the maximal number of&#xD;
      visits required to complete the hearing aid fitting process is 10 visits over 90 days. These&#xD;
      visits on average will be of 30 minutes in duration except for the initial and final visits&#xD;
      which lasts for 45 minutes. A patient will spend a maximum of 330 minutes to complete the&#xD;
      hearing aid fitting process of which 25 minutes will be related to study specific procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects Patients referred by General practitioners or Otolaryngologists for hearing aid&#xD;
      fittings to the offices of two Audiologists who meet the inclusion criteria will be provided&#xD;
      with details of the study including a participant information and consent form at their&#xD;
      initial evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Procedures Recruitment Patients who satisfy the inclusion criteria will be invited to&#xD;
      participate in the study and complete a study consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Allocation Consenting patients will be assigned a study ID and randomized into the Control or&#xD;
      Test group using a table of random numbers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention Process Consenting patients will be randomised using a random number table to&#xD;
      have a post-fitting visit between days 21 to 60 after the initial hearing aid fitting with an&#xD;
      Audiologist (Control group) or the referring Physician (Test Group). At this visit the&#xD;
      audiologist or physician will document the degree of hearing change in specific listening&#xD;
      environment/situations as a result of hearing aid use by following the COSI questionnaire.&#xD;
      This visit will be for a maximum of 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A follow-up visit of this nature is part of routine clinical practice for the participating&#xD;
      audiologist. The physician visit is the novel study intervention after which the patient&#xD;
      returns for all subsequent follow-ups with the hearing aid fitting audiologist in keeping&#xD;
      with routine clinical practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient data to be collected&#xD;
&#xD;
      Demographics:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • age, sex&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical data:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • degree of hearing loss&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Analysis The primary indicator of patient satisfaction will be the scored 15-item SADL&#xD;
      questionnaire. The Statistical Program for the Social Sciences will be used to undertake a&#xD;
      t-test or ANOVA comparison of the mean total SADL questionnaire scores in the Control and&#xD;
      Test groups. The secondary outcome measure hearing aid returns, will be assessed by&#xD;
      Chi-squared tests of the proportion of returned hearing aids returned in both groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Satisfaction with Amplification in Daily Life questionnaire score</measure>
    <time_frame>SADL questionnaire completed at patient's final visit or when hearing aid is returned (77-90 days from initial hearing aid fitting)</time_frame>
    <description>Participant determined satisfaction level with the hearing aid based on the Satisfaction with Amplification in Daily Life (SADL) questionnaire score.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of Hearing aid returned</measure>
    <time_frame>77-90 day post fitting</time_frame>
    <description>Participant dissatisfaction with the hearing aid based on the proportion of hearing aids returned</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Hearing Loss</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Fitting Audiologist completion of the Client Outcome Scale of Improvement at a post fitting follow up visit.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Test Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participant's physician completion of the Client Outcome Scale of Improvement at a post fitting follow up visit.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fitting Audiologist completion</intervention_name>
    <description>Phase II of the COSI (Client Oriented Scale of Improvement) questionnaire completed in a scheduled visit with the fitting Audiologist</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Participant's Physician completion</intervention_name>
    <description>Phase II of the COSI (Client Oriented Scale of Improvement) questionnaire completed in a scheduled visit with the Participant's Physician</description>
    <arm_group_label>Test Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  55 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sensorineural hearing loss greater than 25 dB averaged over frequencies 0.5, 1, 2 and&#xD;
             4 KHz; or 2, 3 and 4 KHz on pure tone audiometry in either ear.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have used a hearing for up to 21 days after being fitted&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age under 55 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to follow doctor/audiologist's instructions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous hearing aid use&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Desmond Nunez, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of British Columbia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kevin Zhao</last_name>
    <phone>7789296191</phone>
    <email>kevin.zhao@alumni.ubc.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Desmond Nunez, MD</last_name>
    <phone>604 875 4664</phone>
    <email>desmond.nunez@ubc.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vancouver General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vancouver</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V5Z1M9</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kevin Zhao, MD</last_name>
      <phone>7789296191</phone>
      <email>kevin.zhao@alumni.ubc.ca</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 13, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 22, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 25, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 27, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 27, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 1, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of British Columbia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Desmond A Nunez</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hearing Loss</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>We intend to IPD post publication of the study's findings. We estimate that this will be from July 2019</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>From July 2019- June 2020</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>By contacting corresponding author in peer reviewed publication.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

