<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03507218</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>180036</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>18-M-0036</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03507218</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pediatric Acute-Onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome (PANS)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical, Laboratory, and Biomedical Characterization of Pediatric Acute-onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome (PANS)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      PANS is an illness that comes on suddenly in children. The full name is Pediatric Acute-Onset&#xD;
      Neuropsychiatric Syndrome. It can cause sudden obsessive-compulsive behaviors. It can also&#xD;
      cause children to suddenly restricte their food intake. Researchers want to learn more about&#xD;
      children with PANS. They also want to learn more about the illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To study some disorders of behavior and emotion that start in childhood.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Children 3 14 years old who have had severe obsessive-compulsive symptoms or food restriction&#xD;
      start quickly&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Parents will answer questions. The topics include:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Their child s medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
      Their child s physical and mental health&#xD;
&#xD;
      Their family history. The focus will be on neurodevelopmental and psychiatric conditions. A&#xD;
      family tree will be drawn.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have a physical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may take tests on paper or computer. These will focus on thinking, memory, and&#xD;
      behavior.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants and parents will give a blood sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). A strong magnetic field and radio&#xD;
      waves take pictures of the brain. Participants will lie on a table that slides in and out of&#xD;
      a metal scanner.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may have photos or videos taken.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may have other tests. These may include heart tests, sleep tests, and lumbar&#xD;
      puncture.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sponsoring Institute: National Institute of Mental Health&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This multi-site study is intended to collect data and samples from a nationwide cohort of&#xD;
      children with Pediatric Acute-onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome (PANS). PANS is defined by&#xD;
      three clinical criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Abrupt, dramatic onset of obsessive-compulsive disorder (OCD) or severely restricted&#xD;
&#xD;
           food intake AND&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Concurrent presence of additional neuropsychiatric symptoms, with similarly severe and&#xD;
           acute onset, from at least two of the following seven categories:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Anxiety (particularly separation anxiety)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Emotional lability and depression&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Irritability, aggression, and/or severely oppositional behaviors&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Behavioral (developmental) regression&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Deterioration in school performance (due to inattention, concentration&#xD;
                difficulties, memory deficits, or others)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Sensory or motor abnormalities&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Somatic signs and symptoms, including sleep disturbances, enuresis, or urinary&#xD;
                frequency&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Symptoms are not better explained by a known neurologic or medical disorder, such as&#xD;
           Sydenham chorea, systemic lupus erythematosus, Tourette disorder, or others.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As a clinical syndrome, PANS likely represents a number of different disorders with unique&#xD;
      symptom constellations, disease mechanisms, and etiologies. The purpose of this investigation&#xD;
      is to identify these distinctive disorders by carefully documenting, archiving, and analyzing&#xD;
      the clinical features of each case of PANS, including not only details of the onset and&#xD;
      course of symptoms, but also results of physical examination, laboratory assays, and&#xD;
      paraclinical assessments, such as electroencephalography (EEG), polysomnography (PSG), brain&#xD;
      imaging (e.g., magnetic resonance imaging [MRI] scans), and others. In addition to defining&#xD;
      the unique clinical features associated with a specific disorder, we also hope to identify&#xD;
      biomarkers of risk and disease severity, including not only determinant genes, but also&#xD;
      environmental triggers, such as those producing post-infectious autoimmunity (e.g., Pediatric&#xD;
      Autoimmune Neuropsychiatric Disorders Associated with Streptococcal infection, or PANDAS). To&#xD;
      accomplish this, we propose to collect and archive clinical information and biospecimens at&#xD;
      different stages of the illness (e.g., initial onset, first exacerbation, following known&#xD;
      environmental triggers, during convalescence, etc.) and also to compare these results against&#xD;
      data and specimens obtained from healthy controls and children with non-PANDAS OCD, tics,&#xD;
      anxiety disorders, or eating disorder. Clinical, laboratory, and biomedical data will be&#xD;
      stored in the NIMH database (housed on the Clinical Trials Database [CTDB] of NICHD) and&#xD;
      blood, genetic material, and other biospecimens, including microbial cultures, stored in the&#xD;
      NIMH Genetics/Biological Repository. There are two types of baseline evaluations within this&#xD;
      protocol. The first is limited to participants with acute-onset neuropsychiatric symptoms&#xD;
      (PANS subjects) and will be conducted in the NIH Clinical Center by investigators from the&#xD;
      NIMH Section on Behavioral Pediatrics (Drs. Swedo, Grant, and Hommer.) These in-depth&#xD;
      phenotyping evaluations will include medical and psychiatric history, family history,&#xD;
      completion of standardized questionnaires, physical and neurological examinations,&#xD;
      neuropsychological testing, MRI scan, throat swab (for microbiologic testing), cheek swab (to&#xD;
      obtain genetic samples), and phlebotomy to obtain blood for laboratory assays and genetic&#xD;
      testing. Children with undiagnosed acute-onset neuropsychiatric symptoms may undergo&#xD;
      additional testing as part of the diagnostic evaluation; these assessments might include&#xD;
      (among others), electroencephalography (EEG), echocardiogram/electrocardiogram (ECHO/ECG)&#xD;
      and/or polysomnography (PSG). If the child s clinical presentation warrants a lumbar puncture&#xD;
      as part of the diagnostic evaluation, (e.g. abnormal findings on neurologic exam, EEG or PSG,&#xD;
      or lab abnormalities suggestive of systemic autoimmunity or neuroinflammation), a sample of&#xD;
      cerebrospinal fluid will be collected for research, as well as for clinical testing. Sedation&#xD;
      will not be used for these lumbar punctures, nor will it be used for any research purposes in&#xD;
      this protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The second type of baseline evaluation will be used at NIMH for subjects with non-PANDAS&#xD;
      psychiatric disorders and healthy volunteers. At participating extramural institutions, this&#xD;
      is the evaluation that will be used for all participants (PANS, non-PANS, healthy volunteers)&#xD;
      evaluated. These evaluations will include standardized questionnaires, medical and&#xD;
      psychiatric history, family history, physical examination, throat swab (for microbiologic&#xD;
      testing), cheek swab (to obtain genetic samples), and phlebotomy to obtain blood for clinical&#xD;
      assays and research, including genetic studies. The assessments will generally be completed&#xD;
      in an outpatient clinic at the participating site, but also might be performed on&#xD;
      hospitalized children, if their medical condition permits research participation. Family&#xD;
      members of PANS probands will have a medical and psychiatric history and physical exam and&#xD;
      provide a blood sample (or cheek swab) for genetic research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Affected Probands, Healthy Volunteers, and Subjects with Non-PANS Psychiatric Disorders&#xD;
      will have follow-up evaluations annually, as well as on Ad Hoc basis. The Annual check-ups&#xD;
      will include an interim clinical history and relevant symptom ratings (tailored to the&#xD;
      subject s clinical profile). These follow-up evaluations may be done by phone or&#xD;
      videoconference. Ad hoc evaluations will occur during periods of health (if not healthy at&#xD;
      baseline) and during an episode of acute illness (either infectious illness or&#xD;
      neuropsychiatric symptom exacerbations) and convalescence (at least 8 weeks after recovery).&#xD;
      These in-person evaluations will include an interim clinical history, relevant symptom&#xD;
      ratings, phlebotomy to obtain research bloods, and in some cases, acquisition of microbial&#xD;
      samples (oral, nasal, nasopharyngeal and/or pharyngeal swabs, and feces). To identify&#xD;
      biomarkers of disease and recovery, children with PANS may be followed until their 18th&#xD;
      birthday, even if fully recovered from their acute illness. Healthy volunteers and&#xD;
      psychiatric controls will be followed no longer than 3 years from study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a natural history study, with the primary goal of collecting clinical data and&#xD;
      biospecimens in order to identify subgroups of patients sharing a common disease mechanism&#xD;
      and thus provide opportunities for development of new treatment and prevention strategies.&#xD;
      The wealth of clinical information and the large number of biologic and genetic samples&#xD;
      acquired in this prospective, longitudinal investigation also permits us to address four&#xD;
      specific aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Identify unique and distinctive clinical, paraclinical, and laboratory features of&#xD;
           acuteonset neuropsychiatric disorders among patients meeting criteria for PANS.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Determine the role of environmental pathogens, such as Group A streptococci, in the&#xD;
           etiopathogenesis of acute-onset neuropsychiatric disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Investigate factors influencing host susceptibility and resistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Elucidate the role of immune dysfunction in PANS or a subgroup of its patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Provide clinical diagnostic assessments to children with undiagnosed acute-onset&#xD;
           neuropsychiatric symptoms.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    PI left and section closed.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 20, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 23, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 23, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Establish national database and samples repository for pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome (PANS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Study Completion</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Identify unique and distinctive features of subgroups of patients with PANS, in order to determine the shared disease mechanism</measure>
    <time_frame>Study completion</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Elucidate the role of immune dysfunction in the syndrome of PANS, as well as for subgroups of patients</measure>
    <time_frame>Study completion</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine role of environmental pathogens, such as Group A streptococci, in the etiopathogenesis of PANS</measure>
    <time_frame>Study completion</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Investigate factors influencing host susceptibility and resistance</measure>
    <time_frame>Study completion</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">9</enrollment>
  <condition>Pediatric Acute-onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome (PANS)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <description>Children with Pediatric Acute-onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome (PANS)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        study population will include potential participants from primary care and specialty&#xD;
        medical referrals, community samples, and self-referral from across the United States.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Affected Probands (Children with PANS) will be eligible if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Are 3 to 14 years of age (initial enrollment must occur prior&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have a history of abrupt onset (less than 24-48 hours) of impairing OCD and/or eating&#xD;
             restrictions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Are able to travel safely to the regional medical center where the evaluations will be&#xD;
             conducted and are able to be examined safely over a period of one or more days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Assent to participate (if they are at least seven years old and have capacity to do&#xD;
             so) and have legal guardians who consent to their minor child s participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Are under the care of a primary physician in their home community.&#xD;
&#xD;
        First-degree Relatives will be eligible if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Are a biologic parent or sibling of an affected proband.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Consent (or assent) to undergo study evaluations and to provide blood, microbial and&#xD;
             genetic samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Children with Non-PANS Neuropsychiatric Symptoms may be enrolled if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Are 3 to 14 years of age (initial enrollment must occur prior to the participant s&#xD;
             15th birthday to permit prospective longitudinal evaluations)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have OCD, tics, anxiety disorders, or other psychiatric symptoms, but do NOT have a&#xD;
             history of acute symptom onset.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Are willing to participate in medical, psychiatric, and behavioral assessments and to&#xD;
             provide bio-specimens including blood, urine, and microbial flora (mouth, oropharynx,&#xD;
             and/or stool).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Assent to participate (if they are at least seven years old and have capacity to do&#xD;
             so) and have legal guardians who consent to their minor child s participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Are under the care of a primary physician in their home community.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Healthy Pediatric Volunteers may be enrolled if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Are 3 to 14 years of age (initial enrollment must occur prior to the participant s&#xD;
             15th birthday to permit prospective longitudinal evaluations).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Are physically healthy and do not have psychiatric symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Are willing to participate in medical, psychiatric, and behavioral assessments and to&#xD;
             provide bio-specimens including blood, urine, and microbial flora (mouth, oropharynx,&#xD;
             and/or stool).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Assent to participate (if they are at least seven years old and have capacity to do&#xD;
             so) and have legal guardians who consent to their minor child s participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants will not be eligible if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Appear to the investigators to be too unstable psychiatrically or medically to&#xD;
             participate safely in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Are unwilling or unable to be evaluated and followed prospectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have a parent/guardian who is not willing to participate at a distance through&#xD;
             web-based or phone-based data collection.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Susan E Swedo, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Arizona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tucson</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85724</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lucille Salter Packer Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stanford</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94304</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nemours/Alfred I. duPont Hospital for Children</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wilmington</city>
        <state>Delaware</state>
        <zip>19803</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Southern Florida</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33620</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Harvard Medical School</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Minnesota</name>
      <address>
        <city>Minneapolis</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55415</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Missouri</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbia</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>65205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chang K, Frankovich J, Cooperstock M, Cunningham MW, Latimer ME, Murphy TK, Pasternack M, Thienemann M, Williams K, Walter J, Swedo SE; PANS Collaborative Consortium. Clinical evaluation of youth with pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome (PANS): recommendations from the 2013 PANS Consensus Conference. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2015 Feb;25(1):3-13. doi: 10.1089/cap.2014.0084. Epub 2014 Oct 17.</citation>
    <PMID>25325534</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Williams KA, Swedo SE. Post-infectious autoimmune disorders: Sydenham's chorea, PANDAS and beyond. Brain Res. 2015 Aug 18;1617:144-54. doi: 10.1016/j.brainres.2014.09.071. Epub 2014 Oct 7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25301689</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 24, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 24, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 25, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 24, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 24, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 25, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Obsessive Compulsive Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Anxiety Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>PANDAS (Pediatric Autoimmune Neuropsychiatric Disorders Associated d</keyword>
  <keyword>Eating Disorders</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

