<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01429181</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MP10-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01429181</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy &amp; Safety Study of Nonracemic Methadone for the Relief of Chronic Peripheral Neuropathic Pain</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pilot Study to Evaluate Efficacy, Tolerability and Safety Nonracemic Methadone HCl in Patients With Chronic Peripheral Neuropathic Pain: Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Crossover Study Followed by Open-Label, Single-Arm Extension</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>MetaPharm, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>MetaPharm, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There is a growing evidence that the d-isomer of methadone is effective in treating&#xD;
      neuropathic pain while the l-isomer of methadone is the only effective isomer of methadone&#xD;
      for treating somatic pain. This study will examine a combination of different amounts of the&#xD;
      d- and l-isomers of methadone specifically tailored to the chronic peripheral neuropathic&#xD;
      pain. Non-racemic mixture of methadone isomers will be tested in this pilot efficacy and&#xD;
      safety study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will evaluate effect of the three doses of the non-racemic mixture of methadone&#xD;
      hydrochloride patients with chronic peripheral neuropathic pain compared with a placebo. The&#xD;
      study will also examine the minimally effective and maximally tolerated doses of the&#xD;
      non-racemic mixture of methadone. Finally, the safety and tolerability of the non-racemic&#xD;
      methadone therapy will be evaluated.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate effect of the three doses of the non-racemic methadone HCl on the metrics of&#xD;
           pain intensity in comparison to placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine minimally effective and maximally tolerated doses of non-racemic methadone&#xD;
           HCl for the treatment of diabetic peripheral neuropathic pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate safety and tolerability of non-racemic methadone HCl therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a pilot efficacy and safety study comprised of two parts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part I is a double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover study of three daily doses (15 mg, 30&#xD;
      mg and 40 mg) of non-racemic methadone compared with placebo. Two lower doses (15 mg and 30&#xD;
      mg) will be administered for 1 week. The final dose (40 mg) will be administered for 2 weeks.&#xD;
      After receiving three consecutive doses of the assigned drug the subjects will be switched to&#xD;
      another regimen. Two 28-day treatment periods will be separated by a 14-day washout&#xD;
      (drug-free) interval.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be randomly assigned to one of the two treatment sequences:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sequence 1: non-racemic methadone HCl (Period 1) followed by Placebo (Period 2); Sequence 2:&#xD;
      Placebo (Period 1) followed by non-racemic methadone HCl (Period 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects completing Part I will be enrolled into the open-label, single-arm extension.&#xD;
      Subjects discontinuing the study while on placebo may also be eligible for the enrollment.&#xD;
      During the 6-week extension phase (Part II of the study) subjects will be treated with&#xD;
      non-racemic methadone HCl with continuous dose titration driven by the clinical response&#xD;
      (degree of pain relief) and reported adverse events. The Parts I and II will be separated by&#xD;
      a 14-day washout (study drug-free) interval.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Number of Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up to fifty (50) subjects diagnosed with neuropathic pain associated with diabetic peripheral&#xD;
      neuropathy will be enrolled in the study; approximately 30 subjects are expected to complete&#xD;
      Study Part I. Enrollment will be terminated when this completion target is achieved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Duration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The duration of Study Part I is approximately 12 weeks, the duration of Study Part II is&#xD;
      approximately 6 weeks. A total study duration (including screening and final evaluations) is&#xD;
      expected to be approximately 20 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in average daily pain scores</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline to Week 4</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">37</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetic Peripheral Neuropathic Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non Racemic Methadone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Non-Racemic Methadone Hydrochloride 5 mg Capsules containing a non-racemic mixture of methadone isomers.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Matching placebo capsules</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Non-racemic mixture of methadone HCl</intervention_name>
    <description>Non-racemic mixture of methadone HCl capsules, 5 mg</description>
    <arm_group_label>Non Racemic Methadone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female 18 years of age or older;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female with a negative serum βhCG pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female of non-childbearing potential (postmenopausal or surgically sterile) OR female&#xD;
             of child-bearing potential agreed to use the protocol-approved contraceptive method&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented diagnosis of neuropathic pain associated with diabetic peripheral&#xD;
             neuropathy for at least 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Average daily pain severity score &gt;=4 for the seven days prior to randomization (based&#xD;
             on an 11-point numerical rating scale where 0= no pain and 10=worst possible pain)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Score &gt;= 40 mm on the VAS of the Short Form McGill Pain Questionnaire (SF-MPQ) at&#xD;
             screening and randomization visits&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stable doses (for at least three weeks) of non-opioid analgesics including NSAIDS,&#xD;
             corticosteroids, gabapentin, pregabalin or antidepressants prescribed for the purposes&#xD;
             of pain control or pain treatment naïve&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to refrain from any pain-relieving drugs other than the protocol-approved&#xD;
             rescue medications (acetaminophen, &lt;= 3 g daily or aspirin &lt;= 325 mg daily) during the&#xD;
             screening phase and the course of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to limit alcohol consumption during the study according to protocol&#xD;
             requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to understand and complete study diary and questionnaires&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to give informed consent prior to entry into the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A documented neuropathy of any cause other than diabetic peripheral neuropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A severe intermittent pain for reasons other than radiculopathy (e.g., migraine&#xD;
             attacks)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of head injury and/or increased intracranial pressure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any neurologic disorder unrelated to diabetic peripheral neuropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-adequate renal and/or hepatic function as follows: Serum creatinine &gt; 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
             (upper limit of normal range) Liver enzymes (ALT and AST) &gt; 2 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other know laboratory abnormality that, in the investigator's opinion, would&#xD;
             contraindicate study participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic hepatitis B, hepatitis C, or HIV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal cognition defined as obvious clinical findings of state of arousal, confusion&#xD;
             and memory or concentration deficit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent history (within the previous 12 months) of respiratory depression, acute&#xD;
             bronchial asthma or hypercarbia, or any other severe pulmonary or respiratory disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent history (within the previous 12 months) of sleep apnea&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any hemostatic disorders or a current treatment with anticoagulants;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unstable cardiovascular disease or symptomatic peripheral vascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypotension: sitting or standing systolic blood pressure &lt;= 90 mmHg and/or diastolic&#xD;
             blood pressure &lt;= 60 mmHg at screening and/or orthostatic hypotension (defined as a&#xD;
             difference between sitting and standing systolic blood pressure &gt;20 mmHg and/or a&#xD;
             difference between sitting and standing diastolic blood pressure &gt;10 mmHg)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any clinically important ECG abnormality (including QT interval exceeding 450 ms)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent history (within the last 12 months) of risk factors for development of&#xD;
             prolonged QT interval, including cardiac hypertrophy, concomitant diuretic use,&#xD;
             hypocalcemia, hypomagnesemia&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eugene Mironer, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>MetaPharm, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 31, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 2, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 5, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 28, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 28, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Peripheral Neuropathic Pain</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Methadone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

