<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04719962</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>7609</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04719962</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Direct Diagnosis of Disseminated Lyme Borreliosis.</brief_title>
  <acronym>DIALYD</acronym>
  <official_title>Diagnosis of Disseminated Lyme Borreliosis by Targeted Proteomics</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Strasbourg, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Strasbourg, France</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Lyme borreliosis is a bacterial multisystemic infection transmitted by an Ixodes tick. It&#xD;
      affects the skin, the joint and the brain. At the early phase, the diagnosis is clinical,&#xD;
      relying on the presence of an erythema migrans at the site of the tick bite. The diagnosis of&#xD;
      disseminated infections, more difficult to assess, mainly relies on indirect diagnosis test,&#xD;
      i.e. serology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will evaluate a new direct diagnosis method based on proteomics, which aims to&#xD;
      demonstrate proteins of live bacteria in the skin and the synovial or cerebrospinal fluids in&#xD;
      a direct manner.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Lyme borreliosis is a multisystemic bacterial infection affecting the skin, the joint and the&#xD;
      nervous system. It has been shown that the skin is an essential interface as a site of&#xD;
      bacteria inoculation and multiplication. In mouse acutely infected with different Borrelia&#xD;
      species, the investigators have detected several protein markers of active infection in the&#xD;
      skin by discovery proteomics, which allowed us to design a subsequent targeted proteomics&#xD;
      assay. The invcestigators tested the same techniques in skin biopsies of humans presenting&#xD;
      with an erythema migrans. Most of the bacterial proteins previously identified in the skin of&#xD;
      infected mice were also detected in biopsies of human lesional skin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The diagnosis of disseminated Lyme borreliosis currently mainly relies on evocative clinical&#xD;
      symptoms along with a positive Borrelia serology. However, a positive serological test does&#xD;
      not prove an active infection but merely reflects exposure to the pathogen, which is quite&#xD;
      common in endemic regions and thus lacks positive predictive value. Moreover, direct&#xD;
      bacteriological diagnosis tools such as culture and nucleic acid amplification (PCR)&#xD;
      currently lack sensitivity. Planning to test the ability of proteomics to assist in the&#xD;
      diagnosis of disseminated Lyme borreliosis, we have first developed a model of late infection&#xD;
      in mouse, and achieved the identification of several bacterial proteins as markers of ongoing&#xD;
      infection in the murine skin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators now wish to investigate whether the skin also constitutes a reservoir for&#xD;
      these bacteria during persistent disseminated infection in humans, and if they can detect&#xD;
      bacterial proteins in this easily accessible tissue by the same approach. They will directly&#xD;
      look for bacterial proteins by selected reaction monitoring-mass spectrometry (SRM-MS), the&#xD;
      method successfully employed in early infection setting. The ability to detect borrelial&#xD;
      proteins in synovial fluid (patients with Lyme arthritis), cerebrospinal fluid (patients with&#xD;
      Lyme neuroborreliosis) or lesional skin (patients with acrodermatitis chronica atrophicans)&#xD;
      will also be investigated, as appropriated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To improve the detection of Borrelia proteins in healthy-looking skin, a dermocorticoid will&#xD;
      be prealably applied for a short 2-days course, a procedure the investigators demonstrated&#xD;
      both useful and safe in mice. Since tick bite mainly occurs in the lower part of the body,&#xD;
      the upper part of the thigh will be the site of topical steroids application and skin biopsy&#xD;
      .&#xD;
&#xD;
      The proteomics yield will be compared to the two main other methods of direct detection, i.e.&#xD;
      culture and PCR.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Direct diagnosis of disseminated Lyme disease by proteomics</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Detection or not of targeted proteins by SRM-MS in healthy-looking skin samples of patients with disseminated Lyme borreliosis (either clinical presentation)&#xD;
Detection or not of targeted borrelial proteins by SRM-MS in synovial fluid of patients with Lyme arthritis&#xD;
Detection or not of targeted borrelial proteins by SRM-MS incerebrospinal fluid of patients with neuroborreliosis&#xD;
Detection or not of targeted borrelial proteins by SRM-MS in lesional skin of patients with acrodermatitis chronica atrophicans</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Lyme Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Disseminated Lyme infection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Only patients presenting with disseminated Lyme borreliosis will be part of the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Targeted proteomics in skin +/- cerebrospinal or synovial fluid to diagnose disseminated Lyme disease</intervention_name>
    <description>Following a 2-days course of local daily clobetasol propionate 0,05% cream application, a skin biopsy (3 mm punch-biopsy ) of healthy-looking skin of the upper part of the thigh will be performed in all patients,.&#xD;
Arthrocentesis (in patients with Lyme arthritis only) and lumbar puncture to collect cerebrospinal fluid (in patients with neuroborreliosis only) will be performed in the usual care setting as appropriated.&#xD;
All biological samples will be subject to Borrelia culture, PCR and SRM-MS proteomics.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Disseminated Lyme infection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject over 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject informed of the results of the previous medical examination and informed about&#xD;
             research objectives and risks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject affiliated to a social health insurance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject having signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with clinical and serological criteria that meet the criteria of French&#xD;
             societies, published in May and June 2019 (Jaulhac et al., 2019) as well as the&#xD;
             European criteria of ESGBOR, corresponding to a disseminated infection of Lyme&#xD;
             borreliosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Clinical Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  acute or subacute meningoradiculitis in a subject exposed to tick bites&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uni- or bilateral peripheral facial paralysis in a subject exposed to tick bites&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic radiculitis table compatible with Lyme borreliosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mono- or oligo arthritis of large jointsin the absence of other obvious diagnosis&#xD;
             (inflammatory rheumatism flares, microcrystalline arthritis…)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Skin changes suggestive of acrodermatitis chronica atrophicans&#xD;
&#xD;
        Serological criteria: positivity for Lyme serology (two-tiered, IgG)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  contraindication to performing a skin biopsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  contraindication to local lidocaine anaesthesia with or without adrenaline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  contraindication to dermocorticoids (hypersensitivity)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  antibiotic treatment for borreliosis already administered&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inability to provide informed information&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject under safeguard of justice&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Benoît JAULHAC</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hôpitaux Universitaires de Strasbourg</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Benoît JAULHAC</last_name>
    <phone>+33 3 69 55 14 52</phone>
    <email>Benoit.jaulhac@chru-strasbourg.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Nathalie BOULANGER</last_name>
    <phone>+33 3 69 55 14 49</phone>
    <email>nathalie.boulanger@chru-strasbourg.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Les Hôpitaux Universitaires de Strasbourg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Strasbourg</city>
        <zip>67091</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Benoît JAULHAC</last_name>
      <phone>+33 3 69 55 14 49</phone>
      <email>benoit.jaulhac@chru-strasbourg.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Nathalie BOULANGER</last_name>
      <phone>+33 3 69 55 14 49</phone>
      <email>nathalie.boulanger@chru-strasbourg.fr</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Benoit JAULHAC</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Yves HANSMANN</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christelle SORDET</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Cédric LENORMAND</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>targeted proteomics</keyword>
  <keyword>skin biopsy</keyword>
  <keyword>biomarker</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lyme Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

