<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04718779</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TAK-669-4017</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04718779</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Enzyme Replacement Therapy (VPRIV) in People With Type 1 Gaucher Disease Who Were Previously Treated With Substrate Reduction Therapy</brief_title>
  <acronym>SWITCH</acronym>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Interventional, Retrospective and Prospective Study of Enzyme Replacement Therapy (VPRIV) Clinical Outcomes and Safety in Gaucher Disease Type 1 Patients Previously Treated With Substrate Reduction Therapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Takeda</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Takeda</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study will provide information on outcomes in people with type 1 Gaucher disease when&#xD;
      they are treated with velaglucarase alfa (also called VPRIV), under standard care. Standard&#xD;
      care means the participant will be treated according to the clinic's standard practice. The&#xD;
      study sponsor will not be involved in how participants are treated with VPRIV, will provide&#xD;
      instructions on how the clinic will record what happens during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VPRIV is a type of enzyme replacement therapy (also known as ERT). Before starting the study,&#xD;
      participants must either have switched from substrate reduction therapies (SRT) to VPRIV or&#xD;
      switched from other enzyme replacement therapies to SRT then finally to VPRIV. During this&#xD;
      time, medical data will be collected from the participants' medical records.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the study, participants will be treated with VPRIV according to their clinic's&#xD;
      standard practice. VPRIV is given by a slow injection into the vein, also known as an&#xD;
      infusion. This will happen in the clinic or at home.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will record if blood levels of specific substances remain stable or improve during&#xD;
      the switch to treatment with VPRIV. Some of these substances will show if organs such as the&#xD;
      liver or spleen are working well. Others are blood cells that help blood to clot, known as&#xD;
      platelets. Another is a substance in a red blood cell used to carry oxygen around the body,&#xD;
      known as hemoglobin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will use a digital tool so they can be more involved in decision making in their&#xD;
      treatment. The digital tool is a mobile phone app, in which each participant can log their&#xD;
      daily activities, their general health and wellbeing, and other key information.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical data will also be collected from the participants' charts during this time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Health problems of the participants will be recorded during the study to check if there were&#xD;
      any side effects from VPRIV treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be in this study for up to 12 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 22, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 26, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 26, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Hemoglobin (Hb) Concentration up to 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Hemoglobin concentration level less than (˂) 1.5 gram per deciliter (g/dl) decrease will be assessed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Platelet Count up to 12 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Platelet count ˂ 25 percent (%) decrease will be assessed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Liver Volume up to 12 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Liver volume ˂ 20% increase will be assessed using ultrasound or MRI.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Spleen Volume up to 12 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Spleen volume ˂ 25% increase will be assessed using ultrasound or Magnetic Resonance Image (MRI).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Adverse Events (AEs) and Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of the study up to Month 12/ Early Termination (ET)</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is defined as any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical investigation participant administered with a drug; it does not necessarily have to have a causal relationship with this treatment. An SAE is any event that results in: death; life-threatening; requires inpatient hospitalization or results in prolongation of existing hospitalization; persistent or significant disability/incapacity; a congenital anomaly/birth defect or a medically important event. AEs include SAEs, non-serious AEs.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Gaucher Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Velaglucerase Alfa (VPRIV)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive VPRIV 60 Units per kilogram (U/kg) intravenous infusion every other week for 60 minutes as per physician treatment plan up to 12 months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Velaglucerase alfa</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive VPRIV 60 U/kg intravenous infusion every other week for 60 minutes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Velaglucerase Alfa (VPRIV)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>VPRIV</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participant eligibility is determined according to the following criteria prior to entry&#xD;
        into the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the opinion of the investigator, the participant is capable of understanding and&#xD;
             complying with protocol requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant either signs and dates a written, informed consent form or completes an&#xD;
             e-consent process prior to the initiation of any study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has been diagnosed with GD type I, diagnosis was confirmed biochemically&#xD;
             and/or genetically.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has been treated with an SRT for at least 3 months prior to switch to&#xD;
             VPRIV.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has been treated with VPRIV at least 3 months prior to enrollment&#xD;
             (Baseline [Day 0]).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is aged 18 or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is able to use mobile application based on clinician's judgment, (e.g.,&#xD;
             owns an iPhone version 5 or later or smartphones with Android operating systems, have&#xD;
             an active data plan or regular Wi-Fi access).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants primary language is English.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any participant who meets any of the following criteria will not qualify for entry into the&#xD;
        study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is an immediate family member, study site employee, or is in a dependent&#xD;
             relationship with a study site employee who is involved in conduct of this study&#xD;
             (e.g., spouse, parent, child, sibling) or may consent under duress.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is judged by the investigator as being ineligible for any other reason.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has L444P/L444P GBA1 genotype (c.1448T greater than [&gt;] C).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has Parkinson's disease, a history of central nervous system [CNS]&#xD;
             manifestations, or any other neurological disorder (e.g. Lewy Body Disease,&#xD;
             Alzheimer's Disease, Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, Multiple sclerosis).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Study Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Takeda</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Takeda Contact</last_name>
    <phone>+1 866 842 5335</phone>
    <email>ClinicalTransparency@takeda.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Lysosomal and Rare Disorders Research and Treatment Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fairfax</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>22030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>703-261-6220</phone>
      <email>info@ldrtc.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ozlem Goker-Alpan, Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.takeda.com/study-detail/600e8a40565ce300294c6ae6</url>
    <description>To obtain more information on the study, click here/on this link</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gaucher Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Takeda provides access to the de-identified individual participant data (IPD) for eligible studies to aid qualified researchers in addressing legitimate scientific objectives (Takeda's data sharing commitment is available on https://clinicaltrials.takeda.com/takedas-commitment?commitment=5). These IPDs will be provided in a secure research environment following approval of a data sharing request, and under the terms of a data sharing agreement</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_access_criteria>IPD from eligible studies will be shared with qualified researchers according to the criteria and process described on https://vivli.org/ourmember/takeda/. For approved requests, the researchers will be provided access to anonymized data (to respect patient privacy in line with applicable laws and regulations) and with information necessary to address the research objectives under the terms of a data sharing agreement.</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>https://vivli.org/ourmember/takeda/</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

