<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04713774</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Liege REBON Vasc</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04713774</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Bone Density and Vascular Calcifications Evolution After Renal Transplant</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evolution of Bone Density, Bone Micro-architecture and Vascular Calcifications in Patients After Kidney Transplantation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Liege</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Liege</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators project is based on:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Assessment of bone architecture by high resolution peripheral scanner (HRpQCT) and bone&#xD;
           densitometry (DEXA);&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The non-invasive detection of vascular calcifications (by abdominal CT scanner) and bone&#xD;
           abnormalities associated with kidney transplantation, as well as the analysis of&#xD;
           evolution over time;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Longitudinal evaluation of nephrological clinical parameters (glomerular filtration&#xD;
           rate, number and type of rejections, immunosuppressive medications) as well as&#xD;
           biological and urinary parameters of mineral metabolism (parathormone, sclerostin, bone&#xD;
           alkaline phosphatase) depending on the type and severity of bone abnormalities;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The evaluation of these nephrological clinical parameters and of the biological&#xD;
           parameters of mineral metabolism depending on the extent and evolution of vascular&#xD;
           calcifications but also on bone morphology;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The study of possible relationships between bone mass and muscle mass (and functioning)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Bone and mineral abnormalities are frequent in kidney transplant patients and are associated&#xD;
      with a high risk of fracture, cardiovascular mortality, but also with an increase in the&#xD;
      frequency of hospitalisations and thus healthcare's costs. The pathophysiology of bone&#xD;
      disorders appearing after transplantation arises from a complex interaction between different&#xD;
      factors. These include both pre-transplant renal osteodystrophy lesions and bone loss&#xD;
      associated with the kidney transplant itself. This bone loss results from a variety of&#xD;
      causes. The management of these bone abnormalities is complex in daily clinical practice&#xD;
      because only the bone biopsy can accurately determine the type of abnormality present, and&#xD;
      this examination is rarely performed due to its invasive nature. The link between the&#xD;
      development of bone abnormalities and the presence or even the progression of vascular&#xD;
      calcifications remains very poorly understood. This link is however fundamental because&#xD;
      vascular calcifications could explain the increased risk of cardiovascular mortality in these&#xD;
      patients. Understanding and diagnosing bone abnormalities early, ideally in a non-invasive&#xD;
      manner, could help prevent bone and vascular degradation frequently found after renal&#xD;
      transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite significant improvement in recent years, mortality as well as cardiovascular&#xD;
      morbidity remain very high in kidney transplant patients. The reported annual risk of fatal&#xD;
      or non-fatal cardiovascular events is 3.5% to 5%, even after adjusting for traditional risk&#xD;
      factors (such as diabetes, hypertension, obesity, smoking and dyslipidemia). Certain factors&#xD;
      related to chronic kidney disease (CKD) or transplant appear to influence the high incidence&#xD;
      of cardiovascular events. These include, among others, the duration of dialysis before the&#xD;
      transplant, the function of the graft after transplantation, proteinuria, episodes of acute&#xD;
      rejection, new cases of post-transplant diabetes, the toxic effects of immunosuppressive&#xD;
      drugs but also the bone metabolism abnormalities observed in transplant patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is therefore essential to be able to accurately assess the presence of abnormalities in&#xD;
      bone metabolism by non-invasive techniques and thus to determine whether or not there is a&#xD;
      link between them and cardiovascular morbidity and mortality. This allows appropriate&#xD;
      management as well as a precise assessment of the impact of new drugs on bone metabolism and&#xD;
      the future of transplant patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Currently, the clinical management of bone abnormalities includes the use of surrogate&#xD;
      biochemical markers such as parathyroid hormone (PTH), bone alkaline phosphatases (bPhA),&#xD;
      osteoprotegerin (OPG), the N-terminal propeptide of procollagen type I (P1NP), tartrate&#xD;
      resistant acid phosphatase type 5b (TRAP5b), C-terminal collagen type I telopeptides (CTX),&#xD;
      osteocalcin and sclerostin. There are conflicting data in the literature as to their&#xD;
      correlation with histological and histomorphometric analysis of bone biopsies. These&#xD;
      biomarkers tend to take a place in the diagnosis and in the follow-up of patients with&#xD;
      abnormalities of bone metabolism, as well as possibly in the detection of vascular&#xD;
      calcifications. However, the effectiveness and reliability of this biochemical approach&#xD;
      remain to be demonstrated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the other hand, imaging techniques allow us to approach the bone structure. They could&#xD;
      therefore also be associated with biomarkers to replace bone biopsy. Bone density by&#xD;
      bi-photonic x-ray absorptiometry (DEXA) is a relatively accurate and non-invasive screening&#xD;
      method for estimating bone mass, mainly trabecular, and which appears to help predict the&#xD;
      risk of fracture in kidney transplant patients. DEXA is, however, unable to assess the&#xD;
      microarchitecture of bone and only provides a two-dimensional assessment of bone density. The&#xD;
      correlation between BMD and fracture risk is, however, much less clear in patients with renal&#xD;
      impairment and some studies sometimes even find an absence of correlation. Currently a new&#xD;
      software used in DEXA, the Trabecular Bone Score (TBS), seems to help in the assessment of&#xD;
      bone microarchitecture. This score is most often weighted with the FRAX to give a better&#xD;
      value of the fracture risk. Some data currently appear in the normal population, but no&#xD;
      robust data are present in kidney transplant patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the other hand, the peripheral high-resolution scanner (HRpQCT) provides information on&#xD;
      the bone micro-architecture as well as a quantitative measurement of the volumetric density&#xD;
      of the cortical bone, which is more impacted during renal failure, and. In this context, the&#xD;
      investigators goal in this study is to collect all of these biological and imaging data in&#xD;
      order to predict the underlying bone histomorphometry.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The analysis of bone density by DEXA will be carried out at the vertebral, hip and wrist&#xD;
      level as a direct result of the transplantation (first 10 days post transplant) at 3 months&#xD;
      and then annually for all renal transplant patients included in the study. Analysed of the&#xD;
      relevance of this examination for the detection of BMD and long-term fracture risk&#xD;
      (longitudinal study). The TBS will also be assessed by the same exam to assess its&#xD;
      sensitivity for the detection of fracture risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The high-resolution scanner will be performed on the distal part of the radius and tibia for&#xD;
      the evaluation of bone micro-architecture. This examination will be performed at the same&#xD;
      frequency as the DEXA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Then we will evaluate prospectively (at 3 months and 12 months) with a longitudinal follow-up&#xD;
      the various BMD data related to the presence and evolution of vascular calcifications (see&#xD;
      below) detected by DEXA as well as the various blood and urinary biomarkers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Markers such as vitamin D, Ca2 +, PTH, bPhA, OPG, P1NP, TRAP5b, CTX, osteocalcin, sclerostin,&#xD;
      vitamin K and the decarboxylated and dephosphorylated form of the matrix-Gla protein (MGP),&#xD;
      and intact fibroblast growth factor 23 (FGF23) will be evaluated in order to seek a possible&#xD;
      link with graft survival, the development of vascular calcifications and the risk of&#xD;
      fractures. Depending on the results of the DEXA performed and if a therapeutic indication is&#xD;
      considered in the context of fracture osteoporosis (bisphosphonates, denosumab), the patients&#xD;
      will be followed prospectively and their data will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A measurement of DEXA and bone microarchitecture by HRpQCT will also be carried out&#xD;
      bilaterally in the upper limbs in order to assess the impact of the location of the&#xD;
      arteriovenous fistula on bone density in view of the possible impact described in the&#xD;
      literature on a population of hemodialysis patients&#xD;
&#xD;
      The assessment of renal fibrosis will also be analyzed on the basis of renal biopsies&#xD;
      performed routinely in transplant patients at 3 months and in the event of biopsies performed&#xD;
      due to deterioration of renal function. The assessment of the degree of fibrosis will be&#xD;
      analyzed in light of the abnormalities of the phosphocalcic balance to see if a link between&#xD;
      the two exists.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Currently the reference technique for the detection of calcifications remains the chest&#xD;
      scanner with detection of CAC. This tedious and irradiating technique is however difficult to&#xD;
      use in current clinical practice. Calcifications of the abdominal aorta (AA) are as important&#xD;
      as CAC and are associated with sudden death mortality in patients with renal failure. In the&#xD;
      general population, the detection of calcifications by CT scan or by lateral radiography at&#xD;
      the AAA level (AAB profile) has shown good correlations with the level of CAC. In the general&#xD;
      population, the measurement of AA calcifications based on the lateral radiography images used&#xD;
      during DEXA also seems to demonstrate good sensitivities and specificities, when the images&#xD;
      obtained by DEXA are compared to the radiography of the AAB and to detection of AA&#xD;
      calcifications by CT scan. In a population of transplant patients, the demonstration of&#xD;
      calcifications via DEXA was associated with the risk of cardiovascular mortality of patients&#xD;
      but has never been compared to the profile blank abdomen which remains the standard&#xD;
      technique. In the population of kidney transplant patients, the literature has not&#xD;
      established a link between the detection of calcifications by these two techniques (DEXA and&#xD;
      abdominal scan) on the risk of cardiovascular events.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis is that the detection and follow-up of calcifications in the aorta could only&#xD;
      be done with this simple and rapid test, DEXA, and that it could therefore be combined with&#xD;
      the measurement of BMD. We will therefore study the correlation between calcifications of the&#xD;
      abdominal aorta detected by abdominal CT scan and those detected by DEXA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first objective is to prospectively study between 40 and 50 transplant patients. We will&#xD;
      measure the calcifications observed by DEXA and follow them over time (first measurement&#xD;
      carried out 3 months after transplant, and then once a year). Correlation analyzes will be&#xD;
      performed to assess the sensitivity of the different techniques for the detection of&#xD;
      calcifications both between techniques (abdominal CT scan during the first 10 days&#xD;
      post-transplant and at 1 year) as well as between observers (3 observers: radiologist,&#xD;
      nephrologist and rheumatologist). A measurement of the difference in calcifications according&#xD;
      to the examinations will be evaluated to make it possible to assess the evolution of&#xD;
      calcifications in the same patient according to the different clinical and biological&#xD;
      parameters&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Bone density evolution</measure>
    <time_frame>At 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Evolution of bone density after kidney transplantation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Bone density evolution</measure>
    <time_frame>At 2 year</time_frame>
    <description>Evolution of bone density after kidney transplantation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Bone micro-architecture evolution</measure>
    <time_frame>At 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Bone micro-architecture evolution evaluate by HRpQCT after kidney transplantation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Bone micro-architecture evolution</measure>
    <time_frame>At 2 year</time_frame>
    <description>Bone micro-architecture evolution evaluate by HRpQCT after kidney transplantation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vascular calcification evolution</measure>
    <time_frame>At 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Evolution of vascular calcification evaluated by abdominal calcification score on CT-SCan after kidney transplantation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vascular calcification evolution</measure>
    <time_frame>At 3 months, 1 year and 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Evolution of vascular calcification evaluated by abdominal calcification score on CT-SCan after kidney transplantation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Kidney Transplant; Complications</condition>
  <condition>Bone Loss</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>High-resolution peripheral quantitative CT scanner (HRpQCT)</intervention_name>
    <description>HR-pQCT images of the distal radius and distal tibia (non-dominant, non-fractured limb) will be obtained using the XtremeCT device with standard protocols. HR-pQCT images wil be analysed with standard software and extended cortical measures software. This software identifies the periosteal and endosteal boundaries, enabling assessment of cortical micro- structural bone properties, including apparent cortical thickness (Ct.Th, mm), cortical tissue mineral density (TMD, mgHA/cm3) and cortical porosity (Ct.Po, %).</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Kidney recipients aged over 18 and of all sexes recruited from the Centre Hospitalier&#xD;
        Universitaire de Liege&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent kidney transplant patients (&lt;3 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical history available&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biological parameters of the past year available&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with bisphosphonate, RANKL inhibitor or SERM with bone action in the last 3&#xD;
             months before the transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Multiple organ transplant patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Antoine Bouquegneau</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Liege</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Antoine Bouquegneau</last_name>
    <phone>+32473353321</phone>
    <email>antoine.bouquegneau@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Pierre Delanaye</last_name>
    <email>pierre_delanaye@yahoo.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Liège</name>
      <address>
        <city>Liège</city>
        <zip>4300</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Antoine Bouquegneau, MD</last_name>
      <phone>0032473353321</phone>
      <email>antoine.bouquegneau@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Pierre Delanaye</last_name>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Liege</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Antoine Bouquegneau</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vascular Calcification</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

