<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04712253</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04712253</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>International Study to Evaluate Outcomes and Safety of Patients Undergoing ERCP Using a Single-use Cholangioscope and Single-use Duodenoscope</brief_title>
  <acronym>MESE</acronym>
  <official_title>Multicenter Retrospective International Study to Evaluate Outcomes and Safety of Patients Undergoing ERCP Using a Single-use Cholangioscope (SpyGlass DS II) and Single-use Duodenoscope (Exalt) - The MESE Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istituto Clinico Humanitas</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istituto Clinico Humanitas</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Since its introduction more than 40 years ago, endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography&#xD;
      (ERCP) has fundamentally changed the treatment of biliopancreatic diseases. Since late 1970s&#xD;
      there have been sporadic reports of nosocomial infections linked to endoscopic procedures,&#xD;
      the majority caused by inadequate reprocessing of endoscopes. Infections due to&#xD;
      multidrug-resistant organisms (MDROs) however have increasingly become a concern in health&#xD;
      care, including in gastrointestinal (GI) endoscopy. Since 2010, reports of individual cases&#xD;
      and serial outbreaks of MDRO infections associated with ERCP have been published worldwide.&#xD;
      This is because, unlike a gastroscope or colonoscope, the duodenoscope is a complex&#xD;
      instrument with unique mechanical features incorporated at the distal tip. This includes a&#xD;
      recessed space containing an elevator, a wire cable that moves the elevator, working channel,&#xD;
      and most recently, a seal that prevents contamination of the elevator wire channel. This&#xD;
      complex design creates hard-to-reach areas that make optimal mechanical cleaning and&#xD;
      disinfection difficult. With the aim of overcoming these issues, a single-use duodenoscope&#xD;
      (EXALT Model D, Boston Scientific Corporation, Marlborough, Massachusetts, USA) has been&#xD;
      developed in the United States of America (USA) and approved by the United States Food and&#xD;
      Drug Administration (FDA) for clinical use in December 2019. Different studies evaluating&#xD;
      this new device, including randomized clinical trials (RCTs), have already been published,&#xD;
      which have confirmed that single-use duodenoscopes represent an alternative to reusable&#xD;
      duodenoscopes for performing low-complexity ERCP procedures in experienced hands.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Digital Single Operator Cholangioscopy (D-SOC) using the single use Spyglass DS II (Boston&#xD;
      Scientific Corporation, Marlborough, Massachusetts, USA) is a diagnostic and therapeutic&#xD;
      modality which allows for direct endoscopic visualization of the biliopancreatic ductal&#xD;
      system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The principal diagnostic indication of D-SOC are bile duct or pancreatic strictures and&#xD;
      unclear filling defects, adding direct endoscopic appearance data to biopsy sampling or brush&#xD;
      cytology in order to improve the diagnostic yield.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The major therapeutic indication for D-SOC is lithotripsy for difficult biliary and&#xD;
      pancreatic stones.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, cholangioscopy increased the risk of post ERCP cholangitis. Bacteremia was suggested&#xD;
      to be specifically related to cholangioscopy in 13.9% of 72 patients, based on serial blood&#xD;
      samplings, and to be associated with biopsy sampling and strictures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For this reason, the recent European Society of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy (ESGE) guideline&#xD;
      suggests that patients should be considered to be at high risk for post-ERCP cholangitis when&#xD;
      cholangioscopy is performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Presently, there are very few clinical reports about technical and clinical outcome of ERCPs&#xD;
      performed with single use duodenoscope and there is complete lack of data about efficacy,&#xD;
      safety and adverse events of the combination of the new single-use duodenoscope and the&#xD;
      Spyglass DS II.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this multicentric retrospective study was to evaluate the technical success,&#xD;
      clinical outcome and rate of adverse events of this procedure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Technical success</measure>
    <time_frame>6 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Technical success defined as the ability to successfully complete the entire procedure (completed without cross-over to a reusable duodenoscope) with the intended diagnostic or therapeutic maneuvers according to the clinical indication (i.e. stone fragmentation/removal, biopsies from the targeted tissue, etc)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>6 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Numbers of adverse events</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Biliary Condition</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients that required an ERCP with cholangioscopy performed with the single-use EXALT&#xD;
        duodenoscope in combination with the Spyglass DS II between January 2020 and the time the&#xD;
        IRB\Ethics Committee (EC) has approved the protocol for this retrospective series. The date&#xD;
        of IRB\EC approval will vary from center to center. At each center, retrospective data&#xD;
        collection will be completed immediately upon the local IRB\EC approval. The study plan is&#xD;
        to complete the retrospective series by July 2020.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - patients that required an ERCP with cholangioscopy performed with the single-use EXALT&#xD;
        duodenoscope in combination with the Spyglass DS II&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt; 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of follow-up data (30 days at least)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than 3 cases performed during the study period&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Alessandro Repici, MD</last_name>
    <phone>0039-02-82247493</phone>
    <email>alessandro.repici@hunimed.eu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Andrea Anderloni, MD</last_name>
    <phone>0039-02-82247308</phone>
    <email>andrea.anderloni@humanitas.it</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Endoscopy Unit, Humanitas Research Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rozzano</city>
        <state>Milano</state>
        <zip>20089</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alessandro Repici, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+39282247493</phone>
      <email>alessandro.repici@humanitas.it</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alessandro Repici, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Andrea Anderloni, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alessandro Fugazza, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

