<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04717440</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ET20-101 PALPHA-1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04717440</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Assessment of the Reasons for Accepting or Refusing Early Palliative Care</brief_title>
  <acronym>PALPHA-1</acronym>
  <official_title>Assessment of the Reasons for Accepting or Refusing Early Palliative Care by the Patients Included in an Early Phase Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Leon Berard</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Leon Berard</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, multicentre study, considered as &quot; non-RIPH (&quot;Recherche n'Impliquant&#xD;
      pas la Personne Humaine - Research that does not involve humans &quot;. Indeed, the patient's&#xD;
      participation in the study and the completion of the various questionnaires has no impact on&#xD;
      patient's safety and is not likely to change patients' management. Patients accepting to take&#xD;
      part to an early phase trial will be proposed to participate in the PALPHA-1 trial. They can&#xD;
      accept or refuse to have palliative supportive care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective of this study is to assess the reasons for accepting and refusing early&#xD;
      palliative care in patients included in an early phase clinical trial. The secondary&#xD;
      objectives will enable to describe and analyze the number (effective) and the rate (%) of&#xD;
      acceptance and/or refusal of early palliative support, to assess patients' understanding and&#xD;
      perception of the &quot; combined &quot; management by comparing the semantic content of the&#xD;
      patient-investigator ecological interaction during the proposal for inclusion in the trial&#xD;
      (i.e. what was explicitly said), with that of the semi-structured post-consultation inclusion&#xD;
      interviews ( ie what the patients understood, perceived), to compare the quality of life and&#xD;
      the anxiety-depression of patients according to their acceptance or refusal of the mixed care&#xD;
      at the inclusion and at the end of the early phase trial, to compare the clinical, medical&#xD;
      and socio-demographic characteristics of the patients, the overall survival of patients&#xD;
      according to their acceptance or refusal of the combined management and finally for the&#xD;
      patients accepting the Palliative Care Management (PCM), to describe throughout the study,&#xD;
      the patients' compliance to palliative supportive care undertaken.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In a context of promotion of precision medicine, if palliative management and inclusion in an&#xD;
      Early Clinical trial Phase (ECP) may at first glance appear antagonistic, some authors&#xD;
      support the idea of a possible synergy in order to improve quality of life, reduce symptoms&#xD;
      of exhaustion linked to treatment side effects and allow patients to complete their treatment&#xD;
      protocol. To date and to our knowledge, few studies have assessed the brakes and/or levers&#xD;
      for patient acceptance and/or refusal as well as the feasibility of a such mixed therapeutic&#xD;
      management therapeutic. In this context, the beliefs and representations of patients must be&#xD;
      taken into account in the decision-making process, which is also governed by the social norms&#xD;
      of the caregiver-patient relationship. A better understanding of patients' acceptance and/or&#xD;
      refusal of palliative care is an essential and innovative prerequisite for better&#xD;
      understanding the processes involved at this stage of the care process.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective of this study is to assess the reasons for accepting and refusing early&#xD;
      palliative care in patients included in an early phase clinical trial. The secondary&#xD;
      objectives will enable to describe and analyze the number (effective) and the rate (%) of&#xD;
      acceptance and/or refusal of early palliative support, to assess patients' understanding and&#xD;
      perception of the &quot; mixed &quot; management by comparing the semantic content of the&#xD;
      patient-investigator ecological interaction during the proposal for inclusion in the trial&#xD;
      (i.e. what was explicitly said), with that of the semi-structured post-consultation inclusion&#xD;
      interviews ( ie what the patients understood, perceived), to compare the quality of life and&#xD;
      the anxiety-depression of patients according to their acceptance or refusal of the mixed care&#xD;
      at the inclusion and at the end of the early phase trial, to compare the clinical, medical&#xD;
      and socio-demographic characteristics of the patients, the overall survival of patients&#xD;
      according to their acceptance or refusal of the combined management and finally for the&#xD;
      patients accepting the PCM, to describe throughout the study, the patients' compliance to&#xD;
      palliative supportive care undertaken.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients approached for inclusion in an early phase clinical trial during the&#xD;
      Multidisciplinary Consultation Meeting (MCR) will be offered to participate to the study. In&#xD;
      order to assess the reasons for accepting / refusing the inclusion in palliative supportive&#xD;
      care in patients entering an early phase clinical trial, two subgroups will be formed. The&#xD;
      first group will be made up of patients who accepts joint palliative care (n = 20) and the&#xD;
      second group of those who refuse (n = 20). Following their acceptance, the consultation for&#xD;
      setting up the early phase clinical trial will be recorded and participants will be invited&#xD;
      to participate in a semi-structured interview just before the first line of treatment.&#xD;
      Patients (both having accepted or refused the palliative care) will also have to answer a&#xD;
      self-questionnaire on quality of life and anxiety-depression at inclusion and at the end of&#xD;
      the clinical trial. The study results will make it possible to determine patients'&#xD;
      motivations for accepting or refusing palliative care management in order to better define&#xD;
      their expectations, beliefs in terms of management, their understanding and impact of this&#xD;
      management.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 15, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 25, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of the reasons for accepting / refusing early palliative care in patients included in an early phase clinical trial</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Thematic content analysis of semi-directive qualitative interviews</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Description and analysis of the number (effective) of acceptance of early palliative support</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Numbers of acceptance of the early palliative care management for all patients seen in early phase unit consultation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Description and analysis of the percentage of acceptance of early palliative support</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Percentages of acceptance of the early palliative care management for all patients seen in early phase unit consultation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of patients' understanding and perception of the early palliative care management</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of qualitative semantic content of patient-investigator interaction with the semi-directive post-consultation inclusion interview</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the quality of life of patients according to their acceptance or refusal of the mixed care</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of life evaluated with the FACT-G7 (Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy - General - 7-item version) questionnaire (range from 0 (better outcome) to 28 (worse outcome)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the anxiety-depression of patients according to their acceptance or refusal of the mixed care</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Anxiety-depression evaluated with the HADS (Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale) questionnaire (range 0-7: No symptoms, range 8-10: Doubtful symptoms, range &gt;=11: Symptoms of anxiety or depression)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the clinical, medical and socio-demographic characteristics of patients for the patients accepting the palliative care management</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Using PALLIA 10 scale (PALLIAtive scale composed of 10 items, minimum value: 1, maximum value: 10. A specialized advice in palliative care is required if score &gt; 3)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the clinical, medical and socio-demographic characteristics of patients who accept or refuse the palliative care management</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Using PRONOPALL score (Prognostic overall survival score). Range 0-3: Favorable overall survival score, Range 4-7: Intermediate overall survival score, Range 8-10: Unfavorable overall survival score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the clinical characteristics of patients who accept or refuse the palliative care management</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical symptoms evaluated using ESAS (Edmonton Symptom Assessment System) questionnaire (range from 0 (better outcome) to 10 (worse outcome))</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the socio-demographic characteristics of patients who accept or refuse the palliative care management</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Patients' characteristics (Age, sex, family situation, place of residence, socio-educational level, professional activity)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the medical characteristics of patients who accept or refuse the palliative care management</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patients' medical history: Treatments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the medical characteristics of patients who accept or refuse the palliative care management</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patients' medical history: Use of specialists' consultations (e.g. intensive care unit, emergency hospitalization, palliative care unit, number/types of consultations, pain, nutrition)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the use of social services of patients who accept or refuse the palliative care management</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patients' medical history: Use of social service...</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival of patients according to their acceptance or refusal of the &quot;mixed&quot; management</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Vital status</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>For patients having accepted the palliative support, description throughout the study of patients' compliance to palliative supportive care undertaken</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patients having performed at least 50 percent of the visits</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients accepting palliative care</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients included in an early phase trial and accepting palliative care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients refusing palliative car</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients included in an early phase trial but refusing palliative care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This is a prospective, multicentre study, considered as &quot; non-RIPH (Recherche n'Impliquant&#xD;
        pas la Personne Humaine - Research that does not involve humans &quot;. Indeed, the patient's&#xD;
        participation in the study and the completion of the various questionnaires has no impact&#xD;
        on patient's safety and is not likely to change patient's management. Patients accepting to&#xD;
        take part to an early phase trial will be proposed to participate in the PALPHA-1 trial.&#xD;
        They can accept or refuse to have palliative supportive care. Patients' follow up will be&#xD;
        performed according to the palliative standard procedures.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age over 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient included in an early phase clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who has not been taken in charge for palliative care&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of at least 16 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient not opposed to data's collection and processing for the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient affiliated to a social security system&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient unable to read/understand the French language&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with psychological disability (e.g. too great vulnerability, psychiatric&#xD;
             disorder) or physical disability (e.g. physical / motor disability)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under autorship, curators or legal protection,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients already participating in a clinical trial or interventional study related to&#xD;
             supportive care.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gisèle CHVETZOFF, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre Leon Berard</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Julien GAUTIER</last_name>
    <phone>+33 4.26.55.68.29</phone>
    <email>julien.gautier@lyon.unicancer.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gisèle CHVETZOFF, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+33 4.78.78.26.57</phone>
    <email>gisele.chvetzoff@lyon.unicancer.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Leon Berard</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lyon</city>
        <zip>69008</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>CHVETZOFF Gisèle, MD</last_name>
      <email>gisele.chvetzoff@lyon.unicancer.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 10, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 15, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Palliative care</keyword>
  <keyword>Early phase trial</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

