<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04717232</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MentoringComperence</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04717232</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness of Interprofessional Mentoring Competence Education for Dental Health Care Professionals</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of Interprofessional Mentoring Competence Education for Dental Health Care Professionals: A Quasi-experimental Study Protocol</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Oulu</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Oulu</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Clinical practice is an integral part of dental and dental hygiene students' education. The&#xD;
      curriculum for a degree is guided by best academic practices for European undergraduate&#xD;
      dental education, published by the Association for Dental Education in Europé (ADEE), and the&#xD;
      dental hygienist education is based on a European qualifications framework. Interprofessional&#xD;
      education has been recognized as a means to improve oral health professional training due to&#xD;
      the linked form of education with improved health outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The interprofessional mentoring education is needed for the clinical practice, which has to&#xD;
      be implemented in interprofessional teams. Clinical practice mentors need to have completed&#xD;
      an interprofessional mentoring education. Different types of educational approaches have been&#xD;
      previously affecting mentors' competence development in mentoring. Dental and dental hygiene&#xD;
      students can experience team-based, interprofessional education by participating in clinical&#xD;
      practice sessions offered in a communal learning environment. Traditional lectures can be&#xD;
      transformed into modern, enhanced learning experiences that correspond to the new generation&#xD;
      of students. Online learning methods are increasingly being incorporated into dental health&#xD;
      care education. Online learning is designed to be able to support learners with technology&#xD;
      supporting and facilitating student learning. Those methods can be used in dental health care&#xD;
      continuous education.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is designed to evaluate educational intervention's effectiveness of&#xD;
      inter-professional mentoring education on mentors' competence development of dentists and&#xD;
      dental hygienists mentors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      METHODOLOGY&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study setting:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The interprofessional intervention applying blended learning will be conducted at the higher&#xD;
      education institution's interactive learning facilities, while the online interprofessional&#xD;
      intervention will be conducted in an online learning environment in collaboration with the&#xD;
      teaching-learning company of the Finnish Dental Association.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a nonrandomized pre-post quasi-experimental study. The participants in this study&#xD;
      will participate in interprofessional mentoring education. Participants will self-assess&#xD;
      their level of Competence in mentoring, which includes seven dimensions; mentor&#xD;
      characteristics, mentor motivation, mentoring practices in the workplace, reflection during&#xD;
      mentoring, goal-oriented mentoring, student-centered evaluation and constructive feedback.&#xD;
      There will be three assessment time points: at baseline (before education, T0), immediately&#xD;
      after the education (T1), and 3 months after the education (T2). The control group will not&#xD;
      receive any educational intervention. The interventions and control group will be used the&#xD;
      same self-assessment instrument and assessment time points.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study size:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intervention and control groups will include 60 participants per group. The 60&#xD;
      participants in the intervention group will be further divided into two groups: one group (30&#xD;
      participants) completing the blended learning module and the other group (30 participants)&#xD;
      completing an online learning module.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study duration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intervention will be conducted for a duration of 6 months. More precisely, the blended&#xD;
      learning module will be offered twice, in spring 2019 and spring 2020. The online learning&#xD;
      module will be conducted during spring 2020 and autumn 2021.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sampling of participants&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      An announcement about both interventions will be published in Finnish journals of dental&#xD;
      health care and the official journal of the Finnish Dental Association. The mentors can then&#xD;
      choose which form of education was more convenient in terms of time and location. The blended&#xD;
      learning approach will be offered once per year in the springtime, while the online mentoring&#xD;
      education is available throughout the year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blended learning approach to mentoring education for dental health care professionals for&#xD;
      participants (dentists and dental hygienists) in the intervention group comprises completion&#xD;
      of specialist lectures, discussions, interprofessional group work and self-reflection. The&#xD;
      mentoring education will last five weeks, include four face-to-face seminars (2+2 days) and&#xD;
      self-reflection assignments lasting an estimated two days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The online mentoring education for participants (dentists and dental hygienists) in the&#xD;
      intervention group comprises of completion of represents a collaboration between members of&#xD;
      the dental association, specialist lectures and the coordinator of the dental association.&#xD;
      The online mentoring education environment, Priima, includes videos of specialist lectures,&#xD;
      e-learning materials, along with assignments concerning reflection skills and&#xD;
      participant-based evaluation. In addition, the learners will be informed that they could get&#xD;
      in touch with the coordinator of the association if necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants in the control group are dentists and dental hygienists who are listed as&#xD;
      working at health care centers on the Finnish Dental Association site&#xD;
      (tkharjoittelu.hammaslaakariliitto.fi) and participate in student mentoring. Data concerning&#xD;
      the control group, which did not receive any educational intervention. The control group&#xD;
      represents dentists or dental hygienists from randomly selected organizations, while all of&#xD;
      the participants will be selected from subdivisions of the 2007 NUTS (Nomenclature of&#xD;
      Territorial Units for Statistics). Control group randomization will be performed via Research&#xD;
      Randomizer (https://www.randomizer.org/#randomize) and ensured that participants in the&#xD;
      intervention groups are similar with respect to both known and unknown prognostic factors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The target of participant selection is to obtain a sufficiently large sample size that&#xD;
      represents a highly heterogeneous study group so that concrete conclusions about the&#xD;
      effectiveness of the educational interventions can be drawn. A power analysis applying&#xD;
      settings outlined in the latest study was used to calculate the appropriate sample size, with&#xD;
      the results indicating that 60 participants per group (intervention and control group) would&#xD;
      provide a sufficiently large Cohen's d effect size.&#xD;
&#xD;
      INSTRUMENTS AND DATA COLLECTION&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention: The blended learning module and online learning module for mentoring education&#xD;
      for interprofessional dental health care professionals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Instruments: Mentors' Competence in mentoring will be measured using the self-assessment of&#xD;
      the Mentors' Competence Instrument (MCI), which includes seven mentoring competence&#xD;
      sub-dimensions and 45 items.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Finnish language versions of the questionnaire will contain the following sections:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Sociodemographic data:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Sex&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Age&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Education background&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Year of completion of education&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Job title&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Place of work&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Work experience&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Role of mentor&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  A time when last mentored a student&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  A most recent case of mentoring&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Previous participation to mentoring education&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Experience of previous mentoring education&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Competence in mentoring using MCI, which contains 45 items divided into 7 sections&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  mentor characteristics&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  mentor motivation&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  mentoring practices in the workplace&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  reflection during mentoring&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  goal-oriented mentoring&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  student-centered evaluation&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  constructive feedback&#xD;
&#xD;
      DATA COLLECTION&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention group&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Blended learning approach to mentoring education for dental health care professionals;&#xD;
           Baseline questionnaire (T0): Paper-based questionnaires will be administered to&#xD;
           participants in the intervention group on the day of study recruitment before mentoring&#xD;
           education. A researcher will provide details to participants on the completion of the&#xD;
           questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The online mentoring education (T0): Online questionnaire will be administered to&#xD;
           participants in the intervention group by giving a weblink with the cover letter of the&#xD;
           questionnaire outlines to the study purpose, protecting participant anonymity, and&#xD;
           contact details of the researchers.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Post-course questionnaire (T1): A blended learning approach to mentoring education for&#xD;
           dental health care professionals; Paper-based questionnaires will be administered to&#xD;
           participants in the intervention group immediately following completion of the mentoring&#xD;
           education.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The interprofessional online mentoring education (T1): Online questionnaire will be&#xD;
           administered to participants in the intervention group immediately following completion&#xD;
           of the mentoring education.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Follow-up of the 3-month questionnaire (T2): A blended learning approach to mentoring&#xD;
           education for dental health care professionals; Paper-based questionnaires will be sent&#xD;
           to participants via post to participants' home addresses. The online mentoring&#xD;
           education; An online questionnaire will be sent to weblink to participants via&#xD;
           participants' email.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control group&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Baseline questionnaire (T0): Paper-based questionnaires will be sent in sealed envelop&#xD;
           to participants of the control group during the timeline of the intervention group's&#xD;
           mentoring education.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Post questionnaire (T1): Paper-based questionnaires will be sent in sealed envelop to&#xD;
           participants of the control group after five weeks of the baseline measurement.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Follow-up of the 3-month questionnaire (T2): Paper-based questionnaire will be sent in&#xD;
           sealed envelop to participants of the control group after three months of the baseline&#xD;
           measurement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ETHICAL CONSIDERATIONS&#xD;
&#xD;
      All phases of the study will follow guidelines for ethical research. The study will not&#xD;
      require a statement from the ethics committee, as the research will not violate the&#xD;
      participants' physical integrity and/or cause physical or mental harm. Permission for data&#xD;
      collection was obtained from the organizations where education will be conducted.&#xD;
      Participants will be informed of the study's purpose, the voluntary of their participation&#xD;
      and of their right to withdraw from the study, protection of participants' anonymity, and&#xD;
      contact details of the researchers. Answering the questionnaire was taken as an informed&#xD;
      agreement to participate in the study. All of the collected data will be coded according to&#xD;
      the key code in questionnaires T1, T2 and T2. The results of the study will be reported&#xD;
      according to the CONSORT 2010 Statement and the TIDieR checklist. Process evaluations of the&#xD;
      designed interventions will be reported in accordance with the Medical Research Council (MRC)&#xD;
      guidelines. Respondent confidentiality will be assured throughout the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be analyzed with SPSS (V. 22.0, IBM Corporation, Armonk, NY). Data will be analyzed&#xD;
      using descriptive statistics, the Mann-Whitney U test and pre-and post-test changes will be&#xD;
      assessed using the Wilcoxon Signed-Rank test. Parametric data analysis methods will be used&#xD;
      for sensitivity testing. In this study, will be used two-tailed testing and the significance&#xD;
      level will be set at a p-value &lt;0.05.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 14, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Competence in mentoring students in the clinical practice</measure>
    <time_frame>The Outcome Measures will be assessed a change. The change is being assessed; Pre intervention, immediately after intervention and 3 months after intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>Mentor competence will be measured using the Mentors' Competence Instrument (MCI), which includes seven sum-variables and 45 items. Respondents rate each item of the instrument using a four-point Likert scale.(1=totally disagree, 2=disagree to some extent, 3=agree to some extent, and 4=totally agree). Higher scores mean a better outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in mentoring students</measure>
    <time_frame>The Outcome Measures will be assessed a change. The change is being assessed; Immediately after intervention and 3 months after intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>Satisfaction with mentoring education. The willingness of mentoring student. Measured will be using the Mentors' Competence Instrument (MCI), which includes seven sum-variables and 45 items. Respondents rate each item of the instrument using a four-point Likert scale. (1=totally disagree, 2=disagree to some extent, 3=agree to some extent, and 4=totally agree). Higher scores mean a better outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Competence</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The blended learning approach to mentoring education for dental health care professionals</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The blended learning approach to mentoring education for dental health care professionals will last five weeks, including four face-to-face seminars, interprofessional group work and self-reflection assignments lasting for two days. The educational content will include mentoring as a process, mentoring as a relationship, challenges of mentoring, and personal mentoring.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The interprofessional online mentoring education</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The intervention group will attend mentoring competence education. The Interprofessional online mentoring educations includes videos of specialist lectures, e-learning materials, along with assignments concerning reflection skills and participant-based evaluation. The education content included the processes and interactions of mentoring, goal-oriented mentoring, along with student-based feedback and student-centered evaluation. The mentoring education can be completed in an online learning environment and participants can complete the education at their own pace within six weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group are dentists´ and dental hygienists´ who are working at health care centers on the Finnish Dental Association site, participate in student mentoring and have not received any education before.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Blended learning approach to mentoring education for dental health care professionals</intervention_name>
    <description>The participants in the intervention group are dentists´ and dental hygienists´. The mentoring education for dental health care professionals (3 ECTS credits) will be organized by the program leader in Dentistry at the place-blinded. The aim of the mentoring education is to build understanding of how to support a student's professional development (both basic education and specialization) and transfer skills that are relevant to working as an independent expert in oral health care.</description>
    <arm_group_label>The Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>The blended learning approach to mentoring education for dental health care professionals</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The interprofessional online mentoring education</intervention_name>
    <description>The participants in the intervention group are dentists´ and dental hygienists´. The interprofessional online mentoring education (3 ECTS credits) will be organized in collaboration with the Finnish Dental Association in an online environment. The aim of the intervention is to in-crease mentors' competence in guidance processes and interactions, supporting students´ goal-oriented learning and professional evaluation, and providing constructive feedback.</description>
    <arm_group_label>The Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>The interprofessional online mentoring education</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dentist or dental hygienist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Working in dental health care&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Readiness to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Professional from a field other than dental health care&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to provide consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kristina Mikkonen, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Oulu</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anna-Leena Keinänen, MHSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Oulu. Oulu University of Applied Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Healthcare organizations in Nordic Finland</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oulu</city>
        <country>Finland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Finland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gilbert JH, Yan J, Hoffman SJ. A WHO report: framework for action on interprofessional education and collaborative practice. J Allied Health. 2010 Fall;39 Suppl 1:196-7.</citation>
    <PMID>21174039</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hoffmann TC, Glasziou PP, Boutron I, Milne R, Perera R, Moher D, Altman DG, Barbour V, Macdonald H, Johnston M, Lamb SE, Dixon-Woods M, McCulloch P, Wyatt JC, Chan AW, Michie S. Better reporting of interventions: template for intervention description and replication (TIDieR) checklist and guide. BMJ. 2014 Mar 7;348:g1687. doi: 10.1136/bmj.g1687.</citation>
    <PMID>24609605</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Keinänen AL, Mikkonen K, Lähdesmäki R, Kääriäinen M. The dental healthcare professionals' competence in mentoring students in the clinical practice. Eur J Dent Educ. 2021 May;25(2):385-396. doi: 10.1111/eje.12615. Epub 2020 Oct 30.</citation>
    <PMID>33058327</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Moher D, Hopewell S, Schulz KF, Montori V, Gøtzsche PC, Devereaux PJ, Elbourne D, Egger M, Altman DG; CONSORT. CONSORT 2010 explanation and elaboration: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. Int J Surg. 2012;10(1):28-55. doi: 10.1016/j.ijsu.2011.10.001. Epub 2011 Oct 12. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22036893</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Räsänen L, Moore E. Critical evaluation of the guidelines of the Finnish Advisory Board on Research Integrity and of their application. Res Integr Peer Rev. 2016 Oct 17;1:15. doi: 10.1186/s41073-016-0020-9. eCollection 2016.</citation>
    <PMID>29451531</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tuomikoski AM, Ruotsalainen H, Mikkonen K, Miettunen J, Juvonen S, Sivonen P, Kääriäinen M. How mentoring education affects nurse mentors' competence in mentoring students during clinical practice - A quasi-experimental study'. Scand J Caring Sci. 2020 Mar;34(1):230-238. doi: 10.1111/scs.12728. Epub 2019 Jun 28.</citation>
    <PMID>31250935</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>World Medical Association. World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki: ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA. 2013 Nov 27;310(20):2191-4. doi: 10.1001/jama.2013.281053.</citation>
    <PMID>24141714</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Oulu</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Anna-Leena Keinanen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

