<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04712786</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BursaRetinaEyeH</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04712786</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Refractive Changes Following Vitrectomy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Refractive Changes in Pseudophakic Eyes Following Vitrectomy With or Without Gas Tamponade</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bursa Retina Eye Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bursa Retina Eye Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      We aimed o compare the refractive changes associated with pars plana vitrectomy with or&#xD;
      without intraocular gas tamponade in pseudophakic eyes. This retrospective study included&#xD;
      pseudophakic patients with Nd:YAG laser posterior capsulotomy who underwent 23G PPV between&#xD;
      February 2015 and March 2019. Group 1 consisted of patients with regmatogenous RD who&#xD;
      underwent PPV and 12% perflouropropane (C3F8) gas tamponade whereas Group 2 consisted of&#xD;
      patients who underwent PPV for epiretinal membrane or vitreous hemorrhage (VH). No tamponade&#xD;
      was used in Group 2. Minimum follow-up was 12 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This research was reviewed by an independent ethical review board and conforms with the&#xD;
      principles and applicable guidelines for the protection of human subjects in biomedical&#xD;
      research. This was a retrospective, comparative case series including pseudophakic patients&#xD;
      who underwent PPV. Group 1 consisted of patients with pseudophakic RRD who underwent PPV and&#xD;
      12% perflouropropane (C3F8) gas tamponade whereas Group 2 consisted of patients with ERM or&#xD;
      VH who underwent PPV without any tamponade between February 2015 and March 2019 at Bursa&#xD;
      Retina Eye Hospital. Informed consent was obtained from all the participants. The study was&#xD;
      in line with the ethical standarts of the Helsinki Declaration&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient eligibility Patients who underwent uncomplicated cataract surgery with&#xD;
      phacoemulsification and in-the-bag IOL implantation and subsequent&#xD;
      neodymium:yttrium-aluminum-garnet (Nd:YAG) laser due to capsular opacification were included.&#xD;
      Preoperative refractive data obtained after Nd:YAG laser and six months prior to vitrectomy&#xD;
      surgery. Postoperative refractive data was obtained at 12 months after vitrectomy. Eyes with&#xD;
      a preoperative spherical refractive error &gt; ±6 D or cylindrical refractive error &gt; ±3 D were&#xD;
      excluded. Also eyes with corneal disorders were excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ocular parameters&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients underwent complete ophtalmic examination including best corrected visual acuity&#xD;
      (BCVA) in the logMAR scale, slit-lamp examination, intraocular pressure (IOP) assessment,&#xD;
      fundus examination and autokeratorefractometry (auto kerato-refractometer KR-8800 from&#xD;
      Topcon, Tokyo, Japan) at preoperative and postoperative month-12. Induced astigmatism values&#xD;
      were calculated through vector analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgical procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
      All surgeries were performed by the same surgeon (S.Y.). Retrobulbar block anesthesia (a&#xD;
      mixture of 2 ml of lidocaine hydrochloride 2% and 2 ml of bupivacaine hydrochloride 0.5%) was&#xD;
      used. Three port 23-gauge (G) transconjunctival PPV was performed using the vitrectomy system&#xD;
      DORC (Dutch Ophthalmic Research Center, Zuidland, Netherlands) and Zeiss microscope with&#xD;
      EIBOS 2 (Haag Streit, Mason, OH, USA) attachment for non-contact fundus viewing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In group 1, all patients underwent a near-complete vitrectomy including base shaving, laser&#xD;
      endo-photocoagulation and C3F8 gas tamponade. In group 2, patients with ERM received a&#xD;
      limited vitrectomy including; core vitrectomy, induction of a posterior vitreous detachment&#xD;
      if not present and peeling of the ERM and inner limiting membrane (ILM). Peripheral retina&#xD;
      was examined with indentation to identify any retinal breaks. Neither laser&#xD;
      endo-photocoagulation, nor gas tamponade and vitreous base shaving was performed. For&#xD;
      patients with VH patients, a near-complete vitrectomy, including base shaving, laser&#xD;
      endo-photocoagulation was performed except for gas tamponade. In both groups, the sclera is&#xD;
      sutured with 8-0 polyglactin suture (Vicryl) in case of wound leakage.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 27, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 25, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The rate of spherical and cylindrical refractive changes</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in spherical and cylindrical refractive error 12 months after pars plana vitrectomy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">47</enrollment>
  <condition>Retinal Detachment</condition>
  <condition>Refractive Errors</condition>
  <condition>Vitreous Hemorrhage</condition>
  <condition>Epiretinal Membrane</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>27 patients, Group 1 consisted of patients with pseudophakic rhegmatogoneous retinal detachment who underwent pars plana vitrectomy and 12% perflouropropane (C3F8) gas tamponade and 20 patients Group 2 consisted of patients with epiretinal membrane or vitreous hemorrhage who underwent PPV without any tamponade</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>pars plana vitrectomy</intervention_name>
    <description>23 gauge pars plana vitrectomy was performed for retinal detachment, vitreous hemorrhage or epiretinal membrane</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Pseudophakic patients treated with neodymium:yttrium-aluminum-garnet Nd: YAG laser and&#xD;
        subsequently underwent 23 gauge pars plana vitrectomy for vitreous hemorrhage, epiretinal&#xD;
        membrane, or rhegmatogenous retinal detachment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients aged ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pseudophakic patients who underwent pars plana vitrectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients aged 18 years &gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a spherical refractive error &gt; ±6 D&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a cylindrical refractive error &gt; ±3 D&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sami Yılmaz, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Bursa Retina Eye Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Remzi Avcı, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Bursa Retina Eye Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aysegul Mavi Yıldız, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Bursa Retina Eye Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Retina Eye Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bursa</city>
        <zip>16130</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hamoudi H, Kofod M, La Cour M. Refractive change after vitrectomy for epiretinal membrane in pseudophakic eyes. Acta Ophthalmol. 2013 Aug;91(5):434-6. doi: 10.1111/j.1755-3768.2012.02574.x. Epub 2012 Sep 23.</citation>
    <PMID>22998208</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Byrne S, Ng J, Hildreth A, Danjoux JP, Steel DH. Refractive change following pseudophakic vitrectomy. BMC Ophthalmol. 2008 Oct 13;8:19. doi: 10.1186/1471-2415-8-19.</citation>
    <PMID>18851731</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Bursa Retina Eye Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>sami yilmaz</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Medical doctor, ophthalmology specialist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Myopic shift</keyword>
  <keyword>Gas tamponade</keyword>
  <keyword>Pars plana vitrectomy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Retinal Detachment</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Refractive Errors</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Epiretinal Membrane</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vitreous Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

