<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04715594</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>4-2019-0596</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04715594</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>CONNECT DES Registrty</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Whole Population-based Study on COreaN NationwidE Claims daTa on Drug-Eluting Stent (CONNECT DES) Registry</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yonsei University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yonsei University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To date, drug-eluting stents (DES) have become the standard of care in daily practice for the&#xD;
      treatment of ischemic heart disease, by overcoming the risk of in-stent restenosis, a major&#xD;
      issue raised in the bare-mare stents era. The application of potent anti-proliferative drugs&#xD;
      and polymer structures that ensures sustained released of the drugs markedly reduced the&#xD;
      neointimal hyperplasia, leading to much improved clinical outcomes compared with bare-metal&#xD;
      stents. However, although first-generation sirolimus-eluting stents and paclitaxel-eluting&#xD;
      stents significantly reduced the risk of in-stent restenosis and target-vessel&#xD;
      revascularization, an augmented risk for very late stent thrombosis and fatal clinical events&#xD;
      emerged as a new issue to be solved. Second- and newer- generation DESs adopted innovative&#xD;
      stent platforms, novel stent materials, anti-proliferative drugs, and biocompatible polymers&#xD;
      (including both durable and bioresorbable). Nowadays, numerous types of DESs (over 20 types)&#xD;
      are available in clinical practice as well as bare-metal stents. However, little is known&#xD;
      about the clinical outcome according to type of DESs in real-word practice. Given that many&#xD;
      of recent randomized clinical trials (RCTs) demonstrate the 'non-inferiority' of brand-new&#xD;
      DESs over older DESs in limited period time (usually for 1-year) in a selected patients&#xD;
      eligible for RCTs, the real-world clinical outcomes according to type of DES implanted are&#xD;
      still unveiled. Although, the question about the differential impact of generation of DES,&#xD;
      type of biocompatible polymers (bioresorbable versus durable), thickness of stent struts and&#xD;
      type of eluted anti-proliferative drugs are very important in clinical aspect of view, but&#xD;
      there is little study conducted on all patients who are actually confronted in daily clinical&#xD;
      practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Korea operates national insurance system that covers most of the Koreans (97.1%) that are&#xD;
      strictly monitored by National Health Insurance Service (NHIS). Of note, the claims database&#xD;
      of NHIS of Korea contains all information including the demographic characters of patietns,&#xD;
      diagnosis codes (ICD-9 and ICD-10), type of procedures or surgeries and the medical devices&#xD;
      utilized, death certificates that contains type of death, and the drugs prescribe in&#xD;
      outpatient clinic and hospitals in a individual pill level, that enables monitoring for the&#xD;
      drug compliance. This unique feature of NHIS database allows the investigators to gain access&#xD;
      to the dose and duration of cardio-protective medications including anti-platelet agents,&#xD;
      lipid-lowering agents, anti-hypertensive agents, glucose-lowering agents, nitrate donors,&#xD;
      vasodilators, and others. Given the benefits of NHIS database of Korea, we would like to&#xD;
      establish a whole-population registry, named as COreaN NationwidE Claims daTa on Drug-Eluting&#xD;
      Stent Registry (CONNECT DES Registry). A comprehensive analysis of this data is expected to&#xD;
      shed new light on the impact of type of DESs and drug use in real-world practice that could&#xD;
      be fully revealed through RCTs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      According to stringent policy of NHIS database to protect personal information, information&#xD;
      regarding type of DES including the thickness of strut, eluted drugs, type of polymer,&#xD;
      generation of the DES will be provided after sufficient encryption. Likewise, all information&#xD;
      regarding drug prescription, including the total number of pills prescribed during the&#xD;
      period, patients' compliance and dosage of drugs will be provided after sufficient&#xD;
      encryption. After decrypting the information provided to establish a database suitable for&#xD;
      analysis, all eligible patients will be divided into two or more groups according to the type&#xD;
      of DES or drug use pattern after DES implantation, which include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. 1st-generation vs. 2nd-generation DES&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Durable polymer vs. bioresorbable polymer 2nd-generaion DES&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Ultra-thin strut vs. Conventional strut vs. Thick-strut DES&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. According to the type of eluted drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. DAPT duration after DES implantation&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Type of anti-platelet therapy after cessation of DAPT&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Intensity of statin therapy after DES implantation&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. According to use of nitrate donor or vasodilator after DES implantation&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Use of anti-hypertensive agents after DES implantation&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Use of glucose-lowering agents in diabetic subset of patients&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 11, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Death from any cause</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiovascular mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Confirmed by death certificate with cardiovascular related diagnosis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Myocardial infarction</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiovascular mortality or myocardial infarction</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>A composite of cardiovascular mortality and myocardial infarction</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ischemic Stroke</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hemorrhagic stroke</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Any Stroke</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>A composite of ischemic stroke and hemorrhagic stroke</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gastrointestinal bleeding</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Any bleeding</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Any bleeding</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Major bleeding</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Any bleeding that requires transfusion ≥2 units of red-blood cells, hospitalizaiton, procedure, surgery, or leading to disability or death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Net adverse clinical events (NACE)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>A composite of all-cause mortality, recurrent MI, revascularization, ischemic stroke, and major bleeding</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Major adverse cardiac events (MACE)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>A composite of all-cause mortality, recurrent MI, and revascularization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Major adverse cardiac and cerebrovascular events (MACCE)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>A composite of all-cause mortality, recurrent MI, revascularization, and ischemic stroke</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">350000</enrollment>
  <condition>Stent Thrombosis</condition>
  <condition>Coronary Artery Disease</condition>
  <condition>Stent Stenosis</condition>
  <condition>Myocardial Infarction</condition>
  <condition>Ischemic Heart Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CONNECT DES Registrty</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>1st-generation drug-eluting stent</intervention_name>
    <description>Implantation of 1st-generation drug-eluting stent</description>
    <arm_group_label>CONNECT DES Registrty</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>2nd-generation drug-eluting stents</intervention_name>
    <description>Implantation of 2nd-generation drug-eluting stent</description>
    <arm_group_label>CONNECT DES Registrty</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Approximately 350,000 patients with DES implantation between 2005 and 2016 would be&#xD;
        incorporated in the analyses from National Health Insurance Service (NHIS) database&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who were over 20 years old at the implantation of DES and treated with DES&#xD;
             between 1-January-2005 and 31-December-2016&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who died within 1 week after DES implantation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hong Myeong-Ki</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fischman DL, Leon MB, Baim DS, Schatz RA, Savage MP, Penn I, Detre K, Veltri L, Ricci D, Nobuyoshi M, et al. A randomized comparison of coronary-stent placement and balloon angioplasty in the treatment of coronary artery disease. Stent Restenosis Study Investigators. N Engl J Med. 1994 Aug 25;331(8):496-501.</citation>
    <PMID>8041414</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stettler C, Wandel S, Allemann S, Kastrati A, Morice MC, Schömig A, Pfisterer ME, Stone GW, Leon MB, de Lezo JS, Goy JJ, Park SJ, Sabaté M, Suttorp MJ, Kelbaek H, Spaulding C, Menichelli M, Vermeersch P, Dirksen MT, Cervinka P, Petronio AS, Nordmann AJ, Diem P, Meier B, Zwahlen M, Reichenbach S, Trelle S, Windecker S, Jüni P. Outcomes associated with drug-eluting and bare-metal stents: a collaborative network meta-analysis. Lancet. 2007 Sep 15;370(9591):937-48. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17869634</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Camenzind E, Steg PG, Wijns W. Stent thrombosis late after implantation of first-generation drug-eluting stents: a cause for concern. Circulation. 2007 Mar 20;115(11):1440-55; discussion 1455. Epub 2007 Mar 7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17344324</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bangalore S, Toklu B, Patel N, Feit F, Stone GW. Newer-Generation Ultrathin Strut Drug-Eluting Stents Versus Older Second-Generation Thicker Strut Drug-Eluting Stents for Coronary Artery Disease. Circulation. 2018 Nov 13;138(20):2216-2226. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.118.034456.</citation>
    <PMID>29945934</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kim D, Yang PS, Sung JH, Jang E, Yu HT, Kim TH, Uhm JS, Kim JY, Pak HN, Lee MH, Lip GYH, Joung B. Less dementia after catheter ablation for atrial fibrillation: a nationwide cohort study. Eur Heart J. 2020 Dec 14;41(47):4483-4493. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa726.</citation>
    <PMID>33022705</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 20, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Yonsei University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Myeong-Ki Hong</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>coronary artery disease; drug-eluting stents; percutaneous coronary intervention</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Impossible to share the data due to goverment policy</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

