<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04718545</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>OCarcuac-modFGG</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04718545</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness of Modified-free Gingival Graft for Treatment of Localized Gingival Recession Defects</brief_title>
  <official_title>Treatment of Localized Gingival Recession Defects at Lower Mandibular Incisors Using a Modified-free Gingival Graft: a Randomized Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Göteborg University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Göteborg University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the present study is to evaluate, whether use of the modified free gingival graft&#xD;
      (mod-FGG) technique improves treatment outcomes after surgical root coverage at mandibular&#xD;
      incisors with gingival recession defects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Gingival recession defects (GRD), defined as displacement of the gingival margin apical to&#xD;
      the cemento-enamel junction, are frequent clinical findings in the general population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The major indications for root coverage procedures are improved esthetics, reduction of root&#xD;
      hypersensitivity and the increase of the dimensions of keratinized tissue in order to&#xD;
      facilitate infection control and prevent further progression of gingival recession defects.&#xD;
      Numerous surgical techniques for root coverage have been suggested, with different degrees of&#xD;
      success as assessed by the proportion of complete root coverage. The scientific evidence has&#xD;
      revealed that mandibular incisors were associated with the least favourable outcomes when&#xD;
      compared to other teeth. The lower success rate and lower predictability of root coverage&#xD;
      procedures at lower incisors, teeth with the highest frequency of GRDs, may be related to the&#xD;
      unfavorable anatomic conditions including marginal frenum attachment, high muscle pull and a&#xD;
      shallow vestibule. These features are frequently encountered in the anterior area of the&#xD;
      mandible, while they are rare in the maxillary anterior region.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The so-called &quot;Free Gingival Graft&quot; (FGG) was shown to be the most effective procedure for&#xD;
      gingival augmentation at sites with minimal amount of keratinized tissue. Great variability&#xD;
      in terms of proportion of root coverage (range: 11% to 87%; mean: 63%) has been reported when&#xD;
      applying this technique, however. One of the challenges may be the inadequate blood supply to&#xD;
      the portion of the FGG placed on the exposed root surface. A modified version of the FGG&#xD;
      technique (mod-FGG) has been proposed, aiming to improve the vascularity of the recipient&#xD;
      site over the denuded root surface. However, there is to date no scientific evidence whether&#xD;
      the mod-FGG provides better clinical results than the conventional FGG.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis of the study is that the mod-FGG will improve predictability and treatment&#xD;
      outcomes for root coverage at mandibular incisors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>mean mid-facial recession coverage (mRC)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>mRC measured as a percentage</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Keratinized tissue (KT) gain</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months and 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>KT gain measured in mm</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Gingival Recession, Localized</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Free Gingival Graft</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>A mucogingival surgery where a gingival graft harvested from the palate is placed on a conventionally prepared recipient site and sutured to cover the mucosal recession</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Modified Free Gingival Graft</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A mucogingival surgery where a gingival graft harvested from the palate is placed on a modified recipient site and sutured to cover the mucosal recession</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mucogingival surgery</intervention_name>
    <description>The gingival recession at mandibular incisor site will be covered by a gingival graft harvested from the palate.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Free Gingival Graft</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Modified Free Gingival Graft</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Periodontally and systemically healthy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Full-mouth plaque score and full-mouth bleeding score ≤ 20% (measured at four sites&#xD;
             per tooth)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thin phenotype&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Probing pocket depth (PPD) ≤3 mm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of excessive tooth mobility&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of cervical composite restorations or non-carious cervical lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Shallow vestibule&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smoking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alcoholism&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Para-functional habits&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Poor oral hygiene&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Excessive crowding or misalignment of teeth&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tord Berglundh, DDS, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Goteborg University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Olivier Carcuac, DDS, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>556275575</phone>
    <phone_ext>00971</phone_ext>
    <email>olivier.carcuac@gu.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jan Derks, DDS, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>317863124</phone>
    <phone_ext>0046</phone_ext>
    <email>jan.derks@odontologi.gu.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tonetti MS, Jepsen S; Working Group 2 of the European Workshop on Periodontology. Clinical efficacy of periodontal plastic surgery procedures: consensus report of Group 2 of the 10th European Workshop on Periodontology. J Clin Periodontol. 2014 Apr;41 Suppl 15:S36-43. doi: 10.1111/jcpe.12219.</citation>
    <PMID>24640999</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Cairo F. Periodontal plastic surgery of gingival recessions at single and multiple teeth. Periodontol 2000. 2017 Oct;75(1):296-316. doi: 10.1111/prd.12186. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28758301</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Cortellini P, Bissada NF. Mucogingival conditions in the natural dentition: Narrative review, case definitions, and diagnostic considerations. J Periodontol. 2018 Jun;89 Suppl 1:S204-S213. doi: 10.1002/JPER.16-0671. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29926948</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Zucchelli G, Marzadori M, Mounssif I, Mazzotti C, Stefanini M. Coronally advanced flap + connective tissue graft techniques for the treatment of deep gingival recession in the lower incisors. A controlled randomized clinical trial. J Clin Periodontol. 2014 Aug;41(8):806-13. doi: 10.1111/jcpe.12269. Epub 2014 Jun 5.</citation>
    <PMID>24802283</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Holbrook T, Ochsenbein C. Complete coverage of the denuded root surface with a one-stage gingival graft. Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 1983;3(3):8-27.</citation>
    <PMID>6358084</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Cairo F, Nieri M, Pagliaro U. Efficacy of periodontal plastic surgery procedures in the treatment of localized facial gingival recessions. A systematic review. J Clin Periodontol. 2014 Apr;41 Suppl 15:S44-62. doi: 10.1111/jcpe.12182. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24641000</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gingival Recession</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

