<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04712565</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>32-514 ex 19/20</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04712565</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Hard and Soft Tissue Maintenance Around Implants With a Sloped Configuration</brief_title>
  <official_title>Hard and Soft Tissue Maintenance Around Implants With a Sloped Configuration Without GBR in Comparison to a Conventional Neck Design With GBR-procedure: A Prospective Randomized Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical University of Graz</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of Graz</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a controlled, randomized clinical trial over about 16-months (active phase). 40&#xD;
      patients in need of replacement of a single tooth with a minimal crestal bone width of 4 -&#xD;
      5mm and suitable for simultaneous GBR (Guided Bone Regeneration) procedure as well as at&#xD;
      least a neighboring tooth on its mesial aspect will be consecutively recruited at the&#xD;
      Department of Dental Medicine and Oral Health Graz. Volunteers will be screened and eligible&#xD;
      subjects will be randomized to two different groups. In group 1 implants with regular neck&#xD;
      design (Astra Tech Implant EV C, Dentsply Implants Manufacturing GmbH, Hanau, Germany) and&#xD;
      GBR procedure (BioOss® and BioGide®, Geistlich, Wolhusen, Schweiz) fixed with two membrane&#xD;
      pins (Hipp Medical AG, Kolbingen, Germany) will be used; in group 2 implants with sloped&#xD;
      marginal configuration (Astra Tech Implant Profile EV C, Dentsply Implants Manufacturing&#xD;
      GmbH, Hanau, Germany) without bone augmentation are used. The dimension of the bony defect&#xD;
      and amount of lingual-buccal bone height discrepancy (max. 5mm) respectively bone width will&#xD;
      be evaluated using a 3-D volume tomography (Planmeca ProMax® 3D Max, Planmeca, Helsinki,&#xD;
      Finland), which is needed for digital planning (Simplant Planning Software, Leuven, Belgium)&#xD;
      of the implant position, length and diameter as well.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Digital scans will be done at first, 5th, 6th, 8th, and 10th visit to get the possibility to&#xD;
      determine and compare volume changing and stability at augmented or not augmented implant&#xD;
      sites during follow up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to standard procedure, patients will receive an antibiotic regime (Augmentin 1g,&#xD;
      2x1, GlaxoSmithKline, Vienna, Austria; in case of penicillin-allergy: DalacinC 300mg, 3x1,&#xD;
      Pfizer, Vienna, Austria) starting one day prior surgery till 3 days after surgery. Before&#xD;
      implant surgery patients are advised to rinse with a local antiseptic chlorhexidine gluconate&#xD;
      solution (Chlorhexamed forte 2mg/ml, GlaxoSmithKline, Vienna, Austria). Articain is used for&#xD;
      local anesthesia (Ultracain D-S forte with epinephrine 1:100.000, Sanofi Aventis, Vienna,&#xD;
      Austria). These drugs are not object of the investigation. After flap elevation the&#xD;
      lingual-buccal height discrepancy and bone width is measured using a periodontal probe. The&#xD;
      implant surgery is done following the standard surgical protocol of implant placement of the&#xD;
      Department of Dental medicine and Oral Health Graz using a pilot drill guide. After implant&#xD;
      insertion the marginal bone level will be measured using a periodontal probe. Implant&#xD;
      shoulder attends as a reference.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After implant insertion (Astra Tech Implant EV C or Astra Tech Implant Profile EV C, Dentsply&#xD;
      Implants Manufacturing GmbH, Hanau, Germany), GBR (Astra Tech Implant EV C) and a healing&#xD;
      period of approximately 3 months for both groups, the implants will be uncovered following&#xD;
      the standard protocol of the Department of Dental medicine and Oral Health Graz, and titanium&#xD;
      gingiva formers will be placed (non-investigational devices). After implant recovery the&#xD;
      marginal bone level will be measured again using a periodontal probe. Implant shoulder&#xD;
      attends as a reference.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will receive CE-certified gingiva formers, which are used in the Department of&#xD;
      Dental Medicine and Oral Health Graz and which are approved in Austria. 1 week after reentry&#xD;
      the sutures will be removed and the digital impression (PrimeScan) for the CAD/CAM (Computer&#xD;
      Aided Design /Computer Aided Manufacturing) manufactured single implant crowns using&#xD;
      customized individual abutments (Atlantis, Mölndal, Sweden) will be done.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Radiographic examinations (single-tooth x-ray) will be done at implant recovery (3 months&#xD;
      after implant placement, visit 6), visit 10 and visit 11.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A complete periodontal status (PD=probing depth, BOP= Bleeding on probing, PI= Plaque index)&#xD;
      should be evaluated at the first visit (before implant placement). These parameters (PD, BOP,&#xD;
      PI) as well as Papilla Index should be performed 8, 12, and 15 months after implant placement&#xD;
      at implant and reference tooth site. In addition, PD and Papilla Index will be performed 4&#xD;
      months after implant placement (at time of integration of the implant crown). At the first&#xD;
      visit, complete periodontal status will be evaluated to prove if the participant fulfills the&#xD;
      inclusion criteria. During the following visits only reference teeth (neighboring tooth or&#xD;
      teeth to the implant) and the implant site will be determined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The soft tissue maintenance will be detected using the Papilla Index by Jemt (Jemt T, 1997)&#xD;
      which assesses the size of interproximal gingival papillae adjacent to single implant&#xD;
      restorations. Using this, one can determine the papilla remodeling between a dental implant&#xD;
      and each neighboring tooth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intraoral photographs will be taken at every study visit (except suture removal), evaluating&#xD;
      the esthetic outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Oral Health Impact Profile (OHIP-G 14) will be done at the first visit and 12 months after&#xD;
      implant placement. The Oral Health Impact Profile as a self-rating patient-centered&#xD;
      instrument designed to assess the oral health-related quality of life within the last month.&#xD;
      Especially, the following dimensions are captured by the OHIP-G 14: functional Limitation&#xD;
      (e.g., &quot;pronouncing any words because of problems with your teeth, mouth, dentures, or jaw?&quot;)&#xD;
      and physical Pain (e.g., &quot;Have you had painful aching in your mouth&quot;). 14 questions are&#xD;
      raised, which are answered using a rating scale from 0 (never) to 4 (very often).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A questionnaire evaluating patient satisfaction will be performed one week after implant&#xD;
      surgery and 12 months after implant placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visual analog scale (VAS) for subjective measurement of pain will be performed immediately&#xD;
      and 1 week after implant placement using a combined VAS and numeric rating scale (NRS) The&#xD;
      scale ranges from 0 (smiling face), which means no pain, to 10 (sad face), which means most&#xD;
      pain imaginable).&#xD;
&#xD;
      GCP Statement: This study will be conducted in compliance with the principles of the&#xD;
      Declaration of Helsinki, the ICH-GCP guidelines and in accordance with the relevant&#xD;
      provisions of Austrian Medical Devices Act (MPG), the European Directive on implantable&#xD;
      medical devices (90/385/EEC), the Styrian Hospitals Act (KALG), the Federal Law on hospitals&#xD;
      (KAKuG), the EN-ISO standards 14155-1 and -2, EN ISO 14971, 10993 and all other ENISO&#xD;
      eligible relevant legislations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 14, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>marginal bone level</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>measured by single tooth X-ray</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>implant survival rate (ISR) in percent</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>measured in percent</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>clinical parameter: Probing depth</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>using a periodontal probe; in mm</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>clinical parameter: Bleeding on probing</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>in percent</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>clinical parameter: Plaque index</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>in percent</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>clinical parameter: Papilla index</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Papilla Index (Jemt T, 1997), the index ranges from 0 to 4, while 2 and 3 indicate physiological outcome</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>patient satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>no difference in patient satisfaction measured with OHIP G14 questionnaire. The following dimensions are captured by the OHIP-G 14: functional Limitation (e.g., &quot;pronouncing any words because of problems with your teeth, mouth, dentures, or jaw?&quot;) and physical Pain (e.g., &quot;Have you had painful aching in your mouth&quot;). 14 questions are raised, which are answered using a rating scale from 0 (never) to 4 (very often).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Tooth Loss</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Astra Tech Implant System Profile EV</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Implants with sloped marginal configuration without bone augmentation are used.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Astra Tech Implant System EV</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Implants with regular neck design and GBR procedure fixed with two membrane pins will be used.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Astra Tech Implant System Profile EV</intervention_name>
    <description>dental implant with a sloped neck configuration</description>
    <arm_group_label>Astra Tech Implant System Profile EV</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Astra Tech Implant System EV</intervention_name>
    <description>dental implant with a conventional neck configuration</description>
    <arm_group_label>Astra Tech Implant System EV</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written consent after clarification&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  capability of giving an informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  good health as defined by the subjects medical history (no contraindications as&#xD;
             described in the exclusion criteria below)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age 18 years of age and over&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Good periodontal status: BOP &lt; 20%, PI &lt; 30%, no PD &gt; 4mm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No heavy smokers (&lt; 10 cigarettes/day)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 1 missing tooth in the premolar and molar region (in selected cases in the&#xD;
             frontal area) either in the maxilla or in the mandible requiring implant therapy for&#xD;
             reconstruction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  implant site must present a buccal bone defect not extending a lingual-buccal or&#xD;
             buccal-palatinal height discrepancy of 5mm and a sufficient bone width for&#xD;
             simultaneously GBR procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  implant site must present at least a neighbouring tooth on its mesial aspect&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insufficient bone volume for implant placement requiring a sinus floor elevation or&#xD;
             extensive bone augmentation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Heavy Smokers (&gt;10 cigarettes/day)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medication with a contraindication for implant therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Skeletal immaturity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any active malignancy or ongoing treatment for malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An active infection at the operative site&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindications to the class of drugs which are used at regular surgical procedures,&#xD;
             e.g. known hypersensitivity or allergy to class of drugs or the investigational&#xD;
             product, except penicillin-allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unable or unwilling to return for follow-up visits for a period of at least 16 months&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical Universtiy Graz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Graz</city>
        <zip>8010</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Martin Lorenzoni</last_name>
      <phone>+43 316 385</phone>
      <phone_ext>12976</phone_ext>
      <email>martin.lorenzoni@medunigraz.at</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Araújo MG, Lindhe J. Dimensional ridge alterations following tooth extraction. An experimental study in the dog. J Clin Periodontol. 2005 Feb;32(2):212-8.</citation>
    <PMID>15691354</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hof M, Pommer B, Strbac GD, Sütö D, Watzek G, Zechner W. Esthetic evaluation of single-tooth implants in the anterior maxilla following autologous bone augmentation. Clin Oral Implants Res. 2013 Aug;24 Suppl A100:88-93. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0501.2011.02381.x. Epub 2011 Dec 8.</citation>
    <PMID>22150807</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jemt T. Regeneration of gingival papillae after single-implant treatment. Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 1997 Aug;17(4):326-33.</citation>
    <PMID>9497723</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lekholm U, Adell R, Lindhe J, Brånemark PI, Eriksson B, Rockler B, Lindvall AM, Yoneyama T. Marginal tissue reactions at osseointegrated titanium fixtures. (II) A cross-sectional retrospective study. Int J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 1986 Feb;15(1):53-61.</citation>
    <PMID>3083006</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lorenzoni M, Pertl C, Wegscheider W, Keil C, Penkner K, Polansky R, Bratschko RO. Retrospective analysis of Frialit-2 implants in the augmented sinus. Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 2000 Jun;20(3):255-67.</citation>
    <PMID>11203567</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pietrokovski J, Massler M. Alveolar ridge resorption following tooth extraction. J Prosthet Dent. 1967 Jan;17(1):21-7.</citation>
    <PMID>5224784</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schropp L, Wenzel A, Kostopoulos L, Karring T. Bone healing and soft tissue contour changes following single-tooth extraction: a clinical and radiographic 12-month prospective study. Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 2003 Aug;23(4):313-23.</citation>
    <PMID>12956475</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zuiderveld EG, Meijer HJ, Vissink A, Raghoebar GM. Outcome of Treatment with Single Implants in Preserved Versus Nonpreserved Alveolar Ridges: A 1-year Cohort Study. Int J Oral Maxillofac Implants. 2019 Nov/Dec;34(6):1457-1465. doi: 10.11607/jomi.7367.</citation>
    <PMID>31711086</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zumstein T, Schütz S, Sahlin H, Sennerby L. Factors influencing marginal bone loss at a hydrophilic implant design placed with or without GBR procedures: A 5-year retrospective study. Clin Implant Dent Relat Res. 2019 Oct;21(5):817-826. doi: 10.1111/cid.12826. Epub 2019 Aug 21.</citation>
    <PMID>31432605</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Karasan D, Güncü MB, Ersu B, Canay Ş. Biomechanical Behavior of Implants with a Sloped Marginal Configuration. Int J Prosthodont. 2018 Nov/Dec;31(6):587-590. doi: 10.11607/ijp.5882.</citation>
    <PMID>30408141</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Noelken R, Donati M, Fiorellini J, Gellrich NC, Parker W, Wada K, Berglundh T. Soft and hard tissue alterations around implants placed in an alveolar ridge with a sloped configuration. Clin Oral Implants Res. 2014 Jan;25(1):3-9. doi: 10.1111/clr.12079. Epub 2012 Dec 5.</citation>
    <PMID>23210667</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tooth Loss</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>results will be shared by publishing an article</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

