<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04717752</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SZ-POR-DTMAR-2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04717752</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Randomized Controlled Study of Different Trigger Modes of Antagonist Regimen in Patients With Low Ovarian Reserve</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Controlled Study of Different Trigger Modes of Antagonist Regimen in Patients With Low Ovarian Reserve</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nanjing University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Nanjing University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Assisted reproductive technology (ART), especially controlled ovarian stimulation (COS),&#xD;
      significantly increased clinical pregnancy rates among infertile patients. However, about 9%&#xD;
      to 24% of patients had poor ovarian response to gonadotropins (GNS) stimulation, which was&#xD;
      called poor ovarian response (POR). In recent years, the diagnosis and treatment of patients&#xD;
      with low fertility is the challenge for reproductive medicine. To better demonstrate the&#xD;
      effectiveness of various interventions and distinguish the different subgroups of patients,&#xD;
      2016 POSEIDON (Patient-Oriented Strategies Encompassing Individualized Oocyte Number)&#xD;
      standard changed low reaction into low prognosis of patient-oriented individual strategies to&#xD;
      obtain eggs. For patients in group 3 and group 4 classified by POSEIDON, ovarian reserve&#xD;
      function decline, follicular development desynchrony and low numbers of oocytes obtained lead&#xD;
      to poor prognosis. In 2020, the prognosis based on Delphi method of assisted reproductive&#xD;
      technology to treat low crowd diagnosis expert opinion in China recommended to give these&#xD;
      patients conventional cosine solutions such as antagonist. In the first cycle, follicle&#xD;
      stimulating hormone (FSH) starting dose of 225 ~ 300 iu is suggested to achieve plenty of&#xD;
      ovarian stimulation for standards and maximize the benefits of superovulation. Because of the&#xD;
      particularity of luteal support in the antagonist regimen, it is of great clinical&#xD;
      significance to explore the trigger mode and combination mode of luteal support in the&#xD;
      antagonist regimen for patients with poor prognosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 20, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical pregnancy rate in each transplantation cycle</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>number of pregnant cases are confirmed by ultrasound/ total number of transplanted</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of cancelled cycle</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>number of cancelled cycles/ number of total cycles</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of mature eggs</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>number of matured oocytes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of high-quality embryos</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>number of D3 high quality embryos (≥7 scores)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Implantation rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>number of gestational sacs/ number of transplanted embryos</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Early abortion rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>number of miscarriage cases/ number of pregnant cases confirmed by ultrasound</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative pregnancy rate per stimulation cycle</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>number of pregnant cases which are confirmed by ultrasound/ total number of stimulation cycle</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">310</enrollment>
  <condition>Poor Ovarian Response</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Double trigger unit</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>HCG: 6000IU (Ovidrel: 250ug) + GnRH-a (Troprilin) 0.2mg</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HCG trigger unit</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>HCG: 6000IU (Ovidrel: 250ug)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ovidrel</intervention_name>
    <description>recombinant human chorionic gonadotropin for injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Double trigger unit</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>HCG trigger unit</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Troprilin</intervention_name>
    <description>triptorelin acetate injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Double trigger unit</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age less than or equal to 42 years old, AFC&lt;5 and or AMH&lt;1.2ng/ml ② Adopt antagonist&#xD;
             program for controlled ovulation hyperstimulation (COH); patients with fresh cycle&#xD;
             transplantation;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Accept conventional IVF or intracytoplasmic sperm injection (ICSI);&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  The ART treatment cycle is less than 3 times.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal chromosome karyotype;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Severe endometriosis;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Abnormal thyroid function; ④ Pregnancy contraindications; ⑤ Past history of&#xD;
                       ovarian tumors or after receiving radiotherapy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>42 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Reproductive Medicine Center, The affiliated Drum Towel Hospital of Nanjing University Medical School</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nanjing</city>
        <state>Jiangsu</state>
        <zip>210008</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Haixiang Sun</last_name>
      <phone>+86 025 83107188</phone>
      <email>stevensunz@163.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ferraretti AP, La Marca A, Fauser BC, Tarlatzis B, Nargund G, Gianaroli L; ESHRE working group on Poor Ovarian Response Definition. ESHRE consensus on the definition of 'poor response' to ovarian stimulation for in vitro fertilization: the Bologna criteria. Hum Reprod. 2011 Jul;26(7):1616-24. doi: 10.1093/humrep/der092. Epub 2011 Apr 19.</citation>
    <PMID>21505041</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Poseidon Group (Patient-Oriented Strategies Encompassing IndividualizeD Oocyte Number), Alviggi C, Andersen CY, Buehler K, Conforti A, De Placido G, Esteves SC, Fischer R, Galliano D, Polyzos NP, Sunkara SK, Ubaldi FM, Humaidan P. A new more detailed stratification of low responders to ovarian stimulation: from a poor ovarian response to a low prognosis concept. Fertil Steril. 2016 Jun;105(6):1452-3. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2016.02.005. Epub 2016 Feb 26.</citation>
    <PMID>26921622</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Orvieto R. Triggering final follicular maturation--hCG, GnRH-agonist or both, when and to whom? J Ovarian Res. 2015 Aug 21;8:60. doi: 10.1186/s13048-015-0187-6.</citation>
    <PMID>26293447</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nakano R, Mizuno T, Kotsuji F, Katayama K, Wshio M, Tojo S. &quot;Triggering&quot; of ovulation after infusion of synthetic luteinizing hormone releasing factor (LRF). Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 1973;52(3):269-72.</citation>
    <PMID>4582787</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gonen Y, Balakier H, Powell W, Casper RF. Use of gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist to trigger follicular maturation for in vitro fertilization. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1990 Oct;71(4):918-22.</citation>
    <PMID>2119392</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Griesinger G, Diedrich K, Devroey P, Kolibianakis EM. GnRH agonist for triggering final oocyte maturation in the GnRH antagonist ovarian hyperstimulation protocol: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Hum Reprod Update. 2006 Mar-Apr;12(2):159-68. Epub 2005 Oct 27.</citation>
    <PMID>16254001</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Griesinger G, Kolibianakis EM, Papanikolaou EG, Diedrich K, Van Steirteghem A, Devroey P, Ejdrup Bredkjaer H, Humaidan P. Triggering of final oocyte maturation with gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist or human chorionic gonadotropin. Live birth after frozen-thawed embryo replacement cycles. Fertil Steril. 2007 Sep;88(3):616-21. Epub 2007 Apr 23.</citation>
    <PMID>17451691</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Youssef MA, Van der Veen F, Al-Inany HG, Mochtar MH, Griesinger G, Nagi Mohesen M, Aboulfoutouh I, van Wely M. Gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist versus HCG for oocyte triggering in antagonist-assisted reproductive technology. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014 Oct 31;(10):CD008046. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD008046.pub4. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25358904</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Griesinger G, Meldrum D. Introduction: Management of the luteal phase in assisted reproductive technology. Fertil Steril. 2018 May;109(5):747-748. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2018.02.009.</citation>
    <PMID>29778366</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lawrenz B, Coughlan C, Fatemi HM. Individualized luteal phase support. Curr Opin Obstet Gynecol. 2019 Jun;31(3):177-182. doi: 10.1097/GCO.0000000000000530. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30855289</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Griffin D, Benadiva C, Kummer N, Budinetz T, Nulsen J, Engmann L. Dual trigger of oocyte maturation with gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist and low-dose human chorionic gonadotropin to optimize live birth rates in high responders. Fertil Steril. 2012 Jun;97(6):1316-20. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2012.03.015. Epub 2012 Apr 3.</citation>
    <PMID>22480822</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schachter M, Friedler S, Ron-El R, Zimmerman AL, Strassburger D, Bern O, Raziel A. Can pregnancy rate be improved in gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) antagonist cycles by administering GnRH agonist before oocyte retrieval? A prospective, randomized study. Fertil Steril. 2008 Oct;90(4):1087-93. Epub 2007 Nov 26.</citation>
    <PMID>18023439</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Li S, Zhou D, Yin T, Xu W, Xie Q, Cheng D, Yang J. Dual trigger of triptorelin and HCG optimizes clinical outcome for high ovarian responder in GnRH-antagonist protocols. Oncotarget. 2018 Jan 4;9(4):5337-5343. doi: 10.18632/oncotarget.23916. eCollection 2018 Jan 12.</citation>
    <PMID>29435182</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eftekhar M, Mojtahedi MF, Miraj S, Omid M. Final follicular maturation by administration of GnRH agonist plus HCG versus HCG in normal responders in ART cycles: An RCT. Int J Reprod Biomed. 2017 Jul;15(7):429-434.</citation>
    <PMID>29177244</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lin MH, Wu FS, Lee RK, Li SH, Lin SY, Hwu YM. Dual trigger with combination of gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist and human chorionic gonadotropin significantly improves the live-birth rate for normal responders in GnRH-antagonist cycles. Fertil Steril. 2013 Nov;100(5):1296-302. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2013.07.1976. Epub 2013 Aug 28.</citation>
    <PMID>23993928</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhou X, Guo P, Chen X, Ye D, Liu Y, Chen S. Comparison of dual trigger with combination GnRH agonist and hCG versus hCG alone trigger of oocyte maturation for normal ovarian responders. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2018 Jun;141(3):327-331. doi: 10.1002/ijgo.12457. Epub 2018 Feb 21.</citation>
    <PMID>29388691</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lu X, Hong Q, Sun L, Chen Q, Fu Y, Ai A, Lyu Q, Kuang Y. Dual trigger for final oocyte maturation improves the oocyte retrieval rate of suboptimal responders to gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist. Fertil Steril. 2016 Nov;106(6):1356-1362. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2016.07.1068. Epub 2016 Aug 1.</citation>
    <PMID>27490046</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Griffin D, Feinn R, Engmann L, Nulsen J, Budinetz T, Benadiva C. Dual trigger with gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist and standard dose human chorionic gonadotropin to improve oocyte maturity rates. Fertil Steril. 2014 Aug;102(2):405-9. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2014.04.028. Epub 2014 May 17.</citation>
    <PMID>24842671</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gold JI, Stocker AA. Visual Decision-Making in an Uncertain and Dynamic World. Annu Rev Vis Sci. 2017 Sep 15;3:227-250. doi: 10.1146/annurev-vision-111815-114511. Epub 2017 Jul 17. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28715956</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Belova EV, Emtseva VP, Obolenskiĭ IuA. [Characteristics of autonomic and hormonal reactions during the performance of different types of intellectual work]. Fiziol Cheloveka. 1988 May-Jun;14(3):482-5. Russian.</citation>
    <PMID>2844614</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Deepika K, Rathore S, Garg N, Rao K. Empty follicle syndrome: Successful pregnancy following dual trigger. J Hum Reprod Sci. 2015 Jul-Sep;8(3):170-4. doi: 10.4103/0974-1208.165152.</citation>
    <PMID>26538861</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zilberberg E, Haas J, Dar S, Kedem A, Machtinger R, Orvieto R. Co-administration of GnRH-agonist and hCG, for final oocyte maturation (double trigger), in patients with low proportion of mature oocytes. Gynecol Endocrinol. 2015 Feb;31(2):145-7. doi: 10.3109/09513590.2014.978850. Epub 2014 Nov 11.</citation>
    <PMID>25385007</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Oliveira SA, Calsavara VF, Cortés GC. Final Oocyte Maturation in Assisted Reproduction with Human Chorionic Gonadotropin and Gonadotropin-releasing Hormone agonist (Dual Trigger). JBRA Assist Reprod. 2016 Dec 1;20(4):246-250. doi: 10.5935/1518-0557.20160047. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28050961</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eser A, Devranoğlu B, Bostancı Ergen E, Yayla Abide Ç. Dual trigger with gonadotropin-releasing hormone and human chorionic gonadotropin for poor responders. J Turk Ger Gynecol Assoc. 2018 Jun 4;19(2):98-103. doi: 10.4274/jtgga.2017.0045. Epub 2018 Mar 8.</citation>
    <PMID>29516855</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lin MH, Wu FS, Hwu YM, Lee RK, Li RS, Li SH. Dual trigger with gonadotropin releasing hormone agonist and human chorionic gonadotropin significantly improves live birth rate for women with diminished ovarian reserve. Reprod Biol Endocrinol. 2019 Jan 4;17(1):7. doi: 10.1186/s12958-018-0451-x.</citation>
    <PMID>30609935</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ding N, Liu X, Jian Q, Liang Z, Wang F. Dual trigger of final oocyte maturation with a combination of GnRH agonist and hCG versus a hCG alone trigger in GnRH antagonist cycle for in vitro fertilization: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2017 Nov;218:92-98. doi: 10.1016/j.ejogrb.2017.09.004. Epub 2017 Sep 14. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28957685</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Nanjing University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Li-jun Ding</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Reproductive Medicine Center, Drum Tower Hospital Affiliated to Nanjing University Medical College</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>poor ovarian response</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chorionic Gonadotropin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

