<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04711642</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Dry Eye and Cataract Surgery</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04711642</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comprehensive Study on Dry Eye and Ocular Surface Disease Prior and After Cataract Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comprehensive Study on Dry Eye and Ocular Surface Disease Prior and After Cataract Surgery: Effects of Treatment on Dry Eye and Inflammatory Biomarkers.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fundación Oftalmológica Los Andes</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Alcon Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fundación Oftalmológica Los Andes</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Ocular surface disease (OSD), particularly dry eye, is one of the most common conditions seen&#xD;
      by ophthalmologists. Dry eye (DE) is a multifactorial disease of the tears and ocular surface&#xD;
      that results in symptoms of discomfort, visual disturbance, and tear instability. DE&#xD;
      significantly reduces quality of life and affects 5-30% of the population. As the proportion&#xD;
      of individuals over age 60 increases because of greater life expectancies, we can anticipate&#xD;
      the number of people with dry eye will also increase, which represents a major challenging&#xD;
      for aging societies, like the Chilean one.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the last few years clinical research on OSD is being intensely focused on diagnostic&#xD;
      criteria, treatment strategies, methods used in diagnosis and better correlations between&#xD;
      symptoms and clinical test results. All these lines of interest aim to improve the&#xD;
      understanding of alterations and consequences occurring in the ocular surface disorders.&#xD;
      Diagnostic testing is greatly valuable both for the detection of early changes due to DE and&#xD;
      also to grade the severity of surface disease. The most commonly performed tests include the&#xD;
      Schirmer test, tear break up time (TBUT), and ocular surface staining. However, newer&#xD;
      point-of-care diagnostics tests such as tear osmolarity and matrix metalloprotease-9 (MMP-9)&#xD;
      have been shown to have a high sensitivity and specificity in diagnosing ocular surface&#xD;
      dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given that ocular surface dysfunction has been shown to have an adverse impact on visual&#xD;
      function and can worsen after surgery, it is critical to identify and address any tear film&#xD;
      and ocular surface abnormalities before cataract surgery. In the setting of preoperative&#xD;
      cataract surgery planning, DE disease and meibomian gland dysfunction can impair critical&#xD;
      refractive measures such as keratometry values worsening surgical outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To the best of our knowledge there are no ongoing or published studies that have evaluated DE&#xD;
      and OSD as evidenced by either an abnormal tear-film parameter (elevated MMP-9 or abnormal&#xD;
      osmolarity), or corneal surface and meibography evaluation findings (using novel non-invasive&#xD;
      technology) in patients previous and after cataract surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A prospective randomized study has been designed to assess and characterize OSD/DE in&#xD;
      consecutive patients presenting for cataract surgery evaluation and to identify eventual&#xD;
      changes on biomarkers of the tear film of the same population postoperatively. At the same&#xD;
      time, 2 different postoperative eye drops regimen will be evaluated in order to determine its&#xD;
      impact on postoperative OSD/DE.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All group of patients will be subjected to Dry Eye assessment using diagnosis criteria and&#xD;
      methodologies recommended by the 2017 Dry Eye Workshop (DEWS II) (2), which includes the&#xD;
      assessment of a battery of symptoms (OSDI questionnaire), signs (tear meniscus height,&#xD;
      corneal and conjunctival lissamine green/fluorescein staining), laboratory tests (Schirmer I,&#xD;
      TBUT assessment, tear osmolarity, tear MMP-9, meibography, ocular redness, lipid layer&#xD;
      thickness) and physical examination (lid, meibum gland assessment). This assessment will be&#xD;
      carried out in all groups preoperative and at postoperative week 4 and postoperative week 12.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Altogether, by identifying definite changes either in novel tear film biomarkers or non&#xD;
      invasive ocular tests of patients subjected to cataract surgery, we expect to contribute to&#xD;
      the understanding of the pathophysiology of the OSD and Dry Eye associated to cataract&#xD;
      surgery and to give lights on the utility of those changes as biomarkers in diagnosis and&#xD;
      therapy assessment in these conditions committing the ocular surface.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The research hypothesis is that there is a high prevalence of ocular surface dysfunction&#xD;
      among patients presenting for cataract surgery as measured by point-of-care objective tear&#xD;
      tests and cataract surgery results in altered ocular surface in a major fraction of patients.&#xD;
      Dry eye symptoms are not necessary associated with objective signs in the ocular surface, but&#xD;
      are less in the group of patients treated with associated lubricant eyedrops postoperatively.&#xD;
      Patients more symptomatic in the postoperative period tend to have multiple preoperative&#xD;
      OSD/DE biomarkers altered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consecutive patients presenting for cataract surgery evaluation will be recruited at the&#xD;
      Fundacion Oftalmologica Los Andes (FOLA) Ophthalmology Clinic (Santiago, Chile). Patients&#xD;
      will be eligible according to inclusion and exclusion criteria indicated. Eligible patients&#xD;
      will be invited to participate voluntary in the study. The study will comprise three groups&#xD;
      with 30-35 patients per group. Dry eye patients will be diagnosed according to TFOS DEWS II&#xD;
      report and to the recommendations of the Dry Eye Workshop of 2017. It will basically consist&#xD;
      of: a) patient history: symptoms and signs (e.g. ocular irritation, dryness or foreign body&#xD;
      sensation, redness, etc), exacerbating conditions, duration of symptoms, etc., will be&#xD;
      obtained by using the Ocular Surface Disease Index (OSDI). b) physical examination: visual&#xD;
      acuity measurement, external examination and slit lamp biomicroscopy (tear film, tear&#xD;
      meniscus, eyelashes, eyelid margins, conjunctiva, cornea, lens and retina). c) Diagnostic&#xD;
      tests: Tear film osmolarity (using Tearlab), Tear film MMP-9 levels (using InflammaDry).&#xD;
      Non-invasive tests will be performed using Keratograph 5M, which includes: non-invasive tear&#xD;
      film break up time tear meniscus height, lipid layer thickness, ocular redness and&#xD;
      meibography.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will comprise three groups. Each group will comprise 30-35 patients. Each of the&#xD;
      100 patients will be featured by a list of clinical parameters (ocular signs and symptoms and&#xD;
      laboratory tests used conventionally for Dry Eye diagnostic). It is expected to observe&#xD;
      differences in parameters before and after cataract surgery and between the control group and&#xD;
      the two interventional groups. Association of those differences with the type of&#xD;
      postoperative regimen will be defined statistically by using Student t-test and ANOVA for&#xD;
      parametric data and U-test of Mann-Whitney for non-parametric data (p&lt;0.05 will be taken as&#xD;
      significant). Altogether, it is expected that such a multiplicity of signs and symptoms will&#xD;
      give valuable data on specificities of Dry Eye after cataract surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All the participant surgeons will have a summary document of the inclusion and exclusion&#xD;
      criteria and a flowchart of the patient's enrollment process to improve compliance. The data&#xD;
      will be stored on an external digital platform and only the data analyst will have access to&#xD;
      it. In addition, there will be written records of each enrolled patient.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 15, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 15, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Eligible patients will be enrolled and randomly assigned by a computer generated randomization list in a 1:1:1 ratio to the intervention groups (2) or the control group. After cataract surgery, all groups will be given a topical steroid-antibiotic (tobramycin 0.3% and dexamethasone acetate 0.1%) commercially available and commonly used by ophthalmologists worldwide postoperatively, in a 3-week tapered regimen (every 2 hours the first day, then every 4 hours for 6 days, then 3 times a day for 1 week and twice a day for 1 week). The 2 study groups will be also prescribed lubricant eye drops from the postoperative day 7 containing sodium hyaluronate 0.1% (in 2 different commercially available formulations) to instill 4 times daily for the following 3 months. Study group patients will be instructed to instill the lubricant eyedrops at least 10 minutes after the tobramycin-dexamethasone eyedrops. At postoperative visits, patients will be asked about compliance with the assigned treatment.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dry eye ocular symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 30 days, 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in Ocular Surface Disease Index (OSDI) scores between groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non-invasive Break-up time</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 30 days, 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in NIBUT scores between treated and untreated groups and between treated groups using 2 different lubricating drops.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tear osmolarity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline 30 days, 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in Tear Osmolarity between treated and untreated groups and between treated groups using 2 different lubricating drops.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>InflammaDry (MMP9) test</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 30 days, 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in proportion of patients with a positive InflammaDry (MMP9) between treated and untreated groups and between treated groups using 2 different lubricating drops.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Dry Eye Disease</condition>
  <condition>Dry Eye Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Evaporative Dry Eye</condition>
  <condition>Cataract</condition>
  <condition>Phacoemulsification</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Sodium hyaluronate 0.1% eyedrops (Systane ultra plus), q.i.d from day 7 to day 30 after cataract surgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Sodium hyaluronate 0.1% eyedrops (Hylo-comod), q.i.d from day 7 to day 30 after cataract surgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The study will include three arms, one non interventional and 2 interventions. The intervention arms will include two commercially available sodium hyaluronate 0.1% (Systane ultra plus and Hylo-comod)</intervention_name>
    <description>All groups will receive a topical steroid-antibiotic for 3 weeks. The study groups will be also prescribed eye drops containing sodium hyaluronate 0.1% from the postoperative day 7 for 4 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Indication of phacoemulsification for refractive purposes or for the presence of&#xD;
             visually significant cataract.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of intraoperative or postoperative complications of phacoemulsification&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to participate in the study (signed informed consent)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ocular surgeries within the previous 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contact lenses user.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe blepharitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Palpebral malposition and secondary dry eye&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of filamentary keratitis, corneal neovascularization, or herpetic keratitis&#xD;
             within previous 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypersensitivity to investigated substances or diagnostic stains used.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Antiglaucomatous topical medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Artificial tears with instillation frequency greater than 3 times a day in the last&#xD;
             week&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Luis Montecinos Buneder, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fundacion Oftalmologica Los Andes</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Juan Stoppel Ortiz, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fundacion Oftalmologica Los Andes</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Felipe Valenzuela Santana, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Fundación Oftalmológica Los Andes</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Cristobal Loezar Hernandez, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fundacion Oftalmologica Los Andes</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Felipe Valenzuela Santana, MD</last_name>
    <phone>23704633</phone>
    <email>felipevalenz@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Cristobal Loézar Hernández, MD</last_name>
    <phone>23704600</phone>
    <email>cristobal.loezar@uv.cl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cataract surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Dry eye disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Ocular surface osmolarity</keyword>
  <keyword>matrix metalloproteinase-9</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cataract</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dry Eye Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Keratoconjunctivitis Sicca</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Eye Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Capsule Opacification</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hyaluronic Acid</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

