<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04716296</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0328-20-RMC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04716296</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ketamine in Deep Brain Stimulation (DBS) Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Intraoperative Use of Ketamine for Awake Deep Brain Stimulation (DBS) Surgery Compared to Standard Procedure</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rabin Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rabin Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Deep brain stimulation (DBS) is a well-established and effective treatment for motor symptoms&#xD;
      resulting from idiopathic Parkinson's disease (PD). During the DBS surgery , a brain&#xD;
      electrode is implanted in the basal ganglia, which is involved in the pathophysiology of the&#xD;
      disease. The surgery consists of three steps: 1. Opening the skin, drilling the skull bone&#xD;
      and inserting a temporary electrode. 2. Recording electrical activity of the brain,&#xD;
      electrical stimulation of the brain which guide the implantation of the electrode.3&#xD;
      Transferring wires and implanting a subcutaneous pacemaker battery in the chest area.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Today, standard treatment protocols consist undergoing the second stage (or first and second&#xD;
      stage, depending on the treatment center protocol) of the surgery awake (under local&#xD;
      anesthesia only). As systemic anesthetics affect cerebral electrical activity and prevent&#xD;
      patient cooperation, they inhibit precise identification of the cerebral target under&#xD;
      'physiological navigation' guided by electrical recording and brain stimulation. As a result,&#xD;
      the accuracy of electrode implantation decreases. However, undergoing surgery in an awake&#xD;
      format often causes severe patient discomfort and anxiety necessitating shortening the length&#xD;
      of surgery or aborting the surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As such there is a need for establishing an alternative anesthesia protocol for DBS&#xD;
      surgeries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ketamine is considered a unique anesthetic due to its hypnotic properties, analgesia, and&#xD;
      possible amnesia. Standard doses of ketamine are currently used worldwide to treat patients&#xD;
      with various injuries and brain diseases. Research from monkeys has shown that ketamine (in&#xD;
      low dose) does not affect electrical brain activity used for physiological navigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators therefore propose a prospective , randomized , blinded study to evaluate&#xD;
      the utility of low dose of ketamine in the second stage of DBS surgeries for increasing&#xD;
      patient satisfaction and cooperation without detracting from the accuracy of physiological&#xD;
      navigation to the cerebral target.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will compare two treatment arms :&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment arm consisting of patients randomized to receive a low dose of ketamine for the&#xD;
      second stage of DBS surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control arm consisting of patients randomized to receive sham control of saline during the&#xD;
      second stage of DBS surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. On the day before surgery the participant will be shown 10 objects that he should&#xD;
           remember. On the day after surgery he will be requested to recall the objects he&#xD;
           remembers and to answer the level of anxiety he is feeling using the Visual Anxiety&#xD;
           Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. In the event of discharges (a possible side effect of ketamine due to muscarinic /&#xD;
           parasympathetic stimulation), a single dose of scopolamine (1 mg - ) will be given&#xD;
           intravenously.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. At the end of the surgical phase of opening (of the same side being operated on) the&#xD;
           propopol will be discontinued (as routinely done), and a continuous low-dose ketamine&#xD;
           infusion (0.25 mg per kilogram per hour) will be given until the permanent electrode is&#xD;
           implanted on the same operated side, or in the event that unwanted side effects that&#xD;
           can't be controlled appear.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. During surgery, monitoring of muscle activity (EMG) and brain activity (EEG) will be&#xD;
           performed&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. During the operation a short canola will be inserted through the meningeal opening and&#xD;
           fixed to the surface of the cerebral cortex.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Through the cannula A 10 mm deep microelectrode will be inserted, which will record&#xD;
           electrical activity from the cerebral cortex for several minutes (up to 15 minutes).&#xD;
           During the recording period the patient may be asked to perform a simple cognitive task&#xD;
           using a computer or iPad. Following the recording the canola and the microelectrode will&#xD;
           be removed and the canola will be inserted to the depth of the brain as part of the&#xD;
           standard surgery and through it the microelectrode will be inserted into the brain&#xD;
           target, and recording of electrical activity from the depths of the brain, as is&#xD;
           customary will be performed. At the end of the ketamine phase, at the end of the&#xD;
           electrophysiological monitoring required for navigation, prior to the electrical&#xD;
           stimulation, when the electrode is placed at the bottom of the sub-thalamic nucleus, the&#xD;
           patient will be shown for 60 seconds 10 images of objects (a single object in each&#xD;
           image, different from the objects presented to him the day before) which he will asked&#xD;
           to remember. At the same time on the screen will present electrical recordings from the&#xD;
           depth of the brain (MER) by the brain electrode. In addition, the patient will be asked&#xD;
           grade the anxiety level he is experiencing using the Visual Anxiety Scale (VAS) .&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. On the day after surgery, the patient will be asked to recall which objects were&#xD;
           presented to him the day before the operation and during the operation. Note that the&#xD;
           two object lists will be from a database of objects used in functional day-to-day life&#xD;
           (standard lists used for the CMT test - contextual memory test). In addition, the&#xD;
           patient will be asked to answer a Visual Anxiety Scale (VAS) and the Iowa satisfaction&#xD;
           score questionnaire detailing the patients overall overall experience, mood and feelings&#xD;
           during surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
           These assessments will be performed by a neuropsychologist and using a validated&#xD;
           questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Two weeks surgery, the patient will be presented with pictures of various objects and&#xD;
           will be asked to recall which of them were presented before and during surgery. In&#xD;
           addition the patient will be requested to fill grade his VAS anxiety scale and the IOWA&#xD;
           questionnaire.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>blinded: The participant , the neurologist, the neurophysiologist and neuropsychologist treating the participant will be blinded to the randomization arm. The neurosurgeon and anesthesiologist assigned to the patient will be unblinded to the randomization arm</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Electrophysiological recordings MER, Local field potentials and multiunit activity</measure>
    <time_frame>During surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Efficacy of Ketamine for use of the second stage of DBS surgery</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Side effects from ketamine use</measure>
    <time_frame>During surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Example : hypertension resulting following ketamine use.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The participants neurological status</measure>
    <time_frame>During surgery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patients satisfaction levels measured using owa Satisfaction with Anesthesia Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to two weeks postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Overall participant satisfaction</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Deep Brain Stimulation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ketamine arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treatment arm consisting of patients randomized to receive a low dose of ketamine for the second stage of DBS surgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control arm consisting of patients randomized to receive sham control of saline during the second stage of DBS surgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ketamine</intervention_name>
    <description>Ketamine will be given for the second stage of the DBS surgery.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ketamine arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Saline</intervention_name>
    <description>Saline will be given for the second stage of the DBS surgery.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients aged 18 and above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with history of Parkinson's disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing deep brain stimulation surgery on subthalamic nucleus from the&#xD;
             neurology and the neurosurgery at Beilinson hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with the ability to comply with the study requirements and undergoing&#xD;
             Patients whom fulfill all above requirements will be approached for enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who can't cooperate and fulfill study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are at increased risk for performing study related tasks&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Idit O Tamir, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rabin Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Idit Tamir, MD</last_name>
    <phone>055-6840465</phone>
    <email>iditta1@clalit.org.il</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rabin Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Petah tikva</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Idit Tamir</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Idit Tamir</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 20, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rabin Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Idit tamit</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head of DBS surgery unit</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ketamine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

