<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04718805</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CR108955</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>TMC114IFD1004</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04718805</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Darunavir in the Presence of Cobicistat When Administered as a Fixed Dose Combination Under Fed Conditions</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Single-dose, Open-label, Randomized, Crossover Pivotal Bioequivalence Study in Healthy Participants to Assess the Bioequivalence of Darunavir 675 mg in the Presence of 150 mg Cobicistat When Administered as a Fixed Dose Combination (Darunavir/Cobicistat) Compared to the Co-administration of the Separate Agents (Darunavir and Cobicistat) Under Fed Conditions</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the single-dose Pharmacokinetic (PK) and&#xD;
      bioequivalence of darunavir (DRV) in the presence of cobicistat (COBI) when administered as a&#xD;
      scored fixed dose combination (FDC) tablet (DRV/COBI) compared to the co-administration as&#xD;
      the separate available tablet formulations (DRV and COBI), under fed conditions in healthy&#xD;
      participants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Observed Analyte Concentration (Cmax) of Darunavir (DRV)</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, up to 72 hours post dose (up to Day 4)</time_frame>
    <description>Cmax is defined as the maximum observed analyte concentration of DRV.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Analyte Concentration-time Curve from time Zero to Last Quantifiable time (AUC[0-last]) of DRV</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, up to 72 hours post dose (up to Day 4)</time_frame>
    <description>AUC(0-last) is the area under the analyte concentration-time curve from time zero to the time of the last measurable (non-below quantification limit [non-BQL]) concentration, calculated by linear-linear trapezoidal summation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Analyte Concentration-time Curve from Time Zero to Infinite Time (AUC[0-infinity]) of DRV</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, up to 72 hours post dose (up to Day 4)</time_frame>
    <description>AUC (0-infinity) is the area under the analyte concentration-time curve from time zero to infinite time, calculated as the sum of AUC(0-last) and C(last)/lambda(z), wherein AUC(0-last) is area under the analyte concentration-time curve from time zero to last quantifiable time, Clast is the last observed measurable (non-BQL) concentration, and lambda(z) is elimination rate constant.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Adverse Events (AEs) as a Measure of Safety and Tolerability</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant participating in a clinical study that does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the pharmaceutical/biological agent under study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax of Cobicistat (COBI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, up to 72 hours post dose (up to Day 4)</time_frame>
    <description>Cmax is defined as the maximum observed analyte concentration of COBI.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Analyte Concentration-time Curve from time Zero to Last Quantifiable time (AUC[0-last]) of COBI</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, up to 72 hours post dose (up to Day 4)</time_frame>
    <description>AUC(0-last) is the area under the analyte concentration-time curve from time zero to the time of the last measurable (non-BQL) concentration, calculated by linear-linear trapezoidal summation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Analyte Concentration-time Curve from Time Zero to Infinite Time (AUC[0-infinity]) of COBI</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, up to 72 hours post dose (up to Day 4)</time_frame>
    <description>AUC (0-infinity) is the area under the analyte concentration-time curve from time zero to infinite time, calculated as the sum of AUC(0-last) and C(last)/lambda(z), wherein AUC(0-last) is area under the analyte concentration-time curve from time zero to last quantifiable time, Clast is the last observed measurable (non-BQL) concentration, and lambda(z) is elimination rate constant.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">22</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive Treatment A (a single dose of darunavir [DRV]/cobicistat [COBI] as one fixed dose combination [FDC] tablet under fed condition on Day 1) as per assigned treatment sequence (Treatment sequence AB or BA). A washout period of at least 7 days will be maintained between each treatment period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive Treatment B (a single dose of DRV/COBI as separate tablets under fed condition on Day 1) as per assigned treatment sequence (Treatment sequence BA or AB). A washout period of at least 7 days will be maintained between each treatment period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Darunavir</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive a single dose of Darunavir tablets orally as per assigned treatment sequence.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment B</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>TMC114</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cobicistat</intervention_name>
    <description>Participant will receive a single dose of Cobicistat tablets orally as per assigned treatment sequence.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment B</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>JNJ-48763364</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Darunavir/Cobicistat FDC</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive a single dose of darunavir and cobicistat FDC tablets orally as per assigned treatment sequence.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment A</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI) between 18.5 and 30.0 kilograms per meter square (kg/m^2)&#xD;
             inclusive, and body weight not less than 50.0 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be healthy on the basis of physical examination, medical history, vital signs,&#xD;
             and 12-lead electrocardiogram (ECG) performed at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be healthy on the basis of clinical laboratory tests performed at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-postmenopausal women must have a negative highly sensitive serum beta-human&#xD;
             chorionic gonadotropin (beta- hCG) 4 days or less before dosing of the first treatment&#xD;
             period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A woman must agree not to donate eggs (ova, oocytes) for the purposes of assisted&#xD;
             reproduction during the study and for at least 90 days after receiving the last dose&#xD;
             of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraceptive use by men or women should be consistent with local regulations&#xD;
             regarding the use of contraceptive methods for participants participating in clinical&#xD;
             studies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be willing and able to adhere to the prohibitions and restrictions specified in&#xD;
             this protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  During the study and for a minimum of at least 90 days after receiving the last dose&#xD;
             of study drug, a male participant: must wear a condom when engaging in any activity&#xD;
             that allows for passage of ejaculate to another person (male participants should also&#xD;
             be advised of the benefit for a female partner to use a highly effective method of&#xD;
             contraception as condom may break or leak), must agree not to donate sperm for the&#xD;
             purpose of reproduction&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of malignancy within 5 years before screening (exceptions are squamous&#xD;
             and basal cell carcinomas of the skin and carcinoma in situ of the cervix, or&#xD;
             malignancy, which is considered cured with minimal risk of recurrence)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received an investigational drug or used an investigational medical device within&#xD;
             60 days before the first administration of the study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of hepatitis A antibody immunoglobulin M (IgM), hepatitis B surface&#xD;
             antigen (HBsAg) or hepatitis C virus antibody (anti-HCV) positive, or other clinically&#xD;
             active liver disease, or tests positive for hepatitis A antibody IgM, HBsAg or&#xD;
             anti-HCV at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has previously participated in more than 3 single-dose trials or a multiple-dose trial&#xD;
             with darunavir (DRV) and/or cobicistat (COBI)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has had any contact with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2)&#xD;
             positive or Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) patients within the last 2 weeks prior&#xD;
             to admission to the clinical research center&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is a woman who is pregnant, breast-feeding, or planning to become pregnant during the&#xD;
             study or within 90 days after the last dose of study drug, or a woman of childbearing&#xD;
             potential who is unwilling to use acceptable methods of contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 or type 2 (HIV-1 or HIV-2)&#xD;
             antibody positive, or tests positive for HIV at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive test for SARS-CoV-2 test participants within the last 2 weeks prior to&#xD;
             admission or during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is a man who plans to father a child while enrolled in the study or within 90 days&#xD;
             after the last dose of study drug, or who is unwilling to use acceptable methods of&#xD;
             contraception&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC Clinical Trial</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>SGS Clinical Pharmacology Unit (located in ZNA Stuivenberg)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Antwerpen</city>
        <zip>2060</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://pam.sylogent.com/cr/CR108955</url>
    <description>To learn how to participate in this trial please click here.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Darunavir</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cobicistat</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data sharing policy of the Janssen Pharmaceutical Companies of Johnson and Johnson is available at www.janssen.com/clinical- trials/transparency. As noted on this site, requests for access to the study data can be submitted through Yale Open Data Access (YODA) project site at yoda.yale.edu</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

