<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04710641</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MNA-3521-014</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04710641</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety, Tolerability and Anti-tumour Activity Study of MTL-CEBPA Plus Sorafenib</brief_title>
  <acronym>OUTREACH2</acronym>
  <official_title>An Open Label Phase 2 Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of MTL-CEBPA Administered in Combination With Sorafenib in Participants With Hepatocellular Carcinoma (HCC) and Hepatitis B or Hepatitis C Virus (OUTREACH2)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mina Alpha Limited</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mina Alpha Limited</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase II study in patients with advanced liver cancer (hepatocellular carcinoma)&#xD;
      caused by a hepatitis B and/or C infection. Participants will be dosed with a combination of&#xD;
      MTL-CEBPA (an experimental treatment) and sorafenib. The MTL-CEBPA is administered once a&#xD;
      week via intravenous infusion for three consecutive weeks followed by a week of rest (one&#xD;
      cycle). Sorafenib is taken orally from Day 8 at a dose of 400 mg twice a day. Participants&#xD;
      will receive cycles of treatment until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, withdrawal&#xD;
      of consent or death occurs.This combination of treatment was tested in a previous Phase I&#xD;
      study (OUTREACH) which showed anti-tumour activity along with a good safety and toxicity&#xD;
      profile.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      After a participant has signed the consent form (to confirm they wish to participate in the&#xD;
      study) a number of assessments (screening) will be completed to determine whether they are&#xD;
      suitable to be enrolled in the study. The first dose of experimental drug (MTL-CEBPA) will be&#xD;
      given via infusion on the first day (Day 1) of the study. It will subsequently be&#xD;
      administered to participants once a week for the first 3 weeks in each cycle (the fourth week&#xD;
      is a rest week; each cycle consists of 4 weeks). Sorafenib (a drug which is already used to&#xD;
      treat liver cancer) will be started on the eighth day of the study (tablets) and taken daily&#xD;
      whilst the participant is in the study. If the participant is tolerating the combination of&#xD;
      drugs and there is no evidence that the cancer is advancing they will continue to receive&#xD;
      cycles (28 days in length) of treatment (being administered both MTL-CEBPA and sorafenib).&#xD;
      All participants will have contrast-enhanced CT scans (form of X-ray) of the chest, abdomen&#xD;
      and pelvis at the beginning of the study and then every 8 weeks whilst in the study.&#xD;
      Assessments will be completed throughout the study to ensure the combination of drugs is&#xD;
      safe. These will include recording any adverse events (untoward medical occurrences), vital&#xD;
      signs (such as blood pressure, pulse, body temperature, and breathing rates), ECG, and&#xD;
      completing blood tests. Blood samples, analysed in both local (hospital) and central&#xD;
      laboratories (ie, facilities independent of hospital labs)will be taken throughout the study&#xD;
      but less frequently from Cycle 2 onwards. The maximum amount of blood taken in any 28-day&#xD;
      treatment cycle is approximately 150 mL. A patient questionnaire will be used to assess&#xD;
      changes in health-related quality of life for participants. The questionnaire will be used&#xD;
      for all participants in the study and will be completed every 3 weeks. All participants must&#xD;
      agree to undergo a liver tumour biopsy prior to being administered with the study treatment.&#xD;
      A post treatment biopsy of the tumour area one day after the last MTL-CEBPA administration of&#xD;
      week 3 (Cycle 2) is mandated for all participants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>All patients will receive both the experimental drug, MTL-CEBPA, and sorafenib tablets</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dose of MTL-CEBPA to study completion, an average of one year</time_frame>
    <description>Any new medical event</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-tumour activity</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline CT scan until end of documented progression or date of death from any cause assessed up o 100 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline CT scan using the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumours (RECIST) guideline V1.1 modified RECIST (mRECIST)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma concentration of the study drug MTL-CEBPA when co-administered with sorafenib</measure>
    <time_frame>Blood samples will be collected during Cycle 1 (4 weeks duration)</time_frame>
    <description>Collected blood samples will be analysed to define maximum plasma concentration (Cmax) plasma concentration (Cmax) of MTL-CEBPA after intravenous administration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Hepatitis B</condition>
  <condition>Hepatitis C</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MTL-CEBPA in combination with sorafenib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intravenous infusion of MTL-CEBPA 130mg/m2 given once a week for 3 weeks followed by a rest week combined with oral sorafenib 400mg twice day commencing C1D8</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MTL-CEBPA</intervention_name>
    <description>Administered over a 4 week cycle on Day, D8 and D15</description>
    <arm_group_label>MTL-CEBPA in combination with sorafenib</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sorafenib</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral adminstration twice a day</description>
    <arm_group_label>MTL-CEBPA in combination with sorafenib</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Nexavar</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed advanced HCC with cirrhosis arising in a patient with a&#xD;
             history of - Hepatitis B and/or C&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Child-Pugh classification A&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients considered unsuitable for liver tumour resection and/or refractory to loco&#xD;
             regional therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients naïve to TKIs [including sorafenib, regorafenib, cabozantinib, and&#xD;
             lenvatinib]&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy greater than 3 months at time of recruitment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one measurable liver lesion (RECIST 1.1) with target lesion size more than 1&#xD;
             cm as measured by CT scan orMRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &gt; 60 x10 9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum albumin ≥ 28g/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ALT and AST ≤ 5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bilirubin ≤ 50 μmol /L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  WBC ≥ 2.0 x 10 9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1.5 x 10 9/L• Haemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  INR &lt; 1.5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 50 mL/min (Cockcroft &amp; Gault or equivalent according&#xD;
             to local practice at Investigator site)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative blood pregnancy test for women of childbearing potential (within 10 days&#xD;
             prior to first drug administration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For women of child-bearing potential, agreement to use highly effective contraception&#xD;
             (defined as method(s) that result in a failure rate of &lt; 1% per year) in females of&#xD;
             childbearing potential during the entire study and defined post-study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For male participants with partners of child-bearing potential agreement to use&#xD;
             barrier contraception plus an additional contraceptive method that together result in&#xD;
             a failure rate of &lt; 1% per year during the treatment period and for at least three&#xD;
             months after the last dose of MTL-CEBPA (see additional information / requirements in&#xD;
             Section 5.1.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to comply with all the requirements of the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Child-Pugh classification B and C&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients without a history hepatitis B and/or hepatitis C&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received TKI prior to the study or any other systemic therapy&#xD;
             (chemotherapy, CPI, other clinical study agents)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who received investigational drug(s) within the last 30 days prior to study&#xD;
             treatment initiation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any episode of bleeding from oesophageal varices or other uncontrolled bleeding within&#xD;
             the last 3 months prior to study treatment initiation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with history of haemorrhage or gastrointestinal perforation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known infection with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that had other malignancies in the last five years prior to screening, with&#xD;
             the exception of malignancies with a negligible risk of metastasis or death&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with central nervous system (CNS) metastasis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients presenting with a marked baseline prolongation of QT/QTc interval defined as&#xD;
             repeated demonstration of a QTc interval≥ 450ms (males) and ≥ 460ms (females) using&#xD;
             Fridericia's correction formula.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signs and symptoms of heart failure characterised as greater than New York Heart&#xD;
             Association (NYHA) Class I or other clinically significant cardiac abnormalities (such&#xD;
             as myocardial infarction) including stable abnormalities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery within the last 30 days prior to study treatment initiation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with history of organ transplantation or cardiac surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with sepsis, ineffective biliary drainage with or without cholangitis,&#xD;
             obstructive jaundice or encephalopathy at screening visit or within the last two weeks&#xD;
             prior to study treatment initiation, whichever is earlier&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of spontaneous bacterial peritonitis or renal failure, or allergic reaction&#xD;
             at screening visit or within the last two weeks prior to study treatment initiation,&#xD;
             whichever is earlier&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating women&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tim Meyer, MD</last_name>
    <phone>07879645480</phone>
    <email>t.meyer@ucl.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.minatx.com</url>
    <description>Sponsor website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>saRNA</keyword>
  <keyword>MTL-CEBPA</keyword>
  <keyword>Sorafenib</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

