<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04710849</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PUTH-COPD001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04710849</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Relationship Between Plasma Metabolome and the Efficacy of Systemic Glucocorticoid in AECOPD</brief_title>
  <official_title>Relationship Between Plasma Metabolome and the Efficacy of Systemic Glucocorticoid in Acute Exacerbation of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Peking University Third Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Peking University Third Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (AECOPD) significantly increases&#xD;
      the mortality of the patients with COPD. Guidelines have recommended systemic glucocorticoid&#xD;
      as regular treatment. Recently, evidences have shown that systemic glucocorticoid cannot not&#xD;
      be benefit to all of the patients with AECOPD. Thus the problem that how the clinicians can&#xD;
      screen the patients who can benefit from systemic glucocorticoid needs to be solved urgently.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (AECOPD) significantly increases&#xD;
      the mortality of the patients with COPD. Guidelines have recommended systemic glucocorticoid&#xD;
      as regular treatment. Recently, evidences have shown that systemic glucocorticoid cannot not&#xD;
      be benefit to all of the patients with AECOPD. Thus the problem that how the clinicians can&#xD;
      screen the patients who can benefit from systemic glucocorticoid needs to be solved urgently.&#xD;
      A previous study found that plasma metabolome changed significantly after dexamethasone&#xD;
      treatment in health participants. Furthermore, inter-person variability was high and remained&#xD;
      uninfluenced by treatment, suggesting the potential of metabolomics for predicting the&#xD;
      efficacy and side effects of systemic glucocorticoid. Our previous study found that serum&#xD;
      metabolites profile in COPD patients differed from that in controls. Therefore, the&#xD;
      investigators hypothesized that metabolome changes in patients with AECOPD may be associated&#xD;
      with the efficacy of systemic glucocorticoid. In this study, the investigators will utilize&#xD;
      ultraperformance liquid chromatography / mass spectrometry (LC-MS) and gas chromatography /&#xD;
      mass spectrometry (GC-MS) methods for analysis of the metabolites in AECOPD patients and&#xD;
      compare the metabolites profiles between patients with systemic glucocorticoid treatment&#xD;
      success and treatment failure. The investigators aim to detect the metabolic biomarkers and&#xD;
      metabolic pathways which are related to efficacy of systemic glucocorticoid and contribute to&#xD;
      the precise treatment of COPD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Year</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Metabolic markers related to systemic glucocorticoid therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Through metabolomics research methods such as liquid chromatography-mass spectrometry and gas chromatography-mass spectrometry, study the metabolic marker group profile of patients with acute exacerbation of COPD before receiving systemic glucocorticoid therapy, and look for possible systemic metabolic markers related to the short-term and long-term effects of glucocorticoids.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The time interval from admission to discharge of the patient this time</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time from discharge to the next exacerbation</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The time interval from the patient's discharge from the hospital to the next acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Side effects of glucocorticoid therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Any side effects related to glucocorticoid therapy, including osteoporosis, hyperglycemia, infection, etc.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality within 1 year</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The mortality rate of the patients within 1 year after enrollment, including overall mortality and COPD-related mortality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acute exacerbation frequency</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The number of acute exacerbations of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease in the one year follow-up after enrollment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>mMRC score</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate the severity of dyspnea through a modified version of the British Medical Research Council Respiratory Questionnaire (mMRC)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CAT score</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate the severity of dyspnea through the COPD assessment Test questionnaire (CAT)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in pulmonary function</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Ventilation function and changes indicated by the patient's pulmonary function test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>COPD</condition>
  <condition>COPD Exacerbation Acute</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Failure Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>The diagnostic criteria of AECOPD is defined in global initiative for chronic obstructive lung disease (GOLD 2016). According to the efficacy of systemic hormone therapy during hospitalization, they were divided into treatment success group and treatment failure group. Definition of systemic glucocorticoid treatment failure during hospitalization is (Reference: Crisafulli E, Torres A, Huerta A, et al. COPD, 2016, 13(1): 82-92): The following occurs from the 2nd to the 7th day after admission Situation: ①Need to receive mechanical ventilation treatment or need to be admitted to the ICU due to illness; ②72 hours after the initial anti-infective treatment, clinical signs of infection persist and need to change antibiotic treatment; ③Death from any cause.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Success Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>The diagnostic criteria of AECOPD is defined in global initiative for chronic obstructive lung disease (GOLD 2016). According to the efficacy of systemic hormone therapy during hospitalization, they were divided into treatment success group and treatment failure group. The treatment success group was defined as not meeting any of the following conditions for failure of systemic hormone therapy during hospitalization (reference: Crisafulli E, Torres A, Huerta A, et al. COPD, 2016, 13(1): 82-92): ①Need to receive mechanical ventilation treatment or need to be admitted to the ICU due to illness; ②72 hours after the initial anti-infective treatment, clinical signs of infection persist and need to change antibiotic treatment; ③Death from any cause.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Serum metabolic markers</intervention_name>
    <description>Ultraperformance liquid chromatography / mass spectrometry (LC-MS) and gas chromatography / mass spectrometry (GC-MS) methods for analysis of the metabolites in AECOPD patients and compare the metabolites profiles between patients with systemic glucocorticoid treatment success and treatment failure.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Failure Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Success Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Metbolomics</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        A prospective study was conducted to recruit consecutive patients from January 1, 2020 to&#xD;
        January 1, 2021 who were hospitalized in the Department of Respiratory and Critical Care&#xD;
        Medicine in Peking University Third Hospital and met the diagnostic criteria of acute&#xD;
        exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (AECOPD) in Global Initiative for&#xD;
        Chronic Obstructive Lung Diseas 2016 (GOLD 2016).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who meet the diagnostic criteria for acute exacerbation of chronic&#xD;
             obstructive pulmonary disease in GOLD 2016 and require hospitalization.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bronchial asthma, bronchiectasis and other airflow obstructive diseases;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Combined with community-acquired pneumonia, hospital-acquired pneumonia or aspiration&#xD;
             pneumonia;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Combined with severe liver and kidney insufficiency;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Malignant tumor;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immune deficiency due to chemotherapy or HIV infection;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received systemic hormone therapy due to acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive&#xD;
             pulmonary disease within 1 month before this admission;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe trauma or stress, etc.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Peking University Third Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beijing</city>
        <zip>100191</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Qiu-Yu Li, MD</last_name>
      <phone>15901118991</phone>
      <email>liqiuyu19871011@foxmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Zhuo-Yu An, MD</last_name>
      <phone>15010638916</phone>
      <email>anzhuoyu@pku.edu.cn</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Peking University Third Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>li qiuyu</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Attending Doctor of Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

