<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04718454</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>equator implant attachment</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04718454</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Retention and Wear Characteristic Assessment of OT Equator Smart Box Attachment</brief_title>
  <official_title>Retention and Wear Characteristic Assessment of OT Equator Smart Box Attachment Versus Ball Attachment for Mandibular Two Implant Assisted Over Denture , In-vitro Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research aimed to evaluate the retentive power and wear of the smart box attachment use&#xD;
      with tilted two implant assisted mandibular overdenture&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Implant supported overdenture can provide better mastication force than complete denture but&#xD;
      less than the normal teeth . Most of the patient reported that implant supported overdenture&#xD;
      has many superior features over the conventional complete denture in stability and retention&#xD;
      Key factors related to successful treatment with overdentures include the number, location,&#xD;
      and distribution of implants and choice of abutment. While the use of parallel implants that&#xD;
      are widely distributed is generally desirable for optimal treatment, patients often present&#xD;
      with challenging anatomical features, insufficient bone volume in all dimensions, and/or&#xD;
      critical anatomy that precludes ideal placement of dental implants. Some clinicians may&#xD;
      consider the ideal placement of implants for overdentures as parallel to each other and&#xD;
      perpendicular to the occlusal plane of the denture Anatomical features associated with&#xD;
      mandibular or maxillary edentulous ridges can range from straight or rounded to irregular and&#xD;
      sharp ridges, and variability in bone width may limit potential implant sites for&#xD;
      overdentures. Factors such as narrow bone volume, the inferior alveolar nerve being anterior&#xD;
      or superior positioned, extensive bony undercuts, the inferior portion of the maxillary&#xD;
      sinus, proximity to high-risk vascular structures, or a patient's desire to avoid additional&#xD;
      surgical procedures may prompt a clinician to angulate a dental implant, which could result&#xD;
      in the positioning of implants in non-ideal configurations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Excessive angulation, increased maintenance and wear of inserts, and difficulty maintaining&#xD;
      hygiene. Increased angulation may result in greater challenges to inserting and removing the&#xD;
      prosthesis, which can become difficult for patients who are older and/or have limited&#xD;
      dexterity. This challenge also can make it hard for patients to properly clean the inside of&#xD;
      the retentive portion of the stud-style abutment and may increase wear of the retentive&#xD;
      inserts Resilient Ball attachment most commonly used Ball attachment the simplest of all stud&#xD;
      attachments which widely used because it is practical, effective, relatively low cost, less&#xD;
      technique sensitive, ease of handling, minimal chair side time requirements and their&#xD;
      possible applications with both root and implant-supported prostheses so it is used with&#xD;
      non-splinted implants in clinical studies, it has been shown that changes in the retention of&#xD;
      the prostheses occurred frequently. Both decrease and considerable increase in retention&#xD;
      occurred as a result of attachment abrasion and micro movements during the mastication&#xD;
      process The ball attachments showed only a few minor, easy manageable complications. Four out&#xD;
      of 36 attachments gave reason for treatment. Two matrices loosened out of the mandibular&#xD;
      denture and had to be fastened by adding acrylic resin after 1 and 4 weeks of loading. One&#xD;
      patrix part of the ball attachment unsettled after 2 days of loading and was refastened. One&#xD;
      ball attachment matrix lost its retention capacity and had to be reactivated after a period&#xD;
      of 2 weeks. All these complications occurred in subjects where the implants were not&#xD;
      perfectly parallel to each other positioned in the mandible. The loading conditions of these&#xD;
      attachments were therefore not as favorable as for more parallel inserted implants A lack of&#xD;
      parallelism of the implants creates considerable wear of the rubber rings in a relatively&#xD;
      short time span.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rhein 83, Italy, also has developed Smart Box, which could be used with the OT Equator in&#xD;
      patients of extreme divergencies among the implants. The Smart Box has an inner tilting&#xD;
      mechanism that enables a passive insertion with divergent implants up to 50 degrees(159).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Retention</measure>
    <time_frame>6 month</time_frame>
    <description>Retention of OT equator smart box attachment versus ball attachment for mandibular two implant assisted over denture</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>wear evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>6 month</time_frame>
    <description>wear evaluation of OT equator smart box attachment versus ball attachment for</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Implant Breakage</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Equator attachment</arm_group_label>
    <description>Implant installation over epoxy resin model at the canine area on both sides following the surgical protocol of the implant placement,Equator Attachment fabrication is firmly screwed to the fixture on both sides at the canine region</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ball attachment</arm_group_label>
    <description>Implant installation over epoxy resin model at the canine area on both sides following the surgical protocol of the implant placement,ball Attachment fabrication is firmly screwed to the fixture on both sides at the canine region</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>dental attachment</intervention_name>
    <description>This research aimed to evaluate the retentive power and wear of the smart box attachment use with tilted two implant assisted mandibular overdenture</description>
    <arm_group_label>Equator attachment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ball attachment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        10 mandibular edentolous casts&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mandibular cast&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Doaa A Heshmat, lecturer</last_name>
    <phone>01006455491</phone>
    <email>doaa.heshmat@dentistry.cu.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ahmad R, Abu-Hassan MI, Chen J, Li Q, Swain MV. The Relationship of Mandibular Morphology with Residual Ridge Resorption Associated with Implant-Retained Overdentures. Int J Prosthodont. 2016 Nov/Dec;29(6):573-580. doi: 10.11607/ijp.4726.</citation>
    <PMID>27824977</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 21, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Doaa Amr Heshmat</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>lecturer od prosthodontic dep,</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>dental attachment</keyword>
  <keyword>overdenture</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

