<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04715945</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>276/97</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04715945</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Southampton Women's Survey</brief_title>
  <acronym>SWS</acronym>
  <official_title>Southampton Women's Survey - a Study of Non-pregnant Women and Follow-up of Offspring Through Pregnancy and Childhood</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Southampton</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Southampton</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The Southampton Women's Survey was established to assess the influence of factors operating&#xD;
      before conception and during pregnancy on the health and development of the offspring. 12,583&#xD;
      non-pregnant young women were recruited, and 3,158 were followed through pregnancy, with&#xD;
      their offspring followed-up at 6 months and 1, 2, 3, 4, 6-7, 8-9 and 12-13 years. The 17-19&#xD;
      year follow-up has been piloted and is about to start.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Southampton Women's Survey (SWS) was established to assess the influence of factors&#xD;
      operating before conception and during pregnancy on the health and development of the&#xD;
      offspring. 12,583 non-pregnant young women were recruited and the subsequent offspring of&#xD;
      3158 of them are being followed-up. Few other longitudinal studies of children have data on&#xD;
      the tempo of prenatal growth, and none in high-income countries has information recorded&#xD;
      before pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objectives of the SWS are: (a) to characterise the influences of a mother's own fetal&#xD;
      growth and of her dietary balance, body composition and endocrine profile before and during&#xD;
      pregnancy on (i) the early trajectory of fetal growth; (ii) the maintenance of this growth&#xD;
      trajectory in late gestation; and (iii) placental and fetal adaptive responses, (b) to&#xD;
      examine how maternal and intrauterine influences interact with the offspring's genes and&#xD;
      postnatal environment to determine: (i) weight gain and linear catch-up growth in infancy;&#xD;
      (ii) the pathways of growth and development during childhood that lead to poor adult health&#xD;
      (obesity, obstructive airways disease, cardiovascular disease, diabetes, and osteoporosis).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Between 1998 and 2002, 12,583 women aged 20 to 34 years were interviewed and their diet, body&#xD;
      composition, physical activity levels, lifestyles and social circumstances were assessed.&#xD;
      Blood, urine and mouthwash samples were collected for genetic and other analyses. Women who&#xD;
      subsequently became pregnant were followed-up at 11, 19 and 34 weeks' gestation and fetal&#xD;
      ultrasound scans were performed to obtain longitudinal measurements of fetal growth during&#xD;
      pregnancy. Between 1998 and 2007, 3,158 women delivered a single live born infant. Biological&#xD;
      samples were taken and anthropometric measurements of the baby were made within 48 hours of&#xD;
      birth. In a sample of 1,000 children, dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) was performed in&#xD;
      the first two weeks of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The children were followed up at ages 6, 12, 24 and 36 months. A variety of assessments were&#xD;
      made at the different follow-up interviews including breastfeeding, diet, anthropometry, and&#xD;
      illnesses. At 24 months, the social circumstances of the family were assessed and, at 36&#xD;
      months, parenting, and emotional and behavioural issues were recorded. Subsequently, samples&#xD;
      of the cohort have been seen at specific ages; at 4 years approximately 1,000 cohort&#xD;
      participants; at 6-7 years approximately 2,000, and at 8-9 years approximately 1,000. At each&#xD;
      time point from 4 years, body composition and bone indices were assessed using DXA; at 4&#xD;
      years, cognitive function was measured, at 6-7 years the focus was respiratory health and&#xD;
      cognitive function, and at 8-9 years cardiovascular structure and function. Over 1000 child&#xD;
      have been seen at age 12-13 years and the visits at 17-19 years of age have been piloted and&#xD;
      are about to start with a focus on preparation for parenthood. Furthermore, plans are being&#xD;
      developed to follow up the 12,583 women originally recruited to the SWS to assess the&#xD;
      influence of their younger adult lifestyles, body composition and hormones on their&#xD;
      transition through the menopause.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 6, 1998</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Child health and development</measure>
    <time_frame>0 - 19 years</time_frame>
    <description>Child health and development from birth to 19 years, focussing on body composition, nutrition, asthma and cardiovascular health</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">12583</enrollment>
  <condition>Child Development</condition>
  <condition>Child Obesity</condition>
  <condition>Child Behavior</condition>
  <condition>Nutritional and Metabolic Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Asthma in Children</condition>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Risk Factor</condition>
  <condition>Bone Loss</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Women</arm_group_label>
    <description>12,583 women recruited when non-pregnant</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Children</arm_group_label>
    <description>3,158 liveborn singleton offspring of women recruited to the study</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood, urine, mouth swaps, umbilical cord, cord blood, placental samples&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All non-pregnant women in the correct age group living in Southampton between 1998 and 2002&#xD;
        were eligible.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not pregnant, resident in Southampton UK.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  GP requested no contact&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Non-pregnant women</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>34 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Cyrus Cooper, FMedSci</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University of Southampton</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Inskip HM, Godfrey KM, Robinson SM, Law CM, Barker DJ, Cooper C; SWS Study Group. Cohort profile: The Southampton Women's Survey. Int J Epidemiol. 2006 Feb;35(1):42-8. Epub 2005 Sep 29.</citation>
    <PMID>16195252</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 20, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All data can be shared subject to approval of SWS oversight group and completion of confidentiality agreements.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Most data are already available and will continue to be available we hope beyond completion of the study.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Application to SWS oversight group</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>http://www.mrc.soton.ac.uk/sws/</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

