<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01444807</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GP1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01444807</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluate the Efficacy of Sorafenib in Renal Cell Carcinoma Patients After a Radical Resection of the Metastases</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Open Label, Multicenter Phase 2 Study, to Evaluate the Efficacy of Sorafenib in Patients With Advanced Renal Cell Carcinoma (RCC) After a Radical Resection of the Metastases</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fondazione IRCCS Istituto Nazionale dei Tumori, Milano</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fondazione IRCCS Istituto Nazionale dei Tumori, Milano</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of sorafenib in RCC patients underwent to&#xD;
      metastasectomy&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Advanced RCC presents poor prognosis, because its pathogenesis is not clearly understood.&#xD;
      However, up-regulation of the Ras pathway is thought to play a role.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VEGF expression could represent independent prognostic factors for survival possibly linking&#xD;
      expression of this protein with clinical outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sorafenib is a potent inhibitor of both Raf-kinase and VEGF R2 signalling The anti-tumoral&#xD;
      activity of Sorafenib was clearly demonstrated in phase III trial regarding advanced&#xD;
      pretreated RCC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgical removal of metastatic disease could potentially increase the disease control rate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Particularly in patients with a disease free interval post nephrectomy of at least 1 year,&#xD;
      with one small metastatic lesion, metastasectomy could represents an important therapeutic&#xD;
      approach.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After a radical resection of the metastatic disease is unclear if an anti-tumoral systemic&#xD;
      therapy may increase patient survival.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In summary, both the preclinical and clinical data support further evaluation of Sorafenib in&#xD;
      RCC patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrence Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>December 2011 - December 2014 (3 years)</time_frame>
    <description>Efficacy of Sorafenib compared with BSC, in RCC patients that have undergone radical resection of recurrent metastatic disease, after prior nephrectomy. The primary efficacy endpoint is Recurrence Free Survival (RFS),</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>December 2011 - December 2014 (3 years)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety Profile</measure>
    <time_frame>December 2011 - December 2014 (3 years)</time_frame>
    <description>Physical examination, vital signs, Red blood count: haemoglobin, hematocrit, platelet count, white blood cell count. WBC should include differential neutrophil, lymphocyte, monocyte, basophil and eosinophil counts. Electrolyte panel: sodium, potassium, chloride and corrected calcium.Chemistry panel: AST, ALT, bilirubin, alkaline phosphatase, uric acid, total protein, albumin, calcium, lipase, amylase, phosphate, LDH, glucose, creatinine,BUN, and bicarbonate. Coagulation panel: PT, PT-INR, PTT. Urinalysis, Adverse event</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vascular endothelial growth factors (VEGF) levels in BSC and Sorafenib arm.</measure>
    <time_frame>December 2011 - December 2014 (3 years)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">132</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Renal Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sorafenib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Active Arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Best Supportive Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Comparator</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>sorafenib</intervention_name>
    <description>sorafenib 400 mg bid</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sorafenib</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Nexavar (Bayer Health Care - Leverkusen - Germany)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with cytological or histological diagnosis of Renal Cell Carcinoma (RCC)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of residual lesions following surgical removal of metastatic disease.&#xD;
             Assessment must be performed by CT-scan or MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically proven disease free margins of resected surgical specimen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No more than three months from radical resection on metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG Performance Status of 0 or 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate bone marrow, liver and renal function as assessed by the following laboratory&#xD;
             requirements to be conducted within 7 days prior to screening:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt; 9.0 g/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;1,500/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count 100,000/ml&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin &lt; 1.5 times the upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ALT and AST &lt; 2.5 x upper limit of normal (&lt; 5 x upper limit of normal for patients&#xD;
             with liver involvement of their cancer)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alkaline phosphatase 4 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PT-INR/PTT &lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal [Patients who are being therapeutically&#xD;
             anticoagulated with an agent such as coumadin or heparin will be allowed to&#xD;
             participate provided that no prior evidence of underlying abnormality in these&#xD;
             parameters exists.] For patients on warfarin, close monitoring of at least weekly&#xD;
             evaluations will be performed, until INR is stable based on a measurement at pre-dose,&#xD;
             as defined by the local standard of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine &lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Amylase and lipase &lt;1.5 X upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent must be obtained prior to any study specific procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior systemic treatment for metastatic RCC. It is allowed an adjuvant or neoadjuvant&#xD;
             therapy before or after nephrectomy if stopped at least 6 months before the resection&#xD;
             of metastatic lesion/s.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cardiac disease: congestive heart failure &gt;NYHA class 2; active CAD (MI&#xD;
             more than 6 mo prior to study entry is allowed); cardiac arrhythmias requiring&#xD;
             anti-arrhythmic therapy (beta blockers or digoxin are permitted) or uncontrolled&#xD;
             hypertension (&gt;= 160 mmHg systolic and/or 90 mmHg diastolic).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of HIV infection or chronic hepatitis B or C&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active clinically serious infections (&gt; grade 2 NCI-CTC version 3.0)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptomatic metastatic brain or meningeal tumors unless the patient is &gt; 6 months from&#xD;
             definitive therapy, has a negative imaging study within 4 weeks of study entry and is&#xD;
             clinically stable with respect to the tumor at the time of study entry. Also the&#xD;
             patient must not be undergoing acute steroid therapy or taper (chronic steroid therapy&#xD;
             is acceptable provided that the dose is stable for one month prior to and following&#xD;
             screening radiographic studies)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with seizure disorder requiring medication (such as steroids or&#xD;
             anti-epileptics)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of organ allograft&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with evidence or history of bleeding diathesis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing renal dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of other disease, metabolic dysfunction, physical examination finding or&#xD;
             clinical laboratory finding giving reasonable suspicion of a disease condition that&#xD;
             contraindicates use of an investigational drug or patient at high risk from treatment&#xD;
             complications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous or concurrent cancer that is distinct in primary site or histology from the&#xD;
             cancer being evaluated in this study EXCEPT cervical carcinoma in situ, treated basal&#xD;
             cell carcinoma, superficial bladder tumors (Ta, Tis &amp; T1) or any cancer curatively&#xD;
             treated &gt; 3 years prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anticancer chemotherapy or immunotherapy during the study or within 4 weeks of study&#xD;
             entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiotherapy during study or within 3 weeks of start of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery within 4 weeks of start of study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Autologous bone marrow transplant or stem cell rescue within 4 months of study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of biologic response modifiers, such as G-CSF, within 3 week of study entry.&#xD;
             (G-CSF and other hematopoietic growth factors may be used in the management of acute&#xD;
             toxicity such as febrile neutropenia when clinically indicated or at the discretion of&#xD;
             the investigator, however they may not be substituted for a required dose reduction.)&#xD;
             (Patients taking chronic erythropoietin are permitted provided no dose adjustment is&#xD;
             undertaken within 2 months prior to the study or during the study)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Investigational drug therapy outside of this trial during or within 4 weeks of study&#xD;
             entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior exposure to the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast-feeding patients. Women of childbearing potential must have a&#xD;
             negative pregnancy test performed within 7 days of the start of treatment. Both men&#xD;
             and women enrolled in this trial must use adequate barrier birth control measures&#xD;
             during the course of the trial and two weeks after the completion of trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Substance abuse, medical, psychological or social conditions that may interfere with&#xD;
             the patient's participation in the study or evaluation of the study results&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that is unstable or could jeopardize the safety of the patient and their&#xD;
             compliance in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unable to swallow oral medications&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Giuseppe Procopio, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Istituto Tumori Milano</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istituto Tumori Milano</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milan</city>
        <state>Mi</state>
        <zip>20156</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cinzia Ortega</name>
      <address>
        <city>Alba</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alessandra Bearz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aviano</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alfredo Berruti</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brescia</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Saverio Cinieri</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brindisi</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Francesco Atzori</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cagliari</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rodolfo Passalaqua</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cremona</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Francesco Di Costanzo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Firenze</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vincenzo Emanuele Chiuri</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lecce</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alessandra Mosca</name>
      <address>
        <city>Novara</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vittorio Gebbia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palermo</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Enrico Cortesi</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roma</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Francesco Cognetti</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roma</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Franco Morelli</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Giovanni Rotondo</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.istitutotumori.mi.it</url>
    <description>Web page of Istituto Tumori in Milan</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ljungberg B. The role of metastasectomy in renal cell carcinoma in the era of targeted therapy. Curr Urol Rep. 2013 Feb;14(1):19-25. doi: 10.1007/s11934-012-0293-6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23212738</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 8, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 30, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 3, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>sorafenib</keyword>
  <keyword>metastatic renal cell carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>metastasectomy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

