<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02099292</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Mainz-135</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02099292</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Rituximab and DexaBEAM as Salvage Therapy for Relapsed Lymphoma</brief_title>
  <acronym>Mz-135</acronym>
  <official_title>Eine Phase II Studie Zur Beurteilung Der Wirksamkeit Von Rituximab in Der Salvage- Und Hochdosistherapie Mit Autologer Stammzelltransplantation Bei Patienten Mit B-Zell-Non-Hodgkin-Lymphom</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Georg Hess, MD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Roche Pharma AG</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Klinikum Frankfurt Höchst</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigator prospectively evaluated the combination of Rituximab and Dexa-BEAM&#xD;
      (dexamethasone, carmustine, etoposide, cytarabine, melphalan) followed by high dose therapy&#xD;
      in patients with relapsed/refractory aggressive and indolent lymphoma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study was a prospective, open label, single arm multicenter phase II study. It was&#xD;
      approved by the ethics committees of the participating centers, and all regulatory issues and&#xD;
      the principles of GCP were followed. The study was initiated in 2002, and recruitment closed&#xD;
      in 2006. Final data analysis was performed in 3/2013. The trial had been registered at the&#xD;
      clinical trial database of the CIMT consortium The overall treatment plan in brief, eligible&#xD;
      patients were treated with two cycles of R-DexaBEAM in a 3-4 week interval, and stem cell&#xD;
      mobilization was scheduled after the second cycle. Mobilization after the first cycle was&#xD;
      allowed if the patient had received extensive prior therapy and if no evidence of&#xD;
      BM-involvement was found. HDT was scheduled within 4-8 weeks after the last R-DexaBEAM cycle&#xD;
      in patients achieving at least PR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Protocols: The applied chemotherapy protocols were as follows: The&#xD;
      salvage/mobilization-regimen consisted of R-DexaBEAM: Rituximab 375mg/m² d1, dexamethasone 24&#xD;
      mg t.i.d p.o., d 1-10; BCNU 60mg/m² i.v., d 2; etoposide 75mg/m² i.v., d 4-7; cytarabin&#xD;
      200mg/m² b.i.d i.v., d 4-7 in 2 doses; melphalan 20mg/m² i.v., d3. For high dose&#xD;
      radio/chemotherapy, two different conditioning regimens were defined in the protocol:&#xD;
      chemo-radiotherapy R-TBI/Cy consisted of Rituximab 375mg/m² i.v. d -7, -2, fractionated total&#xD;
      body irradiation with 12 Gy, d -6 to -4; and cyclophosphamide 60 mg/kgbw i.v., day -3 to -2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The chemotherapy protocol used for conditioning was R-BEAM: Rituximab 375mg/m² i.v. d -8, -2,&#xD;
      BCNU 300mg/m² i.v., d -7; cytarabin 400mg/m² b.i.d. i.v., d -6 to -3; etoposide 200mg/m² i.v.&#xD;
      b.i.d., d -6 to -3; melphalan 140mg/m² i.v., d -2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stem cell mobilization: Following mobilization chemotherapy, stem cells were collected after&#xD;
      G-CSF stimulation (5-10µg/kg bw/d, starting on day 11 after R-DexaBEAM) using standard&#xD;
      apheresis procedures, and stem cells were processed and cryopreserved according to local&#xD;
      standards. A minimum number of 2x106/kgbw CD34 positive cells were required for the conduct&#xD;
      of high dose therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Autologous stem cell transfusion: For stem cell rescue after HDT, at least 2x106/kg CD34&#xD;
      positive cells were applied. Stem cells were thawed at bedside and infused via central venous&#xD;
      catheter.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Concomitant treatments were conducted according to local standards, e.g. for antiemetic&#xD;
      prophylaxis, hydration and parenteral nutrition. At the time of trial initiation, a&#xD;
      prophylactic antibiotic treatment was recommended due to local standards, e.g. ciprofloxacin.&#xD;
      For PJP prophylaxis co-trimoxazole was mandatory until recovery to a CD4-cell count of 200/µl&#xD;
      had been reached or until day 100 post stem cell re-transfusion. In cases of symptomatic&#xD;
      CMV-reactivation, treatment with ganciclovir was recommended. In addition, maintenance of&#xD;
      immunoglobulin levels at concentrations &gt;5g/l was recommended. G-CSF support was optional&#xD;
      after salvage or high dose therapy (5µg/kgbw).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Diagnostic evaluation: Throughout the entire treatment, routine laboratory investigations&#xD;
      were performed. In addition, CMV-reactivation screening was mandatory in CMV positive&#xD;
      patients. staging procedures including CT-scans were scheduled at baseline, prior to HDT and&#xD;
      2, 6, 9, 12, 18, 24, 36 months after HDT, and thereafter as clinically indicated. Responses&#xD;
      were assessed using the criteria of Cheson et al. BM was evaluated at baseline, and&#xD;
      re-evaluation was only needed to confirm complete remission.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis The primary efficacy endpoint of the study was progression-free survival&#xD;
      (PFS), as calculated for the intent-to-treat population. Event-free survival was defined as&#xD;
      the time from the date of trial inclusion to the time of either disease progression or death&#xD;
      (irrespective of cause) or the latest follow-up without progression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary efficacy endpoints were overall response rate at day 60 post stem cell&#xD;
      re-transfusion, overall survival (time from inclusion to death, irrespective of cause),&#xD;
      safety and side effects, toxicity of high dose therapy according to Bearman score, and number&#xD;
      of CMV-reactivations. Further endpoints, which will be reported separately, were the&#xD;
      percentage of patients being negative for minimal residual disease (MRD) by either t(14;18) -&#xD;
      FL or t(11;14) - MCL PCR, time to immune reconstitution with achievement of a CD4 count of&#xD;
      200/µl.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Results for time-to-event endpoints were analysed according to Kaplan-Meier estimator, and&#xD;
      comparisons were performed with the log-rank test. P &lt;0.05 was considered statistically&#xD;
      significant. GraphPad Prism version 5.0 for Windows, (GraphPad Software, CA, USA) was used&#xD;
      for all calculations. Statistical advice was given by the Institute of Epidemiology and&#xD;
      Biometrical Statistics at the University of Mainz.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2001</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2005</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>five years follow up</time_frame>
    <description>PFS at 5 years in patients&#xD;
completing the entire protocol (PPP)&#xD;
intention to treat population (IIT)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>five years follow up</time_frame>
    <description>Overall survival at five years and median overall survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>until day 100 post hig-dose therapy (HDT) with autologous stemcell-transplantation (SCT)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients with Adverse Events; Side effects and toxicity of high dose therapy according to Bearman score; Treatment related mortality</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">103</enrollment>
  <condition>Relapsed Non-Hodgkin-Lymphoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Rituximab and DexaBEAM</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Rituximab and DexaBEAM</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rituximab and DexaBEAM</intervention_name>
    <description>combination treatment</description>
    <arm_group_label>Rituximab and DexaBEAM</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Rituxan</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age between 18 and 65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with aggressive B-cell-lymphoma:diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLBCL), mantle&#xD;
             cell lymphoma (MCL) or grade IIIB follicular lymphoma (FL) with relapse after complete&#xD;
             remission (CR) or failure to achieve CR on treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with indolent lymphoma: FL grade I-IIIA, marginal zone lymphoma (MZL) and&#xD;
             immunocytoma (IC) if relapsed or failure to achieve at least partial remission (PR) on&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CD20 positive&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  previous therapy: at least 3 cycles of anthracycline containing regimens.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group) 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  measurable disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  adequate bone marrow function (absolute neutrophil count [ANC] &gt;1500/µl; platelet&#xD;
             count &gt;100,000/µl), unless there was clear evidence of bone marrow involvement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  glomerular filtration rate &gt; 60ml/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASAT(aspartate transaminase)/ALAT(alanine aminotransferase) &lt; 2.5-fold upper limit of&#xD;
             normal (ULN) unless associated with liver infiltration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  free from other cancers for at least 5 years, with the exception of basal cell&#xD;
             carcinoma and carcinoma in situ of the uterine cervix.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  given informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (central nervous system) CNS-lymphoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatitis B or C&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  breast-feeding women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  high dose therapy or allogeneic transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  glomerular filtration rate &lt; 60ml/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASAT/ALAT &gt; 2.5-fold upper limit of normal (ULN) unless associated with liver&#xD;
             infiltration&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Georg Hess, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 21, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 25, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 28, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 25, 2014</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 25, 2014</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 28, 2014</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Georg Hess, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head Study Department of the Department of Hem / Onc</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>lymphoma</keyword>
  <keyword>high dose therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>DexaBEAM</keyword>
  <keyword>Rituximab</keyword>
  <keyword>role of alternative salvage treatment - dexaBEAM</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

