<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03217214</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017/2119</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03217214</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Investigation of Contact Based Method for Diagnosis of Cardiovascular Disease</brief_title>
  <acronym>INDICES</acronym>
  <official_title>Investigation of a Non-invasive/ Minimally Contact Based Method for Diagnosis of Cardiovascular Disease: Blockage(Stenosis) and Blood Flow</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Heart Centre Singapore</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Nanyang Technological University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Heart Centre Singapore</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In the proposed method of sensing the vital health sign related to cardiovascular diseases,&#xD;
      thermal heat transfer performance of the skin will be evaluated using a non-contact based&#xD;
      Infra-Red temperature sensor. The temperature of the skin is significantly dependent upon the&#xD;
      heat source as blood vessels (veins and capillaries) in the vicinity of the skin. However,&#xD;
      there are several locations in the human body, where arteries are also at a relatively less&#xD;
      depth from the outer skin surface (radial or ulnar arteries at the wrist and carotid artery&#xD;
      in the neck). If it is possible to track the flow of blood from the thermal performance of&#xD;
      the skin, then it could be useful in predicting various states of the human health related to&#xD;
      cardiovascular activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will undergo Existing Procedure EP- Passive Thermography PT for Phase I and Existing&#xD;
      Procedure EP- Active Thermography ATLIC/ATPC for Phase II, with Duplex Ultrasound being the&#xD;
      existing procedure that is considered as more reliable in clinical practice. Existing Passive&#xD;
      Thermography will be used to setup the baseline data for Phase I. The currently&#xD;
      under-development temperature mapping method (Active Thermography) that involves application&#xD;
      of cooling (either pulsed or lock-in cooling) over the skin will be utilized for Phase II.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      HYPOTHESIS AND OBJECTIVES In the proposed method of sensing the vital health sign related to&#xD;
      Cardiovascular diseases, thermal heat transfer performance of the skin will be evaluated&#xD;
      using a non-contact based Infrared temperature sensor. The temperature of the skin is&#xD;
      significantly dependent upon the heat source as blood vessels (veins and capillaries) in the&#xD;
      vicinity of the skin. However, there are several locations in the human body, where arteries&#xD;
      are also at a relatively less depth from the outer skin surface (radial or ulnar arteries at&#xD;
      the wrist and carotid artery in the neck). In any scenario, if it is possible to track the&#xD;
      flow of blood from the thermal performance of the skin, then it could be useful in predicting&#xD;
      various states of the human health related to cardiovascular activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In the proposed hypothesis, a momentarily higher heat transfer window will be created&#xD;
           using localized cooling of a small section of the skin over the superficial blood vessel&#xD;
           (minimally contact) and hence, the warming process will be tracked using a non-contact&#xD;
           and non-invasive Infrared temperature sensor. With the formation of plaques in the&#xD;
           arteries at main aorta, carotid bifurcation or anywhere in the vessel, the flow turns&#xD;
           into chaotic turbulent kind or in the case of blockage a very low or no blood flow,&#xD;
           which impacts the heat transfer from the blood flow and can be easily detected from the&#xD;
           heat transfer over the skin during that momentarily higher heaty transfer window.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In order to apply this approach to Cardiovascular diseases diagnosis one of the probable&#xD;
           method could be scanning temperature change at two locations of the body:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. On both carotid artery on left and right of the neck.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. On both superficial temporal artery on the left and right of the forehead.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. It is expected that skin thermal variation at the forearm will always be in a&#xD;
                relation to the blood flow in carotid artery for a healthy person that could be&#xD;
                used as a signature marker for an individual to make comparison. Therefore,&#xD;
                temperature mapping of the left forearm (upper limb).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study involves 3 different techniques to be tested on 100 human subjects. Existing&#xD;
      procedure to be used will be readily available Duplex Ultrasound that is considered as more&#xD;
      reliable in clinical practice. Since the new technology involves temperature mapping,&#xD;
      existing potential thermography technique (Passive Thermography) will be used to setup the&#xD;
      baseline data. Other than this, currently under-development temperature mapping method&#xD;
      (Active Thermography) that involves application of cooling (either pulsed or lock-in cooling)&#xD;
      over the skin will be utilized. Accordingly, the whole study is divided into two parts:&#xD;
      phase-1 and phase-2 as shown in Figure 2. By the time, the Active Thermography technique will&#xD;
      be developed; data collection with the techniques mentioned in phase-1 will be completed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase-1&#xD;
&#xD;
      Existing Technology: Duplex Ultrasound exam will be done on all the subjects to divide them&#xD;
      into two groups as healthy and diseased.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Passive Thermography (PT): The study procedures involve taking 2 thermoscans of the following&#xD;
      parts:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Both carotid artery on left and right of the neck.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Both superficial temporal artery on the left and right of the forehead.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Left forearm (upper limb).&#xD;
&#xD;
      No relaxation time will be given between any of the two tests. Each thermoscanning of&#xD;
      individual regions of measurement (ROM) will take around 60 seconds. The complete procedure&#xD;
      will take around 10-15 minutes of time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase-2&#xD;
&#xD;
      Existing Technology: Duplex Ultrasound exam will be done on all the subjects to divide them&#xD;
      into two groups as healthy and diseased.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Active Thermography (AT): For this case, temperature mapping over both carotid arteries will&#xD;
      be done with the application of maximum cooling (within comfort limit) for 45-60 seconds&#xD;
      either in pulsed or lock-in manner. While pulsed mode is the continuous application of&#xD;
      cooling, lock-in cooling will be intermittent. The frequency of application of cooling under&#xD;
      lock-in cooling method is yet to be decided. However, for both the methods, maximum cooling&#xD;
      time will remain fixed as 45-60 seconds. The final cooling method to be used is yet to be&#xD;
      decided. Cooling will be done either through a cooling pad or using a cold air blower. The&#xD;
      temperature of the cooling fluid in the cooling pad and air for the blower will be maintained&#xD;
      in the range of 0oC to 5oC (provisionally), respectively. Due to application of cooling, the&#xD;
      localized skin tissue will cool down and start rewarming to attain equilibrium temperature&#xD;
      with the ambient as earlier (before application of cooling). A continuous thermoscanning will&#xD;
      be done from the instance of application of cooling to the reaching of a fixed temperature&#xD;
      (to be decided) during the rewarming. However, the maximum acquisition time after the removal&#xD;
      of cooling will be kept fixed to 180 seconds. This procedure will be done 2 times for each&#xD;
      subject on both carotid arteries. The relaxation time between every procedure will be 10&#xD;
      minutes. A warming pad or hot air blower will be used after every run of the test so as to&#xD;
      quickly bring the skin temperature to normal. Temperature of the hot fluid in the warming pad&#xD;
      or warm air through blower will be kept slightly higher than room temperature but less than&#xD;
      body core temperature (provisionally in the range of 25oC to 35 oC). The total time for the&#xD;
      complete procedure would be around 60 min.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Taking all the standard clinical procedure care, there is no risk of any adverse condition as&#xD;
      the whole process of data collection is completely non-invasive and minimally contact (only&#xD;
      for phase-2 study).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 19, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 30, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 30, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Skin thermal variation</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Flow of blood from thermal performance of the skin can be tracked</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">67</enrollment>
  <condition>Carotid Artery Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>EP-PT</arm_group_label>
    <description>Existing Procedure EP- Passive Thermography PT (40 patients)&#xD;
Passive Thermography (PT): 2 thermoscans of the following parts:&#xD;
Both carotid artery on left and right of the neck.&#xD;
Both superficial temporal artery on the left and right of forehead.&#xD;
Left forearm. No relaxation time will be given between the two tests. Each thermoscanning of region will take 60 seconds. The complete procedure will take 10-15 minutes of time.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>EP-ATLIC/ATPC</arm_group_label>
    <description>Existing Procedure EP- Active Thermography ATLIC/ATPC (60 patients)&#xD;
Active Thermography (AT): Temperature mapping over both carotid arteries will be done with the application of maximum cooling for 45-60 seconds in pulsed or lock-in manner. Pulsed mode is continuous, lock-in cooling will be intermittent. Maximum cooling time is 45-60 seconds, using a cooling pad/ cold air blower. Continuous thermoscanning will be done from the instance of application of cooling to reaching of a fixed temperature during rewarming. Procedure will be done 2 times per subject on both carotid arteries. Relaxation time between procedures is 10 minutes. A warming pad/ hot air blower will be used after the test to bring the skin temperature to normal. The complete procedure will take 60 min.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Thermography</intervention_name>
    <description>Passive thermography for Phase I subjects and Active Thermography for Phase II subjects</description>
    <arm_group_label>EP-ATLIC/ATPC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>EP-PT</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with clinical indication for Duplex Carotid Ultrasound for arterial stenosis&#xD;
        detection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Aged between 35 - 70&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Planned for Duplex carotid artery duplex scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Ability to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Known significant stenosis / disease in subclavian artery&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known multiple stenoses or occlusion in cerebral (carotid / vertebral / intracranial )&#xD;
             circulation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>A/Prof Lim Soo Teik, MBBS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Heart Centre Singapore</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Heart Centre Singapore</name>
      <address>
        <city>Singapore</city>
        <zip>169609</zip>
        <country>Singapore</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Singapore</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 11, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 11, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 14, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carotid Artery Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

