<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03210662</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017-0341</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2018-01123</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2017-0341</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03210662</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pembrolizumab and External Beam Radiation Therapy in Treating Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Study of Pembrolizumab and Fractionated External Beam Radiotherapy in Patients With Relapsed and Refractory Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase II trial studies how well pembrolizumab and external beam radiation therapy work&#xD;
      in treating patients with non-Hodgkin lymphoma that has come back (relapsed) or does not&#xD;
      respond to treatment (refractory). Immunotherapy with monoclonal antibodies, such as&#xD;
      pembrolizumab, may help the body's immune system attack the cancer, and may interfere with&#xD;
      the ability of tumor cells to grow and spread. Giving pembrolizumab and external beam&#xD;
      radiation therapy may work better in treating patients with non-Hodgkin lymphoma than&#xD;
      pembrolizumab alone.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine the overall response rate (ORR) of pembrolizumab with concurrent fractionated&#xD;
      external beam radiotherapy (EBRT) among patients with relapsed and refractory non-Hodgkin&#xD;
      lymphoma (NHL).&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine the safety of pembrolizumab with fractionated EBRT in patients with relapsed&#xD;
      and refractory NHL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To determine the overall response rate and complete response rate (CRR) of irradiated and&#xD;
      non-irradiated lesions to treatment with concurrent pembrolizumab and fractionated EBRT in&#xD;
      patients with relapsed and refractory NHL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To determine the progression free survival (PFS) of pembrolizumab in combination with&#xD;
      fractionated EBRT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To determine the overall survival (OS) of pembrolizumab in combination with fractionated&#xD;
      EBRT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      V. To determine the duration of response of irradiated and non-irradiated lesions after&#xD;
      concurrent pembrolizumab and fractionated EBRT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To identify tumor and peripheral blood markers predictive of response to concurrent&#xD;
      pembrolizumab and low to moderate dose EBRT in the setting of relapsed and refractory NHL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To determine if a course of hypo-fractionated EBRT can improve response after progressive&#xD;
      disease among patients treated with fractionated EBRT and pembrolizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Beginning on day 1, patients undergo fractionated EBRT daily for 5 consecutive days a week&#xD;
      for up to 12 or 22 treatments. Patients also receive pembrolizumab intravenously (IV) over 1&#xD;
      hour on day 2. Treatment with pembrolizumab repeats every 21 days for up to 35 cycles in the&#xD;
      absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 30 days, every 3 months for&#xD;
      1 year and then every 6 months thereafter.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 19, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 19, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate of an unirradiated lesion to pembrolizumab with external beam radiation therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>At 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Response rate and its 95% confidence interval will be estimated for each patient cohort separately. The overall response (OR: complete response + partial response) of non-irradiated lesion(s) at three months and dose limiting toxicity (DLT) at one course (3 weeks) will be monitored simultaneously using the Bayesian stopping boundaries calculated based on beta-binomial distributions. Independence is assumed between OR and DLT.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Disease response will be assessed via revised Lugano classification for the response assessment of Hodgkin and non-Hodgkin lymphoma.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated using the method of Kaplan and Meier. Comparison of time-to-event endpoints by important patient characteristics will be made using the log-rank test. The log-rank test will be performed to test the difference in time-to-event distributions between patient groups. Cox proportional hazards model may be used to include multiple covariates in the time-to-event analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated using the method of Kaplan and Meier. Comparison of time-to-event endpoints by important patient characteristics will be made using the log-rank test. The log-rank test will be performed to test the difference in time-to-event distributions between patient groups. Cox proportional hazards model may be used to include multiple covariates in the time-to-event analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Primary Mediastinal (Thymic) Large B-Cell Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Aggressive Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Mature T- Cell and NK-Cell Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent T-Cell Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Transformed Follicular Lymphoma to Diffuse Large B-Cell Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Aggressive Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory T-Cell Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Transformed Follicular Lymphoma to Diffuse Large B-Cell Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Transformed Marginal Zone Lymphoma to Diffuse Large B-Cell Lymphoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (EBRT, pembrolizumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Beginning on day 1, patients undergo fractionated EBRT daily for 5 consecutive days a week for up to 12 or 22 treatments. Patients also receive pembrolizumab IV over 1 hour on day 2. Treatment with pembrolizumab repeats every 21 days for up to 35 cycles in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>External Beam Radiation Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Undergo EBRT</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (EBRT, pembrolizumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Definitive Radiation Therapy</other_name>
    <other_name>EBRT</other_name>
    <other_name>External Beam Radiotherapy</other_name>
    <other_name>External Beam RT</other_name>
    <other_name>external radiation</other_name>
    <other_name>External Radiation Therapy</other_name>
    <other_name>external-beam radiation</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (EBRT, pembrolizumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Keytruda</other_name>
    <other_name>Lambrolizumab</other_name>
    <other_name>MK-3475</other_name>
    <other_name>SCH 900475</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have at least one site of lymphomatous disease amenable to external beam radiation&#xD;
             therapy (EBRT)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have pathologic confirmation of aggressive non-Hodgkin lymphoma (including diffuse&#xD;
             large B cell lymphoma, transformed follicular lymphoma, transformed marginal zone&#xD;
             lymphoma, primary mediastinal B-cell lymphoma, T cell lymphoma and NK T-cell&#xD;
             lymphoma). Patients with indolent B cell lymphoma are excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be willing and able to provide written informed consent/assent for the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have measurable disease (&gt;= 1.5 cm in the longest diameter for nodal or extranodal&#xD;
             disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have provided archival tumor tissue sample or newly obtained core or excisional biopsy&#xD;
             of a tumor lesion not previously irradiated. Formalin-fixed, paraffin embedded (FFPE)&#xD;
             tissue blocks are preferred to slides. Newly obtained biopsies are preferred to&#xD;
             archived tissue. Newly-obtained is defined as a specimen obtained up to 6 weeks (42&#xD;
             days) prior to initiation of treatment on day 1. Subjects for whom newly-obtained&#xD;
             samples cannot be provided (e.g. inaccessible or subject safety concern) may submit an&#xD;
             archived specimen. Note: If submitting unstained cut slides, newly cut slides should&#xD;
             be submitted to the testing laboratory within 14 days from the date slides are cut&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 to 1.&#xD;
             Evaluation of ECOG is to be performed within 7 days prior to the date of&#xD;
             allocation/randomization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1,000 /mcL (performed within 10 days of treatment&#xD;
             initiation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &gt;= 50,000 / mcL (performed within 10 days of treatment initiation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 8 g/dL or &gt;= 5.6 mmol/L without transfusion or erythropoietin (EPO)&#xD;
             dependency (within 7 days of assessment) (performed within 10 days of treatment&#xD;
             initiation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine OR measured or calculated creatinine clearance (creatinine clearance&#xD;
             should be calculated per institutional standard) (glomerular filtration rate [GFR] can&#xD;
             also be used in place of creatinine or creatinine clearance [CrCl]) =&lt; 1.5 x upper&#xD;
             limit of normal (ULN) OR &gt;= 60 mL/min for subject with creatinine levels &gt; 1.5 x&#xD;
             institutional ULN (performed within 10 days of treatment initiation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x ULN OR direct bilirubin =&lt; ULN for subjects with total&#xD;
             bilirubin levels &gt; 1.5 ULN (performed within 10 days of treatment initiation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) serum glutamic-oxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT) and&#xD;
             alanine aminotransferase (ALT) serum glutamic pyruvic transaminase (SGPT) =&lt; 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
             OR =&lt; 5 x ULN for subjects with liver metastases (performed within 10 days of&#xD;
             treatment initiation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Albumin &gt;= 2.5 mg/dL (performed within 10 days of treatment initiation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  International normalized ratio (INR) or prothrombin time (PT) =&lt; 1.5 x ULN unless&#xD;
             subject is receiving anticoagulant therapy as long as PT or partial thromboplastin&#xD;
             time (PTT) is within therapeutic range of intended use of anticoagulants (performed&#xD;
             within 10 days of treatment initiation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) =&lt; 1.5 x ULN unless subject is receiving&#xD;
             anticoagulant therapy as long as PT or PTT is within therapeutic range of intended use&#xD;
             of anticoagulants (performed within 10 days of treatment initiation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subject of childbearing potential should have a negative urine or serum&#xD;
             pregnancy within 72 hours prior to receiving the first dose of study medication. If&#xD;
             the urine test is positive or cannot be confirmed as negative, a serum pregnancy test&#xD;
             will be required&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects of childbearing potential must be willing to use an adequate method of&#xD;
             contraception as outlined - contraception, for the course of the study through 120,&#xD;
             corresponding to time needed to eliminate any Merck study treatment(s) and/or any&#xD;
             active comparator/combination, plus 30 days (a menstruation cycle) for study&#xD;
             treatments with risk of genotoxicity days after the last dose of study medication.&#xD;
             Note: Abstinence is acceptable if this is the usual lifestyle and preferred&#xD;
             contraception for the subject&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has had prior radiation therapy to the potential radiation target such that additional&#xD;
             radiation therapy is considered unsafe by the treating radiation oncologist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of allogeneic stem cell transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a diagnosis of active scleroderma or lupus or any other autoimmune disease that by&#xD;
             the opinion of the treating radiation oncologist would put the patient at unacceptable&#xD;
             risk of toxicity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently participating and receiving study therapy or has participated in a study&#xD;
             of an investigational agent and received study therapy or used an investigational&#xD;
             device within 4 weeks of the first dose of treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a diagnosis of immunodeficiency or is receiving systemic steroid therapy or any&#xD;
             other form of immunosuppressive therapy within 7 days prior to the first dose of trial&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of active Bacillus tuberculosis (TB)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypersensitivity to pembrolizumab or any of its excipients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has had a prior anti-cancer monoclonal antibody (mAb) within 4 weeks prior to study&#xD;
             day 1 or who has not recovered (i.e., =&lt; grade 1 or at baseline) from adverse events&#xD;
             due to agents administered more than 4 weeks earlier&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has had prior chemotherapy, targeted small molecule therapy, or radiation therapy&#xD;
             within 2 weeks prior to study day 1 or who has not recovered (i.e., =&lt; grade 1 or at&#xD;
             baseline) from adverse events due to a previously administered agent&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Note: subjects with =&lt; grade 2 neuropathy are an exception to this criterion and&#xD;
                  may qualify for the study&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Note: if subject received major surgery, they must have recovered adequately&#xD;
                       from the toxicity and/or complications from the intervention prior to&#xD;
                       starting therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known additional malignancy that is progressing or requires active treatment&#xD;
             within the past 3 years. Exceptions include basal cell carcinoma of the skin or&#xD;
             squamous cell carcinoma of the skin that has undergone potentially curative therapy or&#xD;
             in situ cervical cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has known active central nervous system (CNS) lymphoma or lymphomatous meningitis.&#xD;
             Subjects with previously treated brain metastases may participate provided they are&#xD;
             stable (without evidence of progression by imaging for at least four weeks prior to&#xD;
             the first dose of trial treatment and any neurologic symptoms have returned to&#xD;
             baseline), have no evidence of new or enlarging brain metastases, and are not using&#xD;
             steroids for at least 7 days prior to trial treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has active autoimmune disease that has required systemic treatment in the past 2 years&#xD;
             (i.e. with use of disease modifying agents, corticosteroids or immunosuppressive&#xD;
             drugs). Replacement therapy (e.g., thyroxine, insulin, or physiologic corticosteroid&#xD;
             replacement therapy for adrenal or pituitary insufficiency, etc.) is not considered a&#xD;
             form of systemic treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has history of (non-infectious) pneumonitis that required steroids, evidence of&#xD;
             interstitial lung disease or active, non-infectious pneumonitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an active infection requiring systemic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history or current evidence of any condition, therapy, or laboratory abnormality&#xD;
             that might confound the results of the trial, interfere with the subject's&#xD;
             participation for the full duration of the trial, or is not in the best interest of&#xD;
             the subject to participate, in the opinion of the treating investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has known psychiatric or substance abuse disorders that would interfere with&#xD;
             cooperation with the requirements of the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is pregnant or breastfeeding, or expecting to conceive or father children within the&#xD;
             projected duration of the trial, starting with the pre-screening or screening visit&#xD;
             through 120 days after the last dose of trial treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A woman of child bearing potential (WOCBP) who has a positive urine pregnancy test&#xD;
             within 72 hours prior to receiving the first dose of study medication. If the urine&#xD;
             test is positive or cannot be confirmed as negative, a serum pregnancy test will be&#xD;
             required. Note: in the event that 72 hours have elapsed between the screening&#xD;
             pregnancy test and the first dose of study treatment, another pregnancy test (urine or&#xD;
             serum) must be performed and must be negative in order for subject to start receiving&#xD;
             study medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received prior therapy with an anti-PD-1, anti-PD-L1, or anti-PD-L2 agent directed&#xD;
             to another stimulatory or co-inhibitory T-cell receptor (e.g., CTLA-4, OX-40, CD137)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) (HIV 1/2 antibodies)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has known active hepatitis B (e.g., hepatitis B surface antigen [HBsAg] reactive) or&#xD;
             hepatitis C (e.g., hepatitis C virus [HCV] ribonucleic acid [RNA] [qualitative] is&#xD;
             detected)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received a live vaccine within 30 days of planned start of study therapy. Note:&#xD;
             seasonal influenza vaccines for injection are generally inactivated flu vaccines and&#xD;
             are allowed; however intranasal influenza vaccines (e.g., Flu-Mist) are live&#xD;
             attenuated vaccines, and are not allowed&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Chelsea C Pinnix</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Chelsea C. Pinnix, MD</last_name>
    <phone>713-563-2300</phone>
    <email>ccpinnix@mdanderson.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M D Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Chelsea C. Pinnix</last_name>
      <phone>713-563-2300</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Chelsea C. Pinnix</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>MD Anderson Cancer Center Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 5, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 5, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 7, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Follicular</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell, Peripheral</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Aggression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

