<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03217747</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017-0014</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2018-01118</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2017-0014</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03217747</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Avelumab, Utomilumab, Anti-OX40 Antibody PF-04518600, and Radiation Therapy in Treating Patients With Advanced Malignancies</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I/II Study to Evaluate the Safety and Tolerability of Avelumab in Combination With Other Anti-Cancer Therapies in Patients With Advanced Malignancies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I/II trial studies the side effects of avelumab when given in different&#xD;
      combinations with utomilumab, anti-OX40 antibody PF-04518600, and radiation therapy in&#xD;
      treating patients with malignancies that have spread to other places in the body.&#xD;
      Immunotherapy with monoclonal antibodies, such as avelumab, utomilumab, and anti-OX40&#xD;
      antibody PF-04518600, may help the body's immune system attack the cancer, and may interfere&#xD;
      with the ability of tumor cells to grow and spread. Radiation therapy uses high-energy rays&#xD;
      to kill tumor cells and shrink tumors. It is not yet known how well avelumab works in&#xD;
      combination with these other anti-cancer therapies in patients with advanced malignancies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. For Arms D-F, to establish the safety, tolerability, and dose-limiting toxicities (DLTs)&#xD;
      of different treatment combinations of avelumab when administered in combination with&#xD;
      checkpoint agonist(s) with or without radiation in patients with metastatic solid tumors in&#xD;
      order to estimate the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and select the recommended phase 2 dose&#xD;
      (RP2D).&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To correlate pre- and post-treatment CD8 expression with clinical benefit (complete&#xD;
      response [CR], partial response [PR], or stable disease [SD] for &gt; 6 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate the efficacy of the different treatment combinations in patients with&#xD;
      metastatic solid tumors by assessing objective response rate (ORR) per Response Evaluation&#xD;
      Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1 and immune-related RECIST (irRECIST).&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To evaluate the efficacy of the different treatment combinations in patients with&#xD;
      metastatic solid tumors by assessing progression-free survival (PFS), duration of response&#xD;
      (DOR), and overall survival (OS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To understand the mechanism of action of the avelumab plus an immune modulator&#xD;
      combination, as well as potential mechanisms of resistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To characterize the effect of avelumab combinations on immune biomarkers in peripheral&#xD;
      blood and tumor tissue obtained from subjects pre- and post-treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To compare the response in irradiated versus non-irradiated lesions in Arms D-F.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To investigate immune biomarkers that are potentially predictive of response and&#xD;
      resistance with the combination of avelumab and an immune modulator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: Patients are assigned to 1 of 6 arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM A: Patients receive utomilumab intravenously (IV) over 60 minutes on day 1 of each cycle&#xD;
      and avelumab IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 beginning day 15 of cycle 1. Cycles repeat&#xD;
      every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM B: Patients receive anti-OX40 antibody PF-04518600 IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 of&#xD;
      each cycle and avelumab IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 beginning day 15 of cycle 1.&#xD;
      Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM C: Patients receive anti-OX40 antibody PF-04518600 IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 of&#xD;
      each cycle, utomilumab over 60 minutes on day 1, and avelumab IV over 60 minutes on days 1&#xD;
      and 15 beginning day 15 of cycle 1. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease&#xD;
      progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM D: Patients undergo radiation therapy on days -14 to -1. Patients receive avelumab IV&#xD;
      over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 of beginning day 15 of cycle 1 and utomilumab IV over 60&#xD;
      minutes on day 1. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or&#xD;
      unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM E: Patients undergo radiation therapy on days -14 to -1. Patients receive avelumab IV&#xD;
      over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 beginning day 15 of cycle 1 and anti-OX40 antibody&#xD;
      PF-04518600 IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15, and. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the&#xD;
      absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM F: Patients undergo radiation therapy on days -14 to -1. Patients receive avelumab IV&#xD;
      over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 beginning day 15 of cycle 1, utomilumab IV over 60 minutes&#xD;
      on day 1, and anti-OX40 antibody PF-04518600 IV on days 1 and 15. Cycles repeat every 28 days&#xD;
      in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients will be followed up at 30 days and then every&#xD;
      12 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 2, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Will be graded per National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 4.03. Descriptive statistics will be provided on the grade and type of toxicity by dose level.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of CD8 immune biomarkers assessed in tumor and blood biospecimens</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Will be assessed per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version (v) 1.1 and immune-related RECIST (irRECIST). A 95% confidence interval of response rate will be estimated based on a binomial distribution.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>From cycle 1 start date until the earliest date of disease progression, assessed up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Will be assessed per RECIST v1.1 and irRECIST.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response</measure>
    <time_frame>From time from earliest date of disease response until the earliest date of disease progression, assessed up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Will be assessed per RECIST v1.1 and irRECIST.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>From the cycle 1 start date until death due to any cause, assessed up to 1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response data in irradiated and non-irradiated lesions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of various immune biomarkers from tumor and blood biospecimens</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">173</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Castration-Resistant Prostate Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Prostate Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Prostate Carcinoma Metastatic in the Bone</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVA Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVB Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A (utomilumab, avelumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive utomilumab IV over 60 minutes on day 1 of each cycle and avelumab IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 beginning day 15 of cycle 1. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B (PF-04518600, avelumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive anti-OX40 antibody PF-04518600 IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 of each cycle and avelumab IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 beginning day 15 of cycle 1. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C (PF-04518600, utomilumab, avelumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive anti-OX40 antibody PF-04518600 IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 of each cycle, utomilumab over 60 minutes on day 1, and avelumab IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 beginning day 15 of cycle 1. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm D (avelumab, utomilumab, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients undergo radiation therapy on days -14 to -1. Patients receive avelumab IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 of beginning day 15 of cycle 1 and utomilumab IV over 60 minutes on day 1. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm E (avelumab, PF-04518600, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients undergo radiation therapy on days -14 to -1. Patients receive avelumab IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 beginning day 15 of cycle 1 and anti-OX40 antibody PF-04518600 IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15, and. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm F (avelumab, PF-04518600, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients undergo radiation therapy on days -14 to -1. Patients receive avelumab IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15 beginning day 15 of cycle 1, utomilumab IV over 60 minutes on day 1, and anti-OX40 antibody PF-04518600 IV on days 1 and 15. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Anti-OX40 Antibody PF-04518600</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B (PF-04518600, avelumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C (PF-04518600, utomilumab, avelumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm E (avelumab, PF-04518600, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm F (avelumab, PF-04518600, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PF-04518600</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Avelumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A (utomilumab, avelumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B (PF-04518600, avelumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C (PF-04518600, utomilumab, avelumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm D (avelumab, utomilumab, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm E (avelumab, PF-04518600, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm F (avelumab, PF-04518600, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Bavencio</other_name>
    <other_name>MSB-0010718C</other_name>
    <other_name>MSB0010718C</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Radiation Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Undergo radiation therapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm D (avelumab, utomilumab, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm E (avelumab, PF-04518600, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm F (avelumab, PF-04518600, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cancer Radiotherapy</other_name>
    <other_name>Irradiate</other_name>
    <other_name>Irradiated</other_name>
    <other_name>irradiation</other_name>
    <other_name>Radiation</other_name>
    <other_name>Radiotherapeutics</other_name>
    <other_name>RADIOTHERAPY</other_name>
    <other_name>RT</other_name>
    <other_name>Therapy, Radiation</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Utomilumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A (utomilumab, avelumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C (PF-04518600, utomilumab, avelumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm D (avelumab, utomilumab, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm F (avelumab, PF-04518600, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PF 05082566</other_name>
    <other_name>PF 5082566</other_name>
    <other_name>PF-05082566</other_name>
    <other_name>PF-2566</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must be refractory to, or intolerant of, established therapy known to provide&#xD;
             clinical benefit for their conditions, or where subjects refuse existing therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have measurable disease (RECIST v 1.1) or patients may have bone&#xD;
             metastatic disease evaluable by Prostate Cancer Working Group 2 (PCWG2) for subjects&#xD;
             with metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer (CRPC) or according to tumor&#xD;
             evaluation criteria best suitable and accepted for the tumor type evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &gt;= 100 x 10^9/L (For patients with hepatocellular carcinoma, platelets &gt;= 70&#xD;
             x 10^9/L).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1.5 x 10^9/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  White blood cell (WBC) &gt;= 3 x 10^9/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must be transfusion independent (i.e., no blood product transfusions for a&#xD;
             period of at least 14 days prior to cycle 1 day 1 [start of study treatment]).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alanine transaminase (ALT) =&lt; 2.5 x upper normal limit (ULN) (=&lt; 5 x ULN for subjects&#xD;
             with documented metastatic disease to the liver).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) =&lt; 2.5 x ULN (=&lt; 5 x ULN for subjects with documented&#xD;
             metastatic disease to the liver).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alkaline phosphatase &lt; 4 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x ULN (In the expansion cohort, subjects with Gilbert's&#xD;
             syndrome [hereditary indirect hyperbilirubinemia] who must have a total bilirubin of&#xD;
             =&lt; 3 x ULN).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Albumin &gt;= 3 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine =&lt; 2 x upper limit of normal (ULN) or estimated creatinine clearance&#xD;
             &gt;= 30 ml/min as calculated using the Cockcroft-Gault formula.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has recovered to grade =&lt; 1 by the National Cancer Institute Common&#xD;
             Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events, version 4.03 (NCI-CTCAE v 4.03) from the&#xD;
             effects of recent surgery, radiotherapy, chemotherapy, hormonal therapy, or other&#xD;
             targeted therapies, with the exception of alopecia. The exceptions for such effects&#xD;
             are allowed lab values of =&lt; grade 2 specified elsewhere in these inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative serum pregnancy test in women of childbearing potential within 7 days of&#xD;
             first dose of treatment and patients of child-bearing potential must agree to use&#xD;
             effective contraception during and after 90 days post dose. A woman of childbearing&#xD;
             potential is defined as a premenopausal female capable of becoming pregnant. This&#xD;
             includes women on oral, injectable or mechanical contraception; women who are single&#xD;
             and women whose male sexual partners have been vasectomized or whose male sexual&#xD;
             partners have received or are utilizing mechanical contraceptive devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have biopsiable disease. For Arms A, B, and C, subjects must have at&#xD;
             least two lesions amenable to biopsy and response evaluation. For Arms D, E, and F,&#xD;
             subjects should have at least three lesions amenable to biopsy, response evaluation,&#xD;
             and radiation. Tumor lesions used for biopsy should not be lesions used as RECIST&#xD;
             target lesions. However, if patients in Arms D, E, and F do not have three separate&#xD;
             lesions, patients will be eligible if there are two lesions, in which one is &gt; 2&#xD;
             centimeters (short axis) and can be used for both biopsy and response evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must give informed consent according to the rules and regulations of the&#xD;
             individual participating sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with primary central nervous system (CNS) tumor or CNS tumor involvement.&#xD;
             However, subjects with metastatic CNS tumors may participate in this study if the&#xD;
             subject is: &gt; 4 weeks from prior therapy completion (including radiation and/or&#xD;
             surgery); clinically stable with respect to the CNS tumor at the time of study entry;&#xD;
             not receiving steroid therapy in treating CNS tumor or CNS tumor involvement; not&#xD;
             receiving anti-convulsive medications (that were started for brain metastases).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery, radiation therapy or systemic anti-cancer therapy within 4 weeks of&#xD;
             study drug administration (6 weeks for mitomycin C or nitrosoureas). Palliative&#xD;
             radiotherapy to a limited field is allowed after consultation with the medical monitor&#xD;
             at any time during study participation, including during screening, unless it's&#xD;
             clearly indicative of disease progression.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with prior anti-PD-1, anti-PD-L1 treatment. For Arms A and D, subjects may&#xD;
             not have had prior 4-1BB treatment. For Arms B and E, subjects may not have had prior&#xD;
             OX40 treatment. For Arms C and F, subjects may not have had prior 4-1BB or OX40&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis or recurrence of invasive cancer other than the present cancer within 3&#xD;
             years (except basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin that has been definitively&#xD;
             treated).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant (i.e., active) cardiovascular disease: cerebral vascular&#xD;
             accident/stroke (&lt; 6 months prior to enrollment), myocardial infarction (&lt; 6 months&#xD;
             prior to enrollment), unstable angina, congestive heart failure (&gt;= New York Heart&#xD;
             Association classification class II), or serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring&#xD;
             medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection requiring systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with an investigational anti-cancer study drug within 4 weeks prior to study&#xD;
             drug administration date.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent therapy with approved or investigational anticancer therapeutics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known prior severe hypersensitivity to investigational product(s) or any component in&#xD;
             its formulations, including known severe hypersensitivity reactions to monoclonal&#xD;
             antibodies (NCI CTCAE v 4.03 grade &gt;= 3).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of immunosuppressive medication, EXCEPT for the following: a. intranasal,&#xD;
             inhaled, topical steroids, or local steroid injection (e.g., intra-articular&#xD;
             injection); b. systemic corticosteroids at physiologic doses =&lt; 10 mg/day of&#xD;
             prednisone or equivalent; c. steroids as premedication for hypersensitivity reactions&#xD;
             (e.g., computed tomography [CT] scan premedication).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active autoimmune disease that might deteriorate when receiving an immuno-stimulatory&#xD;
             agent. Patients with diabetes type I, vitiligo, psoriasis, or hypo- or hyperthyroid&#xD;
             diseases not requiring immunosuppressive treatment are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior organ transplantation including allogenic stem-cell transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of testing positive for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or known&#xD;
             acquired immunodeficiency syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatitis B virus (HBV) or hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection at screening (positive&#xD;
             HBV surface antigen or HCV ribonucleic acid (RNA) if anti-HCV antibody screening test&#xD;
             positive).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vaccination (live attenuated virus) within 4 weeks of the first dose of avelumab and&#xD;
             while on trials is prohibited except for administration of inactivated vaccines.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persisting toxicity related to prior therapy (NCI CTCAE v. 4.03 Grade &gt; 1); however,&#xD;
             alopecia, sensory neuropathy grade =&lt; 2, or other grade =&lt; 2 not constituting a safety&#xD;
             risk based on investigator's judgment are acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other severe acute or chronic medical conditions including colitis, inflammatory bowel&#xD;
             disease, pneumonitis, pulmonary fibrosis or psychiatric conditions including recent&#xD;
             (within the past year) or active suicidal ideation or behavior; or laboratory&#xD;
             abnormalities that may increase the risk associated with study participation or study&#xD;
             treatment administration or may interfere with the interpretation of study results&#xD;
             and, in the judgment of the investigator, would make the patient inappropriate for&#xD;
             entry into this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical, psychological or social conditions that may interfere with the patient's&#xD;
             participation in the study or evaluation of the study results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or lactation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men whose partner is a woman of child-bearing potential, (i.e. biologically able to&#xD;
             conceive), and who is not employing two forms of highly effective contraception.&#xD;
             Highly effective contraception (e.g. male condom with spermicide, diaphragm with&#xD;
             spermicide, intra-uterine device) must be used by both sexes during the study and must&#xD;
             be continued for 90 days after the end of study treatment. Women of child-bearing&#xD;
             potential is defined as sexually mature women who are not surgically sterile or who&#xD;
             have not been naturally postmenopausal for at least 12 consecutive months (e.g., who&#xD;
             has had menses any time in the preceding 12 consecutive months).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A diagnosis of active scleroderma, lupus, or other rheumatologic disease which in the&#xD;
             opinion of the treating radiation oncologist precludes safe radiation therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has had prior radiation therapy within the past 3 months where the high dose area of&#xD;
             the prior radiation would overlap with the high dose area of the intended radiation&#xD;
             based on the judgement of the treatment oncologist.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aung Naing</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M D Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 12, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 12, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 14, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Avelumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulin G</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

