<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04512690</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY19090210</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04512690</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Spinal Cord Stimulation for Restoration of Arm and Hand Function in People With Subcortical Stroke</brief_title>
  <official_title>Spinal Cord Stimulation for Restoration of Arm and Hand Function in People With Subcortical Stroke</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Marco Capogrosso</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pittsburgh</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this study is to verify whether electrical stimulation of the cervical spinal&#xD;
      cord can activate muscles of the arm and hand in people with hemiplegia following stroke.&#xD;
      Participants will undergo a surgical procedure to implant a system which provides epidural&#xD;
      electrical stimulation (EES) of the cervical spinal cord. Researchers will quantify the&#xD;
      ability of EES to recruit arm and hand muscles and produce distinct kinematic movements. The&#xD;
      implant will be removed after less than 30 days. Results of this study will provide the&#xD;
      foundation for future studies evaluating the efficacy of a minimally-invasive&#xD;
      neuro-technology that can be used in clinical neurorehabilitation programs to restore upper&#xD;
      limb motor function in people with subcortical strokes, thereby increasing independence and&#xD;
      quality of life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Specifically, researchers will 1) quantify the motor potentials in arm and hand muscles&#xD;
      generated by single pulses of electrical stimulation of the spinal cord using FDA-cleared&#xD;
      devices 2) characterize optimal stimulation parameter ranges to maximize induced arm and hand&#xD;
      movement, 3) measure neural changes that could be induced by the system, 4) characterize&#xD;
      potential clinical effects by assessing patient mobility, spasticity, and neurophysiology&#xD;
      with standard clinical tests and simple motor tasks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective, non-randomized, open-label, descriptive, experimental</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evoked motor responses in arm muscles asses with surface electromyography (EMG)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline at Week 1</time_frame>
    <description>We will measure bipolar surface EMGs from shoulder, arm and forearm muscles in responses to electrical stimulation of the cervical spinal cord. We will then quantify peak to peak amplitudes of evoked EMG potentials occurring within 50 ms from each stimulation pulse.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in comfort/discomfort levels during electrical stimulation of the cervical spinal cord</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline at Week 4</time_frame>
    <description>After each stimulation trains patients will be asked to report their perceived discomfort level using a 10 value subjective scale. Low values will be assigned to low discomfort, and high values to high discomfort.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Selectivity of muscle recruitment</measure>
    <time_frame>Score at Week 1</time_frame>
    <description>We will measure bipolar surface EMGs from shoulder, arm and forearm muscles in responses to electrical stimulation of the cervical spinal cord. We will then quantify peak to peak amplitudes of evoked EMG potentials occurring within 50 ms from each stimulation pulse. Peak to peak amplitudes of muscle responses will be mathematically compared to responses in other muscles. Measurements will be performed for each electrode contact. A selectivity measure summarizing the ability to evoke responses in one muscle and not in other muscles will be assessed and reported for each muscle and each contact. Specificity scores range from 0 to 1 where 0 is no-specific and 1 is very specific.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Shoulder, elbow and wrist joint angles</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline at Week 3</time_frame>
    <description>We will measure the maximal range of motion of each joint of the arm during a isotonic movements with and without electrical stimulation of the cervical spinal cord</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <condition>Brain Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Central Nervous System Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Nervous System Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Epidural electrical stimulation of the cervical spinal cord</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Individuals with prior subcortical stroke and hemiparesis of the upper extremity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Epidural electrical stimulation (EES) of the cervical spinal cord</intervention_name>
    <description>All participants enrolled in this group will undergo a surgical procedure to implant a system which provides epidural electrical stimulation (EES) of the cervical spinal cord. Researchers will quantify the ability of EES to recruit arm and hand muscles and produce distinct kinematic movements. The implant will be removed after less than 30 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Epidural electrical stimulation of the cervical spinal cord</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Single, ischemic or hemorrhagic stroke more than 6 months prior to the time of&#xD;
             enrollment with hemiparesis as a result.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Stroke-related damage, radiologically visible, in the deep white matter of the&#xD;
             affected frontal lobe.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Scores higher than 7 and lower than 35 on the Fugl-Meyer scale&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Serious disease or disorder (ex. neurological condition other than stroke, cancer,&#xD;
             severe cardiac or respiratory disease, renal failure, etc.) or cognitive impairments&#xD;
             that could affect the ability to participate in study activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pregnancy or breast feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Receiving anticoagulant, anti-spasticity or anti-epileptic medications prior to or&#xD;
             throughout the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Presence of any implanted medical devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Severe claustrophobia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Spasticity scores higher than 2 on the Modified Ashworth Scale in any upper extremity&#xD;
             muscle.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Results from the Brief Symptoms Inventory (BSI-18) and additional discussions with the&#xD;
             Principal Investigator and a study physician that deem participant inappropriate for&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marco Capogrosso, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amy Boos, MS</last_name>
    <phone>412-648-4179</phone>
    <email>amy.boos@pitt.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Marco Capogrosso, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>412-388-4017</phone>
    <email>mcapo@pitt.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Amy Boos, MS</last_name>
      <phone>412-648-4179</phone>
      <email>amy.boos@pitt.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Capogrosso M, Milekovic T, Borton D, Wagner F, Moraud EM, Mignardot JB, Buse N, Gandar J, Barraud Q, Xing D, Rey E, Duis S, Jianzhong Y, Ko WK, Li Q, Detemple P, Denison T, Micera S, Bezard E, Bloch J, Courtine G. A brain-spine interface alleviating gait deficits after spinal cord injury in primates. Nature. 2016 Nov 10;539(7628):284-288. doi: 10.1038/nature20118.</citation>
    <PMID>27830790</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Coscia M, Wessel MJ, Chaudary U, Millán JDR, Micera S, Guggisberg A, Vuadens P, Donoghue J, Birbaumer N, Hummel FC. Neurotechnology-aided interventions for upper limb motor rehabilitation in severe chronic stroke. Brain. 2019 Aug 1;142(8):2182-2197. doi: 10.1093/brain/awz181. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31257411</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Angeli CA, Edgerton VR, Gerasimenko YP, Harkema SJ. Altering spinal cord excitability enables voluntary movements after chronic complete paralysis in humans. Brain. 2014 May;137(Pt 5):1394-409. doi: 10.1093/brain/awu038. Epub 2014 Apr 8. Erratum in: Brain. 2015 Feb;138(Pt 2):e330.</citation>
    <PMID>24713270</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Capogrosso M, Wenger N, Raspopovic S, Musienko P, Beauparlant J, Bassi Luciani L, Courtine G, Micera S. A computational model for epidural electrical stimulation of spinal sensorimotor circuits. J Neurosci. 2013 Dec 4;33(49):19326-40. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1688-13.2013.</citation>
    <PMID>24305828</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lu DC, Edgerton VR, Modaber M, AuYong N, Morikawa E, Zdunowski S, Sarino ME, Sarrafzadeh M, Nuwer MR, Roy RR, Gerasimenko Y. Engaging Cervical Spinal Cord Networks to Reenable Volitional Control of Hand Function in Tetraplegic Patients. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2016 Nov;30(10):951-962. Epub 2016 May 18.</citation>
    <PMID>27198185</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Barra B, Roux C, Kaeser M, Schiavone G, Lacour SP, Bloch J, Courtine G, Rouiller EM, Schmidlin E, Capogrosso M. Selective Recruitment of Arm Motoneurons in Nonhuman Primates Using Epidural Electrical Stimulation of the Cervical Spinal Cord. Annu Int Conf IEEE Eng Med Biol Soc. 2018 Jul;2018:1424-1427. doi: 10.1109/EMBC.2018.8512554.</citation>
    <PMID>30440659</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 12, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Marco Capogrosso</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Central Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data may be shared with other researchers for the purpose of data analysis and collaboration.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

