<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04511026</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-53978</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>GYNEND0006</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>IRB-53978</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04511026</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Concurrent Use Lymphoseek &amp; Indocyanine Green in Sentinel Lymph Node Detection in Endometrial Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Concurrent Use of Lymphoseek and Indocyanine Green for Sentinel Lymph Node Detection in Endometrial Cancer - a Prospective Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Stanford University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Stanford University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this study is to (i) improve detection of sentinel nodes and (ii) reduce&#xD;
      additional surgical dissection that is needed in case a sentinel lymph node cannot be&#xD;
      detected.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Primary Objective: To determine the detection rate of bilateral sentinel lymph nodes with the&#xD;
      concurrent use of Lymphoseek and Indocyanine Green.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objective: (1) To determine the overall detection rate of sentinel lymph nodes with&#xD;
      concurrent use of Lymphoseek and Indocyanine Green (2) To determine location and number of&#xD;
      Lymphoseek-positive sentinel lymph nodes preoperatively by single-photon emission computed&#xD;
      tomography (SPECT/CT imaging) and intraoperatively by a laparoscopic handheld gamma detection&#xD;
      device and near- infrared fluorescent imaging (3) To determine the concordance of&#xD;
      Lymphoseek-positive sentinel lymph nodes with intraoperatively detected Indocyanine&#xD;
      Green-positive sentinel lymph nodes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Suspended</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Efficacy&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 20, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Bilateral sentinel lymph node (SLN) detection rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of surgery</time_frame>
    <description>A sentinel lymph node will be defined as being detected if it is detected on the pre-operative SPECT/CT imaging scan or intraoperatively using near-infrared imaging or the handheld gamma detection device. Bilateral sentinel lymph node (SLN) detection rate, which will be calculated as the number of patients with bilateral SLN detection divided by the total number of patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall detection of SLN detection</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of surgery</time_frame>
    <description>For each subject, an assessment will be made of whether there was overall sentinel node detection. A sentinel lymph node will be defined as being detected if it is detected on the pre-operative SPECT/CT imaging scan or intraoperatively using near-infrared imaging or the handheld gamma detection device. If at least one SLN is detected (on any side), then this outcome will be considered a 'Yes'.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Location of SLNs detected by Lymphoseek:</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The location and number of sentinel lymph nodes detected by Lymphoseek will be assessed. A sentinel lymph node will be defined as being detected by Lymphoseek if it is detected using the pre-operative SPECT/CT imaging scan and/or intraoperatively using the gamma detection device.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of SLNs detected by Lymphoseek:</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The number of sentinel lymph nodes detected by Lymphoseek will be assessed. A sentinel lymph node will be defined as being detected by Lymphoseek if it is detected using the pre-operative SPECT/CT imaging scan and/or intraoperatively using the gamma detection device.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of SLNs detected by Indocyanine Green</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Number of SLNs detected by Indocyanine Green: The location and number of sentinel lymph nodes detected by Indocyanine Green will be assessed. A sentinel lymph node will be defined as being detected by Indocyanine Green if it is detected intraoperatively using near-infrared imaging only and not by the gamma detection device.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Location of SLNs detected by Indocyanine Green</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Location of SLNs detected by Indocyanine Green: The location and number of sentinel lymph nodes detected by Indocyanine Green will be assessed. A sentinel lymph node will be defined as being detected by Indocyanine Green if it is detected intraoperatively using near-infrared imaging only and not by the gamma detection device.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Endometrial Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lymphoseek/SPECT-CT/Indocyanine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The subject will receive f 0.5 mL each Lymphoseek into the uterine cervix prior to surgery and subsequent SPECT/CT imaging preoperatively. Intraoperatively, following anesthesia induction, Indocyanine Green (0.5 mL) will be injected into the uterine cervix. Using near-infrared imaging, efferent lymphatic vessels and lymph nodes will be visualized and confirmed by detected radioactivity using a laparoscopic gamma counter. The preoperatively obtained SPECT/CT images will help guide the surgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lymphoseek</intervention_name>
    <description>Radioactive diagnostic agent</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lymphoseek/SPECT-CT/Indocyanine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>technetium Tc 99m tilmanocept</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Single Photon Emission Computed Tomography (SPECT)</intervention_name>
    <description>Imaging test</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lymphoseek/SPECT-CT/Indocyanine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Indocyanine Green (ICG)</intervention_name>
    <description>Cyanine dye used in medical diagnostics manufactured by Akorn Inc.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lymphoseek/SPECT-CT/Indocyanine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Neoprobe Gamma Detection System NPB11L(Model1102)</intervention_name>
    <description>Neoprobe Gamma Detection System NPB11L(Model1102) made by Devicor Medical Products, Inc.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lymphoseek/SPECT-CT/Indocyanine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Laparoscopic handheld gamma counter</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has histological diagnosis of cancer of the endometrium of any histology&#xD;
             or grade.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient should have received no prior treatment for her endometrial cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has clinically uterine confined disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient is a candidate for minimal invasive surgery, with sentinel lymph node&#xD;
             assessment with IC-GREEN planned as part of standard of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has an Eastern Cooperative Group (ECOG) performance status of 0-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If age less than or equal to 55 years, the patient has a negative pregnancy test&#xD;
             within 72 hours before administration of Lymphoseek, has been surgically sterilized,&#xD;
             or has been postmenopausal for at least 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has provided written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient is at least 18 years of age at the time of consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has clinical or radiological evidence of metastatic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has a history of a prior loop electrosurgical excision procedure (LEEP) or&#xD;
             cone procedure performed on her cervix.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has participated in another investigational drug study within 30 days of&#xD;
             scheduled surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has an iodine allergy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient is pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Amer K Karam, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Stanford Universiy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford University, School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stanford</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94304</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 12, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

