<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04511455</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AURORA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04511455</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase II, Non-randomized, Single Arm, Translational Study of Cabozantinib for Patients With Hepatocellular Carcinoma (HCC) Refractory to Lenvatinib Treatment</brief_title>
  <official_title>Translational Study of Cabozantinib for Patients With Hepatocellular Carcinoma (HCC) Refractory to Lenvatinib Treatment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Institut für Klinische Krebsforschung IKF GmbH at Krankenhaus Nordwest</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ipsen</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institut für Klinische Krebsforschung IKF GmbH at Krankenhaus Nordwest</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients suffering from advanced stage hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) who have shown disease&#xD;
      progression during lenvatinib-based first line treatment, will be enrolled in this trial.&#xD;
      Patients who progressed either during lenvatinib monotherapy or lenvatinib-IO&#xD;
      (immuno-oncology) combination therapy will be eligible for study participation, whereas at&#xD;
      least 50% of the enrolled patients should be in favor of lenvatinib monotherapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a open-label, single-arm, multicenter phase II trial for patients with locally&#xD;
      advanced and/or metastatic and/or unresectable hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who have histologically proven or were clinically diagnosed (by guideline criteria&#xD;
      in cirrhotic patients) with locally advanced or metastatic and/or unresectable HCC will be&#xD;
      included to receive cabozantinib peroral 60 mg/day. A stepwise dose de-escalation schedule on&#xD;
      individual level is available for patients with lower tolerability against cabozantinib.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study treatment will be limited to a maximum of 12 months (including temporary&#xD;
      interruptions).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tumor tissue will be collected for accompanying research project. (Participation is optional&#xD;
      for participant).&#xD;
&#xD;
      During treatment, clinical visits (blood cell counts, ECG, detection of toxicity) occur every&#xD;
      four weeks during treatment phase. Safety will be monitored continuously by careful&#xD;
      monitoring of all adverse events (AEs) and serious adverse events (SAEs) reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During treatment, tumor response will be assessed by the Investigator according to RECIST 1.1&#xD;
      (radiological imaging by CT and/or MRI of the chest, abdomen, pelvis and all other sites of&#xD;
      disease every 10 weeks until end of treatment (EOT) and every 12 weeks during follow-up (FU),&#xD;
      in case of EOT due to other reasons than progressive disease. Safety-FU visit and Survival FU&#xD;
      visits will be assessed 30 days-, and every 12 weeks after EOT.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 8, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time-on-treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>at study end (approx. 30 months after FPI)</time_frame>
    <description>Time on treatment will be assessed as time from date of first dose of cabozantinib intake till date of permanent discontinuation of treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>at 18 months after last patient randomized</time_frame>
    <description>Survival rates will be assessed from the date of first dose of cabozantinib intake to the date of death from any cause using Kaplan-Meier methods.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>at study end (approx. 18 months after last patient randomized)</time_frame>
    <description>Survival rates for the different time points will be determined using the Kaplan-Meier analysis and RECIST 1.1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>at study end (approx. 18 months after last patient randomized)</time_frame>
    <description>Objective response rate will be defined as the proportion of subjects experiencing a confirmed complete response (CR) or confirmed partial response (PR) per RECIST 1.1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response</measure>
    <time_frame>at study end (approx. 18 months after last patient randomized)</time_frame>
    <description>Time from documentation of tumor response to disease progression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment exposure</measure>
    <time_frame>at study end (approx. 18 months after last patient randomized)</time_frame>
    <description>Time on treatment/dose intensity/dose reductions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Toxicity: o Treatment-related adverse events (TRAEs) o TRAE related treatment interruptions o TRAE related treatment modifications o TRAE related treatment discontinuations</measure>
    <time_frame>at study end (approx. 18 months after last patient randomized)</time_frame>
    <description>All observed toxicities and side effects will be graded according to NCI CTCAE v5.0 and the degree of association of each with the study treatment assessed and summarized.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in ECOG Performance Status</measure>
    <time_frame>at study end (approx. 18 months after last patient randomized)</time_frame>
    <description>Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group patient performance status (Grading from 0 to 5)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in ALBI Grade</measure>
    <time_frame>at study end (approx. 18 months after last patient randomized)</time_frame>
    <description>ALBI score = -0.085 × (albumin g/L) + 0.66 × l g(TBil μmol/L)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Child Pugh Score</measure>
    <time_frame>at study end (approx. 18 months after last patient randomized)</time_frame>
    <description>Child-Pugh Classification Score (Grading from A to C)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Translational research</measure>
    <time_frame>at study end (approx. 18 months after last patient randomized)</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation of biomarkers potentially associated with clinical efficacy (OS, PFS and ORR) of cabozantinib by NGS Oncopanel analysis and VEGF module expression analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">45</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Carcinoma Non-resectable</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Hepatocellular Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cabozantinib peroral 60 mg/day&#xD;
A stepwise dose de-escalation schedule on individual level is available for patients with lower tolerability against cabozantinib.&#xD;
The study treatment will be limited to a maximum of 12 months (including interruptions).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cabozantinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Cabozantinib 60 mg/day peroral</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Fully-informed written consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Males and females ≥ 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
             *There are no data that indicate special gender distribution. Therefore, patients will&#xD;
             be enrolled in the study gender-independently.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Locally advanced or metastatic and/or unresectable HCC with diagnosis confirmed by&#xD;
             histology/ cytology or clinically by guideline criteria in cirrhotic patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Disease that is not amenable to curative surgical and/or locoregional therapies, or&#xD;
             progressive disease after surgical and /or locoregional therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients who have shown progressive disease despite of lenvatinib treatment (in terms&#xD;
             of lenvatinib monotherapy or combination therapy with IO) OR patients must have had&#xD;
             their treatment interrupted after at least 1 administration, as treatment with&#xD;
             lenvatinib is no longer clinically indicated due to the level of toxicities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. ECOG performance status ≤ 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Resolution of any acute, clinically significant treatment-related toxicity from prior&#xD;
             therapy to Grade 1 prior to study entry, with the exception of alopecia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. For women of childbearing potential and men who are sexually active with women of&#xD;
             childbearing potential: agreement to remain abstinent (refrain from heterosexual&#xD;
             intercourse) or use contraceptive methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Unwillingness to give informed consent for participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Prior sorafenib treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pregnancy or breastfeeding, or intention of becoming pregnant during study treatment&#xD;
             or within at least 5 months after last dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test result&#xD;
             within 14 days prior to initiation of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Significant portal hypertension (moderate or severe ascites).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Known fibrolamellar HCC, sarcomatoid HCC, or mixed cholangiocarcinoma and HCC.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Liver cirrhosis Child-Pugh B (&gt; 7 points).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Severely impaired kidney function.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of encephalopathy in past 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Significant cardiovascular disease (such as New York Heart Association Class II or&#xD;
             greater cardiac disease, myocardial infarction, or cerebrovascular accident) within 3&#xD;
             months prior to initiation of study treatment, unstable arrhythmia, or unstable&#xD;
             angina.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Baseline QTcF &gt;500 ms.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Major surgical procedure, other than for diagnosis, within 4 weeks prior to initiation&#xD;
             of study treatment, or anticipation of need for a major surgical procedure during the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Severe infection within 4 weeks prior to initiation of study treatment, including, but&#xD;
             not limited to, hospitalization for complications of infection, bacteremia, or severe&#xD;
             pneumonia.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Any other disease, metabolic dysfunction, physical examination finding, or clinical&#xD;
             laboratory finding that contraindicates the use of an investigational drug, may affect&#xD;
             the interpretation of the results, or may render the patient at high risk from&#xD;
             treatment complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Elevations of AST/ALT exceeding 5 X ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Treatment with investigational systemic therapy within 28 days prior to initiation of&#xD;
             study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Prior cabozantinib use.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Is currently participating or has participated in a study of an investigational agent&#xD;
             or has used an investigational device within 4 weeks prior to the first dose of study&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Patients who have been incarcerated or involuntarily institutionalized by court order&#xD;
             or by the authorities § 40 Abs. 1 S. 3 Nr. 4 AMG.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Patients who are unable to consent because they do not understand the nature,&#xD;
             significance and implications of the clinical trial and therefore cannot form a&#xD;
             rational intention in the light of the facts [§ 40 Abs. 1 S. 3 Nr. 3a AMG].&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Arndt Vogel, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hannover Medical School Department of Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Endocrinology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Arndt Vogel, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+49 176</phone>
    <phone_ext>1 532 9590</phone_ext>
    <email>vogel.arndt@mh-hannover.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Johanna Riedel, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+49 69 7601</phone>
    <phone_ext>4635</phone_ext>
    <email>riedel.johanna@ikf-khnw.de</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Schleswig-Holstein Campus Lübeck</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lübeck</city>
        <zip>23538</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jens Marquardt, Prof.</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 22, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 22, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 24, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>No IPD will be shared.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

