<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04519775</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D12217 Phase III</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04519775</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>HOBSCOTCH Phase III</brief_title>
  <official_title>HOBSCOTCH Phase III: Efficacy of Enhanced Virtual HOBSCOTCH</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the efficacy of an entirely virtual version of the&#xD;
      home-based cognitive self-management program &quot;HOBSCOTCH.&quot; It will test whether HOBSCOTCH can&#xD;
      be delivered nationally from a distance utilizing e-health tools (telephone, computer, and&#xD;
      phone).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      HOBSCOTCH (Home Based Self-management and Cognitive Training Changes lives) is a home-based&#xD;
      self-management program to treat cognitive symptoms and improve quality of life, while&#xD;
      minimizing the barriers of access to care. The program is based on Problem Solving Therapy&#xD;
      (PST) and teaches problem solving strategies and compensatory mechanisms to help manage&#xD;
      cognitive dysfunction and enhance quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HOBSCOTCH Phase III is a study to examine an entirely virtual version of the program. While&#xD;
      HOBSCOTCH was shown to be effective as an in-person and telephone-based program in previous&#xD;
      trials (HOBSCOTCH Phase I and II), this study aims to test a version of the program adapted&#xD;
      for entirely virtual delivery. This is a single-center study, with the HOBSCOTCH intervention&#xD;
      being delivered by staff affiliated with Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center in Lebanon, NH.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 12, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and at months 3, 6, 9, 12</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will use the Quality of Life in Epilepsy (QOLIE-31). This validated tool contains 16 multi-item scales which assess health related quality of life, emotional well-being, memory and attention deficits, medication effects, seizure control, psychosocial functioning, and health perception. Scores range from 0 to 100, with a higher score reflecting a higher quality of life.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cognitive function</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and at months 3, 6, 9, 12</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will use the Cognitive Function sub-scale of the NeuroQOL. This is a brief validated tool developed by the NIH for use in patients with neurological disease. Scores range from 8 to 40, with a higher score indicating better reported cognitive functioning.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in depression</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and at months 3, 6, 9, 12</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will use the Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ-9). The PHQ-9 is a brief 9-item validated depression scale. Scores range from 0 to 27. Scores of 5, 10, 15, and 20 represent cut-offs for mild, moderate, moderately severe, and severe depression, respectively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in self-management practices</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and at months 3, 6, 9, 12</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will use the Adult Epilepsy Self-Management Measurement Instrument (AESMMI-65).This is a 65 item scale that assesses use of epilepsy self-management practices. Scores range from 65 to 325, with a higher score indicating more frequent use of self-management strategies.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in self-reported seizure frequency</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing through entire study baseline - 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will collect seizure information throughout the entire study by use of a smartphone app or paper log to track seizures daily. No range.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in medication adherence</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing through entire study baseline - 12 months, and at baseline and at months 3, 6, 9, 12</time_frame>
    <description>Medication adherence will be collected using the Medication Adherence Rating Scale (MARS), a 10-item inventory to measure medication adherence, as well as by a daily single item medication adherence question through a smartphone app or paper log. For the MARS, scores range from 0 to 10, with a higher score indicating better adherence.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in health confidence</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and at months 3, 6, 9, 12</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will use the Health Confidence Score, a 4-item measure of health confidence. Scores range from 0 to 13, with a higher score indicating better health confidence.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in healthcare utilization</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and at months 3, 6, 9, 12</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will use the Health Care Utilization 4-item measure from the Self-Management Resource Center to capture utilization of health services in the last 6 months. No range.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in overall well-being</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing through entire study baseline - 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will collect daily well-being information throughout the entire study by use of a smartphone app or paper log and a basic single item Likert-scale of well-being. No range.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">116</enrollment>
  <condition>Epilepsy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HOBSCOTCH-V (virtual)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive the HOBSCOTCH intervention consisting of 1:1 sessions delivered once per week, including:&#xD;
1 pre-HOBSCOTCH Session (on webcam)&#xD;
1 educational session (on webcam)&#xD;
6 telephone sessions&#xD;
1 wrap-up session (webcam or telephone)&#xD;
Participants will also receive 3 booster sessions, via webcam or telephone, once per month.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be wait listed and will receive HOBSCOTCH-V (above) following a 6 month wait period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Home Based Self-management and Cognitive Training Changes lives (HOBSCOTCH)</intervention_name>
    <description>HOBSCOTCH is a home-based self-management program to treat cognitive symptoms and improve quality of life, while minimizing the barriers of access to care. The program is based on Problem Solving Therapy (PST) and teaches problem solving strategies and compensatory mechanisms to help manage cognitive dysfunction and enhance quality of life.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>HOBSCOTCH-V (virtual)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>HOBSCOTCH</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18+&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of epilepsy, with controlled or uncontrolled seizures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjective memory complaints&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No changes in antiepileptic and antidepressant medication regimen for 1 month, however&#xD;
             brief discontinuation of antiepileptic medicine for inpatient video EEG evaluation is&#xD;
             acceptable&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Literate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Telephone access&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Internet access&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects self-reporting a dementing illness or a mention of a dementing illness in&#xD;
             their medical record&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe mental disability or estimated IQ less than 70 per clinical judgement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant visual impairment precluding reading or writing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No reliable telephone or internet access&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No diagnosis of epilepsy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Barbara Jobst, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center and Dartmouth College</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Morgan Mazanec</last_name>
    <phone>603-650-4225</phone>
    <email>Morgan.T.Mazanec@hitchcock.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Samantha Schmidt</last_name>
    <phone>603-650-8165</phone>
    <email>Samantha.S.Schmidt@hitchcock.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lebanon</city>
        <state>New Hampshire</state>
        <zip>03756</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Morgan Mazanec</last_name>
      <phone>603-650-4225</phone>
      <email>Morgan.T.Mazanec@hitchcock.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Samantha Schmidt</last_name>
      <phone>603-650-8165</phone>
      <email>Samantha.S.Schmidt@hitchcock.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Caller TA, Secore KL, Ferguson RJ, Roth RM, Alexandre FP, Henegan PL, Harrington JJ, Jobst BC. Design and feasibility of a memory intervention with focus on self-management for cognitive impairment in epilepsy. Epilepsy Behav. 2015 Mar;44:192-4. doi: 10.1016/j.yebeh.2014.12.036. Epub 2015 Feb 27.</citation>
    <PMID>25731132</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Caller TA, Ferguson RJ, Roth RM, Secore KL, Alexandre FP, Zhao W, Tosteson TD, Henegan PL, Birney K, Jobst BC. A cognitive behavioral intervention (HOBSCOTCH) improves quality of life and attention in epilepsy. Epilepsy Behav. 2016 Apr;57(Pt A):111-117. doi: 10.1016/j.yebeh.2016.01.024. Epub 2016 Mar 2.</citation>
    <PMID>26943948</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 17, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 20, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 13, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Barbara Jobst</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Staff Physician, Neurology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Epilepsy Memory Problems</keyword>
  <keyword>Self-Management</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

