<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04513938</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PENI</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04513938</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Interest of the Second Phase of the Oral Challenge Test in Patients With Suspected Long-standing Penicillin Allergy</brief_title>
  <acronym>PENI</acronym>
  <official_title>Interest of the Second Phase of the Oral Challenge Test in Patients With Suspected Long-standing Penicillin Allergy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The most common drug allergy reported is penicillin allergy, approximately 10% of the world's&#xD;
      population. According to the latest studies, only 1-2% of them have a proven hypersensitivity&#xD;
      to penicillins. Being wrongly labeled &quot;allergic&quot; leads to a loss of chance for patients to be&#xD;
      treated with a molecule of less efficacy than penicillins, an increase in bacterial&#xD;
      resistance by broadening the spectrum of action of the molecules prescribed as an alternative&#xD;
      and ultimately a additional financial cost. There are several forms of hypersensitivity: the&#xD;
      two most classic: immediate hypersensitivity (type I according to Gell and Combs) with a&#xD;
      reaction within an hour of taking and non-immediate hypersensitivity with a reaction&#xD;
      occurring several days later (type IV according to Gell and Combs). A large majority of&#xD;
      patients report a history of allergy in childhood that is poorly described and most often&#xD;
      absent from health records. In most cases, this may be a viral rash concomitant with a&#xD;
      febrile episode mistakenly mistaken for an allergic skin reaction. Patients are then tested&#xD;
      for several decades, in adulthood, after their initial reaction. This latency of time&#xD;
      involves a risk of negativation of the allergic tests and it is not excluded that the skin&#xD;
      tests or drug reintroductions re cause sensitization to the antibiotic tested and that&#xD;
      ultimately the patient reacts when taking the future drug. In fact, it is recommended to&#xD;
      optimally explore patients approximately 6 months after an allergic reaction (except for&#xD;
      severe drug eruptions).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The exploration of drug hypersensitivity to penicillins therefore involves a strict&#xD;
      questioning of the circumstances of the so-called allergic reaction allowing the reaction to&#xD;
      be classified as immediate or delayed, then skin tests (prick test, IDR and Patch test&#xD;
      according to the immediate profile or delayed) and finally the hospital provocation test.&#xD;
      While provocation tests are carried out conventionally most often within one day, it has been&#xD;
      shown that some patients react several days after taking penicillin repeatedly: 6.1% have a&#xD;
      reaction in their protocol of taking for 5 days at home in the context of a delayed allergy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the allergology service at hôpital Paris Saint-Joseph, the protocol corresponds to 2&#xD;
      successive reintroductions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is to evaluate the protocol for reintroducing Amoxicillin or Augmentin carried out&#xD;
      over two stages: a first with 100 mg (i.e. 1 / 10th of a dose) then a second with a dose of&#xD;
      1200 mg 1 month later. It would be a question of seeing if with the second reintroduction,&#xD;
      one could not catch up with allergic people who would have presented a false negative during&#xD;
      the first reintroduction because of explorations too far away from their initial reaction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 20, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 20, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the second oral challenge test</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>This outcome corresponds to the percentage of patients diagnosed with allergies during the second Oral Challenge Test versus all patients with a negative first Oral Challenge Test.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">195</enrollment>
  <condition>Allergy Penicillin</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This study will be carried out on the data of patients, having carried out two TPO of&#xD;
        amoxicillin or Augmentin between December 2017 and December 2018 in HDJ or during an&#xD;
        allergology consultation within the Paris Saint-Joseph hospital.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient aged ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with a history of drug allergy and eviction for more than 12 months of&#xD;
             penicillins A: mainly amoxicillin and amoxicillin + clavulanic acid&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who had two amoxicillin or Augmentin Oral Challenge Test between December&#xD;
             2017 and December 2018 in allergology department of the Paris Saint-Joseph hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  French-speaking patient&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with uncontrolled asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with an ongoing infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with positive skin tests for penicillin before the first TPO&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient under guardianship or curatorship&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient deprived of liberty&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient objecting to participation in the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>GEST Noemie, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint-Joseph</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris 14</city>
        <zip>75014</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Solensky R, Earl HS, Gruchalla RS. Lack of penicillin resensitization in patients with a history of penicillin allergy after receiving repeated penicillin courses. Arch Intern Med. 2002 Apr 8;162(7):822-6.</citation>
    <PMID>11926858</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Marwood J, Aguirrebarrena G, Kerr S, Welch SA, Rimmer J. De-labelling self-reported penicillin allergy within the emergency department through the use of skin tests and oral drug provocation testing. Emerg Med Australas. 2017 Oct;29(5):509-515. doi: 10.1111/1742-6723.12774. Epub 2017 Apr 5.</citation>
    <PMID>28378949</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Shenoy ES, Macy E, Rowe T, Blumenthal KG. Evaluation and Management of Penicillin Allergy: A Review. JAMA. 2019 Jan 15;321(2):188-199. doi: 10.1001/jama.2018.19283. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30644987</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>de Haan P, Bruynzeel DP, van Ketel WG. Onset of penicillin rashes: relation between type of penicillin administered and type of immune reactivity. Allergy. 1986 Jan;41(1):75-8.</citation>
    <PMID>2938516</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Blanca M, Romano A, Torres MJ, Férnandez J, Mayorga C, Rodriguez J, Demoly P, Bousquet PJ, Merk HF, Sanz ML, Ott H, Atanasković-Marković M. Update on the evaluation of hypersensitivity reactions to betalactams. Allergy. 2009 Feb;64(2):183-93. doi: 10.1111/j.1398-9995.2008.01916.x. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19133923</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hjortlund J, Mortz CG, Skov PS, Bindslev-Jensen C. Diagnosis of penicillin allergy revisited: the value of case history, skin testing, specific IgE and prolonged challenge. Allergy. 2013 Aug;68(8):1057-64. doi: 10.1111/all.12195. Epub 2013 Jul 29.</citation>
    <PMID>23889703</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Devillers L, Sicsic J, Delbarre A, Le Bel J, Ferrat E, Saint Lary O. General Practitioner trainers prescribe fewer antibiotics in primary care: Evidence from France. PLoS One. 2018 Jan 25;13(1):e0190522. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0190522. eCollection 2018.</citation>
    <PMID>29370178</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 12, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

