<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04512599</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ORA20072703</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04512599</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prebiotics in the Parkinson's Disease Microbiome</brief_title>
  <official_title>Short Chain Fatty Acid Enhancing Prebiotics and Normalization of Parkinson's Disease Microbiome: A Pilot Tolerability Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rush University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rush University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There are about one million Parkinson's disease (PD) patients in America. The risks&#xD;
      associated with whether or not an individual may develop PD include environment and genetic&#xD;
      (biologic, hereditary) factors. Studies have show that certain things may be triggers, for&#xD;
      example cells in the brain that are made active and associated inflammation in the brain. The&#xD;
      gut is the largest interface between the PD patient and the environment, and it is highly&#xD;
      thought to be pathway to the environment trigger. Research studies have looked at how&#xD;
      information is passed back and forth between the brain and the gut.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of this study (pilot) is to gather information to conduct a larger clinical trial.&#xD;
      For this pilot study is to determine if a microbiota-directed (bacteria in the gut)&#xD;
      intervention (dietary bar) is capable of correcting the bacteria gut balance in PD. This is&#xD;
      based on the thought that an imbalance of bacteria in the gut of PD patients may lead to the&#xD;
      gut and intestines working correctly. The long term goal is to see if the intervention has&#xD;
      the potential to modify the disease or protect the brain in PD. If the intervention&#xD;
      successfully improves the bacterial imbalance in PD, it will be the first attempt to modify&#xD;
      the Gut-Brain communication in PD, which can lead to additional studies aimed at improving&#xD;
      the disease progression or prevention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this project, the investigators will test how well Parkinson's disease patients tolerate&#xD;
      changes in the gut and intestines by providing the participants a dietary bar to eat for 10&#xD;
      days. The investigators intend to conduct this pilot clinical trial in which the&#xD;
      investigators believe that daily oral intake of a &quot;prebiotic&quot; mixture will be safe and well&#xD;
      tolerated in a small number Parkinson's disease participants prior to a larger clinical trial&#xD;
      looking at efficacy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Intestinal microbiota, are a dynamic community of commensal bacteria that modulate gut&#xD;
      homeostasis and systemic biological processes including brain development and function&#xD;
      through a bidirectional &quot;Gut-Brain axis&quot;. Recent studies in both rodent models of disease and&#xD;
      human have shown disrupted intestinal microbiota community in multiple systemic metabolic and&#xD;
      inflammatory disorders including neurological disease. More specifically emerging evidence&#xD;
      shows that stool and intestinal mucosal associated microbiota composition and function are&#xD;
      abnormal in PD patients. Divergence of commensal bacteria composition from the microbial&#xD;
      communities found in healthy persons (so called &quot;dysbiosis&quot;), has been associated with PD in&#xD;
      early and late stages, as well as in patients with REM sleep behavior disorder (RBD), a group&#xD;
      that are at high risk of progression to PD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this project, the investigators will test the tolerability of Parkinson's disease patients&#xD;
      in modulating the gut microbiota through dietary means. The investigators intend to conduct a&#xD;
      pilot clinical trial in which the investigators hypothesize that daily oral intake of a&#xD;
      prebiotic mixture will be safe and well tolerated in a small number Parkinson's disease&#xD;
      participants prior to a larger clinical trial looking at efficacy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research design and protocol:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is an open-label, non-randomized study in 10 Parkinson's disease participants at&#xD;
      Rush University Medical Center (RUMC) under the supervision of Drs. Hall and Keshavarzian.&#xD;
      The trial will include 10 PD patients who are de novo (not yet on medication) or moderate&#xD;
      stage (on medications). Participants will take the prebiotics in a form of a bar (Table 1)&#xD;
      for 10 days- one bar (10 gram fiber) a day for 3 days and then one bar twice a day for&#xD;
      additional one week.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each participant will have a baseline visit and a follow up visit after 10 days of the&#xD;
      intervention (consumption of prebiotic dietary bar). At each visit, participants will&#xD;
      complete questionnaires regarding adverse events including a questionnaire that rates bowel&#xD;
      movement, stool consistency, discomfort, flatulence, abdominal pain, and bloating on a scale&#xD;
      from 1 (best) to 10 (worst). Participants will also complete a Perceived Stress Questionnaire&#xD;
      (Appendix D) and GI Symptom and Severity Checklist (Appendix A). Participants will be asked&#xD;
      to fill out a diet record (24ASA diet questionnaire) (Appendix E) during the last 3 days on&#xD;
      the intervention. Participant will also are asked to self-collect stool at home before&#xD;
      consuming (eating) the first probiotic bar in the study and during the last day of the study&#xD;
      at home. Supplies for stool collection (2 stool collection kit) and instructions for specimen&#xD;
      handling and for completing these tasks will be given at Visit 1 and refreshed before visit&#xD;
      2. At visit 1 participants will be provided with 2 stool collection kits. First stool will be&#xD;
      collected at home about 1 day and participants are asked to mail the stool in a pre-paid Fed&#xD;
      Ex right after collecting the stool. The second stool collection will be on the last day that&#xD;
      participants consume the probiotic bars prior to coming to for study visit 2 when the&#xD;
      participants bring the stool to the study visit. The kit includes supplies to preserve the&#xD;
      sample with gas packs and collection bag so the sample can be brought with the participant to&#xD;
      the visits within 24 hours. The self-collected stool samples will be saved by the study team&#xD;
      and frozen for future use. Participants will be asked to complete several dietary&#xD;
      questionnaires including a Mediterranean diet screener (Appendix F), food timing screener&#xD;
      (Appendix B) and food frequency questionnaire (Appendix C). Before Visit 2, each participant&#xD;
      will collect the stool and complete the 3-day food record; these will be returned at Visit 2.&#xD;
      At Visit 2, participants will complete a Perceived Stress Questionnaire (Appendix D) and GI&#xD;
      Symptom and Severity Checklist and associated instructions (Appendix A). Each participant&#xD;
      will also have blood draw (1 red top to collect serum and 1 EDTA tube to collect plasma) at&#xD;
      visit 1 (baseline) and at visit 2 (completion of the study) to check for serum short chain&#xD;
      fatty acids, lipopolysaccharides, interleukins and cytosine monophosphate(check for safety).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will provide written informed consent (Visit 1) before any study procedures,&#xD;
      data or sample collection are performed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 31, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The study is an open-label, non-randomized study in Parkinson's disease participants</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tolerability of prebiotic bar after 10 days in PD participants</measure>
    <time_frame>10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Tolerability of the prebiotic bar will be assessed for change in the GI Symptoms and Severity Checklist at 10 days from baseline</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of prebiotic bar during 10 days in Parkinson's disease participants</measure>
    <time_frame>10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of safety will be assessed using the frequency of adverse events over the 10 day trial period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Parkinson Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Open-label consumption of prebiotic bar(s); 1 bar for 3 days; followed by 2 bars for 7 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prebiotic Bar</intervention_name>
    <description>The prebiotic bar is a proprietary formula created by the study co-investigators, who will not be involved in participant recruitment, selection or outcome measures.The prebiotic bars will be shipped and stored at room temperature prior to consumption.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical diagnosis of Parkinson's disease,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &gt;age 30,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be able to consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  prior intestinal resection,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patient history of GI diseases except for hiatal hernia, gastroesophageal reflux&#xD;
             disease, hemorrhoids,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe renal disease defined by creatinine more than 2 ½ times normal,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  markedly abnormal liver function defined by liver function tests over 4 times normal&#xD;
             levels or elevated bilirubin,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  antibiotic use within the last 12 weeks prior to enrollment,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a plan to have a major change in dietary habit during the study,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  consumption of probiotics, prebiotics or synbiotics without an appropriate 2 week&#xD;
             washout period&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Deborah A Hall, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rush University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Deborah A Hall, MD PhD</last_name>
    <phone>312-563-2900</phone>
    <email>Deborah_A_Hall@rush.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Teresa A Chmura, BS</last_name>
    <phone>312-942-8002</phone>
    <email>tchmura@rush.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rush University Medical Cener</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Patrick McNamara, BS</last_name>
      <phone>312-563-3794</phone>
      <email>Patrick_McNamara@rush.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Teresa A Chmura, BS</last_name>
      <phone>312-942-8002</phone>
      <email>tchmura@rush.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 31, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 12, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 31, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 31, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rush University Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Deborah Hall, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Neurological Sciences</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>microbiome</keyword>
  <keyword>prebiotic</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

