<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04518020</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>N-20160047</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04518020</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Single Crown Supported by Short Implant Versus Standard Implant in Conjunction With Maxillary Sinus Floor Augmentation.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Single Crown Supported by Short Implant Versus Standard Implant in Conjunction With Maxillary Sinus Floor Augmentation in the Posterior: a Randomized, Controlled Clinical Trial.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Aalborg University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dentsply International</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Aalborg University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Implant placement in the posterior part of the maxilla is frequently compromised due to&#xD;
      atrophy of the alveolar process. Therefore, alveolar ridge augmentation is frequently&#xD;
      necessary before or in conjunction with implant placement. The most commonly used method to&#xD;
      augment the maxillary premolar and molar region involves the maxillary sinus floor&#xD;
      augmentation (MSFA) with autogenous bone graft or a bone substitute. However, the use of&#xD;
      autogenous bone grafts is associated with risk at the donor site morbidity and unpredictable&#xD;
      graft resorption. Consequently, short implants are used increasingly to eliminate the need&#xD;
      for bone augmentation. However, long-term studies comparing short implants and standard&#xD;
      implants in conjunction with MSFA supporting single crown restoration in the posterior&#xD;
      maxilla are missing. The primary outcome measures include survival of implant and&#xD;
      suprastructures, peri-implant marginal bone level (MBL), professional evaluation of the&#xD;
      suprastructure and soft tissue using pink esthetic score (PES) and white esthetic score&#xD;
      (WES), patient satisfaction using visual analogue scale (VAS), and oral health related&#xD;
      quality of life using oral health impact profile (OHIP-14) questionnaire. Secondary outcome&#xD;
      measure include evaluation of the complication rate related to the two treatment modalities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of the present study is to test the H0 hypothesis of:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. No differences in survival of suprastructures and implants with the two treatment&#xD;
           modalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. No differences in peri-implant MBL, PES, WES, and patient satisfaction using VAS with&#xD;
           the two treat modalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. No differences in oral health related quality of life using OHIP-14 with the two&#xD;
           treatment modalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objective will include:&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. Complications related to bone harvesting, implant installation, and MSFA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome measures included:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Survival of suprastructures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Survival of implants.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Radiographic peri-implant MBL.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Professional evaluation of suprastructure and soft tissue using PES and WES.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient satisfaction using VAS&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Oral health related quality of life using OHIP-14 questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary outcome measures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Pre- and postoperative complications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 16, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized controlled clinical trial (RCT)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival of suprastructures.</measure>
    <time_frame>1-year follow up</time_frame>
    <description>Survival of suprastructures is defined as absence of mechanical/or biological complications causing loss of suprastructures. Chipping of ceramics and loosening of the suprastructure were not categorized as loss of suprastructure.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival of implants.</measure>
    <time_frame>1-year follow up</time_frame>
    <description>Survival of implants is defined as clinically stable and osseointegrated implants with absence of mobility, progressive marginal bone loss, and infection.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Radiographic MBL.</measure>
    <time_frame>1-year follow up</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of marginal bone level in millimeter.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Professional evaluation of the prosthetic restoration and soft tissue using pink esthetic score (PES) and white esthetic score (WES).</measure>
    <time_frame>1-year follow up</time_frame>
    <description>Esthetic evaluation of suprastructure and soft tissue using PES and WES. PES includes 7 different variables: mesial papilla, distal papilla, soft-tissue level, soft-tissue contour, alveolar process deficiency, soft-tissue colour, and texture. Each variable is assessed with a 0, 1, or 2 score, with 0 being the poorest score and 2 the best according to the degree of match or mismatch compared with the anterior premolar or molar. The highest possible PES is 14. WES includes 5 different variables: Crown form, volume, colour, translucency, and texture. Each variable is assessed with a 0, 1, or 2 score, with 0 being the poorest score and 2 the best according to the degree of match or mismatch compared with the anterior premolar or molar. The highest possible WES is 10.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction.</measure>
    <time_frame>1-year follow up</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of patient satisfaction using visual analogue scale (VAS). VAS with 0 indicating extreme dissatisfaction and 10 indicating complete satisfaction.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Oral health related quality of life as defined by oral health impact profile (OHIP-14).</measure>
    <time_frame>1-year follow up</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of oral health related quality of life using OHIP-14 questionnaire. OHIP-14 scale ranges from 0 to 56, with higher scores indicating poorer oral health impact profile.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complications.</measure>
    <time_frame>1-year follow up</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of biological and mechanical complication rate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Dental Implant Failed</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Short implant</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Short implant 6 mm installed</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Conventional implant + bone augmentation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard length implant 13 mm in conjunction with maxillary sinus floor augmentation serves as a control group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>40 patients will be randomly allocated to short implants and standard implants in conjunction with MSFA</intervention_name>
    <description>40 patients will be randomly allocated to short implants (group 1) and standard implants in conjunction with MSFA using 50% particulated autogenous mandibular bone graft mixed with 50% Bio-Oss (group 2).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Conventional implant + bone augmentation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Short implant</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &gt;20 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Partial edentulism in the posterior maxilla.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Height and weight of the maxillary alveolar process of at least 5.5 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mandibular occluding teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  General contraindications to implant therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Poor oral hygiene.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progressive periodontitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute infection in the area intended for implant placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parafunction, bruxism, or clenching.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric problems or unrealistic expectations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Heavy tobacco use, define as &gt;10 cigarettes per day.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 14, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 14, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 14, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Aalborg University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Helle Baungaard Nielsen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator, PhD. Student, Department of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

