<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04519463</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0081-20-EMC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04519463</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Local Anesthesia With Lidocaine During Insertion and Removal of Nasal Packing</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Local Anesthesia With Lidocaine During Insertion and Removal of Nasal Packing</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Muhamed Masalha</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>HaEmek Medical Center, Israel</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to investigate the effect of local nasal anesthesia with lidocaine spray on&#xD;
      the insertion of nasal tampons during active nasal bleeding.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Nasal packing has many uses, such as prevention of postoperative bleeding following&#xD;
      endoscopic sinus surgery, stabilization of the nasal septum, prevention of adhesions&#xD;
      following septoplasty, and treatment of active epistaxis1,2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The utilization of tampons for nasal packing during nasal and sinus surgeries is widely used&#xD;
      and safe. Nasal tampons assist in creating a moist supportive environment for tissue healing&#xD;
      without causing local irritation or foreign body reaction3. The removal is performed after&#xD;
      24-48 hours. On the other hand, there are some disadvantages to the uses of nasal tampons:&#xD;
      trauma to the nasal mucosa, infection of the nose and sinuses, aspiration of part of the&#xD;
      tampon, and even toxic shock syndrome3. One of the most troublesome aspects to the patient&#xD;
      and the clinician is the pain and discomfort during insertion and removal of the tampons3,4.&#xD;
      In our experience, these symptoms are of considerable significance to the patient experience&#xD;
      and satisfaction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is a wide range of commercially available nasal packings such as Merocel and Nasopore.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In our practice, Merocel nasal tampons are used, which contain polyvinyl acetate. This type&#xD;
      of material expands upon contact with fluids, and it is not soluble. This product is used at&#xD;
      the end of endoscopic nasal surgeries and in the treatment of active epistaxis, not amenable&#xD;
      to local pressure and without a recognizable source of bleeding. In case of unstoppable&#xD;
      bleeding despite the use of nasal tampons, a nasal balloon is inflated in the nasal cavity.&#xD;
      Its insertion and inflation are associated with patient pain and discomfort.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lidocaine is a drug commonly used for local anesthesia. It is used for local nasal anesthesia&#xD;
      by a variety of commercially available sprays, atomizers, nebulizers, gels, and ointments.&#xD;
      Lidocaine causes local anesthesia by affecting sodium channels, causing decreased initiation&#xD;
      and conduction of neural impulses. In turn, fewer afferent impulses reach the central nervous&#xD;
      system6. In healthy individuals, side effects are negligible, but it could influence patients&#xD;
      with cardiac infarction. The main side effects of lidocaine are neurological, which could be&#xD;
      of significance in the case of inflamed or damaged tissue because of rapid absorption. The&#xD;
      use of Lidocaine spray (Xylocaine 10%) is commonly available worldwide and is routinely used&#xD;
      in our institution before fiberoptic laryngoscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous publications have mentioned the positive effect of local anesthesia during the&#xD;
      removal of nasal tampons5,7. In a recent meta-analysis, local anesthetics were associated&#xD;
      with less pain during the removal of nasal tampons and shortened time of the procedure. Yet,&#xD;
      the authors recognized the need for additional randomized controlled trials7. There are no&#xD;
      previous publications on the effect of local anesthetics on the insertions of nasal tampons&#xD;
      during active nasal bleeding. In the experience of the senior author, for many years, the&#xD;
      application of lidocaine spray 10% before the insertions of nasal tampons for epistaxis was&#xD;
      associated with a significant reduction of pain and discomfort.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study aims to investigate the effect of local nasal anesthesia with lidocaine spray on&#xD;
      the insertion of nasal tampons during active nasal bleeding. Secondary objectives include the&#xD;
      impact on nasal tampons removal after the cessation of nasal bleeding and after endoscopic&#xD;
      sinus surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research hypothesis: local anesthesia with lidocaine before the insertion of nasal tampons or&#xD;
      inflatable balloon reduces patients' pain, discomfort, and stress during insertion for the&#xD;
      treatment of active nasal bleeding, and during removal of nasal tampons either&#xD;
      postoperatively or after cessation of epistaxis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study population involves 30 patients with spontaneous epistaxis and another 30 patients&#xD;
      who went tampon removal postoperatively in our institution. Recruitment includes patients who&#xD;
      came to the emergency department with active epistaxis and still had active bleeding after&#xD;
      the application of local pressure without an identified source of bleeding, requiring&#xD;
      treatment with tampons or an inflatable balloon. The second group included patients who&#xD;
      require postoperative removal of nasal tampons.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Double-Blind Randomized Controlled Trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Both Xylocaine spray and Placebo (saline) will be in similar containers with serial numbers, Both clinician and patient are blinded to the content.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Analogue Scale (VAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) ranging from 0- no pain at all to 10 - unbearable pain.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Questionnaires</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Patient symptoms: nausea, vomiting, allergic reaction, localized pain, numbness in the pharynx, bitter taste, dysphagia. For any side effect, the duration until the symptoms had passed. Scale of symptoms severity ranging from 0- no symptoms at all to 10 - worst symptoms severity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Epistaxis</condition>
  <condition>Analgesia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Xylocaine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>30 patients who receive Xylocaine 10% nasal spray</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Saline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>30 patients who receive saline nasal spray</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Xylocaine Mucosal Product</intervention_name>
    <description>Xylocaine 10% Nasal Spray</description>
    <arm_group_label>Xylocaine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Sodium Chloride 0.9%</description>
    <arm_group_label>Saline</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age of 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both sexes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No known allergy for local anesthetics agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active nasal bleeding requiring the insertion of a tampon or an&#xD;
             inflatable balloon, or patients requiring tampon removal postoperatively.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age under 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy to local anesthetics&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of willingness to participate in a clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient unable to give informed consent from any reason&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Muhamed Masalha, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Emek Medical Center, Afula, Israel.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Muhamed Masalha, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+972-54-635-5305</phone>
    <email>masalha.muhamed@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emek Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Afula</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Muhamed Masalha, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+972-54-635-5305</phone>
      <email>masalha.muhamed@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.hamichlol.org.il/%D7%9C%D7%99%D7%93%D7%95%D7%A7%D7%90%D7%99%D7%9F</url>
    <description>Lidocaine Drug Information</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Watson MG, Campbell JB, Shenoi PM. Nasal surgery: does the type of nasal pack influence the results? Rhinology. 1989 Jun;27(2):105-11.</citation>
    <PMID>2781213</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weber R, Keerl R, Hochapfel F, Draf W, Toffel PH. Packing in endonasal surgery. Am J Otolaryngol. 2001 Sep-Oct;22(5):306-20. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11562881</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Haytoğlu S, Kuran G, Muluk NB, Arıkan OK. Different anesthetic agents-soaked sinus packings on pain management after functional endoscopic sinus surgery: which is the most effective? Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2016 Jul;273(7):1769-77. doi: 10.1007/s00405-015-3807-2. Epub 2015 Oct 28.</citation>
    <PMID>26511988</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Karaaslan K, Yilmaz F, Gulcu N, Yigit B, Kocoglu H. The effect of prilocaine and prilocaine plus meperidine infiltration on the pain during nasal packing removal. Rhinology. 2007 Dec;45(4):321-4.</citation>
    <PMID>18085028</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tsai SC, Lai MT, Kao YL, Wu CC. Effect of infiltrating nasal packing with local anesthetics in postoperative pain and anxiety following sinonasal surgeries: a systemic review and meta-analysis. Braz J Otorhinolaryngol. 2020 May - Jun;86(3):376-382. doi: 10.1016/j.bjorl.2019.12.011. Epub 2020 Feb 12.</citation>
    <PMID>32127341</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 6, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 18, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 18, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>HaEmek Medical Center, Israel</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Muhamed Masalha</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr, Muhamed Masalha; Principal Investigator; Senior Surgeon in the Endoscopic Sinus Surgery Unit, the Department of Otolaryngology-Head and neck surgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Nasal Spray</keyword>
  <keyword>Nasal Anesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>Epistaxis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epistaxis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

