<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04519918</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AOA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04519918</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Application of Artificial Oocyte Activation Technique (AOA) in ART</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Application of Artificial Oocyte Activation Technique (AOA) in Assisted Reproduction Technology</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tang-Du Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tang-Du Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Oocyte activation is an imperative stage in the initiation of embryo development during the&#xD;
      fertilization. Indeed, the entrance of sperm into the oocyte causes sequences of calcium&#xD;
      oscillations in its cytoplasm, regulating a series of molecular events called oocyte&#xD;
      activation. The intracytoplasmic sperm injection (ICSI) has allowed fertilization in couples&#xD;
      with severe male factor infertility. But, there was still fertilization failure or low&#xD;
      fertilization occurs in ICSI cycles. It has reported that insufficient of oocyte activation&#xD;
      is the important cause of fertilization failure. Artificial oocyte activation (AOA)&#xD;
      represents an effective technique, can restore the calcium oscillations to improve the&#xD;
      fertilization. Here, the investigators explore the effective of different AOA methods&#xD;
      including oocyte was injected CaCl2 or mechanical stimulated then treated with calcium&#xD;
      ionophore.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The ICSI procedure improves fertilization rates in cases of male factor infertility. However,&#xD;
      fertilization failure still occurs in 1-5% in ICSI cycles. The main cause of failed&#xD;
      fertilization is failure to complete oocyte activation. Oocyte activation involves a&#xD;
      multitude of molecular changes. The investigators use a variety of mechanical, electrical,&#xD;
      and chemical methods to trigger the calcium oscillations necessary to activate oocytes.&#xD;
      During mechanical activation of oocytes, oolemmas are pierced using a microneedle to trigger&#xD;
      a calcium influx. Another method for mechanical oocyte activation is the direct&#xD;
      microinjection of calcium into the oocyte to increase intracellular calcium. It has been&#xD;
      described with the use of calcium ionophore A23187, which can mimic the natural pattern of&#xD;
      calcium rise. Mechanical and chemical activation are the most commonly used methods for&#xD;
      artificial oocyte activation, can mimic calcium oscillations resulting in successful&#xD;
      fertilization. AOA, a highly specialized fertilization technique that can be added to&#xD;
      conventional ICSI to overcome fertilization failure in patients that had failed fertilization&#xD;
      or poor quality embryos history.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When the number of retrieved oocytes was &gt;10, sibling oocytes were divided into 3 groups to&#xD;
      perform the standard ICSI procedure (control group), chemical AOA (A1 experiment group) or&#xD;
      mechanical AOA (A2 experiment group). When the number of retrieved oocytes was 6-10, sibling&#xD;
      oocytes were randomized 1:1 to perform the chemical AOA (A1 experiment group) or mechanical&#xD;
      AOA (A2 experiment group). The number of retrieved oocytes was 1-5, all oocytes were perform&#xD;
      the chemical AOA. Control group, a single spermatozoon was injected into the ooplasm,&#xD;
      standard ICSI procedure. A1 experiment group, were treated by injecting CaCl2 concurrently&#xD;
      with ICSI followed by sequential exposure of calcium ionophore A23187 activation solution for&#xD;
      two times of post-ICSI AOA. A2 experiment group, mechanical stimulation was done before&#xD;
      standard ICSI procedure, then the oocytes were transferred into the calcium ionophore A23187&#xD;
      activation solution for two times of post-ICSI AOA. The investigators want to establish the&#xD;
      effective and safe of different AOA methods, to improve the fertilization outcome and embryo&#xD;
      quality, and finally obtain healthy offspring.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of AOA on fertilization</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the normal fertilization rate (2PN rate)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of AOA on embryo quality</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the good-quality embryo rate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of AOA on clinical outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the live-birth rate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Fertilization</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard ICSI procedure</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>a single spermatozoon was injected into the ooplasm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Chemical oocyte activation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>After CaCl2 was injected, the oocytes were transferred into the calcium ionophore A23187 activation solution for two times of post-ICSI AOA.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mechanical oocyte activation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Mechanical stimulation was done before standard ICSI procedure, then the oocytes were transferred into the calcium ionophore A23187 activation solution for two times of post-ICSI AOA.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AOA</intervention_name>
    <description>AOA represents an invasive non-physiological technique.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Chemical oocyte activation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Mechanical oocyte activation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patients suffered at least one complete fertilization failure or low fertilization&#xD;
             rate after performing standard ICSI in previous cycle. Low fertilization was defined&#xD;
             as less than 33% fertilization rate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patients suffered at least 2 cycles complete fertilization failure or low&#xD;
             fertilization rate after performing IVF in previous cycle. Low fertilization was&#xD;
             defined as less than 33% fertilization rate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The sperm of the patients has the following characteristics: globozoospermia,&#xD;
             acrosomal deletion or small, severe head deformity, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sperm of testicular origin and/or sperm that has been freeze-thawed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The sperm was PLC-ζ missing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The MII oocytes were IVM cultured and/or freeze-thawed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patients suffered at least 2 cycles no available embryos, because of the embryo&#xD;
             development block or fragmentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal fertilization IVF/ICSI cycles.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>22 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Li Bo, Doctor</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Reproductive Medicine Center, Tangdu Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Wang Ming, Master</last_name>
    <phone>8613259809290</phone>
    <email>wangmingbio@snnu.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tangdu Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Xi'an</city>
        <state>Shaanxi</state>
        <zip>710038</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>wang ming</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 30, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 19, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 20, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 30, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 30, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Fertilization failure</keyword>
  <keyword>Artificial Oocyte Activation (AOA)</keyword>
  <keyword>Calcium ionophore</keyword>
  <keyword>Fertilization</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

