<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04519229</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RK/30062020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04519229</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Child-Parent Psychotherapy - a Feasibility Study for Children in Foster Care</brief_title>
  <official_title>Child-Parent Psychotherapy for Children 0-6 Years Old With Experiences of Adverse Life Events - a Feasibility Study for Children in Foster Care</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kronoberg County Council</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Stiftelsen Allmänna Barnhuset</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kronoberg County Council</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Children in foster care have an increased risk of exposure to adverse experiences during&#xD;
      childhood and across the lifespan. In current studies of interventions children in foster&#xD;
      care are often excluded, or they are too few to be included in statistical analyses of&#xD;
      outcomes. As a consequence, knowledge on feasibility of treatment methods for some of the&#xD;
      most exposed and maltreated children in society is sparse.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Child-Parent Psychotherapy (CPP) is an intervention for children 0-6 years who have been&#xD;
      exposed to adverse and traumatic events. CPP is currently being implemented in Sweden. The&#xD;
      aim of this study is to investigate the feasibility of CPP for children in foster care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aim. The aim of the current study is to investigate the feasibility of CPP for young children&#xD;
      who have an increased risk of exposure to adverse and traumatic experiences with negative&#xD;
      effects on their health and development. Feasibility will be conceptualized as acceptance of&#xD;
      the method by therapists, caregivers, and children; practical applications of the method; any&#xD;
      need for modifications; and observed outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research questions The main research question is: Is CPP feasible for children in foster&#xD;
      care? Additional research questions are: 1) How do children in foster care experience&#xD;
      participating in CPP? 2) How do foster parents experience participating in CPP? 3) How do&#xD;
      clinicians experience using CPP with children in foster care and their caregivers? 4) What&#xD;
      outcomes can be observed in treatment with children in foster care in terms of increased&#xD;
      psychological health in children and foster parents; decrease in symptoms of post-traumatic&#xD;
      stress in children and foster parents; and foster parents' experiences of their caregiving&#xD;
      capacity and relationship with the child.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method Design. The project has a naturalistic mixed-methods study design. Qualitative and&#xD;
      quantitative research methods will be used to collect and analyze data. Qualitative data&#xD;
      concerning childrens', caregivers', and clinicians' experiences of the treatment method as&#xD;
      well as quantitative data concerning practical applications of the method, any modifications&#xD;
      made, and reported levels of symptoms will be studied.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants. Nine agencies in different regions of Sweden offering CPP as part of their&#xD;
      regular services have accepted to participate in the study. Participants are consecutively&#xD;
      recruited at the participating agencies. Inclusion will be terminated when 20 children have&#xD;
      been included (whereof at least 12 children aged 3-6 years).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedure. At treatment start caregivers and custodians (this can include foster parents,&#xD;
      social services, and biological parents) will be informed about the study and asked for&#xD;
      consent to participate. Because of their low age children aged 3-6 will be informed and asked&#xD;
      for consent to participate in connection to the interviews. Quantitative data will be&#xD;
      collected by self-report instruments completed by the foster parents before treatment and&#xD;
      after 20 sessions or at termination, if treatment if terminated earlier. Participation,&#xD;
      fidelity, and modifications are registered by clinicians continuously. Foster parents and&#xD;
      clinicians will be asked to schedule interviews by one of the researchers in the project&#xD;
      after 20 sessions or at termination, if treatment if terminated earlier.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background information. Demographical and background data will be collected using a form&#xD;
      designed for this purpose, before treatment and after 20 sessions or at termination, if&#xD;
      treatment is terminated earlier.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Instrument. Qualitative interviews focusing acceptance and experiences of the method will be&#xD;
      conducted with children, foster parents, and clinicians. The interviews will be conducted by&#xD;
      child psychologists experienced in clinical treatment as well as in research with families&#xD;
      with young children in in difficult life situations. The interviews will be recorded and&#xD;
      transcribed verbatim. Clinicians will register participation, fidelity, and any modifications&#xD;
      after each treatment session in a log-book. Quantitative data on outcome concerning exposure,&#xD;
      symptoms of post-traumatic stress, psychological health, and caregiving experiences will be&#xD;
      collected by self-report instruments completed by foster parents before treatment and after&#xD;
      20 sessions or at termination, if treatment is terminated earlier.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analyses. The interviews will be analyzed by thematic analysis or interpretative&#xD;
      phenomenological analysis, according to the applicability in relation to the research&#xD;
      questions and data collected. Descriptive statistical methods will be used to describe&#xD;
      exposure, symptoms pre- and post-treatment, and treatment modifications made. Non-parametric&#xD;
      statistical methods will be used to analyze and describe indications concerning outcome.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 30, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Ecologic or Community</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline score on the Strengths and Difficulties Questionnaire - Parent version at 20 completed sessions or at termination of intervention if terminated earlier.</measure>
    <time_frame>After 20 completed sessions or immediately after termination of the intervention, if terminated earlier than 20 sessions</time_frame>
    <description>Caregiver report of child psychopathology. Minimum score 0, maximum score 40, higher score indicating worse outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline score on the Trauma Symptom Checklist for Young Children at 20 completed sessions or at termination of intervention if terminated earlier.</measure>
    <time_frame>After 20 completed sessions or immediately after termination of the intervention, if terminated earlier than 20 sessions</time_frame>
    <description>Caregiver report of child symptoms of post-traumatic stress. Minimum score 90, maximum score 360, higher score indicating worse outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline score on the Linköping Youth Life Experiences Scale at 20 completed sessions or at termination of intervention if terminated earlier.</measure>
    <time_frame>After 20 completed sessions or immediately after termination of the intervention, if terminated earlier than 20 sessions</time_frame>
    <description>Caregiver report of child exposure to traumatic and adverse life events. Minimum score 0, maximum score 41, higher score indicating worse outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline score on the Child-Parent Psychotherapy Symptom Screener at 20 completed sessions or at termination of intervention if terminated earlier.</measure>
    <time_frame>After 20 completed sessions or immediately after termination of the intervention, if terminated earlier than 20 sessions</time_frame>
    <description>Caregiver report of child symptoms of post-traumatic reactions. Minimum score 0, maximum score 93, higher score indicating worse outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline score on the Hopkins Symptom Check List-25 at 20 completed sessions or at termination of intervention if terminated earlier.</measure>
    <time_frame>After 20 completed sessions or immediately after termination of the intervention, if terminated earlier than 20 sessions</time_frame>
    <description>Caregiver report of psychological distress and symptoms. Minimum score 0, maximum score 100, higher score indicating worse outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline score on the Impact of Event Scale-Revised at 20 completed sessions or at termination of intervention if terminated earlier.</measure>
    <time_frame>After 20 completed sessions or immediately after termination of the intervention, if terminated earlier than 20 sessions</time_frame>
    <description>Caregiver report of symptoms of post-traumatic stress. Minimum score 0, maximum score 80, higher score indicating worse outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline score on the Life Incidence of Traumatic Events Questionnaire at 20 completed sessions or at termination of intervention if terminated earlier.</measure>
    <time_frame>After 20 completed sessions or immediately after termination of the intervention, if terminated earlier than 20 sessions</time_frame>
    <description>Caregiver report of exposure to traumatic and adverse life events. Minimum score 0, maximum score 41, higher score indicating worse outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline score on the Caregiving Helplessness Questionnaire at 20 completed sessions or at termination of intervention if terminated earlier.</measure>
    <time_frame>After 20 completed sessions or immediately after termination of the intervention, if terminated earlier than 20 sessions</time_frame>
    <description>Caregiver report on caregiving experiences. Minimum score 18, maximum score 90, higher score indicating worse outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Adherence</measure>
    <time_frame>After 20 completed sessions or immediately after termination of the intervention if terminated earlier than 20 sessions</time_frame>
    <description>Log of clinicians' ratings of fidelity to the method of Child-Parent Psychotherapy and adaptions immediately after each session, up to 20 times</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Childrens' experiences of participating in Child-Parent Psychotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>After 20 completed sessions or immediately after termination of the intervention if terminated earlier than 20 sessions</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative data from interviews with children 3-6 years old</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Foster parents' experiences of participating in Child-Parent Psychotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>After 20 completed sessions or immediately after termination of the intervention if terminated earlier than 20 sessions</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative data from interviews with foster parents</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Clinicians' experiences of working with Child-Parent Psychotherapy with Children in foster care</measure>
    <time_frame>After 20 completed sessions or immediately after termination of the intervention if terminated earlier than 20 sessions</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative data from interviews with clinicians</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Child Abuse</condition>
  <condition>Child Neglect</condition>
  <condition>Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder in Children</condition>
  <condition>Parent-Child Relations</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Children in fostercare in CPP-treatment</arm_group_label>
    <description>Children in foster care taking part in Child-Parent Psychotherapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Child-Parent Psychotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Relationship-based trauma focused psychotherapy for Children 0-6 years old and their caregivers. The objective is to decrease symptoms of post-traumatic tress and re-establish a secure attachment for the child and good caregiving from the caregiver/s.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Children in fostercare in CPP-treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Children in foster care offered Child-Parent Psychotherapy at any of the nine participating&#xD;
        agencies.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 0-6 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  being offered Child-Parent Psychotherapy as part of their regular treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Families in need of translator for interviews.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>6 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Karin Pernebo, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Psychology, Linnaeus University, Sweden and Department of Research and Development, Region Kronoberg, Sweden</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Research and Development, Region Kronoberg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Växjö</city>
        <zip>35112</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Children</keyword>
  <keyword>Adverse childhood events</keyword>
  <keyword>Post traumatic stress</keyword>
  <keyword>Children in foster care</keyword>
  <keyword>Psychotherapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

