<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04517747</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RE-ExPEL</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04517747</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ramucirumab Plus TAS-102 in Patients With Advanced or Metastatic Gastric Adenocarcinoma or the Gastroesophageal Junction</brief_title>
  <acronym>RE-ExPEL</acronym>
  <official_title>A Pilot Study of Ramucirumab Beyond Progression Plus TAS-102 in Patients With Advanced or Metastatic Adenocarcinoma of the Stomach or the Gastroesophageal Junction, After Treatment Failure on a Ramucirumab Based Therapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Institut für Klinische Krebsforschung IKF GmbH at Krankenhaus Nordwest</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institut für Klinische Krebsforschung IKF GmbH at Krankenhaus Nordwest</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this study is to determine whether a combination of ramucirumab, beyond&#xD;
      progression after a SOC 2nd line ramucirumab based pre-treatment (Ram beyond progression) in&#xD;
      patients with locally advanced or metastatic adenocarcinoma, plus TAS-102 shows good&#xD;
      tolerability without safety issues regarding the serious adverse event rate of any cause, and&#xD;
      whether the combination shows positive signals regarding efficacy in the secondary endpoints&#xD;
      (e.g. prolongation of progression-free survival of TAS-102 plus ramucirumab compared with&#xD;
      TAS-102 monotherapy - historical data according to TAGS trial).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an interventional, prospective, non-randomized, open-label, multicenter single-arm&#xD;
      pilot study of ramucirumab plus TAS-102 in patients with advanced or metastatic&#xD;
      adenocarcinoma of the stomach or the gastroesophageal junction, after treatment failure on a&#xD;
      ramucirumab based therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total number of 20 patients will be enrolled. Potential study participants will be assessed&#xD;
      for eligibility during one or several screening visits. The patient has to provide a signed&#xD;
      informed consent form prior to any study-specific screening evaluations. Once the patient&#xD;
      provides a signed informed consent form and eligibility is confirmed (all inclusion/exclusion&#xD;
      criteria have been verified), the patient can be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All screening procedures must be completed during the 14-day screening period. All patients&#xD;
      must have had disease status confirmed as per CT or MRI scan of the tumor(s) within ≤ 4 weeks&#xD;
      prior to the first dose. Other screening assessments include blood sampling, performance&#xD;
      status (ECOG) and ECG according to clinical routine. Study treatment will be continued until&#xD;
      progression or intolerable toxicity, but for a maximum of 4 months. Further treatment after&#xD;
      progression will be at the investigator's discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tumor assessment will be performed according to clinical routine at screening and every 8&#xD;
      weeks (±7 days) during the treatment phase of the study and every 12 weeks (±14 days) during&#xD;
      follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The expected duration of the active study phase (FPI - LPO) is 18 months. The active phase&#xD;
      per individual patient is approximately 6 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tolerability and toxicity: rate of serious adverse events (SAEs) of any cause</measure>
    <time_frame>Frist Treatment until 30 days after end of treatment, up to 5 months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary endpoint of the study is tolerability and toxicity, defined by the rate of serious adverse events (SAEs) of any cause according to CTCAE v5.0</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of treatment-related AEs and SAE</measure>
    <time_frame>Frist Treatment until 30 days after end of treatment, up to 5 months</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of treatment-related AEs and SAEs according to CTCAE v5.0</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events for neutropenia</measure>
    <time_frame>Frist Treatment until 30 days after end of treatment, up to 5 months</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of grade 3 or worse adverse events for neutropenia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events for anemia</measure>
    <time_frame>Frist Treatment until 30 days after end of treatment, up to 5 months</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of grade 3 or worse adverse events for anemia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events for leucopenia</measure>
    <time_frame>Frist Treatment until 30 days after end of treatment, up to 5 months</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of grade 3 or worse adverse events for leucopenia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events for thrombocytopenia</measure>
    <time_frame>Frist Treatment until 30 days after end of treatment, up to 5 months</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of grade 3 or worse adverse events for thrombocytopenia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Abnormal laboratory parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>Frist Treatment until 30 days after end of treatment, up to 5 months</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of abnormal laboratory parameters</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Progression free survival (PFS) is defined as the time from enrollment to the first documented evidence of disease progression or death; up to 16 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Progression Free Survival (PFS) according to RECIST 1.1, Progression free survival (PFS) is defined as the time from enrollment to the first documented evidence of disease progression or death. If no information will be available for the evaluation of progression, patients will be censored at the timepoint of last tumor assessment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>defined as the time from enrollment up to 16 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Objective response rate is defined as proportion of patients with a best overall response of complete response (CR) or partial response (PR). Tumor response will be evaluated using RECIST 1.1 criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Overall survival (OS) is defined as the time from enrollment to the date of death from any cause.; up to 16 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Overall survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Gastric Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Adenocarcinoma of the Gastroesophageal Junction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ramucirumab plus TAS-102</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Ramucirumab 8 mg/kg i.v. on day 1 and day 15 of a 28-day cycle and TAS-102 35 mg/m2/dose p.o. twice daily on days 1 to 5 and days 8 to 12 of a 28-day cycle Each cycle will be repeated after 28 days (from day 1) for a maximum of 4 cycles.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ramucirumab</intervention_name>
    <description>chemotherapy i.v.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ramucirumab plus TAS-102</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cyramza</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TAS 102</intervention_name>
    <description>p.o. twice daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ramucirumab plus TAS-102</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lonsurf</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Signed informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Men or women* ≥ 18 years of age. Patients of reproductive age must be prepared to use&#xD;
             a suitable contraceptive method during the study and up to 6 months after the end of&#xD;
             treatment. A suitable method of contraception is defined as surgical sterilization&#xD;
             (e.g. bilateral fallopian tube ligation, vasectomy), hormonal contraception&#xD;
             (implantable, patch, oral), and double barrier methods (each two-fold combination of&#xD;
             intrauterine pessary, condom for men, or women with spermicidal gel, diaphragm,&#xD;
             contraceptive sponge, cervical cap). Women of child-bearing potential must have a&#xD;
             negative pregnancy test within the last 7 days prior to the start of study therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
             *There is no data that indicates a specific gender distribution. Therefore, patients&#xD;
             are included regardless of their gender.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Histologically proven adenocarcinoma of the stomach, including adenocarcinoma of the&#xD;
             gastroesophageal junction (note: previous histological assessment during disease&#xD;
             history of patient sufficient, current biopsy during screening for this trial is not&#xD;
             mandatory)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Documented, objective, radiological or clinical progression of the disease during or&#xD;
             within 4-6 weeks after the last dose of a ramucirumab based second-line therapy&#xD;
             (ramucirumab monotherapy or a combination of ramucirumab + paclitaxel, respectively&#xD;
             ramucirumab + FOLFIRI).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Measurable or non-measurable but evaluable disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. ECOG Performance status 0-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Life expectancy &gt; 8 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Appropriate haematological, hepatic and renal function:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Absolute number of neutrophils (ANC) ≥ 1.5 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Platelets ≥ 100 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dL (5.58 mmol/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times the upper limit of normal (UNL)&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. AST (SGOT) and ALT (SGPT) ≤ 2.5 x UNL without existing liver metastases, or ≤ 5 x&#xD;
                  UNL in the presence of liver metastases; AP ≤ 5 x UNL&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x UNL or creatinine clearance (measured by 24h urine) ≥ 40 mL /&#xD;
             min (i.e. if the serum creatinine level is &gt; 1.5 x UNL, then a 24h urine test must be&#xD;
             performed to check the creatinine clearance to be determined). Protein level in urine&#xD;
             ≤ 1+ by dipstick analysis or routine urine measurement (if the dipstick analysis or&#xD;
             the routine test ≥ 2+, a subsequent 24h urine protein measurement must show a value of&#xD;
             &lt; 1000mg of protein within 24h of participation to ensure the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Adequate coagulability, as determined by the International Normalized Ratio (INR) ≤&#xD;
             1.5 and partial thromboplastin time (PTT) ≤ 5 seconds above the UNL (unless&#xD;
             anti-coagulation therapy has been given). Patients receiving warfarin / phenoprocoumon&#xD;
             must be switched to low molecular weight heparin and must have a stable coagulation&#xD;
             profile before starting study-specific therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subject is willing and able to comply with the protocol (including contraceptive&#xD;
             measures) for the duration of the study including undergoing treatment and scheduled&#xD;
             visits and examinations including follow up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Presence of tumors other than adenocarcinomas (e.g., leiomyosarcoma, lymphoma) or a&#xD;
             secondary tumor other than squamous or basal cell carcinomas of the skin or in situ&#xD;
             carcinomas of the cervix which have been effectively treated. The sponsor decides to&#xD;
             include patients who have received curative treatment and have been disease-free for&#xD;
             at least 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Squamous cell carcinoma of the stomach or gastroesophageal junction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Simultaneous, ongoing, systemic immunotherapy, chemotherapy, or hormone therapy not&#xD;
             described in the study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Simultaneous treatment with a different anti-cancer therapy other than that provided&#xD;
             for in the study (excluding palliative radiotherapy for symptom control).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The patient is receiving chronic antiplatelet therapy, including aspirin, nonsteroidal&#xD;
             anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs, including ibuprofen, naproxen, and others),&#xD;
             dipyridamole or clopidogrel, or similar agents. Once-daily aspirin use (maximum dose&#xD;
             325 mg/day) is permitted&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The patient has undergone major surgery within the last 28 days prior to the start of&#xD;
             study-specific therapy or has undergone minor surgery within the last 7 days prior to&#xD;
             the start of study therapy. The patient had subcutaneous venous access within the last&#xD;
             7 days prior to the start of the study-specific therapy. The patient plans to undergo&#xD;
             major surgery while participating in the clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Gastrointestinal bleeding grade 3-4 within the last 3 months prior to enrollment in&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of deep vein thrombosis (DVT), pulmonary embolism (PE), or any other&#xD;
             clinically important thromboembolic event during the last 3 months prior to the start&#xD;
             of study-specific therapy (thrombosis caused by venous ports, catheters, or&#xD;
             superficial venous thrombosis are not considered &quot;clinically meaningful&quot;).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Stage B cirrhosis according to Child-Pugh criteria (or worse) or cirrhosis (of any&#xD;
             grade) with a history of hepatic encephalopathy or clinically significant ascites&#xD;
             resulting from cirrhosis. Clinically significant ascites is defined as ascites&#xD;
             resulting from cirrhosis requiring diuretics or paracentesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Known brain or leptomeningeal metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Known allergic / hypersensitive reactions to at least one of the treatment components.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Other serious illnesses or medical ailments within the last 12 months prior to the&#xD;
             start of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Any arterial thromboembolic event which includes, but is not limited to, the&#xD;
             following: myocardial infarction, transient ischemic attack, cerebrovascular insult,&#xD;
             unstable angina within the last 6 months prior to the initiation of study therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Uncontrolled or under-adjusted hypertension (&gt; 160 mmHg systolic or &gt; 100 mmHg&#xD;
             diastolic hypertension for more than 4 weeks) despite standard medical treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Presence of an active, uncontrollable infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Chronic inflammatory bowel disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Active disseminated intravascular coagulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Any other serious concomitant or medical condition that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator, presents a high risk of complications to the patient or reduces the&#xD;
             likelihood of clinical effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Known dihydropyrimidine dehydrogenase (DPD) deficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. History of gastrointestinal perforation / fistula (within the last 6 months prior to&#xD;
             the start of study-specific therapy) or presence of risk factors favoring perforation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Serious or non-healing wounds, ulcers, or broken bones within the last 28 days prior&#xD;
             to the start of study-specific therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. The patient is pregnant or breast-feeding.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thorsten O Götze, Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Institute of Clinical Cancer Research UCT - University Cancer Center Frankfurt</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institute for Clinical Cancer Research Krankenhaus Nordwest</name>
      <address>
        <city>Frankfurt</city>
        <zip>60488</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hamburg Hämatologisch-Onkologische Praxis Eppendorf-Facharztzentrum Eppendorf</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>20246</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tagestherapiezentrum am ITM Universitätsmedizin Mannheim</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mannheim</city>
        <zip>68167</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Technische Universität München Klinikum Rechts der Isar</name>
      <address>
        <city>Muenchen</city>
        <zip>81675</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Ulm</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ulm</city>
        <zip>89081</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 17, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 18, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ramucirumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

