<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04515836</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB20-0117</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04515836</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Olaparib in Patients With HRD Malignant Mesothelioma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Trial of Olaparib in Homologous Recombination Deficient (HRD) Malignant Mesothelioma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Chicago</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Chicago</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this study, researchers will give olaparib (a drug) to mesothelioma patients who have&#xD;
      specific changes in their DNA (known as gene mutations). Researchers will give this drug to&#xD;
      each patient on the study to find out if it will help the patient's tumor shrink or stop&#xD;
      growing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 19, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 15, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 15, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate of Patients to Olaparib</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years.</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the percentage of patients with mesothelioma tumors (containing certain gene/cell mutations) that shrink or stop growing as a response to olaparib.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival of Patients Taking Olaparib</measure>
    <time_frame>Three years.</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the length of time patients on the study are still alive after taking olaparib.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-Free Survival of Patients Taking Olaparib</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years.</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the length of time patients taking olaparib can live with mesothelioma without their cancer getting worse.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of Treatment-Related Side Effects/ Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years.</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the frequency of treatment-related side effects/ adverse events reported among study participants. These side effects will be assessed by attribution (source), type and grade. Adverse events/side effects will be graded using the NCI Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (Version 5).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">56</enrollment>
  <condition>Mesothelioma</condition>
  <condition>Homologous Recombination Deficiency</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Olaparib will be given orally to patients in 28-day cycles. Patients will attend the clinic on days 1 (first day of treatment) and 15 of the first cycle following the beginning of study treatment and then every 4 weeks (day 1 of every cycle) until discontinuation of treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Olaparib</intervention_name>
    <description>Olaparib is a chemotherapy drug (packaged as a pill) that can be taken by mouth, twice daily.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lynparza</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have a medical diagnosis of malignant mesothelioma that has been confirmed by a&#xD;
             physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must be able to sign a consent form stating that they choose (of their own&#xD;
             free will) to participate in the study and agree to follow the study requirements and&#xD;
             restrictions that are listed in the consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be willing to sign and date consent form before any mandatory study-specific&#xD;
             procedures, sample collecting and tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to experience genetic testing to determine study eligibility. Must be willing&#xD;
             to genetically test tumor and normal body cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Before participating in the treatment phase of this study, participants must be&#xD;
             willing to give their own consent (agreement) to have their samples collected for&#xD;
             genetic and biomarker research.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must show evidence of specific DNA changes/genetic mutations defined as&#xD;
             follows: A) BAP1 loss (the loss of a protein called ubiquitin carboxyl-terminal&#xD;
             hydrolase) verified by physicians at the University of Chicago using sampling tests&#xD;
             AND/OR B) A mutation (abnormal change) in the participant's germ cells (reproductive&#xD;
             cells) or somatic cells (non-reproductive cells) that disrupts protein function in at&#xD;
             least one of the patient's genes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with cisplatin or carboplatin is required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have platinum-sensitive disease (cancer that responds to treatments with&#xD;
             anticancer drugs containing metal platinum). For eligibility in this study,&#xD;
             platinum-sensitive disease will be defined as no disease progression while on a&#xD;
             platinum agent (chemotherapy drug) or for at least 3 months after completing treatment&#xD;
             with a platinum agent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have normal organ and bone marrow function measured within 28 days prior&#xD;
             to receiving study treatment. Normal bone marrow and organ function will be assessed&#xD;
             using specific lab tests/ criteria set by the study's lead physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a life expectancy of 16 weeks or more.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have a tumor that can be measured according to criteria set by the modified&#xD;
             Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) standards for pleural&#xD;
             mesothelioma and RECIST 1.1 for peritoneal and tunica vaginalis mesothelioma. Patients&#xD;
             in the study must have at least one area of damaged tissue (a lesion) that has not&#xD;
             received previous radiation treatment. This damaged tissue must be accurately measured&#xD;
             at the beginning of the study as greater than or equal to 10 mm in the longest&#xD;
             diameter (except lymph nodes which must have short axis greater than or equal to 15&#xD;
             mm). The patient's tumor would be measured using computed tomography (CT), which is&#xD;
             suitable for accurate repeated measurements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both male and female patients can participate in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If a woman is of childbearing potential and wishes to participate in the study, she&#xD;
             most show evidence that she is not pregnant using a negative urine or serum pregnancy&#xD;
             test within 28 days of study treatment and confirmed prior to treatment on day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are postmenopausal and wish to participate in the study, must also show&#xD;
             evidence of postmenopausal status. Postmenopausal status will be defined as: 1) A&#xD;
             woman who does not experience menstruation (known as amenorrhea) for 1 year or more&#xD;
             following the end of hormonal treatments. 2) Women who have reproductive/hormone&#xD;
             levels in the post-menopausal range for women under 50 as confirmed by medical tests;&#xD;
             3) Radiation-induced oophorectomy (removal of one or more ovaries) with last menses&#xD;
             greater than 1 year ago; 4) Menopause caused by chemotherapy with greater than 1 year&#xD;
             since last menses 5) Surgical sterilization (bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male patients must use a condom during treatment and for 3 months after the last dose&#xD;
             of study drug (olaparib) when having sexual intercourse with a pregnant woman or with&#xD;
             a woman of childbearing potential. Female partners of male patients should also use a&#xD;
             highly effective form of contraception if they are of childbearing potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  NOTE 1: Tests to confirm the eligibility of participants who have the above mutations&#xD;
             (altered germ or somatic cells) will take place at a germline or tumor sequencing lab&#xD;
             that is certified under the Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments (CLIA).&#xD;
             Eligibility of study participants will be confirmed once the physical leading this&#xD;
             study receives the official mutation report from the lab and confirms that the&#xD;
             participant's identified mutation fits the definition outlined above. All other&#xD;
             patients must consent to tumor and normal sample sequencing as described in study&#xD;
             procedures below during the prescreening phase to determine eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  NOTE 2: Rare exceptions of participants who may have conflicting evidence regarding&#xD;
             protein function will be interpreted on an individual basis by the physician leading&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Medical conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any evidence of uncontrollable illness that the physician leading this study deems&#xD;
             undesirable for the patient to participate in the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other malignancy (tumor/cancer) unless it has been treated with no evidence of disease&#xD;
             for 3 or more years except: adequately treated non-melanoma skin cancer, curatively&#xD;
             treated in situ cancer of the cervix, ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS), Stage 1, grade&#xD;
             1 endometrial carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with BAP1 tumor predisposition syndrome will be included in the trial. These&#xD;
             patients may be eligible if they have a history of syndrome-related cancers, provided&#xD;
             they completed their surgery and chemotherapy more than three years prior to&#xD;
             registration, and the patient remains free of disease that continues to re-occur or&#xD;
             spread to other parts of the body.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with cancer that does not respond to platinum chemotherapy drugs (known as&#xD;
             platinum-resistant disease), defined as disease progression during or within 3 months&#xD;
             of receiving chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Resting electrocardiogram (ECG) that shows the patient has uncontrolled, potentially&#xD;
             reversible cardiac conditions or patients with congenital long QT syndrome (a heart&#xD;
             rhythm condition that can cause fast, chaotic heartbeats), as judged by the study's&#xD;
             lead physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persistent toxicities (greater than the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Event&#xD;
             (CTCAE) grade 2) caused by previous cancer therapy, excluding alopecia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS)/acute myeloid leukemia (AML) or with&#xD;
             findings suggestive of MDS/AML.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with cancer cells that have moved from one part of their body to the brain&#xD;
             (brain metastases) causing the patient to show symptoms/signs of more serious illness.&#xD;
             A scan to confirm the absence of cancerous cells in the brain is not required. The&#xD;
             patient can receive a stable dose of corticosteroids before and during the study as&#xD;
             long as these were started at least 4 weeks prior to treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with spinal cord compression unless considered to have received definitive&#xD;
             treatment for this and evidence of clinically stable disease for 28 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients considered a poor medical risk due to a serious, uncontrolled medical&#xD;
             disorder, non-cancerous systemic disease or active, uncontrolled infection. Examples&#xD;
             include, but are not limited to, uncontrolled ventricular arrhythmia, recent (within 3&#xD;
             months) myocardial infarction, uncontrolled major seizure disorder, unstable spinal&#xD;
             cord compression, superior vena cava syndrome, extensive interstitial bilateral lung&#xD;
             disease on High Resolution Computed Tomography (HRCT) scan or any psychiatric disorder&#xD;
             that prohibits obtaining informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unable to swallow oral medications and patients with gastrointestinal&#xD;
             disorders likely to interfere with absorption of the study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have a compromised immune system, e.g., patients who have tested positive&#xD;
             for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known active hepatitis (i.e. Hepatitis B or C) confirmed by medical&#xD;
             tests; patients with a past or resolved Hepatitis B infection are eligible. Patients&#xD;
             positive for hepatitis C virus are eligible only if samples of the patient's DNA tests&#xD;
             negative for hepatitis C, according to genetic tests (using polymerase chain&#xD;
             reaction).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Prior/concomitant therapy (medications/treatments that may conflict with the study drug,&#xD;
        olaparib):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any previous treatment with a type of drug/substance called a PARP inhibitor (which&#xD;
             stands for poly-ADP ribose polymerase inhibitor), including olaparib.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of any systemic chemotherapy or radiotherapy (except for palliative reasons)&#xD;
             within 3 weeks prior to study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are using strong cancer drugs called CYP3A inhibitors (also called&#xD;
             Cytochrome P-450) for treatment (eg. itraconazole, telithromycin, clarithromycin,&#xD;
             protease inhibitors boosted with ritonavir or cobicistat, indinavir, saquinavir,&#xD;
             nelfinavir, boceprevir, telaprevir) or moderate CYP3A inhibitors (eg. ciprofloxacin,&#xD;
             erythromycin, diltiazem, fluconazole, verapamil). Any treatment previously taken by&#xD;
             the patient must be washed out of the patient's system 2 weeks before taking olaparib&#xD;
             in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are using known strong CYP3A inducers (drugs for cancer patients&#xD;
             including phenobarbital, enzalutamide, phenytoin, rifampicin, rifabutin, rifapentine,&#xD;
             carbamazepine, nevirapine and St John's Wort) or moderate CYP3A inducers (eg.&#xD;
             bosentan, efavirenz, modafinil). Any patients taking enzalutamide must have the drug&#xD;
             washed out of their system 5 weeks before stating olaparib in this study; patients&#xD;
             taking phenobarbital and other agents must have the drug washed out of their system 3&#xD;
             weeks before taking olaparib in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery within 2 weeks of starting study treatment; patients must have recovered&#xD;
             from any effects of any major surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous allogenic bone marrow transplant or double umbilical cord blood&#xD;
             transplantation (dUCBT).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Prior/concurrent clinical study experience:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in another clinical study where the patient received a study drug in the&#xD;
             last month before starting this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a known hypersensitivity to olaparib or any of the ingredients in the&#xD;
             product.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Other exclusions:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Involvement in the planning and/or conduct of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The lead study physician deciding that the patient should not participate in the study&#xD;
             if the patient is unlikely to follow study procedures, restrictions and requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast-feeding women.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hedy L Kindler, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Chicago</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hedy L Kindler, MD</last_name>
    <phone>773-702-0360</phone>
    <email>hkindler@medicine.bsd.uchicago.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Chicago Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60615</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>mesothelioma, lung cancer, malignant mesothelioma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mesothelioma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mesothelioma, Malignant</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Olaparib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

