<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04516304</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BIO-1811</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04516304</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Nutritional Supplement on Vasomotor Symptoms in Women</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Double-Blind, Randomized, Placebo-Controlled Study to Assess a Nutritional Supplement on Vasomotor Symptoms In Perimenopausal and Menopausal Women</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pharmavite LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Biofortis, Merieux NutriSciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pharmavite LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Vasomotor symptoms (VMS), such as flushes, sweating, and sleep disturbances, are experienced&#xD;
      by up to 80% of women during the menopausal transition. Night sweats, which are hot flushes&#xD;
      that occur at night, can be particularly bothersome in women and contribute to disturbed&#xD;
      sleep. These symptoms occur mainly during the 1-3 years prior to menopause (late&#xD;
      perimenopause) and early menopause (~4 years after menstruation ceases). Many women look to&#xD;
      supplements for the management of menopausal symptoms. Soy isoflavones and their metabolites&#xD;
      are one category of dietary supplements that have been extensively studied for the management&#xD;
      of VMS. The most active soy isoflavone is S-equol, which is not found directly in soy, but&#xD;
      rather is the metabolite that is produced by gut microflora from consumption of the soy&#xD;
      isoflavone daidzein. However, only 20-30% of US women are actually able to produce S-equol&#xD;
      from the consumption of daidzein. Equelle® is a currently available dietary supplement that&#xD;
      has S-equol as its active component, which allows the delivery of the active soy isoflavone&#xD;
      metabolite directly without dependence on the gut microflora metabolism. The intention of&#xD;
      this study is to assess the effect of a product containing S-equol on the management of VMS&#xD;
      in normally healthy women.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Condition or disease: Vasomotor Symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention/treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dietary Supplement: S-equol Dietary Supplement: Placebo&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind, parallel study, which will include a&#xD;
      screening visit (Visit 1; week -3), a 2-week run-in period for baseline determination and&#xD;
      assessment of placebo response (Visit 2; week -2; and Visit 3; week -1), one baseline visit&#xD;
      (Visit 4; week 0), and three test visits (Visits 5, 6, and 7; weeks 4, 8, and 12).&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Visit 1 (week -3), after subjects have provided informed consent, medical history will be&#xD;
      reviewed, and clinic visit procedures will be performed, including assessments of&#xD;
      prior/current medication/supplement use, evaluations of inclusion/exclusion criteria, and a&#xD;
      last menses query. Fasting (10-14 h) blood samples will be collected for assessment of FSH&#xD;
      and estradiol levels. The Soy Food Frequency Questionnaire will be administered and subjects&#xD;
      will be instructed to maintain their habitual diets (with the exception of avoiding soy&#xD;
      foods) and physical activity patterns throughout the study period. Additionally, subjects&#xD;
      will be dispensed the Insomnia Severity Index Questionnaire (ISIQ) and the VMS Diary to&#xD;
      assess insomnia and VMS, respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Visit 2 (week -2), eligible subjects will be instructed to start the run-in placebo&#xD;
      product for two weeks. Subjects will be also instructed to continue daily recording in the&#xD;
      VMS Diary. At Visit 3 (week -1), the VMS Diary will be collected/reviewed to assess response&#xD;
      to the run-in placebo product. Subjects who continue to meet the inclusion/exclusion criteria&#xD;
      will be allowed to continue with the study and will be dispensed a sleep tracking device to&#xD;
      wear for sleep/wake pattern evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Visit 4 (week 0), eligible subjects will be randomized to one of the study products&#xD;
      (Active or Placebo) and instructed to consume with water for 12 weeks. Additionally, the&#xD;
      Pittsburg Sleep Quality Index (PSQI), RAND-36 Questionnaire, Profile of Mood States (POMS),&#xD;
      Day-to-Day Impact of Vaginal Aging Questionnaire (DIVQ), Chalder Fatigue Scale, and&#xD;
      Menopause-Specific Quality of Life (MENQOL) Questionnaire will be administered. The VMS Diary&#xD;
      and ISIQ will be collected and reviewed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Visits 5 and 6 (weeks 4 and 8), the VMS Diary and ISIQ will be collected/reviewed, and the&#xD;
      PSQI and MENQOL will be administered. Subjects will return to the clinic prior to Visit 7&#xD;
      (week 12) to receive the sleep tracking device to wear for sleep/wake pattern evaluation one&#xD;
      week (7 d) prior to Visit 7 (week 12).&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Visit 7 (week 12), the VMS Diary and ISIQ will be collected and reviewed. The PSQI,&#xD;
      RAND-36, POMS, DIVQ, Chalder Fatigue Scale, and MENQOL will be administered and study product&#xD;
      will be collected/reviewed, and compliance will be determined. Additionally, the sleep&#xD;
      tracker will be collected, and data will be downloaded for evaluation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 27, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 22, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 22, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Vasomotor symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Week 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Daily frequency of vasomotor symptoms, including hot flushes and night sweats</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vasomotor symptom</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Weeks 4 and 8]</time_frame>
    <description>Daily frequency of vasomotor symptoms, including hot flushes and night sweats</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hot Flush</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Weeks 4, 8, and 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Daily frequency of hot flush</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Night Sweat</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Weeks 4, 8, and 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Daily frequency of night sweat</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vasomotor symptom severity - number</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Weeks 4, 8, and 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average number of moderate-to-severe VMS episode per day</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vasomotor symptom severity - total score</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Weeks 4, 8, and 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average of VMS severity total score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hot flush symptom severity - number</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Weeks 4, 8, and 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average number of moderate-to-severe hot flush episode per day</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hot flush severity - total score</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Weeks 4, 8, and 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average of hot flush severity total score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Night sweat severity - number</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Weeks 4, 8, and 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average number of moderate-to-severe night sweat episode per day</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Night sweat severity - total score</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Weeks 4, 8, and 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average night sweat severity total score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insomnia score</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Weeks 4, 8, and 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average insomnia score per day obtained from Insomnia severity questionnaire (ISIQ)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep duration</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Week 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average sleep duration per day, obtained from sleep tracker</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Actual sleep duration</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Week 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average actual sleep duration per day obtained from sleep tracker</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep efficiency</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Week 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average sleep efficiency per day obtained from sleep tracker</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep onset latency</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Week 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average sleep onset latency per day obtained from sleep tracker</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Latency to persistent sleep</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Week 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average latency to persistent sleep per day obtained from sleep tracker</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Wake after sleep onset</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Week 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average wake after sleep onset per day obtained from sleep tracker</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Week 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average fatigue score obtained from Chalder fatigue scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep quality</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Weeks 4, 8, and 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average sleep quality obtained from Pittsburgh sleep quality index</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vaginal bothersome score</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Week 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average bothersome score obtained from Vaginal bothersome symptoms diary</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vaginal aging score</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Week 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average vaginal aging score obtained from Day-to-day impact vaginal aging questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Menopause-specific quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Weeks 4, 8, and 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average score obtained from Menopause-specific quality of life</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>General quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Week 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average score obtained from RAND-36 questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mood</measure>
    <time_frame>[Time Frame: Change from baseline to Weeks 4, 8, and 12]</time_frame>
    <description>Average score obtained from Profile of mood states (POMS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">118</enrollment>
  <condition>Menopause</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>S-equol</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>4 tablets/d (2 in the morning and 2 in the evening)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>S-equol</intervention_name>
    <description>4 tablets/d (2 in the morning and 2 in the evening), providing 10 mg S-equol total a day Other Names: •Equelle®</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject is a perimenopausal or menopausal female experiencing specific&#xD;
             menopausal-related VMS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject has a BMI of ≥18.5 to ≤38.0 kg/m2 at Visit 1 (week -3).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. At screening visit (Visit 1; week -3), subject reports to have 4 or more moderate to&#xD;
             severe hot flushes/night sweats during 24 h prior to the visit. At Visit 3 (week -1),&#xD;
             subject has ≥25 moderate to severe hot flushes/night sweats per week for one week&#xD;
             between Visit 2 and 3 (weeks -2 and -1). At Visit 4 (week 0), subject has an average&#xD;
             ≥28 moderate to severe hot flushes/night sweats per week for 2 weeks before Visit 4&#xD;
             (week 0).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject is willing to maintain habitual diet (with the exception of restricted&#xD;
             foods/beverages), physical activity patterns, and body weight during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject is willing to abstain from using products (other than study product) that&#xD;
             contains estrogen, progestin, or progesterone within 30 d prior to Visit 1 (week -3)&#xD;
             and throughout the study trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. If a smoker, subject is willing to maintain current smoking habits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject has no health conditions that would prevent her from fulfilling the study&#xD;
             requirements as judged by the Clinical Investigator on the basis of medical history&#xD;
             and routine laboratory test results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject understands the study procedures and signs forms providing informed consent to&#xD;
             participate in the study and authorizes the release of relevant protected health&#xD;
             information to the Clinical Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject has abnormal laboratory test results of clinical importance at Visit 1 (week&#xD;
             -3) at the discretion of the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject has a history or presence of clinically important pulmonary (including&#xD;
             uncontrolled asthma), cardiac (including, but not limited to, atherosclerotic disease,&#xD;
             history of myocardial infarction, peripheral arterial disease, stroke), hepatic,&#xD;
             renal, endocrine, hematologic, immunologic (including chronic inflammatory&#xD;
             conditions), neurologic (such as Alzheimer's or Parkinson's disease), psychiatric&#xD;
             (including depression and/or anxiety disorders) or biliary disorders, that, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the Clinical Investigator, could interfere with the interpretation of the&#xD;
             study results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject has a history or presence of any gastrointestinal condition that could&#xD;
             potentially interfere with absorption of the study product (e.g., inflammatory bowel&#xD;
             syndrome, celiac disease, history of gastric bypass surgery).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject has a history of estrogen-dependent neoplasia, atypical ductual hyperplasia of&#xD;
             the breast, or undiagnosed vaginal bleeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject has a history of endometrial hyperplasia, melanoma, or uterine/endometrial&#xD;
             breast or ovarian cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject has uncontrolled hypertension (systolic blood pressure ≥140 mm Hg or diastolic&#xD;
             blood pressure ≥90 mm Hg) as defined by the blood pressure measured at Visit 1 (week&#xD;
             -3). One re-test will be allowed on a separate day for subjects whose blood pressure&#xD;
             exceeds either of these cut points at Visit 1, in the judgment of the Clinical&#xD;
             Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject has a history of any major trauma or major surgical event within two months of&#xD;
             Visit 1 (week -3).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject has a history or presence of cancer in the prior 2 years to Visit 1 (week -3),&#xD;
             except for non-melanoma skin cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subject has a contraindication to estrogen and/or progestin therapy or&#xD;
             allergy/sensitivity to the use of estradiol and/or progesterone, soy, or any&#xD;
             components in the study product.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subject has used estrogen alone or estrogen/progestin, selective estrogen receptor&#xD;
             modulator, testosterone, or estrogen/testosterone within 30 d prior to Visit 1 (week&#xD;
             -3).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subject has used any prescription or over-the-counter products/supplements (e.g., soy&#xD;
             products, herbal supplements) that have potential to alter progesterone or estrogen&#xD;
             activity or is being used to treat VMS within 30 d prior to Visit 1 (week -3).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subject has self-described extreme or irregular dietary habits, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             Clinical Investigator or has been diagnosed with an eating disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subject has elective hospitalizations planned (e.g., elective cosmetic procedures)&#xD;
             during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subject has been exposed to any non-registered drug product or has participated in&#xD;
             another intervention study within 30 d prior to Visit 1 (week -3).&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Subject has a recent history of (within 12 months of screening; Visit 1; week -3) or&#xD;
             strong potential for alcohol or substance abuse. Alcohol abuse is defined as &gt;14&#xD;
             drinks per week (1 drink = 12 oz beer, 5 oz wine, or 1½ oz distilled spirits).&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Individual has a condition the Clinical Investigator believes would interfere with his&#xD;
             ability to provide informed consent, comply with the study protocol, which might&#xD;
             confound the interpretation of the study results, or put the subject at undue risk.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Biofortis Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Addison</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60601</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 13, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 13, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 18, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 13, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 13, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 18, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>menopause</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Equol</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

