<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04510428</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-0925</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04510428</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>OSIG-eye Drops Treatment for Dry Eye Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Randomized Placebo-Controlled, Double Blind, Single-Center, Tolerability and Efficacy Clinical Trial of Ocular Surface Immunoglobulin (OSIG) Eye Drops In Patients With Dry Eye Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Illinois at Chicago</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Illinois at Chicago</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main objective of this study is to assess the clinical and mechanistic effect of using&#xD;
      Ocular surface immunoglobulin (OSIG) eye drops for treating Dry Eye Disease. Therefore, the&#xD;
      investigator will perform a prospective, phase II, randomized, placebo-controlled,&#xD;
      double-masked, tolerability and efficacy clinical trial using OSIG-eye drops in patients with&#xD;
      Dry Eye Disease. This clinical trial will be powered to detect efficacy of the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This will be a Randomized controlled trial, in which a total of 40 subjects will be enrolled&#xD;
      at one clinical site. Subjects will be randomly assigned to one of two groups (#1, #2), with&#xD;
      20 subjects per group. One group will be given placebo (Normal saline eye drops) and the&#xD;
      other group will be given eye drops containing the study drug (OSIG). Treatment will be for&#xD;
      eight weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 14, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean reduction in Epitheliopathy at week 8, compared to day 1 (pre-dose), as measured by corneal staining score using National Eye Institute (NEI) grading scale.</measure>
    <time_frame>8 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Corneal staining score as measured by Lissamine Green dye staining using National Eye Institute (NEI) grading scale. Dye is applied to each eye and a slit lamp is used to observe corneal staining. NEI scale relies on a chart that divides the cornea into 5 sections and assigns a value from 0 (absent) to 3 (severe) to each section, based on the density of punctate staining, final staining score being the sum of individual section scores with a range of 0 (minimum) -15 (maximum) points. Complete corneal staining clearance with Lissamine dye defined as a score of 0 indicating the best outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean reduction in Dry Eye Disease (DED) symptoms as measured by the Ocular surface disease index (OSDI) score at 8 week, compared to day 1 (pre-dose)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Ocular Surface Disease Index (OSDI), a 12-item questionnaire, assesses symptom of ocular irritation in dry eye disease (DED) and how it affects functioning related to vision in the past week. It has 3 subscales: ocular symptoms, vision-related function, and environmental triggers. Patients rate their responses on 0 to 4 scale with 0 being &quot;none of the time&quot; and 4 being &quot;all of the time.&quot; OSDI score range from 0-100 with score 0-12 being normal, 13-22 being mild DED, 23-32 being moderate DED, and &gt;33 being severe DED. OSDI=[(sum of scores for questions answered)×100]/[(total questions answered)×4]</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Analog Scale at 8 Weeks (56 Days)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Subjects will assess their tolerance to the administration of the test medication (placebo/ study drug), utilizing a Visual Analog Scale (VAS). The VAS is a 100 mm horizontal line with verbal descriptors at either end. Subjects will place a single slash mark across the horizontal line between the end labeled &quot;completely intolerable&quot; (0 mm) and &quot;easily tolerable&quot; (100mm). The VAS ratings will be completed after administration of the test medication on Day 1 (post-dose), week 4 and week 8.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Dry Eye</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>OSIG-Eye Drop</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Ocular Surface Immune Globulin (OSIG) eye drops 4 mg/ml (0.4%) four times a day for 8 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo-Eye Drop</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Normal Saline Eye Drops (0.9% NaCl) four times a day for 8 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ocular Surface Immune Globulin (OSIG)</intervention_name>
    <description>Ocular Surface Immune Globulin (OSIG) eye drops 4 mg/ml (0.4%) four times a day for 8 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>OSIG-Eye Drop</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Normal Saline Eye Drops (0.9% NaCl) four times a day for 8 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo-Eye Drop</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Able to Sign and date the informed consent form approved by the Institutional Review&#xD;
             Board (IRB)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ≥ 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient reported dry eye-related ocular symptoms for at least 3 months before the&#xD;
             Screening Visit and use or desire to use artificial tears, ointments or dry eye&#xD;
             treatments in the 2 weeks preceding the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Women must be post-menopausal ≥ 1 year, or surgically sterilized. If not, a negative&#xD;
             urine pregnancy test is required within 14 days of receiving her first dose of test&#xD;
             medication (placebo/ study drug) along with definite evidence of contraceptive use&#xD;
             during the duration of the study. Women of reproductive age should use a method of&#xD;
             birth control that is acceptable to the subject and the study doctor. This may include&#xD;
             oral contraceptive pills, birth control implants, barrier methods or abstinence. If a&#xD;
             subject mentions she suspects she may be pregnant after being enrolled, another&#xD;
             pregnancy test will be administered. If the test is positive, she will be discontinued&#xD;
             from the study immediately.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Be willing/able to return for all study visits and to follow instructions from the&#xD;
             study investigator and his staff&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Inability to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Vulnerable populations, such as neonates, children, prisoners, institutionalized&#xD;
             individuals, or others who may be considered vulnerable populations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Contact lens wear within two weeks of baseline visit.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sandeep Jain, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Illinois at Chicago</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sandeep Jain, MD</last_name>
    <phone>312-355-5220</phone>
    <email>jains@uic.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Illinois Eye and Ear Infirmary, University of Illinois</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 6, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 12, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Illinois at Chicago</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sandeep Jain, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dry Eye Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Keratoconjunctivitis Sicca</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Eye Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>gamma-Globulins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulins, Intravenous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rho(D) Immune Globulin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

