<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04511637</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20088</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04511637</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Compare the Effect of the Formulations (Orally Disintegrating Tablet and Film-coated Tablet) on the Bioequivalence of Drug Rivaroxaban (Xarelto) at Dose of 15 mg in Japanese Healthy Male Adult Subjects</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized, Non-blinded, Two-way Crossover Study to Assess Bioequivalence Between a Rivaroxaban 15 mg Orally Disintegrating Tablet Administered With Water or Without Water and a Rivaroxaban 15 mg Film-coated Tablet in Japanese Healthy Male Adult Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bayer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bayer</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Researchers in this study wanted to compare the effect of the formulation (orally&#xD;
      disintegrating tablet and film-coated tablet) on the bioequivalence of drug Rivaroxaban&#xD;
      (brand name: Xarelto) at dose of 15 mg in Japanese healthy male subjects aged 20 to 40 years.&#xD;
      Rivaroxaban is an approved drug to be used for the prevention of events/diseases caused by&#xD;
      blood clots. Currently, there are two formulations of Rivaroxaban available on the market in&#xD;
      Japan and they are film-coated tablets and fine granules. To further improve patients'&#xD;
      convenience, a new formulation, orally disintegrating tablet (ODT, a drug dosage form&#xD;
      designed to be dissolved on the tongue rather than swallowed whole) is under development. The&#xD;
      goal of this study was to compare the effect of this new formulation with film-coated tablets&#xD;
      when taken with or without water.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in this study received one oral dose of rivaroxaban 15 mg ODT either with or&#xD;
      without water and one oral dose of rivaroxaban 15 mg film-tablet. There were at least 5 days&#xD;
      between the two doses. Observation for each participant lasted about 6 weeks in total. Blood&#xD;
      samples were collected from the participants to measure the blood level of the study drug.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 21, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 12, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 7, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax for plasma rivaroxaban concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 hours after study medication</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum observed concentration</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC(0-tlast) for plasma rivaroxaban concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 hours after study medication</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the concentration versus time curve from time 0 to the last data point &gt; lower limit of quantitation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects with treatment-emergent adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days after study medication</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Clinical Pharmacology</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Test C: 15 mg ODT with water, then 15 mg film-coated tablet</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants received one single dose of 15 mg rivaroxaban orally disintegrating tablet (ODT) with water in the fasted state. After a washing period of 5 days, participants received one single oral dose of 15 mg rivaroxaban film-coated tablet in the fasted state</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Test C: 15 mg film-coated tablet, then 15 mg ODT with water</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants received one single dose of 15 mg rivaroxaban film-coated tablet in the fasted state. After a washing period of 5 days, participants received one single oral dose of 15 mg rivaroxaban orally disintegrating tablet (ODT) with water in the fasted state</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Test D: 15 mg ODT without water, then 15 film-coated tablet</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants received one single dose of 15 mg rivaroxaban orally disintegrating tablet (ODT) without water in the fasted state. After a washing period of 5 days, participants received one single oral dose of 15 mg rivaroxaban film-coated tablet in the fasted state</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Test D: 15 mg film-coated tablet, then 15 mg ODT without water</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants received one single dose of 15 mg rivaroxaban film-coated tablet in the fasted state. After a washing period of 5 days, participants received one single oral dose of 15 mg rivaroxaban orally disintegrating tablet (ODT) without water in the fasted state</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rivaroxaban (BAY 59-7939, Xarelto) in ODT form</intervention_name>
    <description>15 mg as 1 x 15 mg orally disintegrating tablet (ODT)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Test C: 15 mg ODT with water, then 15 mg film-coated tablet</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Test C: 15 mg film-coated tablet, then 15 mg ODT with water</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Test D: 15 mg ODT without water, then 15 film-coated tablet</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Test D: 15 mg film-coated tablet, then 15 mg ODT without water</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rivaroxaban (BAY 59-7939, Xarelto) in film-coated form</intervention_name>
    <description>15 mg as 1 x 15 mg film-coated tablet</description>
    <arm_group_label>Test C: 15 mg ODT with water, then 15 mg film-coated tablet</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Test C: 15 mg film-coated tablet, then 15 mg ODT with water</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Test D: 15 mg ODT without water, then 15 film-coated tablet</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Test D: 15 mg film-coated tablet, then 15 mg ODT without water</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Japanese healthy male subjects, aged 20 to 40 years (inclusive), with body mass index&#xD;
             17.6 to 26.4 kg/m²&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with incompletely cured pre-existing diseases for which it can be assumed that&#xD;
             the absorption, distribution, metabolism, elimination, and effects of the study drugs&#xD;
             will not be normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with known hypersensitivity to the study drugs (active substances or&#xD;
             excipients of the preparations)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with known coagulation disorders (e.g. von Willebrand disease, hemophilia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with febrile illness within 1 week before the first study drug administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with suspicion of drug or alcohol abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with intake of foods or beverages containing grapefruit, pomelo, Seville&#xD;
             orange, and tangelo within 1 week before the first study drug administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with therapies (e.g. physiotherapy, acupuncture, etc.) within 1 month before&#xD;
             starting study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with clinically relevant findings in the electrocardiogram (ECG) such as a&#xD;
             second- or third-degree atrioventricular block, prolongation of the QRS complex over&#xD;
             120 msec or of the corrected QT (QTc) interval over 450 msec&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with systolic blood pressure below 90 or above 130 mmHg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with diastolic blood pressure below 45 or above 85 mmHg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with clinically relevant deviations of the screened laboratory parameters from&#xD;
             reference ranges&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sumida Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sumida-ku</city>
        <state>Tokyo</state>
        <zip>130-0004</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fukuoka Mirai Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fukuoka</city>
        <zip>813-0017</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical Co. LTA Nishikumamoto hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kumamoto</city>
        <zip>861-4157</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://clinicaltrials.bayer.com/</url>
    <description>Click here to find results for studies related to Bayer products</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 12, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 12, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 12, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rivaroxaban</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Availability of this study's data will be determined according to Bayer's commitment to the EFPIA/PhRMA &quot;Principles for responsible clinical trial data sharing&quot;. This pertains to scope, timepoint and process of data access. As such, Bayer commits to sharing upon request from qualified researchers patient-level clinical trial data, study-level clinical trial data, and protocols from clinical trials in patients for medicines and indications approved in the US and EU as necessary for conducting legitimate research. This applies to data on new medicines and indications that have been approved by the EU and US regulatory agencies on or after January 01, 2014. Interested researchers can use www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com to request access to anonymized patient-level data and supporting documents from clinical studies to conduct research. Information on the Bayer criteria for listing studies and other relevant information is provided in the Study sponsors section of the portal.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

