<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04514510</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>200137</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>20-H-0137</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04514510</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Fixed Dose Flavonoid Isoquercetin on Thrombo-Inflammatory Biomarkers in Subjects With Stable Sickle Cell Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Fixed Dose Flavonoid Isoquercetin on Thrombo-Inflammatory Biomarkers in Subjects With Stable Sickle Cell Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sickle cell disease (SCD) is an inherited hemoglobin disorder. People with SCD have an&#xD;
      increased chance for getting blood clots. Researchers want to see if a dietary supplement&#xD;
      called Isoquercetin can decrease levels of inflammation and blood clotting in people with&#xD;
      SCD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To see how Isoquercetin works in people with SCD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults age 18-70 years old who have SCD and are in a steady-state (have not experienced a&#xD;
      pain crisis in the last 60 days and, if taking hydroxyurea, have not had a dose change in the&#xD;
      past 90 days).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with a physical exam, medical history, medicine review, and&#xD;
      blood tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may have a peripheral arterial tonometry (Endo-Pat) test to check the function&#xD;
      of their blood vessels. For this, a thimble-shaped cup is placed on their finger and a blood&#xD;
      pressure cuff is placed on their arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be put in 1 of 2 treatment groups. They will take 4 capsules of&#xD;
      Isoquercetin or placebo all at once, by mouth, every day for 4 weeks. They will get a pill&#xD;
      dispenser and keep a medicine diary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will take folic acid once a day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have an end-of-study visit. They will discuss any side effects and repeat&#xD;
      some of the screening tests. They may have an Endo-Pat test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      About a month after the last study visit, participants will be contacted by phone to see if&#xD;
      they have any side effects. Those who do may have a follow-up visit. At this visit, they may&#xD;
      have blood tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation will last from 8 to 12 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Sickle Cell Disease (SCD) is an inherited monogenic hemoglobin disorder caused by a mutation&#xD;
      in the gene encoding the beta globin subunit of adult hemoglobin (HbA) resulting in a&#xD;
      substitution of valine for glutamic acid at position 6 and thus producing hemoglobin S (HbS).&#xD;
      When deoxygenated, HbS polymerizes, rendering the red cell rigid, viscous, and abnormally&#xD;
      adherent to the capillary endothelium. This impedes blood flow in the microcirculation,&#xD;
      causing ischemia and microinfarcts that lead to painful crises, cerebrovascular stroke, renal&#xD;
      impairment, retinopathy and other end-organ damage. The current scientific literature&#xD;
      currently recognizes the contribution of an acquired hypercoagulable state in SCD to vascular&#xD;
      pathobiology, chronic organ dysfunction, and mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Similar to cancer, sickle cell disease is associated with an acquired hypercoagulable state&#xD;
      and exhibits a high prevalence of incident and recurrent venous thromboembolism (VTE).&#xD;
      Elevated levels of the procoagulant protein tissue factor and its activator, protein&#xD;
      disulfide isomerase in humans with SCD suggest a causal role for thrombogenesis. In cancer&#xD;
      patients, pharmacological inhibition of plasma PDI with Isoquercetin (IQ) led to a reduction&#xD;
      in VTE biomarkers and VTE recurrence. These findings provide support to test the hypothesis&#xD;
      that Isoquercetin in sickle cell disease would diminish thrombo-inflammatory VTE biomarkers&#xD;
      and attenuate the associated hypercoagulable state.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 2, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 28, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary outcome will be the change in the plasma soluble P-selectin level comparing the baseline to IQ response</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome will be the change in plasma soluble P-selectin level comparing the baseline versus IQ or placebo.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>plasma protein disulfide isomerase activity</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Compare baseline and end of study plasma protein disulfide isomerase activity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>tissue factor positive extracellular vesicle number</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Compare baseline and end of study plasma tissue factor positive extracellular vesicle number</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>procoagulant activity</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Compare baseline and end of study plasma tissue factor procoagulant activity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>inflammation and coagulation parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Compare baseline and end of study inflammation and coagulation parameters</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>biomarkers of vascular function and atherothrombosis</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Compare baseline and end of study contemporary biomarkers of vascular function and atherothrombosis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>safety/tolerability and adherence to oral IQ</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Assess safety/tolerability and adherence to oral IQ</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>VTE</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ISO</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects with sickle cell disease; Isoquercetin 1000mg once daily 28 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects with sickle cell disease; placebo once daily fr 28 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Isoquercetin</intervention_name>
    <description>Isoquercetin (quercetin-3-O-D-glucoside, also referred to as isoquercitrin) is a naturally occurring monoglucoside of the most studied and widely consumed bioflavonoid, quercetin.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ISO</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Silicified microcrystalline cellulose NF, Ascorbic acid, Nicotinic acid, Mg stearate, Silica and Colloidal Anhydrous Ph. Eur./Colloidal Silicon dioxide USP/NF</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For enrollment onto the active phase of the study (IQ supplement vs placebo), subjects must&#xD;
        meet all of the following criteria during the screening period (visit #1) which can last&#xD;
        from 0-28 days prior to start of study intervention:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unequivocal diagnosis of sickle cell anemia (Hemoglobin SS or Hemoglobin SC or Beta&#xD;
             Thalassemia Major or Beta Thalassemia Minor) confirmed by hemoglobin electrophoresis&#xD;
             performed on patients at least 90 days after a blood transfusion if previously&#xD;
             transfused, or DNA genotyping.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18-70 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Steady state SCD (no acute vaso-occlusive crisis within 60 days of D0 of the study)&#xD;
             and if on HU therapy, on an optimized dose for at least 30 days. For those newly&#xD;
             initiated on HU therapy, the dose should be unchanged for at least 90 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be willing to comply with all study procedures for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have provided signed written informed consent prior to performing any study procedure,&#xD;
             including screening procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects who meet any of the following criteria during screening will not receive the study&#xD;
        intervention and will be counted toward study accrual. Screen failures will not be included&#xD;
        in the analysis for statistical purposes:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SCD with a recent VOC (&lt;60 days from D0 of study).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SCD with history of recent blood transfusion (&lt;60 days from D0 of study) or exchange&#xD;
             transfusion (&lt;90 days from D0 of study).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SCD with a recent VTE (within 90 days of diagnosis of either DVT, PE or both).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patient receiving crizanlizumab therapy for SCD or that has received crizanlizumab&#xD;
             within the past 30 days of D0 of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a significant medical condition that confers an unacceptable risk to&#xD;
             participating in the study, and/or that could confound the interpretation of the study&#xD;
             data. Such significant medical conditions include, but are not limited to the&#xD;
             following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. History of recent (within 3 months prior to signing informed consent) congestive&#xD;
                  heart failure; myocardial infarction or unstable angina pectoris; hemorrhagic,&#xD;
                  embolic, or thrombotic stroke.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Active infection requiring the use of parenteral antimicrobial agents or Grade&#xD;
                  greater than or equal to 3 in severity (per National Cancer Institute Common&#xD;
                  Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events v5.0) within 2 months prior to the first&#xD;
                  dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Active viral infection as evidenced by testing positive for hepatitis B surface&#xD;
                  antigen or hepatitis C virus (HCV) antibody (Ab) with signs of active hepatitis B&#xD;
                  or C virus infection. If the subject is positive for HCV Ab, a reverse&#xD;
                  transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction test will be conducted. Subjects with&#xD;
                  hepatitis C may be rescreened after receiving appropriate hepatitis C treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Testing positive for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) 1 or 2 Ab with evidence&#xD;
                  for ongoing active infection (i.e., CD4 count &lt;400/microL and viral load &gt;100,000&#xD;
                  copies/mL) on antiretroviral therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Active acute inflammatory disorders rheumatoid arthritis or systemic lupus&#xD;
                  erythematosus on disease modifying therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Diabetes mellitus judged to be under poor control by the Investigator evidenced&#xD;
                  by a single fasting sugar value &gt;250 gm/dl or requiring &gt;3 antidiabetic agents,&#xD;
                  including insulin (all insulins are considered 1 agent); use of insulin per se is&#xD;
                  not exclusionary.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. History of any primary malignancy, with the exception of curatively treated&#xD;
                  nonmelanomatous skin cancer; curatively treated cervical or breast carcinoma in&#xD;
                  situ; or other primary tumor treated with curative intent, no known active&#xD;
                  disease present, and no treatment administered during the last 3 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Any injury or medical condition that, in the judgement of the Investigator would&#xD;
                  prevent the subject from participating&#xD;
&#xD;
                  in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a prior bone marrow or stem cell transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION OF VULNNERABLE PARTICIPANTS:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Vulnerable subjects will not be included in this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>46 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Arun S Shet, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Brenda F Merriweather, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 529-7440</phone>
    <email>brenda.merriweather@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2020-H-0137.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 14, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 14, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>VTE</keyword>
  <keyword>protein disulfide isomerase</keyword>
  <keyword>thrombo-inflammatory pathobiology</keyword>
  <keyword>HbS polymerizes</keyword>
  <keyword>P-selectin</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

