<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03005275</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCKH/CGRH-04-2016</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03005275</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Comparison of Cost - Effectiveness of Stimulated ICSI and IVM Strategy in PCOS Women</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Comparison of Cost - Effectiveness of Stimulated ICSI and IVM Strategy in PCOS Women</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vietnam National University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vietnam National University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) patients, both in vitro maturation (IVM) and&#xD;
      intra-cytoplasmic sperm injection (ICSI) are indicated as optional treatments. Although&#xD;
      recently ICSI techniques have been reported as more successful the IVM in achieving&#xD;
      pregnancy, they have also become much more expensive for the couples involved. Whilst most&#xD;
      high-income countries offer Assisted Reproductive Technology (ART) procedures fully or&#xD;
      partially paid by the government, the patients in low or middle-income countries have to&#xD;
      cover self-fund infertility treatments. With limited resource, a study conducting based on&#xD;
      the prevalence - based cost - effectiveness analysis is necessary for health managers, policy&#xD;
      makers and especially to assist patients' decision making in these countries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, there are still limited published studies that have evaluated the cost-effectiveness&#xD;
      of these strategies are available in the literature. This study is conducted based on the&#xD;
      prevalence - based cost - effectiveness analysis from the patient's perspective. Activity -&#xD;
      based costing method is used to cost in all levels of the healthcare system, which the&#xD;
      patients have to pay directly or indirectly. It also analyses incremental cost -&#xD;
      effectiveness to evaluate the cost - effectiveness of IVM and ICSI in PCOS women.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A Cost - Effectiveness Analysis (CEA) Study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To identify, measure, and evaluate the cost of ICSI treatment and IVM treatment in PCOS&#xD;
           patients, and the incremental cost of ICSI system implemented in PCOS patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To quantify the effectiveness of ICSI treatment and the IVM through number and&#xD;
           proportion of clinical pregnancy, live birth, and incremental effectiveness of the ICSI&#xD;
           treatment implemented in PCOS patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the cost - effectiveness of ICSI treatment compared with IVM in PCOS&#xD;
           patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To measure the incremental cost - effectiveness of ICSI treatment implemented. The&#xD;
           sample size for this study of 140 subjects, in both groups, being treated for 1 IVM or&#xD;
           ICSI cycle is based upon the cost and the effectiveness (live birth rate).&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS Cost - Effectiveness Analysis (CEA) Activity - based costing method is used to cost&#xD;
      in all levels of the healthcare system which the patients have to pay directly or indirectly&#xD;
      for IVM or ICSI. This study also analyzes incremental cost - effectiveness to evaluate the&#xD;
      cost - effectiveness of ICSI treatment implemented in PCOS patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sensitivity analysis In this study, two techniques of sensitivity analysis below employing&#xD;
      for the decision tree model, which is mentioned as below, are one - way sensitivity analysis&#xD;
      and Probabilistic Sensitivity Analysis (PSA).&#xD;
&#xD;
      One - way sensitivity analysis with Tornado diagram will analyses and Probability sensitivity&#xD;
      analysis with Monte Carlo simulation and Scatter plots of the difference in costs respecting&#xD;
      with the difference in live birth gained will analyses if all parameters varying together&#xD;
      simultaneously.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study also provided the cost - effectiveness acceptability curve (CEAC). The CEAC is&#xD;
      applying on the probability sensitivity analysis result, basing on the willingness to pay&#xD;
      (WTP). This technique assesses the probability of being cost effective of ICSI treatment&#xD;
      comparing to the IVM treatment, respecting to the WTP.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Setting: My Duc Hospital Type of data: This study uses a retrospective secondary data&#xD;
      collection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interventions:&#xD;
&#xD;
      IVM:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Day 2-4: Ultrasound for Antral Follicles Counts (AFC).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  FSH injection: Day 9, 10 and 11 (can be adjusted 1-3 days before or after to avoid&#xD;
           Ultrasound and OPU on holidays). Dose: normally 100 IU/day (maybe 75 - 150 IU/day).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Follicle and endometrium can be evaluated: on the day of final injection or one day&#xD;
           later.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cancel this cycle, if pregnancy is detected or suspected ovulation through ultrasound.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  hCG 10.000 IU: one day after the final FSH injection, at 9 p.m. Can be adjusted HCG&#xD;
           injection day (± 1-2 days) to avoid Ultrasound and OPU on vacation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  OPU: 1,5 day after hCG injection (normally 36-42 hours later).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Sperm collection: on OPU day (if mature follicle presents) or 1 day after OPU day.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Embryo transfer: 3 days after OPU.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Luteal support: progesterone gel (90 mg once daily) intra-vaginally and estradiol (4&#xD;
           mg/day PO, twice daily) initiated on the day of OPU or the day thereafter.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ICSI:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Daily SC injections with rFSH - recombinant follicle stimulating hormone (minimum starting&#xD;
      dose is around 150 IUI) are started on On day 2 or day 3 of the menstrual cycle (Stimulation&#xD;
      Day 1) and continue up to and including Stimulation Day 7.&#xD;
&#xD;
      From Stimulation Day 8 onwards, subjects from ICSI treatment groups will continue with a&#xD;
      daily SC dose of rFSH up to the day before Gonadotrophin-releasing hormone (GnRH) agonist&#xD;
      day. The maximum rFSH dose to continue treatment after the first 7 days is 300 IU but the&#xD;
      dose could be adjusted when desired.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To prevent premature luteinizing hormone (LH) surges the GnRH antagonist (ganirelix acetate&#xD;
      SC 0.25 mg/ 0.5 mL) is administered starting on stimulation day 5.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If no follicles ≥ 11mm is visible on the USS on Stimulation day 8, or if no embryo transfer&#xD;
      the cycle is to be cancelled. If the ovarian response too high or if there is a risk for&#xD;
      Ovarian hyperstimulation syndrome (OHSS), (more than 30 follicles ≥ 11mm on USS), rec-hCG is&#xD;
      required to be withheld, and the treatment cycle is to be cancelled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As soon as three follicles of 17mm are observed by USS at least, a GnRH agonist (Triptorelin&#xD;
      0.2 mg) will be used for final oocyte maturation at the same day. About 34-36 h thereafter,&#xD;
      OPU followed by ICSI is performed. Two days after oocyte pick-up 2 fresh embryos will be&#xD;
      transferred. Patients with high progesterone level on the trigger day (progesterone level &gt;&#xD;
      2ng/ml), freeze all will be recommended.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients using GnRH agonist will have fresh transfer with intense luteal phase support of E2&#xD;
      and P4 (receive intense luteal phase support with E2 and P4 as the same dose mentioned above&#xD;
      and progesterone 50 mg i.m. /day), unless patients have high progesterone level on day of&#xD;
      trigger (progesterone level &gt; 2ng/ml), freeze all will be recommended.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Frozen embryo transfer cycles:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Time of starting:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Day 2-4 of the cycle.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  When starting to use drugs, endometrial thickness ≤ 9mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Estradiol valerate (Valiera 2mg, Progynova 2mg).&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Starting dose: 8mg/day (Valiera 2mg per os, four times, daily) for 6 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adjusting dose:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Increasing to 12mg/day (Valiera 2mg per os, three times per day, every time 02&#xD;
                tablets) for 5 days if EM thickness &lt; 10mm after 6 days using 8mg/day.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Increasing to 16 mg/day (Valiera 2mg per os, four times, every time 2 tablets) for&#xD;
                4 days if EM thickness &lt; 10mm after 5 days using 12mg/day.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Attention: Dose up to 16mg/day, patient must be performed ultrasound every 3-4 days&#xD;
                for detecting the side effects (headache, dizzy). When this side effect happens,&#xD;
                stop your regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Maximum treatment interval is 28 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Decide to transfer:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Endometrium thickness (EM) ≥ 8mm (this standard doesn't apply to all patients).&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The minimum time for using estradiol valerate: 10 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Drug:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Progesterone per vagina:&#xD;
&#xD;
                       -  Cyclogest 400mg, tid pv, 01 tablet, for 16 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
                       -  or Crinone 8% gel, tid pv, 01tube.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Estradiol valerate:&#xD;
&#xD;
                       -  Valiera 2mg, four times per os, 01 tablet for 16 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
                       -  The day for Embryo transfer depends on the age of embryo (Day 2, 3, or&#xD;
                          5).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessments Before the start of ovarian stimulation, pregnancy is excluded by means of an hCG&#xD;
      test, a blood sample is obtained for hormone assessments, and USS is performed to measure and&#xD;
      count visible follicles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will return to the clinic for USS and blood sampling on stimulation days 5 and 8,&#xD;
      and the day of hCG or GnRH agonist administration. Additional blood samples will be collected&#xD;
      on the day of embryo transfer and 2 weeks after embryo transfer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chief investigator (CI) will review all the medical records and collect all the data (cost,&#xD;
      effectiveness, epidemic characteristics...), contacts of PCOS patients. Then CI and&#xD;
      colleagues will call the patients for inviting to participate in this project and provide&#xD;
      information about the study. If they agree to take part in, collecting data of indirect cost&#xD;
      (transportation, administrative costs...) will be provided. The patients have the right to&#xD;
      withdraw from the study at any time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ETHICAL CONSIDERATIONS Institutional Review Board of My Duc Hospital will review the study.&#xD;
      The main ethical concerns are whether the research will place the patients at undue risk and&#xD;
      whether the subjects are fully informed about the nature of the study. The study will only be&#xD;
      conducted after the Ethics Committee approval has been granted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethics approval - From My Duc Hospital Confidentiality - Information sheet de-identified. A&#xD;
      unique number is given to each participant. Master list held by CI separately from data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Declaration of interests - None Access to data - Investigators only Ancillary and post-trial&#xD;
      care - None&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>live birth</measure>
    <time_frame>36 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>the complete expulsion or extraction from its mother of a product of conception, irrespective of the duration of the pregnancy, which, after such separation, breathes or shows any other evidence of life - e.g. beating of the heart, pulsation of the umbilical cord or definite movement of voluntary muscles - whether or not the umbilical cord has been cut or the placenta is attached. Each product of such a birth is considered live born (WHO).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>direct costs</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>the costs (Vietnam dong) for medical services, medication, examinations, procedures, etc.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>indirect costs</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>the costs (Vietnam dong) for patients' working hour loss (income per one working hour x number of hours), transportation fee (by motorbike, car, bus, taxi, others), accommodation (including hotel, guest house, etc.).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Infertility</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IVM</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>FSH injection: Day 9, 10 and 11 (can be adjusted 1-3 days before or after to avoid Ultrasound and OPU on holidays). Dose: normally 100 IU/day (maybe 75 - 150 IU/day).&#xD;
Follicle and endometrium can be evaluated: on the day of final injection or one day later.&#xD;
hCG 10.000 IU: one day after the final FSH injection, at 9 p.m. Can be adjusted HCG injection day (± 1-2 days) to avoid Ultrasound and OPU on vacation.&#xD;
OPU: 1,5 day after hCG injection (normally 36-42 hours later).&#xD;
Sperm collection: on OPU day (if mature follicle presents) or 1 day after OPU day.&#xD;
Embryo transfer: 3 days after OPU.&#xD;
Luteal support: progesterone gel (90 mg once daily) intra-vaginally and estradiol (4 mg/day PO, twice daily) initiated on the day of OPU or the day thereafter.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ICSI</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Daily SC injections with rFSH (minimum starting dose is around 150 IUI) are started on On day 2 or day 3 of the menstrual cycle (Stimulation Day 1) and continue up to and including Stimulation Day 7.&#xD;
From Stimulation Day 8 onwards, subjects from ICSI treatment groups will continue with a daily SC dose of rFSH up to the day before GnRH agonist day. The maximum rFSH dose to continue treatment after the first 7 days is 300 IU but the dose could be adjusted when desired.&#xD;
As soon as three follicles of 17mm are observed by USS at least, a GnRH agonist (Triptorelin 0.2 mg) will be used for final oocyte maturation at the same day. About 34-36 h thereafter, OPU followed by ICSI is performed. Two days after oocyte pick-up 2 fresh embryos will be transferred.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>IVM</intervention_name>
    <description>FSH injection: Day 9, 10 and 11 (can be adjusted 1-3 days before or after to avoid Ultrasound and OPU on holidays). Dose: normally 100 IU/day (maybe 75 - 150 IU/day).&#xD;
Follicle and endometrium can be evaluated: on the day of final injection or one day later.&#xD;
hCG 10.000 IU: one day after the final FSH injection, at 9 p.m. Can be adjusted HCG injection day (± 1-2 days) to avoid Ultrasound and OPU on vacation.&#xD;
OPU: 1,5 day after hCG injection (normally 36-42 hours later). Sperm collection: on OPU day (if mature follicle presents) or 1 day after OPU day.&#xD;
Embryo transfer: 3 days after OPU. Luteal support: progesterone gel (90 mg once daily) intra-vaginally and estradiol (4 mg/day PO, twice daily) initiated on the day of OPU or the day thereafter.</description>
    <arm_group_label>IVM</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ICSI</intervention_name>
    <description>Daily SC injections with rFSH (minimum starting dose is around 150 IUI) are started on On day 2 or day 3 of the menstrual cycle (Stimulation Day 1) and continue up to and including Stimulation Day 7.&#xD;
From Stimulation Day 8 onwards, subjects from ICSI treatment groups will continue with a daily SC dose of rFSH up to the day before GnRH agonist day. The maximum rFSH dose to continue treatment after the first 7 days is 300 IU but the dose could be adjusted when desired.&#xD;
As soon as three follicles of 17mm are observed by USS at least, a GnRH agonist (Triptorelin 0.2 mg) will be used for final oocyte maturation at the same day. About 34-36 h thereafter, OPU followed by ICSI is performed. Two days after oocyte pick-up 2 fresh embryos will be transferred</description>
    <arm_group_label>ICSI</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Include:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Couples undergoing IVM or ICSI treatment for the 1st time.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Husband: total mobile sperm count over 10 million/ml (before washing) or over 2&#xD;
             million/ml (after washing) or normal semen analysis (WHO 2010 criteria).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Wife: PCOS patients (Rotterdam European Society of Human Reproduction and Embryology&#xD;
             (ESHRE)/ American Society of Reproductive Medicine (ASRM) 2004 aged from 18 to 37 at&#xD;
             the time of conducting IVM or ICSI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Each subject must have results of clinical laboratory test (complete blood count&#xD;
             (CBC), blood chemistries, and urinalysis, pap smear) within normal limits or&#xD;
             clinically acceptable to the investigator, as measured by the local laboratory at&#xD;
             screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Each subject must have results of a physical examination, including blood pressure,&#xD;
             within normal limits or clinically acceptable limits to the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclude:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject (wife) has a recent (i.e. within 3 years prior to conducting IVM or ICSI)&#xD;
             history of/ or any current endocrine abnormality (irrespective whether the patient is&#xD;
             stabilized on treatment).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has a recent history of/or current epilepsy, thrombophilia, diabetes,&#xD;
             cardiovascular, gastro-intestinal, hepatic, renal or pulmonary or auto-immune disease&#xD;
             requiring regular treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Endometriosis (in uterine muscle, ovary or pelvis) or IVF/ICSI with donated sperm,&#xD;
             donated eggs or IVM with donated sperm, clomiphene citrate resistant PCOS (PCOS),&#xD;
             tubal factor (blocked fallopian tube, hydrosalpinx), abnormal uterine structure&#xD;
             (submucosal fibroid or intramural fibroid ≥30 mm, uterine polyp, bicornuate uterus,&#xD;
             didelphic uterus).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has tested positive for Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) or Hepatitis B&#xD;
             (by the local laboratory; results obtained within one year prior to conducting IVM or&#xD;
             ICSI are considered valid).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has contraindications for the use of gonadotropins (ex; tumors,&#xD;
             pregnancy/lactation, undiagnosed vaginal bleeding, hypersensitivity, or ovarian cysts)&#xD;
             or GnRH-antagonist (e.g. hypersensitivity, pregnancy/lactation).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has known gene defects, genetic abnormalities, or abnormal karyotyping,&#xD;
             relevant for the current indications or for the health of the offspring.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject smokes or has recently stopped smoking (ex. within the last 3 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has a history or presence of alcohol or drug abuse within 12 months prior&#xD;
             to conduct IVM or ICSI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has used any experimental drugs within 3 months prior to conduct IVM or&#xD;
             ICSI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject is participating in any other clinical study (excluding surveys).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who do not complete the process of IVM or IVF/ICSI (withdrawing, no embryo for&#xD;
             transfer or embryos haven't been transferred).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>37 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Khoa D Le, Dr</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mỹ Đức Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 19, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 22, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 29, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 17, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 17, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 18, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Vietnam National University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Manh Tuong Ho</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

