<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03054298</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>826085 (UPCC 02916)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03054298</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>CAR T Cells in Mesothelin Expressing Cancers</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I Study of Human Chimeric Antigen Receptor Modified T Cells in Patients With Mesothelin Expressing Cancers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health (NIH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Tmunity Therapeutics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pennsylvania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Phase I study to establish safety and feasibility of both intravenous administration and&#xD;
      local delivery of lentiviral transduced huCART-meso cells with or without lymphodepletion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase I study evaluating the safety and feasibility of lentiviral transduced&#xD;
      huCART-meso cells with and without cyclophosphamide and via different routes of&#xD;
      administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort 1 (N=3-6): will receive a single dose of 1-3x10^7 /m^2 lentiviral transduced&#xD;
           huCART-meso cells on day 0 without any conditioning chemotherapeutic regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort 2 (N=3-6): will receive a single dose of 1-3x10^7 /m^2 lentiviral transduced&#xD;
           huCART-meso cells on day 0, following a flat dose of 1 gram/m2 of cyclophosphamide&#xD;
           administered 2-4 days prior to huCARTmeso cells (day -4 to day -2).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort 3 (N=3-6): will receive a single dose of 1-3x10^8 /m^2 lentiviral transduced&#xD;
           huCART-meso cells on day 0 without any conditioning chemotherapeutic regimen. **Cohort 3&#xD;
           permanently closed**&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort 4 subjects (N=3-6) will receive a single dose of 1-3x10^8 /m^2 lentiviral&#xD;
           transduced huCART-meso cells on day 0, following a flat dose of 1 gram/m^2 of&#xD;
           cyclophosphamide administered 2-4 days prior to huCART-meso cells (day -4 to day -2).&#xD;
           **Cohort 4 permanently closed**&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort 5 (N=up to 6): will receive a single dose of 1-3x10^7 /m^2 lentiviral transduced&#xD;
           huCART-meso cells on day 0 by intrapleural infusion (IP) through an indwelling pleural&#xD;
           catheter without any conditioning chemotherapeutic regimen. The safety of this dose&#xD;
           level has been established by Cohorts 1 and 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort 6 (N=up to 6): will receive lentiviral transduced huCART-meso cells at a dose of&#xD;
           1-3x10^7 via IV infusion on Day 0, following a flat dose of 1 gram/m^2 of&#xD;
           cyclophosphamide administered 2-4 days prior to huCART-meso cells (~Day -4 to -2). This&#xD;
           initial infusion may be followed by up to two additional IV infusions of huCART-meso&#xD;
           cells at the same dose level, given between 21-42 days apart, if the subject meets&#xD;
           eligibility to receive additional infusions. Cyclophosphamide will not be repeated prior&#xD;
           to subsequent doses of huCART-meso cells. Enrollment into Cohort 6 will occur in&#xD;
           parallel with Cohort 5.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort 7 (N = up to 6): will receive a single dose of 1-3x107 huCART-meso cells/m2 via&#xD;
           intraperitoneal (i.p.) administration, following lymphodepleting chemotherapy with&#xD;
           cyclophosphamide 300 mg/m2/day and fludarabine 30 mg/m2/day given over 3 days by&#xD;
           intravenous infusion. Lymphodepleting chemotherapy will be scheduled such that the last&#xD;
           day of chemotherapy is 3 days (+/- 1 day) prior to the 1st infusion of huCART-meso&#xD;
           cells. This initial i.p. infusion may be followed by up to two additional infusions of&#xD;
           huCART-meso cells via intravenous (IV) administration at the same dose level, given&#xD;
           between 21-42 days apart. The subject must meet eligibility to receive additional&#xD;
           infusions . Lymphodepleting chemotherapy will not be repeated prior to additional&#xD;
           infusions of huCART-meso cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD) is defined as the dose at which 0-1 DLT occurs in 6&#xD;
      evaluable subjects tested within the dose range of this study. The maximum tolerated dose has&#xD;
      been established as 1-3x10^7/m^2 lentiviral transduced huCART-meso cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adverse events will be collected and evaluated during the protocol specified adverse event&#xD;
      reporting period&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events as assessed by CTCAE v4.03</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical anti-tumor effect by standard criteria (RECIST)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28, Month 3 and 6</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical anti-tumor effect by standard criteria [modified RECIST for mesothelioma]</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28, Month 3 and 6</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Year 2</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Year 2</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>7</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">27</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Peritoneal Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Fallopian Tube Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Mesotheliomas Pleural</condition>
  <condition>Mesothelioma Peritoneum</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single dose of 1-3x10^7/m^2 lentiviral transduced huCART-meso cells</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cyclophosphamide 1 grams/m^2 administered 2-4 days prior to a single dose of 1-3x10^7 /m^2 lentiviral transduced huCART-meso cells</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>PERMANENTLY CLOSED</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>PERMANENTLY CLOSED</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single dose of 1-3x107 huCART-meso cells/m2 day 0 by intrapleural infusion (IP) through an indwelling pleural catheter without any conditioning chemotherapeutic regimen. Subjects in this cohort will be enrolled after safety is demonstrated at this dose level by completion of Cohorts 1 and 2. Subjects in Cohort 5 may be enrolled in parallel to Cohort 6.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 6</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose of 1-3x107 huCART-meso cells/m2 via IV infusion on Day 0, following a flat dose of 1 gram/m2 of cyclophosphamide administered 2-4 days prior to huCART-meso cells (~Day -4 to -2). This initial infusion may be followed by up to two additional IV infusions of huCART-meso cells at the same dose level, given approximately 21-42 days apart, if the subject meets eligibility to receive additional infusions. Cyclophosphamide will not be repeated prior to subsequent doses of huCART-meso cells. Cohort 6 was activated with Protocol V6. Enrollment into Cohort 6 will occur in parallel with Cohort 5.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 7</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>a single dose of 1-3x107 huCART-meso cells/m2 via intraperitoneal (i.p.) administration, following lymphodepleting chemotherapy with cyclophosphamide 300 mg/m2/day and fludarabine 30 mg/m2/day given over 3 days by intravenous infusion. Lymphodepleting chemotherapy will be scheduled such that the last day of chemotherapy is 3 days (+/- 1 day) prior to the infusion of huCART-meso cells. This initial i.p. infusion may be followed by up to two additional infusions of huCART-meso cells via intravenous (IV) administration at the same dose level, given between 21-42 days apart. The subject must meet eligibility to receive additional infusions. Lymphodepleting chemotherapy will not be repeated prior to additional infusions of huCART-meso cells. Infusion #1 for the first three subjects in Cohort 7 will be staggered by at least 21 days to allow for the assessment of DLTs. Enrollment into Cohort 7 will occur in parallel with Cohort 5 and Cohort 6.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>huCART-meso cells</intervention_name>
    <description>Intravenous administration or local delivery of lentiviral transduced huCART-meso cells in 7 cohorts with or without lymphodepletion..</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 6</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 7</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Histologically confirmed cancer (one of the following):&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Cohorts 1-4 and Cohort 6 participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  **Note: Cohorts 3 and 4 permanently closed**&#xD;
&#xD;
                  **Note: As of 1-Feb-2021 lung adenocarcinoma patients are no longer being&#xD;
                  enrolled in this trial**&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Metastatic or recurrent lung adenocarcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Persistent or recurrent serous epithelial ovarian cancer or primary&#xD;
                       peritoneal carcinoma or fallopian tube carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Malignant pleural and peritoneal mesothelioma (histologically confirmed&#xD;
                       epithelial)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Cohort 5 participants: **Note: As of 1-Feb-2021 lung adenocarcinoma patients are&#xD;
                  no longer being enrolled in this trial**&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Metastatic or recurrent lung adenocarcinoma with documented pleural effusion&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Persistent or recurrent serous epithelial ovarian cancer or primary&#xD;
                       peritoneal carcinoma or fallopian tube carcinoma with documented pleural&#xD;
                       effusion&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Malignant pleural and peritoneal mesothelioma (histologically confirmed&#xD;
                       epithelial) with documented pleural effusion&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Cohort 7 patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Persistent or recurrent serous epithelial ovarian cancer or primary&#xD;
                       peritoneal carcinoma or fallopian tube carcinoma with evidence of ascites&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Malignant peritoneal mesothelioma (histologically confirmed epithelial) with&#xD;
                       evidence of ascites **Note: Ascites does not need to be confirmed malignant&#xD;
                       by cytology.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. CRITERIA HAS BEEN RETIRED&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Failure of at least one prior standard of care chemotherapy for advanced stage&#xD;
             disease. ALLOWANCE FOR PRIOR PD-1 or PDL-1 THERAPIES REMOVED.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects must have measureable disease as defined by RECIST 1.1 criteria or modified&#xD;
             RECIST criteria (mesothelioma only).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects with asymptomatic CNS metastases that have been treated (and are off steroids&#xD;
             for the treatment of CNS disease) are allowed. They must meet the following at the&#xD;
             time of enrollment:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. No concurrent treatment for the CNS disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. No progression of CNS metastasis on MRI at screening scans&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. No evidence of leptomeningeal disease or cord compression&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects ≥ 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Satisfactory organ and bone marrow function as defined by the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,000/μl&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥75,000/μl&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 8 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilirubin ≤ 2.0x the institutional normal upper limit unless secondary to bile&#xD;
                  duct obstruction by tumor&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine ≤ 1.5x the institutional normal upper limit&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Albumin ≥ 2&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤ 5x the&#xD;
                  institutional normal upper limit viii.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cardiac ejection fraction of ≥40% as measured by resting echocardiogram, with no&#xD;
                  clinically significant pericardial effusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Blood coagulation parameters: PT such that international normalized ratio (INR) is ≤&#xD;
             1.5 and a PTT ≤ 1.2 time the upper limit of normal unless the patient is&#xD;
             therapeutically anti-coagulated for history of cancer-related thrombosis and has&#xD;
             stable coagulation parameters.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects of reproductive potential must agree to use acceptable birth control methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Sarcomatoid mesothelioma histology which is known in the literature to not express&#xD;
             mesothelin; biphasic mesothelioma is also excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known leptomeningeal carcinomatosis or spinal cord compression. Screening for this is&#xD;
             not required unless suspicious symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects with symptomatic CNS metastases are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. EXCLUSION CRITERIA HAS BEEN RETIRED&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Active invasive cancer other than the one of the three cancers in this study. Subjects&#xD;
             with active non-invasive cancers (such as non-melanoma skin cancer, superficial&#xD;
             cervical and bladder and prostate cancer with PSA level &lt; 1.0) are not excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. HIV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Active hepatitis B or hepatitis C infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Active autoimmune disease (including but not limited to: systemic lupus erythematosus,&#xD;
             Sjogren's syndrome, rheumatoid arthritis, psoriasis, multiple sclerosis, inflammatory&#xD;
             bowel disease, etc.) requiring immunosuppressive therapy within four (4) weeks prior&#xD;
             to eligibility confirmation by physician-investigator, with the exception of thyroid&#xD;
             replacement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients with ongoing or active infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Planned concurrent treatment with systemic high dose corticosteroids. Subjects may be&#xD;
             on a stable low dose of steroids (≤10mg equivalent of prednisone) for chronic&#xD;
             respiratory conditions or adrenal insufficiency. Corticosteroids treatment as&#xD;
             anti-emetic prophylaxis on the day of cyclophosphamide administration is allowed per&#xD;
             institutional guidance.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients requiring supplemental oxygen therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Prior therapy with lentiviral gene modified cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. History of allergy or hypersensitivity to study product excipients (human serum&#xD;
             albumin, DMSO, and Dextran 40)&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Any clinically significant pericardial effusion, Class II-IV cardiovascular disability&#xD;
             according to the New York Heard Association Classification or other cardiovascular&#xD;
             condition that would preclude assessment of mesothelin induced pericarditis, or which&#xD;
             may worsen as a result of expected toxicities in this study. This determination will&#xD;
             be made by a cardiologist if cardiac issues are suspected.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Any clinically significant pleural or peritoneal effusion that cannot be drained with&#xD;
             standard approaches. An indwelling drainage device placed prior to eligibility&#xD;
             confirmation by physician / investigator is acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Pregnant or breastfeeding women.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. EXCLUSION HAS BEEN RETIRED&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Treatment with a PD-1 or PD-L1 inhibitor, including but not limited to nivolumab,&#xD;
             pembrolizumab, atezolizumab, and/or durvalumab, within two (2) months prior to&#xD;
             eligibility confirmation by investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Subjects with significant lung disease as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subjects with radiographic evidence of greater than lobar lymphangitic pulmonary&#xD;
                  involvement, greater than lobar bronchial wall thickening suggestive of&#xD;
                  peribronchial lymphatic disease extension, and/or evidence of extensive bilateral&#xD;
                  parenchymal metastatic burden.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subjects with radiographic and/or clinical evidence of active radiation&#xD;
                  pneumonitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subjects with radiographic evidence of underlying interstitial lung disease,&#xD;
                  including evidence of unresolved drug toxicity from any agent (e.g. chemotherapy,&#xD;
                  targeted agents, amiodarone, nitrofurantoin, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        **No exceptions to eligibility will be granted.**&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janos L Tanyi, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Pennaylvania</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Abramson Cancer Center Clinical Trials Service</last_name>
    <phone>855-216-0098</phone>
    <email>PennCancerTrials@emergingmed.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pennsylvania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Abramson Cancer Center Clinical Trials Service</last_name>
      <phone>855-216-0098</phone>
      <email>PennCancerTrials@emergingmed.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 9, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 10, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 15, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mesothelioma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mesothelioma, Malignant</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma of Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

