<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03051282</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HUM00114879</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03051282</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Genetic Determinants of ACEI Prodrug Activation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Genetic Determinants of ACEI Prodrug Activation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Michigan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Michigan</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitors (ACEIs) are among the most frequently prescribed&#xD;
      medications worldwide for the treatment of essential hypertension, left ventricular systolic&#xD;
      dysfunction, acute myocardial infarction, and prevention of the progression of diabetic&#xD;
      nephropathy. However, the outcome of ACEI treatment varies significantly between individuals&#xD;
      and selected populations. Suboptimal response, therapeutic failure, and significant side&#xD;
      effects are commonly documented in patients receiving ACEI therapy. Approximately 80% of the&#xD;
      ACEIs available for use in the US are synthesized as esterified prodrugs in order to improve&#xD;
      otherwise poor oral bioavailability of the active molecule. The activation of ACEI prodrugs&#xD;
      primarily occurs in the liver via metabolic de-esterification of the parent drug. The&#xD;
      critical activation step is essential in delivering a successful therapeutic outcome since&#xD;
      the active metabolites are approximately 10-1000 times more potent relative to their&#xD;
      respective parent compounds. Carboxylesterase 1 (CES1), the most abundant hydrolase in the&#xD;
      liver, is responsible for the activation of ACEI prodrugs in humans. Marked interindividual&#xD;
      variability in CES1 expression and activity has been documented, which results in varied&#xD;
      therapeutic efficacy and tolerability of many drugs serving as substrates of CES1. Genetic&#xD;
      variation of CES1 is considered to be a major factor contributing to variability in CES1&#xD;
      function. The study team proposes to conduct a multiple-dose healthy volunteer study to&#xD;
      evaluate the impact of CES1 genetic variation on the activation, pharmacokinetics, and&#xD;
      pharmacodynamics of enalapril, a model ACEI prodrug activated by CES1. The completion of this&#xD;
      study will represent a major step towards the establishment of an evidence base from which a&#xD;
      more individualized use of ACEI prodrugs can emerge.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Suspended</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Enrollment and interactions/interventions are paused due to COVID-19 and are expected to resume&#xD;
    in the future. This is not a suspension of IRB approval.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The measurements of the mean area under the curve (AUC) of enalaprilat plasma concentrations</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the mean AUC of enalaprilat plasma concentrations between the non-carrier control and the G143E carriers groups</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The measurements of the maximum enalaprilat plasma concentrations</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the maximum enalaprilat plasma concentrations between the non-carrier control and the G143E carriers groupsG143E carriers groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The measurements of angiotensin converting enzyme (ACE) activity in plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the plasma ACE activity between the non-carrier control and the G143E carriers groupsG143E carriers groups following enalapril treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The measurements of blood pressures (BPs) following enalapril treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the changes of BPs between the non-carrier control and the G143E carriers groupsG143E carriers groups following enalapril treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Volunteers</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>non-carrier control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects who do not carry the CES1 variant G143E (rs71647871) will receive 10 mg Enalapril orally once daily for 7 consecutive days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>G143E carriers group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects who carry the CES1 variant G143E (rs71647871) will receive 10 mg Enalapril orally once daily for 7 consecutive days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Enalapril</intervention_name>
    <description>Study participants in both arms will be treated with 10 mg enalapril orally once daily for seven consecutive days</description>
    <arm_group_label>G143E carriers group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>non-carrier control group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Vasotec®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must be male and female (50:50) between the ages of 18-55 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females must have a negative urine pregnancy test prior to the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All subjects must have no clinically significant diseases or clinically significant&#xD;
             abnormal laboratory values as assessed during the screening medical history, nursing&#xD;
             assessment, and laboratory evaluations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent must be signed by the eligible subject prior to the initiation of any&#xD;
             study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of a known medical condition that would preclude the use of enalapril&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of any surgical or medical condition (active or chronic) that may&#xD;
             interfere with drug absorption, distribution, metabolism, or excretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A positive urine pregnancy test in the MCRU prior to the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No subjects weighing under 50 kg will be selected&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The lack of use of acceptable methods of birth control unless abstinent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who regularly take medications, vitamins, herbal supplements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The use of any illicit drugs or habitual consumption of large quantities of ethanol&#xD;
             (&gt;3 drinks/day)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The consumption of grapefruit or grapefruit juice a week prior to, and during the&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Asians will not be included in the study as the CES1 SNP G143E is absent in this&#xD;
             population&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects hypersensitive to enalapril&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with a history of angioedema&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smokers&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Michigan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 9, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 9, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 13, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Michigan</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Haojie Zhu</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Enalapril</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

