<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02428400</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TG1050.02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02428400</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Tolerability of TG1050: A Dose-finding Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I/IB Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo Controlled, Dose-finding Study to Evaluate Safety, Tolerability of TG1050 Single/Multiple Doses, and Evaluation of TG1050 Immunologic/Antiviral Activity in Patients With Chronic Hep B Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Transgene</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Transgene</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Methodology:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled, multi-cohort Phase 1/1b study in&#xD;
      patients that are currently being treated for chronic HBV infection. For all cohorts,&#xD;
      patients must be receiving antiviral treatment with either tenofovir disoproxil fumarate&#xD;
      (TDF) or entecavir (ENT) for at least two years, and have their HBV infection well-controlled&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of TG1050 administered as single or multiple doses: Overall number of AEs, including SAEs, Grade 3 or 4 AEs, Grade 3 or 4 laboratory abnormalities, and any AE leading to a permanent discontinuation of IMP for any reason.</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 54</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dosage of TG1050/placebo administration for investigation in Part B of the study will be determined.</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 54</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">48</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Hepatitis B</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TG1050</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TG1050 SD cohort, administered SC as a single injection: 9.0 Log [10^9] 10.0 Log [10^10], 11.0 Log [10^11] virus particles&#xD;
TG1050 MD cohort, administered SC as 3 once weekly injections:9.0 Log [10^9] 10.0 Log [10^10], 11.0 Log [10^11] virus particles&#xD;
TG1050 Part B cohort, dose(s) and schedule to be determined</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo SD cohort, administered SC as a single injection: 9.0 Log [10^9] 10.0 Log [10^10], 11.0 Log [10^11] virus particles&#xD;
Placebo MD cohort, administered SC as 3 once weekly injections: 9.0 Log [10^9] 10.0 Log [10^10], 11.0 Log [10^11] virus particles&#xD;
Placebo Part B cohort, dose(s) and schedule to be determined</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TG1050</intervention_name>
    <description>TG1050: adenovirus serotype 5 vector based immunotherapeutic product in adenovirus reference material (ARM) buffer</description>
    <arm_group_label>TG1050</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo: adenovirus reference material (ARM) buffer</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 through 65 years of age, inclusive&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be undetectable for neutralizing antibodies to Adenovirus serotype 5&#xD;
             (Ad5) (PART A ONLY)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative serum β-HCG (for women of childbearing potential only; women of&#xD;
             non-childbearing potential are defined as a woman who has been postmenopausal for ≥ 2&#xD;
             years or who had had a hysterectomy, bilateral oophorectomy, or medically documented&#xD;
             ovarian failure)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients of childbearing potential must be willing to use double effective&#xD;
             methods of contraception (e.g. two of the following: hormonal contraception, condom or&#xD;
             occlusive cap, intrauterine device (IUD) or intrauterine system (IUS), male&#xD;
             sterilisation, or true abstinence) through 3 months after the last IMP administration;&#xD;
             male patients must agree to use a double effective method of contraception (e.g. two&#xD;
             of the following: hormonal contraception, condom or occlusive cap, IUD or IUS, male&#xD;
             sterilisation, or true abstinence) during heterosexual intercourse with a partner&#xD;
             capable of becoming pregnant throughout 3 months after the last IMP administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently on treatment for HBV monoinfection (any HBV genotypes) for at least 2 years&#xD;
             with either the nucleos(t)ide analogue TDF or ENT&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of HBV DNA &lt; 20 IU/mL for at least 6 months before entry and HBV DNA &lt; 20&#xD;
             IU/mL at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HBsAg positive&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HBeAg positive or HBeAg negative patients with HBV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Compensated liver disease; defined as direct or conjugated bilirubin ≤ 1.2 × ULN,&#xD;
             PT/INR ≤ 1.2 × ULN, platelets ≥ 150,000/mm3, serum albumin ≥ 3.5 g/L, and no prior&#xD;
             history of clinical hepatic decompensation (eg, ascites, jaundice, encephalopathy,&#xD;
             variceal hemorrhage)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ALT ≤ 1.5 x ULN. Due to its biological variability, a re-test of the ALT parameter is&#xD;
             allowed if the ALT value at screening does not exceed 10% of the 1.5 x ULN value and&#xD;
             all other eligibility criteria are met. In this case, the ALT re-test can be performed&#xD;
             no more than one month after the initial ALT screening assay and has to be confirmed&#xD;
             within 2 weeks. Values of the two ALT assays re-tests have to be below 1.5 x ULN to&#xD;
             include the patient. In case of re-test of the ALT parameter, all hematology and&#xD;
             biochemistry parameters will be reassessed in parallel of the second ALT re-test to&#xD;
             ensure that they are still matching TG1050.02 eligibility criteria.• Hemoglobin ≥ 10&#xD;
             g/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine clearance &gt; 50mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neutrophils ≥ 1,500/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed, written Independent Ethics Committee (IEC)-approved informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any evidence of hepatocellular carcinoma or any other liver cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with α-fetoprotein &gt; 50 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients co-infected with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis C virus (HCV)&#xD;
             or hepatitis Delta virus (HDV)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with either a) medical history or evidence of cirrhosis who had any biopsy&#xD;
             showing cirrhosis or any approved non-invasive test indicative of cirrhosis as&#xD;
             documented in the medical source documents; OR b) either of the following at&#xD;
             screening: transient elastography score ≥ 10.5 kPa OR a Fibrotest® Fibrosure® score of&#xD;
             ≥ 0.48 and an aspartate aminotransferase platelet ratio Index (APRI) of ≥1. Note: If a&#xD;
             biopsy or non-invasive test has never been performed or if a biopsy or non-invasive&#xD;
             test has been performed but showed no cirrhosis, then b) must be followed at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of uncontrolled thyroid disease or abnormal thyroid&#xD;
             stimulating hormone (TSH) levels at screening (defined as &lt; 0.8 × lower limit of&#xD;
             normal [LLN] or &gt; 1.2 × ULN; patients are eligible with abnormal TSH levels if the&#xD;
             free triiodothyronine (FT3) and free thyroxine (FT4) are within normal limits)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant concomitant medical disorder including active systemic infection or proven&#xD;
             or suspected immunosuppressive disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of immunodeficiency or autoimmune disease (including autoimmune hepatitis, or&#xD;
             preexisting autoimmune or antibody-mediated disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or history of clinically significant oncologic, pulmonary, hepatic,&#xD;
             gastrointestinal, renal, cardiovascular, metabolic, endocrine, neurologic, hematologic&#xD;
             illness, major organ transplantation, or any other major medical disorder that, in the&#xD;
             judgment of the investigator, would interfere with patient treatment, or preclude&#xD;
             patient participation in this study; should be discussed case by case with the Sponsor&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast-feeding women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with an experimental gene therapy product or a gene therapy product&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior participation in another research protocol involving an investigation medicinal&#xD;
             product (IMP) within 4 months prior to TG1050/placebo injection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of substance abuse, including alcohol abuse that in the judgment of the&#xD;
             investigator would deem the patient as not be suitable for participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unable or unwilling to comply with the protocol requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
        All key inclusion and exclusion criteria remain the same for patients in Part A, MD Cohort&#xD;
        and in Part B of the study except for the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients with detectable or undetectable anti-Ad5 neutralizing antibodies are eligible&#xD;
        (i.e. regardless of their pre-immunity to Ad5 nAb).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Edmonton</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Calgary</city>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Montréal</city>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Grenoble</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Lyon</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Nancy</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Strasbourg</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Freiburg</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Hannover</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Mainz</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 18, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 22, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 28, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 26, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 26, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 27, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

