<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02423044</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>150114</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>15-M-0114</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02423044</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Spatial Context and Fear Learning</brief_title>
  <official_title>fMRI Spatial Context and Fear Conditioning</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Fear is a normal response to a threat. Learning fear can be helpful sometimes. For people&#xD;
      with anxiety disorders, fear can be long-lasting and too intense. Researchers want to study&#xD;
      how people become fearful of situations. They want to understand how the brain learns when it&#xD;
      is helpful to feel fear and when it is not.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To better understand brain processes related to fear and anxiety.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Right-handed adults ages 18 50 with generalized anxiety disorder, panic disorder, social&#xD;
           anxiety disorder, or post-traumatic stress disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Right handed volunteers ages 18-50 without psychiatric disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  And free of psychiatric medication for 2 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will first be screened under another protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will play a video game inside a magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scanner.&#xD;
           The scanner is a metal cylinder It is surrounded by a strong magnetic field.&#xD;
           Participants will lie on a table that can slide in and out of the scanner. A device&#xD;
           called a coil will be placed over the head.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  During the scan, participants may play a virtual reality video game. Game instructions&#xD;
           will be explained before they enter the scanner.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  While playing the game, participants will wear 2 electrodes on their fingers. These&#xD;
           measure sweat on the skin. They will also have 2 small electrodes attached to the left&#xD;
           hand. These can give brief mild electrical shocks.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be asked questions when playing the game during the scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Before and after the scan, participants will fill out questionnaires about their&#xD;
           emotions. They may complete questionnaires online while at the clinic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To examine the processes involved in distinguishing between threatening and safe conditions,&#xD;
      we aim to investigate the neural bases of contextual fear learning using functional magnetic&#xD;
      resonance imaging (fMRI). To do this, we will study behavioral, physiological, and brain&#xD;
      responses as aversive stimuli are encountered in a virtual environment, and will explore how&#xD;
      fear-related responses depend on the surrounding environment. In addition, we will examine&#xD;
      how these responses differ in clinical anxiety.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We are interested in studying Pavlovian aversive context conditioning in healthy controls and&#xD;
      patients with anxiety disorders. We will examine the extent to which participants learn to&#xD;
      discriminate between dangerous and safe virtual contexts, and how this learning maps to the&#xD;
      neural networks underlying anxiety and context coding. We expect successful learning of the&#xD;
      contextual fear response in healthy controls, as evidenced by differential skin conductance&#xD;
      response and neural activation to safe vs. threat context. Accordingly, we anticipate higher&#xD;
      neuronal activity in the hippocampus, prefrontal cortex, and amygdala. These findings will be&#xD;
      accompanied with increased hippocampus-prefrontal cortex connectivity during approach and&#xD;
      exploration of the dangerous context, and increased amygdala activation during anticipation&#xD;
      of shock in the dangerous context. Physiologically, SCR will increase in threat context&#xD;
      compared to safe context. However, anxious patients are expected to fail to learn to&#xD;
      differentiate safe from threat context, exhibiting increased SCR and neural activation in&#xD;
      both safe and threat contexts, an index of contextual generalization of fear. Particularly,&#xD;
      the lack of contextual fear discrimination in anxious patients will be associated with weaker&#xD;
      hippocampal activation to contextual learning. To examine differential context fear&#xD;
      conditioning, we will use a virtual reality (VR) paradigm. VR provides an optimal way to&#xD;
      probe spatial navigation and simulates context. The VR task presents an outdoor space, which&#xD;
      comprises a dangerous (probabilistic electrical shocks) and a safe (no shocks) location.&#xD;
      Healthy controls and patients with anxiety disorders will be compared on their physiological&#xD;
      and neural reactivity during task performance. Preliminary psychophysiological data suggest&#xD;
      that the proposed procedure is an effective way to promote different responses to a safe and&#xD;
      dangerous spatial location. Hence, we anticipate that this procedure will allow us to examine&#xD;
      brain correlates of differential contextual fear responses in humans and compare them between&#xD;
      healthy participants and patients diagnosed with an anxiety disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two study populations, healthy volunteers and patients diagnosed with an anxiety disorder&#xD;
      (generalized anxiety disorder (GAD), social anxiety disorder (SAD), panic disorder, and&#xD;
      post-traumatic stress disorder) will complete the protocol. Participants will be adult males&#xD;
      and females, aged 18 to 50 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This fMRI study will compare performance, physiological and neural measures between healthy&#xD;
      adults and patients with anxiety disorders, who perform a threat VR task in the scanner.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The VR task entails navigating in a virtual outdoor environment, which, unbeknownst to the&#xD;
      participants is divided into a safe and a dangerous context, which are recognizable by&#xD;
      environmental characteristics (e.g., mountain, clouds). The dangerous context is associated&#xD;
      with probabilistic shocks, which are never encountered in the safe context. Participants&#xD;
      learn about these two contexts as they collect flowers (cues), one at a time, in either&#xD;
      context. In the dangerous context, the flowers are associated with 50% chance of a shock&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome measures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome measures will be the cerebral fMRI blood-oxygen-level dependent (BOLD)&#xD;
      responses to three events: (1) shock anticipation: after collecting the cues (flowers) during&#xD;
      anticipation of a potential shock, (2) context exploration: as participants navigate in the&#xD;
      threat context or safe context in between trials (which start when a flower appears in the&#xD;
      environment), and (3) cue approach: during approach towards the flower, in the threat or safe&#xD;
      context. The secondary outcome measures will consist of the changes in psychophysiological&#xD;
      responses, such as SCR, heart rate, pupil dilatation, and respiratory rate, which will&#xD;
      validate fear responses.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 18, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 30, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 30, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary objective is to investigate the neural bases of contextual fear learning measures by the event-related hemodynamic response (fMRI).</measure>
    <time_frame>12/29/16</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The secondary objective is to see learning of the contextual fear response that will be measured by psychophysiological responses such as SCR, heart rate, pupil dilatation, and breathing.</measure>
    <time_frame>12/29/16</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">82</enrollment>
  <condition>Anxiety Disorders</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ages 18-50&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects able to give their consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Right handed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients only: a primary diagnosis of GAD, panic disorder, SAD, or PTSD according to&#xD;
             the Structured Clinical Interview for DSM-IV-TR&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-English speaking individual&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any significant medical or neurological problems (e.g. cardiovascular illness,&#xD;
             respiratory illness, neurological illness, seizure, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High or low blood pressure (SBP&gt;140 or SBP&lt;90; SDP&lt;50 or SDP&gt;90)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alcohol/drug abuse in the past year or lifetime alcohol or drug dependence according&#xD;
             to the Structured Clinical Interview for DSM-IV-TR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medications that act on the central nervous system (e.g., Lorazepam, Codeine) and thus&#xD;
             may interfere with the interpretation of study results. Specific exclusionary drug&#xD;
             classes include but are not limited to: (opioid analgesics, DA receptor agonists,&#xD;
             anticholinergics, MAO inhibitors, COMT inhibitors, as well as any illicit substances)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or positive pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurological syndrome of the wrist (e.g., carpal tunnel syndrome, cubital tunnel&#xD;
             syndrome, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive urine toxicology screen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IQ &lt;80&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who report getting severe motion sickness, especially by playing video&#xD;
             games&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any medical condition that increases risk for fMRI:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any metal implants (clips, screws, plates, pins, etc) or metal fragments cause by&#xD;
                  injuries or metal working&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any sort of medical implants (aneurysm clips, pacemaker, insulin pump, Hickman&#xD;
                  line, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Permanent eye liner and tattoos above the neck&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients who have difficulty lying flat on their back for up to 60 min in the&#xD;
                  scanner&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants who are uncomfortable in small closed spaces (have claustrophobia)&#xD;
                  and would feel uncomfortable in the MRI machine&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional Exclusion Criteria for Healthy Volunteers:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or past Axis I psychiatric disorders as identified with the Structured&#xD;
             Clinical Interview for DSM-IV-TR, non-patient edition (SCID-np)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of psychotropic medications (i.e. fluoxetine (Prozac), fluvoxamine&#xD;
             (Luvox), sertraline (Zoloft), paroxetine (Paxil), citalopram (Celexa) or escitalopram&#xD;
             (Lexapro), etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
        &lt;TAB&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional Exclusion Criteria for Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are currently on psychotropic medications. (Patients are required to be&#xD;
             free of all psychotropics medication (i.e. fluvoxamine (Luvox), sertraline (Zoloft),&#xD;
             paroxetine (Paxil), citalopram (Celexa) or escitalopram (Lexapro), etc.) for 2 weeks,&#xD;
             5 weeks for fluoxetine prior to testing. Patients will not be taken off medications&#xD;
             for the purpose of the study)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients will be excluded if they have a current or past history of any psychotic&#xD;
             disorder, delirium, dementia, amnestic disorder, cognitive disorder not otherwise&#xD;
             specified, any of the pervasive developmental disorders, or mental retardation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have a primary diagnosis of major depressive disorder.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Monique Ernst, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Britton JC, Lissek S, Grillon C, Norcross MA, Pine DS. Development of anxiety: the role of threat appraisal and fear learning. Depress Anxiety. 2011 Jan;28(1):5-17. doi: 10.1002/da.20733. Epub 2010 Aug 23. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20734364</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Huff NC, Zeilinski DJ, Fecteau ME, Brady R, LaBar KS. Human fear conditioning conducted in full immersion 3-dimensional virtual reality. J Vis Exp. 2010 Aug 9;(42). pii: 1993. doi: 10.3791/1993.</citation>
    <PMID>20736913</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 30, 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 18, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 18, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 22, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 1, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 1, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>fMRI</keyword>
  <keyword>Virtual Reality</keyword>
  <keyword>Shock Threat</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

