<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02824133</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P140402</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2014-005428-81</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02824133</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment With AZD4547 for Recurrent Malignant Glioma Expressing FGFR-TACC Gene Fusion&quot;</brief_title>
  <acronym>TARGET</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase I/II, Open-Label, Multicentre Study to Assess The Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics and Clinical Efficacy of AZD4547 in Patients With Relapsed/Refractory Glioma Positive for an FGFR Fusion</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators will look for the presence of the fusion gene in all patients operated on&#xD;
      for glioma. This search will be limited to all gliomas that show no IDH1 mutation, the latter&#xD;
      being sought in both routine and anomalies never co-existing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis is that the rate of progression-free survival in grade IV gliomas and III&#xD;
      without IDH1 mutation, with the usual chemotherapy, only 15% at 6 months (ie, 85% of patients&#xD;
      relapse before 6 months of treatment), must be with this new treatment 35% (primary&#xD;
      endpoint).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective is the evaluation of disease-free survival at 6 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      3% of GBM and IDHwt gliomas have a highly oncogenic FGFR-TACC gene fusion that confers high&#xD;
      sensitivity to FGFR inhibitors to tumor cells, in vitro and in vivo. Preclinical data shows&#xD;
      that expression of FGFR-TACC fusions confers sensitivity to FGFR inhibitors (including&#xD;
      AZD4547) to GBM models.AZD4547 (AstraZeneca) is a potent and selective inhibitor of FGFR-1, 2&#xD;
      and 3 receptor tyrosine kinases. Preclinical data have shown some CNS penetration. Some of&#xD;
      the important adverse events are hyperphosphatemia, and ocular complications. The primary&#xD;
      objective and assessment criterion is to assess the efficacy of AZD4547 by measuring the rate&#xD;
      of Progression Free Survival at 6 months (PFS6) in recurrent malignant glioma patients with&#xD;
      FGFR-TACC fusion.Secondary objectives and assessment criteria are: - To characterize the&#xD;
      safety, tolerability and PK of AZD4547 in glioma patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To further assess the anti-tumor activity of AZD4547 for patients with recurrent glioma&#xD;
           with FGFR-TACC fusion based on Overall Response Rate for patients with a measurable&#xD;
           residue.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To further assess the anti-tumor activity of AZD4547 for patients with recurrent glioma&#xD;
           with FGFR-TACC fusion based on the duration of PFS&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To further assess the anti-tumor activity of AZD4547 for patients with recurrent glioma&#xD;
           with a FGFR-TACC fusion based on Overall Survival AZD4547 Exploratory objectives - To&#xD;
           elucidate the mechanism of response and resistance (primary and secondary) by&#xD;
           exploratory biomarker analysis Experimental design: This is a phase II study in patients&#xD;
           diagnosed with a FGFR3-TACC3 or FGFR1-TACC1 fusion positive glioma presenting with a&#xD;
           recurrence of the disease after chemotherapy and radiotherapy. RNA will be&#xD;
           systematically screened for the presence of FGFR-TACC in each of the 11 participating&#xD;
           centers, and IHC for FGFR3 hyperexpression. The investigators also encourage a wide use&#xD;
           of FGFR3 IHC in non participating centers in order to identify additional potential&#xD;
           candidates who can be referred to one of the 11 centers for assessment of FGFR-TACC&#xD;
           expression by RNA analysis..&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will receive AZD4547 at a dose of 80mg bd on a continuous schedule, until disease&#xD;
      progression. With the following hypothesis: P0: PFS6=15%, P1: PFS6=35%, with alpha=5% and&#xD;
      power=80%, an initial cohort of 12 patients will be treated. If objective anti-tumor effects&#xD;
      are observed, the cohort will be expanded to include a total number of 38 subjects. Grade II&#xD;
      gliomas are also eligible but they will constitute an extra small cohort.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival measured according to RANO (Response Assessment in Neuro-Oncology) criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the efficacy of AZD4547 by measuring the rate of Progression Free Survival at 6 months (PFS6) in recurrent malignant glioma patients with FGFR-TACC fusion.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate measured according to RANO criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>To further assess the anti-tumor activity of AZD4547 for patients with recurrent glioma with FGFR-TACC fusion based on Overall Response Rate for patients with a measurable residue.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of PFS</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>To further assess the anti-tumor activity of AZD4547 for patients with recurrent glioma with FGFR-TACC fusion based on the duration of PFS</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>To further assess the anti-tumor activity of AZD4547 for patients with recurrent glioma with a FGFR-TACC fusion based on Overall Survival AZD4547</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of AZD4547 (Number of patients who experienced grade III-IV (CTCAE v4.0) toxicity related to the drug)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic of AZD4547: Maximum Plasma Concentration [Cmax]</measure>
    <time_frame>Dosages will be performed at the cycle 2 or 3: predose, 2, 3, 4 and 6h post-dose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic of AZD4547: Area Under the Curve [AUC]).</measure>
    <time_frame>Dosages will be performed at the cycle 2 or 3: predose, 2, 3, 4 and 6h post-dose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic of AZD4547: Residual Plasma Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Dosages will be performed at the cycle 2 or 3: predose, 2, 3, 4 and 6h post-dose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">14</enrollment>
  <condition>Recurrent IDHwt Gliomas With FGFR3-TACC3 Fusion</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent IDHwt Gliomas With FGFR1-TACC1 Fusion</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AZD4547</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>AZD4547: intake of 80mg bd (160mg/day), on a continuous schedule.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AZD4547</intervention_name>
    <description>80 mg bd (per os)</description>
    <arm_group_label>AZD4547</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Potent and selective inhibitor of FGFR-1, 2 and 3 receptor tyrosine kinases (enzyme and cellular phosphorylation endpoints) with lower potency for inhibition of IGF1R and KDR</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Recurrent glioma after standard treatment, expressing the FGFR3-TACC3 or FGFR1-TACC1&#xD;
             fusion gene as confirmed by RT-PCR sequencing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. First recurrence occurring more than three months from the end of the radiotherapy or&#xD;
             occurring outside the irradiated volume.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. World Health Organisation performance status 0-2 (KPS&gt;50) with no deterioration over&#xD;
             the previous 2 weeks and minimum life expectancy of 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Provision of signed and dated, written informed consent prior to any study specific&#xD;
             procedures, sampling and analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
             If a patient declines to participate in any voluntary exploratory research component&#xD;
             of the study, there will be no penalty or loss of benefit to the patient and he/she&#xD;
             will not be excluded from other aspects of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Aged at least 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients should be using adequate contraceptive measures which should be maintained&#xD;
             during the whole duration of AZD4547 treatment and at least 7 days after treatment&#xD;
             suspension. Females should not be breast feeding and must have a negative pregnancy&#xD;
             test prior to start of dosing if of child-bearing potential or must have evidence of&#xD;
             non-child-bearing potential by fulfilling one of the following criteria at screening:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Post-menopausal defined as aged more than 50 years and amenorrheic for at least&#xD;
                  12 months following cessation of all exogenous hormonal treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Documentation of irreversible surgical sterilisation by hysterectomy, bilateral&#xD;
                  oophorectomy or bilateral salpingectomy but not tubal ligation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Treatment with any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Nitrosourea within 6 weeks before the first dose of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any investigational agents or study drugs from a previous clinical study within&#xD;
                  30 days before the first dose of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any other chemotherapy, anticancer immunotherapy or anticancer agents within 4&#xD;
                  weeks before the first dose of study treatment, except hormonal therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Potent inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A4 or 2D6 or substrates of CYP3A4 within the&#xD;
                  required washout period as specified in the section 7.3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prior treatment in this or another AZD4547 study, or prior randomisation in a&#xD;
                  study in which AZD4547 is/was under investigation. Prior treatment with any FGFR&#xD;
                  inhibitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Major surgery (excluding placement of vascular access) within 14 days before the first&#xD;
             dose of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. With the exception of alopecia, any unresolved toxicities from prior therapy greater&#xD;
             than Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) grade 1 at the time of&#xD;
             starting study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. As judged by the investigator, any evidence of severe or uncontrolled systemic&#xD;
             diseases, including uncontrolled hypertension, active bleeding diatheses, or active&#xD;
             infection including hepatitis B, hepatitis C and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV).&#xD;
             Screening for chronic conditions is not required&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any of the following cardiac criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Mean QT interval corrected for heart rate (QTc) ≥470 ms calculated from 3&#xD;
                  electrocardiograms (ECGs) using Fridericia's correction.Any clinically important&#xD;
                  abnormalities in rhythm, conduction or morphology of resting ECG eg, complete&#xD;
                  left bundle branch block, third degree heart block&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any factors that increase the risk of QTc prolongation or risk of arrhythmic&#xD;
                  events such as heart failure, hypokalaemia, congenital long QT syndrome, family&#xD;
                  history of long QT syndrome or unexplained sudden death under 40 years of age or&#xD;
                  any concomitant medication known to prolong the QT interval&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of myocardial infarction, unstable angina, stroke or transient ischemic&#xD;
                  attack within the last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Inadequate bone marrow reserve or organ function as demonstrated by any of the&#xD;
             following laboratory values:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophile count &lt;1.5 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count &lt;100 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Haemoglobin &lt;90 g/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine aminotransferase &gt;2.5 times the upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate aminotransferase &gt;2.5 times ULN Total bilirubin &gt;1.5 times ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine &gt;1.5 times ULN concurrent with creatinine clearance &lt;50 ml/min&#xD;
                  (measured or calculated by Cockcroft and Gault equation); confirmation of&#xD;
                  creatinine clearance is only required when creatinine is &gt;1.5 times ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Corrected calcium &gt;ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Phosphate &gt;ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Refractory nausea and vomiting, chronic gastrointestinal diseases, inability to&#xD;
             swallow the formulated product or previous significant bowel resection that would&#xD;
             preclude adequate absorption of AZD4547&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of hypersensitivity to active or inactive excipients of AZD4547 or drugs with&#xD;
             a similar chemical structure or class to AZD4547&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Judgment by the investigator that the patient should not participate in the study if&#xD;
             the patient is unlikely to comply with study procedures, restrictions and requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Any of the following ophthalmological criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current evidence or previous history of retinal pigmented epithelium detachment&#xD;
                  (RPED)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previous laser treatment or intra-ocular injection for treatment of macular&#xD;
                  degeneration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current evidence or previous history of dry or wet age-related macular&#xD;
                  degeneration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current evidence or previous history of retinal vein occlusion (RVO)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current evidence or previous history of retinal degenerative diseases (eg,&#xD;
                  hereditary)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current evidence or previous history of any other clinically relevant&#xD;
                  chorioretinal defect&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Contraindications to MRI&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marc Sanson, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Neuro onsology unit - Groupe Hospitalier Pitié-Salpêtrière</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75013</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 21, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 1, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 6, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 24, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 24, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 29, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Glioma grade III</keyword>
  <keyword>Glioma grade IV</keyword>
  <keyword>Glioma recurrent</keyword>
  <keyword>IDHwt</keyword>
  <keyword>FGFR-TACC fusion</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

