<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01209754</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MTN-016</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>3UM1AI068633</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>10737</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01209754</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>EMBRACE (Evaluation of Maternal and Baby Outcome Registry After Chemoprophylactic Exposure)</brief_title>
  <acronym>EMBRACE</acronym>
  <official_title>HIV Prevention Agent Pregnancy Exposure Registry: EMBRACE Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Microbicide Trials Network</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Microbicide Trials Network</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The Prevention Agent Pregnancy Exposure Registry, also known as EMBRACE (Evaluation of&#xD;
      Maternal and Baby Outcome Registry After Chemoprophylactic Exposure) is a prospective&#xD;
      observational cohort investigation of exposures to study agents under investigation for HIV&#xD;
      prevention. The study population will consist of female participants who are identified as&#xD;
      becoming pregnant during their participation in a microbicide or PrEP trial, or who have had&#xD;
      planned exposures in pregnancy safety studies as well as their babies resulting from these&#xD;
      pregnancies. This study will only enroll babies who have not yet reached their 1 year birth&#xD;
      date.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Prevention Agent Pregnancy Exposure Registry, also known as EMBRACE (Evaluation of&#xD;
      Maternal and Baby Outcome Registry After Chemoprophylactic Exposure) is a prospective&#xD;
      observational cohort study of maternal exposures to investigational HIV prevention agents.&#xD;
      Approximately 550 pregnant participants and 400 live infants will be offered enrollment. The&#xD;
      study population will consist of current or recent female participants identified as becoming&#xD;
      pregnant during microbicide or PrEP trials, or who have had planned exposures in pregnancy&#xD;
      safety studies. This study will also include infants resulting from those pregnancies. This&#xD;
      protocol will monitor for adverse pregnancy and delivery outcomes, monitor the prevalence of&#xD;
      major malformations, evaluate growth parameters of infants during the first year of life, and&#xD;
      evaluate the prevalence and persistence of HIV drug resistance mutations in a cohort of&#xD;
      infants who were either exposed to active study agents or not exposed to active study agents&#xD;
      while in utero.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 6, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 6, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pregnancy and delivery outcomes comparison</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of Study</time_frame>
    <description>To compare adverse pregnancy and delivery outcomes between participant mothers assigned to an active agent with those of mothers assigned to placebo/control. Pregnancy and delivery outcomes of interest are:&#xD;
delivery prior to 37 completed weeks of gestation&#xD;
stillbirth or intrauterine fetal demise (≥ 20 weeks)&#xD;
spontaneous abortion (&lt; 20 weeks)&#xD;
ectopic pregnancy&#xD;
intrapartum hemorrhage&#xD;
postpartum hemorrhage&#xD;
non-reassuring fetal status&#xD;
chorioamnionitis&#xD;
hypertensive disorders of pregnancy&#xD;
gestational diabetes&#xD;
intrauterine growth restriction</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Major malformations comparison</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of Study</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the prevalence of major malformations identified in the first year of life between infants of mothers assigned to an active agent with those of infants of mothers assigned to placebo/control. Major malformations are defined as structural abnormalities with surgical, medical, or cosmetic importance.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Infant growth parameters comparison</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of Study</time_frame>
    <description>To compare growth parameters in the first year of life between infants of mothers assigned to an active agent with those of mothers assigned to placebo/control. Growth parameters of interest are weight, length, and head circumference at birth, one month, six months and 12 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HIV drug resistance mutations comparison</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of Study</time_frame>
    <description>2. To evaluate the prevalence and persistence of HIV drug resistance mutations in plasma among HIV-infected infants.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">873</enrollment>
  <condition>Pregnancy Related</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant Women</arm_group_label>
    <description>Pregnant women exposed to an HIV prevention study agent during pregnancy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Infant</arm_group_label>
    <description>Infants resulting from pregnancies where there exists maternal HIV prevention agent exposure</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study population will consist of female participants who become or became pregnant&#xD;
        during HIV prevention agent trials, or who have or had planned exposures in pregnancy&#xD;
        safety studies, and the infants resulting from those pregnancies. Mother participants must&#xD;
        still be pregnant, or have had a pregnancy outcome diagnosis less than one year before&#xD;
        screening/enrollment, and infant participants must be less than one year old. The study may&#xD;
        include HIV-uninfected and -infected participants. Mothers may participate in EMBRACE&#xD;
        without participation of their infants; however, infants whose mothers have not enrolled in&#xD;
        EMBRACE will not participate.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: Mother cohort&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Able and willing to provide written informed consent to take part in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. During participation in a parent protocol, has/had a known confirmed pregnancy,&#xD;
             meeting at least one of the following sets of criteria in A or B:&#xD;
&#xD;
             A. Two consecutive monthly study visits, at least 14 days apart, with positive&#xD;
             pregnancy tests, in the absence of signs/symptoms of miscarriage or participant report&#xD;
             of pregnancy termination.&#xD;
&#xD;
             B. One or more of the following assessments:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Auscultation of fetal heart tones&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Positive pregnancy test confirmed by clinic staff in the presence of clinically&#xD;
                  confirmed enlarged uterus&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Positive pregnancy test confirmed by clinic staff in the presence of missed&#xD;
                  menses (no menses occurring at least 60 days from the first day of the last&#xD;
                  menses) by participant report (For amenorrheic or irregularly cycling women, two&#xD;
                  consecutive positive hCG tests (criterion A) or any of the other clinical signs&#xD;
                  of pregnancy included under the criteria B listing will be used to confirm&#xD;
                  MTN-016 eligibility).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clinical assessment of fetal movement&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Demonstration of pregnancy by ultrasound&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Able and willing to provide adequate locator information, as defined in site SOPs&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: Participants do not have to be currently enrolled or engaged in follow-up in a parent&#xD;
        protocol to participate in EMBRACE.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria: Infant cohort&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Has written informed consent provided by parent(s)/guardian to take part in the study&#xD;
             in a manner consistent with local standards, site Institutional Review Board (IRB)&#xD;
             guidance and the US Code of Federal Regulations (CFR)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Born to EMBRACE participant mother from pregnancy concurrent with participation in&#xD;
             parent study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: Mother cohort&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Has any condition that in the opinion of the investigator or designee, would&#xD;
             complicate interpretation of study outcome data, make participation in the study&#xD;
             unsafe, or otherwise interfere with achieving the study objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pregnancy outcome occurred greater than one year ago&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: Infant cohort&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Has any condition that, in the opinion of the investigator or designee, would&#xD;
             complicate interpretation of study outcome data, make participation in the study&#xD;
             unsafe, or otherwise interfere with achieving the study objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Has reached 1 year birth date&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Richard Beigi, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Microbicide Trials Network</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama at Birmingham</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35294</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wits Reproductive Health Institute (WRHI)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Johannesburg</city>
        <state>Gauteng</state>
        <zip>2001</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CAPRISA-The Aurum Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Johannesburg</city>
        <state>Guateng</state>
        <zip>2193</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CAPRISA eThekwini</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durban</city>
        <state>KwaZulu Natal</state>
        <zip>4001</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Perinatal HIV Research Unit (PHRU)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Johannesburg</city>
        <state>Soweto</state>
        <zip>1804</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South African MRC HIV CTU Med Research Council; Botha's Hill Clinical Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durban</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South African MRC HIV CTU Med Research Council; Isipingo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durban</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South African MRC HIV CTU Med Research Council; Overport</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durban</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South African MRC HIV CTU Med Research Council; R.K. Khan Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durban</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South African MRC HIV CTU Med Research Council; Tongaat</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durban</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South African MRC HIV CTU Med Research Council; Umkomaas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durban</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South African MRC HIV CTU Med Research Council; Verulam</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durban</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Makerere University-Johns Hopkins University Collaboration</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kampala</city>
        <country>Uganda</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ-UCSF HIV Prevention Trials Unit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chitungwiza</city>
        <state>Seke South</state>
        <country>Zimbabwe</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ-UCSF HIV Prevention Trials Unit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Harare</city>
        <state>Spilhaus</state>
        <country>Zimbabwe</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ-UCSF HIV Prevention Trials Unit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chitungwiza</city>
        <state>Zengeza</state>
        <country>Zimbabwe</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>South Africa</country>
    <country>Uganda</country>
    <country>United States</country>
    <country>Zimbabwe</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Makanani B, Balkus JE, Jiao Y, Noguchi LM, Palanee-Phillips T, Mbilizi Y, Moodley J, Kintu K, Reddy K, Kabwigu S, Jeenariain N, Harkoo I, Mgodi N, Piper J, Rees H, Scheckter R, Beigi R, Baeten JM. Pregnancy and Infant Outcomes Among Women Using the Dapivirine Vaginal Ring in Early Pregnancy. J Acquir Immune Defic Syndr. 2018 Dec 15;79(5):566-572. doi: 10.1097/QAI.0000000000001861.</citation>
    <PMID>30383589</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mhlanga FG, Noguchi L, Balkus JE, Kabwigu S, Scheckter R, Piper J, Watts H, O'Rourke C, Torjesen K, Brown ER, Hillier SL, Beigi R. Implementation of a prospective pregnancy registry for antiretroviral based HIV prevention trials. HIV Clin Trials. 2018 Feb;19(1):8-14. doi: 10.1080/15284336.2017.1411419. Epub 2017 Dec 21.</citation>
    <PMID>29268654</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 23, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 24, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 27, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pregnancy</keyword>
  <keyword>Chemoprophylactic Exposure</keyword>
  <keyword>Mother</keyword>
  <keyword>Infant</keyword>
  <keyword>malformations</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

