<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01208649</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H80-MC-O008</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01208649</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Exenatide (Byetta®) on Liver Function in Patients With Nonalcoholic Steatohepatitis (NASH)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Exenatide (Byetta®) on Biochemical and Histological Parameters of Liver Function in Patients With Nonalcoholic Steatohepatitis (NASH)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ruhr University of Bochum</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ruhr University of Bochum</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective is to test the hypothesis that 24 weeks of treatment with exenatide&#xD;
      will improve the histological acitvity of NASH (steatosis,necroinflammation, ballooning),&#xD;
      summarized in the recently introduced NASH-score in patients with normal, impaired or&#xD;
      diabetic glucose tolerance compared to dietary guidance alone.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Non alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH), a chronic liver disease characterized by insulin&#xD;
      resistance, accumulation of hepatic fat and hepatocellular necroinflammation, has been&#xD;
      recognized as a leading cause of (cryptogenic) liver cirrhosis in developed countries. Given&#xD;
      the rising prevalence of NASH and the associated socio-economic burden associated, novel&#xD;
      therapeutic options are warranted. The incretin mimetic Exenatide (Byetta®) exhibits strong&#xD;
      glucoregulatory activities through its multiple biological effects. In addition, exenatide&#xD;
      treatment has been shown to improve lipid homeostasis and reduce body weight. Since the&#xD;
      development of NASH has been tightly linked to the presence of obesity, hyperlipidaemia and&#xD;
      diabetes, this study will examine, whether 24 weeks of treatment with exenatide will also&#xD;
      result in improvements in liver function in patients with NASH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      60 patients with histologically proven NASH will be randomized to receive either exenatide (2&#xD;
      x 5 µg s.c. for 4 weeks, 2 x 10 µg thereafter) or placebo treatment, in a 1:1 ratio. Liver&#xD;
      biopsies will be performed after 24 weeks of treatment. In addition, a non-invasive&#xD;
      assessment of hepatic mitochondrial function will be carried-out using a 13C-methionine&#xD;
      breath test at baseline, and at weeks 12 and 24. Insulin sensitivity and glucose tolerance&#xD;
      will be assessed by a hyperinsulinaemic-euglycaemic clamp (baseline and week 24) and an oral&#xD;
      glucose tolerance test (baseline, weeks 12 and 24). Hepatic fat content will be measured by&#xD;
      magnetic resonance tomography. Liver enzymes will be monitored closely throughout the study&#xD;
      period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These studies will clarify whether exenatide treatment, in addition to its beneficial effects&#xD;
      on glucose homeostasis and body weight, will also result in improvements of liver function in&#xD;
      patients with NASH.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>histological activity of NASH (steatosis, necroinflammation, ballooning)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Liver fibrosis, as determined using the fibrosis score</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">13</enrollment>
  <condition>Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Exenatide</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drug (including placebo)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exenatide</intervention_name>
    <description>Exenatide; 48 weeks 10 microg injection s.c., twice daily, before the morning and evening meal with a four week wash-in phase with 5 microg injection s.c.twice daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>Exenatide</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age between 18 and 75 years, inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients present with histologically proven non-alcoholic steatohepatitis ascertained&#xD;
             by the single center pathologist between visit 1 and 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. First liver biopsy was obtained not later than 6 months before visit 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients have HbA1c not exceeding 10.0%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients have a history of stable body weight (not varying by &gt;10% for at least 3&#xD;
             months prior to screening&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients are investigator site personnel directly affiliated with the study, or are&#xD;
             immediate family of investigator site personnel directly affiliated with the study.&#xD;
             Immediate family is defined as a spouse, parent, child, or sibling, whether biological&#xD;
             or legally adopted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Females of childbearing potential who are pregnant, breast-feeding or intend to become&#xD;
             pregnant or are not using adequate contraceptive methods (adequate contraceptive&#xD;
             measures include sterilisation, hormonal intrauterine devices, oral contraceptives,&#xD;
             sexual abstinence or vasectomised partner). A male subject who is sexually active and&#xD;
             has not been surgically sterilised must be informed that he must either use a condom&#xD;
             during intercourse, ensure that his partner practices contraception, or he must&#xD;
             refrain from sexual intercourse during the trial and until 1 month after completion of&#xD;
             the trial. This is to prevent the possibility of a pregnancy from spermatocytes that&#xD;
             can potentially be damaged by trial medication. It is strongly recommended that the&#xD;
             female partners use a highly effective contraception (Pearl Index &lt; 1%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients have participated in an interventional medical, surgical, or pharmaceutical&#xD;
             study (a study in which an experimental, drug, medical, or surgical treatment was&#xD;
             given) within 30 days prior to screening. This criterion includes drugs that have not&#xD;
             received regulatory approval for any indication at the time of study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with evidence of viral or autoimmune hepatitis (positive testing for HBsAG,&#xD;
             anti-HCV or anti-HIV, pos. AMA-screen, ANA-titer &gt; 1:160)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients with inherited liver diseases (e.g. Wilson's disease, Hemochromatosis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients have alcohol consumption (&gt;20 g daily for males and &gt;10 g daily for females)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients have decompensated liver cirrhosis (Child-Pugh score &gt;7)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients have alanine aminotransaminase (ALT) greater than ten times the upper limit&#xD;
             of the reference range.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients have had greater than three episodes of severe hypoglycemia within 6 months&#xD;
             prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients are undergoing therapy for a malignancy, other than basal cell or squamous&#xD;
             cell skin cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients have cardiac disease that is Class III or IV, according to the New York Heart&#xD;
             Association criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients have a known allergy or hypersensitivity to exenatide, or excipients&#xD;
             contained in these agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients have or had concomitant medication with thiazolidinediones.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patients have a history of renal transplantation or are currently receiving renal&#xD;
             dialysis or have serum creatinine &gt;1.8 mg/dL for males and greater than or equal to&#xD;
             &gt;1.5 mg/dL for females.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Patients have known hemoglobinopathy or chronic anemia&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Patients are receiving chronic (lasting longer than 2 weeks) systemic glucocorticoid&#xD;
             therapy (excluding topical and inhaled preparations) or have received such therapy&#xD;
             within 2 weeks immediately prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Patients have used any prescription drug to promote weight loss within 3 months prior&#xD;
             to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Patients have any other condition (including known drug or alcohol abuse or&#xD;
             psychiatric disorder) that precludes them from following and completing the protocol,&#xD;
             in the opinion of the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Patients fail to satisfy the investigator of suitability to participate for any other&#xD;
             reason.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wolfgang E. Schmidt, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Ruhr-University Bochum</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wolfgang E. Schmidt, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ruhr-University Bochum</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Medicine I; University Hospital St. Josef-Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bochum</city>
        <zip>44791</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2010</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 23, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 24, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 23, 2010</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 23, 2010</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">September 24, 2010</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Prof. Dr. med. Wolfgang E. Schmidt; Director Department of Medicine l;</name_title>
    <organization>Universitiy Hospital; Ruhr-University Bochum; Gudrunstr. 56; 44791 Bochum; Germany</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>exenatide</keyword>
  <keyword>hepatic steatosis</keyword>
  <keyword>insulin resistance</keyword>
  <keyword>insulin sensitizers</keyword>
  <keyword>nonalcoholic fatty liver disease</keyword>
  <keyword>- GLP1-Analog</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Exenatide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

