<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01200940</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>100163</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10-DK-0163</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01200940</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Metabolic Effects of Non-Nutritive Sweeteners</brief_title>
  <official_title>Metabolic Effects of Non-Nutritive Sweeteners</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Artificial sweeteners, such as sucralose (brand name Splenda), are very commonly found in&#xD;
      products such as diet soft drinks. Recently, researchers learned that these sweeteners may&#xD;
      affect hormones in the body, especially when they are consumed in combination with real&#xD;
      sugar. Changes in hormone levels may, in turn, result in changes in blood sugar, appetite,&#xD;
      and weight. Researchers are interested in studying the effects of artificial sweeteners on&#xD;
      the metabolism and hormonal levels of healthy volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To study the effects that artificial sweeteners have on hormone levels, blood sugar, and&#xD;
           appetite.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate whether artificial sweeteners change the rate at which food passes out of&#xD;
           the stomach into the gut, or the rate at which the body absorbs sugar from the gut.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the effects that different amounts of artificial sweeteners have on hormone&#xD;
           levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Healthy volunteers between 18 and 45 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This study will require one screening visit and four testing visits, scheduled on&#xD;
           different days.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At the screening visit, eligible participants will be screened with a physical&#xD;
           examination, medical history, blood samples, and body measurements (including height,&#xD;
           weight, body circumferences, and skin folds). Participants will also be asked about how&#xD;
           much artificial sweetener they typically consume and will have taste tests, in which a&#xD;
           small amount of flavored liquid is placed on the tongue and participants will name the&#xD;
           flavor and rate its intensity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will have four glucose tolerance tests on four different days. In&#xD;
           preparation for the test, participants will not eat or drink anything but water for 12&#xD;
           hours prior to the test. Blood will be drawn before the test, and participants will&#xD;
           drink one of the following study liquids, selected at random:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Plain water&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Water mixed with sucralose (the amount found in one 12 oz diet soft drink)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Water mixed with sucralose (the amount found in 2.5 12 oz diet soft drinks)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Water mixed with sucralose (the amount found in 3.7 12 oz diet soft drinks)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ten minutes after drinking the study liquid, participants will have a sugary drink that&#xD;
           will allow researchers to measure sugar absorption and the speed with which food leaves&#xD;
           the stomach.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In addition, participants will complete questionnaires about hunger levels before&#xD;
           drinking the sugar solution and at regular intervals for 2 hours afterward. Blood&#xD;
           samples will be taken at regular intervals as well.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consumption of non-nutritive sweeteners is common practice in the US, and these chemicals are&#xD;
      generally thought to be metabolically inert. However, recent data obtained from animal&#xD;
      studies demonstrate that non-nutritive sweeteners play an active metabolic role within the&#xD;
      gastrointestinal tract. Sweet-taste receptors, including the T1R family and Alpha-gustducin,&#xD;
      respond not only to caloric sugars such as sucrose, but also to non-nutritive sweeteners,&#xD;
      including sucralose (Splenda ) and acesulfame-K . In both humans and animals, these receptors&#xD;
      have been shown to be present in glucagon-like-peptide-1 (GLP-1) secreting L cells of the gut&#xD;
      mucosa as well as in lingual taste buds , and serve as critical mediators of GLP-1 secretion&#xD;
      . We have demonstrated in a previous study that diet soda augments glucose-stimulated GLP-1&#xD;
      secretion . In addition, there is evidence in animals that activation of intestinal&#xD;
      sweet-taste receptors by non-nutritive sweeteners enhances intestinal glucose absorption via&#xD;
      upregulation of the glucose transporter, GLUT2 .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to broadly explore the effects of non-nutritive sweeteners on&#xD;
      glucose and glucoregulatory hormones in healthy humans. To this end, we plan the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Aim: To confirm that the non-nutritive sweetener sucralose (versus other ingredients&#xD;
      in diet soda) augments glucose-stimulated GLP-1 secretion&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To study whether increased GLP-1 secretion due to non-nutritive sweeteners alters&#xD;
           gastric emptying or satiety&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To determine a dose-response relationship for non-nutritive sweeteners on&#xD;
           glucose-stimulated GLP-1 secretion&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To determine whether non-nutritive sweeteners alter the rate of intestinal glucose&#xD;
           absorption&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. To test whether non-nutritive sweeteners affect levels of other incretin or gut hormones&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy men and women ages greater than or equal to 18 years, and prepubertal children ages&#xD;
      6-12 years, across a wide range of body mass indices will participate in a variety of paired&#xD;
      experiments, in randomized order, with each subject serving as his or her own control. In&#xD;
      each experiment, the subject will ingest either a non-nutritive sweetener or control, and a&#xD;
      glucose load (oral glucose tolerance test). The following measurements will be obtained:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Serial measurement of glucose, insulin, C-peptide, GLP-1, and other incretin and gut&#xD;
           hormones&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Rate of gastric emptying using acetaminophen labeling in the oral glucose or mixed meal&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Measurement of hunger and satiety using validated questionnaires&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Measurement of intestinal glucose absorption using a glucose analog&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 4, 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 30, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>GLP-1 secretion change with sucralose</measure>
    <time_frame>At minute -10,0,10, 20,30,60,90,120</time_frame>
    <description>After a 10-hour fast, subjects will drink a 75-gram oral glucose solution. Samples will be drawn at -10, 0, 10, 20, 30, 60, 90, and 120 minutes.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in gastric emptying</measure>
    <time_frame>At minute -10,0,10, 20,30,60,90,120</time_frame>
    <description>Gastric emptying will be assessed using acetaminophen labeling. For this test, 1450 mg of acetaminophen oral solution (14.5 mL of acetaminophen infant drops, 100 mg/mL) will be mixed with the oral glucose solution or mixed meal. Acetaminophen levels will be measured at the same time points as the primary outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in satiety</measure>
    <time_frame>At minute -10,0,10, 20,30,60,90,120</time_frame>
    <description>Perceived ratings of hunger and satiety will be measured through the use of questionnaires during the OGTT or mixed meal tests. Starting 10 minutes before consumption of the non- nutritive sweetener/placebo, the subject with fill out a Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) which contains questions on hunger and satiety. The VAS will be filled out at -10,0,30, 60, 90, and 120 minutes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>8</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">118</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Volunteers</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I - Low-dose sweetener</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>68 mg sucralose dissolved in 360 mL of water will be drunk 10 minutes prior to a 75 g oral glucose tolerance test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I - Medium-dose sweetener</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>170 mg sucralose dissolved in 360 mL of water will be drunk 10 minutes prior to a 75 g oral glucose tolerance test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I Control Condition</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>360 mL of water will be drunk 10 minutes prior to a 75 g oral glucose tolerance test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I- High-dose sweetener</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>250 mg sucralose dissolved in 360 mL of water will be drunk 10 minutes prior to a 75 g oral glucose tolerance test.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Control Condition</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>360 mL of water will be drunk 10 minutes prior to a 75 g oral glucose tolerance test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Diet Soda 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>less than or equal to 5mg/kg sucralose, less than or equal to 15 mg/kg acesulfame-potassium dissolved in 360 mL of water will be drunk 10 minutes prior to a 75 g oral glucose tolerance test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Diet Soda 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>less than or equal to 5 mg/kg sucralose, less than or equal to 50 mg/kg aspartame, less than or equal to 15 mg/kg acesulfame-potassium dissolved in 360 mL of water will be drunk 10 minutes prior to a 75 g oral glucose tolerance test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Water with sucralose and acesulfame-potassium</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>less than or equal to 5mg/kg sucralose, less than or equal to 15 mg/kg acesulfame-potassium dissolved in 360 mL of water will be drunk 10 minutes prior to a 75 g oral glucose tolerance test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sucralose</intervention_name>
    <description>sucralose will be given at doses of 68 mg (equivalent to one 12 oz soda) 170 mg (equivalent to two and one-half 12 oz sodas, and 250 mg (equal to 100% of the FDA s acceptable daily intake for a 50kg individual).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I - Low-dose sweetener</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I - Medium-dose sweetener</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I- High-dose sweetener</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Diet Soda 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Diet Soda 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Water with sucralose and acesulfame-potassium</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Aspartame</intervention_name>
    <description>To determine the impact of sucralose and acesulfame- potassium ( aspartame) together on GLP-1 secretion, satiety, and the rate of intestinal glucose absorption. The doses of sucralose and acesulfame- potassium reflect the sweetener concentrations in the previously used Diet Rite Cola .</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Diet Soda 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acesulfame-Potassium</intervention_name>
    <description>To determine the impact of sucralose and acesulfame- potassium ( aspartame) together on GLP-1 secretion, satiety, and the rate of intestinal glucose absorption. The doses of sucralose and acesulfame- potassium reflect the sweetener concentrations in the previously used Diet Rite Cola .</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Diet Soda 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Diet Soda 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Water with sucralose and acesulfame-potassium</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control</intervention_name>
    <description>360 mL of water will be drunk 10 minutes prior to a 75 g oral glucose tolerance test</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I Control Condition</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Control Condition</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  MAIN STUDY:&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age greater than or equal to 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No known active medical conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of prescription or non-prescription medication. Certain exceptions are&#xD;
             permitted, including topical medications, vitamins, and hormonal contraceptives. Other&#xD;
             medications may be permitted at the discretion of the investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent (past 2 months) use of drugs that alter glucose metabolism (e.g. metformin),&#xD;
             alter gastric pH (e.g. proton pump inhibitors) or gastric emptying (e.g.&#xD;
             metoclopramide)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ALT or AST more than 1.5 times the upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive urine pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy, sensitivity or other contraindication to any study food or drug or its&#xD;
             vehicle&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric or cognitive disorder that will, in the opinion of the investigators,&#xD;
             limit the subject's ability to provide informed consent, or to comply with study&#xD;
             procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight less than 50 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diabetes (fasting blood glucose of 126 mg/dl or higher, or 2-hour blood glucose of 200&#xD;
             or higher on oral glucose tolerance testing)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Glycosuria&#xD;
&#xD;
        PEDIATRIC PILOT STUDY:&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 6-12 years at enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight at least 17 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prepubertal (Tanner stage I breasts in girls, or testicular volumes less than or equal&#xD;
             to 3 mL in boys)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No known active medical conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of prescription or non-prescription medication. Certain exceptions are&#xD;
             permitted, including topical medications and vitamins. Other medications may be&#xD;
             permitted at the discretion of the investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent (past 2 months) use of drugs that alter glucose metabolism (e.g. metformin),&#xD;
             alter gastric pH (e.g. proton pump inhibitors) or gastric emptying (e.g.&#xD;
             metoclopramide)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ALT or AST more than 1.5 times the upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy, sensitivity or other contraindication to any study food or drug or its&#xD;
             vehicle&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric or cognitive disorder that will, in the opinion of the investigators,&#xD;
             limit the subject's ability to provide assent, and/or the subject s parent/guardian to&#xD;
             provide informed consent, or to comply with study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal glucose tolerance (fasting blood glucose of 100 mg/dl or higher, or 2-hour&#xD;
             blood glucose of 140 or higher on oral glucose tolerance testing)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Glycosuria&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rebecca J Brown, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?B_2010-DK-0163.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 11, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 11, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 14, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>GLP-1</keyword>
  <keyword>Glucose Tolerance</keyword>
  <keyword>Gut Hormones</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

