<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01209884</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SIRB# 10-5416</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01209884</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Metabolomics of Aging: Sub-study of the Healthy Elderly Active Longevity (HEAL) Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>Metabolomics</acronym>
  <official_title>Metabolomics of Aging: Sub-study of the Healthy Elderly Active Longevity (HEAL) Cohort</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Scripps Translational Science Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Scripps Translational Science Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research is being done to learn more about healthy aging. We hope to learn which bodily&#xD;
      processes or functions are important for the elderly to maintain good health. Metabolites&#xD;
      (for example, glucose) are small molecules in our bodies that are used in all bodily&#xD;
      reactions. Looking at their levels in healthy elderly people may help researchers find out&#xD;
      which processes lead some people to get to disease and others to not.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Metabolites are the basic building blocks for people. They are used to construct larger&#xD;
      complexes(such as proteins), relay signals from one part of the body to another, and as a&#xD;
      source of energy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While most people have essentially the same types of metabolites, the relative levels of&#xD;
      these metabolites vary from one individual to another. These levels reflect the body's state&#xD;
      of growth, development, and reproduction. An appropriate balance in metabolites is important&#xD;
      to maintaining general health. Conditions like cancer and diabetes result in disrupted levels&#xD;
      of metabolites that are associated with changes in bodily functions. Deviations from normal&#xD;
      levels of metabolites can be used as a signature for disease. Researchers have discovered&#xD;
      that a disruption in unique metabolite levels is associated with human aging. In this study&#xD;
      we hope to learn which, if any, of these disruptions are associated with the onset of&#xD;
      age-related disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The HEAL study criteria includes subjects who are 80 years of age and older who have not&#xD;
      experienced a chronic condition. This sub-study will use plasma samples of up to 100 HEAL&#xD;
      subjects to compare the metabolomic findings found within this group with existing young and&#xD;
      elderly plasma samples that are currently under analysis at the Siuzdak lab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this sub-study is to determine if metabolites that are downregulated in elderly&#xD;
      relative to young individuals are similarly downregulated in the Wellderly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Metabolomics is a rapidly emerging field focused on profiling small, naturally occurring&#xD;
      (endogenous) molecules collectively known as the &quot;metabolome.&quot; Metabolomics offers a&#xD;
      significant advantage over other &quot;omics&quot; sciences (e.g., transcriptomics and proteomics) in&#xD;
      that metabolites represent the most&#xD;
&#xD;
      downstream end products of cellular reactions and therefore most closely correlate with the&#xD;
      phenotype. Thus, by comparative untargeted profiling, metabolomics provides a powerful&#xD;
      strategy for understanding changes associated with a unique phenotype at the molecular level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Untargeted metabolomics denotes the profiling of all low molecular weight biochemicals,&#xD;
      including lipids, hormones, saccharides, nucleotides, organic acids, and amino acids that&#xD;
      serve as substrates and products in metabolic pathways. The analytes are measured without&#xD;
      specifically &quot;targeting&quot; distinct metabolites or molecules. Untargeted metabolomics has the&#xD;
      capacity to implicate unanticipated metabolites or pathways associated with a unique&#xD;
      phenotype (i.e., advanced age), and thereby provide great insight into cellular mechanisms&#xD;
      and pathobiology. In the latter context, the Siuzdak Laboratory has pioneered a new approach&#xD;
      for investigating disease known as therapeutic metabolomics in which cellular pathways&#xD;
      associated with disease are identified and then perturbed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Study the metabolomics of the healthy aging</measure>
    <time_frame>December 2013</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">14</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Elderly sub-group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Healthy males between the age of 80-85 years old who have not experienced chronic disease during their lifetime.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood sample will be collected from each subject after informed consent is obtained&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood collection&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 10mL of blood will be collected. The blood will be collected for the purpose of&#xD;
      isolating plasma, as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      1 X 10mls Sodium (Na) Heparin tube&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood will be drawn by hospital/clinic phlebotomy services, a nurse or a medical assistant.&#xD;
      Blood will be collected from each subject one time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once aliquoted, the plasma will be catalogued in a central registry (LIMS database) and then&#xD;
      stored. Metabolite extraction and protein precipitation will be performed to remove proteins&#xD;
      and extract the maximum number of metabolites. The samples will be maintained at 4 degrees&#xD;
      Celcius in the autosampler and then analyzed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        General outpatient and community population&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 80 to 85 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Gender: Male&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Enrolled in the Healthy Elderly (HEAL) study prior to enrollment in this sub-study&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Eligible for Blood draw&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Be reliable, cooperative and willing to comply with all protocol-specified procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Able to understand and grant informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Be healthy or have mild medical conditions that may be associated with the normal&#xD;
             aging process, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Hypertension, well controlled with no more than 3 medications&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Osteoporosis or Osteopenia&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Osteoarthritis&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Benign Prostatic Hypertrophy&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Cataracts, Glaucoma or Macular Degeneration&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Dyslipidemia&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Hypothyroidism&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Pre-Diabetes/Impaired Fasting Glucose (fasting blood glucose 100-126 mg/dL, if&#xD;
                  known)&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Basal or Squamous Cell Carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
        Individuals will be excluded if ANY of the following conditions apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Less than 80 years of age or greater than 85 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Gender: Female&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Currently undergoing treatment with any investigational agents or devices within 30&#xD;
             preceding enrollment in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Self-reported history or current diagnosis of significant chronic conditions&#xD;
             including&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Any Cancer (including polycythemia; excluding basal or squamous cell carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Coronary Artery Disease, Myocardial Infarction&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Stroke or Transient Ischemic Attack (TIA)&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Deep Vein Thrombosis or Pulmonary Embolism&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Chronis Renal Disease or Hemodialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Significant Auto-Immune or Inflammatory conditions such as Rheumatoid Arthritis,&#xD;
                  Lupus, Crohn's Disease, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Alzheimer's or Parkinson's Disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Diabetes (Hemoglobin A1C &gt; 6.5% or fasting glucose &gt; 126 mg/dL or is treated with&#xD;
                  insulin or oral diabetic medication&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Aortic or Cerebral Aneurysm&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Currently taking any of the following medications on a regular basis:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Chemotherapeutic agents (ex. Tamoxifen, Doxorubicin, Mitoxantrone, bleomycin&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Anti-platelet or anticoagulant agents, not including Aspirin (ex.&#xD;
                  Clopidogrel/Plavix, Dipyridamole/Aggrenox/Persantine, Ticlopidine/Ticlid,&#xD;
                  Warfarin/Coumadin, Plasugrel, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Cholinesterase inhibitor for Alzheimer's disease (i.e. Donzepril/Aricept)&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Insulin or oral diabetic medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Individual has a significant medical condition which, in the investigator's opinion,&#xD;
             may interfere with the individual's optimal participation in the study or would&#xD;
             potentially confound interpretation of the individual's phenotype.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>80 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eric E Topol, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Scripps Translational Science Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Scripps Translational Science Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>La Jolla</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92037</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 24, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 24, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 27, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 7, 2014</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 7, 2014</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 9, 2014</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Scripps Translational Science Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Eric Topol, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

