<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01302405</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PRI-724-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01302405</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of PRI-724 in Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase Ia/Ib Clinical Trial of PRI-724 in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Prism Pharma Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>inVentiv Health Clinical</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Prism Pharma Co., Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      PRI-724 is a new investigational drug being studied to treat subjects with cancer who have&#xD;
      advanced solid tumors. PRI-724 is thought to work by blocking the Wnt signaling pathway that&#xD;
      cancer cells need to grow and spread(metastasize).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase Ia: Patient cohorts with solid tumor malignancies will be treated with escalating doses&#xD;
      (per cohort) of PRI-724 in order to identify the MTD of this single-agent regimen. PRI-724&#xD;
      dosing is to start at 40 mg/m2/day, CIV infusion over 24 hours × 7 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase Ib: This phase is to begin upon identification of the MTD in Phase 1a. Patient cohorts&#xD;
      with CRC will be treated with escalating doses (per cohort) of PRI-724 administered in&#xD;
      combination with a modified regimen of FOLFOX6 (mFOLFOX 6, standardized doses and schedule)&#xD;
      in order to identify the MTD of this combined regimen. Up to 2 dose levels of PRI-724 are to&#xD;
      be examined (640 and 905 mg/m2/day, CIV infusion over 24 hours × 7 days), with potential to&#xD;
      evaluate a previously unexamined intermediate dose, if indicated, to more fully characterize&#xD;
      tolerability. The MTD cohort (or maximum dose to be studied) will be expanded up to 12&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Primary Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine the MTD of PRI-724 when administered as a 7-day CIV intravenous infusion to&#xD;
           patients with solid tumors (Phase Ia).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine the MTD of PRI-724 when administered as a 7-day CIV infusion in combination&#xD;
           with mFOLFOX6 in patients with colorectal carcinoma (Phase Ib).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Describe the dose-limiting toxicities (DLTs) and adverse event profile of PRI-724 when&#xD;
           administered as a 7-day CIV infusion either alone in patients with solid tumors, or in&#xD;
           combination with mFOLFOX6 in patients with colorectal carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine the pharmacokinetic (PK) profile of PRI-724 and C-82 when administered as a&#xD;
           7-day CIV infusion in these patient populations (In Phase 1b PK assessments will not be&#xD;
           performed in expanded MTD cohort patients).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Obtain preliminary assessment of anti-tumor activity as manifested by responses to&#xD;
           treatment in these patient populations.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Measure the mRNA expression of survivin by reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain&#xD;
           reaction (RT-PCR), pre- and post-treatment with PRI-724:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  In circulating tumor cells (CTC)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  In tumor biopsy specimens from CRC patients (Phase Ib only) Also, evaluate whether&#xD;
                survivin expression in CTC is consistent and reflective of expression in tumor&#xD;
                specimens.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Obtain preliminary assessments of potential associations of survivin that may be&#xD;
           impacted by the pharmacodynamic (PD) properties of PRI-724 and clinical outcome,&#xD;
           toxicity and PK parameters&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Assess the effects of Wnt inhibitor C-82 on the hair follicle neogenesis and the amount&#xD;
           of collagen expression&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory Objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Obtain matrix metalloproteinase-7 (MMP7) levels in serum via enzyme-linked immunosorbent&#xD;
      assay (ELISA) testing&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the Phase Ia portion, an accelerated titration design, specifically, design 4A (no&#xD;
      within-patient dose escalation) will be used, and will begin at the starting dose of 40&#xD;
      mg/m2/day. This involves an initial accelerated (double-step) dose escalation phase followed&#xD;
      by a standard 3+3 design (single-step) dose escalation phase. In the initial accelerated&#xD;
      phase, cohorts of one new patient will be treated per dose level and double-step dose&#xD;
      escalations will be used. The accelerated phase will end when the first instance of DLT is&#xD;
      observed during any cycle of treatment, or when a second patient experiences a moderate&#xD;
      toxicity (MT) during any cycle. The cohort at the current dose level will be expanded and the&#xD;
      standard 3+3 design phase (single-step) dose escalation will start for all subsequent&#xD;
      cohorts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, the accelerated phase will end with Dose Level 9 (640 mg/m2/day), unless the&#xD;
      toxicity criteria for terminating the accelerated phase are met earlier.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the accelerated phase, decisions to escalate, expand, or de-escalate will be made when&#xD;
      all patients at the current dose level have completed one cycle (2 weeks) of PRI-724, and&#xD;
      have received at least 75% of the planned PRI-724 dose, or have experienced a MT or DLT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the standard 3+3 phase, decisions to escalate, expand, or de-escalate will be made&#xD;
      when all patients at the current dose level have completed two cycles (4 weeks) of PRI-724&#xD;
      and have received at least 75% of the planned PRI-724 dose, or have experienced DLT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the Phase Ib portion, dose escalation in patients with CRC will begin at Level 9 of&#xD;
      the doses evaluated during Phase Ia (640 mg/m2/day). Up to 2 dose levels will be evaluated&#xD;
      (640 and 905mg/m2/day; potential to evaluate a previously unexamined intermediate dose, if&#xD;
      indicated) using a standard 3+3 design (single-step dose escalation). Decisions to escalate,&#xD;
      expand, or de-escalate will be made when all patients at the current dose level have&#xD;
      completed two cycles (4 weeks) of PRI-724 plus mFOLFOX6 (i.e., 2 courses of PRI-724 and 2&#xD;
      courses of mFOLFOX6), and have received at least 75% of the planned PRI-724 dose, or have&#xD;
      experienced a DLT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In both Phase 1a and Phase 1b, the decision to escalate, expand, or de-escalate a cohort may&#xD;
      be made by the Sponsor and the Investigator(s) in the absence of a defined DLT if it is&#xD;
      determined that a dose level is impractical due to the frequency or nature of toxicities that&#xD;
      do not meet DLT criteria. In such a case when a particular dose is deemed impractical, the&#xD;
      next lower dose cohort may be expanded for further investigation. Once additional safety data&#xD;
      are available, consideration may be given toward identifying the lower dose as the MTD or&#xD;
      recommended Phase 2 dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Throughout the study, enrollment will be staggered between the first and second patient in&#xD;
      each new cohort, to allow for one cycle (2 weeks) to elapse prior to enrolling the second&#xD;
      patient into the cohort.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following toxicities considered by the Investigator to be at least possibly related to&#xD;
      study therapy (or study therapy plus chemotherapy) are defined as DLTs:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Non-Hematological DLTs:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  All Grade 3-4 non-hematologic toxicities that represent a 2 grade increase from&#xD;
           baseline, excluding:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Untreated or inadequately treated nausea, vomiting and diarrhea&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Alopecia&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Grade 3 fatigue that returns to Grade 2 or lower within 7 days&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Grade 3 laboratory and/or metabolic abnormalities that do not return to Grade 2 or lower&#xD;
           within 72 hours despite treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  QTcF &gt; 500 msec OR an increase in QTc by 60 msec from baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hematologic DLTs:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Grade 4 neutropenia&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Grade 4 thrombocytopenia&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Neutropenic fever&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ≥ Grade 3 anemia unresponsive to supportive care including blood transfusion and/or&#xD;
           erythropoietin therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Grade 3 thrombocytopenia with clinically significant bleeding The DLT observation&#xD;
           period, measured from the start of the infusion on the first day, is 2 weeks for the&#xD;
           accelerated phase in the Phase Ia portion, and 4 weeks for the 3 + 3 phase in both the&#xD;
           Phase Ia and Phase Ib portions of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Moderate toxicity (MT) is defined as any ≥ Grade 2 toxicity (except alopecia) that is&#xD;
      considered by the Investigator to be at least possibly related to the study therapy and that&#xD;
      does not qualify as a DLT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the Phase Ia portion, MTD is defined as the highest dose level tested in which no&#xD;
      patient or only 1 patient experienced a DLT attributable to the study drug(s), when at least&#xD;
      6 patients were treated at that dose and are evaluable for toxicity. The MTD is one dose&#xD;
      level below the maximally administered dose (MAD), which is the lowest dose level tested in&#xD;
      which 2 or more patients experienced a DLT attributable to the study drug(s). In Phase Ia at&#xD;
      least 6 patients will be treated at the MTD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the Phase Ib portion, the MTD is defined as the highest dose level tested in which no&#xD;
      patient or only 1 patient experienced a DLT attributable to the study drug(s), when at least&#xD;
      6 patients were treated at that dose and are evaluable for toxicity, or when &lt; 33.3% of&#xD;
      patients experienced a DLT attributable to the study drug(s) when 7 to 12 patients were&#xD;
      treated at that dose and are evaluable for toxicity. (This would allow for up to 2 DLTs when&#xD;
      7 to 9 patients have been enrolled in the expansion cohort or up to 3 DLTs when 10 to 12&#xD;
      patients have been enrolled in the expansion cohort.) The MTD is one dose level below the MAD&#xD;
      which is the lowest dose tested in which&gt; 1 patient in a 3- to 6-patient cohort, or &gt; 33.3%&#xD;
      of patients in an expanded 7- to 12-patient cohort, experienced a DLT attributable to the&#xD;
      study drug(s). In Phase Ib at least 12 patients will be treated at the MTD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is potential for expansion of a lower dose cohort up to 12 patients if the initially&#xD;
      identified and expanded MTD cohort is found to exceed tolerability.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    closing due to low enrollment, no safety issues&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>February 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Therapeutic Dose, as defined by the highest dose identified in which ≤1/3 or ≤2/6 patients do not experience a dose limiting toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at the completion of each patient enrollment cohort. Each patient monitoring duration is 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum Therapeutic Dose (MTD) will be the highest dose in which no dose limiting toxicity (DLT) is seen in a accelerated enrollment cohort (1 patient) and then subsequently a 3-6 patient cohort following a 3+3 study design. MTD may also be determined by evaluation of PK and PD results of patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Therapeutic Dose of combined regimen, as defined by the highest dose identified in which ≤1/3 or ≤2/6 patients do not experience a dose limiting toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at the completion of each patient enrollment cohort. Each patient monitoring duration is 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum Therapeutic Dose (MTD) of the combined regimen will be the highest dose in which MTD is defined as the highest dose level tested in which no patient or only 1 patient experienced a DLT in a 3-6 patient cohort or less than 33.3% of 7 - 12 patients experienced a DLT in the 12-patient expansion cohort. MTD may also be determined by evaluation of PK and PD results of patients.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">23</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Solid Tumors</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PRI-724</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PRI-724</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose escalation</description>
    <arm_group_label>PRI-724</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients must fulfill all of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. In the dose-escalation part of the study (Phase Ia), patients mu have histological or&#xD;
             cytological evidence of solid tumor malignancy; in the tumor-specific,&#xD;
             dose-escalation/MTD-expansion part of the study (Phase Ib), patients must have&#xD;
             histological or cytological evidence of colorectal cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients must have neoplastic disease that is metastatic or unresectable, that has&#xD;
             recurred or progressed following standard therapy, not be candidates for standard&#xD;
             therapy, or have a malignancy for which no standard therapy exists. In Phase&#xD;
             Ib,patients must have colorectal cancer with tumor sites safely accessible for biopsy,&#xD;
             and they must have measurable disease according to the response evaluation criteria in&#xD;
             solid tumors (RECIST 1.1) criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. In Phase Ib patients must have received and either relapsed from or failed at least&#xD;
             two but no more than three prior regimens of chemotherapy, and be eligible to receive&#xD;
             third- or fourth-line therapy for their malignancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients must agree, as part of the informed consent, to provide blood samples for&#xD;
             molecular correlative studies. In the Phase Ib cohorts, patients must agree to pre-&#xD;
             and post-treatment biopsies of their malignant disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients must be &gt; 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients must have a Karnofsky Performance Score of 70% - 100%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients must have a life expectancy of at least 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients or their legal representatives must be able to comprehend and provide written&#xD;
             informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients must have adequate bone marrow reserve as evidenced by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  White blood cell (WBC) count&gt; 3,000/µL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt; 1,500/µL - Platelet count&gt; 100,000/µL&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients must have adequate renal function as evidenced by a serum creatinine value&#xD;
             less than the upper limit of normal (&lt; ULN) for the reference lab or creatinine&#xD;
             clearance (CrCl) of &gt; 60 mL/min (as calculated by Cockcroft-Gault formula).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients must have adequate hepatic function as evidenced by a serum bilirubin &lt; 1.5&#xD;
             mg/dL and serum aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT)&#xD;
             levels &lt; 3X the ULN for the reference lab (&lt; 5X the ULN if there is evidence of&#xD;
             hepatic involvement by malignant disease).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients must be recovered to Grade 1 from the effects (excluding alopecia) of any&#xD;
             prior therapy for their malignancies. In Phase Ib patients must have no peripheral&#xD;
             sensory neuropathy &gt; Grade 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) and male patients with WOCBP partner must be&#xD;
             using an adequate method of contraception to avoid pregnancy throughout the study and&#xD;
             for up to 12 weeks after the last dose of investigational product in such a manner&#xD;
             that the risk of pregnancy is minimized. WOCBP include any female who has experienced&#xD;
             menarche and who has not undergone successful surgical sterilization (hysterectomy,&#xD;
             bilateral tubal ligation, or bilateral oophorectomy) or is not postmenopausal.&#xD;
             Postmenopausal is defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Amenorrhea ≥12 consecutive months without another cause or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  For women with irregular menstrual periods and on hormone replacement therapy&#xD;
                  (HRT), a documented serum follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) level&gt; 35 mIU/mL.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Women who are using oral contraceptives, other hormonal contraceptives (vaginal products,&#xD;
        skin patches, or implanted or injectable products), or mechanical products such as an&#xD;
        intrauterine device or barrier methods (diaphragm, condoms, spermicides) to prevent&#xD;
        pregnancy, or are practicing abstinence or where their partner is sterile (e.g., vasectomy)&#xD;
        should be considered to be of childbearing potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
        WOCBP must have a negative serum pregnancy test (minimum sensitivity 25 IU/L or equivalent&#xD;
        units of human chorionic gonadotropin [HCG]) within 72 hours prior to the start of&#xD;
        investigational product.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients exhibiting any of the following will be excluded from the trial:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Infection requiring systemic antibiotics 72 hours prior to the first dose of PRI-724.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known hypersensitivity to any of the components of PRI-724.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Women who are pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Untreated central nervous system (CNS) metastases; patients whose CNS metastases have&#xD;
             been treated by surgery or radiotherapy, who are no longer on corticosteroids, and who&#xD;
             are neurologically stable may be enrolled in the initial dose escalation portion of&#xD;
             the trial (Phase Ia), but not in the Phase Ib portion of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Treatment with any investigational agent within a period of 28 days between the last&#xD;
             dose of the investigational agent and the first dose of PRI-724.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. QTcF intervals &gt; 470 msec (females) or &gt; 450 msec (males).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Active hepatitis B, hepatitis C.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class 3 or 4; myocardial infarction, acute coronary&#xD;
             syndrome, diabetes mellitus with ketoacidosis or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease&#xD;
             (COPD) requiring hospitalization in the preceding 6 months; or any other intercurrent&#xD;
             medical condition that contra-indicates treatment with PRI-724 or places the patient&#xD;
             at undue risk for treatment-related complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Any other condition, including mental illness or substance abuse, deemed by the&#xD;
             Investigator to be likely to interfere with a patient's ability to sign informed&#xD;
             consent, cooperate and participate in the study, or interfere with the interpretation&#xD;
             of the results.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with a current condition of osteopenia or osteoporosis via a Dual Energy&#xD;
             X-ray Absorptiometry (DEXA) scan; patients with a history of either are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients on any dose of warfarin are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Given the potential interaction between C82, the metabolite of PRI-724, and CYP3A4&#xD;
             inhibitors, treating physicians should exercise caution and switch patients to&#xD;
             equivalent drugs that are not potent CYP3A4 inhibitors when feasible. Medications&#xD;
             which are sensitive substrates of CYP2C9 or CYP3A4 with a narrow therapeutic range&#xD;
             should be used with caution.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. In Phase 1b, patients with a history of poor FOLFOX tolerability as manifested by&#xD;
             inability to tolerate standard therapeutic doses (i.e., at minimum patients must have&#xD;
             tolerated an oxaliplatin dose of 85 mg/m2 and a 5FU dose of 2400 mg/m2).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: Patients are eligible for this trial if, during the previous FOLFOX administration,&#xD;
        they underwent one dose reduction of oxaliplatin due to sensory neuropathy (provided the&#xD;
        neuropathy has now resolved to Grade 1 or less), and/or one dose reduction of 5FU due to&#xD;
        cumulative toxicity.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anthony El-Khoueiry, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Southern California</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Scottsdale</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85259-5499</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Southern California, Norris Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90033</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic, Department of Oncology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55901</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 18, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 18, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 24, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 16, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 16, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 17, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Advanced solid tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>phase 1</keyword>
  <keyword>pancreatic cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>colon cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>unresectable neoplastic disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Progressive cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>metastatic solid tumor</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

