<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01308944</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10-0447 / 201104047</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01308944</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Therapeutic Targeting of Stress Factors in Ovarian Cancer Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Feasibility Study: Therapeutic Targeting of Stress Factors in Ovarian Cancer Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Washington University School of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Washington University School of Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research is looking at the effect of biobehavioral factors such as stress and whether&#xD;
      these factors alter how the body responds to chemotherapy, one of the purposes of this study&#xD;
      is to determine if the addition of a beta-blocker such as Propranolol (Inderal) is tolerable&#xD;
      when given with chemotherapy in the treatment of newly diagnosed ovarian, fallopian tube, or&#xD;
      primary peritoneal cancer. An additional purpose of the study is to understand if behavioral&#xD;
      factors such as depression and anxiety can alter different blood markers that affect tumor&#xD;
      vascularity. The Investigator wishes to determine whether the use of beta-blocker drugs such&#xD;
      as Inderal, might alter these behavioral factors by drawing blood prior to and after the&#xD;
      administration of Inderal as well as giving behavioral questionaires at different time&#xD;
      points. Beta-blockers are commonly used for the treatment of hypertension, protection of the&#xD;
      heart after a heart attack, and irregularities in heartbeats. Altering these factors might&#xD;
      boost the immune system and affect other areas of cancer biology, thereby allowing the&#xD;
      chemotherapy to be more effective. The significance of this research is that it may help&#xD;
      improve our treatments of this disease in the future.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of concurrent beta-blocker administration with chemotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Completion of 6 cycles of chemotherapy/propranolol</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients who successfully complete 6 cycles of chemotherapy and concurrent treatment with propranolol</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival rates</measure>
    <time_frame>From time of diagnosis to 1 year following the 6th cycle of chemotherapy or 18 months following surgery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pilot data on blood markers in patients with ovarian cancer pre- and post-beta blockade</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-surgery, Completion of 3rd cycle of chemo, Completion of 6th cycle of chemo</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterization of biobehavioral states with surveys</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-surgery, Completion of 3rd cycle of chemo, Completion of 2nd cycle of chemo</time_frame>
    <description>To characterize the biobehavioral states of these patients by using the Functional Assessment of Chronic Illness and Therapy- Ovary (FACT-O), Hospital Anxiety and Depression Survey (HADS) and the Center for Epidemiologic Studies Depression Scale (CESD)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of immunohistochemistry of angiogenic markers on tumor samples</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of initial surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Immunohistochemistry for VEGF, IL-6, IL-8, MMP-2 and MMP-9 will be performed on tumor samples.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Invasive Epithelial Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Primary Peritoneal Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Fallopian Tube Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Propranolol 40mg po orally twice daily to begin at least 48 hours prior to surgical debulking. This will ideally be titrated in order to maintain a heart rate between 60 and 80 without hypotension.&#xD;
After surgery, the patient will resume the propranolol once tolerating clear liquids in the hospital and will remain on them until completion of chemotherapy.&#xD;
After completion of chemotherapy, the patient will be weaned off the medication over the following two weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Propranolol</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Inderal</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Preoperative Eligibility Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspected preoperative diagnosis of invasive ovarian cancer, primary peritoneal&#xD;
             carcinoma, fallopian tube cancer based on imaging and CA-125 levels&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must scheduled for a planned tumor debulking at least 72 hours in advance in&#xD;
             order for the patient to take at least 48 hours of prescribed Propranolol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intention for chemotherapy administration at Washington University&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An approved informed consent and authorization permitting release of personal health&#xD;
             information must be signed by patient or guardian&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gynecologic Oncology Group performance status 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient's of childbearing age must have a negative pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who receive neoadjuvant chemotherapy for their ovarian, primary peritoneal,&#xD;
             or fallopian tube cancer are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a prior diagnosis of a borderline tumor that was surgically resected and&#xD;
             who subsequently develop an unrelated new invasive epithelial ovarian, primary&#xD;
             peritoneal, or fallopian tube cancer are eligible, provided that they have not&#xD;
             received chemotherapy for any tumor&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received prior radiotherapy to any portion of the abdominal cavity&#xD;
             or pelvis are excluded. Prior radiation therapy for localized cancer of the breast,&#xD;
             head and neck, or skin is permitted provided that it was completed more than 3 years&#xD;
             prior to registration, and the patient remains free of recurrent or metastatic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a past history of primary endometrial cancer are excluded unless all of&#xD;
             the following conditions are met: stage not greater than stage IA; no more than&#xD;
             superficial myometrial invasion, without vascular or lymphatic invasion; no poorly&#xD;
             differentiated subtypes, including papillary serous, clear cell, or other FIGO grade 3&#xD;
             lesions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With the exception of non-melanoma skin cancer and other specific malignancies as&#xD;
             noted above, patients with other invasive malignancies who had (or have) any evidence&#xD;
             of the other cancer present with the last five years or whose previous cancer&#xD;
             treatment contraindicates this protocol therapy are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of systemic glucocorticoids such as Prednisone or Decadron in the last month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to accurately answer questions (e.g. dementia, brain metastases) or speak&#xD;
             English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cirrhosis of the liver&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a GOG Performance status 3 or 4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under the age of 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Comorbid conditions: Addison's disease, autoimmune hepatitis, hepatitis B, hepatitis&#xD;
             C, AIDS or HIV, lupus erythematosus, mixed connective tissue disease, rheumatoid&#xD;
             arthritis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patients already on beta-blockers or contraindicated to receive beta-blockers&#xD;
&#xD;
        Post-operative Eligibility Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologic diagnosis of invasive epithelial ovarian cancer, primary peritoneal&#xD;
             carcinoma, fallopian tube cancer. Histologic epithelial cell types are eligible:&#xD;
             serous adenocarcinoma, endometrioid adenocarcinoma, mucinous adenocarcinoma,&#xD;
             undifferentiated carcinoma, clear cell carcinoma, mixed epithelial carcinoma, or&#xD;
             adenocarcinoma not otherwise specified. However, the histologic features must be&#xD;
             compatible with primary Müllerian epithelial adenocarcinoma. Patients with low grade&#xD;
             invasive epithelial ovarian cancers may participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stages I-IV of the above cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients having undergone a suboptimal or optimal tumor debulking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gynecologic Oncology Group performance status 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have adequate:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Bone marrow function: Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) greater than or equal to&#xD;
                  1500/ml.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Platelets greater than 100,000/ml&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Renal function: Creatinine ≤ 1.5 x institutional upper limit normal&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Hepatic function: Bilirubin less than or equal to 1.5 x institutional upper limit&#xD;
                  normal; SGOT and alkaline phosphatase less than or equal to 2.5 x institutional&#xD;
                  upper limit normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Neurologic function: Neuropathy (sensory and motor) less than or equal to grade 1&#xD;
                  according to Common Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Events version 3 (CTCAE).&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Blood coagulation parameters: PT such that international normalized ratio (INR)&#xD;
                  is ≤1.5 (or an in-range INR, usually between 2 and 3, if a patient is on a stable&#xD;
                  dose of therapeutic warfarin for the management of venous thrombosis including&#xD;
                  pulmonary embolus) and a PTT &lt;1.2 times institutional upper limit of normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received targeted therapy (including but not limited to vaccines,&#xD;
             antibodies, tyrosine kinase inhibitors) or hormonal therapy for management of their&#xD;
             primary peritoneal, ovarian, or fallopian tube cancer. Patients cannot receive&#xD;
             concurrent bevacizumab or other targeted therapy as part of their primary&#xD;
             chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with non-epithelial ovarian tumors that do not require adjuvant chemotherapy,&#xD;
             borderline epithelial ovarian tumor, or recurrent invasive epithelial ovarian, low&#xD;
             grade ovarian cancer, primary peritoneal, or fallopian tube cancer treated with&#xD;
             surgery only (such as patients with stage IA or IB)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a synchronous primary endometrial cancer are excluded unless all of the&#xD;
             following conditions are met: stage not greater than stage IA; no more than&#xD;
             superficial myometrial invasion, without vascular or lymphatic invasion; no poorly&#xD;
             differentiated subtypes, including papillary serous, clear cell, or other FIGO grade 3&#xD;
             lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metastases to the ovaries from other organs except fallopian tube or primary&#xD;
             peritoneal carcinoma&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Premal Thaker, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Washington University School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington University in St. Louis</name>
      <address>
        <city>St Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.siteman.wustl.edu</url>
    <description>Alvin J. Siteman Cancer Center at Barnes-Jewish Hospital and Washington University School of Medicine</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 16, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 2, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 4, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 11, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 11, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 12, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>invasive epithelial ovarian cancer,</keyword>
  <keyword>primary peritoneal carcinoma,</keyword>
  <keyword>fallopian tube cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Ovarian Epithelial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Propranolol</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

