<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02577835</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>VASOTENS REGISTRY</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02577835</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>International Registry for Ambulatory Blood Pressure and Arterial Stiffness Telemonitoring</brief_title>
  <acronym>VASOTENS</acronym>
  <official_title>International Registry for Ambulatory Blood Pressure and Arterial Stiffness Telemonitoring</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Italian Institute of Telemedicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>BPLab</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Italian Institute of Telemedicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This Registry is an investigator-initiated, international, multicenter, observational,&#xD;
      prospective study aiming at: i) evaluating non-invasive 24-h ambulatory blood pressure and&#xD;
      arterial stiffness estimates (through 24-h pulse wave analysis) in hypertensive subjects; ii)&#xD;
      assessing the changes in estimates following treatment; iii) weighing the impact of 24-h&#xD;
      pulse wave analysis on target organ damage and cardiovascular prognosis; iv) assessing the&#xD;
      relationship between arterial stiffness, blood pressure absolute level and variability, and&#xD;
      prognosis. Approximately 2000 subjects, referred to 20 hypertension clinics for routine&#xD;
      diagnostic evaluation and follow-up of hypertension, will be recruited. Data collection will&#xD;
      include ambulatory blood pressure monitoring, performed with a device allowing simultaneous&#xD;
      non-invasive assessment of blood pressure and arterial stiffness, and clinical data&#xD;
      (including cardiovascular outcomes). A web-based telemedicine platform will be used for data&#xD;
      collection. Subjects will visit the centers at 6-12 month intervals. First follow-up results&#xD;
      are expected to be available in the next 2-years. The results of the Registry will help&#xD;
      defining the normalcy thresholds for current and future indices derived from 24-h pulse wave&#xD;
      velocity, according to outcome data. They will also provide supporting evidence for the&#xD;
      inclusion of such evaluation in recommendations on hypertension management.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The VASOTENS Registry is an international, multicenter, observational, prospective project&#xD;
      Actually, it is a large database of ambulatory blood pressure recordings obtained with a&#xD;
      non-invasive device, able to determine central blood pressure and various indices of arterial&#xD;
      stiffness (mainly pulse wave velocity and augmentation index) over the 24-hours, based on a&#xD;
      clinically validated technology of pulse wave analysis of oscillometric blood pressure&#xD;
      measurements, integrated in an ambulatory blood pressure monitor. Specifically, this project&#xD;
      aims at creating an international network of centers performing ambulatory blood pressure&#xD;
      monitoring and arterial stiffness monitoring, in order to evaluate the impact of such&#xD;
      estimates on the clinical outcome of hypertensive patients. The results of the data collected&#xD;
      at baseline and during regular follow-up of hypertensive patients (up to 2 years) will help&#xD;
      to provide evidence on the clinical usefulness of such technologies for the screening and&#xD;
      follow-up of the hypertensive patients. The registry will include data from subjects&#xD;
      fulfilling the inclusion criteria and whose data are contained in existing databases&#xD;
      collected by the participating centers and who are regularly followed-up at the center. New&#xD;
      subjects can be enrolled for this project, but they must be submitted to ambulatory blood&#xD;
      pressure monitoring because it is required for evaluating their hypertension status,&#xD;
      according to current recommendations. Data collection is ensured by a dedicated web-based&#xD;
      telemedicine platform, including an electronic case report form (e-CRF). The e-CRF allows&#xD;
      collection of patient's clinical data, such as family history, anthropometric data, habits,&#xD;
      past and current diseases, therapies, office blood pressure, and laboratory tests, including&#xD;
      evaluation of target organ damage. The project does not involve any type of intervention&#xD;
      related to the study and the physicians can manage the patients included in the Registry&#xD;
      according to the requirements of clinical practice and current guidelines. However, as&#xD;
      recommended by current guidelines, each patient has to be followed-up with visits occurring&#xD;
      at regular intervals (ideally every 6 months, and not less than once a year). The physicians&#xD;
      is also free to use the ambulatory blood pressure data in the clinical management of the&#xD;
      patients. At least 30 Hypertension centers are planned to be involved in the project, each&#xD;
      one providing at least 100 patients, which have to be followed-up over time. Centers will be&#xD;
      selected in different countries, initially in Europe, starting from Italy and Russia.&#xD;
      Mandatory criteria of a center to be included in the study are the availability in the&#xD;
      facility of a BPLab ambulatory blood pressure monitor, the potential for providing and&#xD;
      properly following-up the number of patients required by the protocol, the availability of&#xD;
      Internet connection, regular access to the web and human resources to upload ambulatory blood&#xD;
      pressure and clinical data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>2 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>24-hour Pulse Wave Velocity (PWV)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>24-hour average value for arterial stifness (m/s)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>24-hour Augmentation Index (AI)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>24-hour average value for waves reflection (percent)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>24-hour Central Blood Pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>24-hour average central aortic pressure (mmHg)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>24-hour Systolic Blood Pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Average 24-hour brachial systolic blood pressure (mmHg)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>24-hour Diastolic Blood Pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Average 24-hour brachial diastolic blood pressure (mmHg)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>24-hour Systolic and Diastolic Blood Pressure standard deviation</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of blood pressure variability (mmHg)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>24-hour Systolic and Diastolic Blood Pressure weighted standard deviation</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of blood pressure variability (mmHg)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>24-hour Systolic and Diastolic Blood Pressure average real variability</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of blood pressure variability (mmHg)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiac Damage (left ventricular hypertrophy at echocardiogram or ECG)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Left ventricular hypertrophy indexed by body surface area (g/m^2)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vascular Damage (carotid plaque at ultrasonography)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Intima media tickness (mmm)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Renal damage (urine protein)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Urine proteine (mg/24h)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiovascular fatal and non fatal events</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Cardiovascular outcomes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2000</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypertension</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hypertensive patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>No intervention. Patients will be sumbitted to standard tests required for hypertension management, including ambulatory blood pressure monitoring, and pharmacologically treated according to recommendations of international guidelines. The registry will include data from subjects fulfilling the inclusion criteria and whose data are contained in existing databases collected by the participating centers and who are regularly followed-up at the center. New subjects can be enrolled for this project, but they must be submitted to ambualtory blood pressure monitoring because it is required for evaluating their hypertension status, according to current recommendations.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ambulatory blood pressure monitoring</intervention_name>
    <description>Ambulatory blood pressure monitoring with arterial stiffness evaluation at 6-12 month intervals.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hypertensive patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Suspected hypertensive patients referred to routine diagnostic evaluation for their&#xD;
        condition (hypertension) or established hypertensive subjects&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects referred to routine diagnostic evaluation for hypertension or established&#xD;
             hypertensive subject&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ABPM performed for clinical reasons with a BPLab device&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Valid ambualtory blood pressure recordings (interval between measurements not &gt;30&#xD;
             minutes, at least 70% of expected number of readings, at least 20 valid readings&#xD;
             during the day-time and 7 during the night-time)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Availability of individual measurements for ambulatory blood pressure monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Availability of basic demographic and clinical information&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Availability of a signed informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Atrial fibrillation, frequent ectopic beats, second or third degree atrioventricular&#xD;
             blocks, or other conditions which might make difficult or unreliable the automatic&#xD;
             blood pressure measurement with the oscillometric technique&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Upper arm circumference &lt;22 cm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Stefano Omboni, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Italian Institute of Telemedicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Stefano Omboni, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+390331984176</phone>
    <email>stefano.omboni@iitelemed.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>DIM Clinica Privada</name>
      <address>
        <city>Buenos Aires</city>
        <country>Argentina</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pedro Forcada, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Servicio de Clínica Médica y Sección Hipertensión Arterial, Hospital Italiano de Buenos Aires</name>
      <address>
        <city>Buenos Aires</city>
        <country>Argentina</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gabriel Waisman</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Center of Preventive Cardiology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Erevan</city>
        <zip>00014</zip>
        <country>Armenia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Parounak Zelveian, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Biomedical Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Macquarie University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sydney</city>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alberto Avolio</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mark Butlin, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Edward Barin, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dipartimento di Scienze Mediche e Chirurgiche, Università di Brescia, Medicina 2, Spedali Civili</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brescia</city>
        <zip>25100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maria Lorenza Muiesan, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anna Paini, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Damiano Rizzoni, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Unità Operativa di Nefrologia ed Ipertensione, Centro di Riferimento Regionale per l'Ipertensione Arteriosa, Policlinico Paolo Giaccone</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palermo</city>
        <zip>90127</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Giuseppe Mulè, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Functional Diagnostics, Medical Centre Hospital of President's Affairs Administration of The Republic of Kazakhstan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Astana</city>
        <country>Kazakhstan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ayana Arystan</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Guadalajara, Dept. of Physiology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Guadalajara</city>
        <zip>44340</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ernesto Cardona Muñoz, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Carlos Ramos, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Adrian Alanis, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clínica da Aveleira, Instituto de Investigação e Formação Cardiovascular</name>
      <address>
        <city>Coimbra</city>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>João Manuel Peixoto Maldonado, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Escola Superior de Tecnologia da Saúde de Coimbra , Instituto Politécnico de Coimbra</name>
      <address>
        <city>Coimbra</city>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Telmo Pereira, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cardiac Rehabilitation Clinic, Tirgu Mures Emergency Clinical County Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Târgu-Mureş</city>
        <country>Romania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ioan Tilea, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Andreaa Varga, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South Ural State Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chelyabinsk</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Elena Grigoricheva, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Vitaly V Evdokimov, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anastasiya Y Kuznetsova, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Diagnostics Department, The Hospital within the Russian Railroad Network</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chita</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Vitaliy Barkan, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marina Gubanova, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Viktoria Lazareva</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Cardiology and Personalized Medicine, Faculty of Doctors' Advanced Training, Peoples' Friendship University of Russia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yulia Kotovskaya, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Cardiology, Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Natalia Bulanova</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Propaedeutics of Internal Diseases, Medical Faculty, Peoples' Friendship University of Russia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Zhanna Kobalava, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institute of Personalized Medicine, Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Philippe Kopylov</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lomonosov Moscow State University Clinic, State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Iana Orlova, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Natalya Kurlykina, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Volga District Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nizhniy Novgorod</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Irina Minyukhina, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Irina Borisova</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tatiana Svetozarsky</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Petrosavodsk Research Center and Department of Faculty Therapy, Infectious Diseases and Epidemiology, Petrozavodsk State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Petrozavodsk</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Viktoria Korneva, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tatyana Kuznetsova, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rostov State Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rostov-at-Don</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Elena Zheleznyak, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>El Zhelezniak, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>North-West Federal Medical Research Centre, Department of Epidemiology</name>
      <address>
        <city>St. Petersburg</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alexandra Konradi, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Oxana Rotar, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alexander Orlov, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Volgograd State Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Volgograd</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mikhail E Statsenko</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Maria V Derevyanchenko</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Scientific Center &quot;M.D. Strazhesko Institute of Cardiology&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kyiv</city>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yuriy M Sirenko, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Oksana Recovets</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
    <country>Armenia</country>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Kazakhstan</country>
    <country>Mexico</country>
    <country>Portugal</country>
    <country>Romania</country>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
    <country>Ukraine</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.vasotens.org</url>
    <description>The official website of the study</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Omboni S, Posokhov IN, Parati G, Avolio A, Rogoza AN, Kotovskaya YV, Mulè G, Muiesan ML, Orlova IA, Grigoricheva EA, Cardona Muñoz E, Zelveian PH, Pereira T, Peixoto Maldonado JM. Vascular Health Assessment of The Hypertensive Patients (VASOTENS) Registry: Study Protocol of an International, Web-Based Telemonitoring Registry for Ambulatory Blood Pressure and Arterial Stiffness. JMIR Res Protoc. 2016 Jun 29;5(2):e137. doi: 10.2196/resprot.5619.</citation>
    <PMID>27358088</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Omboni S, Posokhov IN, Kotovskaya YV, Protogerou AD, Blacher J. Twenty-Four-Hour Ambulatory Pulse Wave Analysis in Hypertension Management: Current Evidence and Perspectives. Curr Hypertens Rep. 2016 Oct;18(10):72. doi: 10.1007/s11906-016-0681-2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27659178</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Omboni S, Posokhov I, Parati G, Rogoza A, Kotovskaya Y, Arystan A, Avolio A, Barkan V, Bulanova N, Cardona Muñoz E, Grigoricheva E, Konradi A, Minyukhina I, Muiesan ML, Mulè G, Orlova I, Pereira T, Peixoto Maldonado JM, Statsenko ME, Tilea I, Waisman G; VASOTENS Registry Study Group. Ambulatory blood pressure and arterial stiffness web-based telemonitoring in patients at cardiovascular risk. First results of the VASOTENS (Vascular health ASsessment Of The hypertENSive patients) Registry. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich). 2019 Aug;21(8):1155-1168. doi: 10.1111/jch.13623. Epub 2019 Jul 11.</citation>
    <PMID>31294910</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Omboni S, Posokhov I, Parati G, Arystan A, Tan I, Barkan V, Bulanova N, Derevyanchenko M, Grigoricheva E, Minyukhina I, Mulè G, Orlova I, Paini A, Peixoto Maldonado JM, Pereira T, Ramos-Becerra CG, Tilea I, Waisman G; VASOTENS Registry Study Group. Variable association of 24-h peripheral and central hemodynamics and stiffness with hypertension-mediated organ damage: the VASOTENS Registry. J Hypertens. 2020 Apr;38(4):701-715. doi: 10.1097/HJH.0000000000002312.</citation>
    <PMID>31834122</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Omboni S, Campolo L, Panzeri E. Telehealth in chronic disease management and the role of the Internet-of-Medical-Things: the Tholomeus® experience. Expert Rev Med Devices. 2020 Jul;17(7):659-670. doi: 10.1080/17434440.2020.1782734. Epub 2020 Jun 30. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32536214</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Omboni S, Panzeri E, Campolo L. E-Health in Hypertension Management: an Insight into the Current and Future Role of Blood Pressure Telemonitoring. Curr Hypertens Rep. 2020 Jun 6;22(6):42. doi: 10.1007/s11906-020-01056-y. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32506273</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Omboni S. The role of e-health in 24-h monitoring of central haemodynamics and vascular function. 2019; 25(1-2): 11-17.</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 13, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 14, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 16, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
  <keyword>Arterial Stiffness</keyword>
  <keyword>Ambulatory blood pressure</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <pending_results>
    <submitted>October 21, 2021</submitted>
    <returned>November 18, 2021</returned>
  </pending_results>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

