<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02237352</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DN-HLV0178-DV</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02237352</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mechanisms of Diabetic Nephropathy in Ecuador</brief_title>
  <official_title>Physiopathogenic Mechanisms Involved in Diabetic Nephropathy, Looking for Prevention and Treatment Solutions</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universidad Estatal de Milagro</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Secretaría de Ciencia, Tecnología e Innovación (Senescyt)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>PROMETEO</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universidad Estatal de Milagro</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The prevalence of diabetes mellitus (DM) is increasing worldwide, suggesting that 45% of&#xD;
      diabetics are undiagnosed. DM induces a kidney disease called diabetic nephropathy (DN) which&#xD;
      is the largest single cause of end-stage renal disease and dialysis requirement. In South&#xD;
      America the prevalence of DM and chronic kidney disease has increased, and great disparity&#xD;
      exists among countries in regards to access to the dialysis treatment. It has been&#xD;
      considerate that Hispanic origin increases the risk for DM. The South Americans have&#xD;
      distinctive habits, culture, environment, behavior and genetic background and the factors&#xD;
      involved in DN have not been defined yet. The early kidney lesions such as neoangiogenesis&#xD;
      (pathologic generation of the new blood vessels) and extracellular matrix expansion have been&#xD;
      described. The vascular endothelial growth factor A (VEGF) has been linked to angiogenesis,&#xD;
      but the role of VEGF in DN has not been elucidated yet. VEGF signals mainly through VEGF&#xD;
      receptor 2 (VEGFR2). VEGFR2 interacts with alphaV beta3 integrin (AVB3) in kidney.&#xD;
      Additionally tenascin C is expressed in the extracellular matrix. Tenascin C and the tenascin&#xD;
      C/AVB3 complex have also been linked to angiogenesis, however their roles have not been&#xD;
      unveiled yet in the DN. Investigators hypothesize that VEGF signaling and tenascin C play an&#xD;
      important role in DN and that VEGFR2, AVB3 and tenascin C interact. The purposes of this&#xD;
      study is to characterize social, environmental and biological factors implicated in the DN in&#xD;
      Ecuador and define the role of VEGF signaling and tenascin C in the pathogenesis of the DN.&#xD;
      Investigators propose to study factors involved in DN in diabetic and non-diabetic adults&#xD;
      from general population, with and without DN. In a single time investigators will evaluate&#xD;
      demographics data, habits, personal and family history through a survey. Investigators will&#xD;
      measure anthropometrics parameters and blood pressure; investigators will quantify blood&#xD;
      glucose, glycosylated hemoglobin A1c and proteinuria. In addition investigators will examine&#xD;
      the role of tenascin C and VEGF signaling by analyzing paraffin embedded kidney tissue,&#xD;
      plasma and urine samples. Characterizing the factors involved in the DN from Hispanic people&#xD;
      is key to establish adequate strategies of prevention, diagnosis and treatment in this&#xD;
      population. Furthermore elucidating the role of proteins involved in DN may offer valuable&#xD;
      tools for the development of new treatments.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Determinations of social, environmental and biological factor implicated in diabetic&#xD;
           nephropathy in Ecuador Investigators will study subjects from the general population.&#xD;
           Investigators will contact community and religious leaders in order to invite adult&#xD;
           subjects from the general population to participate in this study and 10000 persons will&#xD;
           be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
           After teaching basic concepts about prevention of diabetic nephropathy in all subjects,&#xD;
           investigators will collect demographics data, house conditions and localization (rural,&#xD;
           urban or around the cities), number of people that share a home, education level,&#xD;
           employment and economical condition, personal health insurance, medical checkup history,&#xD;
           toxic habits (alcohol, cigarette abuse of addictive substances) and physical exercises&#xD;
           habits. Investigators will collect personal and family antecedent of diabetes mellitus,&#xD;
           diabetic nephropathy, hypertension, kidney diseases, diabetes gestational, current&#xD;
           treatments and other chronic diseases. Investigators will measure body weight (Kg),&#xD;
           height (m) and investigators will calculate body mass index. Investigators will also&#xD;
           measure blood pressure, blood glucose, glycosylated hemoglobin, microalbuminuria and&#xD;
           proteinuria. Trained personnel will fill out the person's survey. Investigators will&#xD;
           supervise and collect data from 2% of the sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Role of extracellular matrix proteins and growth factors signaling in diabetic&#xD;
           nephropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Systemic and urine studies: proteins involved in diabetic nephropathy pathogenesis&#xD;
                as vascular endothelial factor A (VEGF) and extracellular matrix protein as&#xD;
                tenascin C (tenascin) concentration will be measured by a commercially available&#xD;
                kits in plasma and urine (respectively). Samples will be obtained from diabetics&#xD;
                with (n: 20) and without diabetic nephropathy (n: 20) and from non-diabetic&#xD;
                subjects (controls) from the general population (n: 2000). Determinations of&#xD;
                social, environmental and biological factor will be completed as in aim 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Kidney tissue studies: investigators will determine the role of protein involved in&#xD;
                diabetic nephropathy, VEGF signaling and tenascin in:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I) Paraffin embedded kidney tissue obtained from the sample libraries of pathology&#xD;
      laboratories will be studied. Slides from non-diabetics (n: 10) and diabetics with diabetic&#xD;
      nephropathy (n: 20) and without diabetic nephropathy (n: 10) will be collected. The role of&#xD;
      proteins involved in diabetic nephropathy as VEGF signaling and tenascin will be studied by&#xD;
      immunohistochemistry and proximity link assay.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II) Paraffin embedded kidney slides from diabetics with diabetic nephropathy (n: 12),&#xD;
      non-diabetic control (n: 6) with primary glomerulopathy as minimal change disease, and&#xD;
      diabetic controls without diabetic nephropathy (n: 6), will be studied. Investigators will&#xD;
      recruit patients with kidney biopsy indicated, and scheduled to be performed, by their&#xD;
      medical doctors. After pathology diagnosis completion, some of the remnant paraffin embedded&#xD;
      tissue will be used for this study. The role of proteins involved in diabetic nephropathy,&#xD;
      VEGF signaling and tenascin will be studied by immunohistochemistry and proximity link assay.&#xD;
      Urine and plasma will be collected prior to the kidney biopsy in order to measure protein&#xD;
      concentration of potentially useful biomarkers of diabetic nephropathy; VEGF and tenascin&#xD;
      levels will be quantified. Patients will be informed and signed consent will be required.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood glucose will be measured by the blood glucose meter and test strip. Glycosylated&#xD;
      hemoglobin A1c and microalbuminuria (albumin/creatinine in spot urine) will be quantified&#xD;
      using the portable machine (Siemens).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In fasting conditions investigators will consider normal blood glucose values &lt;99 mg%,&#xD;
      pre-diabetes between 100 and 125 mg% and diabetes ≥126 mg%. In non-fasting conditions values&#xD;
      of blood glucose &gt;200mg% will be considered as diabetes. Investigators will deem normal&#xD;
      glycosylated A1c hemoglobin values &lt;5.6 %, pre-diabetes between 5.7 and 6.4% and diabetes&#xD;
      ≥6.5%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigators will deem normal albuminuria values of albumin/creatinine ratio &lt;29mg/g,&#xD;
      microalbuminuria values between 30 and 299 mg/g and macro-albuminuria values ≥300mg/g.&#xD;
      Proteinuria will also be evaluated by reactive urine strips.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the case of inconsistent results or out of range values the analysis will be repeated in&#xD;
      the same sample or re analyzed by standard laboratory equipment and techniques.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigators will consider diabetic nephropathy as persistent proteinuria associated to&#xD;
      diabetic retinopathy and decreased endogen glomerular filtration rate (in subjects without a&#xD;
      diagnosis of other kidney or urinary tract diseases). In Type 1 diabetics, diabetic&#xD;
      nephropathy will be diagnosed if the history of diabetes is longer than 10 years prior to the&#xD;
      onset of proteinuria; in diabetic type 2, proteinuria associated to a decreased glomerular&#xD;
      filtration rate at diagnosis time, investigators will deem diabetic nephropathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In all paraffin embedded kidney samples we will measure the protein expression and&#xD;
      localization. Investigators will use kits, primary and secondary antibodies commercially&#xD;
      available to perform immunohistochemistry and proximity link assay. Investigators will&#xD;
      perform those experiments in cooperation with pathologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All subjects recruited from general population will be identified by a unique code. Number&#xD;
      and capital letters code will be placed in the survey and in the sample labels as M0001 (M:&#xD;
      city, number 0001: person number 0001). Data will be uploaded and saved in a secure data&#xD;
      base. Trained personnel will be in charge of handling the data base. Investigators will&#xD;
      supervise the data entry. An investigator at least once every 6 months will randomly select&#xD;
      2% survey and will match it against the information uploaded in the database. Furthermore,&#xD;
      investigators will analyze and report all collected data from the surveys even if they are&#xD;
      incomplete by adjusting the analysis parameters of the incomplete ones.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigators will use descriptive statistic tools to describe groups (mean, standard&#xD;
      deviation and standard error or median and interquartile range). For group comparisons,&#xD;
      unpaired T test, Mann Whitney or Fisher's test will be used. ANOVA, Kruskal Wallis and Chi&#xD;
      Square test will be performed for to compare unmatched groups; to quantify association&#xD;
      between two variables Pearson and Spearman correlation test will be used. Simple or multiple&#xD;
      regressions will be considered to predict value from variables. P value &lt;0.05 will be deemed&#xD;
      significant. A sample from the general population was calculated considering the adult&#xD;
      population between 21-70 years old in Ecuador.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 15, 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Day</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>House localization</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 month</time_frame>
    <description>House localization (rural, urban or around the cities) in 2000 persons</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Protein expression</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 month</time_frame>
    <description>Protein expression in 1000 persons</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Education level</measure>
    <time_frame>up 12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Education level (primary school, secondary school, university) in 2000 persons.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Employment</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Employment conditions in 2000 persons.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Health insurance coverage</measure>
    <time_frame>12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Personal health insurance coverage in 2000 persons.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Smoking habit</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Smoking habit in 2000 persons.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Physical exercises habits.</measure>
    <time_frame>upt to 12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Physical exercises habits in 2000 persons.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Personal and family antecedent of diabetes mellitus</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Personal and family antecedent of diabetes mellitus in 2000 persons</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Personal and family antecedent of kidney diseases</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Personal and family antecedent of kidney diseases in 2000 persons</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Body mass index</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Body mass index evaluation in 2000 persons</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Systolic pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Systolic pressure evaluation in 2000 persons</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Blood glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>up 12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Blood glucose evaluation in 2000 persons</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Albuminuria</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 month</time_frame>
    <description>Albuminuria evaluation in 2000 persons</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10064</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetic Nephropathy</condition>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <condition>Kidney Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Diabetic Kidney Disease</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Kidney Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <description>Subjects without diabetic nephropathy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Diabetic nephropathy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Subjects with diabetic nephropathy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Plasma and urine.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Community sample (general healthy population and diabetics subjects), and patients with and&#xD;
        without diabetic nephropathy evaluated at Hospital Luis Vernaza&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  adults,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age between 21 and 70 years old,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  persons able to sign informed consent,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  diabetics without diabetic nephropathy,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  diabetic with diabetic nephropathy,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  not hospitalized,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  not suffering acute disease,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  living in their home for at least 6 months before to be contacted.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects with acute diseases,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects with not metabolic compensation,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  persons temporarily residing in the place of contact,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  younger than 21 years old,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  older than 70 years old.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Delma Veron, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Universidad Estatal de Milagro</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UNEMI, Universidad Estatal de Milagro, Facultad de Ciencias de la Salud</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milagro</city>
        <state>Guayas</state>
        <zip>091050</zip>
        <country>Ecuador</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Ecuador</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 10, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 11, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diabetes mellitus</keyword>
  <keyword>Diabetic nephropathy</keyword>
  <keyword>Social Factors</keyword>
  <keyword>Biological Factors</keyword>
  <keyword>VEGF-A</keyword>
  <keyword>Tenascin C</keyword>
  <keyword>Disease characterization</keyword>
  <keyword>Mechanisms</keyword>
  <keyword>Kidney</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic kidney disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Secondary nephropathy</keyword>
  <keyword>South America</keyword>
  <keyword>Hispanics</keyword>
  <keyword>Ecuador</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetic Nephropathies</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

