<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00340418</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999905182</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>05-E-N182</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00340418</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mechanisms of Lung Allograft Rejection</brief_title>
  <official_title>Mechanisms of Lung Allograft Rejection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences (NIEHS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will explore the ways in which lung transplants are rejected. A series of&#xD;
      experiments will evaluate the differences in airway gene expression. Lung transplantation has&#xD;
      become an important option for patients with advanced lung disease. More than 10,000 patients&#xD;
      have received them to date, and about 1,200 transplant operations are performed worldwide&#xD;
      each year. Although short-term survival has continued to improve, the 5-year survival rate is&#xD;
      less than 50%. Most posttransplant deaths are directly or directly caused by chronic lung&#xD;
      rejection, a condition of scarring that worsens lung function. .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients ages 18 and older who have received lung transplants, who are undergoing&#xD;
      bronchoscopy as part of the usual care after transplant, and who are not pregnant may be&#xD;
      eligible for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Bronchoscopy and other procedures performed during this study are done only by doctors with&#xD;
      special training. They will take a total of 30 to 60 minutes. During a bronchoscopy, patients&#xD;
      will lie on a flat bed. They will be awake and follow instructions. First they will breathe&#xD;
      Xylocaine (lidocaine), an anesthetic mist, for 8 to 10 minutes. That will lessen the&#xD;
      discomfort of a small flexible tube called a bronchoscope that will be guided through the&#xD;
      back of the patient's mouth or nose and into the breathing tubes. When the flexible tube is&#xD;
      placed, patients will not be able to speak. They will receive the medication Versed&#xD;
      (midazolam), to make them relaxed and not remember most of the procedure, and fentanyl, to&#xD;
      decrease the possibility of feeling pain. These medications will be given through a narrow&#xD;
      tube feeding into a small needle placed into a vein in the arm. The risks of the tube placed&#xD;
      in the vein include bleeding, swelling, redness, and pain. Side effects from the medications&#xD;
      may include stomach upset, heart palpitations (awareness of heartbeat), and changes in blood&#xD;
      pressure. Patients will be carefully monitored for heart rate, blood pressure, breathing, and&#xD;
      oxygen levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the bronchoscopy, a procedure called bronchoalveolar lavage is done, in which a small&#xD;
      amount of germ-free salt water is injected into through the bronchoscope into the lung and&#xD;
      immediately suctioned back, thus washing the lining of the airways and checking for infection&#xD;
      and rejection of the transplanted lungs. About 1 or 2 tablespoons of fluid will be collected&#xD;
      for analysis. Also, an endobronchial brush biopsy may be performed. A small brush removes&#xD;
      some of the cells from the surface of the airway. These cells will be sent to a laboratory at&#xD;
      Duke University Health system to analyze the signals from the cells that may eventually led&#xD;
      to scarring and chronic rejection of the lungs. Then, an endobronchial forceps biopsy is&#xD;
      performed, in which one or two small pieces, each about the size of a grain of rice, of the&#xD;
      lining of the lung's large airways is removed. A small surgical tool like tweezers is passed&#xD;
      into the lung. Risks of biopsies may include bleeding, injury to the lung, or an air leak in&#xD;
      the lung.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will not have a direct benefit for participants. However, it is hoped that&#xD;
      information gathered will enhance researchers' understanding of how lung rejection occurs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Lung transplantation has emerged as a viable therapeutic option in the care of patients with&#xD;
      advanced pulmonary parenchymal and pulmonary vascular disease. Currently, over 10,000&#xD;
      patients have received lung transplantation with approximately 1200 transplant operations&#xD;
      performed worldwide each year. Short term survival after lung transplantation has continued&#xD;
      to improve since the widespread application of this procedure and one-year survival at most&#xD;
      centers now approaches 80%. Unfortunately, long-term outcomes after lung transplantation are&#xD;
      disappointing with five-year survival below 50%. Most posttransplant deaths are due directly&#xD;
      or indirectly to the development of chronic allograft rejection, which affects approximately&#xD;
      50% of all five-year survivors. Acute rejection is the major risk factor for the development&#xD;
      of chronic rejection. Chronic lung rejection leads to a condition of irreversible fibrosis&#xD;
      and obliteration of the small to medium size bronchioles known as obliterative bronchiolitis&#xD;
      (OB). Very little is known about the pathogenic mechanisms that lead to the development of&#xD;
      OB. Furthermore, it is unclear why acute rejection leads to the development of chronic&#xD;
      rejection in some but not all patients. In order to better understand the mechanisms of OB we&#xD;
      propose a series of experiments designed to evaluate differences in airway gene expression in&#xD;
      a series of lung transplant recipients with and without acute rejection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 23, 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date>April 13, 2007</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <enrollment>120</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Transplant</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Allograft Rejection</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All adult (18 and older) lung transplant recipients who are undergoing bronchoscopy as part&#xD;
        of the usual posttransplant care will be eligible.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NIEHS, Research Triangle Park</name>
      <address>
        <city>Research Triangle Park</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27709</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tazelaar HD, Yousem SA. The pathology of combined heart-lung transplantation: an autopsy study. Hum Pathol. 1988 Dec;19(12):1403-16.</citation>
    <PMID>3142814</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 13, 2007</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 19, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 19, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 21, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Bronchoalveolar Lavage</keyword>
  <keyword>Acute Rejection</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Rejection</keyword>
  <keyword>Genetic Polymorphisms</keyword>
  <keyword>Innate Immunity</keyword>
  <keyword>Lung Transplantation</keyword>
  <keyword>Lung Allograft Rejection</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

