<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04297761</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19-2078</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04297761</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cardiovascular Effects of Exposure to Wood Smoke in Healthy Human Adults</brief_title>
  <acronym>MASKOFF</acronym>
  <official_title>Cardiovascular Effects of Exposure to Wood Smoke in Healthy Human Adults</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Purpose: The study is designed to investigate cardiovascular effects of young healthy human&#xD;
      subjects exposed to wood smoke.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants: Approximately 80 young (18-35 years old) healthy subjects to complete.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedure (methods): After consenting to participate in the study, subjects will undergo&#xD;
      exposures over consecutive days, once to filtered air alone and once to air containing 500&#xD;
      µg/m^3 of wood smoke. Each exposure will be 2 hours long with alternating 15 min of mild&#xD;
      exercise (cycle ergometer) and rest . The exercise level will be adjusted to achieve 12&#xD;
      L/min/m^2 minute ventilation. Induced sputum samples will be collected 4 hours post exposure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Wood smoke pollution is a common problem across the world, including in the US. This wood&#xD;
      smoke comes from people using wood to heat and cook, as well as from wildfires. The purpose&#xD;
      of this research study is to investigate the cardiovascular effects of exposure to wood smoke&#xD;
      in young healthy human subjects. Results from this study will also increase our understanding&#xD;
      of how wood smoke exposure adversely affects the functioning of the human cardiovascular and&#xD;
      respiratory systems. This understanding may be especially important for patients with&#xD;
      cardiopulmonary diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 80 people will participate in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You should expect to be in this study for about a month, but your participation could&#xD;
      possibly last for 6 months. There are 4 sessions, including a consenting session (today)&#xD;
      which will last for about 4 hours. The two exposure-day sessions will last approximately 8-9&#xD;
      hours each. There will also be an approximately 3-hour follow-up visit the day after your&#xD;
      last exposure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before you agree to participate in this study, you must read the consent forms in their&#xD;
      entirety. The research and medical staff will then answer all your questions and explain all&#xD;
      the risks involved in this study to your satisfaction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You should have already undergone a general physical examination to ensure that you are a&#xD;
      suitable candidate for this study. If you are a female, you will be asked about your&#xD;
      menstrual history. For all other female participants, a pregnancy test will be performed&#xD;
      today, and this will be repeated on the exposure day if more than 7 days since last pregnancy&#xD;
      test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consenting Day We will go over the study in detail so that you will know what we will expect&#xD;
      from you as a participant and what you should expect from us as investigators. If you agree&#xD;
      to participate in the study, you will sign all study consent forms and receive one set of&#xD;
      signed copies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will have a breathing test (spirometry). You will breathe through a filter into a plastic&#xD;
      device. Your lung function test results should meet certain criteria (Both Forced Vital&#xD;
      Capacity (FVC) and Forced Expiatory Volume at the 1st second (FEV1) are equal to and greater&#xD;
      than 80% of the reference value) to allow you to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will be asked to wear a face mask, also called face filtering pieces (FFP), and the&#xD;
      efficiency of the FFP will be measured. You will complete a short survey on your previous&#xD;
      experience of using such masks. Then you will put on a provided mask under four scenarios&#xD;
      that simulate real world conditions. During the test, you will be asked to perform a few&#xD;
      simple tasks such as bending over, talking, etc. A particle counter will be used to monitor&#xD;
      the particle number behind the facemask and in the ambient air. Room air particles will&#xD;
      consist of fine droplets made up of water and table salt (sodium chloride) that will be&#xD;
      emitted by a particle generator. The efficiency of the facemask performance under each&#xD;
      condition will be recorded and compared.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will undergo a procedure for nasal epithelial lining fluid (NELF) sampling (nasal mucosa)&#xD;
      and a procedure for induced sputum. If you are a non-producer or the quality of the induced&#xD;
      sputum sample that you produce does not meet the study criteria (we will know the sputum&#xD;
      quality in the next two days), we will exclude you from the study. If that happens, you will&#xD;
      be reimbursed for the time and procedures for the consenting session. If you qualify, you&#xD;
      will be given instructions to prepare for the exposure sessions. Then you will be scheduled&#xD;
      for the exposure sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exposure days We will call you a few days before the exposure session to remind you of your&#xD;
      scheduled visit. You should avoid smoke, fumes, alcohol, and strenuous exercise 24 hours&#xD;
      prior to all visits, and abstain from pan fried or grilled meat after midnight of the&#xD;
      exposure day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will be asked to eat a light breakfast and arrive at the EPA medical station by 7:30 am.&#xD;
      Please understand that it is very important that you arrive by this time in order for the&#xD;
      study team to process all of the samples and data. Please note that we may have to cancel&#xD;
      your participation if you arrive late.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to exposure, you will:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have your vital signs checked (heart rate, respiratory rate, blood pressure, oxygen&#xD;
           saturation level, and fill out a symptom questionnaire electronically).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have your heart rhythm recorded by a Holter monitor. You will have (10)&#xD;
           electrocardiogram (ECG) leads attached to your chest. It may be necessary to clean and&#xD;
           shave the areas of your chest where these leads will be placed. Excessive deodorant,&#xD;
           skin lotions, and body sprays may interfere with the function of some of these leads.&#xD;
           Therefore, we ask you to not apply these to your chest area on the day you report to the&#xD;
           HSF. The leads will be connected to 2 monitors (small recording devices about the size&#xD;
           and weight of a cell phone) to obtain readings of your heart rate and rhythm. It is&#xD;
           preferable that the electrodes will stay in place for approximately 2 ½ days as you will&#xD;
           have this measured several times during the study, however, you will be given the option&#xD;
           to remove the electrodes by the end of each exposure day. You will be asked to recline&#xD;
           quietly for 30 minutes while collecting your heart rhythm. It is important that you do&#xD;
           not fall asleep during this 30-minute period. These measurements will allow us to&#xD;
           determine whether wood smoke exposure causes small changes in the ability of your&#xD;
           nervous system to regulate how your heart beats.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have the diameter of an artery in your upper arm measured by an ultrasound machine&#xD;
           (BAU). The ultrasound operator will scan your arm with a probe and then place a&#xD;
           tourniquet on your arm, much like a cuff used to measure blood pressure. Measurement of&#xD;
           the size of the artery will be made two times. First, you will be asked to rest quietly&#xD;
           for 15 minutes, and then the first 90 second scan will be performed. Then the blood&#xD;
           pressure cuff on your arm will be inflated for 5 minutes in order to temporarily stop&#xD;
           the flow of blood. You may feel sensations similar to that when your foot &quot;goes to&#xD;
           sleep&quot;, such as &quot;pins and needles&quot; and tingling. After the pressure cuff is released, a&#xD;
           second scan will be taken of the artery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have your retinas imaged using an ophthalmic camera before and after each exposure, and&#xD;
           on the follow-up visit. You will be asked to place your chin on a rest in front of the&#xD;
           camera. We will take pictures of the inside of both of your eyes. Glasses or contacts&#xD;
           have to be removed for this test. Please bring your own contact lens container and&#xD;
           solutions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Approximately 60 ml blood drawn (about 4 tablespoons) before and after each exposure,&#xD;
           and on the follow-up visit. We will test this blood to see if wood smoke affects the&#xD;
           ability of your blood cells to function. A small portion of the blood sample will be&#xD;
           used to measure the relative content of various fatty acids present in your blood. With&#xD;
           your permission, we also store some of the blood that we obtain during the study for&#xD;
           yet-to-be-determined tests in the future.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have a breathing test (spirometry).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Enter the exposure chamber and be exposed to filtered air or wood smoke.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the exposure, you will:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Undergo exposure for 2 hours to either clean filtered air or wood smoke in the chamber. You&#xD;
      will receive clean filtered air on one day and wood smoke on the other day. You will not be&#xD;
      given the information of the sequence of the exposure. The concentration of wood smoke that&#xD;
      you will be exposed to in this study (approximately 500 μg/m3) are below those reported for&#xD;
      those using biomass burning for heating and food preparation, those firefighters are exposed&#xD;
      to, and those living in the area of a forest fire or agricultural burning are exposed to.&#xD;
      Chamber conditions will be at a comfortable temperature and relative humidity. You will do&#xD;
      mild exercise on a stationary bicycle in the chamber every other 15 minutes alternating with&#xD;
      resting period for a total of 1 hour of exercise per chamber exposure. The target ventilation&#xD;
      rate will be maintained at 12 L/min/ m2 and monitored by using pneumotach and BioPac methods.&#xD;
      A study coordinator or other trained person will be seated outside the chamber observing you&#xD;
      at all times. During the exposure, your heart will be monitored and the amount of oxygen&#xD;
      present in your blood will be monitored by placing a device (pulse oximeter) on your finger.&#xD;
      If it appears you are experiencing significant discomfort, breathing or heart problems, the&#xD;
      exposure will be terminated immediately. In addition, you may elect to terminate the exposure&#xD;
      at any time for any reason. If you do so, you will be paid in full for that day's session but&#xD;
      will be ineligible for further participation in the study and any payments you would have&#xD;
      received for future participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Immediately following the exposure, you will repeat the pre-exposure procedures and have a&#xD;
      low fat lunch brought by you.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Once you complete the above procedures, you will have about 1-2 hour waiting time before&#xD;
           the next procedure. You can bring your personal laptop or books to use during that time.&#xD;
           You will not be able to eat any food during this break time. We also encourage you to&#xD;
           take a shower to get rid of the wood smoke odor at a private shower facility here at the&#xD;
           HSF. Towel, soap and shampoo will be provided.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have samples of your nasal epithelial lining fluid (NELF) collected. Study staff will&#xD;
           give you small filter paper strips and you will insert one into each nostril. You will&#xD;
           wear nose clips for two minutes to allow for lining fluid absorption to the paper. The&#xD;
           paper will then be removed and collected specimen placed into sample tubes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have samples of your airway secretions collected using the induced sputum procedure. You&#xD;
           will be asked to breathe in different saline solutions (up to 5%) to help you&#xD;
           expectorate. We will coach you on the procedure. First, you will gargle and clear your&#xD;
           throat, and the cough up samples from deep in your chest and spit them into a cup. Your&#xD;
           lung function will be monitored during the procedure. Food must be avoided for 2 hours&#xD;
           prior to this test.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  TracMyAir: The TracMyAir App on an EPA provided smartphone will be used by study&#xD;
           personnel each day when you visit the EPA health study facility. The App will not be&#xD;
           installed on your phone. The study staff will ask you questions on your home building&#xD;
           characteristics, home operating conditions, time-spent in different outdoor and indoor&#xD;
           environments, and time-spent at different physical activity levels. The study personnel&#xD;
           will input data for you into the App. At the end of each exposure day, the EPA&#xD;
           smartphone with TracMyAir app will be issued to you and will continuously measure your&#xD;
           location like a GPS travel recorder. You will return the phone on the following day.&#xD;
           TracMyAir does not save the calculated exposures on the smartphone and the data is&#xD;
           de-identified.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  GPS travel recorder: will be issued to you on the day of your exposure session and&#xD;
           returned to facility on the next day. This device continuously monitors GPS coordinates&#xD;
           and records internally. You will carry the device at all times (24 hours) to record your&#xD;
           location so that we can assess your exposure to air pollution during the day. The&#xD;
           location data are not displayed and are only available to download with proper&#xD;
           proprietary software after your session. Data will be downloaded and stored onto a&#xD;
           secure database.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Be assessed and discharged by the study personnel.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow up visit (about 3 hours) You will return to the HSF the next morning (approximately 18&#xD;
      hours after your 2nd exposure) and you will repeat the pre-exposure procedures.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in polymorphonuclear neutrophils (PMN%) in the Sputum</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 2</time_frame>
    <description>Airway inflammation will be assessed by the % PMN in the sputum</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Forced Expired Volume in the First Second (FEV1) (liter) from Day 1 to Day 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 2</time_frame>
    <description>FEV1 is determined by spirometry on day 1 and day 2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in FEV1 (liter) from Day 2 to follow-up day</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2, 18 hr post exposure</time_frame>
    <description>FEV1 is determined by spirometry on day 2 and on the follow-up day</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Forced Vital Capacity (FVC) (liter) from Day 1 to Day 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 2</time_frame>
    <description>FVC is determined by spirometry on day 1 and day 2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in FVC (liter) from Day 2 to follow-up day</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2, 18 hrs post exposure</time_frame>
    <description>FVC is determined by spirometry on day 2 and on the follow-up day</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Endothelial Cell Function (mm) from Day 1 to Day 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 2</time_frame>
    <description>Brachial artery ultrasound will be used to evaluate flow-mediated dilatation which will be performed using an ultrasound instrument on day 1 and day 2.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Endothelial Cell Function (mm) from Day 2 to follow-up day</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2, 18 hrs post exposure</time_frame>
    <description>Brachial artery ultrasound will be used to evaluate flow-mediated dilatation which will be performed using an ultrasound instrument on day 2 and on the follow-up day.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Diameters (mm) of Retinal Arteries and Veins from Day 1 to Day 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 2</time_frame>
    <description>Retinal images will be taken using an FDA-approved, commercially available, non-mydriatic fundus camera. Images will be taken from both eyes on day 1 and day 2.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Diameters (mm) of Retinal Arteries and Veins from Day 2 to follow-up day</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2, 18 hrs post exposure</time_frame>
    <description>Retinal images will be taken using an FDA-approved, commercially available, non-mydriatic fundus camera. Images will be taken from both eyes on day 2 and on the follow-up day.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent Change in Heart Rate Variability from Day 1 to Day 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 2</time_frame>
    <description>Heart rate variability will be collected by the Holter monitor recording on day 1 and day 2.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent Change in Heart Rate Variability from Day 2 to follow-up day</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2, 18 hrs post exposure</time_frame>
    <description>Heart rate variability will be collected by the Holter monitor recording on day 2 and on the follow-up day.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Blood Fatty Acids (ng/mL) from Day 1 to Day 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 2</time_frame>
    <description>Blood sample will be collected for fatty acids analysis on day 1 and day 2.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Blood Fatty Acids (ng/mL) from Day 2 to follow-up day</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2, 18 hrs post exposure</time_frame>
    <description>Blood sample will be collected for fatty acids analysis on day 2 and on the follow-up day.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Blood Cholesterol (ng/mL) from Day 1 to Day 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 2</time_frame>
    <description>Blood sample will be collected for blood cholesterol analysis on day 1 and day 2.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Blood Cholesterol (ng/mL) from Day 2 to follow-up day</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2. 18 hrs post exposure</time_frame>
    <description>Blood sample will be collected for blood cholesterol analysis on day 2 and on the follow-up day.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Cytokines in Nasal Epithelial Lining Fluid (NELF) (ng/mL) from Day 1 to Day 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 2</time_frame>
    <description>NELF samples will be collected for cytokine measurements on day 1 and day 2.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Cytokines in NELF (ng/mL) from Day 2 to follow-up day</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2,18 hrs post exposure</time_frame>
    <description>NELF samples will be collected for cytokine measurements on day 2 and on the follow-up day.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fit Efficiency (percent) of a N95 Respirator</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline visit</time_frame>
    <description>A mask fit procedure will be performed based on a NIOSH (National Institute of Occupational Safety and Health) - approved protocol during the baseline visit. The efficiency of a N95 mask will be determined by a percentage of particle number measured behind the facemask over the particle number in the ambient air. Mask fit efficiency values from different levels of mask fit instructions will be compared.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Filtered air</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be exposed once to filtered air for 2 hours with alternating 15 min of exercise (cycle ergometer) and rest.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Wood Smoke</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be exposed to air containing wood smoke for 2 hours with alternating 15 min of exercise (cycle ergometer) and rest.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Filtered Air</intervention_name>
    <description>Ambient air will be filtered and used for control exposure.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Filtered air</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Wood Smoke</intervention_name>
    <description>Wood smoke is generated by smoldering dry white oak logs and the exposure level will be maintained at an average of 500 µg/m^3 for 2 hours.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Wood Smoke</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18-35 years old healthy male and female (BMI (body mass index) values between 19&#xD;
             and 30, inclusive).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physical conditioning allowing intermittent, mild exercise for 2 hours, and ability to&#xD;
             complete the exposure exercise regimen to induce a minute ventilation rate of 12&#xD;
             L/min/m^2 for 15 min without exceeding 80% of projected maximal heart rate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal EKG (electrocardiogram).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal lung function based on the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey&#xD;
             (NHANES) III reference values.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Forced vital capacity (FVC) equal to or greater than 80 % of that predicted for&#xD;
                  age, gender, ethnicity, and height.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Forced expiratory volume in one second (FEV1) equal to or greater than 80% of&#xD;
                  that predicted for age, gender, ethnicity, and height.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  FEV1/FVC ratio equal to or greater than 80% of predicted values.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Oxygen saturation greater than 94% at the time of physical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Have received the last dose of a COVID-19 vaccine at least 14 days prior to&#xD;
                  participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with following conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  a history of acute or chronic cardiovascular disease, chronic respiratory&#xD;
                  disease, cancer, rheumatologic disease, neuromuscular disease, or&#xD;
                  immunodeficiency state.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  blood pressure readings equal to or greater than 140 systolic and equal to or&#xD;
                  greater than 90 diastolic.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  diabetes (previously diagnosed or with hemoglobin A1c level equal to or greater&#xD;
                  than 6.4%).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  asthma or a history of asthma.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  bleeding/clotting disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with a cardiovascular disease risk score greater than 10% using the&#xD;
             American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association (ACC/AHA) Atherosclerotic&#xD;
             Cardiovascular Disease (ASCVD) risk calculator. (Based on the 10-year risk of heart&#xD;
             disease or stroke using the Atherosclerotic Cardiovascular Disease algorithm published&#xD;
             in 2013 ACC/AHA Guideline on the Assessment of Cardiovascular risk.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who have unspecified illnesses, which in the judgment of the medical staff&#xD;
             might increase the risk associated with wood smoke inhalation will be a basis for&#xD;
             exclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are currently taking systemic steroids or oral anticoagulants long&#xD;
             term.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are taking prescribed medications such as ß-blocker medications, that&#xD;
             may impact the results of wood smoke challenge for the duration of the study. Other&#xD;
             medications not specifically mentioned here may be reviewed by the medical staff prior&#xD;
             to an individual's inclusion in the study. Use of other medications will be evaluated&#xD;
             on a case-by-case basis. There is the potential that an individual's current&#xD;
             medication use will preclude them from participating in the study at the current time,&#xD;
             but they may be reassessed and potentially rescheduled for participation later based&#xD;
             on the judgement of the medical staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are allergic to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  chemical vapors or gases.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  tape or electrodes on their skin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are pregnant, attempting to become pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are currently smoking (including vaping, hookah and e-cigarette) or&#xD;
             have smoking history within 1 year of study or have an equal to or greater than a&#xD;
             5-pack year smoking history.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals living with a smoker who smokes inside the house.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are regularly exposed to high levels of vapors, dust, gases, or fumes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who do not read, speak, or understand English well enough to give informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals that are unable to perform the exercise required for the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are unwilling or unable to stop taking any current dietary supplements&#xD;
             or vitamins for the duration of the study. Prebiotics and probiotics are acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are unwilling to avoid caffeine for 12 hours prior to all visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are not willing to shave their facial hair, if any, that will affect&#xD;
             the N95 facemask sealing for the N95 facemask fit test during the consenting visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Temporary exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who have recent (within 6 month) abdominal and/or eye surgery, or with any&#xD;
             types of hernia, as well as any other contraindications for raised intra-abdominal&#xD;
             pressure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who have had an acute respiratory illness within 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who have active allergies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who take over-the counter pain medications (such as aspirin, Advil, Aleve)&#xD;
             or NSAIDs, or have taken these medications within the last 48 hours.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>James Samet, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Robin Kaminski</last_name>
    <phone>(919) 966-0604</phone>
    <email>Kaminski.Robin@epa.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Patrice Ratliffe</last_name>
    <phone>919-966-0607</phone>
    <email>Ratliffe.Patrice@epa.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency Human Studies Facility</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27514</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Patrice Ratliffe</last_name>
      <phone>919-966-0607</phone>
      <email>Ratliffe.Patrice@epa.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>James Samet, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>919-966-0665</phone>
      <email>Samet.James@epa.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>James Samet, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 3, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Healthy subjects</keyword>
  <keyword>Wood smoke</keyword>
  <keyword>Respiratory effects</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiovascular effects</keyword>
  <keyword>Young</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Deidentified individual data will be shared through the U.S. EPA's ScienceHub database. ScienceHub is used to upload and store datasets associated with journal articles. Non-sensitive datasets are then made publicly accessible via the Environmental Dataset Gateway in fulfillment of the EPA's requirement to adhere to the Office of Management and Budget's Open Data Policy.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The data will be available to the public after the conclusion of the study and the publication of the manuscripts.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Data will be available at the U.S. EPA Science Hub.</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>https://catalog.data.gov/dataset/epa-sciencehub</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

