<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04294901</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IIR 18-228</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04294901</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Engaging Patients to Promote Deprescribing</brief_title>
  <official_title>Engaging Patients to Promote Deprescribing</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      One mechanism to reduce potentially inappropriate medications is through deprescribing, a&#xD;
      deimplementation-based approach to thoughtfully discontinue a medication a patient is&#xD;
      currently prescribed. Many interventions to overcome deprescribing barriers target the&#xD;
      provider, who is already overburdened. Although some believe providers have primary&#xD;
      responsibility for deprescribing, patient-initiated discontinuation discussions can&#xD;
      effectively facilitate deprescribing. In a single-site pilot study, the investigators&#xD;
      successfully engaged VA Primary Care patients to facilitate deprescribing of select&#xD;
      potentially inappropriate medications. The investigators now propose a multisite randomized&#xD;
      controlled trial of engaging Veterans who may be deprescribing candidates. By study end, the&#xD;
      investigators will have established the effectiveness of an innovative, low-tech,&#xD;
      patient-focused intervention to promote deprescribing, thereby directly improving quality,&#xD;
      safety, and value of VA care while also setting the stage for generalization of this approach&#xD;
      to other potentially inappropriate medications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background - Despite multiple provider- and system-level interventions to reduce potentially&#xD;
      inappropriate medications (PIMs), many Veterans are still prescribed drugs that provide&#xD;
      little benefit, placing them at unnecessary risk of adverse drug events (ADEs). One mechanism&#xD;
      to reduce PIMs is through deprescribing, a de-implementation-based approach to thoughtfully&#xD;
      discontinue a medication a patient is currently prescribed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Many Choosing Wisely recommendations address PIMs. Specifically, proton pump inhibitors&#xD;
      (PPIs), a medicine used to reduce gastric acid, should be de-escalated to the lowest dose&#xD;
      necessary to provide relief. Many older patients with diabetes are over-controlled, with&#xD;
      blood sugar levels lower than recommended, yet remain on multiple diabetes medicines and may&#xD;
      be able to use fewer medicines. These patients are also at higher risk of low blood sugar&#xD;
      from insulin and sulfonylureas, and should have limited use of these agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Finally, gabapentin is often used off-label to treat pain, with greatly increased use over&#xD;
      the past several years. There are many barriers to deprescribing PIMs. Many interventions&#xD;
      solely target the prescribing provider. Although some believe providers have primary&#xD;
      responsibility for deprescribing, patient initiation of discontinuation conversations can&#xD;
      effectively facilitate deprescribing. In a single-site pilot study, the investigators&#xD;
      successfully reduced PIMs by engaging VA Primary Care patients by providing them with&#xD;
      Veteran-centric EMPOWER (&quot;Eliminating Medications through Patient Ownership of End Results&quot;)&#xD;
      brochures. However, it is not known if this approach will be as successful for Veterans with&#xD;
      other chronic conditions or at non-pilot sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims - The investigators propose three aims. 1) Examine the impact of a patient-centered&#xD;
      intervention to change provider prescribing (the primary outcome), as determined by the&#xD;
      frequency with which medications are either deprescribed or de-escalated. 2) Examine the&#xD;
      effect of a patient-centered intervention on engaging patients, via post-visit surveys of&#xD;
      Veterans' interaction with the brochures and their influence on deprescribing discussions and&#xD;
      deprescribing. 3) Using qualitative methods, identify key organizational contextual factors&#xD;
      related to intervention fidelity, feasibility, acceptability, and appropriateness to support&#xD;
      future implementation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods and Innovation - The investigators propose a multisite quasi-experimental trial using&#xD;
      a Hybrid Type I Effectiveness-Implementation design of providing EMPOWER brochures directly&#xD;
      to Veterans who may be deprescribing candidates for three cohorts of PIMs (PPIs, diabetes&#xD;
      medications, and gabapentin). The investigators will mail brochures in advance of scheduled&#xD;
      primary care visits, unlike distribution methods used in other studies. The primary outcome&#xD;
      will be the composite of deprescribing and de-escalation of target medications, identified in&#xD;
      pharmacy dispensing records of the Corporate Data Warehouse (Aim 1). Mail-based surveys sent&#xD;
      after the scheduled primary care visit will assess patient engagement with the brochure and&#xD;
      its impact on patient-provider communication (Aim 2). Finally, qualitative data from&#xD;
      clinicians and staff addressing Proctor's Implementation Outcomes will provide the foundation&#xD;
      for future implementation strategies (Aim 3).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Significance and Next Steps - The study directly addresses multiple Veteran Care Priorities,&#xD;
      including health care value, primary care practice, quality/safety, and Whole Health, and is&#xD;
      aligned with current VA initiatives to prioritize patient preferences via&#xD;
      individually-tailored, proactive care plans. The proposed work is strongly supported by&#xD;
      Pharmacy Benefits Management and Office of Patient Centered Care and Cultural Transformation,&#xD;
      which will facilitate the dissemination of findings to improve the quality and safety of&#xD;
      medication use within VA. By study end, the investigators will have established the&#xD;
      effectiveness of an innovative, low-tech, patient-focused intervention to promote&#xD;
      deprescribing of commonly used medications for three populations, thereby directly improving&#xD;
      quality, safety, and value of VA care while also setting the stage for wider implementation&#xD;
      and generalization of this approach to other potentially inappropriate medications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 29, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 29, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 28, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The investigators will target Veterans at three primary care sites who meet eligibility criteria for one of the PIM cohorts and are prescribed the target medication at the time of their scheduled primary care visit. At each intervention site, individual PCPs will be randomized to the sequence of patient cohorts. The study will begin with a 13-month retrospective baseline period, with one month for baseline subject identification and 12 months for observation of baseline subjects' deprescribing outcomes. Then, each PCP will be randomized to the order of three 4-month periods during which their eligible patients receive medication-specific brochures, one medication cohort at a time. The primary comparisons are between &quot;brochure-intervention&quot; patients and &quot;baseline&quot; patients (matched in terms of eligibility) from the same provider.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Our Aim 1 primary quantitative outcome will be binary: deprescribing versus not</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months post-index date</time_frame>
    <description>Non-refill of the medication in the 6 months following the primary care appointment as our a priori definition of cessation, based upon dispensing dates. If the medication continues to be dispensed, the investigators will determine any reduction in the total daily dose, indicating de-escalation (one component of our deprescribing definition). An exception to the de-escalation rule will be for insulin, where only complete cessation will qualify since dose changes are less likely to be reflected in the order compared to oral medications.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Deprescribing conversations</measure>
    <time_frame>index visit until survey completion, expected to occur 1-8 weeks post-index visit .</time_frame>
    <description>Patient report of a conversation about deprescribing during the index primary care visit</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">6800</enrollment>
  <condition>Medical Overuse</condition>
  <condition>Inappropriate Prescribing</condition>
  <condition>Deprescriptions</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Gabapentin (Gaba)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients prescribed gabapentin with a total daily dose &gt;1800mg without exclusion criteria who have a primary care appointment with a provider in the Gaba cohort</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Diabetes (DM)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients prescribed either insulin or a sulfonylurea meeting inclusion/exclusion criteria who have a primary care appointment with a provider in the DM cohort</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Proton Pump Inhibitor (PPI)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients prescribed a PPI meeting inclusion/exclusion criteria who have a primary care appointment with a provider in the PPI cohort</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Direct to patient medication brochure</intervention_name>
    <description>An EMPOWER medication brochure, adapted to the VA, designed to educate and activate patients. These brochures provide detailed medication information, allow self-testing of indications for use, prompt reflection of experiences with potential side effects, discuss alternative therapies (medication and non-pharmacologic options), and provide a vignette of a patient who successfully stopped the medicine. They were designed for a 6th grade reading level and were based upon theories of patient activation, adult learning, and cognitive dissonance. The visually appealing brochure repeatedly emphasizes that patients should not make any medication changes without first consulting their health care providers.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Diabetes (DM)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Gabapentin (Gaba)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Proton Pump Inhibitor (PPI)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Veteran with a Primary Care appointment at one of three Veteran Affairs Medical&#xD;
             Centers (including Community Based Outpatient Clinics)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  PPI Cohort:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  &gt;90 consecutive days of PPI at any dose&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Diabetes Cohorts:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  HbA1c &lt;7%&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  At least one of Age &gt;65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Renal impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Cognitive impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  either &gt;90 consecutive days insulin or sulfonylurea or &gt;90 consecutive days&#xD;
                       of &gt;2 DM medications (neither of which is insulin or sulfonylurea)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Gaba Cohort:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  &gt;90 consecutive days with total daily dose &gt;1800mg&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PPI Cohort Exclusions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Diagnosis warranting PPI treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Medication warranting PPI treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gaba Cohort Exclusions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Neuropathic pain&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Seizure disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  and/or Cancer-related pain&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Amy M Linsky, MD MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>VA Boston Healthcare System Jamaica Plain Campus, Jamaica Plain, MA</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amy M Linsky, MD MSc</last_name>
    <phone>(857) 364-5467</phone>
    <email>amy.linsky@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>San Francisco VA Medical Center, San Francisco, CA</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94121</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mike Steinman, MD</last_name>
      <phone>415-221-4810</phone>
      <phone_ext>23677</phone_ext>
      <email>mike.steinman@ucsf.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA Boston Healthcare System Jamaica Plain Campus, Jamaica Plain, MA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02130</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Amy M Linsky, MD MSc</last_name>
      <phone>857-364-5467</phone>
      <email>amy.linsky@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Amy M Linsky, MD MSc</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA Central Western Massachusetts Healthcare System, Leeds, MA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leeds</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>01053-9764</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kristin Mattocks, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>413-584-4040</phone>
      <phone_ext>2060</phone_ext>
      <email>kristin.mattocks@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>James J. Peters VA Medical Center, Bronx, NY</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bronx</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10468</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kenneth Boockvar, MD</last_name>
      <phone>718-584-9000</phone>
      <phone_ext>3807</phone_ext>
      <email>kenneth.boockvar@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Physician-Patient Relations</keyword>
  <keyword>Implementation Science</keyword>
  <keyword>Decision Making, Shared</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Datasets meeting VA standards for disclosure to the public will be made available within 1 year of publication. Prior to distribution, a local privacy officer will certify that all datasets contains no PHI. Final data sets will be maintained locally until enterprise-level resources become available for long-term storage and access. Guidance on request and distribution processes will be provided by ORD. Those requesting data will be asked to sign a Letter of Agreement.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_time_frame>Within 1 year of publication</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Those requesting data will be asked to sign a Letter of Agreement.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

