<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04299009</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>E3304-P</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1I21RX003304-01A1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04299009</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Bright Light Therapy for Residual Daytime Symptoms Associated With Obstructive Sleep Apnea</brief_title>
  <official_title>Bright Light Therapy for Residual Daytime Symptoms Associated With Obstructive Sleep Apnea</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Sleep apnea is one of the most common chronic condition among US military Veterans, causing&#xD;
      sleepiness, reduced psychomotor vigilance and depression, which undermine daytime functioning&#xD;
      and quality of life. Persistent daytime symptoms of sleepiness in individuals with&#xD;
      Obstructive Sleep Apnea (OSA) who are using Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) are&#xD;
      associated with adverse long term medical and functional outcomes. Residual daytime&#xD;
      sleepiness (RDS) is associated with reduced occupational and family functioning and overall&#xD;
      lower quality of life. Napping is a common behavior among individuals with OSA and RDS and&#xD;
      has been linked to both benefits to and decline in health and functioning. Longer nap times&#xD;
      may maintain, as opposed to decrease, sleepiness by promoting sleep inertia and can&#xD;
      contribute to maintaining subclinical circadian alterations that result in higher&#xD;
      night-tonight variability in sleep patterns. Preliminary studies in humans and animal models&#xD;
      have shown persisting alterations of circadian rhythms in OSA patients, that fail to&#xD;
      normalize with CPAP treatment. CPAP treatment, while effective at correcting respiratory&#xD;
      events and night time blood oxygen saturation levels, does not necessarily re-align the&#xD;
      circadian system. Current treatment options are limited to stimulants and modafinil, whose&#xD;
      long-term safety profile, effectiveness and impact on functional recovery is largely unknown.&#xD;
      Supplementary exposure to bright light has beneficial effects on sleep quality and daytime&#xD;
      vigilance in healthy individuals and it has been increasingly applied in a variety of sleep&#xD;
      and neuropsychiatric conditions. However, no study to date has tested the application of BLT&#xD;
      to treat daytime symptoms associated with sleep apnea. The investigators' study will be the&#xD;
      first to explore the role of Bright Light Therapy (BLT), a well-established&#xD;
      non-pharmacological intervention for circadian disturbances, for the treatment of residual&#xD;
      daytime symptoms of OSA which do not respond to CPAP.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Due to Covid 19 pandemic emergency measures, recruitment for clinical trials is currently on&#xD;
      hold&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background: Sleep apnea is one of the most common chronic condition among US military&#xD;
      Veterans , it causes sleepiness, reduced psychomotor vigilance and depression, which&#xD;
      undermine daytime functioning and quality of life . Persistent daytime symptoms of sleepiness&#xD;
      and depression in individuals with OSA who are using Continuous Positive Airway Pressure&#xD;
      (CPAP) are associated with adverse long term medical and functional outcomes . Current&#xD;
      treatment options are limited to stimulants and modafinil, whose long-term safety profile,&#xD;
      effectiveness and impact on functional recovery is largely unknown. The mechanisms for&#xD;
      residual daytime symptoms in CPAP-treated sleep apnea are poorly understood and very little&#xD;
      attention has been placed on interplay between sleep apnea and the circadian system. Notably,&#xD;
      sleepiness, fatigue and depression, cardinal symptoms of OSA syndrome, are common&#xD;
      manifestations of circadian misalignment. Circadian rhythms are synchronized to the&#xD;
      environmental light or dark and to social activity cycles by zeitgebers (time givers)&#xD;
      .Preliminary studies in humans and animal models have shown persisting alterations of&#xD;
      circadian rhythms in OSA patients, that fail to normalize with CPAP treatment. CPAP&#xD;
      treatment, while effective at correcting respiratory events and night time blood oxygen&#xD;
      saturation levels, does not necessarily re-align the circadian system. Supplementary exposure&#xD;
      to bright light has beneficial effects on sleep quality and daytime vigilance in healthy&#xD;
      individuals and it has been increasingly applied in a variety of sleep and neuropsychiatric&#xD;
      conditions. However, no study to date has tested the application of BLT to treat daytime&#xD;
      symptoms associated with sleep apnea. The investigators' study will be the first to explore&#xD;
      the role of Bright Light Therapy (BLT), a well-established non-pharmacological intervention&#xD;
      for circadian disturbances, for the treatment of residual daytime symptoms of OSA which do&#xD;
      not respond to CPAP.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Epworth Sleepiness Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>change from baseline to week 12</time_frame>
    <description>Brief self report questionnaire used to quantify degree of daytime sleepiness. Minimum score is 0,maximum score is 24; values below 10 are considered normal</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Outcomes of Sleep Questionnaire (FOSQ-10)</measure>
    <time_frame>change from baseline to week 12</time_frame>
    <description>Assesses impact of sleep related disturbances on daily functioning. It is a likert scale whose scaling of items is from zero to four.The potential range of scores for the total score is 5-20, with higher scores indicating worse functioning</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">25</enrollment>
  <condition>Obstructive Sleep Apnea</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Retimer bright light therapy glasses</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>active bright light therapy in the green/blue spectrum range</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>sham-Retimer bright light therapy glasses</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>bright light therapy with light in the red spectrum (not active)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bright light therapy glasses</intervention_name>
    <description>Bright light therapy delivered through glasses</description>
    <arm_group_label>Retimer bright light therapy glasses</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>sham-Retimer bright light therapy glasses</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BLT</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Veterans from the VA Pittsburgh Healthcare System (VAPHS)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented diagnosis of OSA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently on CPAP or BiPAP with documented adherence (defined as wearing CPAP/BiPAP&#xD;
             for &gt;4h/night on at least 75% of nights)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Excessive residual daytime sleepiness (Epworth score &gt; 10)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Endorsing depressive symptoms (Quick Inventory of Depressive Symptomatology&#xD;
             (Self-Report) [QIDS-SR] score&gt;8)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Shift work&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Travel across time zones in the past month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Narcolepsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Congestive heart failure (CHF)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Poorly controlled diabetes (HgA1c&gt;7%)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active substance use disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dementia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bipolar disorder&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Isabella Soreca, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>VA Pittsburgh Healthcare System University Drive Division, Pittsburgh, PA</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Isabella Soreca, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(412) 688-6000</phone>
    <email>Isabella.Soreca@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA Pittsburgh Healthcare System University Drive Division, Pittsburgh, PA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15240</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Isabella Soreca, MD</last_name>
      <phone>412-688-6000</phone>
      <email>Isabella.Soreca@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Isabella Soreca, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 5, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 6, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>sleep apnea</keyword>
  <keyword>CPAP</keyword>
  <keyword>daytime sleepiness</keyword>
  <keyword>bright light therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

