<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01853267</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>JRCOMS0513</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01853267</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Perianal Abscess Packing Randomized ControlledTrial Pilot Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Controlled Trial Evaluating the Requirement for Post-operative Packing of Perianal Abscesses</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Imperial College London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Imperial College London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      TITLE Perianal Abscess Packing (PAP): a randomised controlled trial (Pilot study)&#xD;
&#xD;
      DESIGN Randomised controlled trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HYPOTHESIS In patients with perianal abscesses incision and drainage without packing the&#xD;
      subsequent cavity will reduce patient discomfort without increasing healing time or&#xD;
      recurrence compared with management involving cavity packing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTCOME MEASURES&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Length of hospital stay&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Time to cavity healing&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Recurrent abscess or fistula formation&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pain score&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Analgesia usage POPULATION All patients older than 18 years presenting with a perianal&#xD;
           abscess.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ELIGIBILITY Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  under 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  those unable to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  abscesses associated with Crohn's disease or other underlying causes&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  abscesses in which initial drainage is considered inadequate (if the skin is not open&#xD;
           sufficiently to allow drainage of the abscess cavity)&#xD;
&#xD;
      DURATION Until recruitment of subjects is complete&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. INTRODUCTION&#xD;
&#xD;
           1.1 BACKGROUND&#xD;
&#xD;
           Perianal abscesses are common with an incidence of 0.5-1%. Some present as emergencies&#xD;
           and all require surgery, placing a significant burden on health resources.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The mainstay of management is incision and drainage. Traditionally the residual cavity&#xD;
           is then packed. On discharge, the cavity packing requires frequent changing. This uses&#xD;
           considerable community nursing resource. Perianal abscesses can alternatively be treated&#xD;
           by primary closure or without packing the cavity. Benefits of treating without packing&#xD;
           include greater patient comfort and acceptance and reduced nursing requirement. However&#xD;
           treating without packing is not yet widely accepted, in the absence of sufficient&#xD;
           evidence that it is as safe and effective. This study aims to address this issue.&#xD;
&#xD;
           1.2 RATIONALE FOR CURRENT STUDY&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Question: In patients with perianal abscesses, does incision and drainage without&#xD;
                packing the subsequent cavity reduce patient discomfort without increasing healing&#xD;
                time or recurrence compared with management involving cavity packing?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Hypothesis: Perianal abscess can be managed without cavity packing, with no&#xD;
                increase in healing time or recurrence.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Note this was partly addressed by Tonkin et al (2004) but their study was&#xD;
                underpowered. We intend to have a sufficiently powered study to definitively answer&#xD;
                the question.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. STUDY OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
           - Assess whether there is any statistically significant difference in patients with&#xD;
           perianal abscesses managed with and without cavity packing in terms of:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Length of hospital stay&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Time to cavity healing&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Recurrent abscess or fistula formation&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Pain score&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Analgesia usage&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. STUDY DESIGN&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  This is a randomised controlled trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Due to the nature of the intervention (packing), it is impossible for either the&#xD;
                subjects or the research team to be blinded.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Duration: recruitment into the study will remain open until the target number of&#xD;
                subjects has been reached.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Number and type of subjects: power calculations from a published pilot study show&#xD;
                that to demonstrate a difference of 10% vs 20% in e.g. fistula and recurrent&#xD;
                abscess formation, 316 patients need to be recruited. We will perform a pilot study&#xD;
                of 20 patients in each group and at this time calculate the number of subjects to&#xD;
                be recruited&#xD;
&#xD;
           3.1 STUDY OUTCOME MEASURES&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Length of hospital stay&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Time to cavity healing&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Recurrent abscess or fistula formation&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Pain score&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Analgesia usage&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. PARTICIPANT ENTRY&#xD;
&#xD;
           4.1 PRE-REGISTRATION EVALUATIONS&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Documentation of the duration of symptoms before presentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Examination and documentation of abscess characteristics (can be done at the time&#xD;
                of the operation): size, site and type.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Comorbidities&#xD;
&#xD;
           4.2 INCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Perianal abscess.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Over 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
           4.3 EXCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Under 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Those unable to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Abscesses associated with Crohn's disease or other underlying causes.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Abscesses in which initial drainage is considered inadequate (if the skin is not&#xD;
                open sufficiently to allow drainage of the abscess cavity).&#xD;
&#xD;
           4.4 WITHDRAWAL CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  If the patient wants to withdraw from the study at any point they can do so and&#xD;
                resume standardized treatment pathways&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. ADVERSE EVENTS&#xD;
&#xD;
           5.1 DEFINITIONS Adverse Event (AE): any untoward medical occurrence in a patient or&#xD;
           clinical study subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Serious Adverse Event (SAE): any untoward and unexpected medical occurrence or effect&#xD;
           that:&#xD;
&#xD;
           • Results in death&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Is life-threatening - refers to an event in which the subject was at risk of death&#xD;
                at the time of the event; it does not refer to an event which hypothetically might&#xD;
                have caused death if it were more severe&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Requires hospitalization, or prolongation of existing inpatients' hospitalization&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Results in persistent or significant disability or incapacity&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Is a congenital anomaly or birth defect&#xD;
&#xD;
           Medical judgement should be exercised in deciding whether an AE is serious in other&#xD;
           situations. Important AEs that are not immediately life-threatening or do not result in&#xD;
           death or hospitalization but may jeopardize the subject or may require intervention to&#xD;
           prevent one of the other outcomes listed in the definition above, should also be&#xD;
           considered serious.&#xD;
&#xD;
           5.3 REPORTING PROCEDURES All adverse events should be reported. Depending on the nature&#xD;
           of the event the reporting procedures below should be followed. Any questions concerning&#xD;
           adverse event reporting should be directed to the Chief Investigator in the first&#xD;
           instance.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. ASSESSMENT AND FOLLOW-UP&#xD;
&#xD;
           - Patients in the packing group will have their dressing changed day 1 post-operatively.&#xD;
           On discharge they will have their care transferred to the District Nurses for daily&#xD;
           dressing care in their own home.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Patients in the non-packing group will have the initial haemostatic dressing&#xD;
                removed day 1 post-operatively and be discharged with a superficial protective&#xD;
                dressing to absorb any discharge and protect the wound.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  All patients will be reviewed at 2 weekly intervals in the outpatient clinic until&#xD;
                the cavity is closed and the skin completely re-epithelialized. At outpatient&#xD;
                appointments, patients will be asked to score their pain over the previous two&#xD;
                weeks on a standard 10cm Visual Analogue Scale for pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Patients who do not attend clinic will be interviewed by telephone to gather the&#xD;
                information listed above.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The end point is patient discharge from the outpatient clinic with complete healing&#xD;
                (as described above) or the development of a fistula or recurrent abscess.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. STATISTICS AND DATA ANALYSIS&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Data and all appropriate documentation will be stored for a minimum of 5 years&#xD;
                after the completion of the study, including the follow-up period.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The data will be tested for normal distribution and analyzed accordingly:&#xD;
&#xD;
                o If it is normally distributed, an unpaired T-test will be performed on the&#xD;
                continuous data (time to healing, length of stay, pain score, morphine dose) and a&#xD;
                Fischer test will be performed on the categorical data (fistula rates, recurrence,&#xD;
                delayed healing).&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  If it is not normally distributed, a Mann-Whitney U test will be performed in&#xD;
                     place of the T-test.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  The tests will be two-tailed with a significance level of 0.05.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Following a pilot study of 40 patients we will perform a power calculation however&#xD;
                a similar pilot study already published indicates the need for 316 subjects to be&#xD;
                recruited&#xD;
&#xD;
      8.1 CONSENT Consent to enter the study must be sought from each participant only after a full&#xD;
      explanation has been given, an information leaflet offered and time allowed for&#xD;
      consideration. Signed participant consent should be obtained. The right of the participant to&#xD;
      refuse to participate without giving reasons must be respected. After the participant has&#xD;
      entered the study the clinician remains free to give alternative treatment to that specified&#xD;
      in the protocol at any stage if he/she feels it is in the participant's best interest, but&#xD;
      the reasons for doing so should be recorded. In these cases the participants remain within&#xD;
      the study for the purposes of follow-up and data analysis. All participants are free to&#xD;
      withdraw at any time from the protocol treatment without giving reasons and without&#xD;
      prejudicing further treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      8.2 CONFIDENTIALITY The Chief Investigator will preserve the confidentiality of participants&#xD;
      taking part in the study and is registered under the Data Protection Act.&#xD;
&#xD;
      8.3 AUDITS The study may be subject to inspection and audit by Imperial College London under&#xD;
      their remit as sponsor and other regulatory bodies to ensure adherence to GCP and the NHS&#xD;
      Research Governance Framework for Health and Social Care (2nd edition).&#xD;
&#xD;
      9. STUDY MANAGEMENT&#xD;
&#xD;
      The day-to-day management of the study will be coordinated through Mr Mikael Sodergren.&#xD;
&#xD;
      10. PUBLICATION POLICY&#xD;
&#xD;
      All publications and presentations relating to the study will be authorized by the Trial&#xD;
      Management Group (TMG). The first publication of the trial results will be in the name of the&#xD;
      Trial Management Group, or appropriately names authors. If there are named authors, these&#xD;
      will include at least the trial's Chief Investigator, and Trial Coordinator. Members of the&#xD;
      TMG will be listed and contributors will be cited by name if published in a Joint Research&#xD;
      Office journal where this does not conflict with the journal's policy. Authorship of parallel&#xD;
      studies initiated outside of the Trial Management Group will be according to the individuals&#xD;
      involved in the project but must acknowledge the contribution of the Trial Management Group&#xD;
      and the Study Coordination Centre.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to abscess healing</measure>
    <time_frame>Two weeks post operative</time_frame>
    <description>When abscess cavity has re-epitheliased. Assessed at two weeks and then weekly until healing occurs. Followed up for one year to assess recurrence</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">14</enrollment>
  <condition>Perianal Abscess</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group (Packing)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The perianal abscess cavity will continue to be packed after discharge until healing is complete</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Group (Non-Packing)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The cavity will be allowed to heal by secondary intention without packing.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intervention Group (Non-Packing)</intervention_name>
    <description>The haemostatic pack placed in the perianal abscess cavity will be removed on discharge and the wound will be left to heal without packing in situ</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Group (Non-Packing)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control group (Packing)</intervention_name>
    <description>After the procedure the abscess cavity will be packed with a non-adherent dressing as per standard treatment and the packing changed at regular intervals in the community until healing by secondary intention is complete.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group (Packing)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults aged 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical diagnosis of perianal abscess.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are unable or unwilling to consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known fistulae&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Crohn's Disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immune-suppression or malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recurrent abscess (where initial drainage insufficient).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Paraskevas Paraskevas, MBBS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Surgery and Cancer, Imperial College London</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St Mary's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paddington</city>
        <state>London</state>
        <zip>W2 1NY</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 10, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 10, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 14, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 20, 2014</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 20, 2014</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 21, 2014</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Colorectal</keyword>
  <keyword>Surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Perianal</keyword>
  <keyword>Abscess</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Abscess</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

