<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04678115</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2019P003055</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01EY029437</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04678115</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Trial Comparing Two Non-Surgical Treatments for Severe Blepharoptosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Cross-Over Clinical Trial Comparing Two Non-Surgical Treatments for Severe Blepharoptosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Massachusetts Eye and Ear Infirmary</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Eye Institute (NEI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Massachusetts Eye and Ear Infirmary</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This clinical trial will evaluate two non-surgical devices designed to improve eye lid&#xD;
      opening for patients with severe Blepharoptosis (incomplete opening of the eyelids).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Two non-surgical devices for patients with Blepharoptosis will be evaluated. The Magnetic&#xD;
      Levator Prosthesis (MLP), is an external device that makes use of a newer class of permanent&#xD;
      magnets (made of alloys of neodymium (Nd), iron (Fe) and boron (B)) to restore eyelid&#xD;
      movement. The Kinesiotape Frontalis Sling (KTFS), involves the use of tape to help facilitate&#xD;
      levator muscle contraction to open the eyelid. Video recordings of spontaneous and volitional&#xD;
      blinks will be used to evaluate the effects of each device on eyelid reanimation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The clinical trial will employ a crossover design in which participants will try each device&#xD;
      at home in counterbalanced order with a washout period between. In each period of the&#xD;
      crossover, participants will receive training (during study visits at Massachusetts Eye and&#xD;
      Ear) in how to apply the device and will then try the device at home for one week with daily&#xD;
      follow up by video calls. At the end of the one-week period of home use there will be a study&#xD;
      visit at Massachusetts Eye and Ear when the device will be returned and additional video&#xD;
      recordings of eye blinks will be made.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the crossover period, participants will be asked to complete a questionnaire&#xD;
      comparing the two devices and to select their preferred device. If considered clinically&#xD;
      appropriate, participants may be invited to continue using the preferred device for an&#xD;
      additional two months with weekly follow ups to provide information about longer-term use of&#xD;
      the intervention. Participants who are still using one of the devices at the end of the two&#xD;
      months will be returned to clinical care and receive a study follow up (telephone call) after&#xD;
      another 6 and 12 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 18, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference between MLP and KTFS in the change in interpalpebral fissure during opening and spontaneous blinking</measure>
    <time_frame>Evaluated at baseline and then after being fitted with each device (immediately after, 20 minutes after and 1 week after)</time_frame>
    <description>Measurements of the interpalpebral fissure will be taken from video recordings of eye lid opening and closing when using each of the devices</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference between MLP and KTFS in the changes in interpalpebral fissure during volitional blinking</measure>
    <time_frame>Evaluated at baseline and then after being fitted with each device (immediately after, 20 minutes after and 1 week after)</time_frame>
    <description>Measurements of the interpalpebral fissure will be taken from video recordings of volitional eye lid closing when using each of the devices</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects selecting each device</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of the one-week period of home use of the second device</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of subjects selecting either the MLP, the KTFS or neither</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Blepharoptosis</condition>
  <condition>Ptosis, Eyelid</condition>
  <condition>Myasthenia Gravis</condition>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <condition>Traumatic Brain Injury</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Progressive External Ophthalmoplegia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MLP first, KTFS second</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will receive the MLP in the first period of the crossover and the KTFS in the second period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>KTFS first, MLP second</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will receive the KTFS in the first period of the crossover and the MLP in the second period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Magnetic Levator Prosthesis (MLP)</intervention_name>
    <description>Neodymium magnet embedded in a glasses frame and a polymer embedded (PDMS) micro-magnet array fitted externally to the upper lid with IV 3000 securement film. The IV 3000 is FDA approved for extended wear on the skin.</description>
    <arm_group_label>KTFS first, MLP second</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>MLP first, KTFS second</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Kinesiotape Frontalis Sling (KTFS)</intervention_name>
    <description>Kineso Tape is FDA registered as a 510K exempt class 1 device, typically used by physical and occupational therapist to support muscular healing and movement. It is sometimes used on the face in cases of facial palsy or on the eye lid to support the lid in cases of severe blepharoptosis. In such cases it may be attached near the lid margin above the lashes extending up to the forehead skin overlying the frontalis muscle. Alternatively it may be a very short piece attached only along the lid skin. The tape is easily removed.</description>
    <arm_group_label>KTFS first, MLP second</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>MLP first, KTFS second</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of ptosis for at least one eye which occludes the visual axis in the resting&#xD;
             position (without frontalis drive, lifting with forehead muscles)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate cognitive function or better defined as greater than or equal to 18 out of 30&#xD;
             on a pre-screening of the Mini-Mental State Exam (MMSE)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of ptosis which occludes the visual axis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of a corneal ulcer of any size&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age less than 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe Cognitive impairment defined as MMSE score less than 18, behaviors consistent&#xD;
             with delirium (combinations of disorientation, hallucinations, delusions, and&#xD;
             incoherent speech), or lethargy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of corneal hypoaesthesia;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Orbicularis weakness on the side of the ptosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mechanical ptosis, including ptosis due to orbital or lid tumor, cicatricial processes&#xD;
             affecting the movements of the upper lid, and enophthalmos.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous ptosis surgery less than 3 months prior to Visit 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lid position affected by lid or conjunctival scarring.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of herpes keratitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Periocular neurotoxin (eg, Botox, Xeomin, Dysport, Myobloc) injections on the side of&#xD;
             the ptosis within 3 months prior to Visit 1 and during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hyperthyroidism or thyroid eye disease (ie, exophthalmos, upper eyelid&#xD;
             retraction, diplopia secondary to extraocular muscle involvement). Hypothyroidism that&#xD;
             is controlled on medication is allowed&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kevin Houston, OD MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Massachusetts Eye and Ear</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kevin Houston, OD MSc</last_name>
    <phone>617-573-4177</phone>
    <email>Kevin_Houston@meei.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sheryl Erwin, BS</last_name>
    <phone>617-573-6533</phone>
    <email>sheryl_erwin@meei.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts Eye and Ear</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kevin Houston, OD MSc</last_name>
      <phone>617-573-4177</phone>
      <email>kevin_houston@meei.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Sheryl Erwin, BS</last_name>
      <phone>617-573-6533</phone>
      <email>sheryl_erwin@meei.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 21, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts Eye and Ear Infirmary</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kevin Houston</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Myasthenia Gravis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ophthalmoplegia, Chronic Progressive External</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Injuries, Traumatic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ophthalmoplegia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Blepharoptosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

