<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04670419</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>18/03/024</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04670419</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Morbidity and Mortality of Hepatitis E Virus Infections in Belgium</brief_title>
  <official_title>Morbidity and Mortality of Hepatitis E Virus Infections in Belgium 2010-2018</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Antwerp</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sciensano</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>KU Leuven</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Antwerp</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Hepatitis E Virus (HEV) infections are emerging in the Western world with a predominance of&#xD;
      HEV genotype (gt) 3. Except for age older than 50 years, male gender, chronic liver disease&#xD;
      and immunosuppressed status, no correlators with clinical outcomes have been identified so&#xD;
      far. With this study, we want to examine viral factors associated with the morbidity and&#xD;
      mortality of HEV infections in Belgium as well as find correlators with clinical outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Study objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
           1.1. Primary objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
           To examine viral factors, such as gt, subtype and viral load, associated with the&#xD;
           morbidity and mortality of HEV infections in Belgium.&#xD;
&#xD;
           1.2. Secondary objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  To describe host factors associated with the morbidity and mortality of HEV&#xD;
                infections in Belgium.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  To find independent host and/or viral factors that are associated with the&#xD;
                morbidity and mortality of HEV infections in Belgium.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Investigational plan&#xD;
&#xD;
           2.1. General study design&#xD;
&#xD;
           Retrospective cohort study.&#xD;
&#xD;
           2.2. Study duration, enrollment and number of sites&#xD;
&#xD;
           Subjects for which a serum sample is sent to the Belgian National Reference Center for&#xD;
           Viral Hepatitis Sciensano to diagnose a HEV infection between January 2010 and June&#xD;
           2018.&#xD;
&#xD;
           2.3. Study population&#xD;
&#xD;
           All patients with a confirmed or possible HEV infection at Sciensano between January&#xD;
           2010 up to and included June 2018.&#xD;
&#xD;
           2.3.1. Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  HEV RNA positive AND/OR HEV immunoglobulin (Ig)M positive&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Lab confirmation of the HEV infection performed at Sciensano&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  All ages will be included&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Referring hospital in Belgium&#xD;
&#xD;
           2.3.2. Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  No confirmation of HEV serology AND/OR polymerase chain reaction (PCR) performed at&#xD;
                Sciensano&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Cases not diagnosed in Belgium&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Cases without clinical outcome data&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
           Review of records. Re-evaluation of available liver biopsies by an expert liver&#xD;
           pathologist (Prof. Tania Roskams, UZ Leuven).&#xD;
&#xD;
           3.1. Data sources&#xD;
&#xD;
           In Belgium, Sciensano acts as a National Reference Center (NRC) for viral hepatitis.&#xD;
           Most of the documented HEV infections in Belgium are confirmed in Sciensano and samples&#xD;
           on which HEV serology (IgM and IgG), PCR and genotyping have been performed are&#xD;
           biobanked.&#xD;
&#xD;
           3.2. Data collection&#xD;
&#xD;
           A questionnaire will be sent to all treating physicians of patients with HEV infections&#xD;
           in Belgium. If no response is received, a reminder will be sent by regular mail and&#xD;
           later by e-mail. Different options will be offered to the treating physicians: to fill&#xD;
           in the questionnaire, to complete the questionnaire by telephone with an investigator&#xD;
           from Sciensano, to let the data to be collected at the center site by an investigator of&#xD;
           Sciensano. Available liver biopsies from confirmed HEV cases will be retrieved from the&#xD;
           pathology department of each center and re-evaluated by an expert liver pathologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
           3.3. Variables collected&#xD;
&#xD;
           Demographic data:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Age and geographical origin. Date of symptom onset, date of diagnosis, date of loss to&#xD;
           follow-up / death. Pregnancy at the time of diagnosis. Diabetes mellitus at the time of&#xD;
           diagnosis. Immunocompromised status at the time of diagnosis. Known cirrhosis (fibroscan&#xD;
           / biopsy / …), hematological or oncological disease. Other comorbidities. Blood&#xD;
           transfusion history. Solid organ or stem cell transplantation preceding the HEV&#xD;
           infection, type of organ and date. Renal function or renal replacement therapy.&#xD;
           Infection in other family members. Use of alcohol and number of units per week. Use of&#xD;
           illicit drugs. Travel abroad preceding the HEV infection and name of the country&#xD;
           visited. Consumption of pork meat.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Treatment data:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Treatment with ribavirin. Treatment with other known/putative antiviral therapy.&#xD;
           Reduction of immunosuppressive medication because of the HEV infection. Stop of&#xD;
           immunosuppressive therapy because of HEV infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Disease course and outcomes data:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Acute hepatitis with complete recovery. Liver failure. Hospitalisation. Duration of&#xD;
           hospitalisation in days. Admission to the intensive care unit. Duration of&#xD;
           hospitalisation at the intensive care unit in days. Variceal bleeding. Bacterial&#xD;
           peritonitis. Hepatic encephalopathy. Extrahepatic manifestations and type. Neurologic&#xD;
           disease and type. Chronic HEV infection (as defined by HEV RNA positive for 3 months or&#xD;
           more). Progression to cirrhosis as a consequence of HEV infection. Liver transplantation&#xD;
           as a consequence of HEV infection and date of transplantation. Death and date of death.&#xD;
           Death as a consequence of HEV infection. Total duration of symptoms in weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Biochemical data:&#xD;
&#xD;
           HEV IgM, HEV IgG, HEV (quantitative) PCR, HEV genotype and subtype. HEV genotyping was&#xD;
           performed by Sanger sequencing of a 348 base pair (between 2010 and 2016) or a 493 base&#xD;
           pair (from 2017) region of ORF2. The obtained sequences were aligned against HEV&#xD;
           reference genomes and submitted to HEVnet for genotype assignment (13). Presenting ALT,&#xD;
           peak ALT, presenting AP, peak AP, presenting bilirubin, peak bilirubin, presenting INR,&#xD;
           peak INR, presenting albumin, lowest albumin, presenting eGFR (CKD-EPI), lowest eGFR&#xD;
           (CKD-EPI).&#xD;
&#xD;
           Liver biopsy scoring:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Histological grading and staging on H&amp;E stained liver biopsy slides will be applied in a&#xD;
           blinded manner. One expert liver pathologist, who is unaware of the infection status of&#xD;
           the patient, will score the liver biopsies. The following parameters will be scored from&#xD;
           0-4 in a semi-quantitative manner: general architecture, lobular and portal&#xD;
           inflammation, presence of immune cells and necrotic cells, presence of interfaces. Per&#xD;
           patient, a global score will be assigned taken into account the spread, mean and mode of&#xD;
           the different scored parameters.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Statistical analysis plan&#xD;
&#xD;
      The characteristics of patients will be analysed with the chi-square test for categorical&#xD;
      variables and student t-test (Welch test if unequal variances or Wilcoxon Rank sum test when&#xD;
      normality is not met) for the continuous variables. Numerical data are presented as the mean&#xD;
      and standard deviation or 95% confidence interval, while categorical are expressed as counts&#xD;
      and percentages.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following independent viral variables are defined: HEV gt 3 clade type (abchijklm, efg&#xD;
      and ra), viral load.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following independent host variables are defined, given their known association with&#xD;
      disease outcome or severity: alcohol consumption, diabetes, gender, age, cirrhosis and&#xD;
      immunosuppression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Differences between demographic factors, disease severity (expressed by laboratory data and&#xD;
      histology) and disease outcomes (as defined by hospitalization status and duration, ICU stay,&#xD;
      chronic infection, extrahepatic manifestations and death) will be analysed for the&#xD;
      independent viral variables with an univariate analysis. Multivariable linear or logistic&#xD;
      regression analysis will be performed with dependent variables that were found to be&#xD;
      significantly associated with the independent variables in univariate analysis. Given the&#xD;
      retrospective nature of the analysis, an upfront power calculation for the number of included&#xD;
      patients for the investigated outcome is not possible. Statistical analyses are performed at&#xD;
      a significance level of 5% using the statistical software R or SAS.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>HEV viral factors associated with morbidity and mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>observation period 2010-2018</time_frame>
    <description>Viral factors, such as genotype, subtype and viral load, associated with the morbidity and mortality of HEV infections in Belgium</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Host factors associated with the morbidity and mortality of HEV infections in Belgium.</measure>
    <time_frame>observation period 2010-2018</time_frame>
    <description>Host factors, such as demographics and comorbidities</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>independent host and/or viral factors associated with the morbidity and mortality of HEV infections in Belgium</measure>
    <time_frame>observation period 2010-2018</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">280</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis E</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HEV gt 3 clade abchijklm</arm_group_label>
    <description>patients infected with HEV gt 3 clade abchijklm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HEV gt 3 clade efg</arm_group_label>
    <description>patients infected with HEV gt 3 clade efg</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Viral clade</intervention_name>
    <description>Disease outcomes are compared for patients infected with 2 different clades of a HEV gt 3 infection</description>
    <arm_group_label>HEV gt 3 clade abchijklm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>HEV gt 3 clade efg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Serum samples samples on which HEV serology (IgM and IgG), PCR and genotyping have been&#xD;
      performed FFPE liver biopsy tissue blocks&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients with a confirmed or possible HEV infection at Sciensano between January 2010&#xD;
        up to and included June 2018.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HEV RNA positive AND/OR HEV immunoglobulin (Ig)M positive&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lab confirmation of the HEV infection performed at Sciensano&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All ages will be included&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Referring hospital in Belgium&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No confirmation of HEV serology AND/OR polymerase chain reaction (PCR) performed at&#xD;
             Sciensano&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases not diagnosed in Belgium&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases without clinical outcome data&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas Vanwolleghem, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Antwerp</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 9, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 9, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University Hospital, Antwerp</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Thomas Vanwolleghem</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prof. Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Virus Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis E</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

