<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04674384</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>B01030</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04674384</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Manchester Intermittent and Daily Diet Type 1 Diabetes App Study (MIDDAS-Type 1)</brief_title>
  <acronym>MIDDAS T1</acronym>
  <official_title>A Randomised Feasibility Trial of an Intermittent Low Energy Diet (ILED) and Continuous Low Energy Diet (CLED) in Patients With Type 1 Diabetes and Obesity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To assess the safety, acceptability and feasibility of testing Intermittent Low Energy Diet&#xD;
      (ILED) and Continuous Low Energy Diet (CLED) programmes for 12 weeks in a real life setting&#xD;
      with people with T1D and obesity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study described herein is a small randomised, open-label, single centre feasibility study&#xD;
      of 12 patients with T1D and obesity. The aim of the study is to assess the safety,&#xD;
      acceptability and feasibility of ILED (850kcal/day 2 days/week) and CLED (850kcal/day) over&#xD;
      12 weeks in a real life setting with people with T1D and obesity to help them lose weight and&#xD;
      improve their glycaemic control. The low energy diets will involve Nestle Optifast® meal&#xD;
      replacements as a total diet replacement (TDR).&#xD;
&#xD;
      People with T1D are becoming increasingly accustomed to remote monitoring of their blood&#xD;
      glucose by health professionals using several continuous glucose monitoring devices including&#xD;
      the Freestyle Libre® flash glucose monitoring system. The Freestyle Libre® allows healthcare&#xD;
      professionals to view patient blood glucose trends and patterns from the web-based platform&#xD;
      Libreview®. The study described herein will also assess the safety and practicality of&#xD;
      providing remote follow-up support by healthcare professionals (dietitian, nurse and&#xD;
      psychologist) to patients with T1D and obesity during the course of implementing the low&#xD;
      energy diets. High-frequency remote follow up has been shown to be superior to low-frequency&#xD;
      face-to-face care in weight management interventions. Remote care reduces participants'&#xD;
      burden to attend face-to-face appointments and may be cost-effective compared with&#xD;
      face-to-face care whilst improving access to care. The study described herein will&#xD;
      incorporate high-frequency remote follow up via telephone and/or the Oviva® smartphone&#xD;
      application facilitating messaging, video calls and self-monitoring of weight and blood&#xD;
      pressure. The Freestyle Libre® flash glucose monitoring system will facilitate remote review&#xD;
      of blood glucose readings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Positive results from this feasibility study of two different low energy diets will inform&#xD;
      whether one or both diets go forward into a large and longer term randomised efficacy trial&#xD;
      following the Medical Research Council complex intervention guidance. This could provide the&#xD;
      evidence base to inform the use of low energy diets in individuals with T1D and obesity for&#xD;
      weight loss to improve their metabolic status and reduce the risk of cardiovascular and other&#xD;
      physical and mental co morbidities associated with T1D.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 15, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of episodes of severe hypoglycaemia i.e. capillary blood glucose &lt; 3.0 mmol/l or requiring 3rd party assistance or any episodes of nocturnal hypoglycaemia &lt;3.0 mmol/l.</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent in target (3.9-10mmol/l), below target (&lt;3.9mmol/l and &lt;3.0mmol/l) and above target (&gt;10 mmol/l) on the Freestyle Libre® flash glucose monitoring system over 12 weeks.</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of episodes of Diabetic Ketoacidosis (DKA) and blood ketone β-hydroxybutyrate levels above 1.0mmol/l.</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of Serious Adverse Events (SAEs) deemed potentially related to the dietary programmes.</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Uptake to the trial i.e. percentage of those invited who are eligible and interested to take part</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants who complete the trial measured by attendance at the 12 week appointment (for ILED and CLED)</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adherence to blood glucose and ketone monitoring i.e. frequency of capillary blood tests and scans</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of low energy days completed (for ILED and CLED)</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dietary intake (7 day food diary). Food diaries will be analysed using Nutritics nutrition analysis software to estimate energy, fat, saturated fat, carbohydrate and protein intake</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anonymous patient evaluation of the dietary programmes using an end of study questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
    <description>The End of Study Questionnaire will be analysed using appropriate descriptive statistics for closed questions (scales 1 to 10 with 1 indicating &quot;not at all&quot; and 10 indicating &quot;extremely&quot; in the context of questions around satisfaction, ease of completion etc.). Key themes will be extracted without formal analysis from open questions to inform future research.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of multi-disciplinary team contacts with participants achieved (for ILED and CLED)</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Uptake to and continued use of the Oviva® app i.e. percentage of participants willing to try the app and those who continue to use the different app functions over the 12 week period.</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of other adverse effects potentially associated with the dietary programmes e.g. constipation, fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants preferring food-based low energy days (for ILED and CLED)</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average time spent by the MDT (for ILED and CLED)</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of contacts with Dietitian conducted face to face after baseline (for ILED and CLED)</measure>
    <time_frame>14 week duration of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 1 Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intermittent Low Energy Diet (ILED)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Low Energy Diet (CLED)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Optifast meal replacement shakes</intervention_name>
    <description>Optifast® is provided as 53g sachet. Each sachet replaces one meal. It is available in 5 flavours: vanilla, strawberry, chocolate and coffee shakes and vegetable soup.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Low Energy Diet (CLED)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Intermittent Low Energy Diet (ILED)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  T1D for 12 months or longer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HbA1c 53-108 mmol/mol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI ≥ 30 kg/m2 and &lt;50kg/ m2 or ≥27.5 kg/ m2 and &lt;50kg/ m2 in high-risk minority&#xD;
             ethnic groups i.e. South Asian, Black African and African Caribbean&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Multiple daily injections (MDI) or continuous subcutaneous insulin infusion (CSII)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Completed Dose Adjustment For Normal Eating (DAFNE) education&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to a Freestyle Libre handset and sensors to monitor blood glucose&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to use the Freestyle Libre® flash glucose monitoring system to monitor blood&#xD;
             glucose (flash and capillary) and blood ketones and to record carbohydrate and&#xD;
             insulin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to and ability to use a telephone. If no access to a smartphone running iOS or&#xD;
             Android (to view the LibreLink app®) then access to a computer (to upload results to&#xD;
             the LibreView website).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to undertake Optifast® LEDs and have previously sampled Optifast®.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative urine pregnancy test at screening and agreement to maintain contraception or&#xD;
             abstinence for the trial (where appropriate)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to read, understand and communicate in English.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of severe hypoglycaemia in the last 12 months (more than one episode&#xD;
             requiring third party assistance) or hypoglycaemia unawareness.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with non-stable retinopathy, or grade R2 or later, or had no retinopathy&#xD;
             screen within 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who lack capacity or are unable to read or understand written or verbal&#xD;
             instructions in English or those diagnosed with learning difficulties.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed pregnant via a pregnancy test at screening, planning pregnancy in the next 3&#xD;
             months, or currently breast feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who are currently on treatment with Orlistat or other pharmacological&#xD;
             treatments for weight loss e.g. Glucagon-like-peptide-1 (GLP-1).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who are currently taking a Sodium-Glucose Co-Transporter-2 (SGLT2)&#xD;
             inhibitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed Gastroparesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have previously had bariatric surgery for weight loss including&#xD;
             gastric bypass and sleeve gastrectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are on chronic use of steroids (more than 20mg daily of prednisolone or&#xD;
             its equivalent).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known hypersensitivity to any of the ingredients of Optifast® e.g. fish,&#xD;
             milk, soy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking prohibited medications (see Appendix 3) including warfarin or novel&#xD;
             anticoagulants (NOAC), low molecular weight heparin (LMWH) or equivalent&#xD;
             anti-coagulants and anti-psychotic medication or other psychotropic medications that&#xD;
             may cause excessive weight gain.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Substance abuse or harmful alcohol use as indicated by a score of 16 or above on the&#xD;
             Alcohol Use Disorders Identification Test (AUDIT).[36]&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with a diagnosed eating disorder, or patients with severe binge eating&#xD;
             assessed by a score of 27 or more on the Binge Eating Scale (BES).[37]&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with severe depression assessed by a score of 15 or more on the Patient&#xD;
             Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9) questionnaire.[29]&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with severe anxiety assessed by a score of 15 or more on the General&#xD;
             Anxiety Disorder (GAD-7) questionnaire.[28]&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with very low self-efficacy assessed by a score of 35 or less on the&#xD;
             Weight Efficacy Lifestyle Questionnaire (WEL-SF).[30]&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with severe loss of renal function (eGFR &lt; 30mL/min/1.73m2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with psychiatric or physical comorbidity or scheduled for major surgery,&#xD;
             which in the opinion of the treating medical physician, Chief Investigator (CI) or&#xD;
             Multidisciplinary Team (MDT) would compromise their safety or adherence to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unsatisfactory use of the Freestyle Libre® flash glucose monitoring system or unsafe&#xD;
             use of DAFNE/insulin adjustment principles during the 14-day &quot;run-in&quot; period that in&#xD;
             the opinion of the medical team may undermine the participant's safety on the trial.&#xD;
             This includes flash and capillary monitoring of blood glucose and ketone testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are currently participating in a diabetes drug trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Manchester</city>
        <state>Greater Manchester</state>
        <zip>M23 9QZ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Cathy Spence</last_name>
      <email>cathy.spence@mft.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Basil Issa</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 17, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

