<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04675697</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2019010023</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04675697</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Anlotinib Plus Platinum-etoposide in First-line of Extensive-stage Small-cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Anlotinib Plus Platinum-etoposide in First-line Treatment of Extensive-stage Small-cell Lung Cancer: a Single-arm Phase II Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Xiangya Hospital of Central South University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Chia Tai Tianqing Pharmaceutical Group Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Xiangya Hospital of Central South University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Anlotinib is a novel multi-target tyrosine kinase inhibitor (TKI) for tumor angiogenesis and&#xD;
      tumor cell proliferation. The efficacy of Anlotinib as a third-line or beyond therapy for&#xD;
      SCLC was confirmed in the ALTER1202 trial. The aim of this trial was to investigate the&#xD;
      prognostic value of Anlotinib plus platinum-etoposide in first-line treatment of&#xD;
      extensive-stage SCLC patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This single-arm phase II trial enrolled extensive-stage SCLC patients without prior&#xD;
      systematic chemotherapy or immunity checkpoint inhibitors therapy at Xiangya hospital,&#xD;
      Central South University from Aug 15, 2018 to Oct 7, 2020.The study was done in accordance&#xD;
      with the International Conference on Harmonisation good clinical practice guidelines, the&#xD;
      Declaration of Helsinki, and applicable local regulations with approval from an independent&#xD;
      ethics committee or institutional review boards.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible patients were age 18-70 years with histologically confirmed extensive-stage&#xD;
      small-cell lung cancer as defined according to the staging standard introduced by the&#xD;
      Veterans Administration Lung Study Group (VALG), measurable according to Response Evaluation&#xD;
      Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST v1.1), and an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG)&#xD;
      performance-status (PS) score of 0 or 1, who had not received previous systemic treatment for&#xD;
      extensive-stage small-cell lung cancer and were expected survival time ≥3 months. Patients&#xD;
      with treated asymptomatic central nervous system (CNS) metastases were eligible under some&#xD;
      circumstance (see the Supplementary Appendix). Key exclusion criteria were a history of mixed&#xD;
      small cell carcinoma and non-small cell carcinoma and with active central nervous system&#xD;
      (CNS) metastasis and/or cancerous meningitis during screenings.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 24, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PFS</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>progression-free survival</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ORR</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>objective response rate (ORR, CR+PR)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>OS</measure>
    <time_frame>From randomization until death (up to 15 months)</time_frame>
    <description>overall survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>DCR</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of every 2 cycles (each cycle is 21 days)，through treatment，up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>disease control rate (DCR, CR+PR+SD)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>DoR</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of every 2 cycles (each cycle is 21 days)，through treatment，up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>duration of remission</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Extensive-stage Small-cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Anlotinib+EP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Platinum-etoposide+Anlotinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Platinum-etoposide regiment consisted of etoposide 100mg/m2, d1~3 of 21-day cycle, with investigators' choice of either cisplatin (75-80mg/m2, Q3W) or carboplatin (AUC=5~6, Q3W). Anlotinib treated of 12mg Qd from day 1 to 14 of a 21-day cycle. Eligible patients received anlotinib plus platinum-etoposide for 4~6 cycles, and followed by maintenance therapy with Anlotinib. The efficacy was evaluated every 6 weeks (2 cycles) through treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Anlotinib+EP</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1.Aged 18 to 70 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Rated as grade 0 to 2 in ECOG whole-body status (PS), or grade 3 to 4 if induced by&#xD;
             SCLC;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Of the expected survival no less than 3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With extensive-stage SLCL diagnosed pathologically (according to the VALG staging&#xD;
             standard introduced by the Veterans Administration Lung Study Group), and having a&#xD;
             measurable lesion (a tumor lesion of ≥ 10mm in long diameter in CT scanning, or a&#xD;
             lymph node lesion of ≥ 15mm in short diameter in CT scanning, which had not received&#xD;
             radiotherapy, cryotherapy or other local therapies, according to the RECIST1.1&#xD;
             standard);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having not received chemotherapy or immunotherapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Some patients who have received radiotherapy can be included as long as the&#xD;
             radiotherapy area in them is smaller than 25% of the bone marrow area, they haven't&#xD;
             undergone total pelvic or chest radiation, their previous radiotherapy ended at least&#xD;
             4 weeks before the inclusion, they have recovered from radiotherapy-induced acute&#xD;
             toxicity reaction, and the local lesion that underwent radiotherapy in them is not&#xD;
             included in the measurable lesion, unless significant progress was observed in the&#xD;
             lesion after the last radiotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients included should also have normal major organ functions, that is, their organs&#xD;
             should meet the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Blood routine examination criteria: ANC ≥ 1.5 × 109/L, PLT ≥ 100 × 109/L and&#xD;
                  Hb≥100g/L (no blood transfusion or blood products in 14 days, and no G-CSF or&#xD;
                  other hematopoietic stimulant corrections).&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Biochemical examination criteria: TBIL &lt; 1.5 × ULN, ALT, AST and ALP &lt; 2.5 × ULN,&#xD;
                  BUN and Cr ≤ 1 × ULN, or endogenous creatinine clearance rate ≥ 50ml/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of childbearing age should have taken reliable contraceptives or have had a&#xD;
             negative pregnancy test (serum or urine) result 7 days before inclusion, and should be&#xD;
             willing to take appropriate contraception measures during the study and in 8 weeks&#xD;
             after the last administration of the treatment drug. Males should agree to take&#xD;
             appropriate contraception measures during the study and in 8 weeks after the last&#xD;
             administration of the treatment drug or have undergone sterilization operation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects should voluntarily participate in the study, sign the Informed Consent, and&#xD;
             be well compliant and cooperative in follow-up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having mixed small cell carcinoma and non-small cell carcinoma;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having active central nervous system (CNS) metastases and/or cancerous meningitis or&#xD;
             found to have active central nervous system (CNS) metastases and/or cancerous&#xD;
             meningitis in examinations during the screening stage. Patients can be included in the&#xD;
             study as long as they: (1) Have asymptomatic brain metastases (without progressive&#xD;
             central nervous system symptoms induced by brain metastases, requiring no&#xD;
             corticosteroids, and having the lesion size ≤ 1.5cm), provided that they should&#xD;
             undergo regular brain imaging examinations for the diseased site; (2) Have been&#xD;
             treated and are in stable status, have no imaging evidence for new or enlarged brain&#xD;
             metastases at least 2 weeks after brain metastasis treatment, and have discontinued&#xD;
             steroids or anticonvulsants at least 14 days before the therapy of the study starts.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients whose imaging findings showed invaded central great vessels or obvious&#xD;
             pulmonary cavity or necrotizing tumor should be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with hypertension who are taking two or more antihypertensive drugs should be&#xD;
             excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients having the following should be excluded: Cardiovascular diseases: Myocardial&#xD;
             ischemia or myocardial infarction or grade II or above, uncontrolled arrhythmias, new&#xD;
             functions of grade III to IV, or cardiac ejection fraction &lt; 50%;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal coagulation function (INR &gt; 1.5 or prothrombin time (PT) &gt; ULN+4 seconds, or&#xD;
             APTT &gt; 1.5ULN), prone to bleeding or receiving thrombolytic or anticoagulant therapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had significant cough blood or daily hemoptysis of 2.5ml or more in 2 months before&#xD;
             the inclusion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having bleeding symptoms or definite bleeding tendency of significant clinical&#xD;
             significance, such as gastrointestinal bleeding, hemorrhagic gastric ulcer, fecal&#xD;
             occult blood ++ or above at baseline, or vasculitis, in 3 months before the inclusion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having developed artery/venous thrombosis in 12 months before the inclusion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With known hereditary or acquired bleeding and thrombosis tendency;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having a wound or fracture that has cannot be healed for a long time;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having received major surgery or had severe traumatic injury, fracture or ulcer in 4&#xD;
             weeks before the inclusion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject to factors that significantly affect the absorption of oral medication;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having developed abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation or abdominal abscess&#xD;
             in 6 months before the inclusion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having the urine routine result suggest urine protein ≥++, or confirmed the 24-hour&#xD;
             urine protein amount ≥ 1.0g;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With serous membrane effusion that is with clinical symptoms and requires symptomatic&#xD;
             treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With active infections that require antimicrobial treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having a history of psychotropic drug abuse and unable to quit or with a mental&#xD;
             disorder;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having participated in other clinical trials on anti-tumor drugs 4 weeks before the&#xD;
             inclusion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previously or currently having other incurable malignancies;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having received over-potent CYP3A4 inhibitor treatment in 7 days before the inclusion,&#xD;
             or have received over-potent CYP3A4 inducer treatment in 12 days before the inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating women who are fertile but are unwilling or unable to take&#xD;
             effective contraception measures should be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients as determined by researchers to be subject to other conditions that may&#xD;
             clinically affect the conduct or outcome of the study should be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Huaping S Yang, M.D</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Xiangya Hospital of Central South University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Huaping S Yang, M.D</last_name>
    <phone>+8613973129956</phone>
    <email>lyhuaping@aliyun.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Pengbo Deng, M.D</last_name>
    <phone>+8613574888840</phone>
    <email>12859155@qq.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Xiangya Hospital Central South University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Changsha</city>
        <state>Hunan</state>
        <zip>410000</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Huaping Yang, M.D</last_name>
      <phone>+8613973129956</phone>
      <email>lyhuaping@aliyun.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Pengbo Deng, M.D</last_name>
      <phone>+8613574888840</phone>
      <email>12859155@qq.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 17, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 17, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 17, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

