<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04675229</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ORE#42827</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04675229</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Extending the Validation of SCREEN to Persons Living With Dementia or in Retirement Homes</brief_title>
  <acronym>SCREEN</acronym>
  <official_title>Extending the Validation and Reliability Testing of SCREEN: A Nutrition Risk Screening Tool for Community-living Seniors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Waterloo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CIHR)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Waterloo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Older adults (≥ 55 years) who do not eat enough nutritious food are at risk of malnutrition.&#xD;
      Malnutrition can lead to frailty, hospitalization, poor quality of life, and death. SCREEN&#xD;
      (Seniors in the Community Risk Evaluation for Eating and Nutrition) is the leading nutrition&#xD;
      risk screening tool for cognitively well older adults living in the community. The purpose of&#xD;
      this study is to determine if SCREEN can be used to find nutrition risk among older adults&#xD;
      diagnosed with mild cognitive impairment or dementia (i.e., MCI-D) living in the community&#xD;
      and persons living in retirement homes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SCREEN and other nutrition and health measures will be completed in 600 older adults (300&#xD;
      living in retirement homes with or without MCI-D, and 300 living with MCI-D in the&#xD;
      community). SCREEN will be completed twice to determine reliability, and persons with MCI-D&#xD;
      will have their results compared to those of a caregiver who completes it on their behalf. A&#xD;
      dietitian's assessment and rating of nutrition risk will be used as the gold-standard to&#xD;
      determine validity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      About a third of cognitively well, community-living older Canadians are at nutrition risk,&#xD;
      which has been shown to lead to hospitalizations, poor quality of life, and death. Since&#xD;
      SCREEN was created 20 years ago, there has been considerable growth in the number of&#xD;
      community-living older adults diagnosed with mild cognitive impairment or dementia (i.e.,&#xD;
      MCI-D) and/or living in retirement homes. These two groups are nutritionally vulnerable.&#xD;
      Nutrition risk is specifically associated with the progression of cognitive impairment and&#xD;
      frailty, as well as caregiver burden. Yet, these groups are under-served with respect to&#xD;
      nutrition care; dietitian services are not available in retirement homes and limited in many&#xD;
      primary or memory care clinics. Nutrition screening and subsequent management of identified&#xD;
      nutrition problems by accessing diverse community services (e.g., meal programs) in Canadian&#xD;
      older adults is recommended because it can promote independence and delay frailty. However,&#xD;
      preventative management for those with MCI-D or living in retirement homes is limited by lack&#xD;
      of systematic nutrition screening with a valid and reliable tool that is feasible for these&#xD;
      vulnerable seniors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SCREEN is the leading nutrition risk tool for community-living seniors and is the logical&#xD;
      choice for use in those with MCI-D and/or living in retirement residences. However, it has&#xD;
      not been validated in these groups. It cannot be assumed that the existing validation in&#xD;
      cognitively well older adults living in their own homes can translate to these two vulnerable&#xD;
      groups. As well, one question on grocery shopping needs to be changed to accommodate persons&#xD;
      living in retirement homes. This study is also timely with the recent update of Canada's Food&#xD;
      Guide and recommendations to increase protein intake to mitigate frailty. Two questions on&#xD;
      SCREEN need to be modified to adapt the new language on protein foods used in the new Food&#xD;
      Guide. This study will undertake the validation and reliability testing of SCREEN,&#xD;
      considering these minor revisions, in 600 older adults (community-dwelling older adults with&#xD;
      MCI-D and those living in retirement homes with or without MCI-D). Validation of SCREEN for&#xD;
      these populations will ensure that a single tool can be used in all older adults living in&#xD;
      community and retirement settings. Specifically, understanding at what point a person with&#xD;
      MCI-D is no longer a reliable informant for completing SCREEN will help with identification&#xD;
      when a caregiver should complete the questionnaire. This is why the Montreal Cognitive&#xD;
      Assessment is used, as it provides discrete scores differentiating mild cognitive impairment&#xD;
      from dementia. The results of this study will have significant impact on practice by&#xD;
      allowing, for the first time, confidence in the identification of nutrition risk in these&#xD;
      under-served groups in Canada. There is an urgent need for this research. Early&#xD;
      identification of nutrition risk and its subsequent management has the potential to advance&#xD;
      our health care system by promoting the prevention of frailty and its consequences. This&#xD;
      study will have a meaningful impact in the 'real world' setting of primary and community care&#xD;
      for older adults in Canada and worldwide, by providing a feasible, validated and useful&#xD;
      nutrition risk tool.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Validity of SCREEN</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of SCREEN to a dietitian's assessment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reliability of SCREEN</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Test-retest reliability</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Malnutrition</condition>
  <condition>Nutrition Poor</condition>
  <condition>Dementia</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Persons living with dementia who have a family care partner Persons living in a retirement&#xD;
        home&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  55 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  potential participants with MCI-D will have a caregiver who either lives with the&#xD;
             participant or is in daily contact&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Retirement home participants will have lived in their residence for a minimum of 3&#xD;
             months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  read and communicate in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  provide written consent or assent for persons MCI-D; caregiver written consent&#xD;
             required&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  living in a nursing home&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  do not speak or read English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have MCI-D but do not have a caregiver to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  live outside of the geographic boundaries of this study (i.e., &gt; 45 km from&#xD;
             Kitchener/Waterloo or London).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Heather Keller</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>U Waterloo</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Heather Keller</last_name>
    <phone>15194977868</phone>
    <email>hkeller@uwaterloo.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 14, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Waterloo</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Heather Keller</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>nutrition risk</keyword>
  <keyword>dementia</keyword>
  <keyword>retirement</keyword>
  <keyword>validity</keyword>
  <keyword>reliability</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Repository at University of Waterloo</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>2025- 2035</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>University research</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

