<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04671030</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>KOR-12-35</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04671030</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Thrice Weekly Bowel Care</brief_title>
  <acronym>TWBC</acronym>
  <official_title>Effects of the Addition of a Prokinetic Agent to Thrice Weekly Bowel Care in Individuals With SCI</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>James J. Peters Veterans Affairs Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>James J. Peters Veterans Affairs Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      c. To measure a baseline for each subject, an abdominal x-ray (KUB) was performed, the SCI&#xD;
      Bowel Survey and Treatment Satisfaction Questionnaire (TSQM) were administered and the&#xD;
      subject's weight determined. After all the baseline measurements were acquired, the subjects&#xD;
      underwent transdermal screening with hair epilation to test their response to transdermal&#xD;
      administration of NEO (0.07mg/kg) and GLY (0.014mg/kg). All subjects had a positive response&#xD;
      (bowel movement within 60 minutes of drug administration) and received five more cycles of&#xD;
      bowel care for two weeks. All subjects reported bowel evacuation during each session and some&#xD;
      reported side effects like slight dry mouth, eye twitching, and cramping. These side effects&#xD;
      lasted approximately 20-30 minutes in duration and there were no clinically significant&#xD;
      changes in cardiopulmonary vital signs. Six subjects after completing two weeks of bowel care&#xD;
      had an abdominal x-ray (KUB) done. Also, they were weighted and reassessed using the TSQM and&#xD;
      bowel survey.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Part 1: IV Screening Twenty subjects with chronic SCI (&gt;1 year) and DWE managed by a regular,&#xD;
      thrice weekly BC routines will be recruited for study participation. In order to determine&#xD;
      eligibility for the study, the subject will have to undergo an IV screening to test whether&#xD;
      or not they are responsive to the drug treatment (neostigmine-glycopyrrolate). Subjects will&#xD;
      receive the following dose: 0.03mg/kg NEO and 0.006mg/kg GLY. If the subject responds (bowel&#xD;
      movement) to the IV treatment, they will be allowed to continue on to part 2 of the study. If&#xD;
      patient does not have a successful bowel movement, then they will be considered a&#xD;
      non-responder and study participation will be discontinued. Study procedures can be found in&#xD;
      table below.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part 2: Baseline and Iontophoresis Screening Once eligibility has been determined, and&#xD;
      subject consent has been obtained, each subject will undergo 1 week of baseline observation.&#xD;
      An abdominal x-ray (KUB) will be performed, the SCI Bowel Survey and Treatment Satisfaction&#xD;
      Questionnaire (TSQM) will be administered, and the subject's weight determined. Each subject&#xD;
      will continue with regular bowel care and after 1 week, all of the baseline measurements&#xD;
      (KUB, weight and surveys) will be repeated. This will be followed by an additional screening&#xD;
      visit during which we will concomitantly administer transcutaneous NEO and GLY via&#xD;
      iontophoresis (ION). Subjects will receive the following dose: 0.07mg/kg NEO and 0.014mg/kg&#xD;
      GLY. This visit will be scheduled on a BC day. All procedures will take place in the &quot;Blue&#xD;
      Room&quot; located in the SCI ward. As part of the setup, subjects will be instrumented with blood&#xD;
      pressure cuff; intravenous access will be obtained at a peripheral vein (if one is not&#xD;
      available), as a precautionary measure, since the drug will be administered via an&#xD;
      Iontophoresis transdermal patch. Heart rate will be continuously monitored throughout the&#xD;
      procedure through finger oximetry. Symptoms will be assessed every 5 minutes for 60 minutes.&#xD;
      Impulse Oscillometry system (IOS) will be used to measure the effect of the medication on&#xD;
      airway obstruction. If the subject has a positive response (bowel movement within 60 minutes&#xD;
      of drug administration) he/she will be eligible to continue to the third study phase. If the&#xD;
      subject does not respond, the subject will be considered a non-responder and study&#xD;
      participation will be discontinued. We expect that about 1/3rd of the subjects will be&#xD;
      non-responders, or will be lost to attrition; therefore, we are prepared to over-recruit by 5&#xD;
      subjects in order to ensure that at least 15 subjects will be eligible to complete the second&#xD;
      part of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be stopped once the patient experiences a bowel movement within 30 minutes of&#xD;
      administering ION NEO because the protocol objective will have been achieved. If the patient&#xD;
      should experience cardiopulmonary side effects when receiving the ION NEO that are not&#xD;
      effectively reversed by the ION GLY, the study will be stopped. In addition, the study&#xD;
      investigators reserve the right to stop the study should they have any other safety concerns.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part 3: 2 Week Treatment Each subject will be assessed for their perception of their current&#xD;
      BC routine using the Treatment Satisfaction Questionnaire for Medication (TSQM-Appendix 1),&#xD;
      and their bowel habits using the bowel survey (Appendix 2).The subject will then be asked to&#xD;
      continue with their normal BC routine for two weeks, with the exception that NEO and GLY will&#xD;
      be administered at the beginning of each BC session as an adjunct to each subject's normal&#xD;
      routine. Subjects will be asked to come to the JJPVAMC for each BC session. Each BC session&#xD;
      will be documented by a study team member including the time needed to complete BC, methods&#xD;
      used (i.e. number of enemas used, oral laxatives, suppositories, digital stimulation,&#xD;
      abdominal massage) and the quality and completeness of the bowel movement. Heart rate,&#xD;
      oxygenation and blood pressure will be monitored continuously. Subjects will be weighed at&#xD;
      baseline, once after each week of treatment and once at the post treatment follow-up visit.&#xD;
      After two weeks of treatment, each subject will undergo a final KUB and be reassessed for&#xD;
      their perception of the BC routine for the past two weeks using the TSQM and their bowel&#xD;
      habits (bowel survey).&#xD;
&#xD;
      *During the treatment period (part 3), monitoring will take place for the first hour after&#xD;
      administration of study medications. However, bowel care will continue for as long as is&#xD;
      clinically indicated. Additional techniques for bowel care (i.e. enema, suppository, digital&#xD;
      stimulation, etc.) will be used in coordination with SCI nurses to promote bowel evacuation&#xD;
      for subjects who do not respond.&#xD;
&#xD;
      **An IV line will be inserted during all study visits. Study medication will be administered&#xD;
      intravenously during Part 1 only. An IV line will be available however through all sessions&#xD;
      involving study medication for safety purposes in the case that an antidote needs to be&#xD;
      administered&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 15, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 14, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 14, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Single group interventional study with brief crossover of subjects into the placebo group</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>Subjects are not aware of the nature of the drug that they are receiving</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to first bowel evacuation</measure>
    <time_frame>within 1 hour</time_frame>
    <description>Measured from completion of adminstration to first bowel evacuation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Constipation in Patients With Spinal Cord Injury</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects are screened by criteria, intravenous and transdermal iontophoresis then undergo the study during which they will be administered the placebo alternating with real drug without being aware of which is being given.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo will be given without the subject being aware of the time in advance.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Neostigmine and Glycopyrrolate</intervention_name>
    <description>Intravenous followed by transdermal administration of the two drug combination.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Iontophoresis</intervention_name>
    <description>Application of direct current to skin using an FDA-approved device</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>I-Box</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        1. Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Spinal Cord Injury:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Level of injury C1 to S4&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Duration of injury over 1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Excess time for bowel evacuation (over 60 minutes per bowel training session).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previous Adverse Reaction or Hypersensitivity to Electrical Stimulation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Do not require additional bowel care or have &quot;normal bowel function&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Known sensitivity to Neostigmine and Glycopyrrolate&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Blockage in Bowel or Bladder&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Myocardial Infarction in the past 6months&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Blood Pressure over 160 over 100 mg Hg with being on 3 or more different classes&#xD;
                  of antihypertensive medications&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Organ Damage (heart and kidney) and/or TIA, CVA as a result of hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Known past history of coronary artery disease, chronic heart failure,&#xD;
                  bradyarrythmia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Slow Heart Rate (under 45 bpm)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Active respiratory diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Known history of asthma during lifetime&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Recent (within 3 months) respiratory infections&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adrenal Insufficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pregnancy or potential for pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Lactating/nursing females&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Use of any antibiotics in past 7 days&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Use of medications known to affect respiratory system&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Concurrent participation in other clinical trials (within 30 days)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Anton V Sabiev, MD</last_name>
    <phone>917 717 4643</phone>
    <email>anton.sabiev@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Mark A Korsten, MD</last_name>
    <phone>718 584 9000</phone>
    <phone_ext>6759</phone_ext>
    <email>mark.korsten@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>James J Peters VA Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bronx</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10468</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anton Sabiev</last_name>
      <phone>917-717-4643</phone>
      <email>sabiev@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 10, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 10, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 10, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>James J. Peters Veterans Affairs Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mark A. Kortsen, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chief of Gastroenterology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Constipation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glycopyrrolate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neostigmine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

