<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04673357</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CR108864</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2019-004225-24</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>CNTO1275CRD3004</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04673357</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Ustekinumab in Pediatric Participants With Moderately to Severely Active Crohn's Disease</brief_title>
  <acronym>UNITI Jr</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 3 Study of the Efficacy, Safety, and Pharmacokinetics of Ustekinumab as Open-label Intravenous Induction Treatment Followed by Randomized Double-blind Subcutaneous Ustekinumab Maintenance in Pediatric Participants With Moderately to Severely Active Crohn's Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of ustekinumab dosing in inducing&#xD;
      clinical remission (Global) and in maintaining clinical remission (US); to evaluate the&#xD;
      safety profile and ustekinumab exposure (pharmacokinetics [PK]) in pediatric participants&#xD;
      with moderately to severely active Crohn's disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 6, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 25, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 24, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Induction period is an open-label period and maintenance period is a double-blind period.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Clinical Remission at Induction Week 8</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 8</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with clinical remission in induction period will be assessed. Clinical remission is defined as having a Pediatric Crohn's Disease Activity Index (PCDAI) score less than or equal to (&lt;=) 10 points. PCDAI is an index used to measure disease activity of pediatric patients with Crohn's Disease assessing abdominal pain, stool frequency, patient functioning, hematocrit, erythrocyte sedimentation rate, albumin, weight, height, abdominal tenderness or mass, perirectal disease, and extraintestinal manifestations. It ranges from 0 to 100; higher scores indicate more active disease.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Adverse Events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 74</time_frame>
    <description>An AE can be any unfavorable and unintended sign (including an abnormal finding), symptom, or disease temporally associated with the use of a medicinal (investigational or non investigational) product, whether or not related to that medicinal (investigational or non investigational) product.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 74</time_frame>
    <description>A SAE is any untoward medical occurrence that at any dose: results in death; is life threatening; requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of existing hospitalization; results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity; is a congenital anomaly/birth defect; is a suspected transmission of any infectious agent via a medicinal product; is medically important.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with AEs leading to Discontinuation of Study Intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 74</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with AEs leading to discontinuation of study intervention will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with AEs of Interest</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 74</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with AEs of interest (any newly identified malignancy, or case of active tuberculosis [TB], or opportunistic infection occurring after the first administration of study intervention[s]) will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Abnormalities in Clinical Laboratory Parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with abnormalities in clinical laboratory parameters (such as hematology and chemistry) will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Reactions Temporally Associated with Intravenous (IV) Infusion (Induction Period)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 8 (Induction period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with reactions temporally associated with IV infusion in induction period will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Subcutaneous (SC) Injection-Site Reactions (Maintenance Period)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 44 (Maintenance period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with SC injection-site reactions in maintenance period will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum Ustekinumab Concentrations</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Serum ustekinumab concentrations will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Clinical Remission at Maintenance Week 44</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 44 (Maintenance Period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with clinical remission in maintenance period will be assessed. This will be assessed among participants who are in clinical response at induction week-8 (I-8). Clinical remission is defined as having a PCDAI score &lt;= 10 points. PCDAI is an index used to measure disease activity of pediatric patients with Crohn's Disease assessing abdominal pain, stool frequency, patient functioning, hematocrit, erythrocyte sedimentation rate, albumin, weight, height, abdominal tenderness or mass, perirectal disease, and extraintestinal manifestations. It ranges from 0 to 100; higher scores indicate more active disease.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Clinical Remission</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 6 (Induction period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with clinical remission in induction period will be reported. Clinical remission is defined as PCDAI score and short Pediatric Crohn's Disease Activity Index (sPCDAI) score &lt;= 10 points.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Clinical Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 8 (Induction period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with clinical response in induction period will be reported. Clinical response is defined as a reduction from baseline in the PCDAI score of greater than or equal to (&gt;=) 12.5 points with a total PCDAI score not more than 30.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Clinical Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 6 (Induction period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with clinical response in induction period will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Endoscopic Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 8 (Maintenance period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with endoscopic response in maintenance period will be reported. Endoscopic response is defined as a reduction in the simplified endoscopic score-Crohn's disease (SES-CD) score of &gt;= 50 percent (%) or SES-CD score &lt;= 2 in participants with a baseline SES-CD score of &gt;= 3. The SES-CD score is based on the evaluation of 4 endoscopic components (presence/size of ulcers, proportion of mucosal surface covered by ulcers, proportion of mucosal surface affected by any other lesions, and presence/type of narrowing/strictures) across 5 ileocolonic segments. Each endoscopic component is scored from 0 to 3 for each segment, and a total score is derived from the sum of all the component scores (range, 0 to 60).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Clinical Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 8 (Maintenance period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with clinical response in maintenance period will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Clinical Remission</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 44 (Maintenance period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with clinical remission in maintenance period will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Endoscopic Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 44 (Maintenance period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with endoscopic response in maintenance period will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Clinical Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 44 (Maintenance period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with clinical response in maintenance period will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Corticosteroid-free Clinical Remission</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 44 (Maintenance period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with corticosteroid-free clinical remission in maintenance period will be reported. Corticosteroid-free clinical remission is PCDAI score &lt;= 10 points and not receiving corticosteroids for at least 90 days prior to Week 44.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Corticosteroid-free Clinical Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 44 (Maintenance period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with corticosteroid-free clinical response in maintenance period will be reported. Corticosteroid-free clinical response is a reduction from baseline in the PCDAI score of &gt;= 12.5 points with a total PCDAI score not more than 30 and not receiving corticosteroids for at least 90 days prior to Week 44.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Durable Clinical Remission</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 44 (Maintenance period)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with durable clinical remission in maintenance period will be reported. Durable clinical remission is PCDAI score &lt;=10 points for &gt;= 80% of all maintenance visits between Week M-8 to Week M-44 and in clinical remission at Week M-44.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Crohn Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Open- Label Ustekinumab Intravenous (IV): Induction Period</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All participants will receive a single IV administration of ustekinumab at induction Week 0 (I-0) based on body surface area (BSA) (milligram per meter square [mg/m^2]) or weight-tiered induction dose (milligram per kilogram [mg/kg]).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ustekinumab Subcutaneous (SC) Every 8 Weeks (q8w): Maintenance Period</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive SC administration of ustekinumab q8w based on BSA (mg/m^2) or weight-tiered induction dose (mg/kg) at maintenance weeks (Weeks M)-0, M-8, M-16, M-24, M 32, and M-40 and matching placebo at Weeks M-12 and M-36 to maintain the blind.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ustekinumab SC Every 12 Weeks (q12w): Maintenance Period</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive SC administration of ustekinumab q12w based on BSA (mg/m^2) or weight-tiered induction dose (mg/kg) at Weeks M-0, M-12, M-24, M-36 and matching placebo at Weeks M-8, M-16, M-32, and M-40 to maintain the blind.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ustekinumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Ustekinumab will be administered intravenously in induction period and subcutaneously in maintenance period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Open- Label Ustekinumab Intravenous (IV): Induction Period</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Ustekinumab SC Every 12 Weeks (q12w): Maintenance Period</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Ustekinumab Subcutaneous (SC) Every 8 Weeks (q8w): Maintenance Period</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Matching placebo will be administered as SC injection.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ustekinumab SC Every 12 Weeks (q12w): Maintenance Period</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Ustekinumab Subcutaneous (SC) Every 8 Weeks (q8w): Maintenance Period</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have Crohn's disease or fistulizing Crohn's disease with active colitis, ileitis, or&#xD;
             ileocolitis, confirmed at any time in the past by endoscopy and histology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have moderately to severely active Crohn's disease (as defined by a baseline&#xD;
             Pediatric Crohn's Disease Activity Index [PCDAI] score greater than [&gt;] 30); have&#xD;
             ileocolonoscopy with evidence of active Crohn's disease defined as presence of&#xD;
             ulceration (which is equal to Simple Endoscopic Score for Crohn's disease [SES-CD]&#xD;
             score greater than or equals to [&gt;=] 3) during screening into this study. If unable to&#xD;
             evaluate ulceration due to stricture or inadequate bowel preparation, at least one of&#xD;
             the following criteria may instead be applied: an abnormal C-reactive protein (CRP) (&gt;&#xD;
             0.3 milligram per deciliter [mg/dL] or 3.0 milligram per liter [mg/L] at screening)&#xD;
             or; fecal calprotectin of &gt;= 250 milligram per kilogram [mg/kg] or &gt;= 250 microgram&#xD;
             per gram [mcg/g] at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If receiving enteral nutrition, must have been on a stable regimen for at least 2&#xD;
             weeks prior to induction week 0 (Week I-0)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of childbearing potential must have a negative urine pregnancy test at&#xD;
             screening and at Week I-0 prior to study intervention administration&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has complications of Crohn's disease such as symptomatic strictures or stenosis, short&#xD;
             gut syndrome, or any other manifestation that might be anticipated to require surgery,&#xD;
             that could preclude the use of the PCDAI to assess response to therapy or would&#xD;
             possibly confound the ability to assess the effect of treatment with ustekinumab&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a history of latent or active granulomatous infection, including TB,&#xD;
             histoplasmosis, or coccidioidomycosis, or have had a nontuberculous mycobacterial&#xD;
             infection prior to screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence or history of any malignancy including presence or history of&#xD;
             lymphoproliferative disease including lymphoma, or signs and symptoms suggestive of&#xD;
             possible lymphoproliferative disease, such as lymphadenopathy of unusual size or&#xD;
             location (example, nodes in the posterior triangle of the neck, infraclavicular,&#xD;
             epitrochlear, or periaortic areas), and monoclonal gammopathy of undetermined&#xD;
             significance, or clinically significant hepatomegaly or splenomegaly&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a history of moderate or severe progressive or uncontrolled liver or renal&#xD;
             insufficiency; or significant cardiac, vascular, pulmonary, gastrointestinal,&#xD;
             endocrine, neurologic, hematologic, psychiatric (including suicidality), or metabolic&#xD;
             disturbances&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received an investigational intervention including any investigational vaccines or&#xD;
             used an invasive investigational medical device within 3 months before the planned&#xD;
             first dose of study intervention or is currently enrolled in an investigational study;&#xD;
             receipt of an investigational vaccine for Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) is not&#xD;
             an automatic exclusion criterion&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC Clinical Trial</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Study Contact</last_name>
    <phone>844-434-4210</phone>
    <email>JNJ.CT@sylogent.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nemours DuPont Hospital for Children</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wilmington</city>
        <state>Delaware</state>
        <zip>19803</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Center for Digestive Health Care</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30342</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Morristown Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Morristown</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07962</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cohen Children's Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lake Success</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11042</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Levine Children's at Atrium Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlotte</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28207</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospitals Case Medical Center Rainbow Babies and Childrens Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cleveland Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Penn State Hershey Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hershey</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>17033</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Center For Digestive Health Systems-Greenville</name>
      <address>
        <city>Greenville</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29615</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Medical Center of Dallas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75390-9063</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cook Childrens Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Worth</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>76104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pediatric Specialists Of Virginia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fairfax</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>22031</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seattle Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98105</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitair Kinderziekenhuis Koningin Fabiola</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brussel</city>
        <zip>1020</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cliniques Universitaires Saint-Luc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brussel</city>
        <zip>1200</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ Gent</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gent</city>
        <zip>9000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ Brussel</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jette</city>
        <zip>1090</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ Leuven</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leuven</city>
        <zip>3000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Aachen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aachen</city>
        <zip>52074</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Charite-Universitätsmedizin Berlin - Berlin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berlin</city>
        <zip>13353</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitatsklinikum Essen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Essen</city>
        <zip>45147</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medizinische Hochschule Hannover</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hannover</city>
        <zip>30625</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dr. von Haunersches Kinderspital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Munich</city>
        <zip>80337</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>KUNO Klinik St. Hedwig</name>
      <address>
        <city>Regensburg</city>
        <zip>93049</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Ulm</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ulm</city>
        <zip>89075</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Semmelweis Egyetem</name>
      <address>
        <city>Budapest</city>
        <zip>1083</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Debreceni Egyetem Klinikai Kozpont</name>
      <address>
        <city>Debrecen</city>
        <zip>4032</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Borsod-Abauj-Zemplen Megyei Korhaz es Egyetemi Oktato Korhaz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miskolc</city>
        <zip>3526</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Szabolcs-Szatmar-Bereg Megyei Korhazak es Egyetemi Oktatokorhaz, Josa Andras Oktatokorhaz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nyiregyhaza</city>
        <zip>4400</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Szegedi Tudományegyetem, Gyermekgyógyászati Klinika és Gyermekegészségügyi Centrum</name>
      <address>
        <city>Szeged</city>
        <zip>6720</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Juntendo University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bunkyo-Ku</city>
        <zip>113-8431</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kurume University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fukuoka</city>
        <zip>830-0011</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gunma University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gunma</city>
        <zip>371-0034</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kindai University Nara Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ikoma</city>
        <zip>630-0293</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Saitama Children's Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saitama-shi</city>
        <zip>330-8777</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Miyagi Children'S Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sendai-shi</city>
        <zip>989-3126</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Center for Child Health and Development</name>
      <address>
        <city>Setagaya-ku</city>
        <zip>157-8535</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jichi Medical University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Shimotsuke</city>
        <zip>329-0498</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mie University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tsu</city>
        <zip>514-8507</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Szpital im. M. Kopernika</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gdansk</city>
        <zip>80-803</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Uniwersytecki Szpital Dzieciecy w Krakowie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Krakow</city>
        <zip>30-663</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gabinet Lekarski Bartosz Korczowski</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rzeszow</city>
        <zip>35-302</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Szpital Pomnik Centrum Zdrowia Dziecka</name>
      <address>
        <city>Warszawa</city>
        <zip>04-730</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Uniwersytecki Szpital Kliniczny im. Jana Mikulicza-Radeckiego we Wroclawiu</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wroclaw</city>
        <zip>50-369</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kazan State Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kazan</city>
        <zip>420138</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Russian National Research Medical University named after N.I.Pirogov</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <zip>119571</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>FSBI 'Scientific Centre of Children Health' of the Russian Academy of Medical Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <zip>119991</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Privolzhsky Research Medical University of Ministry of Health of Russian Federation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nizhny Novgorod</city>
        <zip>603950</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Saratov State Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saratov</city>
        <zip>410054</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yaroslavl Regional Children's Clinical Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Yaroslavl</city>
        <zip>150032</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Birmingham Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <zip>B4 6NH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cambridge</city>
        <zip>CB2 0QQ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Hospital for Children and Young People</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edinburgh</city>
        <zip>EH16 4TJ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal London Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>E1 2AT</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>King's College Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SE5 9RS</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Hungary</country>
    <country>Japan</country>
    <country>Poland</country>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://pam.sylogent.com/cr/CR108864</url>
    <description>To learn how to participate in this trial please click here.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 14, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pediatric</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ustekinumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data sharing policy of the Janssen Pharmaceutical Companies of Johnson &amp; Johnson is available at www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency. As noted on this site, requests for access to the study data can be submitted through Yale Open Data Access (YODA) Project site at yoda.yale.edu</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

