<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04672330</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NEO-IO</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04672330</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neoadjuvant PD-1 Monoclonal Antibody in Locally Advanced Upper Tract Urothelial Carcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Open, Single-center Clinical Study to Examine the Efficacy and Safety of Neoadjuvant Tislelizumab in Patients With Locally Advanced Upper Urinary Tract Urothelial Carcinoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>RenJi Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>RenJi Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Neoadjuvant therapy of cisplatin-based chemotherapy has been proved to improve prognosis of&#xD;
      muscle invasive UTUC patients in several studies. This study is designed to investigate the&#xD;
      safety and efficacy of neoadjuvant PD-1 monoclonal antibody in patients with locally advanced&#xD;
      upper urinary tract urothelial carcinoma (UTUC) which are ineligible for cisplatin.&#xD;
      Tislelizumab, an anti-programmed death protein-1 (PD-1) monoclonal antibody, was engineered&#xD;
      to minimize binding to FcγR on macrophages to abrogate antibody-dependent phagocytosis, a&#xD;
      mechanism of T-cell clearance and potential resistance to anti-PD-1 therapy. The safety,&#xD;
      tolerability, and efficacy of tislelizumab in patients with PD-L1 positive urothelial&#xD;
      carcinoma who progressed during/following platinum-containing therapy was proved in a phase 2&#xD;
      trial (CTR20170071). This trial focuses on the efficacy of Tislelizumab to induce&#xD;
      pathological down-staging of locally advanced UTUC in neoadjuvant setting.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Neoadjuvant therapy of cisplatin-based chemotherapy has been proved to improve prognosis of&#xD;
      muscle invasive UTUC patients in several studies. This study is designed to investigate the&#xD;
      safety and efficacy of neoadjuvant PD-1 monoclonal antibody in patients with locally advanced&#xD;
      upper urinary tract urothelial carcinoma (UTUC) which are ineligible for cisplatin.&#xD;
      Tislelizumab, an anti-programmed death protein-1 (PD-1) monoclonal antibody, was engineered&#xD;
      to minimize binding to FcγR on macrophages to abrogate antibody-dependent phagocytosis, a&#xD;
      mechanism of T-cell clearance and potential resistance to anti-PD-1 therapy. The safety,&#xD;
      tolerability, and efficacy of tislelizumab in patients with PD-L1 positive urothelial&#xD;
      carcinoma who progressed during/following platinum-containing therapy was proved in a phase 2&#xD;
      trial (CTR20170071). This trial focuses on the efficacy of Tislelizumab to induce&#xD;
      pathological down-staging of locally advanced UTUC in neoadjuvant setting.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients will receive 2-4 cycles of Tislelizumab (200mg per cycle) prior to radical nephroureterectomy and lymphadenectomy</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>pathologic response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Pathologic response rate include complete pathological remission（pT0N0）and partial pathological remission (≤pT1N0).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pathologic downstaging response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>the rate of pT0-2N0 disease on the final surgical specimen and radiological staging</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>perioperative complication rate</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>the rate of perioperative complications are determined according to Clavien classification</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>the completion rate of neoadjuvant therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>120 days before surgery</time_frame>
    <description>the rate of patients that complete all the neoadjuvant therapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Neoadjuvant Immunotherapy of Locally Advanced Upper Urinary Tract Urothelial Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Neoadjuvant arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive 2-4 cycles of Tislelizumab (200mg per cycle) prior to radical nephroureterectomy and lymphadenectomy.&#xD;
Drug: Tislelizumab 200 mg per cycle, IV on day 1 of every 3-week cycle, for 2-4 cycles prior to radical nephroureterectomy and lymphadenectomy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tislelizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive 2-4 cycles of Tislelizumab (200mg per cycle) before radical nephroureterectomy and lymphadenectomy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Neoadjuvant arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>anti-PD-1 monoclonal antibody</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Patients that are identified as locally advanced upper urinary tract urothelial&#xD;
             carcinoma by ureteroscopic biopsy and imaging diagnosis and are determined as&#xD;
             appropriate candidates for radical nephrectomyby an attending urologist; 2. Has&#xD;
             clinical stage T3-T4, any N, M0 or any T, N1-2, M0; 3. ECOG performance status of 0 to&#xD;
             2; 4. Adequate organ function defined by study-specified laboratory tests; Hemoglobin&#xD;
             ≥90 g/L; Hematological Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1.5×109 /L; Platelets ≥100×109&#xD;
             /L 5. No functional organic disease: T-BIL≤1.5×upper limit of normal (ULN); ALT&#xD;
             andAST≤2.5×ULN; Serum creatinine≤2×ULN; endogenous creatinine clearance rate&gt;30ml/min&#xD;
             6. Agree to comply with scheduled visits, treatment plans, lab tests and any other&#xD;
             required study procedures; 7. Patients who are ineligible for cisplatin for some&#xD;
             reasons, for example endogenous creatinine clearance rate&lt;60ml/min, patients refuse to&#xD;
             receive cisplatin-based chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - 1. Patients who have received prior therapy of an anti-PD-1, anti-PD-L1, or anti-PD-L2&#xD;
        antibody; 2. Patients who are allergic to monoclonal antibodies or any of its excipients;&#xD;
        3. Patients who have received other systems for anti-tumor treatment (e. g., Steroid&#xD;
        therapy, immunotherapy) within 4 weeks or enrolled in other clinical trials; 4. Patients&#xD;
        who are pregnant or breastfeeding, or expecting to conceive; 5. Patients who have a known&#xD;
        history of Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) (HIV 1/2 antibodies); 6. Patients who have&#xD;
        known active Hepatitis B or Hepatitis C; 7. Patients who have active autoimmune disease&#xD;
        that has required systemic treatment in the past 2 years; 8. Patients who have received a&#xD;
        live vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose of trial treatment; 9. Patients who&#xD;
        have received prior radiation therapy to the bladder; 10. Patients who have bladder cancer;&#xD;
        11. Patients who have received allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation or solid&#xD;
        organ transplantation; 12. Patients who have a history of substance abuse or with a history&#xD;
        of mental disorders; 13. Patients who had other malignant tumors in the past five years&#xD;
        that have not recovered except for curable tumors that have been cured including basal or&#xD;
        squamous skin cancer, localized carcinoma in situ of the cervix or the breast and low-risk&#xD;
        prostate cancer, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
        14. Patients who have active tuberculosis; 15. Patients who have other serious and&#xD;
        uncontrollable accompanying diseases that may affect compliance or interfere with the&#xD;
        interpretation of results including active opportunistic infections or advanced (severe)&#xD;
        infections, uncontrollable diabetes, cardiovascular disease (grade III or IV heart failure&#xD;
        defined by the New York Heart Association classification, II degree atrioventricular block&#xD;
        and above, myocardial infarction in the past 6 months, unstable arrhythmia or instability&#xD;
        angina, cerebral infarction within 3 months, etc.) or lung disease (interstitial pneumonia,&#xD;
        history of obstructive lung disease and symptomatic bronchospasm); 16. Patients who have a&#xD;
        large amount of pleural fluid or ascites with clinical symptoms or requiring symptomatic&#xD;
        treatment;&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Shanghai Renji Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Shanghai</city>
        <state>Shanghai</state>
        <zip>200127</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 12, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 12, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 12, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>neoadjuvant therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>radical nephroureterectomy</keyword>
  <keyword>Tislelizumab</keyword>
  <keyword>Cisplatin-ineligible</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Transitional Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Kidney Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ureteral Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

