<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02269384</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MountSMCLA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02269384</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effects of Pain and the Memory of Pain on Autonomic and Neuromuscular Function</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effects of Pain and the Memory of Pain on Autonomic and Neuromuscular Function</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mount St. Mary's College, Los Angeles, CA</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mount St. Mary's College, Los Angeles, CA</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The prevalence of chronic pain has been estimated at 30% in the US and these values may under&#xD;
      report the true prevalence of people who experience long term pain as additional research has&#xD;
      shown that 73% will have a reoccurrence of symptoms within 12 months of the original injury&#xD;
      indicating that while the pain and symptoms may resolve, additional impairments or issues may&#xD;
      underlie the symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biopsychosocial factors such as depression, post traumatic stress, anxiety, pain&#xD;
      catastrophizing, and negative emotions have been closely linked to pain and can influence a&#xD;
      patient's pain perceptions. Along these lines, the memory of past experiences and trauma&#xD;
      potentially play a large role in these biopsychosocial responses. Research is evolving and a&#xD;
      strong correlation has been established between chronic pain and prior history of trauma or&#xD;
      abuse and also non-traumatic incidents such as motor vehicle accidents and injuries/surgical&#xD;
      procedures. This has led to speculation and research that explores how a variety of life&#xD;
      events may become stimulants for long-term alterations in the processing and manifestation of&#xD;
      pain and how they may have an enduring impact on physical health outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The proposed research will add to the body of knowledge underlying the association between&#xD;
      pain, memory, autonomic system, and neuromuscular function. The goal of this project is to&#xD;
      study the relationship between pain memory systems, specifically acute pain, short-term&#xD;
      memory of pain, and long term pain memory, and their effects upon neuromuscular and autonomic&#xD;
      system responses in the body.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Design This study will utilize a repeated measures quasi-experimental case control&#xD;
      design structure. Subjects will be placed into two groupings, those who have a history of&#xD;
      prior lower extremity injury and those who have no history of lower extremity injury. The two&#xD;
      groupings will be age and gender matched. Subjects who have no prior history of lower&#xD;
      extremity injury will be matched to subjects with a prior history of injury. There will be an&#xD;
      equivalent number of participants per group with similar demographic information in both&#xD;
      groups in order to reduce the number of variables influencing the results of the experiment.&#xD;
      Within each of these groupings, specific interventions will be clustered and performed as a&#xD;
      set. These clusters of interventions will be randomized to minimize internal testing error.&#xD;
      Both groups of participants will be exposed to the same interventions (baseline, pain&#xD;
      pressure, visualization of pain pressure and prior injury, and mental challenge test).&#xD;
      Investigators responsible for testing and outcome measurement will be blinded to the&#xD;
      groupings of subjects (past history or no prior history of injury). It is anticipated that&#xD;
      the testing, including initial set up, will take between 60 and 75 minutes. All testing will&#xD;
      take place at the Mount St. Mary's College physical therapy exercise and research lab or in a&#xD;
      private room at Knight Physical Therapy Inc.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Methods Initial Set Up (25 minutes) Upon commencement of the study, subjects will be&#xD;
      asked to fill out the Tampa Kinesiophobia Questionnaire, Fear Avoidance Belief Questionnaire,&#xD;
      Fear of Pain Scale, Pain Catastrophizing Scale, and the Vividness of Visual Imagery&#xD;
      Questionnaire. This should take approximately 10 minutes. Following completion of these&#xD;
      questionnaires, they will be introduced to the investigators and then asked to lie supine&#xD;
      upon the treatment table. A pillow will be placed under their head for comfort. Surface EMG&#xD;
      rRecording electrodes will be placed upon the belly of the tibialis anterior muscle. An&#xD;
      electrode will be placed upon the medial tibia and will serve as a ground for the other two&#xD;
      electrodes. Placement of electrodes will correspond to the side of injury (i.e. prior injury&#xD;
      to the right ankle would result in electrode placement on the right tibialis anterior and&#xD;
      right anterior deltoid muscles). In subjects without history of injury, side of electrode&#xD;
      placement will be predetermined and randomized. Also at this time, subjects with a prior&#xD;
      history of injury will be asked to identify the location of the injury. The tester will then&#xD;
      palpate the area of previous injury and will locate the tender point in this area. This point&#xD;
      will be marked with a pen for later use. In subjects with no prior injury, the anterior&#xD;
      talofibular ligament, the lateral knee joint line, or the lateral belly of the gastrocnemius&#xD;
      muscle will be located and marked on the side of testing. The site will be randomized so as&#xD;
      to blind testers. Testers will be informed of the side to be tested through the sealed&#xD;
      envelope that is opened prior to testing. They will be blinded as to prior injury grouping.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At this point, the subject will be walked through the procedure and an initial pain pressure&#xD;
      threshold measurement will be taken and a simulated break test (see below for description of&#xD;
      break test) will be performed at the foot / ankle in order to familiarize the subject with&#xD;
      the test procedures and also to ensure that all equipment is functioning optimally. This&#xD;
      process should take approximately 10 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following this procedure, a timer will be set and the subject will rest in this position for&#xD;
      five minutes to acclimate to the environment and to normalize their autonomic system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Autonomic System Response (10 minutes) Following the five-minute acclimation period, heart&#xD;
      rate variability (HRV) data will be recorded, marked, and used as a baseline measurement. The&#xD;
      HRV data will be collected throughout each testing procedure. Initially, at the site of&#xD;
      previous injury (or randomized pressure site for subjects with no prior history of injury),&#xD;
      the tester will use their thumb to apply pressure to the site. The pressure will increase&#xD;
      until the subject reports their maximal pain level. Prior to the application of pressure, the&#xD;
      subject will be informed that they are to experience the maximum pain tolerable and to inform&#xD;
      the tester when that level is reached. The subject will next be instructed to notify the&#xD;
      testers when they have reached the maximum tolerable pain. Once achieve, the pressure will be&#xD;
      maintained for 10 seconds in order to get a baseline HRV recording. After 10 seconds, the&#xD;
      pressure will be released and the HRV recording will be marked. At this time, the subject&#xD;
      will be asked to report their level of pain on a scale of 1 to 10. The subject will then rest&#xD;
      for three minutes to return their HRV to baseline values. At this point, the subject will be&#xD;
      instructed to close their eyes and imagine the pain pressure in their leg that was just&#xD;
      applied. HRV and pain values will be marked and recorded. The subject will rest for another&#xD;
      three minutes and then they will once again be asked to close their eyes. In this instance,&#xD;
      they will be asked to visualize the details of their prior injury. In subjects with no prior&#xD;
      injury, they will asked to visualize the muscles, bone, and blood flow of their tibia. Like&#xD;
      before, HRV and pain values will be marked and recorded. Following another three minute rest&#xD;
      period, the subject will be asked to complete a mental challenge test. This test will require&#xD;
      subjects to count backwards as quickly as possible from 100 by 7. HRV and pain values will be&#xD;
      marked and recorded. With this test, and with all testing, the subject will be allowed to&#xD;
      withdrawal from the test for any reason and without repercussions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pressure Pain Threshold (10 minutes) The amount of pain and the force required to elicit the&#xD;
      pain response will be applied and monitored by a Wagner Force Ten™ FDX Digital Force Gauge&#xD;
      Pain Algometer. The algometer is a device designed to measure sensitiveness to pressure and&#xD;
      in pain studies; the algometer is used to measure sensitiveness to pain as a product of&#xD;
      pressure. The Wagner Force Ten Digital Algometer is a portable unit with a small 1&#xD;
      cm2-rubberized tip capable of applying pressures up to 50 lbs./ft. The unit is capable of&#xD;
      remembering multiple data points and storing peak force and force-averaged data that will be&#xD;
      retrieved after testing for later analysis. During each of the five test components&#xD;
      (Baseline, Pain Pressure, Visualization of Pain Pressure, Visualization of Prior Injury, and&#xD;
      Mental Challenge Test) the testing procedures will be identical to those applied earlier,&#xD;
      except instead of measuring muscle performance or HRV, pain pressure will be recorded. The&#xD;
      tip of the pain algometer will be placed upon the site of prior injury or upon the anterior&#xD;
      talofibular ligament. Pressure will be applied through the algometer and the subject will be&#xD;
      instructed to inform the tester when they first begin to experience pain. This value will be&#xD;
      recorded along with HRV values.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neuromuscular Response (15 minutes) During the next phase of testing, a small rolled up towel&#xD;
      will be placed under the test ankle. The towel will be utilized to raise the foot from the&#xD;
      table in order to facilitate testing. At this point, the tester will stabilize the lower&#xD;
      extremity by grasping the calf approximately 12 inches above the malleolus. This hand will&#xD;
      provide a counter force to the forces applied by the test hand. In the test hand, a Hoggan&#xD;
      Scientific Microfet 2TM Handheld Muscle Tester will be placed upon the lateral aspect of the&#xD;
      fifth metatarsal bone of the foot. The placement will be proximal on the metatarsal&#xD;
      approximately at the base of the fifth metatarsal bone. The position of the sensor will be&#xD;
      marked to standardize test position and measured for later force measurement purposes. The&#xD;
      subject will be instructed to isometrically resist the force applied by the tester. At this&#xD;
      point, Surface EMG and Force recording will commence simultaneously. The Surface EMG will be&#xD;
      utilized to measure action potential propagation. Surface recording electrodes are placed&#xD;
      upon the skin to measure these action potentials. At no time will needles be utilized to&#xD;
      collect data and therefore, no penetration of the skin is required. The initiation of the&#xD;
      test will also be noted on the HRV recording. A steady but increasing amount of force will be&#xD;
      applied slowly and gradually to the foot in a medially and slightly caudal direction until&#xD;
      the subject can no longer resist the force. This process is called the &quot;break test&quot; because&#xD;
      the muscle is tested until it can no longer resist the force. The subject will rest for 30&#xD;
      seconds after which the break test and associated data recordings will be repeated two more&#xD;
      times with a 30-second rest period in between tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The subject will be allowed to rest for three minutes prior to beginning the next portion of&#xD;
      the study. HRV testing will be started and then the tester as previously described will place&#xD;
      pain pressure upon the site of previous injury. The location of this site has been previous&#xD;
      marked for consistency of application. In subjects with no prior history of injury, the&#xD;
      pressure will be applied to the anterior talofibular ligament. When pain pressure has reached&#xD;
      it's maximal levels, a second tester will perform a break test on the subject. Following the&#xD;
      test, the subject will rest for 30 seconds and the process will be repeated two more times&#xD;
      with a 30 second rest period in between tests. Force, EMG, HRV, and pain values will be&#xD;
      recorded during each of the break tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following a three minute rest period, the subject will asked to visualize the pain pressure&#xD;
      placed upon the leg (or visualize their tibia as previously described) and three break tests&#xD;
      will be performed during the visualization process. Force, EMG, HRV, and pain values will be&#xD;
      recorded during each of the break tests. This process will be repeated for visualization of&#xD;
      prior injury and for the mental challenge test.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Enrolling by invitation</last_known_status>
  <start_date>May 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in surface electromyography (sEMG) from baseline to either during or immediately post intervention or condition</measure>
    <time_frame>Data will be collected in one, one hour session. During the session, sEMG will be collected during or immediately following intervention or condition.</time_frame>
    <description>Surface electrodes will be placed upon the tibialis anterior muscle to monitor muscle activity during testing.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hand held dynamometric (HHD) measures from baseline to either during or immediately post intervention or condition</measure>
    <time_frame>Data will be collected in one, one hour session. During the session, HHD will be collected during or immediately following intervention or condition</time_frame>
    <description>A Hoggan Scientific Microfet 2 Handheld Muscle Tester will be placed upon the lateral aspect of the fifth metatarsal bone of the foot and a plantar and eversion directed force will be applied until the muscle can no longer resist the force applied (break test).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in pressure pain threshold (PPT) from baseline to either during or immediately post intervention or condition</measure>
    <time_frame>Data will be collected in one, one hour session. During the session, PPT will be collected during or immediately following intervention or condition</time_frame>
    <description>The force required to elicit the pain response will be applied and monitored by a Wagner Force Ten™ FDX Digital Force Gauge Pain Algometer.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in heart rate variability (HRV) from baseline to either during or immediately post intervention or condition</measure>
    <time_frame>Data will be collected in one, one hour session. Continuous monitoring of HRV will occur during each intervention or condition and significant data points will be marked for future analysis.</time_frame>
    <description>The HRV Live heart rate variability monitoring systems will be utilized and recording sensors will be placed upon the wrist of both arms to monitor cardiovagal responses during testing.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in verbal numeric pain scale (NPS) rating from baseline to immediately post intervention or condition</measure>
    <time_frame>Data will be collected in one, one hour session. During the session, NPS will be collected immediately following intervention or condition.</time_frame>
    <description>Verbal numeric pain scale will be used to monitor the amount of pain the subject is experiencing at various points throughout the study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No History of Significant Injury</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Experimental Noxious Stimulus, Memory of Experimental Noxious Stimulus, Memory of Prior Significant Injury, Mental Challenge Test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>History of Significant Injury</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Experimental Noxious Stimulus, Memory of Experimental Noxious Stimulus, Memory of Prior Significant Injury, Mental Challenge Test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Experimental Noxious Stimulus</intervention_name>
    <description>Localized manual pressure will be placed up predetermined points on the lower extremity until maximum pain tolerance levels are reached.</description>
    <arm_group_label>History of Significant Injury</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>No History of Significant Injury</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Acute Pain Stimulus</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Memory of Experimental Noxious Stimulus</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will be asked to visualize previously experience experimental noxious stimulus</description>
    <arm_group_label>History of Significant Injury</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>No History of Significant Injury</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Memory of Prior Significant Injury</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will visual prior significant injury or a predetermined lower extremity region in control subjects.</description>
    <arm_group_label>History of Significant Injury</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>No History of Significant Injury</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mental Challenge Test</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will count backwards from 100 by specified amounts as rapidly as possible</description>
    <arm_group_label>History of Significant Injury</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>No History of Significant Injury</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who have experienced a significant injury in the lower extremity (i.e.&#xD;
             fracture, ligament strain, surgery, trauma) that resulted in a significant loss of&#xD;
             function for greater then three weeks time period will be included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant loss of function will be defined as not being able to walk or being&#xD;
             required to use crutches for the three weeks and trauma shall be defined as physical,&#xD;
             emotional, or social distress or suffering that also coincided with injury to the&#xD;
             lower extremity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with a history of significant injury to the lower extremity will be age&#xD;
             and gender matched with individuals who have no history of traumatic injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute injuries in the lower extremity occurring less than six weeks prior,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any heart conditions, any open wounds in their lower extremities,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe hypertension greater than 180/110,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  poor sensation in the lower extremities, or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  cognitive impairments that prevent following the instructions of the study, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic pain greater then 3/10 in any region of the body.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>M. Samuel Cheng, DSc</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Nova Southeastern University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mount St. Mary's College</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90007</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 11, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 20, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 21, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 17, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 17, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 18, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Mount St. Mary's College, Los Angeles, CA</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Derrick Sueki</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Memory</keyword>
  <keyword>Pressure Pain Threshold</keyword>
  <keyword>Electromyography</keyword>
  <keyword>Heart Rate Variability</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

