<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01894048</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2012RC16</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2012-003923-39</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>13/ES/0064</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01894048</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Targeted Small Airways Therapy in Persistent Asthma</brief_title>
  <acronym>ANDA3</acronym>
  <official_title>Targeted Small Airways Therapy in Persistent Asthma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Dundee</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Teva Pharmaceuticals USA</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Dundee</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The mainstay of asthma treatment is with inhaled steroids (commonly called a 'preventer') to&#xD;
      keep the symptoms of asthma under control. Increasing strengths of steroid inhaler may be&#xD;
      required in order to gain control of asthma, and this is usually guided both by symptoms and&#xD;
      simple measurements of lung function such as peak flow.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The airways (breathing tubes) in the lungs get smaller the further into the lungs they go.&#xD;
      Most simple measurements of lung function only reflect the larger 'central' airways and don't&#xD;
      provide information on the smaller 'peripheral' airways.Newer measurements have been&#xD;
      developed that can now give us accurate information on how the smaller airways are&#xD;
      working.Indeed the small airways seem to play a significant role in asthma in terms of&#xD;
      inflammation and airway narrowing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, new types of steroid inhalers have been developed that have a much smaller particle&#xD;
      size than other standard inhaled steroids.These have been shown to go deeper into the lungs,&#xD;
      thus getting into the smaller airways. There have been a few studies suggesting that this&#xD;
      might improve asthma control. However, we do not know if when small airway function is shown&#xD;
      to be abnormal, whether this improves with extra-fine particle inhaled steroids, nor whether&#xD;
      by improving small airway function specifically this translates into improved asthma control.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study we wish to study asthmatic patients who are not completely controlled on&#xD;
      standard particle size inhaled steroids, in addition to having evidence of abnormal small&#xD;
      airway function. By doing this we want to find out whether changing to the same dose of an&#xD;
      extra-fine particle inhaled steroid instead will improve asthma control by getting deeper&#xD;
      into the lungs and improving small airway function.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A single centre, open-label, single subject study over a 12-24 week period. Invited&#xD;
      participants will receive a written 'Participant Information Sheet' (PIS) detailing the&#xD;
      requirements of the trial and the extent of their participation before attending for a&#xD;
      screening visit. Participants will be given at least 24 hours to read the PIS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to screen (and any subsequent challenge visit) participants will withhold LABAs (or&#xD;
      combination inhaler containing LABA) for 48 hours; and salbutamol for 6 hours. Verbal consent&#xD;
      will be obtained from the patient over the telephone for withholding medications prior to&#xD;
      screen and it will be explained that this in no way means they have consented to the full&#xD;
      study at this stage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the screening visit a member of the research team will discuss the PIS with the&#xD;
      participant, answer any questions posed and written informed consent will be obtained and&#xD;
      witnessed by the member of staff asking for the consent of the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A general physical examination will be carried out by a qualified medical practitioner.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A pregnancy test will be performed on all female patients with advice issued to both male and&#xD;
      female participants to use contraception throughout the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following will be measured:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Asthma Control Questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Mini-Asthma Quality of Life Questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Fractional exhaled nitric oxide levels&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Impulse oscillometry&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Spirometry&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Skin prick test to common allergens&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Full blood count, renal function, electrolytes, liver enzymes and random blood glucose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be checked against all inclusion and exclusion criteria. Those found to be&#xD;
      eligible will proceed to the step down and/or run-in period. This will last for a minimum of&#xD;
      4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be issued with a pre-labelled container for the collection of an overnight&#xD;
      urine sample the night prior to visit V1 with written instruction as to how this should be&#xD;
      done. A sample will be collected prior to visits V2 and V3 as well.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a potential participant who at screening is receiving ≥200µg/day ICS (BDP) without&#xD;
      additional LABA has an ACQ &gt;1.0 they will directly enter the 4 week run-in period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At 2 weeks into the run-in period the participant will be contacted to reassess their ACQ&#xD;
      score. If their ACQ&gt;1.0 they will continue in the run-in period for the remaining 2 weeks at&#xD;
      the same dose of ICS. If their ACQ is not &gt;1.0 then their ICS dose will be approximately&#xD;
      halved (or reduced to a minimum of 200µg/day if this is greater than half the original ICS&#xD;
      dose) and one (if any) second line medication (e.g. theophylline, LTRA) will be discontinued&#xD;
      at the discretion of a study doctor. They will then restart the 4 week run-in period. If they&#xD;
      are already receiving 200µg/day ICS (i.e. the dose cannot be reduced further) then they will&#xD;
      be withdrawn from the study at this juncture.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the 4 week period if the participant still has an ACQ&gt;1.0 they will proceed to&#xD;
      visit V1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a potential participant who at screening is receiving ≥200µg/day ICS (BDP) with additional&#xD;
      LABA has an ACQ score &gt;1.0, their LABA will be discontinued and they will directly enter the&#xD;
      4 week run-in period. If the participant is receiving their LABA as part of a combination&#xD;
      inhaler, they will be converted to an equivalent ICS alone inhaler (i.e. coarse particle ICS)&#xD;
      and enter the 4 week run-in period. Progress through run-in will then be as described before.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a potential participant who at screening is receiving ≥200µg/day ICS (BDP) with additional&#xD;
      LABA has an ACQ not &gt;1.0, then their LABA will be discontinued as per 3.6.2 and their ICS&#xD;
      dose will be approximately halved (or reduced to a minimum of 200µg/day if this is greater&#xD;
      than half the original ICS dose). For example, Seretide 250µg b.i.d. would convert to&#xD;
      Flixotide 125µg b.i.d. They will subsequently enter the 4 week run-in period progressing&#xD;
      through it as described..&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked to perform and record twice daily domiciliary PEF and to complete&#xD;
      a daily diary of reliever use and symptoms from the beginning of the step-down/run-in period&#xD;
      through to the end of the study. Participants will be advised to contact the investigators if&#xD;
      they feel their asthma significantly worsening in the interim. They will also be given a card&#xD;
      with 24 hour emergency contact details.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the 4 week run-in period, participants will be checked against all inclusion&#xD;
      and exclusion criteria to confirm the subject's suitability to receive the study drug&#xD;
      according to study protocol. Those eligible will proceed to study visit 1. Those who do not&#xD;
      fulfil the study criteria will be returned to their pre-study medication and their GP&#xD;
      informed of any medically relevant data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study visits V1, V2 and V3 Full study visits will occur at the end of the run-in period&#xD;
      (baseline), at 4 weeks and 8 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked to withhold their reliever as per the screening visit. (LABAs are&#xD;
      withheld for the duration of the study).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will attend the unit on the morning of the visit day. The overnight urine&#xD;
      collection will be received from the participant for analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Peak flow records will be reviewed along with daily domiciliary symptom and reliever use&#xD;
      diaries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked to complete an ACQ and Mini-AQLQ. A venous blood sample will be&#xD;
      drawn for FBC. A venous blood sample will be drawn for ECP. FeNO, IOS, and spirometry will be&#xD;
      performed in that order. Mannitol bronchial challenge will then be performed&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be converted to Qvar (HFA-beclometasone) at an equivalent therapeutic dose&#xD;
      to their original ICS, e.g. Qvar 100µg = Clenil 200µg = Pulmicort 200µg = Flixotide 100µg =&#xD;
      Asmanex 100µg. A Qvar 50µg or 100µg inhaler will be used to achieve this based on the dose&#xD;
      requirement. An approximately equivalent inhaler device to the one the patient had been&#xD;
      originally using will be used. Equally if the participant normally used a spacer device with&#xD;
      their ICS, this will be provided to use with a Qvar pMDI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Participant Instruction and Appointment Leaflet will be issued, detailing:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Emergency contact numbers How to perform PEF How to write in the diary Record adverse events&#xD;
      and concomitant medication use Withholding times for drugs The Patient Instruction Leaflet&#xD;
      will be discussed fully with the subject and any questions answered&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be issued with a pre-labelled container for the collection of an overnight&#xD;
      urine sample the night prior to visits V2 and V3 respectively, with written instruction as to&#xD;
      how this should be done.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 2 (V2): Sections 3.7.2 to 3.7.10 and 3.7.13 will be repeated. Visit 3 (V3): Sections&#xD;
      3.7.2 to 3.7.10 will be repeated. The study will end at this point with the patient returned&#xD;
      to their prescribed medications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 28, 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 25, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 25, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Asthma Control Questionnaire score from post-run-in baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Impulse oscillometry</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Spirometry</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood eosinophilic cationic protein</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood eosinophils</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exhaled Nitric Oxide</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mannitol PD15</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overnight urinary cortisol/creatinine ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Domiciliary peak expiratory flow</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptoms and reliever use</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mini Asthma Quality of Life Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">26</enrollment>
  <condition>Asthma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Qvar® (beclometasone dipropionate HFA)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be converted to Qvar (HFA-beclometasone) at an equivalent therapeutic dose to their original inhaled corticosteroids. The treatment duration will for 8 weeks after a run-in period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Qvar® (beclometasone dipropionate HFA)</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be converted to Qvar (HFA-beclometasone) at an equivalent therapeutic dose to their original inhaled corticosteroids. The treatment duration will for 8 weeks after a run-in period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Qvar® (beclometasone dipropionate HFA)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and female volunteers aged 18-65, with persistent asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Asthma Control Questionnaire score &gt;1.0 (at end of run-in)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  FEV1 &gt;60% predicted&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  R5&gt;130% predicted and R5-R20&gt;0.03kPa/L/s&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to perform spirometry, impulse oscillometry, bronchial challenge and all&#xD;
             domiciliary measurements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Asthmatic patients receiving treatment at Step 2, 3, or 4 of British Thoracic Society&#xD;
             asthma guidelines&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to withhold long-acting beta-agonists for the duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients already receiving extra-fine particle inhaled corticosteroids (Qvar, Fostair,&#xD;
             Alvesco)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected sensitivity to the Investigational Medicinal Product&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to comply with protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any clinically significant medical conditions that may either endanger the health or&#xD;
             safety of the participant, or jeopardise the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An asthma exacerbation requiring systemic steroid therapy or lower respiratory tract&#xD;
             infection requiring antibiotics within 3 months prior to study commencement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in previous trial within 30 days&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Brian Lipworth, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Dundee</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>William Anderson, MBChB</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Dundee</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brian Lipworth</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dundee</city>
        <zip>DD1 3AU</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kuo CR, Jabbal S, Anderson W, Lipworth BJ. Pragmatic evaluation of inhaled corticosteroid particle size formulations on asthma control. Clin Exp Allergy. 2019 Oct;49(10):1321-1327. doi: 10.1111/cea.13453. Epub 2019 Aug 6.</citation>
    <PMID>31264282</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>September 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 2, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 2, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 9, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 6, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 6, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 9, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Dundee</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Brian J Lipworth</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Allergy and Immunology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>asthma control</keyword>
  <keyword>small airways</keyword>
  <keyword>extra-fine particle inhaled corticosteroids</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Beclomethasone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

