<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01893775</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999913148</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>13-C-N148</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01893775</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Antibody Treatment for Advanced Celiac Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I Study of the Humanized Mik-Beta-1 Monoclonal Antibody Directed Toward IL-2/IL-15R Beta (CD122) That Blocks IL-15 Action In Patients With Refractory Celiac Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Mayo Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Celiac disease is a condition where the immune system attacks the cells of the small&#xD;
      intestine. The intestine becomes inflamed and cannot digest food properly. The disease most&#xD;
      often causes a reaction to foods that contain gluten. Most people can treat celiac disease&#xD;
      with a gluten-free diet. However, some people have digestion problems even on a gluten-free&#xD;
      diet. Researchers want to try a new antibody therapy for celiac disease. The treatment may&#xD;
      block the immune reaction that causes the disease. They will test this antibody in people who&#xD;
      have celiac disease that has not responded to a gluten-free diet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To see if antibody therapy is a safe and effective treatment for celiac disease that has&#xD;
      not responded to standard treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Individuals at least 18 years of age who have been on a gluten-free diet for 6 to 12 months&#xD;
      but still have symptoms of celiac disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be screened with a physical exam and medical history. Blood samples&#xD;
           will be collected. These samples will help determine if the specific antibody treatment&#xD;
           is likely to work.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Before the start of the study, participants will have a biopsy of the small intestine.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will receive three doses of the study antibody as injections. These doses&#xD;
           will be given 3 weeks apart.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Treatment will be monitored with blood tests and heart function tests. Participants will&#xD;
           also have a second small intestine biopsy within a week after the last dose of the&#xD;
           antibody.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Celiac disease is a complex inflammatory disorder with an autoimmune component&#xD;
           characterized by a dramatic expansion of intraepithelial cytotoxic T lymphocytes that&#xD;
           usually regress on a gluten-free diet.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  It is estimated that approximately 10% of patients become refractory on a gluten-free&#xD;
           diet.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A subgroup of refractory celiac disease is characterized by expansion of a highly&#xD;
           oligoclonal intraepithelial T-lymphocyte population that exhibits a high risk of&#xD;
           developing enteropathy associated T-cell lymphoma (EATL).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  There is presently no effective therapy for refractory celiac disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A number of studies indicate that intestinal epithelial derived IL-15 plays a critical&#xD;
           role in the disrupted intraepithelial lymphocyte homeostasis and lymphomagenesis that&#xD;
           characterizes refractory celiac disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A pivotal role for IL-15 in refractory celiac disease and EATL is further supported by&#xD;
           the finding that in two murine models of celiac disease the pathognomonic features were&#xD;
           reversed completely by administration of an antibody to CD122 (IL-2/IL-15R beta) that&#xD;
           blocks IL-15 transpresentation and action.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A Phase I clinical trial in patients with T-cell LGL and hematocytopenia using the&#xD;
           monoclonal antibody, Hu-Mik-Beta-1 that blocks IL-15 action produced under cGMP&#xD;
           conditions by the BDP NCI has been completed in the Metabolism Branch, NCI at the&#xD;
           Clinical Center NIH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Phase I trial to define the safety of Hu-Mik-Beta-1 infusions to 2 groups of patients&#xD;
           each with refractory celiac disease at escalating 0.5 (7 patients) and 1.0 (2 patients)&#xD;
           mg/kg doses.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To define the clinical efficacy of Hu-Mik-Beta-1 infusions in 9 patients with refractory&#xD;
           celiac disease and to correlate these findings with celiac disease specific tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Definition of the receptor saturation capacity on CD122 (IL-2/IL-15R beta) of&#xD;
           intravenously administered Hu-Mik-Beta-1 administered at 0.5 and 1.0 mg/kg body weight&#xD;
           to 2 groups of patients on three occasions separated by 3 weeks in patients with&#xD;
           refractory celiac disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine the immunogenicity of intravenously administered Hu-Mik-Beta-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine the effects of Hu-Mik-Beta-1 on the phenotype and the state of activation of&#xD;
           the elements of the cellular immune system in the circulation and in intestinal biopsies&#xD;
           with special focus on the cells implicated in the pathogenesis of celiac disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with refractory celiac disease (RCD) defined by the following internationally&#xD;
           accepted criteria: persistent or recurrent symptoms (diarrhea, weight loss, and&#xD;
           abdominal pain) associated with intestinal damage characterized by partial to total&#xD;
           villous atrophy with intraepithelial lymphocytes (defined by &gt;25 intraepithelial&#xD;
           lymphocytes per 100 epithelial cells) despite strict adherence to a gluten-free diet for&#xD;
           6-12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Lack of antibodies to Hu-Mik-Beta-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients are not to have circulating antibodies to tissue transglutaminase that are&#xD;
           greater than 10 assay units using recombinant human transglutaminase antibodies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients will be enrolled and treated at the Mayo Clinic with the University of Chicago&#xD;
           and the Clinical Center at the NIH involved as laboratory sites. This is a nonrandomized&#xD;
           openlabel phase I trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In this phase I trial initial patients are enrolled to receive 0.5 mg/kg of&#xD;
           Hu-Mik-Beta-1 (3 patients). Patients receive Hu-Mik-Beta-1 every 3 weeks for a total of&#xD;
           3 doses (given on day 1, week 3 and week 6). At specific points in time the patients are&#xD;
           monitored (see below). If 1 or more of the 3 patients receiving 0.5 mg/kg of&#xD;
           Hu-Mik-Beta-1 experience a NCI CTCAE version 4.0 grade 3 or greater toxicity with the&#xD;
           exception of fatigue of &gt;4days duration possibly, probably or definitely related to the&#xD;
           infusion of Hu-Mik-Beta-1, subject enrollment and dosing is stopped.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At the completion of Week 9, the safety data are reviewed by the Principal Investigator&#xD;
           and DSMB. If the safety data in the 0.5 mg/kg cohort are acceptable, the Sponsor may&#xD;
           then enroll additional patients in doses greater than 0.5 mg/kg, evaluated in a similar&#xD;
           manner as the 0.5 mg/kg (e.g., 3 more patients to receive 1 mg/kg Hu-Mik-Beta-1 every 3&#xD;
           weeks for a total of 3 doses.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Modification: Three subjects completed study dosing with 0.5mg/kg without serious&#xD;
           adverse events. Two subjects were then randomized to 1.0mg/kg dose and both experienced&#xD;
           serious adverse events with a possible connection to the agent. Subject 5 experienced an&#xD;
           event during the study, acute diverticulitis associated with free intraperitoneal air&#xD;
           treated with antibiotics with resolution. Subject 4 who also received 1.0 mg / kg&#xD;
           experienced a colon perforation many months after completing dosing associated with&#xD;
           severe constipation. These events were reviewed by the DSMP. It was determined that even&#xD;
           though direct cause and effect cannot be established because these occurred in subjects&#xD;
           treated with the 1.0mg/kg that dose escalation be abandoned and the study completed with&#xD;
           the lowest dose used 0.5mg/Kg. This modification proposed that any further subjects be&#xD;
           recruited only at the 0.5mg/kg dose in the remaining 4 subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Monitoring:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - At specific points in time the following cardiac tests/studies are obtained, the results&#xD;
      reviewed prior to subsequent doses (at week 3 and week 6):&#xD;
&#xD;
      i. EKG at screening (Week -4 to 0), Day 1, Week 3, Week 6 and Week 7.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ii. CK-MB and troponin I at screening (Week -4 to 0), Day 1, Day 7, Week 3, Week 6, and Week&#xD;
      7.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, an echocardiogram at screening (Week -4 to 0) and Week 7.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  FACS of peripheral blood mononuclear cells and peroral intestinal biopsies for&#xD;
           expression of NKG2D, CD94, NKG2C, NKG2A, NKb44, NKb30, CD158 and granzyme.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Immune profiling on intestinal biopsies performed on the first infusion and one week +&#xD;
           or -3 days following the third infusion to analyze for CD8 T-cells, TCR gamma&#xD;
           rearrangements by multiplex PCR and fluorescence analysis of CD8 and CD3 expression,&#xD;
           high-resolution PCR expression for immunoglobulin gene rearrangement and for IEL, ERK&#xD;
           and JNK phosphorylation reflecting abnormal IEL activation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Furthermore, IL-15, IL-15R alpha and interferon alpha expression will be assayed in the&#xD;
           cells of the intestinal biopsy and in the serum.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  FACS of PBMCs with Hu-Mik-Beta-1 and Hu-Mik-Beta-3 to define saturation of CD122&#xD;
           (IL2/IL-15R beta).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Complete clinical response and by clinical biochemical results at the 20-week time&#xD;
           point.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Secondary partial response, duration of response, toxicities, immunogenicity of&#xD;
           Hu-Mik-Beta- 1.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 12, 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 20, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 20, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>safety of Hu MIK Beta 1 in celiac disease pts</measure>
    <time_frame>end of week 9</time_frame>
    <description>Events will be tabulated and reported by grade with evaluationalso of supportive medications and surrogate markers of absorptionsuch as body mass index, albumin and hemoglobin.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">5</enrollment>
  <condition>Celiac Disease</condition>
  <condition>Celiac Sprue</condition>
  <condition>Gluten Enteropathy</condition>
  <condition>Gluten-Sensitive Enteropathy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Hu-Mik-Beta-1 every 3 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hu-Mik- Beta-1</intervention_name>
    <description>Hu-Mik-Beta-1 every 3 weeks for a total of 3 doses (given on day 1, week 3 and week 6)</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.1.1 Patients must be greater than or equal to 18-years-old.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.1.2 All patients must have a pathologically confirmed diagnosis of refractory celiac&#xD;
        disease(RCD) defined by internationally accepted criteria of persistent and recurrent&#xD;
        symptoms(diarrhea, weight loss, and abdominal pain) associated with intestinal damage,&#xD;
        characterized by partial to total villous atrophy with intraepithelial lymphocytes defined&#xD;
        by &gt; 25 intraepithelial lymphocytes per 100 epithelial cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.1.3 Persistence of the above signs and symptoms despite strict adherence to a&#xD;
        gluten-free diet for 6-12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.1.4 Patients are to have had circulating antibodies to transglutaminase-1 or similar&#xD;
        celiac specific serology&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.1.5 Patients must have a life expectancy of &gt; 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.1.6 Patients must have a creatinine of less than 2.0 mg/dL or if the patient has an&#xD;
        elevated creatinine measured creatinine clearance (Ccr) must be &gt; 60 mL/min/1.73m(2)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.1.7 Patients must have a serum alkaline phosphatase, ALT (SGPT) and AST (SGOT) less&#xD;
        than 3x the upper limits of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.1.8 Patients must have a total bilirubin of less than 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.1.9 Women of childbearing potential must have a negative beta HCG pregnancy test at&#xD;
        initial screening and within 3 days prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.1.10 Patients receiving a stable dose (&gt; 4 weeks) of corticosteroid therapy equal to 20&#xD;
        mg of prednisone per day or less are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.1.11 Patients with a history of curatively treated basal cell carcinoma or&#xD;
        intraepithelial neoplasia of the uterine surface will be allowed on the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.1.12 Patients must be able to understand and sign an informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.1 Patients enrolled in another therapeutic study&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.2 Patients with a history of venous thrombosis&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.3 Patients with antibodies to Hu-Mik-Beta-1&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.4 A contraindication to monoclonal antibody therapy including adverse events related&#xD;
        to prior monoclonal antibody therapy. Patients who have received prior antibody therapy&#xD;
        will have permanent medical records reviewed by the study investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.5 Any uncontrolled or chronic bacterial, mycobacterial or other viral (e.g., herpes&#xD;
        virus), fungal, parasitic or protozoal infection&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.6 History of malignancy (active or within the previous 5 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.7 Patients with HIV infection (antibody positive) with positive confirmatory&#xD;
        molecular tests&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.8 Patients who have chronic hepatitis B or chronic hepatitis C&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.9 Pregnant or breastfeeding women. Women who not using an acceptable method of&#xD;
        contraception. Acceptability of various methods of contraception will be determined by the&#xD;
        investigator. Postmenopausal or surgically sterile women who have documentation of&#xD;
        postmenopausal status or surgical sterility availability prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.10 Patients with significant co-morbidities including uncontrolled hypertension&#xD;
        (diastolic B/P &gt; 115 mm/Hg), unstable angina, congestive heart failure (&gt; N.Y.H.A. Class&#xD;
        II), poorly controlled diabetes, severe chronic pulmonary disease, coronary angioplasty or&#xD;
        myocardial infarction within the last 6 months or uncontrolled atrial or ventricular&#xD;
        cardiac arrhythmias.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.11 Abnormal screening/baseline tests exceeding the limits outlined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total white blood cell count (WBC) &lt;300/mm(3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &lt;85,000/mm(3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  INR greater than or equal to 1.5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine level &gt; 1.5 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum alanine transaminase, aspartate transaminase or creatinine kinase &gt; 2 x the&#xD;
             upper limits of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.12 Patients with a history of a psychiatric disorder that may interfere with the&#xD;
        understanding and compliance with this protocol, and the required follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.13 Exclusion at the discretion of the PI or delegate if participation in the study is&#xD;
        deemed too risky (e.g., clinically significant pleural or pericardial effusion or ascites)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.14 Inability to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        2.1.2.15 History of diverticulitis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas A Waldmann, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic, Rochester</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Trier JS. Celiac sprue. N Engl J Med. 1991 Dec 12;325(24):1709-19. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>1944472</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ryan BM, Kelleher D. Refractory celiac disease. Gastroenterology. 2000 Jul;119(1):243-51. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>10889175</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cellier C, Delabesse E, Helmer C, Patey N, Matuchansky C, Jabri B, Macintyre E, Cerf-Bensussan N, Brousse N. Refractory sprue, coeliac disease, and enteropathy-associated T-cell lymphoma. French Coeliac Disease Study Group. Lancet. 2000 Jul 15;356(9225):203-8.</citation>
    <PMID>10963198</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 20, 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 23, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 2, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 9, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 16, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 16, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 18, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Anti CD 122</keyword>
  <keyword>Monoclonal Antibody Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Autoimmune Inflammatory Enteropathy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Celiac Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Intestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

