<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00981708</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RV-178</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00981708</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lenalidomide, Dexamethasone and Cyclophosphamide in Amyloidosis (AL)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I/II Trial of Lenalidomide Combined With Cyclophosphamide and Intermediate Dose Dexamethasone in Patients With Primary (AL) Systemic Amyloidosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Athens</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hellenic Cooperative Oncology Group</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Athens</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the safety and activity of the combination of&#xD;
      lenalidomide with intermediate dose dexamethasone and cyclophosphamide in patients with&#xD;
      primary systemic (AL ) amyloidosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Primary systemic amyloidosis (AL) is a plasma cell dyscrasia where amyloid fibrils are formed&#xD;
      by monoclonal immunoglobulin light chains and deposit in various organs causing tissue damage&#xD;
      and dysfunction. It is a rare disease with an incidence of 8 patients per million per year.&#xD;
      Virtually all patients die of this disease with a median survival of 12-18 months and less&#xD;
      than approximately 5% surviving 10 years. The current therapeutic approach to systemic&#xD;
      amyloidosis is based on the observation that amyloid deposits can be reabsorbed and organ&#xD;
      function can be restored if the concentration of the amyloidogenic precursor is reduced. The&#xD;
      recognized standard treatment for patients with amyloidosis is alkylating agent-based&#xD;
      chemotherapy - some selected patients can be treated with high dose melphalan with autologous&#xD;
      stem cell transplantation. Recent studies have led to an improved understanding of the&#xD;
      biology of plasma cells. Interactions between the bone marrow microenvironment and plasma&#xD;
      cells have a critical growth regulating influence on myeloma cells. Thalidomide has shown&#xD;
      significant activity in multiple myeloma patients with relapsing or refractory disease and&#xD;
      even more in newly diagnosed patients. However, thalidomide causes somnolence, fatigue,&#xD;
      constipation, and peripheral neuropathy and is not well tolerated in patients with AL&#xD;
      amyloidosis. Lenalidomide is a small molecule structurally related to thalidomide with potent&#xD;
      immunomodulatory effects. Lenalidomide has been found to be significantly active in relapsed&#xD;
      multiple myeloma both in vitro and in Phase I, II and III clinical trials, including patients&#xD;
      who had previously failed thalidomide. Unlike thalidomide, lenalidomide causes no significant&#xD;
      sedation, constipation, neuropathy, or rash. Deep vein thrombosis ,especially in combination&#xD;
      with dexamethasone, has been reported . Combination of thalidomide with with alkylating&#xD;
      agents (such as melphalan or cyclophosphamide) have been very active in patients with myeloma&#xD;
      and have superior activity than combinations of alkylating agents with steroids alone.&#xD;
      However, the toxicity profile of thalidomide is problematic for this combination in patients&#xD;
      with AL. combinations of lenalidomide with alkylating agents (Melphalan + prednisone&#xD;
      +Lenalidomide)are feasible and very active in patients with multiple myeloma.&#xD;
      Cyclophosphamide has a more favorable toxicity profile than melphalan when used in oral&#xD;
      combinations with dexamethasone and thalidomide. However, given the remarkable antimyeloma&#xD;
      activity of lenalidomide, overall improved toxicity profile of lenalidomide compared with&#xD;
      thalidomide and a need for improved treatments for this incurable malignancy, the&#xD;
      combinations of lenalidomide are worthy of study. Preliminary data from Mayo clinic using&#xD;
      CC-5013 and dexamethasone demonstrates that lenalidomide is tolerable and has activity in&#xD;
      patients with AL amyloidosis and may be useful in patients with AL amyloidosis who either are&#xD;
      not candidates for high dose chemotherapy and peripheral blood stem cell transplantation or&#xD;
      who have failed prior therapies. Efficacy and tolerability of oral cyclophosphamide ,&#xD;
      combined with dexamethasone and thalidomide, is well documented in patients with refractory&#xD;
      or relapsed multiple myeloma while this combination has been used in patients with AL&#xD;
      amyloidosis . Intermediate dose dexamethasone is tolerable and without significant toxicity&#xD;
      in patients with AL amyloidosis . The combination of alkylating agents with thalidomide and&#xD;
      dexamethasone has been effective in patients with AL amyloidosis . The combination of an&#xD;
      alkylating agent with Lenalidomide and intermediate dose dexamethasone may lead to more rapid&#xD;
      hematologic responses than either agent alone , and subsequently may lead to increased organ&#xD;
      response rates . Therefore, in this phase I/II trial we explore the safety and efficacy of&#xD;
      the combination of the alkylating agent cyclophosphamide to lenalidomide and intermediate&#xD;
      dose dexamethasone in patients who are no candidates for high dose melphalan chemotherapy&#xD;
      with autologous stem cell transplantation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 11, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 11, 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the maximum tolerated dose of lenalidomide and cyclophosphamide and assess the hematologic response rate of the combination of Cyclophosphamide/Dexamethasone plus lenalidomide in patients with AL amyloidosis.</measure>
    <time_frame>At month 2 for assesment of maximum tolerated dose and monthly for hematologic response</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum Tolerated Dose</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the toxicity of Cyclophosphamide/Dexamethasone plus lenalidomide combination in patients with AL amyloidosis and organ response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Monthly for toxicity and every 3-6 months for organ response</time_frame>
    <description>Toxicity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">37</enrollment>
  <condition>Amyloidosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Lenalidomide, Dexamethasone and cyclophosphamide</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lenalidomide, Dexamethasone and Cyclophosphamide</intervention_name>
    <description>Lenalidomide capsules on days 1 to 21. the dose starts at 5 mg/day up to 25 mg/day.&#xD;
Dexamethasone tablets on days 1 to 4. Dose 20 mg per day.&#xD;
Cyclophosphamide tablets on days 1 to 10. The dose starts at 50 mg per day up to 100 mg per day.&#xD;
The cycle is to be repeated every 28 days (4 weeks)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Revlimid</other_name>
    <other_name>Endoxan</other_name>
    <other_name>Dexamethasone</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Understand and voluntarily sign an informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age &gt;=18 years at the time of signing the informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Able to adhere to the study visit schedule and other protocol requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Confirmed diagnosis of AL amyloidosis (see appendix 3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Need for treatment in the judgment of their treating physician&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Evaluable or measurable disease defined by any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Measurable serum free light chains &gt;= 10 mg/dL, kappa or lambda, provided&#xD;
                  kappa/lambda ratio is abnormal (measurable disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Monoclonal protein in the serum &gt;= 1 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. ECOG Performance Status (PS) 0, 1, 2 or 3&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Laboratory test results within these ranges:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1.5 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count &gt;= 100 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine &gt;= 2.5 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin &gt;= 1.5 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST (SGOT) and ALT (SGPT) &gt; 2 x ULN or &gt; 5 x ULN if hepatic metastases are&#xD;
                  present.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Women of childbearing potential (WCBP)† must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy&#xD;
             test with a sensitivity of at least 50 mIU/mL 10 - 14 days prior to therapy and&#xD;
             repeated within 24 hours of starting study drug and must begin TWO acceptable methods&#xD;
             of birth control, one highly effective method and one additional effective method AT&#xD;
             THE SAME TIME, at least 4 weeks before she starts taking lenalidomide. Women must also&#xD;
             agree to ongoing pregnancy testing. Men must agree not to father a child and agree to&#xD;
             use a condom if his partner is of child bearing potential. (See Appendix 1 Pregnancy&#xD;
             Testing Guidelines and Acceptable Birth Control Methods.)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Disease free of prior malignancies for &gt;= 5 years with exception of currently treated&#xD;
             basal cell, squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, or carcinoma &quot;in situ&quot; of the cervix&#xD;
             or breast&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Able to take aspirin (81 or 325 mg) daily as prophylactic anticoagulation. (patients&#xD;
             intolerant to ASA may use low molecular weight heparin).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with symptomatic multiple myeloma with asymptomatic biopsy confirmed AL&#xD;
             amyloidosis (Appendix 3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any serious medical condition, laboratory abnormality, or psychiatric illness that&#xD;
             would prevent the subject from signing the informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pregnant or breast feeding females. (Lactating females must agree not to breast feed&#xD;
             while taking lenalidomide).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Any condition, including the presence of laboratory abnormalities, which places the&#xD;
             subject at unacceptable risk if he/she were to participate in the study or confounds&#xD;
             the ability to interpret data from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Use of any other experimental drug or therapy within 28 days of baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Known hypersensitivity to thalidomide.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The development of erythema nodosum if characterized by a desquamating rash while&#xD;
             taking thalidomide or similar drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any prior use of lenalidomide.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Concurrent use of other anti-cancer agents or treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Known positive for HIV or infectious hepatitis, type A, B or C.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. &gt; grade 2 peripheral neuropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Life expectancy &lt; 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Concurrent use of steroids (Patients may receive prednisone up to 20 mg/d, or&#xD;
             equivalent corticosteroids for concurrent illness or adrenal replacement therapy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Meletios A Dimopoulos, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Athens, School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alexandra Hospital , Department of Clinical Therapeutics</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <state>Attica</state>
        <zip>115 28</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 19, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 21, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 22, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Athens</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Meletios A. Dimopoulos</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Amyloidosis</keyword>
  <keyword>lenalidomide</keyword>
  <keyword>newly diagnosed</keyword>
  <keyword>relapsed</keyword>
  <keyword>primary systemic AL amyloidosis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Amyloidosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lenalidomide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

