<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03342976</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PHC21-2015-689592</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03342976</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Investigating My Active and Healthy Aging</brief_title>
  <acronym>my-AHA</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of an ICT-based Platform for Early Detection and Intervention to Prevent Frailty in Older Adults</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Turin, Italy</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Turin, Italy</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter, multicultural, randomized control trial. Participants will be&#xD;
      recruited from 10 centers located in Italy, Germany, Austria, Spain, United Kingdom, Belgium,&#xD;
      Sweden, Japan, South Korea and Australia. The main objective of the study is to examine the&#xD;
      efficacy of a sensor-based platform (my-AHA platform) to assess frailty risks and to deliver&#xD;
      tailored interventions in order to prevent in elderly subjects conversion from a pre-frail&#xD;
      status to a frailty status.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In the past decade, frailty has attracted great attention of the scientific community and&#xD;
      public health organizations as precursor and contributor of age-related diseases. Frailty is&#xD;
      a common clinical syndrome in older adults, affecting 7-12% of the older population, and the&#xD;
      occurrence of frailty increases with age and may exceed 45% after age 85 years. Frailty&#xD;
      develops when age-associated degenerative processes overwhelm reserve capacity and reparative&#xD;
      processes that maintain function of the nervous system as well as other physiologic systems.&#xD;
      Overall, frailty consists in the vulnerability of aged population to adverse events as the&#xD;
      result of the subtle and progressive metabolic and physical changes. Frailty confers a&#xD;
      significantly increased risk for poor health outcomes, incident disability, hospitalization,&#xD;
      and mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In recent years there has been an emergence of information and communication technology (ICT)&#xD;
      -based solutions to support active ageing and tackle frailty, cognitive decline and social&#xD;
      isolation of older adults. While these ICT-based solutions are of a certain value regarding&#xD;
      diminishing single risks (e.g. fall risk, etc.), there is still a need for a more holistic&#xD;
      approach which aims to address all of the individual risk factors together. Also it is&#xD;
      necessary to provide tailored interventions based on the outcomes of the risk analysis. This&#xD;
      assessment of risk for frailty and provision of individual tailored interventions is the main&#xD;
      objective of My-AHA project.&#xD;
&#xD;
      My-AHA solution supports active and healthy ageing by enabling early detection and&#xD;
      minimization of risks associated with ageing. In these terms the early risk detection&#xD;
      considers three fundamental aspects of the life of older adults: physical activity (by&#xD;
      considering vital signs data, gait, quality of sleep and in general, physical activity, and&#xD;
      fall risk); cognitive activity (by monitor the cognitive level, e.ge.g. in cognitive games);&#xD;
      and, psychosocial activities (e.g. by analyzing the emotions and the quality of speech of the&#xD;
      users). On the other hand, My-AHA will develop and implement more efficient and effective&#xD;
      ICT-based interventions tailored to the early identified risks. The suggested social&#xD;
      activities, as well as cognitive and physical trainings and the diet proposed to the older&#xD;
      adults via the new platform will help the users in changing their behaviour and in reacting&#xD;
      to the consequences of ageing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 3, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Conversion rate from a pre-frail status to a frail status (Fried criteria)</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of conversion rate in cases and controls between pre-frail status fo frail status</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Frail Elderly Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Cognitive Impairment</condition>
  <condition>Physical Dependence</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cases</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pre-frail subjects will use an ICT platform (my-AHA platform) embedded in a mobile phone and a fit-band that will continuously monitor physical and cognitive activities.&#xD;
Interventions regarding physical, cognitive, psychological and social domains will be prescribed and monitored through the my-AHA platform. In addition, sleep and dietary habits will be investigated and tailored interventions will be suggested.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Controls</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pre-frail subjects will be followed according to &quot;best standard of care&quot; protocols. Interventions regarding physical, cognitive, psychological and social domains will be prescribed. In addition, sleep and dietary habits will be investigated and tailored interventions will be suggested.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>My-AHA platform</intervention_name>
    <description>ICT strategy for early detection of frailties</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cases</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Controls</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION CRITERIA for pre-screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age: over 60 yrs&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able to stand and walk unassisted&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Free of significant cognitive impairment (age-corrected Mini Mental State Examination&#xD;
             Test ≥ 24)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Free of clinically significant mood disturbance (HADS-Anxiety &lt;15; HADS-depression &lt;&#xD;
             15)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Free of any acute or unstable medical conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Able to understand directions and participate in the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Able to sign informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects will be enrolled in the study if they meet one or two of the Fried et al. (2001)&#xD;
        criteria for Frailty (Pre-Frailty status).&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Shrinking, evidenced by weight loss (unintentional) ≥ 4.5 kg unintentional in prior 12&#xD;
        months; or at follow-up assessment ≥ 5% of body weight in prior 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2, Weakness. Grip strength in lowest 20% at baseline adjusted for gender and BMI.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Poor endurance and energy. Self-report of exhaustion as indicated by responses to 2&#xD;
        questions on Center for Epidemiologic Studies Depression (CES-D) scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Slowness .Time to walk 15ft (4.57m) ≤ slowest 20% adjusted for gender and standing&#xD;
        height.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Low physical activity level. Lowest quintile (25%) by gender for weighted kcal&#xD;
        expenditure per week at baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participant excluded if meets 1 or more of below:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Mobility problems&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. cannot stand and ambulate unassisted&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. painful arthritis, spinal stenosis, amputation, or painful foot lesions that limits&#xD;
             balance and mobility,&#xD;
&#xD;
        Concurrent chronic disease independently contributing to frailty&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. suffers from a significant neurodegenerative disorder, e.g.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Alzheimer's disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Lewy body dementia&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration, Fronto-Temporal Dementia&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Parkinson's disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. multiple sclerosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. progressive supranuclear palsy&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. hydrocephalus&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Huntington's disease&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. prion diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. affected by severe peripheral nervous system and/or neuromuscular disorders, e.g.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. myasthenia gravis&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. multiple sclerosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. polymyositis&#xD;
&#xD;
        Concomitant injury or disease known&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. clinical evidence or history of stroke (within 2 yrs) to impact independently&#xD;
             cognitive,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. clinical evidence or history of transient ischemic attack (within 6 months)&#xD;
             psychological or physical function&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. significant head injury with associated loss of consciousness, skull fracture or&#xD;
             persisting cognitive impairment (2 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. epilepsy (a single prior seizure is considered acceptable)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. if meet Diagnostic and Statistical Manual 5 (DSM-5) criteria for:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. major depressive disorder (current)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. schizophrenia or other psychotic disorders (lifetime)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. bipolar disorder (within the past 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. substance (including alcohol) related disorders (within the past 2 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Presence of cognitive, sensory or&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. have language deficits that impair testing perceptual deficits that interfere with&#xD;
             assessment tasks&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. have significant visual impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. have a significant hearing loss&#xD;
&#xD;
        Presence of other conditions or diseases that will compromise ability to undertake&#xD;
        interventions (especially physical)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. have clinically significant cardiovascular disease, i.e:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. hospitalization for acute coronary syndrome (acute myocardial infarction or&#xD;
                  unstable, angina)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. symptoms consistent with angina pectoris, within the 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. signs or symptoms of clinical heart failure within the 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. evidence of uncontrolled atrial fibrillation&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. a cardiac pacemaker&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. preexisting or current signs or symptoms of respiratory failure, e.g.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. chronic obstructive pulmonary disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. bronchial asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. lung fibrosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. other respiratory disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. untreated hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. metastatic cancer or immunosuppressive therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. concurrent acute or chronic clinically significant immunologic, hepatic (such as&#xD;
             presence of encephalopathy or ascites), or endocrine disease (not adequately treated).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Unacceptable Test/Laboratory Values&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Postural hypotension (fall in systolic blood pressure of greater than 30 mmHg or fall in&#xD;
        diastolic blood pressure of greater than 20 mmHg on standing compared to sitting) at the&#xD;
        time of screening. Subjects who present at the time of screening with postural hypotension&#xD;
        yet have no known history of postural hypotension, nor underlying medical condition related&#xD;
        to hypotension, may be rescreened&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Georg Aumayr, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Johanniter International</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Helios De Rosario, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>IBV-Gesmed, Spain</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mathew Summers, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Sunshine Coast University, Australia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Innocenzo Rainero, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+39-011-091</phone>
    <phone_ext>974</phone_ext>
    <email>innocenzo.rainero@unito.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Marcella Caglio, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+39-011-633</phone>
    <phone_ext>4763</phone_ext>
    <email>marcella.caglio@unito.it</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aging Brain and Memory Clinic, Department of Neuroscience, University of Torino</name>
      <address>
        <city>Torino</city>
        <zip>10126</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Innocenzo Rainero, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+39-011-633</phone>
      <phone_ext>4763</phone_ext>
      <email>innocenzo.rainero@unito.it</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Elisa Rubino, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+39-011-633</phone>
      <phone_ext>4763</phone_ext>
      <email>elisa.rubino@unito.it</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Choi J, Ahn A, Kim S, Won CW. Global Prevalence of Physical Frailty by Fried's Criteria in Community-Dwelling Elderly With National Population-Based Surveys. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2015 Jul 1;16(7):548-50. doi: 10.1016/j.jamda.2015.02.004. Epub 2015 Mar 14. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25783624</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kojima G, Taniguchi Y, Iliffe S, Walters K. Frailty as a Predictor of Alzheimer Disease, Vascular Dementia, and All Dementia Among Community-Dwelling Older People: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2016 Oct 1;17(10):881-8. doi: 10.1016/j.jamda.2016.05.013. Epub 2016 Jun 17. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27324809</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shamliyan T, Talley KM, Ramakrishnan R, Kane RL. Association of frailty with survival: a systematic literature review. Ageing Res Rev. 2013 Mar;12(2):719-36. doi: 10.1016/j.arr.2012.03.001. Epub 2012 Mar 12. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22426304</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Panza F, Solfrizzi V, Frisardi V, Maggi S, Sancarlo D, Adante F, D'Onofrio G, Seripa D, Pilotto A. Different models of frailty in predementia and dementia syndromes. J Nutr Health Aging. 2011 Aug;15(8):711-9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21968870</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fried LP, Tangen CM, Walston J, Newman AB, Hirsch C, Gottdiener J, Seeman T, Tracy R, Kop WJ, Burke G, McBurnie MA; Cardiovascular Health Study Collaborative Research Group. Frailty in older adults: evidence for a phenotype. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2001 Mar;56(3):M146-56.</citation>
    <PMID>11253156</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 22, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 14, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 9, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 9, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 11, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Turin, Italy</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Prof. Innocenzo Rainero</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Neurology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Frailty</keyword>
  <keyword>Physical impairment</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognitive decline</keyword>
  <keyword>ICT</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cognitive Dysfunction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>October 22, 2017</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/76/NCT03342976/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

