<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03343626</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ZIK-101</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>U1111-1201-5778</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03343626</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety, Immunogenicity and Dose Ranging Study of Inactivated Zika Virus Vaccine in Healthy Adult Participants</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1, Randomized, Observer-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Safety, Immunogenicity, and Dose Ranging Study of Purified Inactivated Zika Virus Vaccine (PIZV) Candidate in Flavivirus Naïve and Primed Healthy Adults Aged 18 to 49 Years</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Takeda</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Takeda</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to describe the safety, tolerability and immunogenicity of two&#xD;
      doses of purified inactivated Zika virus vaccine (PIZV) given 28 days apart. Three different&#xD;
      vaccine doses containing different protein concentrations (2, 5 or 10 microgram [mcg]) each,&#xD;
      will be given as 2 dose schedule to flavivirus naive and primed healthy adults. Participants&#xD;
      will be followed for 7 days post each dose for tolerability and up to 6 months post dose 2&#xD;
      for safety. Immunogenicity assessment will be performed at 28 days post each dose and 6&#xD;
      months post dose 2. In addition, the selected dose group and control group will be followed&#xD;
      till 24 months post dose 2 for safety and persistence of immunity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The vaccine being tested in this study is called PIZV or TAK-426 adjuvanted with aluminum&#xD;
      hydroxide. The Zika virus vaccine is being tested to provide safety and immunogenicity data&#xD;
      to enable the vaccine to be further developed clinically.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will enroll approximately 240 participants. Participants will be randomly assigned&#xD;
      (by chance, like flipping a coin) to one of the four groups-which will remain undisclosed to&#xD;
      the study observer:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Placebo&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  PIZV: 2 microgram (mcg) Low Dose&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  PIZV: 5 mcg Medium Dose&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  PIZV: 10 mcg High Dose&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will be administered either placebo or PIZV by intramuscular (IM) injection&#xD;
      into the middle third of the deltoid muscle, preferably in the non-dominant arm on Days 1&#xD;
      (Visit 1) and 29 (Visit 4).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This multi-center trial will be conducted in the United States and Puerto Rico. The overall&#xD;
      time to participate in this study is up to 25 months. Participants will make multiple visits&#xD;
      to the clinic on Days 1, 8, 29, 36, 57, 211, 393 and will be contacted by telephone on Day&#xD;
      133 (Visit 7) and Day 575 (Visit 9) and also visit the clinic on Day 757 (Visit 11) depending&#xD;
      on the study arm, for a final follow-up assessment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 13, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 24, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 28, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Solicited Local Injection Site Reactions Within 7 Days After Dose 1 of PIZV or Placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 7 Days after Dose 1 (Day 8)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Solicited Local Injection Site Reactions Within 7 Days After Dose 2 of PIZV or Placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 7 Days after Dose 2 (Day 36)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Solicited Systemic Adverse Events (AEs) Within 7 Days After Dose 1 of PIZV or Placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 7 Days after Dose 1 (Day 8)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Solicited Systemic AEs Within 7 Days After Dose 2 of PIZV or Placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 7 Days after Dose 2 (Day 36)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants who Experience at Least one Non-serious Unsolicited AE Within 28 Days After Dose 1 of PIZV or Placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 28 Days after Dose 1 (Day 29)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants who Experience at Least one Non-serious Unsolicited AE Within 28 Days After Dose 2 of PIZV or Placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 28 Days after Dose 2 (Day 57)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants who Experience at Least one Serious Adverse Event (SAE) Within 28 Days After Dose 1 of PIZV or Placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 28 Days after Dose 1 (Day 29)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants who Experience at Least one Serious Adverse Event (SAE) Within 28 Days After Dose 2 of PIZV or Placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 28 Days after Dose 2 (Day 57)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Neutralizing Antibody Titers (GMTs) of Zika Virus (ZIKV) 28 Days After Dose 2 of PIZV or Placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>28 Days after Dose 2 (Day 57)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants who Experience at Least one SAE During the Study</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to Day 393</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Neutralizing Antibody Titers (GMTs) of ZIKV 28-days After Dose 1, 6, 12 and 24-months After Dose 2 in Applicable Groups</measure>
    <time_frame>28 Days after Dose 1 (Day 29); 6 Months after Dose 2 (Day 211); 12 Months after Dose 2 (Day 393) 24 months after Dose 2 (Day 757)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Seropositivity Rate for PIZV 28 Days After Dose 1, 28 Days After Dose 2, 6 Months, 12 Months and 24 Months After Dose 2 in Applicable Groups</measure>
    <time_frame>28 Days after Dose 1 (Day 29); 28 Days after Dose 2 (Day 57); 6 Months after Dose 2 (Day 211); 12 Months after Dose 2 (Day 393); 24 months after Dose 2 (Day 757)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Seroconversion Rate for PIZV 28 Days Post Dose 1 and 2</measure>
    <time_frame>28 Days after Dose 1 (Day 29); 28 Days after Dose 2 (Day 57)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">271</enrollment>
  <condition>Virus, Zika</condition>
  <condition>Zika Virus Disease</condition>
  <condition>Flavivirus Infections</condition>
  <condition>Healthy Participants</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAK-426 placebo-matching injection, intramuscular, once on Days 1 and 29.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Low Dose: PIZV 2 microgram (mcg)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>PIZV 0.5 milliliter (mL), 2 mcg antigen, injection, intramuscular, once on Days 1 and 29.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Medium Dose: PIZV 5 mcg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>PIZV 0.5 mL, 5 mcg antigen, injection, intramuscular, once on Days 1 and 29.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>High Dose: PIZV 10 mcg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>PIZV 0.5 mL, 10 mcg antigen, injection, intramuscular, once on Days 1 and 29.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>PIZV placebo-matching saline solution.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PIZV</intervention_name>
    <description>Purified inactivated Zika virus vaccine with aluminum hydroxide adjuvant.</description>
    <arm_group_label>High Dose: PIZV 10 mcg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Low Dose: PIZV 2 microgram (mcg)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Medium Dose: PIZV 5 mcg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>TAK-426</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participants who are in good health at the time of entry into the trial as determined&#xD;
             by medical history, physical examination (including vital signs) and eligibility&#xD;
             screening tests (hematology, biochemistry and urinalysis) and clinical judgment of the&#xD;
             investigator. Vital signs must be within normal limits (ie, below Grade 1 as specified&#xD;
             in the Food and Drug Administration [FDA] Toxicity Grading Scale for Healthy Adult and&#xD;
             Adolescent Volunteers). Screening tests must be within normal limits or not be above&#xD;
             Grade 1 as defined in the FDA Toxicity Grading Scale for Healthy Adult and Adolescent&#xD;
             Volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participants who can comply with trial procedures and are available for the duration&#xD;
             of follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. All female participants must be willing to undergo serum beta human chorionic&#xD;
             gonadotropin (B-hCG) pregnancy test and must test negative by urine pregnancy test&#xD;
             prior to each study vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participants and participants' partners with confirmed Zika virus (ZIKV) infection by&#xD;
             self-report.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Traveling to flavivirus endemic countries or flavivirus endemic regions of the United&#xD;
             States (US) or US territories*, within 4 weeks prior to screening or planned travel&#xD;
             through to Visit 6 (applicable only to participants to be enrolled into the flavivirus&#xD;
             naive cohort).&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) website define the information&#xD;
             about the flavivirus endemic countries and US regions and territories.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Known hypersensitivity or allergy to any of the vaccine candidate components&#xD;
             (including excipients of the investigational vaccine or placebo).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Has any history of progressive or severe neurologic disorder, seizure disorder or&#xD;
             neuro-inflammatory disease (example, Guillain-Barré syndrome).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Known or suspected impairment/alteration of immune function, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chronic use of oral steroids (equivalent to 20 milligram per day [mg/day]&#xD;
                  prednisone greater than or equal to [&gt;=] 12 weeks / &gt;= 2 milligram per kilogram&#xD;
                  [mg/kg] body weight / day prednisone &gt;= 2 weeks) within 60 days prior to Day 1&#xD;
                  (use of inhaled, intranasal, or topical corticosteroids is allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Receipt of parenteral steroids (equivalent to 20 mg/day prednisone &gt;= 12 weeks /&#xD;
                  &gt;= 2 mg/kg body weight / day prednisone &gt;= 2 weeks) within 60 days prior to Day&#xD;
                  1.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Receipt of immunostimulants within 60 days prior to Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Receipt of parenteral, epidural or intra-articular immunoglobulin preparation,&#xD;
                  blood products, and/or plasma derived products within 3 months prior to Day 1 or&#xD;
                  planned during the full length of the trial. In addition, participants must be&#xD;
                  advised not to donate blood during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Known Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) infection or HIV-related disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Genetic immunodeficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Has known current or chronic hepatitis B and/or hepatitis C infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Has abnormalities of spleen or thymic function.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Has a known bleeding diathesis, or any condition that may be associated with a&#xD;
             prolonged bleeding time.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Individuals participating in any clinical trial with another investigational product,&#xD;
             including ZIKV vaccine clinical trial within 30 days prior to first trial visit or&#xD;
             intent to participate in another clinical trial at any time during the conduct of this&#xD;
             trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Individuals who received any other vaccines within 14 days (for inactivated vaccines)&#xD;
             or 28 days (for live vaccines) prior to enrollment in this trial or who are planning&#xD;
             to receive any vaccine within 28 days of investigational vaccine/placebo&#xD;
             administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Female participants who are pregnant or breastfeeding, or are planning to become&#xD;
             pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Any positive or indeterminate pregnancy test.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. If female participant of childbearing potential, sexually active, and who has not used&#xD;
             any of the &quot;acceptable contraceptive methods&quot; for at least 2 months prior to trial&#xD;
             entry:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  &quot;Of childbearing potential&quot; is defined as status post onset of menarche and not&#xD;
                  meeting any of the following conditions: menopausal for at least 2 years without&#xD;
                  any other alternative medical cause (as confirmed by a healthcare professional),&#xD;
                  status after bilateral tubal ligation for at least 1 year, status after bilateral&#xD;
                  oophorectomy, or status after hysterectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acceptable birth control methods are defined as one or more of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Hormonal contraceptive (such as oral, injection, transdermal patch, implant,&#xD;
                       cervical ring).&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Barrier (condom with spermicide or diaphragm with spermicide) each and every&#xD;
                       time during intercourse.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Intrauterine device.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Monogamous relationship with vasectomized partner. Partner must have been&#xD;
                       vasectomized for at least six months prior to the participants' trial entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. If female participant of childbearing potential and sexually active, refusal to use an&#xD;
             &quot;acceptable contraceptive method&quot; from trial entry through 2 months after the last&#xD;
             dose of investigational vaccine/placebo. In addition female participants of&#xD;
             childbearing potential must be advised not to donate ova during this period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. To avoid sexual transmission of ZIKV from natural exposure: Refusal to use latex&#xD;
             condoms correctly and consistently by sexually active participants even if other&#xD;
             contraceptive measures are used from signing the informed consent form (ICF) through&#xD;
             the end of the trial. Male participants must be advised not to donate sperm during&#xD;
             this period.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Takeda</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Research of South Florida</name>
      <address>
        <city>Coral Gables</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33134</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Miami Research Associates</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33143</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AppleMed Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33155</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johnson County Clin-Trials</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lenexa</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66219</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Regional Clinical Research Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Endwell</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>13760</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rochester Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>14609</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tekton Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78745</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Puerto Rico Clinical and Translational Research Consortium</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Juan</city>
        <zip>00936</zip>
        <country>Puerto Rico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ponce Medical School Foundation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santurce</city>
        <zip>00909</zip>
        <country>Puerto Rico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Puerto Rico</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 13, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 13, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Drug therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Virus Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Zika Virus Infection</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Flavivirus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Takeda provides access to the de-identified individual participant data (IPD) for eligible studies to aid qualified researchers in addressing legitimate scientific objectives (Takeda's data sharing commitment is available on https://clinicaltrials.takeda.com/takedas-commitment?commitment=5). These IPDs will be provided in a secure research environment following approval of a data sharing request, and under the terms of a data sharing agreement.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_access_criteria>IPD from eligible studies will be shared with qualified researchers according to the criteria and process described on https://vivli.org/ourmember/takeda/. For approved requests, the researchers will be provided access to anonymized data (to respect patient privacy in line with applicable laws and regulations) and with information necessary to address the research objectives under the terms of a data sharing agreement.</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>https://vivli.org/ourmember/takeda/</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

