<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03347383</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ID3-20170628</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03347383</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Trial Investigating the Combination Therapy With Luminor DCB and iVolution Stent in TASC C and D Femoropopliteal Lesions</brief_title>
  <acronym>TINTIN</acronym>
  <official_title>Physician Initiated, Prospective, Non-randomized Belgian Multi-center Trial, Investigating the Safety and Efficacy of the Treatment With the LumINor DCB and The IvolutioN Stent of iVascular in TASC C and D Femoropopliteal Atherosclerotic Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>ID3 Medical</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>ID3 Medical</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The T.I.N.T.I.N. study investigates the safety and efficacy of the combination therapy with&#xD;
      the Luminor drug coated balloon (DCB) and the iVolution stent in the treatment of TASC C and&#xD;
      D femoropopliteal lesions. An expected total of 100 patients will be treated in the scope of&#xD;
      this study. The lesion is located within the native superficial femoral artery and/or the&#xD;
      popliteal artery. Prior to dilatation with the Luminor DCB, pre-dilatation with the Oceanus&#xD;
      balloon is mandatory. After dilatation with the Luminor DCB, stenting with the iVolution&#xD;
      stent need to be performed. Post-dilatation can be performed according to the physician's&#xD;
      discretion. Patients will be invited for a follow-up visit at 1, 6, 12, 24, 36, 48 and 60&#xD;
      month post-procedure. The primary efficacy endpoint of the study is defined as the freedom&#xD;
      from clinically-driven target lesion revascularization (TLR) at 12 months. Secondary&#xD;
      endpoints include primary patency rate at 6 and 12 months, freedom from clinically-driven TLR&#xD;
      at 6, 24, 36, 48 and 60 months, clinical success at 1, 6, 12, 24, 36, 48 and 60 months and&#xD;
      freedom from serious adverse events at pre-discharge, 1, 6, 12, 24, 36, 48 and 60 months&#xD;
      follow-up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this clinical investigation is to evaluate, in a controlled setting, the&#xD;
      long-term safety and efficacy of the combination therapy with the Luminor DCB and the&#xD;
      iVolution stent post CE-certification and according to the indications of the Instructions&#xD;
      for use (IFU) with focus on the treatment of TASC C and D femoropopliteal atherosclerotic&#xD;
      lesions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be selected based on the investigator's assessment, evaluation of the&#xD;
      underlying disease and the eligibility criteria. The patient's medical condition should be&#xD;
      stable, with no underlying medical condition which would prevent them from performing the&#xD;
      required testing or from completing the study. Patients should also be geographically stable,&#xD;
      willing and able to cooperate in this clinical study and remain available for long-term&#xD;
      follow-up. A patient is considered enrolled in the study after obtaining the patients&#xD;
      informed consent, if there is full compliance with the study eligibility criteria and after&#xD;
      successful guidewire passage through the study target lesion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to the index procedure the following tests and clinical data will be collected:&#xD;
      informed consent for data collection, demographics, medical history, medication record,&#xD;
      physical examination, clinical category of chronic limb ischemia (Rutherford category) and&#xD;
      resting ankle-brachial index (ABI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the procedure, the vascular access can be achieved to the investigator's standard&#xD;
      clinical practice. After successful lesion passage, diagnostic angiography of the lesion area&#xD;
      and distal run-off is performed and angiographic measurements (vessel diameter, percentage&#xD;
      stenosis and lesion length) are collected. All inflow-limiting lesion will be treated&#xD;
      according to the investigators standard clinical practice before treatment of the target&#xD;
      lesion. Pre-dilatation of the target lesion is mandatory with the Oceanus balloon. After&#xD;
      pre-dilatation, a least one Luminor DCB will be inflated and at least 1 iVolution stent will&#xD;
      be deployed at the target lesion. At the physician's discretion, post-dilatation can be&#xD;
      performed. No other adjunctive therapies (atherectomy, laser) are allowed. The complete&#xD;
      femoropopliteal vasculature should be treated in one single session, staged interventions are&#xD;
      not allowed. All outflow-limiting lesions must be treated according to the hospital treatment&#xD;
      standard.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The regular follow-ups are necessary to monitor the condition of the patient and the&#xD;
      procedure. Patients will be invited for a follow-up visit at 1, 6, 12, 24, 36, 48 and 60&#xD;
      months after the index procedure. The 24, 36, 48 and 60 month follow-up can be conducted via&#xD;
      a phone call. The following data will be collected during these follow-up visit: medication&#xD;
      record, physical examination, rutherford categorization, ABI and color flow doppler&#xD;
      ultrasound.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 19, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Freedom from clinically-driven TLR at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>TLR defined as a repeated intervention to maintain or re-establish patency within the region of the treated arterial vessel plus 5mm proximal and distal to the treated lesion edge at the respective time points.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary patency rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months post-procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Absence of a hemodynamically significant stenosis on duplex ultrasound (systolic velocity ratio no greater than 2.5) at the target lesion and without TLR within the time of the procedure and the given follow-up.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Technical success</measure>
    <time_frame>Index procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Ability to cross and dilate the lesion and achieve residual angiographic stenosis no greater than 30%</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Freedom from clinically-driven TLR</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 24, 36, 48 and 60 months post-procedure</time_frame>
    <description>TLR defined as a repeated intervention to maintain or re-establish patency within the region of the treated arterial vessel plus 5mm proximal and distal to the treated lesion edge at the respective time points.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical success</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24, 36, 48 and 60 months post-procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement of Rutherford classification compared to the pre-procedure Rutherford classification</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24, 36, 48 and 60 months post-procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Defined according to the Internal Organization of Standardization (ISO) guidelines: ISO 14155:2011</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Peripheral Arterial Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Combination therapy DCB + stent</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients treated with the Luminor DCB and the iVolution stent</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Combination therapy DCB + stent</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will be treated with the Luminor DCB and iVolution stent</description>
    <arm_group_label>Combination therapy DCB + stent</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        General inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient presenting a score from 2 to 5 following Rutherford classification&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is willing to comply with specified follow-up evaluations at the specified&#xD;
             times&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is &gt;18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient understands the nature of the procedure and provides written informed consent,&#xD;
             prior to enrolment in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a projected life expectancy of at least 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior to enrolment, the guidewire has crossed target lesion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is eligible for treatment with the Luminor Paclitaxel-Eluting Peripheral&#xD;
             Balloon Dilatation Catheter and the iVolution stent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male, infertile female or female of child bearing potential practicing an acceptable&#xD;
             method of birth control with a negative pregnancy test within 7 days prior to study&#xD;
             procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
        Angiographic inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  De novo and post-percutaneous transluminal angioplasty (PTA) restenotic lesions&#xD;
             located in the femoropopliteal arteries suitable for endovascular therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The target lesion is located within the native femoropopliteal artery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The length of the target lesion is ≥ 150mm and considered as TASC C or D lesion&#xD;
             according to the TASC II classification.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The target lesion has angiographic evidence of stenosis &gt; 50% or occlusion which can&#xD;
             be passed with standard guidewire manipulation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Target vessel diameter visually estimated is &gt;4mm and &lt;6.5 mm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  There is angiographic evidence of at least one-vessel-runoff to the foot, irrespective&#xD;
             of whether or not outflow was re-established by means of previous endovascular&#xD;
             intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient refusing treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of a stent in the target lesion that was placed during a previous procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Untreated flow-limiting inflow lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any previous surgery in the target vessel (including prior ipsilateral crural bypass)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients for whom antiplatelet therapy, anticoagulants or thrombolytic drugs are&#xD;
             contraindicated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who exhibit persistent acute intraluminal thrombus of the proposed lesion&#xD;
             site&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Perforation at the angioplasty site evidenced by extravasation of contrast medium&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known hypersensitivity to heparin, including those patients who have had&#xD;
             a previous incidence of heparin-induced thrombocytopenia (HIT) type II&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with uncorrected bleeding disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aneurysm located at the level of the superficial femoral artery/popliteal artery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-atherosclerotic disease resulting in occlusion (e.g. embolism, Buerger's disease,&#xD;
             vasculitis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe medical comorbidities (severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, metastatic&#xD;
             malignancy, dementia, etc.) or other medical condition that would preclude compliance&#xD;
             with the study protocol or 1-year life expectancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major distal amputation (above the transmetatarsal) in the study limb or non-study&#xD;
             limb&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Septicemia or bacteremia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of thrombectomy, atherectomy or laser devices during procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patient considered to be hemodynamically unstable at onset of procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy to contrast media that cannot be adequately pre-medicated prior to the&#xD;
             study procedure&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Koen Deloose, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>ID3 Medical</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>O.L.V. Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aalst</city>
        <zip>9300</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Z.N.A.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Antwerpen</city>
        <zip>2060</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Imelda Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bonheiden</city>
        <zip>2820</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sint-Jozefkliniek</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bornem</city>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>A.Z. Sint-Blasius</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dendermonde</city>
        <zip>9200</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>H. Hartziekenhuis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lier</city>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AZ Damiaan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oostende</city>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>R.Z. Heilig Hart</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tienen</city>
        <zip>3300</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AZ Jan Portaels</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vilvoorde</city>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 15, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 20, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

