<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02067741</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SAKK 21/12</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>SNCTP000000389</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02067741</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>CR1447 in Endocrine Responsive-HER2neg and TN-ARpos Breast Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Stratified, Multicenter Phase II Trial of Transdermal CR1447 (4-OH-testosterone) in Endocrine Responsive-HER2 Negative and Triple Negative-androgen Receptor Positive Metastatic or Locally Advanced Breast Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Swiss Group for Clinical Cancer Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Swiss Group for Clinical Cancer Research</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      SAKK 21/12 is a stratified, multicenter Phase II first in-human trial with transdermal CR1447&#xD;
      (4-OH-testosterone) and is directed to patients with endocrine responsive-HER2neg and&#xD;
      TN-ARpos metastatic or locally advanced breast cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial will be conducted in Switzerland with max. 90 patients. CR1447 has a very good&#xD;
      safety and tolerability profile and combines two mechanisms of action, interaction with the&#xD;
      AR and the aromatase enzyme may have a higher activity than drugs with a single mechanism and&#xD;
      might offer the possibility of non-chemotherapy based endocrine therapy to the limited&#xD;
      treatment options in TN-ARpos BC. Transdermal application of CR1447 might have the advantage&#xD;
      to continuously release of 4-OHT into the blood stream, thus omitting a first pass effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Phase II the main objective is to assess activity and to determine the efficacy and&#xD;
      tolerability of CR1447. Phase II will consist of two strata, into which patients will be&#xD;
      stratified according to their hormonal receptor status: Stratum A for patients with endocrine&#xD;
      responsive-HER2neg disease, regardless of their AR status and Stratum B for patients with&#xD;
      triple-negative and determined ARpos disease. Patients with triple-negative disease tested&#xD;
      negative for AR will be excluded from the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In both strata patients will be treated with 400 mg of CR1447 until disease progression,&#xD;
      patients' wish or physicians' decision to end treatment. Biopsies of one defined metastatic&#xD;
      lesion in those patients who gave informed consent will be performed at baseline and within&#xD;
      the third week of treatment with CR1447.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Measurement of AR expression, expression of downstream targets of ERα, ERβ, PR, AR,&#xD;
      angiogenesis and other translational studies as described in this protocol should help&#xD;
      confirming the hypothesis of an increased benefit of CR1447 due to its dual action, efficacy&#xD;
      of topical application, tolerability and in deciding whether one should proceed to a large&#xD;
      randomized trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Breast cancer is the most frequently diagnosed cancer and a heterogeneous disease and tumor&#xD;
      categorization based on molecular characteristics beyond the currently used markers such as&#xD;
      the estrogen receptor (ER), progesterone receptor (PR), and HER2, makes tumor categorization&#xD;
      and treatment a demanding task.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The treatment and prevention of relapses of breast cancer is mainly based on I) surgery of&#xD;
      primary tumors, II) radiotherapy, III) chemotherapy, IV) endocrine therapy, and V) specific&#xD;
      interventions. Although there have been advances in breast cancer therapy with three out of&#xD;
      four women with breast cancer now being cured, one out of four patients will relapse or&#xD;
      present with metastatic disease at the time of first diagnosis and hence be incurable and die&#xD;
      of their disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The endocrine responsive breast cancer is defined by the immunohistochemical detection of the&#xD;
      ER (estrogen receptor) and/or the PR (progesterone receptor) on at least 1% of tumor cells on&#xD;
      the tissue sample to a variable degree and offers the possibility of treatment using&#xD;
      endocrine strategies in about 80% of patients. Endocrine responsive breast cancers may also&#xD;
      express HER2. The triple negative breast cancer (TNBC) is defined by the lack of expression&#xD;
      of ER, PR, and HER2. The analysis is made on the pathological tumor tissue sample. While for&#xD;
      ER and PR, the threshold is less than 1% of tumor cells expressing both receptors, HER2&#xD;
      negativity is defined as immunohistochemical scores of 0/1+ or tumors with scores of 0/1+ or&#xD;
      2+ that are lacking HER2 gene amplification after in situ hybridization. Approximately 15% of&#xD;
      all breast cancers are found to be triple-negative. However, due to the biologically more&#xD;
      aggressive behavior of these tumors, the patient group suffering from this type of disease&#xD;
      are overrepresented within the first five years after initial diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, androgen receptor (AR) targeted therapies gained new interest due to the fact that&#xD;
      the AR is the most abundantly expressed sex hormone receptor in breast cancer (approx. 70% of&#xD;
      all breast tumors) and, importantly, in about 20% (range 10% to 50% depending on the&#xD;
      respective reference) of triple-negative breast tumors. The threshold for ARpos breast cancer&#xD;
      is that &gt;0% of tumor cells expresses the AR. In addition, a significant association was found&#xD;
      between AR expression and longer overall survival of breast cancer patients. Androgens can&#xD;
      induce proliferative changes in breast cancer cell lines, and testosterone acts as a tumor&#xD;
      promoter in several animal models of breast cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endocrine responsive breast cancer Anti-estrogen therapy includes ovariectomy, to remove the&#xD;
      primary source of female sex hormone in premenopausal women, and the application of&#xD;
      luteinizing hormone releasing hormone (LHRH) agonists, to decrease the release of LH and&#xD;
      prevent gonadal estrogen synthesis. These therapies induce a postmenopausal status. The&#xD;
      hormonal treatment of choice for premenopausal women with ER positive metastatic breast&#xD;
      tumors is the use of ER antagonists such as tamoxifen. Tamoxifen and aromatase inhibitors,&#xD;
      preventing the final conversion of androgens to estrogens, are the main endocrine treatment&#xD;
      options for postmenopausal women with metastatic breast cancer. The persisting estrogen&#xD;
      levels in postmenopausal women are mainly due to aromatase activity in extragonadal sources&#xD;
      such as breast tissue, skeletal muscle and adipose tissue. Thus, both ER blockade by&#xD;
      tamoxifen and inhibition of estrogen synthesis inhibit the growth signal for breast cancer&#xD;
      cells expressing ER.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aromatase, the key enzyme of estrogen production in women, is expressed in and around breast&#xD;
      tumors, in ovaries, and in skeletal muscle and adipose tissue in postmenopausal women.&#xD;
      Several aromatase inhibitors (AI) have been developed. The first generation aromatase&#xD;
      inhibitors include testolactone and aminogluthetimide that were replaced by the more potent&#xD;
      second generation inhibitors fadrazole and formestane (4-hydroxy-4-androstenedione, 4-OHA),&#xD;
      and later on by the even more potent third generation inhibitors exemestane, letrozole and&#xD;
      anastrozole. 4OHA and exemestane are steroidal AI and irreversibly block aromatase while the&#xD;
      non-steroidal AI letrozole and anastrozole are reversible inhibitors. Importantly, there&#xD;
      seems to exist no cross-resistance between the two aromatase inhibitor classes, and 4-OHA or&#xD;
      exemestane may still show efficacy after relapse upon letrozole/anastrozole treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In summary, there is a great demand for novel and improved therapeutic strategies, especially&#xD;
      to overcome resistance to chemotherapy or presently available endocrine therapy in&#xD;
      postmenopausal women.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While patients with ER and/or PR positive tumors can be treated with endocrine therapies and&#xD;
      patients with HER2pos disease with treatments directed against HER2 such as trastuzumab,&#xD;
      lapatinib, and trastuzumab/pertuzumab combination therapy, no endocrine or targeted anti-HER2&#xD;
      directed therapy exists for patients suffering from triple negative disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For these patients, only chemotherapy is a therapeutic option. Unfortunately, these tumors&#xD;
      tend to be aggressive and quickly growing with a high relapse rate even after intensive&#xD;
      adjuvant chemotherapy. Due to the absence of estrogen receptors, endocrine therapy based on&#xD;
      anti-estrogen intervention strategies must fail.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are currently no suitable treatment options for patients with metastatic&#xD;
      triple-negative breast tumors whose disease has failed to respond to chemotherapy. Thus,&#xD;
      there is a great demand for novel and improved therapeutic strategies in this patient group&#xD;
      and in all patients with acquired resistance to combat breast cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Testosterone was already used extensively between the 1930s and 1960s for breast cancer&#xD;
      treatment, with anecdotal tumor responses (especially bone metastases) seen in up to 20% of&#xD;
      treated women. Side effects such as hirsutism and aggressive behavior as signs of&#xD;
      virilization in treated women and the evidence that testosterone may be easily be converted&#xD;
      to estrogens in the body led to the discontinuation of its use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CR1447 (4-hydroxytestosterone [4-OHT]) is a steroidal small molecule which has two distinct&#xD;
      properties, acting as a steroidal aromatase inhibitor (AI) and binding to the AR with high&#xD;
      affinity (IC50 4.4 nM). In vitro studies indicate that human breast cancer cell lines are&#xD;
      inhibited by CR1447 in their growth if they express the androgen receptor, while knock out of&#xD;
      the AR abolishes this effect. A significant proportion of 4-OHT is converted to 4-OHA&#xD;
      (4-hydroxyandrostenedione, formestane). In vivo 4-OHT and 4-OHA, form a redox system. 4-OHA&#xD;
      is the 17-beta-oxidized isoform of CR1447. 4-OHA had previously been approved as an aromatase&#xD;
      inhibitor for the treatment of BC via intramuscular (i.m.) injection (Formestane, Lentaron®)&#xD;
      injection, but was discontinued by Novartis due to the development of oral aromatase&#xD;
      inhibitors. Unlike testosterone, both compounds, 4-OHA and 4-OHT, are not converted to&#xD;
      estrogens in vivo. Due to a high first pass effect after oral dosing, 4-OHA had to be&#xD;
      administered parentally e.g. as an intramuscular injection. While this regimen was clinically&#xD;
      effective, local side effects were a dose limiting issue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A clinical feasibility study of transdermally applied 4-OHA showed that significant amounts&#xD;
      of 4-OHA are absorbed by the skin. Intramuscular and transdermally (twice daily) applied&#xD;
      4-OHA achieved comparable the same plasma levels from day 3 on.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 14, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease control at 24 weeks (DC24)</measure>
    <time_frame>at 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>DC24 is obtained in a patient who achieves complete response (CR) or partial response (PR) within the first 24 ± 2 weeks of treatment or stable disease (SD) for at least 24 weeks after treatment start according to the RECIST 1.1 criteria.&#xD;
For patients without CR or PR and no PD before 24 weeks:&#xD;
If the tumor assessment at 24 ± 2 weeks is missing but a later assessment shows SD, the patient will be counted as obtaining DC24.&#xD;
If the tumor assessment at 24 ± 2 weeks is missing and there are no further tumor assessments or the subsequent assessment shows PD, the patient will be counted as not obtaining DC24.&#xD;
Tumor assessments showing CR or PR have to be confirmed after 4 weeks.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after treatment discontinuation and thereafter monthly until all adverse events related to the trial drug have resolved</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PK analysis of CR1447</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 and 6 months of treatment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Estradiol levels during treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 and 6 months of treatment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>mRNA expression signature of downstream target genes of the ERα, ERβ, PR, AR and angiogenesis in biopsies</measure>
    <time_frame>measured at baseline (day 0) and at treatment and within the third week of treatment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ki67 expression</measure>
    <time_frame>measured at baseline (day 0) and at treatment and within the third week of treatment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease control at 12 weeks (DC12)</measure>
    <time_frame>at 12 ± 1 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in tumor size at 12 weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>at 12 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">29</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Breast Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Stratum A - HER2neg BC RD - CR1447</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Stratum A - patients with endocrine responsive-HER2neg BC</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Stratum B - ARpos B - CR1447</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Stratum B - patients with triple-negative and confirmed ARpos BC</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CR1447</intervention_name>
    <description>400 mg, corresponding to two 4 g stick packs applications twice daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>Stratum A - HER2neg BC RD - CR1447</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Stratum B - ARpos B - CR1447</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>4-OHT</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must give written informed consent before registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Post-menopausal women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Locally advanced or metastatic, histologically confirmed breast adenocarcinoma&#xD;
             requiring therapy and not suitable for local treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stratum A: endocrine responsive-HER2neg BC, specifically: ERpos (≥1%), PRpos&#xD;
                  (≥1%), HER2neg; or ERpos(≥1%), PRneg, HER2neg&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stratum B: triple negative BC (ERneg (&lt;1%), PRneg (&lt;1%), HER2neg) and ARpos&#xD;
                  (&gt;0%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive AR of the most recent formalin-fixed paraffin-embedded (FFPE) biopsy&#xD;
             determined by central pathology (Stratum B only). Note: TNBC patients with only&#xD;
             locally assessed ARpos (&gt;0%) status are not allowed to enter the trial in Phase II.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stratum A: Patients had 1 line of prior endocrine treatment for advanced disease&#xD;
                  with a treatment duration of ≥6 months and no evidence of progression at 6&#xD;
                  months. No previous chemotherapy for advanced disease is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stratum B: TN-ARpos BC patients had ≤2 lines of prior chemotherapy treatment for&#xD;
                  advanced disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is suitable for endocrine treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of ≥1 measurable or evaluable lesion according to RECIST 1.1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tumor assessment to be performed within 28 days before or on registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Baseline PRO questionnaire (FACT-ES) has been completed (Phase II only).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  WHO performance status 0-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate hematological values: hemoglobin ≥100 g/L, ANC ≥1.5x109/L, platelets&#xD;
             ≥100x109/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate hepatic function: total bilirubin ≤1.5xULN, ALT ≤2.5xULN (except for liver&#xD;
             metastases ≤5xULN).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate renal function: serum creatinine ≤1.5xULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous malignancy within 5 years with the exception of adequately treated cervical&#xD;
             carcinoma in situ or localized non-melanoma skin cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled central nervous system (CNS) metastases, pulmonary carcinomatous&#xD;
             lymphangiosis (i.e., &gt;50% invasion), or liver metastases on &gt;1/3 of the liver on&#xD;
             ultrasound or computed tomography (CT).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unsuitable for endocrine therapy (e.g. due to rapidly progressing disease or impending&#xD;
             6.2.3complication).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Indication for chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric disorder precluding understanding of information on trial related topics,&#xD;
             giving informed consent, filling out PRO forms, or interfering with compliance for&#xD;
             oral drug intake.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent treatment with other experimental drugs in a clinical trial within 30 days&#xD;
             prior to trial treatment start or other anti-cancer therapy within 14 days. Treatment&#xD;
             with bisphosphonates/denosumab is allowed. Bisphosphonates/denosumab treatment had to&#xD;
             be started at least 3 months before registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any serious underlying medical condition (at the judgment of the investigator) which&#xD;
             could impair the ability of the patient to participate in the trial (e.g. active&#xD;
             autoimmune disease, uncontrolled diabetes).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to trial drug(s) or hypersensitivity to any other component of&#xD;
             the trial drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Local tumor relapse only that is amenable to surgical treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous treatment with formestane (4-OHA).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiotherapy (RT) within 4 weeks prior to treatment start .&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent estrogen or progestin therapy in any formulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition potentially&#xD;
             hampering compliance with the trial protocol and follow-up.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marcus Vetter, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Universitätsspital Basel</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Beat Thürlimann, Prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Cantonal Hospital of St. Gallen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kantonsspital Aarau</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aarau</city>
        <zip>CH-5001</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kantonsspital Baden</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baden</city>
        <zip>CH-5404</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsspital Basel</name>
      <address>
        <city>Basel</city>
        <zip>CH-4031</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istituto Oncologico della Svizzera Italiana - Ospedale Regionale Bellinzona e Valli</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bellinzona</city>
        <zip>CH-6500</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oncocare / Klinik Engeried</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bern</city>
        <zip>3012</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Inselspital Bern</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bern</city>
        <zip>CH-3010</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kantonsspital Graubünden</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chur</city>
        <zip>CH-7000</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kantonsspital Frauenfeld / Brustzentrum Thurgau</name>
      <address>
        <city>Frauenfeld</city>
        <zip>CH-8501</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Luzerner Kantonsspital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Luzern</city>
        <zip>CH-6000</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kantonsspital St. Gallen</name>
      <address>
        <city>St. Gallen</city>
        <zip>CH-9007</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Spital STS AG</name>
      <address>
        <city>Thun</city>
        <zip>CH-3600</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kantonsspital Winterthur</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winterthur</city>
        <zip>CH-8401</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Onkozentrum - Klinik im Park</name>
      <address>
        <city>Zurich</city>
        <zip>CH-8002</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 11, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 17, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 20, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Post-menopausal women</keyword>
  <keyword>topical application CR1447</keyword>
  <keyword>endocrine responsive-HER2neg breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>triple negative-androgen receptor positive breast cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

