<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02290288</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>VGFOUREG-28601</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02290288</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prospective Study for Vaginal Vault Prolapse After Hysterectomy: Comparison of Two Surgical Methods</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prospective Randomized Study for Vaginal Vault Prolapse After Hysterectomy: Comparison of a Vaginal and Laparoscopic Method With Validation of Translated Questionnaire for Symptoms and Quality of Life by Vaginal Prolapse.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Sweden</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Sweden</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study is carried out at the Sahlgrenska University Hospital and the patient population&#xD;
      consists of women referred with symptomatic and bothersome post-hysterectomy vaginal vault&#xD;
      prolapse at least 1 cm above or beyond the hymeneal remnants. The interventions are either&#xD;
      vaginal sacrospinousfixation or laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy following randomization to one of&#xD;
      the types of surgery. The primary outcome is anatomical failure based on clinical assessment.&#xD;
      Failure is defined clinically, according to the Pelvic Organ Prolapse Quantification system,&#xD;
      as Ba, C or Bp at the hymen or below on maximum Valsalva maneuver one and two years after the&#xD;
      surgery. Secondary outcomes are evaluation of continence, sexual function and prolapse&#xD;
      symptoms based on validated questionnaires 1, 2, 5 and 10 years after the surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The lifetime risk for pelvic floor surgery for prolapse is likely to be between 10% and 15%,&#xD;
      and a large number of patients who previously underwent hysterectomy develop vaginal vault&#xD;
      prolapse. There is some evidence that about 2% of all women after hysterectomy would require&#xD;
      a surgery for vault prolapse. There are many different techniques used for correction of&#xD;
      vault prolapse but the evidence for them is lacking and the use is guided mainly by tradition&#xD;
      at the singe institution.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is some evidence indicating that laparoscopic surgery can be superior to the vaginal&#xD;
      approach. Symptoms of prolapse are significantly associated with avulsion injury in patients&#xD;
      after hysterectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our aim is to compare, with a 1- and 2-years follow-up examination in patients with&#xD;
      post-hysterectomy prolapse, the efficacy of two standard surgical procedures for vaginal&#xD;
      vault prolapse: sacrospinous vaginal colpopexy (the Richter procedure) with native tissue&#xD;
      vaginal repair (sacrospinous fixation, SSF) and laparoscopic colposacropexy with mesh.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a single-center, randomized controlled trial of two standard surgical procedures for&#xD;
      vaginal vault prolapse routinely used at our institution.Both procedures are designed to&#xD;
      treat vault prolapse, one with mesh implantation through laparoscopy and the other with&#xD;
      vaginal repairs and apical fixation to the sacrospinous ligament, usually on the right.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients referred to our gynecological unit (Ob/Gyn Department of Sahlgrenska University&#xD;
      Hospital in Gothenburg) because of symptomatic vault prolapse and fulfilling the inclusions&#xD;
      criteria are asked to participate in the study. Eligible for inclusion are: post-hysterectomy&#xD;
      patients with at least two-compartment prolapse (with affected apical/vault compartment,&#xD;
      stage II or higher on the Pelvic Organ Prolapse Quantification system (POP-Q)), suffering&#xD;
      from symptoms of prolapse, requesting pelvic floor reconstructive surgery, and diagnosed with&#xD;
      a vault prolapse. Excluded are: patients with prolapse and uterus in place, those not&#xD;
      requesting pelvic floor surgery, patients who do not understand Swedish or are not capable to&#xD;
      fulfill follow up procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients undergo identical pre- and postoperative assessment procedures, including POP-Q&#xD;
      examination on maximum Valsalva maneuver, which are archived on Case Report Form, and&#xD;
      validated questionnaires PFDI-20, PFIQ-7 and PISQ-12. The study was approved by the regional&#xD;
      ethics committee and all subjects obtain written informed consent to participate. To minimize&#xD;
      the bias we decided that all the follow up examinations are going to be performed by the same&#xD;
      gynecologist who do not perform the surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients can end participation in the study at any moment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The randomization process is carried out by computer, using patient social security number,&#xD;
      at the time of enrollment (usually 2-3 months before the surgery). Patients are informed&#xD;
      about their allocation after the randomization. Both procedures are performed by an&#xD;
      experienced surgeon, with the patient under general anesthesia for the laparoscopic procedure&#xD;
      and regional anesthesia for the sacrospinous fixation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients are followed up at 3 months,1 year and 2 years postoperatively. These postoperative&#xD;
      clinical examinations are performed by a single examiner, who had not been involved in the&#xD;
      surgical procedures. The vaginal descent was assessed at maximum Valsalva maneuver.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In case of recurrence of prolapse and distressing symptoms which a patient desired to be&#xD;
      resolved, a reoperation of prolapse is planned according to the clinical praxis at our&#xD;
      department.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome measure was anatomical failure based on clinical assessment. Failure was&#xD;
      defined clinically as Ba, C or Bp at the hymen or below, on maximum Valsalva maneuver.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As secondary outcome measures we used a continence status, sexual function and prolapse&#xD;
      symptoms based on validated questionnaires: Pelvic Floor Impact Questionnaire (PFIQ - 7),&#xD;
      Pelvic Floor Distress Inventory Questionnaire - Short Form 20 (PFDI-20), Pelvic Organ&#xD;
      Prolapse/Urinary Incontinence Sexual Questionnaire (PISQ-12) and quality of life based on&#xD;
      Short Form (36) Health Survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The power calculation was based on the primary outcome measure and available data which led&#xD;
      us to expect a failure rate of 25% in the sacrospinous fixation group and 10% failure in&#xD;
      laparoscopy group. To detect an expected difference of 15% between the groups, with 80% power&#xD;
      of the test 70 patients are required in each group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>anatomical failure (Failure was defined clinically as Ba, C or Bp at the hymen or below, on maximum Valsalva maneuver.)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome measure was anatomical failure based on clinical assessment. Failure was defined clinically as Ba, C or Bp at the hymen or below, on maximum Valsalva maneuver.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>continence status</measure>
    <time_frame>1 and 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>continence status based on validated questionnaires: Pelvic Floor Impact Questionnaire (PFIQ - 7), Pelvic Floor Distress Inventory Questionnaire - Short Form 20 (PFDI-20), Pelvic Organ Prolapse/Urinary Incontinence Sexual Questionnaire (PISQ-12)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>sexual function</measure>
    <time_frame>1 and 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>sexual function based on validated questionnaires: Pelvic Floor Impact Questionnaire (PFIQ - 7), Pelvic Floor Distress Inventory Questionnaire - Short Form 20 (PFDI-20), Pelvic Organ Prolapse/Urinary Incontinence Sexual Questionnaire (PISQ-12)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>prolapse symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>1 and 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>symptoms based on validated questionnaires: Pelvic Floor Impact Questionnaire (PFIQ - 7), Pelvic Floor Distress Inventory Questionnaire - Short Form 20 (PFDI-20), Pelvic Organ Prolapse/Urinary Incontinence Sexual Questionnaire (PISQ-12</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>1 and 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>quality of life based on validated questionnaires: Pelvic Floor Impact Questionnaire (PFIQ - 7), Pelvic Floor Distress Inventory Questionnaire - Short Form 20 (PFDI-20), Pelvic Organ Prolapse/Urinary Incontinence Sexual Questionnaire (PISQ-12) and quality of life based on Short Form (36) Health Survey.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">138</enrollment>
  <condition>Vaginal Vault Prolapse</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SSF</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>1. vaginal surgery arm (SSF)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LSC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>laparoscopic surgery arm (LSC)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>vaginal surgery</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>SSF</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>laparoscopic surgery</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>LSC</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  post-hysterectomy patients with at least two-compartment prolapse (with affected&#xD;
             apical/vault compartment,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  stage II or higher on the Pelvic Organ Prolapse Quantification system (POP-Q)),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  suffering from symptoms of prolapse,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  requesting pelvic floor reconstructive surgery, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  diagnosed with a vault prolapse.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with prolapse and uterus in place,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  those not requesting pelvic floor surgery,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who do not understand Swedish or are not capable to fulfill follow up&#xD;
             procedure&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dept of Obst Gyn, Sahlgrenska University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gothenburg</city>
        <state>VGR</state>
        <zip>41381</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 4, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 13, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 14, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 18, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 18, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 19, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Sweden</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Janusz Marcickiewicz</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>senior consultant</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prolapse</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pelvic Organ Prolapse</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

