<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02290652</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>12/SC/0296</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02290652</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sexual Function Questionnaire Total Hip Replacement</brief_title>
  <official_title>Development and Validation of a Sexual Function Questionnaire for Female Patients Undergoing Total Hip Replacement</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital Southampton NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital Southampton NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      -  Non-commercial trial&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  2 Centres involved: University Hospital Southampton and Spire Southampton&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Expected number of eligible participants available per year: 100, (95% expected to agree&#xD;
           to participation)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The study will recruit prospectively female patients aged 18 - 65 years undergoing THR.&#xD;
           A retrospective series of similar patients who have had a hip replacement will also be&#xD;
           recruited.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This is a research project that will run over 2 years. Data from 200 patients will be&#xD;
           collected and analysed:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Retrospective 30 question questionnaire: 'Arthroplasty &amp; Sexual Function Questionnaire (ASFQ)&#xD;
      - Post-operative' Version 1.3 11/07/14&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prospective 23 question questionnaire: 'Arthroplasty &amp; Sexual Function Questionnaire (ASFQ) -&#xD;
      Pre-operative' Version 1.3 11/07/14&#xD;
&#xD;
      This project is significant in exploring an area of Orthopaedic medicine that has been little&#xD;
      discussed in the literature. Preliminary results of our questionnaires have already revealed&#xD;
      patients have a great desire to know how hip replacement will affect sexual function.&#xD;
      Components of the questionnaire look at details such as: reasonable time frames for returning&#xD;
      to sexual activity, positions that may be undesirable following replacement and which may&#xD;
      lead to dislocation, concurrent use of analgesia and psychosexual aspects of total hip&#xD;
      replacement surgery. The ultimate objective is to provide patients with detailed information&#xD;
      about what to expect after hip replacement surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Prospective&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be recruited from clinics at University Hospital Southampton and Spire&#xD;
      Southampton Hospital. If they agree in principle to participate they will be provided with&#xD;
      the Patient Information Sheet (PIS) and consent forms. Having completed the consent forms&#xD;
      (one for participant to keep and one for the site file) participants are assigned an&#xD;
      alphanumeric study number, which will be written at the top of all questionnaires and&#xD;
      research paperwork completed. A form detailing demographic information will be filled out on&#xD;
      recruitment to provide data for comparative quantitative analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to their operation, whether in hospital or by post (patient preference), they will&#xD;
      complete a pre-operative ASFQ and FSFI questionnaire. These will be returned to the research&#xD;
      team either in person (if completed by an inpatient) or returned in a pre-stamped addressed&#xD;
      envelope. Copies of the National Joint Registry (NJR) data and PROMs will also be made and&#xD;
      kept for evaluation alongside the questionnaire data. Patients will then complete the&#xD;
      post-operative questionnaires and FSFI validated questionnaire at 6 and 12 months after their&#xD;
      surgery. Questionnaires will be distributed to the patients in clinic at 6 months and sent to&#xD;
      their home address at 12 months post-operatively (returned with stamped and addressed&#xD;
      envelope).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Retrospective&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential participant will be highlighted from previous inpatient list of patients eligible&#xD;
      for participation. These patients will be contacted via telephone by a Good Clinical Practice&#xD;
      (GCP) trained member of the research team member and invited to participate in the trial. If&#xD;
      keen a PIS will be sent out to the patient's home address. The research team member will then&#xD;
      follow-up with a phone-call to gain implied consent and complete an additional form detailing&#xD;
      demographic information (the same information as the prospective cohort). The post-operative&#xD;
      questionnaire, FSFI questionnaire and consent forms (one for participant to keep and one for&#xD;
      the site file) with a stamped address envelope, will then be sent out to the participant to&#xD;
      complete. Once documents are completed they will be returned to the research team.&#xD;
      Questionnaires will be sent out at 6 and 12 months post-op where possible. Maximum time&#xD;
      retrospective recruitment will be 12 months. The patient's NJR and PROMs will also be&#xD;
      accessed for evaluation alongside the questionnaire data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Factors affecting sexual activity related to total hip replacement, as measured by the Arthroplasty &amp; Sexual Function Questionnaire (ASFQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>To determine those patient and implant factors that affect sexual activity after hip replacement surgery. The study data will be used to publish an evidence-based patient information booklet that will be a standard reference for patients and healthcare professionals.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Factors affecting sexual activity related to other joint replacement surgery, as measured by the Arthroplasty &amp; Sexual Function Questionnaire (ASFQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>2-5 years</time_frame>
    <description>The study will be extended to collect data from patients with knee arthritis who undergo knee replacement surgery (partial and total), as well as the partners of patients with hip and knee replacements. The study will also be extended to patients who have pre-arthritic conditions such as femoro-acetabular impingement, who undergo arthroscopic procedures.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Arthritis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective</arm_group_label>
    <description>Prospective - Factors affecting sexual function pre-THR</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Retrospective</arm_group_label>
    <description>Retrospective- Factors affecting sexual function post-THR</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prospective - Factors affecting sexual function pre-THR</intervention_name>
    <description>A prospective assessment of factors affecting sexual function in patients whom are awaiting a total hip replacement.&#xD;
Patients will carry out a prospective 23 question questionnaire: 'Arthroplasty &amp; Sexual Function Questionnaire (ASFQ) - Pre-operative' with validated questionnaire Female Sexual Function Index (FSFI), before their operation.&#xD;
Then at 6 months and 12 months post-operatively they will fill out a retrospective 30 question questionnaire: 'Arthroplasty &amp; Sexual Function Questionnaire (ASFQ) - Post-operative', again with FSFI.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Retrospective- Factors affecting sexual function post-THR</intervention_name>
    <description>A retrospective assessment of factors affecting sexual function in patients whom have undergone a total hip replacement (THR) in the preceding year.&#xD;
Patients will carry out a retrospective 30 question questionnaire: 'Arthroplasty &amp; Sexual Function Questionnaire (ASFQ) - Post-operative' with validated questionnaire Female Sexual Function Index (FSFI), at 6 months and/or 12 months (wherever possible).&#xD;
Maximum retrospective collection of data 12 months.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Retrospective</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All female patients aged over 18 that are listed for a total hip replacement at University&#xD;
        Hospital Southampton NHS Foundation Trust and The Spire Hospital Southampton that fulfill&#xD;
        the inclusion criteria will be asked to participate.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexually active&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Heterosexual&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18- 65 years undergoing THR (prospective) or having undergone THR surgery within the&#xD;
             last year&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexually inactive pre-operatively and wishing to remain sexually inactive&#xD;
             post-operatively&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to comprehend English and with capacity to consent and follow instruction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to sign and date the ethics committee approved consent documentation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joanna C D'Souza, BM BSc(Hons)</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Research Fellow, UHS NHS FT.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Spire Southampton Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Southampton</city>
        <state>Hampshire</state>
        <zip>SO16 6UY</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Southampton NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Southampton</city>
        <state>Hampshire</state>
        <zip>SO16 6YD</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 14, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 5, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 5, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 7, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Sexual function in Orthopaedic patients</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

