<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02295189</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SanAntonioMMC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02295189</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ketorolac Versus Triamcinolone Knee Injections for Osteoarthritis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Ketorolac Versus Triamcinolone Intra-articular Knee Injections for the Treatment of Osteoarthritis. A Prospective, Double-Blinded Randomized Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>San Antonio Military Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>San Antonio Military Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Osteoarthritis is a disabling disease of the joint spaces and has a high impact on society&#xD;
      due to the amount of people who are affected by the disease. Nonoperative management is a&#xD;
      mainstay of therapy in most patients. Ketorolac tromethamine and triamcinolone acetonide&#xD;
      intra-articular knee injections will be compared in a prospective, double-blinded, randomized&#xD;
      trial in subjects with knee osteoarthritis. Subjects will be enrolled from the Orthopaedics&#xD;
      Clinic based on inclusion and exclusion criteria. Intra-articular knee injection of ketorolac&#xD;
      tromethamine or triamcinolone acetonide will be performed under ultrasound guidance. Multiple&#xD;
      outcome measures will be performed throughout the six month period of follow-up. The&#xD;
      investigators predict ketorolac tromethamine will have a longer duration of pain relief when&#xD;
      compared to triamcinolone acetonide. The investigators predict there will be no differences&#xD;
      between the two intra-articular knee injections in terms of function using validated scoring&#xD;
      instruments.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Subject Population: Adult patients, age 18-90 years old who satisfy the inclusion criteria&#xD;
      and do not meet the exclusion criteria will be enrolled from the Orthopaedics Clinic at San&#xD;
      Antonio Military Medical Center (SAMMC). The enrollment period for this study is two years,&#xD;
      patients will be recruited up to 44 enrollees to allow 36 completers. Patients will be&#xD;
      stratified based on gender and age (&lt; 65 or &gt;= 65 years old). Demographics obtained will be&#xD;
      age, gender, height, weight, laterality and body-mass index (BMI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization: This will be a predetermined computerized randomization schedule to identify&#xD;
      treatment, ketorolac tromethamine versus triamcinolone acetonide. A patient key on paper&#xD;
      listing the patient name, last four digits of sponsor's social security number, study number&#xD;
      (randomly assigned), and treatment will be kept with the nurse/technician in the Orthopaedics&#xD;
      Clinic, locked in a cabinet. Patients will be stratified by gender and age (&lt; 65 or &gt;= 65&#xD;
      years old). Subjects will continue to be enrolled until there are at least 10 of each gender&#xD;
      in each group, treated with either ketorolac tromethamine or triamcinolone acetonide. In the&#xD;
      event the subject has bilateral knee pain, both knees will be injected with the same&#xD;
      treatment medication and the knee will be randomized as to which one will be included in the&#xD;
      data analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A pharmacist will prepare the treatment injection in the Orthopaedics Clinic. Injections will&#xD;
      be done with a 2-inch, 21-gauge needle placed on a 10cc syringe with an opaque covering to&#xD;
      conceal its contents to blind the patient and associate investigator to treatment. Injections&#xD;
      will contain either 2cc of ketorolac tromethamine (Toradol, 15mg/cc) in 8cc of bupivacaine&#xD;
      hydrochloride (0.5%) without epinephrine or 2cc of triamcinolone acetonide (Kenalog-40,&#xD;
      40mg/cc) in 8cc of bupivacaine hydrochloride (0.5%) without epinephrine. The subject and the&#xD;
      treatment injection will be taken to the Interdisciplinary Pain Management Center, for&#xD;
      injection under ultrasound guidance. The subject's selected knee, or bilateral knees, at the&#xD;
      superolateral site, will be sterilely prepped in standard fashion with betadine and allowed&#xD;
      to dry, prior to injection. The treatment will be injected by the associate investigator, in&#xD;
      the Interdisciplinary Pain Management Center, who is trained in Physical Medicine and&#xD;
      Rehabilitation and certified to perform ultrasound examinations. The associate investigator&#xD;
      will be blinded to treatment and outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A patient key listing the patient name, last four digits of sponsor's social security number,&#xD;
      age, gender, patient number (randomly assigned) and treatment received will be kept with the&#xD;
      nurse/technician in the Orthopaedics Clinic in a research folder, locked in a cabinet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Radiographs will be obtained at baseline and at 6 months follow-up. Osteoarthritis will be&#xD;
      classified according to Kellgren-Lawrence (K-L) radiographic criteria by associate&#xD;
      investigator who is fellowship trained in Total Joints. K-L grading will be entered on the&#xD;
      Case Report Form (CRF) prior to outcome data entry. The associate investigator will be&#xD;
      blinded to treatment. Outcome data collection will be performed by a study nurse/technician&#xD;
      in the Orthopaedics Clinic, with the exception of part of the Knee Society Score (KSS), which&#xD;
      will be performed by an associate investigator. The nurse/technician will record demographic&#xD;
      data, including height, weight, BMI, gender, laterality and age, at the baseline clinic visit&#xD;
      and at the 6 month follow-up. The use of nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug (NSAID) and&#xD;
      analgesic drugs and adverse events during the study period will be recorded at each visit.&#xD;
      Patients will keep a diary of NSAID and analgesic use during the study. Patients will&#xD;
      follow-up at 2 weeks, 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months. A visual analogue scale (VAS), KSS,&#xD;
      Western Ontario and McMasters Universities (WOMAC) index, Short Form 36 (SF-36), University&#xD;
      California Los Angeles (UCLA) Activity Score and Lysholm Knee Score (LKS) will be obtained at&#xD;
      the baseline clinic visit and each follow-up. All data obtained from the study will be&#xD;
      recorded on the CRF. All data collected will be kept with the nurse/technician in the&#xD;
      Orthopaedics Clinic in a research folder, locked in a cabinet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data from the CRF will be entered into an electronic database on Excel by the principle&#xD;
      investigator on a password protected computer. The database will be made available to the&#xD;
      associate investigators electronically. Data analysis will be performed by the principle&#xD;
      investigator which will also be performed on a password protected computer. All investigators&#xD;
      will remain blinded to the treatment received, until all data analysis is performed. There&#xD;
      will be no patient identifiers in the data provided to the investigators, only the patient&#xD;
      number. The patient number is a number randomly assigned to the patient and is only&#xD;
      identifiable in the patient key, which will be kept separate as above.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A sample size of 16 per group achieve 80% power to detect a difference of 1.6 (16mm) VAS&#xD;
      comparing ketorolac tromethamine to triamcinolone acetonide intra-articular injections with&#xD;
      estimated standard deviations of 1.56 and with a significance level (alpha) of 0.05. There is&#xD;
      an expected drop-out rate of 20%, which implies a sample size of 20 subjects per group. Data&#xD;
      analysis will be performed by the principle investigator and associate investigator who will&#xD;
      be blinded to treatment until data analysis is complete.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Visual analogue scale (VAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 2 weeks, 6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Western Ontario and McMaster Universities Index (WOMAC)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 2 weeks, 6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Knee Society Score (KSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 2 weeks, 6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Tegner-Lysholm Knee Score (TLK)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 2 weeks, 6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Short Form (SF-36)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 2 weeks, 6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Knee Osteoarthritis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Visual analogue scale</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>visual analogue scale versus triamcinolone acetonide visual analogue scale versus ketorolac tromethamine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>visual analogue scale versus triamcinolone acetonide visual analogue scale versus ketorolac tromethamine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ketorolac Tromethamine</intervention_name>
    <description>anti-inflammatory injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Visual analogue scale</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Toradol</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Triamcinolone Acetonide</intervention_name>
    <description>corticosteroid injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Visual analogue scale</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Kenalog</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject must be at least 18 years of age and no older than 90 years of age; of either&#xD;
             gender&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiographic evidence of symptomatic osteoarthritis in one or bilateral knees.&#xD;
             Osteoarthritis will be defined as pain with weight-bearing at the tibiofemoral and/or&#xD;
             patellofemoral articulation together with radiographic findings as described below.&#xD;
&#xD;
        At the painful articulation, radiographic evidence of Kellgren-Lawrence&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grade 2: definite osteophytes and possible narrowing of joint cartilage associated&#xD;
             with sclerosis of subchondral bone or,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grade 3: moderate multiple osteophytes, definite narrowing of the joint space, small&#xD;
             pseudocystic areas with sclerotic walls in the subchondral bone, possible deformity of&#xD;
             bone ends or,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grade 4: large osteophytes, marked narrowing of joint space, severe sclerosis and&#xD;
             altered shape of the bone ends.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject agrees to participate in follow-up evaluations and complete outcome score sheets&#xD;
        (post-injection, 2 weeks, 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any inflammatory or neuropathic arthropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insufficiency of the collateral ligaments or cruciate ligaments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent injection (&lt;3 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant/lactating (β-human chorionic gonadotropin pregnancy test will be completed&#xD;
             prior to injection)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy or hypersensitivity to the study medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently taking any anti-coagulation medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is unable to make his/her own decision regarding the informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is unable to read/understand English&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Siraj Sayeed, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>San Antonio Military Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 12, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 19, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 20, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 19, 2014</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 19, 2014</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 20, 2014</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>San Antonio Military Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jaime L. Bellamy, DO</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Orthopaedic Resident Physician</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Triamcinolone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Triamcinolone Acetonide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Triamcinolone hexacetonide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ketorolac</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ketorolac Tromethamine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Triamcinolone diacetate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <pending_results>
    <submitted>December 2, 2015</submitted>
    <returned>January 7, 2016</returned>
  </pending_results>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

