<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04228497</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MD-87-2019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04228497</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ultrasound Assessment of Gastric Residual Volume in Children Scheduled for Elective Surgery After Clear Fluids Fasting for One Versus Two Hours: a Comparative Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Ultrasound Assessment of Gastric Residual Volume in Children Scheduled for Elective Surgery After Clear Fluids Fasting for One Versus Two Hours; a Comparative Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kasr El Aini Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kasr El Aini Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Ultrasound guided comparison of gastric residual volume after clear fluid fasting for one&#xD;
      versus two hours in pediatrics scheduled for elective surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The traditional 2-hour clear fluid fasting time was recommended by almost all anesthesia&#xD;
      societies [1-3] to decrease the risk of pulmonary aspiration. However, these recommendations&#xD;
      are based on historical adult literature [4,5] that may not be applicable to the pediatric&#xD;
      population. Moreover, recent studies have shown that these recommendations may not be&#xD;
      properly applied, and many children could have been starving for long intervals before&#xD;
      surgery with the current guidelines [6-8] which was associated with increased risk of post&#xD;
      induction hypotension during surgical preparation [9,10] There is a growing evidence that&#xD;
      more liberal clear fluids intake does not result in significant increase in the risk of&#xD;
      pulmonary aspiration [11,12] while children may have less thirst, hunger, anxiety,&#xD;
      postoperative nausea and vomiting[13-15] also, limiting the fasting time may improve the&#xD;
      perioperative inflammatory response in children [16].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hence, a consensus statement was issued by the Association of Pediatric Anesthetists of Great&#xD;
      Britain and Ireland (APAGBI), the European Society of Pediatric Anesthetists and the&#xD;
      French-Language Society of Pediatric Anesthesiologists; encouraging clear fluids to be given&#xD;
      up to 1 hour before elective general anesthesia [17] which was followed by the Canadian&#xD;
      Pediatric Anesthesia Society (CAPS) statement in 2019 [18], however, these statements have&#xD;
      not been translated into guidelines to date until further evidence is released.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Gastric residual volume GRV can be used as a preoperative tool for assessment of the risk of&#xD;
      perioperative pulmonary aspiration in clinical practice [19]. Many methods have been used to&#xD;
      assess gastric volume in pediatrics including nasogastric aspiration [20] , magnetic&#xD;
      resonance imaging (MRI) and ultrasound[19,21]. Of these, only ultrasound is of clinical&#xD;
      utility because it is simple, bedside, reliable [22], safe tool and allows both qualitative&#xD;
      and quantitative assessment of gastric contents [19,23,24].&#xD;
&#xD;
      So, we aim to assess GRV in pediatrics having clear fluids fasting for one hour before&#xD;
      elective surgery. We hypothesize that clear fluids fasting for one hour will not result in a&#xD;
      clinically significant increase in GRV compared to two hours fasting for children scheduled&#xD;
      for elective surgery under general anesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following approval from Research and Ethics Committee of anesthesia department, Faculty of&#xD;
      Medicine, Cairo University. An informed consent will be obtained from parent/care giver prior&#xD;
      to commencement of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria are children aged 3-10 years of both sexes, ASA physical state I and II,&#xD;
      scheduled for non-gastrointestinal (GIT) elective day-case surgery under general anesthesia&#xD;
      and fasting for 6 to 8 hours or more for solids. Exclusion criteria are parent or care giver&#xD;
      refusal, children with gastro-esophageal reflux disease or any disease that impairs gastric&#xD;
      motility and children scheduled for emergency surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be randomly allocated by a computer-generated table into one of the two study&#xD;
      groups; the randomization sequence will be concealed in sealed envelopes. Patients and&#xD;
      anesthetist doing the ultrasound examination will be blinded to group assignment. The sealed&#xD;
      envelopes will be opened in the preparation room by an anesthesia nurse responsible for&#xD;
      preparation and offering the fluid to the children depending on the group allocation but not&#xD;
      involved in the study data collection. Children fasting for 6 to 8 hours or more for solids&#xD;
      only are allowed to drink 3 mL/kg to a maximum of 250 ml of apple juice one hour before&#xD;
      surgery in (1-hour group) and two hours before surgery in (2-hours group) .Volume of given&#xD;
      &quot;apple juice&quot; will be calculated by a 50 mL scaled clean syringe then poured into a clean&#xD;
      cups and offered to the children. Parent/ care giver will be allowed to accompany her/his&#xD;
      child during the examination period to alleviate anxiety and ensure compliance of children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After appropriate time passed, children will be allowed to assess their level of thirst on a&#xD;
      10 cm VAS scale where 0 point is no thirst which will be clarified by laughing face and 10&#xD;
      point is the worst thirst and will be clarified by a crying face. In addition, the parents&#xD;
      will grade their child's thirst on a scale of 0-10. Eligible children weight and height will&#xD;
      be then measured prior to the examination by a scale and a measuring tape.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ultrasound examination will be performed using a high frequency (5-10 MHz) ultrasound probe&#xD;
      (S-NerveTM; SonoSite Inc., Bothell, WA, USA) or a curvilinear (2-5 MHz) probe as appropriate&#xD;
      depending on the child weight and age. Children in both groups will be scanned in two&#xD;
      positions: supine position and right lateral position (RLP) exactly one and two hours&#xD;
      following the clear fluid intake and before admission to the operation room in groups 1H and&#xD;
      2H respectively. All gastric ultrasound assessments will be completed by the same&#xD;
      investigator, who is an anesthetist with 3 years' experience in ultrasound for vascular&#xD;
      access and regional anesthesia in pediatric patients. Gastric antrum will be located in the&#xD;
      sagittal plane with simultaneous identification of left lobe of the liver and the descending&#xD;
      abdominal aorta or inferior vena cava.&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to its shape and contents, the antrum will be considered to be either empty (if it&#xD;
      was flat with juxtaposed anterior and posterior walls), fluid-containing (if it was&#xD;
      distended, with thin walls and hypoechoic content), or solid-containing (if it was distended&#xD;
      with a content of mixed echogenicity).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The antral cross-sectional area (CSA) will be calculated after measuring the two dimensions&#xD;
      of the antrum (D1 and D2) according to the following equation: π [D1 × D2] /4, where D1 and&#xD;
      D2 are the anteroposterior and craniocaudal diameters, respectively. Measurements will always&#xD;
      done from the outer layer of the gastric wall, and all images were obtained between&#xD;
      peristaltic contractions. Three measurements will be collected, and average values were used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The gastric residual volume (GRV) will be calculated using a mathematical model previously&#xD;
      validated in the pediatric population [25] as follows :&#xD;
&#xD;
      Gastric residual volume (ml/kg) = [-7.8 + (0.035 ×RLP CSA (mm2) + 0.127 × age (months)]/ body&#xD;
      weight (kg)&#xD;
&#xD;
      For quantitative assessment of the risk of aspiration, we will use the classification&#xD;
      previously settled by (Van de Putte and Perlas 2014) [24] as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Low risk of aspiration: children with empty antrum and or children with gastric residual&#xD;
           volume less than 1.5 mL/Kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  High risk of aspiration: children with solid contents and or children with gastric&#xD;
           residual volume more than 1.5 mL/Kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the child has high risk of aspiration, the surgery would be postponed for one hour before&#xD;
      another reassessment of the antrum and gastric residual volume.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anesthetic management:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Upon arrival to the operation room; continuous electrocardiography (ECG), pulse oximetry,&#xD;
      non-invasive arterial blood pressure will be applied then general anesthesia will be induced&#xD;
      by an experienced pediatric anesthetist who is blinded to the patient group using a&#xD;
      controlled rapid sequence induction RSI technique (children in a 20° head up position during&#xD;
      preoxygenation and Induction, rapid hypnosis, non-depolarizing muscle relaxant, gentle mask&#xD;
      ventilation using Ayres T piece, laryngoscopy, and finally intubation when full motor&#xD;
      blockade occurred) [26]. If the patient had no intravenous (IV) cannula; anesthesia will&#xD;
      start using titration of 4-8% sevoflurane and 50% air in oxygen using Ayres T piece without&#xD;
      positive pressure until the child was put to sleep, peripheral venous cannula will then&#xD;
      inserted and anesthesia waill be completed using 0.5-1 mg/kg of propofol. If a patient had an&#xD;
      (IV) cannula in place, induction will be performed using 1.5-2.5 mg/kg propofol, in both&#xD;
      situations atracurium at a dose of 0.5 mg/kg will be given intravenously to facilitate&#xD;
      endotracheal intubation and fentanyl at a dose 2 µg/kg was given to abolish stress response&#xD;
      of intubation. The trachea will be then intubated when full motor blockade occurred.&#xD;
      Aspiration will be defined as any documentation of vomiting, gastric material in the airway&#xD;
      during induction till intubation and confirmation of the endotracheal tube ETT using&#xD;
      capnography.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome of study will be GRV in right lateral position after one-hour clear fluid&#xD;
      intake.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary outcomes are antral cross-sectional area in supine and RLP after one-hour clear&#xD;
      fluid intake, antral cross-sectional area in right lateral and supine positions after two&#xD;
      hours clear fluid intake, frequency of high risk and low risk of aspiration and qualitative&#xD;
      grading for assessment of gastric antrum: three-point as follows: Grade 0: empty antrum,&#xD;
      Grade 1: minimal fluid detected in right lateral position only, Grade 2: distended antrum in&#xD;
      both semi-sitting and right lateral positions [27]. Incidence of aspiration and or vomiting&#xD;
      during induction of anesthesia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 10, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 10, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>GRV in right lateral position after one-hour clear fluid intake.</measure>
    <time_frame>one-hour of clear fluid intake</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antral cross-sectional area in right lateral position after one-hour clear fluid intake</measure>
    <time_frame>one-hour clear fluid intake</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antral cross-sectional area in right lateral and supine positions after two hours clear fluid intake</measure>
    <time_frame>two hours clear fluid intake</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gastric residual volume in supine position in both groups</measure>
    <time_frame>one hour after clear fluid intake</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Grade of aspiration risk (frequency of high risk and low risk)</measure>
    <time_frame>one and two hours after clear fluid intake</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Qualitative grading for assessment of gastric antrum: three-point grading will be evaluated</measure>
    <time_frame>one and two hours after clear fluid intake</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>incidence of aspiration and or vomiting</measure>
    <time_frame>10 minutes from induction of anesthesia</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">226</enrollment>
  <condition>Gastric Emptying</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>clear fluids fasting for one hour</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>children fasting for 6 to 8 hours will be allowed to drink 3 mL/kg of apple juice to a maximum of 250 ml one hour before surgery</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>clear fluids fasting for two hours</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>children fasting for 6 to 8 hours will be allowed to drink 3 mL/kg of apple juice to a maximum of 250 ml two hours before surgery</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>gastric ultrasound</intervention_name>
    <description>Children in both groups will be scanned in two positions: supine position and right lateral position (RLP) one and two hours following the clear fluid intake and before admission to the operation room in groups 1 and 2 respectively. Gastric antrum will be located in the sagittal plane with simultaneous identification of left lobe of the liver and the descending abdominal aorta or inferior vena cava.</description>
    <arm_group_label>clear fluids fasting for one hour</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>clear fluids fasting for two hours</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>the clear fluid intake</intervention_name>
    <description>the clear fluid intake</description>
    <arm_group_label>clear fluids fasting for one hour</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>clear fluids fasting for two hours</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • ASA physical state I or II&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Age 3 to 10 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Gender: both sexes.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Scheduled for non-GIT elective day-case surgery under general anesthesia with&#xD;
                  endotracheal intubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Parent/ care giver refusal&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ages &lt; 3 or &gt; 10 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Children with gastro-esophageal reflux disease (GORD): either on treatment or&#xD;
                  under investigation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Renal failure, Diabetes mellitus and cerebral palsy patients&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Esophageal strictures, achalasia or any intestinal disease that may impair the&#xD;
                  gastric emptying.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  GIT surgery and neurosurgical patients&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Emergency surgery&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Khaled A Sarhan, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Lecturer of anesthesia, Cairo university</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kasralainy</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 13, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Kasr El Aini Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Khaled Abdelfattah Abdallah Sarhan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Gastric residual volume; children; ultrasound; fasting</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

