<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01618630</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>12-048</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01618630</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Amino Acid Supplementation in Recovery From Severe Burns</brief_title>
  <acronym>ExAA</acronym>
  <official_title>Amino Acid Benefits in Pediatric Burn Patients Who Participate in Exercise.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Shriners Hospitals for Children</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Exercise during recovery is now Standard of Care at Shriners Hospital for Children Galveston,&#xD;
      since positive effects of exercise training were found on lean body mass and recovery after&#xD;
      burns. Essential amino acids (EAA) effective in healthy individuals.Thus, EAA supplementation&#xD;
      in children recovering from burns, may potentially augment the effects of exercise by&#xD;
      increase muscle mass, improve muscle fat oxidation, reduce tissue fat, and possibly improve&#xD;
      insulin resistance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Severe burns result in persistent and extensive fat deposition in liver and muscle tissue.&#xD;
      This may be related to the prolonged insulin resistance observed following burn. In this&#xD;
      study the investigators will test the hypothesis that essential amino acids act in synergy&#xD;
      with exercise to improve liver steatosis and muscle lipid metabolism, and thus also affect&#xD;
      insulin sensitivity. Children with burns will participate in six weeks of exercise training&#xD;
      with/without amino acid supplementation. Before and after the intervention, measurements will&#xD;
      be done to determine muscle and liver fat content, muscle fat and protein metabolism, and&#xD;
      insulin sensitivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will prospectively enroll 40 children with ≥30% of their total body surface area (TBSA)&#xD;
      burned. The age range will be 7-17 years. Children will be recruited from Shriners Hospitals&#xD;
      for Children (SHC)-Galveston. Burned children will be randomized to undergo an exercise&#xD;
      program in combination with daily intake of EAA (n=20) or a placebo drink (n=20). The&#xD;
      exercise program and daily intake of AA will begin within the first week of discharge from&#xD;
      the burn ICU (approximately 1-3 months post burn, when the patient's wounds are 95% healed).&#xD;
      The definition of 95% healed is 7 days after the final autografting procedure. We anticipate&#xD;
      enrolling 10 children per year for 4 years. Only children meeting the inclusion and exclusion&#xD;
      criteria specified in the Human Subjects Section will be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nutritional Supplement: The nutritional supplement will be administered at a dose of 0.18&#xD;
      g/kg body weight of amino acids two times per day with the following composition: 3%&#xD;
      histidine, 9% isoleucine, 36% leucine, 17% lysine, 4% methionine, 5% phenylalanine, 10%&#xD;
      threonine, 7% valine, and 10% arginine. The dose and choice of amino acids is based on our&#xD;
      preliminary data. Each dose is about 0.03 g/kg body weight higher than what has been shown&#xD;
      effective in adults, as children have higher protein needs. We have shown that only EAA are&#xD;
      needed to affect muscle protein synthesis and lean mass. Thus the amount given (g or kcal)&#xD;
      can be restricted. As in our preliminary studies, we will include arginine in the EAA&#xD;
      mixture, since arginine may have unique anabolic effects (55; 86). Placebo will consist of a&#xD;
      mixture of inert components (sucralose and other pharmaceutical excipients). The supplement&#xD;
      will be taken in two daily doses in the form of drinks (total daily dose of i.e., 0.30 g/kg&#xD;
      body weight total per day), and intake recorded in a diary. The first dose will be taken&#xD;
      between breakfast and lunch, and the second between lunch and dinner. For the children&#xD;
      exercising before lunch, the first dose of EAA will be ingested immediately after exercise.&#xD;
      Correspondingly, for children exercising after lunch, the second EAA dose of the day will be&#xD;
      ingested immediately after exercise. If the child forgets to take one of the drinks during&#xD;
      the day, he/she may take the second one between dinner and bedtime. During the weekends,&#xD;
      parents/caregivers are instructed to take the dosage around the same time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Analysis and Interpretation. To determine effects of amino acids on fat and muscle lipid&#xD;
      stores, changes from pre- to post intervention in the two groups will be compared using&#xD;
      ANCOVA. From the preliminary data, we expect that amino acids will decrease liver and plasma&#xD;
      lipids.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 5, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 5, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Lean Muscle Mass</measure>
    <time_frame>It is the change in time, from baseline until post exercise. Baseline is within the first week of discharge from the burn ICU, approximately 1-3 months post burn. Exercise training is 6-12 weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>Is the total weight of your body minus all the weight due to your fat mass. It is measured in kilograms by dual X-ray absorptiometry scan.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>whole body lipolysis rate</measure>
    <time_frame>It is the change in time, from baseline until post exercise. Baseline is within the first week of discharge from the burn ICU, approximately 1-3 months post burn. Exercise training is 6-12 weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>A euglycemic-hyperinsulinemic clamp is performed over the last 2hr of the 4-hr isotope infusion. It is measured in μmol/kg body weight/min</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hepatic glucose release rate and whole body glucose uptake rate</measure>
    <time_frame>It is the change in time, from baseline until post exercise. Baseline is within the first week of discharge from the burn ICU, approximately 1-3 months post burn. Exercise training is 6-12 weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>A primed, constant (0.44 μmol/kg/min) infusion of [6,6-2H2]-glucose is used for glucose kinetics. A euglycemic-hyperinsulinemic clamp is performed over the last 2h of the 4-hr isotope infusion.It is measured in μmol/kg body weight/min.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Burn Injury</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>EAA Supplementation + Exercise Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drink an amino acid supplementation during exercise training.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo + Exercise Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drink a placebo supplementation during exercise training.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>EAA Supplementation + Exercise Training</intervention_name>
    <description>Amino acids in drinks between meals for exercise training period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>EAA Supplementation + Exercise Training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo + Exercise Training</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo supplementation as drinks in between meals for exercise training period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo + Exercise Training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. 7-17 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Body weight &gt;20 kg (based on blood requirements)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ≥30% Total Body Surface Area (TBSA)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Wounds 95% healed&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Respiratory insufficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Multiple fractures&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of Cancer in the last 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Diabetes Mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Bilirubin &gt; 3 mg/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Associated head injuries requiring specific therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Associated injuries to chest or abdomen requiring surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Serum creatinine &gt; 3 mg/dl after fluid resuscitation&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Receipt of any experimental drug other than the ones supplied within two months of&#xD;
             this study&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Any metal in body including rods, cardiac defibrillator, pacemakers, etc&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Orthopedic casting which would prevent placement of patient in MRI machine&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Hepatitis&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Abnormal EKG&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Electrical burns&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Patients unable to lie still without heavy sedation will be excluded from MRI portion.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Oscar E Suman, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UTMB, Shriners Hospitals for Children</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Shriners Hospitals for Children</name>
      <address>
        <city>Galveston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77550</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 30, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 11, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 13, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 7, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 7, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>burn injury</keyword>
  <keyword>children</keyword>
  <keyword>nutrition</keyword>
  <keyword>lipid metabolism</keyword>
  <keyword>insulin sensitivity</keyword>
  <keyword>amino acids</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Burns</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

