<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02753101</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>32231</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02753101</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>[18F]FTC-146 PET/MRI in Healthy Volunteers and in CRPS and Sciatica</brief_title>
  <official_title>Biodistribution and Pharmacokinetic Determination of the PET Radiopharmaceutical [18F]FTC-146 Using PET/MRI in Healthy (Asymptomatic) Volunteers and in Patients With CRPS and Sciatica</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Stanford University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Mississippi Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Stanford University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic pain can result from injured or inflamed nerves, as occurs in people suffering from&#xD;
      sciatica and CRPS. These nerve injuries or regions of nerve irritation are often the cause of&#xD;
      pain in these conditions, but the current diagnostic tools are limited in pinpointing the&#xD;
      area of origin. Several studies have implicated involvement of sigma-1 receptors in the&#xD;
      generation and perpetuation of chronic pain conditions, others are investigating anti sigma-1&#xD;
      receptor drugs for the treatment of chronic pain. Using the sigma-1 receptor (S1R) detector&#xD;
      and experimental radiotracer [18F]FTC-146 and positron emission tomography/magnetic resonance&#xD;
      imaging (PET/MRI) scanner, the researchers may potentially identify the source of pain&#xD;
      generation in patients suffering from complex regional pain syndrome (CRPS) and chronic&#xD;
      sciatica. The ultimate goal is to assist in the optimization of pain treatment regimens using&#xD;
      an [18F]FTC-146 PET/MRI scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is not designed to induce any physiological/pharmacological effect.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Participants are either pain free (control) or will be recruited based on established&#xD;
      criteria for sciatica or CRPS. A signed consent will be obtained from willing participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the PET/MRI scan, the participants will be injected with [18F]FTC-146 intravenously.&#xD;
      After injection, simultaneous PET and MRI scans will be acquired using a hybrid PET/MRI&#xD;
      scanner. Throughout scanning, participants will be monitored for blood pressure, temperature,&#xD;
      heart rate and pulse oximetry. Participants will be asked to void their bladder as frequently&#xD;
      as they can to reduce radiation exposure. Following the scan, participants will be contacted&#xD;
      to check for adverse drug events, and any events will be recorded in the case report.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Evidence in the literature points strongly toward an involvement of S1 receptors in nervous&#xD;
      system inflammation, which is known to be an important biologic disease/disorder mechanism&#xD;
      for maintenance and perpetuation of chronic pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main purpose of this research study is to image and identify activated pain pathways in&#xD;
      human subjects using [18F]FTC-146 PET/MRI.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 9, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 16, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 9, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Biodistribution of [18F]FTC-146</measure>
    <time_frame>an estimated average of 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Biodistribution of [18F]FTC-146 will be analyzed by drawing regions of interest (ROI) for the reported organs on the PET/MRI images. Processing software will quantify the amount of [18F]FTC-146 uptake within the ROI's and display the amount in terms of standardized uptake values (SUV's).&#xD;
Biodistribution data will be obtained by drawing regions of interest (ROI's) around organs on the PET/MRI images. Processing software will quantify the amount of [18F]FTC-146 uptake within the ROI's and display the amount in terms of standardized uptake values (SUV's).&#xD;
Pharmacokinetic data will be calculated using kinetic analysis (mathematical modeling) of [18F]FTC-146 clearance from the blood.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dosimetry of [18F]FTC-146</measure>
    <time_frame>an estimated average of 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Dosimetry calculations will be determined using the biodistribution (reported as a primary outcome measure) and pharmacokinetics of the tracer in human organs.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and up to 7 days after tracer injection</time_frame>
    <description>[18F]FTC-146 Single IV Treatment-Emergent Adverse Events will be established by collectively assessing real-time vitals monitoring during scans, serial clinical lab work (i.e. blood tests), and patient symptomatic report at baseline and up to 7 days post-injection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Complex Regional Pain Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Sciatica</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>[18F]-FTC-146</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>[18F]-FTC-146</intervention_name>
    <description>10 mCi± 1 mCi of [18F]FTC-146 intravenously</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Sigma-1 receptor radioligand</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        General:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Either male or female&#xD;
&#xD;
        Sciatica:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of pain shooting down a leg below the knee, to the foot or toes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Visual analog scale (VAS) at enrollment of &gt;4 with leg pain greater in intensity than&#xD;
             the back pain&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Focal disc herniation on MRI correlating with radicular symptoms defined as pain or&#xD;
             paresthesias into the leg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Examination with correlating radicular signs defined as any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pain reproduction with straight-leg-raising (pain shooting down the leg with less than&#xD;
             60 degrees elevation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  radicular pattern sensory changes (such as numbness or paresthesias) in the same area&#xD;
             as pain&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  signs of radiculopathy (weakened hallux extension and/or Achilles tendon reflex)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The above inclusion criteria can be met OR individuals who have been determined to&#xD;
             have a very high clinical suspicion of having Sciatica as determined by the referring&#xD;
             pain specialist can be included. This suspicion will be documented in the patient's&#xD;
             medical record.&#xD;
&#xD;
        CRPS:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Disease duration of 6 months or longer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Continuing pain, which is disproportionate to any inciting event&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must report at least one symptom in three of the four following categories:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Sensory: Reports of hyperesthesia and/or allodynia&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Vasomotor: Reports of temperature asymmetry and/or skin color changes and/or skin&#xD;
                  color asymmetry&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Sudomotor/Edema: Reports of edema and/or sweating changes and/or sweating&#xD;
                  asymmetry&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Motor/Trophic: Reports of decreased range of motion and/or motor dysfunction&#xD;
                  (weakness, tremor, dystonia) and/or trophic changes (hair, nail, skin)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must display at least one sign at time of evaluation In two or more of the following&#xD;
             categories:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Sensory: Evidence of hyperalgesia (to pinprick) and/or allodynia (to light touch&#xD;
                  and/or temperature sensation and/or deep somatic pressure and/or joint movement)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Vasomotor: Evidence of temperature asymmetry ( &gt;1°C) and/or skin color changes&#xD;
                  and/or asymmetry&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Sudomotor/Edema: Evidence of edema and/or sweating changes and/or sweating&#xD;
                  asymmetry&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Motor/Trophic: Evidence of decreased range of motion and/or motor dysfunction&#xD;
                  (weakness, tremor, dystonia) and/or trophic changes (hair, nail, skin)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  There is no other diagnosis that better explains the signs and symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For research purposes, diagnostic decision rule will be at least one symptom in all&#xD;
             four symptom categories and at least one sign (observed at evaluation) in two or more&#xD;
             sign categories.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The above inclusion criteria can be met OR individuals who have been determined to&#xD;
             have a very high clinical suspicion of having CRPS as determined by the referring pain&#xD;
             specialist can be included. This suspicion will be documented in the patient's medical&#xD;
             record.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        General:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Another active disorder which could explain the symptoms in the opinions of the&#xD;
             investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of MRI-incompatible materials/devices&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any medication that may affect pain or 18F-FTC-146 uptake or adverse drug interactions&#xD;
             with steroids or amino amide local anesthetics (e.g. lidocaine, bupivacaine,&#xD;
             ropivacaine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or nursing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing menstrual period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe comorbid conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to read or complete questionnaires in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition, which in the opinion of the investigator would impede compliance&#xD;
             or hinder completion of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Sciatica:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that may interfere with interpretation of 18F-FTC-146 uptake in the&#xD;
             region of the pelvis, thighs or lower spine including, but not limited to,&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Spinal, hip or pelvic surgery or prosthesis&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Radiation therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Autoimmune disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Current infections&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Inability to void bladder completely, such as in prostatic enlargement&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Any urinary retention, such as in outlet obstruction, hydronephrosis etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Cauda equina syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Developmental spinal deformities&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. Scoliosis &gt;20 degrees&#xD;
&#xD;
              11. Spondylolysis&#xD;
&#xD;
              12. Vertebral fractures&#xD;
&#xD;
              13. Inflammatory spondylopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
              14. Prior lumbar surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
                  CRPS:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of current or past pulmonary, hepatic, renal disease, arthritis,&#xD;
             hematopoietic, and neurological diseases not related to CRPS.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sandip Biswal, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Stanford University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stanford</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94305</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>James ML, Shen B, Nielsen CH, Behera D, Buckmaster CL, Mesangeau C, Zavaleta C, Vuppala PK, Jamalapuram S, Avery BA, Lyons DM, McCurdy CR, Biswal S, Gambhir SS, Chin FT. Evaluation of σ-1 receptor radioligand 18F-FTC-146 in rats and squirrel monkeys using PET. J Nucl Med. 2014 Jan;55(1):147-53. doi: 10.2967/jnumed.113.120261. Epub 2013 Dec 12.</citation>
    <PMID>24337599</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>James ML, Shen B, Zavaleta CL, Nielsen CH, Mesangeau C, Vuppala PK, Chan C, Avery BA, Fishback JA, Matsumoto RR, Gambhir SS, McCurdy CR, Chin FT. New positron emission tomography (PET) radioligand for imaging σ-1 receptors in living subjects. J Med Chem. 2012 Oct 11;55(19):8272-8282. doi: 10.1021/jm300371c. Epub 2012 Sep 20.</citation>
    <PMID>22853801</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fletcher JW, Djulbegovic B, Soares HP, Siegel BA, Lowe VJ, Lyman GH, Coleman RE, Wahl R, Paschold JC, Avril N, Einhorn LH, Suh WW, Samson D, Delbeke D, Gorman M, Shields AF. Recommendations on the use of 18F-FDG PET in oncology. J Nucl Med. 2008 Mar;49(3):480-508. doi: 10.2967/jnumed.107.047787. Epub 2008 Feb 20.</citation>
    <PMID>18287273</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Puente B, Nadal X, Portillo-Salido E, Sánchez-Arroyos R, Ovalle S, Palacios G, Muro A, Romero L, Entrena JM, Baeyens JM, López-García JA, Maldonado R, Zamanillo D, Vela JM. Sigma-1 receptors regulate activity-induced spinal sensitization and neuropathic pain after peripheral nerve injury. Pain. 2009 Oct;145(3):294-303. doi: 10.1016/j.pain.2009.05.013. Epub 2009 Jun 7.</citation>
    <PMID>19505761</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Entrena JM, Cobos EJ, Nieto FR, Cendán CM, Gris G, Del Pozo E, Zamanillo D, Baeyens JM. Sigma-1 receptors are essential for capsaicin-induced mechanical hypersensitivity: studies with selective sigma-1 ligands and sigma-1 knockout mice. Pain. 2009 Jun;143(3):252-261. doi: 10.1016/j.pain.2009.03.011. Epub 2009 Apr 17.</citation>
    <PMID>19375855</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Maurer AH. Combined imaging modalities: PET/CT and SPECT/CT. Health Phys. 2008 Nov;95(5):571-6. doi: 10.1097/01.HP.0000334064.46217.20.</citation>
    <PMID>18849691</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 22, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 22, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 27, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 1, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 1, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 5, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Stanford University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sandip Biswal</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Positron Emission Tomography</keyword>
  <keyword>Magnetic Resonance Imaging</keyword>
  <keyword>PET/MRI</keyword>
  <keyword>sigma-1 receptor</keyword>
  <keyword>radiopharmaceutical</keyword>
  <keyword>complex regional pain syndrome</keyword>
  <keyword>sciatica</keyword>
  <keyword>chronic pain</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Complex Regional Pain Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Reflex Sympathetic Dystrophy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sciatica</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

