<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02677974</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2015-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02677974</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>On-X Aortic Prosthetic Heart Valve Low Dose Warfarin Post Approval Clinical Registry Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>On-X Aortic Prosthetic Heart Valve Low Dose Warfarin Post Approval Clinical Registry Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>On-X Life Technologies, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>North American Science Associates Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>On-X Life Technologies, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of the proposed study is to assess the occurrence of bleeding, valve-related&#xD;
      thromboembolism and valve thrombosis with the On-X Aortic Prosthetic Heart Valve when&#xD;
      targeted at an International Normalized Ratio (INR) level of 1.8 (1.5-2.0 range) during a&#xD;
      5-year follow-up period. The objective will be to compare adverse event rates for patients in&#xD;
      subgroups as listed below targeted at 1.8 (range 1.5 to 2.0) per On-X instructions for use to&#xD;
      rates from the previous IDE trial (G050208).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is a prospective, multicenter, observational single arm study of newly-enrolled&#xD;
      patients treated with the On-X Aortic Prosthetic Heart Valve. Assuming 20% attrition over 5&#xD;
      years and 40% of enrolled patients will be high risk home monitoring patients, 510 patients&#xD;
      will be enrolled in the study. Patients will be under standard anticoagulation (INR 2.5&#xD;
      (2.0-3.0 range)) for at least 3 months before initiation of low dose (INR 1.8 (1.5-2.0&#xD;
      range)) anticoagulation treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All centers will follow a common protocol in which eligible patients will be entered into the&#xD;
      registry within 1 year after receiving the On-X Aortic Prosthetic Heart Valve. No special&#xD;
      diagnostic or therapeutic procedures will be done for the purposes of the protocol and data&#xD;
      will be collected prospectively on each patient for 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data from all consenting patients at participating sites receiving the On-X Aortic Prosthetic&#xD;
      Heart Valve will be entered into an online registry database. Patients will be recruited&#xD;
      postoperatively within 1 year, most typically at the first post-discharge visit at between 2&#xD;
      and 6 weeks but also by special visit to their surgeon if agreed. Low dose therapy will begin&#xD;
      no earlier than 3 months postop. Data entry is non-randomized, and continues until the sample&#xD;
      size requirements are met and the enrollment into the registry is closed. To minimize bias&#xD;
      all patients meeting the inclusion/exclusion criteria will be recruited and those agreeing to&#xD;
      participate in the follow-up will be entered into the database. A screen failure log of those&#xD;
      patients not agreeing to participate will be kept and entered identifying reasons for&#xD;
      declined enrollment. Once entered patients will be analyzed as a whole and separated into&#xD;
      groups by TE risk factors and warfarin monitoring method. All patients that have no&#xD;
      contraindication for aspirin will be prescribed a daily 'baby' aspirin (75-100mg) for&#xD;
      consistency to prior research and to current society guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary hypothesis for the registry is to confirm the results seen in the IDE trial,&#xD;
      showing that using home monitoring or anticoagulation clinic with an INR target of 1.8 (range&#xD;
      1.5 to 2.0) does not significantly increase patient risk relative to current standard of&#xD;
      practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary analysis will compare the overall composite event rate for the following events:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Thromboembolism (TE)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Valve thrombosis (VT)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Major bleeding&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each of the component events and the combination of TE plus VT will be examined separately as&#xD;
      secondary endpoints.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample size for the registry was calculated with the following assumptions:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Incidence of composite outcome estimated via Poisson regression&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  1-sided test comparing the composite outcome to the reference value&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  5% significance level&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  90% power&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Expected overall composite proportion from the IDE high risk treatment group (pT) =&#xD;
           0.0457/patient-year (ptyr)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Reference value (p95, upper 95% confidence bound from PROACT study) = 0.0693/ptyr&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  800 patient-years of follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Anticipated 5 years of follow-up per subject&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Loss to follow-up over 5 years of 20%&#xD;
&#xD;
      The resulting enrollment target is 510 subjects, which would result in approximately 816&#xD;
      patient-years in the high-risk home-monitoring group. These subjects will be recruited from&#xD;
      at least 15 clinical centers and no more than 35 centers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sponsor will provide a secure Part 11 compliant online database for entry of required&#xD;
      preoperative, operative, follow-up and adverse event data. All appropriate sections of the&#xD;
      registry must be filled out accurately and completely.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To protect patient confidentiality, the sponsor will use the information from the registry&#xD;
      for statistical purposes related to the hypothesis of the trial only and will not routinely&#xD;
      collect all source document medical records, and when such records may be collected they will&#xD;
      be de-identified, i.e. for adjudication of adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The statistical plan provided in this section follows generally the AATS/STS guidance which&#xD;
      is referenced by both FDA and international standards as containing the preferred methods of&#xD;
      analyzing heart valve study data. As the primary and secondary endpoints of this study are&#xD;
      exclusively adverse events, the methods used to analyze these endpoints will be those&#xD;
      specifically used with adverse events. The objective performance criteria (OPC) generally&#xD;
      used for premarket studies will not be used in this post-approval study in preference of&#xD;
      comparisons to rates calculated within AVR control arms of the prior IDE trial (G050208).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The cohort will be analyzed as a whole and in subgroups based on INR monitoring method and TE&#xD;
      risk category where TE risk is defined by the clinical and laboratory criteria of G050208,&#xD;
      except that history of known hypercoagulability will be acceptable for documentation and no&#xD;
      new blood testing for such hypercoagulability will be required. Confounding factors to be&#xD;
      examined include age at implant (under 50, 50-65 inclusive, over 65), gender, preoperative&#xD;
      NYHA classification, occurrence of concomitant or prior cardiac surgery (including stent&#xD;
      placement) and valve size (21 or less, 23 or more).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Early events will be presented as simple percentages. In this study early events will be&#xD;
      presented in three categories: first the standard 30-day postop or date of discharge&#xD;
      (whichever is longer) category, second the 3-months prior to eligibility for home monitoring&#xD;
      category and third the period prior to enrollment (up to 1 year depending upon the patient).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Late events will be determined from the time of shift to low INR and the possible time for&#xD;
      initiation of home monitoring when done. Late event analyses will be conducted by two&#xD;
      methods: linearized rates (to cover total independent events) and Kaplan-Meier life tables&#xD;
      (to cover time to first event).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A steering committee for the registry shall include at least 4 members with at least 2&#xD;
      cardiac surgeons, 1 cardiologist and 1 statistician. The committee shall provide input into&#xD;
      the study conduct and any changes to study design, data elements required or statistical&#xD;
      procedures to be used in analyses. They shall also review any publication that arises from&#xD;
      the registry. The members will be identified prior to commencing enrollment in the registry.&#xD;
      The committee will also either act as or appoint a separate clinical event committee (CEC)&#xD;
      consisting of at least 2 experienced clinical investigators not participating in the&#xD;
      registry. CEC members may be members of the steering committee but may also be in addition to&#xD;
      the steering committee. Both steering committee and CEC will operate from an established&#xD;
      charter for quality assurance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The anticipated uses of the data collected will be FDA and other regulatory review as part of&#xD;
      post approval study requirements and the publication of the aggregated data in peer reviewed&#xD;
      meetings or journals. It is expected that the registry will be fully enrolled within 1 year&#xD;
      after the last site is enrolled and that follow-up will be limited to 5 years per patient.&#xD;
      Once fully enrolled the registry will be closed to further entry of patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 10, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>5 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Thrombotic events</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Rates of occurrence for thromboembolism and/or thrombosis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Major bleeds</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Event rates for major bleeds</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Death</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>All cause mortality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">510</enrollment>
  <condition>Thrombotic and Bleeding Events</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>On-X Aortic Heart Valve replacement</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with On-X Aortic Valve maintained on low dose warfarin anticoagulation with an INR target of 1.5 to 2.0, with or without home monitoring.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>On-X Aortic Heart Valve replacement</intervention_name>
    <description>Aortic valve replacement with low dose warfarin</description>
    <arm_group_label>On-X Aortic Heart Valve replacement</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with On-X aortic heart valve replacements implanted within the prior year.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adult patients (age 18 years or older) who have only an On-X aortic prosthetic heart&#xD;
             valve (ONXA, ONXAE, ONXAC, ONXACE, ONXAN, ONXANE) implant, without or without&#xD;
             concomitant procedures, and agreed to participate in the registry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Life expectancy of at least 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients whose operation occurred within the year prior to recruitment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients having any other type of prosthetic valve implant (isolated or in combination&#xD;
             with another valve(s)) or any On-X mitral valve; i.e. no mitral or multiple valve&#xD;
             implants.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with a prior history of arterial thromboembolic events, or who have such&#xD;
             events or On-X valve thrombosis after AVR and prior to recruitment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Death prior to discharge or recruitment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients whose surgery predates enrollment by more than 1 year.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Goeff Tsang, MBChB</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Southampton University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yael Goode, BA</last_name>
    <phone>845-480-0137</phone>
    <email>Goode.Yael@cryolife.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gretchen Wilderspin, MS</last_name>
    <phone>678-290-4309</phone>
    <email>Wilderspin.Gretchen@cryolife.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Arizona Cardiothoracic &amp; Neurology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tucson</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85718</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tiphanie Worthington</last_name>
      <phone>520-838-2115</phone>
      <email>Tiphanie.Worthington@pimaheart.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Raj Bose</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hartford Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hartford</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06102</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Cynthia Marques</last_name>
      <phone>860-972-5798</phone>
      <email>Cynthia.Marques@hhchealth.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Robert Hagberg, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Franciscan St. Francis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46237</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Stephanie Alford</last_name>
      <phone>317-893-1712</phone>
      <email>Stephanie.Alford@franciscanalliance.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marc Gerdisch, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kentucky</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lexington</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40356</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Joseph Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lexington</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40504</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Our Lady of the Lake</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baton Rouge</city>
        <state>Louisiana</state>
        <zip>70608</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Maine Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Maine</state>
        <zip>04102</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Betsey Gallant</last_name>
      <phone>207-662-1489</phone>
      <email>BGallant@mmc.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Reed Quinn, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sanford Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fargo</city>
        <state>North Dakota</state>
        <zip>58122</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Destini Spaeth</last_name>
      <phone>701-234-2474</phone>
      <email>Destini.Spaeth@sanfordhealth.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Cornelius Dyke, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Lindner Center at The Christ Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cincinnati</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>45219</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Georgia Mattingly</last_name>
      <phone>513-585-1777</phone>
      <email>georgia.mattingly@thechristhospital.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Geoffrey Answini</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cleveland Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mary Alice Bowman</last_name>
      <phone>216-445-0274</phone>
      <email>BOWMANM3@ccf.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gosta Pettersson, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Providence St. Vincent</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michelle Dixon</last_name>
      <phone>503-215-6746</phone>
      <email>michelle.dixon@providence.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Eric Kirker</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oregon Health &amp; Science University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97239</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>David Louie</last_name>
      <phone>503-494-7593</phone>
      <email>Louida@ohsu.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Howard Song, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas Southwestern</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75390</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sarah McNeil</last_name>
      <phone>214-645-7728</phone>
      <email>Sarah.McNeil@UTSouthwestern.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael Wait, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas Health Science Center - Houston</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Madiha Hassan</last_name>
      <phone>713-486-5183</phone>
      <email>Madiha.Hassan@uth.tmc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tuyen &quot;Tom&quot; Nguyen, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anthony Estrera, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baylor Scott &amp; White - Plano</name>
      <address>
        <city>Plano</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75093</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pauline Matheri</last_name>
      <phone>469-814-4854</phone>
      <email>Pauline.Matheri@BSWHealth.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Katherine Harrington, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sentara Norfolk General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Norfolk</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23507</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Melinda Bullivant</last_name>
      <phone>757-388-4024</phone>
      <email>mmbulliv@sentara.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christopher Barreiro, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Carilion Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roanoke</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>24014</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ambili John</last_name>
      <phone>540-853-0115</phone>
      <email>ASJohn@carilionclinic.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mark Joseph, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Swedish Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98122</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andrea Drouhard</last_name>
      <phone>206-215-3982</phone>
      <email>Andrea.Drouhard@swedish.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Eric Lehr, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MultiCare Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tacoma</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98405</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Meredith Barnhart</last_name>
      <phone>253-403-7258</phone>
      <email>meredith.barnhart@multicare.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Allen Graeve, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Calgary</name>
      <address>
        <city>Calgary</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Darlene Ramadan</last_name>
      <phone>403-210-7356</phone>
      <email>ramadan@ucalgary.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alex Gregory</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Victoria Heart Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Victoria</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Ottawa Heart Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ottawa</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>K1Y 4W7</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Suzanne Crowe</last_name>
      <phone>613-696-7000</phone>
      <phone_ext>10656</phone_ext>
      <email>scrowe@ottawaheart.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marc Ruel</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Blackpool Victoria Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Blackpool</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Vansanthi Vasudevan</last_name>
      <email>Vasanthi.Vasudevan@bfwhospitals.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joseph Zacharias, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hull &amp; East Yorkshire Hospitals</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hull</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Bartholomew's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>EC1A 7BE</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>John Radcliffe Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jo Sawyer</last_name>
      <email>Jo.Sawyer@ouh.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rana Sayeed</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Southampton</name>
      <address>
        <city>Southampton</city>
        <zip>SO16 6YD</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kim Golder</last_name>
      <phone>+44 (7717) 852997</phone>
      <email>Kim.Golder@uhs.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Geoff Tsang</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 5, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 8, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 9, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

