<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03400189</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>C01CS</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03400189</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pharmacokinetics and Tolerability of Sulthiame</brief_title>
  <official_title>Preliminary Pilot Exploration of the Pharmacokinetic and Tolerability Profile of Sulthiame in Healthy Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Advicenne Pharma</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This preliminary pilot exploration aims at specifying the pharmacokinetic parameters of&#xD;
      sulthiame, formulated as an immediate release tablet, thus helping to design proper clinical&#xD;
      trials for the future assessment of new paediatric formulations currently under development.&#xD;
      The clinical tolerability to single doses of sulthiame will also be closely monitored to&#xD;
      orient future trials.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Sulthiame (or sultiame), marketed in the 60's in Germany, Austria, Switzerland, Israel,&#xD;
      Australia and Japan under the brand name Ospolot®, has progressively become the therapeutic&#xD;
      first choice in benign focal epilepsies of childhood in these countries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Its antiepileptic activity is thought to result from the inhibition of various subtypes of&#xD;
      carbonic anhydrase (hCA), in particular cytosolic hCA II, thus inducing a degree of&#xD;
      intracellular acidification sufficient to stabilize seizure-eliciting neurons. The&#xD;
      pharmacokinetic profile of sulthiame was scarcely studied in humans.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sulthiame is a suitable candidate for paediatric formulation optimization, as the current&#xD;
      formulation (coated tablets of 50 or 200 mg) allows neither precise and adapted dosing, nor&#xD;
      convenient administration to young children.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 12, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 30, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 22, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Phase I, single centre, prospective, ascending single oral doses, open-label, 3-period clinical trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Elimination half-life of sultiame after single doses of 50, 100 and 200 mg of sulthiame in 4 healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>9 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Sultiame plasma concentration will be measured at predefined times after dose administration, the results will be plotted graphically and traditional pharmacokinetic calculations (log-linear regression) will be used to derive estimates of this pharmacokinetic parameter. This is a descriptive outcome and no statistical test is applied.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under curve (AUC) of sultiame after single doses of 50, 100 and 200 mg of sulthiame in 4 healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>9 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Sultiame plasma concentration will be measured at predefined times after dose administration, the results will be plotted graphically and traditional pharmacokinetic calculations (numerical integration through trapezoidal rule) will be used to derive estimates of this pharmacokinetic parameter. This is a descriptive outcome and no statistical test is applied.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Systemic drug clearance of sultiame after single doses of 50, 100 and 200 mg of sulthiame in 4 healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>9 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Sultiame concentration will be measured at predefined times after dose administration, the results will be plotted graphically and traditional pharmacokinetic calculations (ratio of administered dose over AUC) will be used to derive estimates of this pharmacokinetic parameter. This is a descriptive outcome and no statistical test is applied.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Distribution volume of sultiame after single doses of 50, 100 and 200 mg of sulthiame in 4 healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>9 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Sultiame plasma concentration will be measured at predefined times after dose administration, the results will be plotted graphically and traditional pharmacokinetic calculations (product of clearance by half-life divided by the logarithm of 2) will be used to derive estimates of this pharmacokinetic parameter. This is a descriptive outcome and no statistical test is applied.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose linearity of plasma exposure to sultiame</measure>
    <time_frame>9 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>A linear regression model will be applied to AUC as a function of dose, and the conclusion of dose linearity will be accepted if the model appears statistically non-inferior to an ANOVA model.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma free fraction of sultiame</measure>
    <time_frame>9 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The ratios of free over total plasma concentrations, and of whole blood over total plasma concentrations will be calculated, and its stability over the range of concentrations will be checked by statistical analysis for trend.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Erythrocyte binding of sultiame</measure>
    <time_frame>9 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The ratios of free over total plasma concentrations, and of whole blood over total plasma concentrations will be calculated, and its stability over the range of concentrations will be checked by statistical analysis for trend.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Validation of a liquid chromatography-mass spectrometry (LC-MS/MS) assay method for the determination of sultiame in biological fluids</measure>
    <time_frame>9 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The analytical method used for the study will be assessed for its sensitivity (estimation of detection and quantification limits), precision (estimation of intra-day and inter-day reproducibility) and accuracy (estimation of sultiame recovery using spiked samples). The analytical method will be considered validated if all criteria are within the acceptance range set by FDA/ICH recommendations.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">4</enrollment>
  <condition>Epilepsy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single oral dose of sulthiame (Ospolot® tablets)&#xD;
Period I: 50 mg&#xD;
Period II: 100 mg&#xD;
Period III: 200 mg given 3 weeks apart</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sulthiame</intervention_name>
    <description>Single dose (50, 100, 200 mg)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Ospolot</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy male subjects aged between 18 and 45 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Body weight (BW) ranging between 55 and 95 kg, providing body mass index (BMI) is&#xD;
             between 18 and 29 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Absence of significant findings in the medical history and physical examination as&#xD;
             judged by the Investigator, especially for cardiovascular, pulmonary, haematological&#xD;
             and nervous systems&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Absence of significant laboratory abnormalities as judged by the Investigator.&#xD;
             Gilbert's syndrome (increased total and unconjugated bilirubin when fasting) will be&#xD;
             accepted if mild&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Absence of clinically significant abnormalities on 12-lead electrocardiogram (ECG)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Negative urine drug screen (amphetamines, benzodiazepines, cannabis, cocaine, opiates)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Commitment to refrain from travels outside Europe over the whole study duration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Ability to understand the procedures, agreement to participate and willingness to give&#xD;
             written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Co-operative attitude and availability for scheduled visits over the entire study&#xD;
             period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of major cardiovascular, pulmonary, hepatic, immunological, renal,&#xD;
             haematological, gastrointestinal, genitourinary, neurological, or rheumatologic&#xD;
             disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Active diseases of any type, including inflammatory disorders and infections. Mild&#xD;
             acne is permissible providing no systemic or local treatment is provided or planned&#xD;
             (except for cleaning lotions)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of significant allergy or asthma. Allergic rhinitis or conjunctivitis is&#xD;
             acceptable if non symptomatic when starting the study and if symptoms are not&#xD;
             anticipated to occur during the study to a point that would require corticosteroid&#xD;
             therapy (e.g. in case of annual use)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of cardiovascular dysfunction if considered as clinically relevant (conduction&#xD;
             abnormality, arrhythmia, bradycardia, angina pectoris, cardiac hypertrophy unless&#xD;
             elicited by training, pulmonary embolism)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Hypertension defined as supine blood pressure &gt;150/90 mmHg or recurrent hypotensive&#xD;
             events considered as clinically relevant or documented orthostatic hypotension&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Sick sinus syndrome, known long QT syndrome, reproducible observation of QTc &gt;440 msec&#xD;
             or of pronounced sinus bradycardia (&lt;40 bpm/min)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Intense sport activities. Moderate sport is acceptable and activities should remain&#xD;
             fairly constant throughout the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any clinically significant laboratory value on screening that are not within normal&#xD;
             range on single repeat (Gilbert's syndrome acceptable if mild)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Positive hepatitis B &amp; C antigen screen&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Positive HIV antibody screen or screen not performed&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Any recent acute illness or sequelae thereof which could expose the subject to a&#xD;
             higher risk or might confound the results of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Treatment in the previous three months with any drug known to have well-defined&#xD;
             potential for toxicity to a major organ&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. History of hypersensitivity to any drug if considered as serious including sulthiame&#xD;
             or the excipients of the study formulation&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Use of any medication the week prior to study or as based on 5 plasma half-life rule&#xD;
             and throughout study, including aspirin or other over-the-counter (OTC) preparation.&#xD;
             Paracetamol is permissible before and during study as a concomitant medication but&#xD;
             only with Investigator's permission.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Participation in a clinical investigation or blood donation of 500 ml within the past&#xD;
             3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. History of relevant alcohol or drug abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Smoking. Consumption of &lt;5 cigarettes/day or equivalent is acceptable providing the&#xD;
             subject can refrain from smoking from one week before and during the whole study&#xD;
             duration&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Consumption of a large quantity of coffee, tea, chocolate (more than 4 cups/day) or&#xD;
             equivalent (Cola drinks)&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Present consumption of a large quantity of alcohol or wine (&gt;0.5 L wine/day) or&#xD;
             equivalent, (equivalent to more than &gt;48 g ethanol per day).&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Project to conceive a child during the study period (by principle of precaution, while&#xD;
             no indication exists for a definite reproductive risk following paternal exposure)&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Psychological status which could impact on subject's ability to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Any feature of subject's medical history or present condition which, in the&#xD;
             Investigator's opinion, could confound the results of the study, complicate its&#xD;
             interpretation, or represent a potential risk for the subject.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Division of Clinical Pharmacology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lausanne</city>
        <state>Vaud</state>
        <zip>1011</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 14, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 12, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 17, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 17, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 17, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 18, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Thierry Buclin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sulthiame</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

