<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03404388</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>122415M1E</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03404388</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Brain and Behavioral Influences on Motor Skill Learning in Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Brain and Behavioral Influences on Motor Skill Learning in Multiple Sclerosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Wayne State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Wayne State University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Multiple Sclerosis (MS) is characterized by episodic attacks in which there are sharp&#xD;
      declines in physical function. Although neurorehabilitation is the most promising clinical&#xD;
      strategy for motor recovery in patients with MS, treatment responsiveness and outcomes are&#xD;
      mixed. This is perhaps because each individual with MS has a different capacity to improve&#xD;
      with rehabilitation, and this capacity may be based on a variety of baseline factors, such as&#xD;
      disease duration, motivation, cognitive status and integrity of underlying brain structures.&#xD;
      A better understanding of what &quot;key ingredients&quot; facilitate relearning of motor skills during&#xD;
      neurorehabilitation is critically needed. Much of the focus of rehabilitation is on&#xD;
      relearning motor skills. The initial stage of learning a motor skills often requires explicit&#xD;
      concentration on the details of the movement. As one becomes more proficient in the motor&#xD;
      skill, it becomes less attention-demanding and more automatic. Those who can perform motor&#xD;
      skills more automatically will be better able to manage the additional demands of a secondary&#xD;
      task; thus, capacity for dual-task performance can be used as an index of automaticity.&#xD;
      Individuals with MS experience demyelination that impacts brain areas critical for motor&#xD;
      learning. However, the specific clinical and pathological variables that facilitate capacity&#xD;
      for motor learning in people with MS have not been identified. Identification of such&#xD;
      variables could be leveraged to determine a patient's capacity to benefit from&#xD;
      neurorehabilitation at the outset and potentially to maximize motor learning during&#xD;
      rehabilitation for people with MS. Thus, there is an urgent need to determine the key&#xD;
      ingredients most strongly associated with successful relearning of motor skills in MS&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our long-term goal is to develop individualized rehabilitation for persons with MS. Our&#xD;
      overall objective in this application is to identify clinical and pathological variables&#xD;
      associated with successful relearning of motor skills. Our central hypothesis, based on&#xD;
      preliminary data, is that the ability to learn to make new movements automatically occurs&#xD;
      over a dynamic range and is a function of available cognitive processing speed and the&#xD;
      integrity of corticospinal tract and superior cerebellar peduncles. We will test these&#xD;
      hypotheses by recruiting 146 individuals with relapsing-remitting MS to participate in a&#xD;
      mechanistic trial not designed to be a therapeutic intervention. Participants will complete&#xD;
      baseline testing (including neuroimaging, cognitive testing and dual-task performance)&#xD;
      followed by 4 consecutive days of training on a challenging balance task. After a 2-day&#xD;
      washout period, participants will return for post-testing (including dual-task performance on&#xD;
      a dual-balance and working memory task). The rationale for the proposed research is that&#xD;
      identification of key ingredients associated with the capacity for motor skill acquisition&#xD;
      would allow for more targeted rehabilitation programming, thereby improving patient outcomes&#xD;
      and reducing health care expenses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the completion of the proposed research, we expect to understand more about the capacity&#xD;
      for individuals with MS to improve with motor skill training, and some of the key ingredients&#xD;
      that help predict successful shift toward task automaticity, one critical component of&#xD;
      successful neurorehabilitation. The results of this proposal will facilitate the development&#xD;
      of predictors of motor recovery, needed to improve rehabilitation outcomes for individuals&#xD;
      with MS and other neurodegenerative diseases.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>All participants will receive the same testing and training. A assessor blinded to whether the participant has received training will assess the Berg Balance Scale.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Dual-Task Cost</measure>
    <time_frame>Outcome will be assessed at baseline visit and post-test visit (1 week later)</time_frame>
    <description>Performance of challenging balance task at the same time as a cognitive task</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Berg Balance Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Outcome will be assessed at baseline visit and post-test visit (1 week later)</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical test of balance</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Balance Control</measure>
    <time_frame>Outcome will be assessed at baseline visit and post-test visit (1 week later)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of static and dynamic balance as well as anticipatory postural control with wearable sensors</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Balance Training</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Balance Training</intervention_name>
    <description>4 days of a challenging balance training task</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Diagnosis of Relapsing-Remitting MS,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient Determined Disease Steps (PDDS) &lt;6.5, indicating ability to ambulate with or&#xD;
             without an assistive device (Hohol, 1999; Learmonth, 2013)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. between the ages of 18 and 65;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. stable medication regime for 3 months prior to enrollment, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. able to follow study-related commands.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. history of other neurological or neuromuscular conditions,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. acute orthopedic conditions that prevent participation in the training,&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. steroid use &lt;30 days prior to enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. history of alcohol abuse;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. presence of metallic implants, medical implants or exposure to metallic shrapnel&#xD;
             incompatible with MRI,&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. pregnancy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. history of hospitalization for depression; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. depression as evidenced by a score of ≥10 on the Patient Health Questionnaire-9&#xD;
             (PHQ-9) (Kroenke, 2001), as depression has been shown to impact motor learning in&#xD;
             persons with neurologic disorders (Subramanian, 2015).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wayne State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 11, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 18, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 19, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 6, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 6, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 8, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Wayne State University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nora Fritz</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

