<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04955782</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2104-MUS-006-US</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04955782</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Abstinence Period and Semen Quality</brief_title>
  <official_title>Abstinence Period and Semen Quality</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>ART Fertility Clinics LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>ART Fertility Clinics LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Does period of abstinence impact progressive motility in oligoasthenoteratozoospermic (OATS)&#xD;
      males? In the evaluation of male fertility, semen analysis is an important investigation. An&#xD;
      abstinence between 2 and 7 days before a diagnostic semen analysis has been recommended by&#xD;
      WHO (WHO 2010 guidelines), for the sake of standardization. The European Society of Human&#xD;
      Reproduction and Embryology advises 3-4 days of abstinence before a semen analysis. The exact&#xD;
      impact of abstinence period on sperm quality is a little complex and difficult to interpret.&#xD;
      This study, 250 men with low sperm counts, motility and morphology will be recruited. The&#xD;
      results will be analyzed to ascertain the impact of shorter abstinence period on semen&#xD;
      quality&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The population will be the citizens and residents of Oman. All men included in the study will&#xD;
      be the ones diagnosed in the last one year, with oligoasthenoteratozoospermia. There are&#xD;
      multiple factors that affect the semen parameters in assisted reproductive procedures. One of&#xD;
      the factors is period of abstinence. It has been observed that prolonged abstinence improves&#xD;
      semen volume and sperm concentration, but it may have a negative impact on sperm viability&#xD;
      and motility. The present abstinence guidelines are for testing and analysis only, however,&#xD;
      it is possible that varying periods of abstinence may lead to higher clinical pregnancies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If sufficient sample has not been accomplished even after considering non-response,&#xD;
      investigators will optimize sampled data with complete information required for research.&#xD;
      Regression imputation statistical technique will be done. Instead of deleting any case that&#xD;
      has any missing value, this approach preserves all cases by replacing the missing data with a&#xD;
      probable value estimated by remaining information. The existing variables are used to make a&#xD;
      prediction, and then the predicted value is substituted as if an actual obtained value. After&#xD;
      all missing values will be replaced, the complete data set will be analyzed using the above&#xD;
      mentioned standard techniques to meet the objectives.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data collected will be stored in a password coded excel sheet. The verification of sample&#xD;
      provider will be done by two people. Also, two embryologists will cross check the identifier&#xD;
      details with the sample. The anonymity of patient will be maintained by logging the data onto&#xD;
      an excel sheet without any name, only patient number. The sample will be identified based on&#xD;
      the Vrepro number which is a unique ID for the patient. Eg. For patient X,ID is 0004797. The&#xD;
      details will be saved in a sheet with the ID number 4797 only.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data base will be rigorously defined with the variables destined to be analyzed according&#xD;
      to the objectives set. The necessary information will be exported from the clinical&#xD;
      information manager, Vrepro, to a table in Excel format. The exported data will be duly&#xD;
      codified in order to protect the clinical and personal information of the patients according&#xD;
      to the applicable law in the place where the research project is carried out. Finally and&#xD;
      prior to the statistical study, an exploratory data analysis will be carried out to review&#xD;
      the quality of the information extracted.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 16, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Day</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Seminal pH</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>pH will be analyzed 30 minutes after collection. pH test strips in range of 6.0-10.0 will be used.&#xD;
A value under 7.0 will indicate lack of alkaline seminal vesicular fluid (pH-Fix 0-14 from Macherey-Nagell,Germany)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ejaculate volume</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Ejaculate volume in ml</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sperm viability</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Vitality (in%) will be analyzed by Vital screen, FertiPro N.V. Belgium,as per guidelines of manufacturer.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sperm motility</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>The samples motility (in % of A, B, C, D) will be analyzed in laboratory by Neubauer chamber.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sperm count</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Sperm count in mill/ml</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sperm concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>The samples concentration in mill/ml will be analyzed in laboratory by Neubauer chamber</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sperm morphology</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Morphology (in %) will be assessed by RAL Diff-Quik kit (3x0.5L) from RAL Diagnostics, France as per the manufacturers' recommendation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">250</enrollment>
  <condition>Infertility, Male</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>62-84 hours of abstinence</arm_group_label>
    <description>samples will be analyzed for semen volume, pH, count, concentration, motility, morphology and viability</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1-3 hours of abstinence</arm_group_label>
    <description>samples will be analyzed for semen volume, pH, count, concentration, motility, morphology and viability</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>samples will be analyzed for semen volume, pH, count, concentration, motility, morphology and viability</intervention_name>
    <description>The volume will be measured by weighing the sample in the container in which it has been collected, it will be a pre-weighed container. The volume will be assessed by aspirating the sample using a non-toxic pre scaled surgical pipette.&#xD;
The samples will be liquified in an incubator at 37 C. Complete ejaculate liquefaction is normally achieved within 15-30 minutes at room temperature (WHO2010).&#xD;
pH will be analyzed 30 minutes after collection. pH test strips in range of 6.0-10.0 will be used. A value under 7.0 will indicate lack of alkaline seminal vesicular fluid (pH-Fix 0-14 from Macherey-Nagell,Germany).&#xD;
The samples concentration and motility will be analyzed in laboratory by Neubauer chamber, morphology will be assessed by RAL Diff-Quik kit (3x0.5L) from RAL Diagnostics, France as per the manufacturers' recommendation.&#xD;
Vitality will be analyzed by Vital screen, FertiPro N.V. Belgium,as per guidelines of manufacturer</description>
    <arm_group_label>1-3 hours of abstinence</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>62-84 hours of abstinence</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      semen sample&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The population will be the citizens and residents of Oman. Oman is a diverse country with&#xD;
        Omanis, Asians, Caucasians, Persians, other Arabs (eg. Egyptian, Syrian, Iraqi, Lebanese,&#xD;
        Jordanian, Sudani) residing here. All men with oligoasthenoteratozoospermia.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A semen analysis report not more than 1 year old with sperm concentration less than or&#xD;
             equal to 5 mill/ml and more than or equal to 0.1 mill/ml.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sperm motility less than or equal to 20%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sperm morphology less than 4% normal sperms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Azoospermia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sperm obtained from surgical sperm retrieval&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cryptozoospermia and Necrozoospermia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of chemotherapy, radiotherapy, cryptorchidism, chronic diabetes, active&#xD;
             smokers (someone who smokes any tobacco product at least once a day as per WHO&#xD;
             definition).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Upma Pathak Shanker, Specialist</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>ART Fertility Clinics LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>BARBARA LAWRENZ, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>026528000</phone>
    <phone_ext>1107</phone_ext>
    <email>barbara.lawrenz@artfertilityclinics.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>SHIERYL DIGMA, RN</last_name>
    <phone>026528000</phone>
    <phone_ext>1061</phone_ext>
    <email>shieryl.digma@artfertilityclinics.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>ART Fertility Clinics LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Muscat</city>
        <country>Oman</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Upma Shanker</last_name>
      <phone>0096824475814</phone>
      <email>upma.shanker@artfertilityclinics.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Alberto Linan Tegedor</last_name>
      <phone>0096824475814</phone>
      <email>alberto.linan@artfertilityclinics.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Upma Shanker</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Oman</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United Arab Emirates</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.tandfonline.com/action/showCitFormats?doi=10.1080%2F00031305.1982.10483055</url>
    <description>Allan Donner (1982) The Relative Effectiveness of Procedures Commonly Used in Multiple Regression Analysis for Dealing with Missing Values, The American Statistician, 36:4, 378-381, DOI: 10.1080/00031305.1982.10483055</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Björndahl L, Barratt CL, Fraser LR, Kvist U, Mortimer D. ESHRE basic semen analysis courses 1995-1999: immediate beneficial effects of standardized training. Hum Reprod. 2002 May;17(5):1299-305.</citation>
    <PMID>11980755</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>De Jonge C, LaFromboise M, Bosmans E, Ombelet W, Cox A, Nijs M. Influence of the abstinence period on human sperm quality. Fertil Steril. 2004 Jul;82(1):57-65.</citation>
    <PMID>15236990</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Agarwal A, Gupta S, Du Plessis S, Sharma R, Esteves SC, Cirenza C, Eliwa J, Al-Najjar W, Kumaresan D, Haroun N, Philby S, Sabanegh E. Abstinence Time and Its Impact on Basic and Advanced Semen Parameters. Urology. 2016 Aug;94:102-10. doi: 10.1016/j.urology.2016.03.059. Epub 2016 May 16.</citation>
    <PMID>27196032</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Borges E Jr, Braga DPAF, Zanetti BF, Iaconelli A Jr, Setti AS. Revisiting the impact of ejaculatory abstinence on semen quality and intracytoplasmic sperm injection outcomes. Andrology. 2019 Mar;7(2):213-219. doi: 10.1111/andr.12572. Epub 2018 Dec 20.</citation>
    <PMID>30570220</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sánchez-Martín P, Sánchez-Martín F, González-Martínez M, Gosálvez J. Increased pregnancy after reduced male abstinence. Syst Biol Reprod Med. 2013 Oct;59(5):256-60. doi: 10.3109/19396368.2013.790919. Epub 2013 May 8.</citation>
    <PMID>23651301</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kang H. The prevention and handling of the missing data. Korean J Anesthesiol. 2013 May;64(5):402-6. doi: 10.4097/kjae.2013.64.5.402. Epub 2013 May 24.</citation>
    <PMID>23741561</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>infertilty</keyword>
  <keyword>semen analysis</keyword>
  <keyword>semen parameters</keyword>
  <keyword>progressive motility</keyword>
  <keyword>abstinence period</keyword>
  <keyword>sperm count</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infertility, Male</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

