<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04959175</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10000359</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>000359-C</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04959175</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase I/II Study to Reduce Post-transplantation Cyclophosphamide Dosing for Older or Unfit Patients Undergoing Bone Marrow Transplantation for Hematologic Malignancies</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I/II Study to Reduce Post-transplantation Cyclophosphamide Dosing for Older or Unfit Patients Undergoing Bone Marrow Transplantation for Hematologic Malignancies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Certain blood cancers can be treated with blood or bone marrow transplants. Sometimes the&#xD;
      donor cells attack the recipient's body, called graft-versus-host disease (GVHD). The&#xD;
      chemotherapy drug cyclophosphamide helps reduce the risk and severity of GVHD. Researchers&#xD;
      want to learn if using a lower dose of cyclophosphamide may reduce the drug's side effects&#xD;
      while maintaining its effectiveness. Such an approach is being used in an ongoing clinical&#xD;
      study at the NIH with promising results, but this approach has not been tested for&#xD;
      transplants using lower doses of chemotherapy/radiation prior to the transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To learn if using a lower dose of cyclophosphamide will help people have a successful&#xD;
      transplant and have fewer problems and side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults ages 18-85 who have a blood cancer that did not respond well to standard treatments or&#xD;
      is at high risk for relapse without transplant, and their donors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may be screened with the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical exam&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood and urine tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      Heart and lung tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      Body imaging scans (they may get a contrast agent)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Spinal tap&#xD;
&#xD;
      Bone marrow biopsy&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be hospitalized for 4-6 weeks. They will have a central venous catheter&#xD;
      placed in a chest or neck vein. It will be used to give medicines, transfusions, and the&#xD;
      donor cells, and to take blood. In the week before transplant, they will get 2 chemotherapy&#xD;
      drugs and radiation. After the transplant, they will get the study drug for 2 days. They will&#xD;
      take other drugs for up to 2 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants must stay near NIH for 3 months after discharge for weekly study visits. Then&#xD;
      they will have visits every 3-12 months until 5 years after transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants and donors will give blood, bone marrow, saliva, cheek swab, urine, and stool&#xD;
      samples for research.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      With novel therapies for hematologic malignancies, an increasing number of older and/or less&#xD;
      fit patients are achieving remissions, but these new therapies are not curative, making&#xD;
      consolidation approaches with curative intent such as allogeneic transplantation necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Frailty is a phenotype that predicts a patient s intolerance of physiologic stressors and may&#xD;
      predict a patient s tolerance of intensive consolidative strategies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Frailty phenotype, though increasing in incidence in older patients, can occur in younger&#xD;
      patients and may predict poor survival after allogeneic transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We have yet to define the ideal allogeneic transplantation regimen for older patients or&#xD;
      those with frailty or pre-frail phenotypes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post-transplantation cyclophosphamide (PTCy) reduces rates of severe acute and chronic&#xD;
      graft-versus-host disease (GVHD) after allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplantation (HCT)&#xD;
      and safely facilitates human leukocyte antigen (HLA)-matched-related, HLA-matched-unrelated,&#xD;
      HLA-mismatched-unrelated, and HLA-haploidentical HCT; it has become the most widely adopted&#xD;
      change to transplantation platforms over the last decade.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When clinically translated, the dose (50 mg/kg/day) of PTCy used was partly extrapolated from&#xD;
      murine major histocompatibility complex (MHC)-matched skin allografting models and was partly&#xD;
      empirical.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In both MHC-haploidentical and MHC-disparate murine HCT models, a dose of 25 mg/kg/day was&#xD;
      superior to 50 mg/kg/day on days +3 and +4 in terms of GVHD severity and mortality. Lower&#xD;
      dosing of PTCy also was associated with less broad reductions of T-cell numbers after PTCy&#xD;
      and lower toxicity than higher dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In patients on an NIH study using myeloablative conditioning, a dose of 25 mg/kg/day has been&#xD;
      associated with more rapid engraftment and potentially better immune function without an&#xD;
      increase in severe acute GVHD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Determine whether PTCy 25 mg/kg on days +3 and +4 can maintain adequate protection against&#xD;
      grade III-IV acute GVHD and reduce toxicity associated with transplantation in older and/or&#xD;
      unfit transplant recipients receiving reduced intensity conditioned allogeneic HCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Determine the frailty measures associated with outcomes after allogeneic transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Histologically or cytologically confirmed hematologic malignancy with standard indication for&#xD;
      allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age 60-85 years, or age 18-60 years and unfit for myeloablative conditioning (MAC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      At least one potentially suitable HLA-matched related, HLA-haploidentical donor, HLA-matched&#xD;
      unrelated, or (Bullet)5/10 HLA-mismatched unrelated donor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Karnofsky performance score (Bullet)60&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adequate organ function&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Open-label, multi-center, non-randomized, phase I/II study&#xD;
&#xD;
      There will be four separate arms: HLA-matched elderly, HLA-matched young/infirm,&#xD;
      HLA-partially matched elderly, and HLA-partially matched young/infirm&#xD;
&#xD;
      All subjects will receive nonmyeloablative conditioning consisting of fludarabine,&#xD;
      cyclophosphamide, and total body irradiation; GVHD prophylaxis with PTCy 25 mg/kg on days +3&#xD;
      and +4, MMF, and sirolimus; and bone marrow as the stem cell source.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be evaluated for development of grade III-IV acute GVHD (aGVHD) at day +60 as&#xD;
      the dose-limiting toxicities for the Simon two-stage design. Dose escalation of PTCy will be&#xD;
      permitted within each arm if stopping rules are met at the 25 mg/kg/day on days +3 and +4&#xD;
      dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Frailty assessments will be performed prior to transplantation conditioning and serially&#xD;
      after allogeneic transplantation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 23, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 27, 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>determine if optimal dose of PTCy to prevent grade III-IV acute GVHD (aGVHD) at day +60</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
    <description>The fraction of evaluable patients who experience grade III-IV aGVHD at day +60 will be determined and reported along with 80% and 95% two-sided confidence intervals. In addition, a cumulative incidence curve for this endpoint will be constructed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Grade III-IV acute GVHD at day 100 and 200</measure>
    <time_frame>100 days/200 days</time_frame>
    <description>Estimates will be determined using competing risk-based cumulative incidence curves. Graft failure, relapse, donor lymphocyte infusion, non-relapse mortality, and chronic GVHD will be competing risks for acute GVHD. Grade III-IV aGVHD also will be evaluated descriptively including fractions who attain each condition at day 100 and 200 days, and 95% confidence intervals.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Grade II-IV acute GVHD at day 100 and 200</measure>
    <time_frame>100 days/200 days</time_frame>
    <description>Estimates will be determined using competing risk-based cumulative incidence curves. Grade II-IV aGVHD also will be evaluated descriptively including fractions who attain each condition at day 100 and 200 days, and 95% confidence intervals.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of Fried s Frailty Phenotypes (FP)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of different phenotypes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Chronic GVHD at one year</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Estimates will be determined using competing risk-based cumulative incidence curves. Graft failure, relapse, donor lymphocyte infusion, and non-relapse mortality will be competing risks for chronic GVHD.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression/relapse at one year</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Estimates will be determined using Kaplan-Meier curves. Relapse and non-relapse mortality will be competing risks for each other.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non-relapse mortality at 100 days and one year</measure>
    <time_frame>100 days and 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Estimates will be determined using competing risk-based cumulative incidence curves. Relapse and non-relapse mortality will be competing risks for each other.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival, progression-free survival, and disease-free survival at one year</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Estimates will be determined using Kaplan-Meier curves.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Estimation of platelet engraftment, neutrophil engraftment.</measure>
    <time_frame>day 28 and day 100</time_frame>
    <description>Rate and timing will be evaluated descriptively, including fractions who attain each condition at day 28 and 100, along with 95% confidence intervals. Ranges and medians will be calculated only in engrafting participants.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">320</enrollment>
  <condition>Hematologic Neoplasms</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Donors</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Collection of research samples on bone marrow donors</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects age 60-85 with hematologic malignancies and an HLA-matched related or unrelated donor</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects age 60-85 with hematologic malignancies and an HLA-haploidentical or HLA-mismatched unrelated donor</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects age 18-60 unfit for MAC with hematologic malignancies and an HLA-matched related or unrelated donor</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects age 18-60 unfit for MAC with hematologic malignancies and an HLA-haploidentical or HLA-mismatched unrelated donor</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mycophenolate Mofetil</intervention_name>
    <description>15 mg/kg orally or IV three times daily (max 1000 mg/dose) starting on day +5, continued through day +35. May be continued beyond the protocol specified stop date if there is GVHD or mixed chimerism.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Allogeneic HSCT</intervention_name>
    <description>Stem cell transplant</description>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fludarabine</intervention_name>
    <description>30 mg/m2 IV infusion over 30-60 minutes once daily for 5 days (Pre-Transplant days -6 through -2).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sirolimus</intervention_name>
    <description>Loading dose of 6 mg orally given on day +5 (calculated based on actual body weight, max initial dose 6 mg), then maintenance dose starting at 2 mg orally daily on day +6 with dose adjustments to maintain a trough of 5-12 ng/ml, continued through day +60 with no taper. May be continued beyond the protocol specified stop date if there is GVHD or mixed chimerism.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Filgrastim</intervention_name>
    <description>begins on day +5 at a dose of 5 mcg/kg/day (actual body weight) IV or subcutaneously, until the absolute neutrophil count is &gt; 1,000/mm3 over the course of three days or &gt; 5,000/mm3 on one day. Rounding to the nearest vial is allowed. G-CSF may be stopped early or not administered if required by the clinical circumstance. Additional G-CSF may be administered as warranted.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cyclophosphamide</intervention_name>
    <description>Pre-transplant: 14.5 mg/kg/day IV daily for 2 days pre-transplant (Pre-Transplant days -6 and -5). Post-transplant: 25 mg/kg/day or 35 mg/kg/day (Post-transplant days +3 and +4).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mesna</intervention_name>
    <description>25 or 35 mg/kg (equal to the cyclophosphamide dose) as IV infusion concomitant with cyclophosphamide. Mesna may or may not be given with the pre-transplant cyclophosphamide depending on institutional practice.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Total Body Irradiation (TBI)</intervention_name>
    <description>400 centigray (cGy) to be delivered in 2 fractions as 200 cGy per fraction twice daily. Pre-Transplant Day -1 (or Day 0 prior to graft administration)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Older, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-matched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Younger, HLA-mismatched</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -INCLUSION CRITERIA - Recipient&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects must have a histologically or cytologically confirmed hematologic malignancy&#xD;
             with standard indication for allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplantation including,&#xD;
             but not limited to, one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acute myeloid leukemia in morphologic complete remission (&lt;5% blasts in the bone&#xD;
                  marrow, no detectable abnormal peripheral blasts, and no extramedullary disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  B-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia in first or subsequent complete remission&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  T-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia in first or subsequent complete remission&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Myelodysplastic syndrome of intermediate or higher score by the Revised&#xD;
                  International Prognostic Scoring System (IPSS-R)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Primary myelofibrosis of intermediate-2 or higher risk by the DIPSS&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chronic myelomonocytic leukemia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chronic myelogenous leukemia resistant to or intolerant of &gt;=3 tyrosine kinase&#xD;
                  inhibitors or with history of accelerated phase or blast crisis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  B-cell lymphoma including Hodgkin lymphoma that has relapsed within 1 year of&#xD;
                  completion of primary treatment, after autologous transplantation or has&#xD;
                  progressed through at least 2 lines of therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chronic lymphocytic leukemia with 17p deletion and/or unmutated IgHV or&#xD;
                  refractory or intolerant of both BTK and PI3K inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Mature T or NK neoplasms as defined in the WHO guidelines of sufficient type and&#xD;
                  severity for allogeneic HCT based on the Prognostic Index for T-cell lymphoma&#xD;
                  (PIT) score of low-intermediate risk or higher60 or on recently published&#xD;
                  clinical practice guidelines&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hematologic malignancy of dendritic cell or histiocytic cell type&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Multiple myeloma, stage III, relapsing after therapy with both a proteasome&#xD;
                  inhibitor and an immunomodulatory drug (IMiD)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age 60-85 years, or age 18-60 years and unfit for myeloablative conditioning. Reasons&#xD;
             for unfitness for myeloablative conditioning include:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prior myeloablative HCT&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prior exposure to inotuzumab, gemtuzumab, or other agent that increases the risk&#xD;
                  for sinusoidal obstruction syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Significant organ dysfunction (e.g., creatinine or liver enzymes above the upper&#xD;
                  limit of normal or EGFR &lt;=70 ml/min/1.73sq.m; prior sinusoidal obstruction&#xD;
                  syndrome, hepatic fibrosis, hepatic steatosis, or nodular regenerative&#xD;
                  hyperplasia; reduced ejection fraction &lt;55% or focal hypokinesis, FEV1 or&#xD;
                  adjusted DLCO &lt;75% of predicted)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hematopoietic Cell Transplantation- Comorbidity Index (HCT-CI) &gt;= 3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subject refusal of MAC (including subjects insistent on trying to maintain&#xD;
                  fertility)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pre-frail or frail by Fried s frailty phenotype&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Karnofsky performance score &lt;80&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Significant life-threatening toxicities associated with prior chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Co-morbidity considered by the treating physician to be exclusionary of MAC&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. At least one potentially suitable HLA-matched related, HLA-haploidentical first degree&#xD;
             or collateral related, HLA-matched unrelated, or &gt;=5/10 HLA-mismatched unrelated&#xD;
             donor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Karnofsky performance score &gt;=60&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Ability of subject to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed&#xD;
             consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Adequate organ function defined as possessing all of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cardiac ejection fraction &gt;=35%;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Forced expiratory volume-1, forced vital capacity, and diffusing capacity of the&#xD;
                  lung for carbon monoxide (corrected for hemoglobin) all of &gt;=40% predicted;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine clearance of &gt;=45 ml/minute calculated using the Cockcroft-Gault&#xD;
                  equation;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin &lt;=2X the upper limit of normal;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine aminotransferase and aspartate aminotransferase &lt;=5X the upper limit of&#xD;
                  normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Nonmyeloablative conditioning is toxic to the developing human fetus and is&#xD;
             teratogenic. For this reason, the following measures apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women of child-bearing potential (WOCBP) and men must agree to use adequate&#xD;
                  contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to&#xD;
                  study entry and for at least one year post-transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while she or her&#xD;
                  partner is participating in this study, she should inform her treating physician&#xD;
                  immediately.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  WOCBP must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test within 7 days prior to&#xD;
                  enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. For NIH treated subjects only: subjects requiring standard therapies to prepare for&#xD;
             HCT should be referred in remission, if possible. However, these diseases are often&#xD;
             aggressive and require swift evaluation for HCT while concurrently attempting to&#xD;
             establish disease control through the administration of standard therapies. If ongoing&#xD;
             therapy for the underlying disease outside of the NIH is not in the best interest of&#xD;
             the subject according to the clinical judgment of the NIH PI, then the subject may&#xD;
             receive standard treatment for his/her underlying hematologic malignancy as a bridge&#xD;
             to HCT on this protocol, prior to starting the research phase of the study. If it&#xD;
             becomes apparent that the subject will not be able to proceed to HCT, then he/she must&#xD;
             come off study. Subjects receiving standard therapy will be told about the therapy,&#xD;
             associated risks, potential benefits, alternatives to the proposed therapy, and the&#xD;
             availability of receiving the same treatment elsewhere, outside of a research&#xD;
             protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA - Recipient:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects who are receiving any other investigational agents. Prior experimental&#xD;
             therapies must have been completed at least 2 weeks prior to the date of beginning&#xD;
             conditioning.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Poorly controlled malignant indication for transplantation such as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Leukemia not having achieved morphologic remission (i.e. bone marrow blasts &gt;5%&#xD;
                  or active extramedullary disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Lymphoma not having achieved at least a partial response to prior chemotherapy or&#xD;
                  radiation&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness that in the opinion of the site PI would make it&#xD;
             unsafe to proceed with transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The potential for some of the study medications to be transmissible via breast milk of&#xD;
             nursing mothers is unknown. Because there is unknown but potential risk for adverse&#xD;
             events in nursing infants secondary to treatment of the mother, breastfeeding must be&#xD;
             discontinued.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Active malignancy of non-hematopoietic type which is: metastatic, relapsed/refractory&#xD;
             to treatment, or locally advanced and not amenable to curative treatment, or limited&#xD;
             disease treated with curative intent treatment within the last 2 years. This excludes&#xD;
             nonmelanoma skin cancers.&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA - Related Donor:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Related donor (age &gt;=12) deemed suitable and eligible, and willing to donate, per clinical&#xD;
        evaluations, who are additionally willing to donate blood, bone marrow, and stool for&#xD;
        research.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Related donors will be evaluated in accordance with existing institutional Standard&#xD;
        Policies and Procedures for determination of eligibility and suitability for clinical&#xD;
        donation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Women of child-bearing potential (WOCBP) and men must agree to use adequate contraception&#xD;
        (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry and for at&#xD;
        least 60 days after donation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA - Related Donor:&#xD;
&#xD;
        None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christopher G Kanakry, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jennifer L Sadler</last_name>
    <phone>(240) 760-6172</phone>
    <email>jennifer.sadler@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Shannon McCurdy</last_name>
      <phone>215-614-0698</phone>
      <email>shannon.mccurdy@pennmedicine.upenn.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_000359-C.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 31, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>myeloablative conditioning</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Graft-Versus-Host Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>hematopoietic cell transplantation</keyword>
  <keyword>Fludarabine</keyword>
  <keyword>TOTAL BODY IRRADIATION</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hematologic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fludarabine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

