<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04957225</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-07182</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04957225</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>MIRAA - Implementation of Intensive Rehabilitation of Aphasia and/or Apraxia of Speech in Swedish Healthcare</brief_title>
  <acronym>MIRAA</acronym>
  <official_title>MIRAA - A National Study on Intensive Rehabilitation of Aphasia and Apraxia of Speech Following Stroke</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Karolinska Institutet</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Karolinska Institutet</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Positive outcomes have been shown following intensive treatment of speech and/or language&#xD;
      impairment post stroke, but how to design intensive treatment programs to achieve optimal&#xD;
      recovery and neuroplasticity changes needs to be further researched. The purpose of the MIRAA&#xD;
      (Multimodal Intensive Rehabilitation of Aphasia and Apraxia of Speech) project is to study&#xD;
      feasibility of intensive intervention for acquired aphasia and apraxia of speech (AOS) after&#xD;
      stroke in the regular Swedish health-care according to the updated national guidelines from&#xD;
      the Swedish National Board of Health and Welfare.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      According to the Swedish National Board of Health and Welfare's guidelines for stroke care,&#xD;
      persons with aphasia shall be offered intensive rehabilitation by speech-language&#xD;
      pathologists. The aphasia rehabilitation is however sparse and unevenly distributed over the&#xD;
      country as reported by the Swedish Aphasia Foundation. People with aphasia are seldom offered&#xD;
      long-term treatment and intensive therapy is rarely offered. Intensive treatment is defined&#xD;
      as at least 4h/week by the National Board of Health and Welfare, but higher intensity can be&#xD;
      beneficial if tolerated by the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Multimodal Intensive Rehabilitation of Aphasia and Apraxia of speech, MIRAA, is a modified&#xD;
      Intensive Comprehensive Aphasia Program (ICAP) intervention program developed in the&#xD;
      applicant's research group. MIRAA consists of a selection of evidence-based and/or&#xD;
      well-established methods for speech and language rehabilitation as well as computer training.&#xD;
      The training is both individual and group based, including communication between participants&#xD;
      to promote transfer to real-life situations. Rehabilitation is based on principles that have&#xD;
      been shown to promote neuroplasticity changes, such as high training intensity and multiple&#xD;
      repetitions of tasks, for learning and relearning after brain injury. The intervention is&#xD;
      goal-driven and individualized for high saliency, with focus on each participant's&#xD;
      difficulties with language, speech and communication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Speech and Language Pathologists (SLPs) all over Sweden working with aphasia and/or AOS&#xD;
      following stroke are offered to participate in the study. At the time of recruitment, SLPs&#xD;
      are invited to respond to a questionnaire about their current practice. SLPs accepting to&#xD;
      participate are offered a 2-day workshop and recurring sessions containing introduction to&#xD;
      and training in the MIRAA program as well as information about the logistics of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      42 SLPs from 23 clinics over the country participate in the study. The SLPs recruit&#xD;
      participants with aphasia/AOS from their waiting and offer them a six-week MIRAA&#xD;
      rehabilitation program consisting of a combination of individual treatment and group session&#xD;
      and computer-assisted/homework training, with the goal level of 60 hours. The content of the&#xD;
      program is individually adapted to clinics and participants. Participation in the study is&#xD;
      consecutively offered to all individuals with speech language impairment post stroke that&#xD;
      meet the inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following administration of the MIRAA-program including pre- and post-testing, participating&#xD;
      SLPs will complete a questionnaire on their experiences of delivering the intensive&#xD;
      intervention and factors hindering and facilitating implementation. Participants with&#xD;
      aphasia/AOS and their next of kin will also provide information about their experiences&#xD;
      through questionnaires and semi structured interviews, focus groups interviews and&#xD;
      participant observations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants are tested pre- post and at follow-up by a speech and language pathologist.&#xD;
      Behavioral tests consist of quantitative measurements of speech, language, communication,&#xD;
      cognition and quality of life. Part of the testing (TAX and CAT informative speech) is video-&#xD;
      recorded for analysis after testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background data are obtained noting sex, age, handedness, education level, language history&#xD;
      aphasia type and severity and AOS, time since onset, mental fatigue, social life, number of&#xD;
      strokes and earlier intensive rehabilitation at the time of the first assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A subgroup of participants and SLPs from five clinics distributed over varying types of&#xD;
      clinics reflecting the diversity among the clinics (inpatient care, primary care) take part&#xD;
      in semi-structured interviews based on interview guides combined with focus group interviews&#xD;
      and participant observations during one day of the last week of the intensive program&#xD;
      focusing on facilitating and hindering factors for complying with an intensive intervention&#xD;
      program like MIRAA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A group consisting of SLPs not being able to participate in the study will form a focus group&#xD;
      and discuss the specific factors hindering participation in the study in their respective&#xD;
      settings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary aim of this project is to explore the feasibility for national implementation of&#xD;
      an intensive comprehensive intervention program for aphasia and AOS following stroke (MIRAA)&#xD;
      in Swedish health care.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  What are facilitating or hindering factors for SLPs and their patients in the subacute&#xD;
           and chronic phase post stroke with aphasia and/or AOS to comply with an intensive&#xD;
           intervention program like MIRAA?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  How do participants, next of kin and SLPs experience intensive training in terms of&#xD;
           effects and satisfaction with the program and with the implementation?&#xD;
&#xD;
      A secondary aim is to examine whether short-term and / or long-term effects on language,&#xD;
      speech, communication and quality of life after intensive rehabilitation can be demonstrated.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Can treatment effects regarding speech and/or language be detected when comparing the&#xD;
           control group with the intervention group after six weeks of intensive intervention?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Can treatment effects regarding communication and quality of life be detected when&#xD;
           comparing the control group with the intervention group after six weeks of intensive&#xD;
           intervention?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Can long-term treatment effects on speech, language, communication and quality of life&#xD;
           four months post intervention be detected?&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 10, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Cluster randomized clinical trial with two parallel arms.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Block randomized sealed envelopes handled by external coordinator.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of training, questionnaire to participating Speech and Language Pathologists</measure>
    <time_frame>Directly after intensive treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum score 0, maximum score 12. Higher scores mean better outcome on satisfaction with intensive training and effects on speech, language and functional communication.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of training, questionnaire to participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Directly after intensive treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum score 3, maximum score 12. Higher scores mean better outcome on satisfaction with intensive training and effects on speech, language and functional communication.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comprehensive Aphasia Test (CAT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes from baseline in language battery scores at 6 and 16 (+-2) weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>Comprehensive Aphasia Test (CAT) language battery. Comprehension of spoken language: minimum score 0, maximum score 66; Comprehension of written language: minimum score 0, maximum score 62; Repetition: minimum score 0, maximum score 74; Naming: minimum score 0, maximum score no limit; Reading: minimum score 0, maximum score 70; Writing: minimum score 0, maximum score 76. Higher scores mean better outcome in language functions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Boston Naming Test (BNT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes from baseline scores at 6 and 16 (+-2) weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum score 0, maximum score 60. Higher scores mean better outcome in naming ability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rating scale for apraxia of speech (SkaFTA, Swedish version of ASRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Time Frame: Changes from baseline scores at 6 and 16 (+-2) weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum score 0, maximum score 52. Lower scores mean better outcome in speech functions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Protocol for Apraxia of Speech (TAX)</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes from baseline scores at 6 and 16 (+-2) weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum score 0, maximum score 30. Lower scores mean mean better outcome in speech functions and non verbal oral apraxia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comprehensive Aphasia Test (CAT), subtest cognitive screening</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes from baseline scores at 6 and 16 (+-2) weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum score 0, maximum score 38. Higher scores mean better outcome in cognitive functions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Communicative Effectiveness Index (CETI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes from baseline scores at 6 and 16 (+-2) weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum score 0, maximum score 100. Higher scores mean better outcome in communicative effectiveness.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>General Health Questionnaire 12 questions (GHQ-12)</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes from baseline scores at 6 and 16 (+-2) weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum score 0, maximum score 36. Lower scores mean mean better outcome in general health.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Aphasia</condition>
  <condition>Apraxia of Speech</condition>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Direct intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Goal level 60 hours of intensive treatment during 6 weeks. Intensive treatment of aphasia and AOS in ICAP-format (MIRAA).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Waiting group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>No intervention during 6 weeks, testing directly before and after the waiting period. After the waiting period the participants receives the same intervention as the direct intervention arm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MIRAA (Multimodal Intensive Rehabilitation of Aphasia and Apraxia of speech)</intervention_name>
    <description>Multimodal intensive treatment of aphasia and AOS</description>
    <arm_group_label>Direct intervention</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Modified ICAP (Intensive Comprehensive Aphasia Program)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aphasia minimum 3 months post stroke&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Apraxia of Speech minimum 3 months post stroke&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being able to participate in rehabilitation in Swedish (not in need of translator to&#xD;
             partake).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe loss of sight&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe loss of hearing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe cognitive decline&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ellika Schalling, Ph.D, SLP</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Karolinska Institutet</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Marika J Schütz, Ph.D student</last_name>
    <phone>0046737570430</phone>
    <email>marika.schutz@ki.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Karolinska Institutet, CLINTEC, Division of Speech and Language Pathology, F67, Karolinska University Hospital, Huddinge</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stockholm</city>
        <zip>141 86</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marika Schütz, Ph.D student</last_name>
      <phone>0046737570430</phone>
      <email>marika.schutz@ki.se</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 21, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 30, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Karolinska Institutet</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ellika Schalling</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate professor, Speech Language Pathologist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Intensive rehabilitation</keyword>
  <keyword>Neuroplasticity</keyword>
  <keyword>Implementation in healthcare</keyword>
  <keyword>Stroke guidelines</keyword>
  <keyword>ICAP</keyword>
  <keyword>MIRAA</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Aphasia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Apraxias</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All individual patient data (IPD) that underlie results in a publication.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>2021-2031</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Swedish National Data Service open source</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>http://snd.gu.se</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>June 29, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/25/NCT04957225/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>June 18, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/25/NCT04957225/ICF_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

