<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04959097</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CHLA-RB-liquid-biopsy</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04959097</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>RB Liquid Biopsy Biorepository</brief_title>
  <acronym>rbliqbx</acronym>
  <official_title>Retinoblastoma Patient Clinical Database, Liquid Biopsy and Tissue Biorepository</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Children's Hospital Los Angeles</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Children's Hospital Los Angeles</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Retinoblastoma (RB) is a primary eye cancer that forms in the back of the eye of infants and&#xD;
      toddlers. Traditionally, RB is diagnosed without a biopsy; tumor can only be studied once an&#xD;
      eye has been surgically removed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given this limitation, we use aqueous humor (AH), the clear fluid in the front of the eye to&#xD;
      detect specific markers, or information, that comes from the tumor itself.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Retinoblastoma (RB) is a primary intraocular malignancy that forms in the retina of infants&#xD;
      and toddlers. Traditionally, RB is diagnosed without tissue as direct tumor biopsy is&#xD;
      prohibited due to risk of extraocular spread; tissue can only be obtained once an eye has&#xD;
      been surgically removed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given this limitation, there are no eye-specific molecular biomarkers in current clinical&#xD;
      practice for RB. The lack of in vivo molecular data without removing the eye limits our&#xD;
      ability to prognosticate clinical outcomes and develop personalized treatment plans. It also&#xD;
      limits our understanding of intratumoral dynamics throughout therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aqueous humor (AH) is a high-yield source of tumor-derived nucleic acid that can be&#xD;
      utilized as a liquid biopsy in eyes with retinoblastoma. Detection of biomarkers from the AH&#xD;
      may be used to prognosticate the likelihood of eye salvage and in the future may facilitate&#xD;
      targeted, patient-centered therapies based on molecular biomarkers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Systematically and prospectively record accurate and complete data regarding the&#xD;
           clinical presentation, treatment, and outcomes of patients diagnosed with RB.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Collect, bank, preserve, and analyze biomaterials including AH, blood and saliva from&#xD;
           patients with RB.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Correlate phenotypic data with genotypic findings from human biomaterials in&#xD;
           retinoblastoma patients to identify clinically relevant biomarkers&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>3 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation of Ocular Salvage (eye saved) with biomarkers</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, a minimum of 12 months after diagnosis and average of 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>We aim to evaluate whether any identifiable molecular biomarkers (e.g. chromosomal alterations or tumor fraction) in the aqueous or blood can predict ocular salvage, or the likelihood of saving the eye with therapy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Identification of RB1 gene mutations from the AH liquid biopsy</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, a minimum of 12 months after diagnosis and average of 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>We aim to identify both somatic and germline RB1 gene mutations in the AH</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation of High-Risk Histopathologic Features with presence of biomarkers</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, a minimum of 12 months after diagnosis and average of 24 months (only if the eye is enucleated)</time_frame>
    <description>We aim to evaluate whether any identifiable molecular biomarkers in the aqueous or blood can predict the presence of high risk histopathologic features that are known to increase risk of metastatic disease</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation of class of Seeding with presence of biomarkers</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, a minimum of 12 months after diagnosis and average of 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>We aim to evaluate whether any identifiable molecular biomarkers in the aqueous or blood are associated with the presence of type of seeding</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">800</enrollment>
  <condition>Retinoblastoma</condition>
  <condition>Retinoblastoma Bilateral</condition>
  <condition>Retinoblastoma Unilateral</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Aqueous Humor, Blood, Saliva, Tumor&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients, age 0 days to 18 years, with a diagnosis unilateral or bilateral&#xD;
        retinoblastoma (RB) treated at CHLA who have biospecimens taken for research during the&#xD;
        course of treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients, age 0 days to 18 years, with a diagnosis unilateral or bilateral&#xD;
             retinoblastoma (RB) seen at CHLA.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients referred for second opinions only and not treated at CHLA for any reason.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jesse L Berry, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Children's Hospital Los Angeles</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jesse L Berry, MD</last_name>
    <phone>323-361-4510</phone>
    <email>jberry@chla.usc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Hospital Los Angeles</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90027</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jesse Berry, MD</last_name>
      <phone>323-361-4510</phone>
      <email>jberry@chla.usc.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Berry JL, Xu L, Murphree AL, Krishnan S, Stachelek K, Zolfaghari E, McGovern K, Lee TC, Carlsson A, Kuhn P, Kim JW, Cobrinik D, Hicks J. Potential of Aqueous Humor as a Surrogate Tumor Biopsy for Retinoblastoma. JAMA Ophthalmol. 2017 Nov 1;135(11):1221-1230. doi: 10.1001/jamaophthalmol.2017.4097.</citation>
    <PMID>29049475</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Berry JL, Xu L, Polski A, Jubran R, Kuhn P, Kim JW, Hicks J. Aqueous Humor Is Superior to Blood as a Liquid Biopsy for Retinoblastoma. Ophthalmology. 2020 Apr;127(4):552-554. doi: 10.1016/j.ophtha.2019.10.026. Epub 2019 Oct 31.</citation>
    <PMID>31767439</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Berry JL, Xu L, Kooi I, Murphree AL, Prabakar RK, Reid M, Stachelek K, Le BHA, Welter L, Reiser BJ, Chévez-Barrios P, Jubran R, Lee TC, Kim JW, Kuhn P, Cobrinik D, Hicks J. Genomic cfDNA Analysis of Aqueous Humor in Retinoblastoma Predicts Eye Salvage: The Surrogate Tumor Biopsy for Retinoblastoma. Mol Cancer Res. 2018 Nov;16(11):1701-1712. doi: 10.1158/1541-7786.MCR-18-0369. Epub 2018 Jul 30.</citation>
    <PMID>30061186</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Xu L, Polski A, Prabakar RK, Reid MW, Chevez-Barrios P, Jubran R, Kim JW, Kuhn P, Cobrinik D, Hicks J, Berry JL. Chromosome 6p Amplification in Aqueous Humor Cell-Free DNA Is a Prognostic Biomarker for Retinoblastoma Ocular Survival. Mol Cancer Res. 2020 Aug;18(8):1166-1175. doi: 10.1158/1541-7786.MCR-19-1262. Epub 2020 May 20.</citation>
    <PMID>32434859</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Xu L, Shen L, Polski A, Prabakar RK, Shah R, Jubran R, Kim JW, Biegel J, Kuhn P, Cobrinik D, Hicks J, Gai X, Berry JL. Simultaneous identification of clinically relevant RB1 mutations and copy number alterations in aqueous humor of retinoblastoma eyes. Ophthalmic Genet. 2020 Dec;41(6):526-532. doi: 10.1080/13816810.2020.1799417. Epub 2020 Aug 17.</citation>
    <PMID>32799607</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Polski A, Xu L, Prabakar RK, Kim JW, Shah R, Jubran R, Kuhn P, Cobrinik D, Hicks J, Berry JL. Cell-Free DNA Tumor Fraction in the Aqueous Humor Is Associated With Therapeutic Response in Retinoblastoma Patients. Transl Vis Sci Technol. 2020 Sep 30;9(10):30. doi: 10.1167/tvst.9.10.30. eCollection 2020 Sep.</citation>
    <PMID>33062393</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Xu L, Kim ME, Polski A, Prabakar RK, Shen L, Peng CC, Reid MW, Chévez-Barrios P, Kim JW, Shah R, Jubran R, Kuhn P, Cobrinik D, Biegel JA, Gai X, Hicks J, Berry JL. Establishing the Clinical Utility of ctDNA Analysis for Diagnosis, Prognosis, and Treatment Monitoring of Retinoblastoma: The Aqueous Humor Liquid Biopsy. Cancers (Basel). 2021 Mar 13;13(6). pii: 1282. doi: 10.3390/cancers13061282.</citation>
    <PMID>33805776</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Children's Hospital Los Angeles</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jesse Berry</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Ophthalmology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Retinoblastoma</keyword>
  <keyword>RB</keyword>
  <keyword>Ocular oncology</keyword>
  <keyword>Aqueous humor</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Retinoblastoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified data will be available to other researchers via NIH GDS/dbGAP controlled databases.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_time_frame>October 2023</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_url>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gap/</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

