<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04952792</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2018-002991-41</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04952792</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Apixaban in Patients Receiving Hemodiafiltration</brief_title>
  <acronym>HEMOCIONA</acronym>
  <official_title>Pharmacokinetics, Pharmacodynamics and Safety of Apixaban on Hemodiafiltration</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital Universitari de Bellvitge</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital Universitari de Bellvitge</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Atrial fibrillation (AF) is a prevalent and serious disease in hemodialysis (HD) patients.&#xD;
      Untreated AF increases the risk of deaths related to cardiovascular events and multiplies the&#xD;
      risk of strokes by 5. Anticoagulation with warfarin significantly reduces the incidence of&#xD;
      ischemic strokes in the general population, has a long half-life, and a narrow therapeutic&#xD;
      index that requires periodic monitoring. In addition, warfarin treatment is a frequent cause&#xD;
      of hospital admission for iatrogenesis. In HD patients, the relationship between stroke&#xD;
      prevention benefit and bleeding risk is an unmet medical need. It should be noted that in&#xD;
      these patients the risk of bleeding is multiplied by 3 to 10 times compared to the general&#xD;
      population. The new direct-acting oral anticoagulants (NACOs), thrombin inhibitors&#xD;
      (dabigatran), and activated factor X inhibitors (rivaroxaban, apixaban, edoxaban), do not&#xD;
      require regular monitoring, but their plasma concentrations are altered with the&#xD;
      deterioration of the renal function. According to its technical data sheets, they do not&#xD;
      recommend its use in clinical practice for HD patients. However, the apixaban data sheet&#xD;
      includes the results of a pilot clinical trial in the African American population on HD,&#xD;
      suggesting that it is a safe anticoagulant drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this clinical trial is to evaluate the pharmacokinetics, pharmacodynamics,&#xD;
      and short-term safety (4 weeks) of apixaban in the Spanish population with non-valvular&#xD;
      atrial fibrillation and on hemodialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Long-term safety will be assessed in the extension study: prospective cohort study of&#xD;
      patients included in the clinical trial. Therefore, this project is comprised of 2 clinical&#xD;
      studies (one clinical trial and one extension study) whose objective is to evaluate the&#xD;
      pharmacokinetics, pharmacodynamics, and short and long-term safety of apixaban in patients on&#xD;
      hemodialysis and with non-valvular atrial fibrillation (FANV).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results of this project (clinical trial and extension study) will provide evidence on&#xD;
      whether apixaban may be the anticoagulant treatment of choice for this type of patient.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      7.1 CURRENT STATUS OF SCIENTIFIC-TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE Despite technological advances,&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease remains the most frequent cause of death in hemodialysis (HD)&#xD;
      patients. The higher prevalence of diabetes, anemia, hyperparathyroidism and hypertension in&#xD;
      the population with chronic kidney disease (CKD) favors the appearance of cardiac structural&#xD;
      lesions. In addition, hypervolemia and hydroelectrolytic abnormalities increase the risk of&#xD;
      arrhythmias. In fact, the annual incidence of atrial fibrillation (AF) in the hemodialysis&#xD;
      population is 15 times higher than the general population of the same age and the risk of&#xD;
      presenting a thromboembolic complication by a 5-fold increase.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safely reducing the risk of thromboembolism in patients with AF and CKD is an unmet medical&#xD;
      need. Prospective studies conducted in patients with AF have been systematically excluded in&#xD;
      patients with a Glomerular Filtration Rate (GFR) &lt;30 ml / min. Importantly, patients with CKD&#xD;
      have alterations in hemostasis that predisposes patients to bleeding (reduction of alpha&#xD;
      granules in platelets, reduction of endothelial adhesion molecules) and thrombosis (increased&#xD;
      fibrinogen). This makes it impossible to extrapolate data from the population with normal&#xD;
      kidney function.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Oral anticoagulant treatment with cumarinics such as warfarin, drugs that act as vitamin K&#xD;
      antagonists (AVK), have been shown to be effective in reducing the risk of stroke and&#xD;
      mortality. However, these drugs are not exempt from major complications since it is difficult&#xD;
      to maintain a stable therapeutic index (INR). This frequently leads to the appearance of&#xD;
      hemorrhages (the risk is 2 times higher than in HD patients without anticoagulant treatment)&#xD;
      due to its reduced therapeutic margin and numerous interactions with drugs and foods, which&#xD;
      makes it difficult to predict the pharmacokinetics of these drugs. The use of anticoagulants&#xD;
      in patients with AF and in HD is a controversial topic. For example, the Kidney Disease:&#xD;
      Improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO2012) guidelines do not recommend its use, while the American&#xD;
      College of Cardiology (ACC) / American Heart Association (AHA) / Heart Rhythm Society 2014&#xD;
      guidelines does recommend its use. A recent meta-analysis, which included 7 studies,&#xD;
      concluded that warfarin does not reduce the number of strokes and, in addition, was&#xD;
      associated with a greater number of hemorrhages. In summary, there is not enough high-quality&#xD;
      evidence to recommend warfarin for stroke prevention in patients on hemodialysis with AF.&#xD;
      Furthermore, AVKs favor vascular calcifications and have been related to calciphylaxis&#xD;
      lesions, CKD-associated pathologies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.2. New oral anticoagulants. Apixaban New oral anticoagulants (DOACs) are currently&#xD;
      available, such as direct inhibitors of thrombin (dabigatran) and activated factor X&#xD;
      (rivaroxaban, apixaban, edoxaban). These drugs have demonstrated their clinical efficacy in&#xD;
      patients with GFR&gt; 25 mL/min. DOACs offer the advantage that monitoring of their plasma&#xD;
      levels is not necessary. Importantly, administration of dabigatran and rivaroxaban in&#xD;
      hemodialysis patients has been associated with an increased risk of bleeding and death&#xD;
      compared to warfarin. In contrast, apixaban, a priori, would be the oral anticoagulant of&#xD;
      choice in hemodialysis patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Apixaban is a direct, selective and reversible coagulation Factor Xa (FXa) inhibitor that is&#xD;
      approved to reduce the risk of stroke and systemic embolism in patients with AF of&#xD;
      nonvalvular origin without increasing the risk of bleeding. Apixaban has a rapid absorption,&#xD;
      a half-life of 12 h, it is metabolized by cytochrome P450 and 25% is eliminated via the&#xD;
      kidneys (the rest is eliminated via the digestive tract).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic studies of apixaban in patients with severe chronic&#xD;
      kidney disease (CrCr= 15 mL/min) and in Hemodialysis observed an increase in exposure (area&#xD;
      under the curve of plasma concentration vs. time was 44% and 36% respectively). This&#xD;
      increased exposure is directly correlated with increased anti-Factor Xa activity. However, no&#xD;
      changes were observed in terms of t1/2 (12 hours), maximum concentration (Cmax) or the&#xD;
      presence of adverse effects. In a standard conventional hemodialysis session, the exposure to&#xD;
      apixaban is decreased by 14%. A subsequent study observed the trend towards stability of&#xD;
      apixaban levels after the administration of a reduced dose of apixaban 2.5mg/12h for a week&#xD;
      in a sustained manner, therefore it has been suggested that it can be used in HD without the&#xD;
      need for modify the dose. It should be borne in mind that all the studies that have analyzed&#xD;
      the behavior of apixaban in HD have been carried out in the African American population of&#xD;
      the United States, where the use of convective techniques (HDF) that allow greater&#xD;
      elimination of medium and high molecular weight and that can modify the behavior of drugs&#xD;
      with strong binding to plasma proteins. Apixaban could be affected by this phenomenon as it&#xD;
      is a drug with strong protein binding (UPP 86%). In Catalonia, 65% of patients are on renal&#xD;
      replacement therapy with HDF..&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to the technical data sheet (Section 5.2. Pharmacokinetic properties), in patients&#xD;
      with renal insufficiency: &quot;renal insufficiency had no manifest effect on the relationship&#xD;
      between plasma concentration and anti-Factor Xa activity of apixaban&quot;, and in patients with&#xD;
      end-stage renal disease: &quot;theArea under the Curve (AUC) of apixaban was increased by 36%&#xD;
      compared to that observed in subjects with normal renal function, when a single 5mg dose of&#xD;
      apixaban was administered immediately after hemodialysis. Hemodialysis, started 2 hours after&#xD;
      administration of a single 5mg dose of apixaban, decreased the AUC by 14% in these CKD&#xD;
      subjects, corresponding to an apixaban clearance of 18 mL/min during hemodialysis. Therefore,&#xD;
      hemodialysis is unlikely to be an effective measure to manage apixaban overdose.&quot; Apixaban&#xD;
      appears to be a safe anticoagulant in hemodialysis patients. It should be noted that this&#xD;
      study was conducted in the African American population (87.5%), so we do not know if these&#xD;
      data could be extrapolated to the Spanish population. Apixaban was marketed in May 2011 and&#xD;
      is indicated for &quot;the prevention of stroke and systemic embolism in adult patients with&#xD;
      nonvalvular atrial fibrillation (NVAF) with one or more risk factors such as stroke or&#xD;
      previous transient ischemic attack (TIA); age ≥75 years; hypertension; mellitus diabetes;&#xD;
      symptomatic heart failure (NYHA scale: ≥2). However, there is no information on the&#xD;
      modification of its efficacy with the type of hemodialysis technique, and therefore if it&#xD;
      could be used in clinical practice in hemodialysis patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.3. Work Hypothesis&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Apixaban is a safe oral anticoagulant in patients in our setting with chronic kidney&#xD;
           disease (undergoing hemodiafiltration or hemodialysis) and nonvalvular atrial&#xD;
           fibrillation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Considering that severe renal dysfunction increases the AUC of apixaban by 36% and&#xD;
           hemodialysis treatment only decreases exposure to the drug by 14%, the recommended dose&#xD;
           of apixaban for patients on hemodialysis or hemodiafiltration is 2.5 mg/12h.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Apixaban is an effective oral anticoagulant in patients in our setting with chronic&#xD;
           kidney disease (being treated with hemodiafiltration or hemodialysis) and nonvalvular&#xD;
           atrial fibrillation:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Plasma apixaban concentrations are stable in patients in our setting with chronic&#xD;
                kidney disease (undergoing hemodiafiltration or hemodialysis) and nonvalvular&#xD;
                atrial fibrillation.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. The anti-Factor Xa activity of apixaban is not affected in patients in our setting&#xD;
                with chronic kidney disease (being treated with hemodiafiltration or hemodialysis)&#xD;
                and nonvalvular atrial fibrillation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 20, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood plasma concentrations of Apixaban before, during and after renal replacement therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the plasma concentrations of apixaban before, during and after renal replacement therapy (hemodialysis and hemodiafiltration)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Urine plasma concentrations of Apixaban before, during and after renal replacement therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Study the elimination of apixaban in urine (in those patients with residual diuresis)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-Factor Xa activity of apixaban (heparin activity (IU/mL))</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the heparin activity (IU/mL) before, during and after renal replacement techniques (hemodialysis and hemodiafiltration)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients with medical complications with medical complications not directly related to the underlying disease.</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the number of patients with medical complications with medical complications not directly related to the underlying disease.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dyalisate concentrations of Apixaban before, during and after renal replacement therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the dyalisate concentrations of apixaban during renal replacement therapy (hemodialysis and hemodiafiltration)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total number of adverse events.</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Total number of adverse events.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Economic impact of anticoagulant treatment with apixaban compared to anticoagulant treatment with coumarins- part 1</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>cost of AVK drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Economic impact of anticoagulant treatment with apixaban compared to anticoagulant treatment with coumarins- part 2</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>cost of INR measurements</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Economic impact of anticoagulant treatment with apixaban compared to anticoagulant treatment with coumarins- part 3</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>incremental cost-effectiveness ratios (ICERs)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Economic impact of anticoagulant treatment with apixaban compared to anticoagulant treatment with coumarins- part 4</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>QALY (quality-adjusted life-year)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Atrial Fibrillation</condition>
  <condition>Hemodialysis Complication</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Apixaban</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Apixaban treatment, oral, 2.5 mg/12h, 28 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Apixaban 2.5 milligram Oral Tablet</intervention_name>
    <description>Apixaban 2.5mg/12h, oral, 28 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Apixaban</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adults (18 years or older).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight ≥ 60 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of chronic kidney disease on hemodialysis, clinically stable (with a minimum&#xD;
             of 3 months of treatment) and nonvalvular atrial fibrillation in treatment with&#xD;
             coumarins.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient candidate for change of anticoagulant treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In women of childbearing age, negative pregnancy test (negative human&#xD;
             coriogonadotropine (hCG) urine test).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject gives informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Pregnant or lactating women.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women of childbearing age (period of time from menarche to postmenopausal status,&#xD;
                  defined as 12 months absence of menstruation without other medical cause) who do&#xD;
                  not follow the contraceptive methods recommended by the Clinical Trial&#xD;
                  Facilitation Group (CTFG)&#xD;
                  (https://www.hma.eu/fileadm/dateien/Human_Medicines/01): Hormonal contraceptives&#xD;
                  associated with ovulation inhibitors, intrauterine devices, surgical methods&#xD;
                  (tubal ligation, vasectomy), abstinence, and barrier methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Body weight ≤ 60 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of liver disease (patients with elevated liver enzyme levels alanine&#xD;
                  aminotransferase (ALT) / aspartate aminotransferase (AST)&gt; 2x the upper limit of&#xD;
                  normal, or total bilirubin&gt; 1.5 ULN).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Thrombopenia (&lt;100.000 platelets/mL).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Be on treatment with other anticoagulants (heparins) or antiplatelet drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Be treated with enzyme inhibitors (such as azole antifungals or HIV protease&#xD;
                  inhibitors) or enzyme inducers (such as rifampin, phenobarbital, carbamazepine,&#xD;
                  or phenytoin) of CYP3A4 (Cytochrome P450 3A4 oxidase ).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of bleeding episode in the last month.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of clinical or analytical alterations not attributable to the stage of&#xD;
                  kidney disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participation in another clinical trial of pharmacological treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>MIGUEL HUESO, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>932607385</phone>
    <email>cpolo@idibell.cat</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>CAROLINA POLO, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>932607385</phone>
    <email>cpolo@idibell.cat</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Carolina Polo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08907</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>CAROLINA POLO, MD, PHD</last_name>
      <phone>932607385</phone>
      <email>cpolo@idibell.cat</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>CAROLINA POLO, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>932607385</phone>
      <email>cpolo@idibell.cat</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hospital Universitari de Bellvitge</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>MIGUEL HUESO VAL</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Apixaban</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

