<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04953572</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PekingUTH001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04953572</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment of Cartilage Defects With Peripheral Blood Stem Cells</brief_title>
  <official_title>Autologous Peripheral Blood Mesenchymal Stem Cell Transplantation for Repair of Degree IV Local Cartilage Injury of Knee Joint</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Peking University Third Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Inner Mongolia People's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hebei Medical University Third Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Tianjin Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Peking University Third Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Knee joint cartilage cells metabolize slowly, and it is difficult to repair themselves after&#xD;
      injury. Any knee joint trauma or the progression of osteoarthritis may lead to the&#xD;
      progression of cartilage or osteochondral defects. Compared with bone marrow mesenchymal stem&#xD;
      cells (MSCs), peripheral blood MSCs have better chondrogenic differentiation ability. At the&#xD;
      same time, the mobilization of peripheral blood MSCs and the advancement of extraction&#xD;
      technology also make it feasible to treat osteochondral damage by using peripheral blood&#xD;
      MSCs. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the therapeutic effect of surgical&#xD;
      transplantation of autologous peripheral blood MSCs to repair knee joint Ⅳ-degree localized&#xD;
      cartilage injury, and to explore a new treatment for osteochondral defects based on the&#xD;
      foundation of the research group's previous research.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Explore the clinical efficacy of autologous peripheral blood mesenchymal stem cell&#xD;
           transplantation in the treatment of osteochondral defects&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Exploring the characteristics of cartilage regeneration in autologous peripheral blood&#xD;
           mesenchymal stem cell transplantation&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Magnetic Resonance Imaging in the 6th month after surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after sugery</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic Resonance Imaging，including T2-mapping sequence, to evaluate the magnetic resonance observation of cartilage repair tissue (MOCART) score of cartilage regeneration in the knee articular cartilage defect area at 6 months after sugery. The MOCART score ranges from 0 to 100 points, the higher the score, the better the repair effect.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Magnetic Resonance Imaging in the 12th month after surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months after sugery</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic Resonance Imaging，including T2-mapping sequence, to evaluate the MOCART score of cartilage regeneration in the knee articular cartilage defect area at 12 months after sugery</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Magnetic Resonance Imaging in the 24th month after surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months after sugery</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic Resonance Imaging，including T2-mapping sequence, to evaluate the MOCART score of cartilage regeneration in the knee articular cartilage defect area at 24 months after sugery</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Western Ontario and McMaster Universities (WOMAC) Osteoarthritis Index</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, 12, 18 and 24 months after sugery</time_frame>
    <description>The higher the WOMAC osteoarthritis index, the more severe the OA. Evaluate the severity of OA according to the following criteria: less than 80 is mild, 80-120 is moderate, and greater than 120 is severe.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>International knee documentation committee (IKDC) Knee Joint Score Sheet</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, 12, 18 and 24 months after sugery</time_frame>
    <description>IKDC is an internationally recognized score sheet for comprehensive evaluation of the subjective symptoms and objective signs of the knee joint system.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">252</enrollment>
  <condition>Cartilage Injury</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>test group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in the test group received autologous peripheral blood mesenchymal stem cell therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in the control group 1 received microfracture surgical treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in the control group 2 received microfracture combined with surgical treatment of collagen membrane</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control group 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in the control group 3 received autologous osteochondral transplantation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Genetic</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>autologous peripheral blood mesenchymal stem cell</intervention_name>
    <description>Transplantation of autologous peripheral blood mesenchymal stem cell</description>
    <arm_group_label>test group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Microfracture</intervention_name>
    <description>Microfracture</description>
    <arm_group_label>control group 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Microfracture + collagen membrane</intervention_name>
    <description>Microfracture plus collagen membrane transplantation</description>
    <arm_group_label>control group 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Autologous osteochondral transplantation</intervention_name>
    <description>Autologous osteochondral transplantation</description>
    <arm_group_label>control group 3</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adults over 18 and under 60, regardless of gender.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Symptoms, signs and imaging changes are consistent with knee joint limitations IV&#xD;
             cartilage defect or patella chondromalacia, patellofemoral joint cartilage injury,&#xD;
             mild to moderate knee osteoarthritis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Other treatments are ineffective.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. No treatment for other knee cartilage defects during the specified period of the test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The subject must be able to communicate well with the researcher and comply with the&#xD;
             research requirements, and must give written, signed and dated informed consent before&#xD;
             conducting any research-related activities. All relevant legal representatives will&#xD;
             also sign a written research agreement in accordance with local laws and regulations.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The diameter of the cartilage defect in the patient is less than 5mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Grade Ⅲ and Ⅳ knee joint OA.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The patient's symptoms and signs are not closely related to the cartilage defect area.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Suffering from concomitant inflammatory diseases (such as rheumatoid arthritis),&#xD;
             osteochondrotis dissecans, sepsis, osteonecrosis, and various tumor diseases in the&#xD;
             past; in the past three months, there was in the joint cavity of the affected knee&#xD;
             History of injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Suffer from the underlying medical conditions (including but not limited to&#xD;
             metabolism, hematology, kidney, liver, lung, nerve , Endocrine, heart, infection, or&#xD;
             gastrointestinal tract); currently suffering from a serious progressive or&#xD;
             uncontrolled disease that is not suitable for the test or puts it at high risk,&#xD;
             including the researchers belief that it will prevent the subject from following the&#xD;
             protocol or completing the study according to the protocol Any medical or psychiatric&#xD;
             condition of&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Being infected with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), infectious hepatitis B or&#xD;
             hepatitis C or corresponding medical history.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Suffer from a progressive infection or malignant disease, and be able to produce chest&#xD;
             X-ray, computed tomography (CT scan) or MRI evidence within 12 weeks before screening,&#xD;
             and be evaluated and confirmed by a qualified physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Active systemic infections (except colds) or any other infections that will recur&#xD;
             regularly in the previous two weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. There is a history of chronic or recurrent infectious diseases, or evidence of&#xD;
             tuberculosis infection that was judged to be positive at the time of screening.&#xD;
             Subjects who have obtained positive or uncertain results can participate in the study&#xD;
             if they undergo a comprehensive tuberculosis examination (according to local&#xD;
             practice/guidelines) within 12 weeks before baseline and finally prove that there is&#xD;
             no evidence of active tuberculosis. If the presence of latent tuberculosis is&#xD;
             confirmed, treatment must be initiated and maintained in accordance with local or&#xD;
             national guidelines before the baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of lymphoproliferative disease, or any known malignant tumor, or history of&#xD;
             malignant tumor of any organ system in the past 5 years (Bowen's disease, basal cell&#xD;
             carcinoma, or actinic keratosis after treatment and no evidence of recurrence in the&#xD;
             past 12 weeks Except for diseases; except for excised cervical carcinoma in situ or&#xD;
             non-invasive malignant colon polyps).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Suffer from medical problems at the same time, including but not limited to the&#xD;
             following:&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Uncontrolled hypertension (systolic blood pressure ≥160mmHg and/or diastolic blood&#xD;
             pressure ≥95mmHg), congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association status&#xD;
             classification III or IV).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subjects whose serum creatinine level exceeds 2.0 mg/dl (176.8 μmol/L).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Total white blood cell (WBC) count at screening &lt;2500/μL, or platelet &lt;100000/μL or&#xD;
             neutrophil &lt;1500/μL or hemoglobin &lt;8.5 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. For pregnant or lactating women, pregnancy is defined as the state of a woman after&#xD;
             conception until the termination of pregnancy, which is confirmed by the positive&#xD;
             result of the hCG laboratory test.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Women with childbearing potential are defined as all women who are physiologically&#xD;
             able to become pregnant, unless they use effective contraceptive methods during the&#xD;
             entire study treatment administration period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. In the six months before the baseline, there is a history of alcohol or drug abuse or&#xD;
             evidence of ongoing abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. A history of allergies to the components of the therapeutic drugs used.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. The returning visitors cannot be tracked in time.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jia-kuo Yu, Prof.</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Peking University Third Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jia-kuo Yu, Prof.</last_name>
    <phone>+86 13331031448</phone>
    <email>yujiakuo@126.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institute of Sports Medicine, Peking University Third Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beijing</city>
        <state>Beijing</state>
        <zip>100191</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jia-kuo Yu, MD</last_name>
      <phone>86-10-82267392</phone>
      <email>yujiakuo@126.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Peking University Third Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Yu Jiakuo</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chief physician</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

