<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04957251</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB 150819-1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04957251</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Anterior vs Posterior Approach for Hip Hemiarthroplasty</brief_title>
  <official_title>Does the Anterior or Posterior Approach to the Hip Provide Superior Functional Recovery After Recovery After Performing Hip Hemiarthroplasty</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mount Carmel Health System</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mount Carmel Health System</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Randomized trial to evaluate the role of the anterior vs posterior approach regarding&#xD;
      hemiarthroplasty of the hip. The Investigators' hypothesis is that the muscle sparing&#xD;
      anterior approach may result in improved function in the short term, which may allow shorter&#xD;
      hospital stay and quicker return to prior level of function.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      In patients who sustain a displaced femoral neck fracture, who do not meet criteria for total&#xD;
      hip arthroplasty, the recommendations are made for a hemi-arthroplasty of the hip. There are&#xD;
      multiple surgical approaches that can be used including the anterior approach to the hip and&#xD;
      the posterior approach to the hip. The most widely performed approach to the hip when&#xD;
      performing a total hip arthroplasty or hemi-arthroplasty has been the posterior approach.&#xD;
      However, multiple approaches exist including posterior approach, direct lateral approach,&#xD;
      anterolateral approach and direct anterior approach. There is not a consensus about which&#xD;
      approach is the most appropriate or best for patients. The decision for approach is widely&#xD;
      decided by the surgeon and is based on experience and preference of the surgeon. Recent&#xD;
      advances in the anterior approach to the hip have found improved results with regards to&#xD;
      functional status and decreased complications when compared to the posterior approach for&#xD;
      total hip arthroplasty. There have been several retrospective studies comparing the anterior&#xD;
      vs. posterior approach for hemi-arthroplasty with regards to treatment of femoral neck&#xD;
      fractures. These studies have shown conflicting results with regards to which approach is&#xD;
      superior. Retrospective studies have shown decreased dislocation rate with the anterior&#xD;
      approach, but increased operative time and increased rate of infection with anterior approach&#xD;
      as well. To date, there have been two prospective studies performed comparing the anterior&#xD;
      and posterior approach for hemi-arthroplasty, one in Japan and one in France, both of which&#xD;
      showed decreased dislocation rates but did not display long term functional improvement&#xD;
      comparing the two approaches. Both of these studies' patient population and protocol differ&#xD;
      greatly from standard of care in the United States. To date, there have been no prospective&#xD;
      randomized controlled trials evaluating the functional advantage of the anterior vs. the&#xD;
      posterior approach when performing hip hemi-arthroplasty procedure for femoral neck fractures&#xD;
      in the United States. It is our hypothesis that the anterior approach will provide superior&#xD;
      functional results as a product of the decreased damage to soft tissue and restoration of&#xD;
      normal anatomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are several objectives of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective of this study is to evaluate the functional status of each patient using a&#xD;
      Harris Hip Score to evaluate both function and pain comparing the anterior vs. the posterior&#xD;
      approach for hemi-arthroplasty at 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives of this study include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  time to ambulation post operatively&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  rate of complications including infection, nerve palsy, and DVT/PE&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  operative time&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  rate of dislocation&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  periprosthetic fracture&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  mortality&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  return to preoperative mobility status&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  blood loss&#xD;
&#xD;
      Significance:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results of this study would either confirm the retrospective data that currently exists&#xD;
      showing no difference in functional outcomes between the two approaches or demonstrate a&#xD;
      superior functional status with either the anterior or posterior approach for hip&#xD;
      hemi-arthroplasty. Of which, logically and anecdotally, the Investigators' believe will be&#xD;
      the anterior approach. With this research, theInvestigators' believe the anterior approach&#xD;
      can become the standard of care for the surgical technique with regards to hemi-arthroplasty&#xD;
      for hip fractures&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible patients will include all patients that were previously ambulatory at some level who&#xD;
      sustain a displaced femoral neck fracture that given functional status, age, and&#xD;
      comorbidities will require a hemi-arthroplasty for definitive treatment. Ages 65-99&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who will be excluded from the study are all patients who are non ambulatory at&#xD;
      baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who meet eligibility criteria will be offered to participate in the study. Once the&#xD;
      patient consents, the participants will be randomized to receive either the anterior or&#xD;
      posterior approach for hemi-arthroplasty of the hip. After surgery, the participant will&#xD;
      undergo standard postoperative care (hip precautions) with data collected from the electronic&#xD;
      health record and from standard hospital care including rounding. The participant will then&#xD;
      follow up at appropriate standard interval with the main endpoint of 6 months where Harris&#xD;
      Hip Scores will be used to judge the participant's functional status as well as pain relief.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analysis of the collected data will occur at intervals of 50 patients to evaluate trends or&#xD;
      statistical significance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Monitoring Participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
      If at any time during this study the participant or medical decision maker decides to no&#xD;
      longer participate in the study, the participant will be removed from the study and will&#xD;
      continue to undergo standard treatment for their condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consent:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consent will be obtained so long as the participant meets the appropriate criteria listed&#xD;
      above and will be given a detailed informed consent document outlining the purpose of the&#xD;
      study and associated risks and benefits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Human Subject Protections:&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is currently no widely accepted technique based on outcomes with regards to operative&#xD;
      approach for hip hemi-arthroplasty, nor is there a standard approach for total hip&#xD;
      arthroplasty. Therefore, the participant will not have to do anything different from an&#xD;
      intervention standpoint and therefore are not at any increased risk based on our study&#xD;
      protocol. All participants will receive treatment of hip fracture in an appropriate fashion.&#xD;
      They will be asked standard postoperative questions during their stay and will undergo&#xD;
      standard follow up. The only change from current standard of care in follow up will include&#xD;
      the primary investigator performing a Harris Hip questionnaire and assessment at each&#xD;
      postoperative visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With regards to selection, the only criteria will be a baseline ambulatory status prior to&#xD;
      sustaining a displaced femoral neck fracture. The participants who are demented will be&#xD;
      included in the study because a large percentage of patients who sustain femoral neck&#xD;
      fractures and require a hemi-arthroplasty have some baseline dementia. These participants&#xD;
      will only be included if a medical power of attorney or appropriate medical decision maker is&#xD;
      available.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be collected and analyzed after 50 participants using a student t-test analysis to&#xD;
      evaluate for statistical significance or tends. The goal of 200 patients is to obtain the&#xD;
      largest prospective controlled trial to date. Analysis every 50 is based off of previous&#xD;
      literature that showed statistical significance near 50 patients in some categories including&#xD;
      dislocation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adverse Events Reporting&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is a single surgeon study that is not blinded and all adverse events outside of&#xD;
      the expected complications associated with hip hemi-arthroplasty will be reported immediately&#xD;
      to the IRB board.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient confidentiality&#xD;
&#xD;
      The only PHI data that will be kept will be the FIN number to pull information from the&#xD;
      electronic health record during analysis. This is necessary as a means to be able to&#xD;
      accurately report lab values, operative times, and other pertinent information from their&#xD;
      hospital stay. Otherwise, all hard copy data will be locked in a safe location, and all&#xD;
      electronic data will be password protected.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 28, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Harris Hip Score. Score ranges from 0-100 The higher the HHS, the less dysfunction. A total score of &lt;70 is considered a poor result; 70-80 is considered fair, 80-90 is good, and 90-100 is an excellent result</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Hip Fractures</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Anterior approach</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient's undergoing an anterior approach to the hip</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Posterior Approach</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient's undergoing an posterior approach to the hip</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>anterior approach to the hip</intervention_name>
    <description>anterior hip hemiarthroplasty</description>
    <arm_group_label>Anterior approach</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>posterior approach to the hip</intervention_name>
    <description>posterior hip hemiarthroplasty</description>
    <arm_group_label>Posterior Approach</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eligible patients will include all patients that were previously ambulatory at some&#xD;
             level who sustain a displaced femoral neck fracture that given functional status, age,&#xD;
             and comorbidities will require a hemi-arthroplasty for definitive treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ages 65-99&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who will be excluded from the study are all patients who are non ambulatory&#xD;
             at baseline.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 23, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 30, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hip Fractures</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Database that is kept on site that may be reviewed.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

