<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04959344</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Kleb4V01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04959344</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Immunogenicity of a Klebsiella Pneumoniae Tetravalent Bioconjugate Vaccine (Kleb4V)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Safety and Immunogenicity of a Klebsiella Pneumoniae Tetravalent Bioconjugate Vaccine (Kleb4V) Administered to Healthy Adults: A FTIH Phase I/II Randomized and Controlled Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>LimmaTech Biologics AG</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>LimmaTech Biologics AG</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this study, the tetravalent bioconjugate candidate vaccine Kleb4V will be tested to obtain&#xD;
      first-time-in-human (FTIH) data on its safety and immunogenicity in healthy adults.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Kleb4V is a tetravalent bioconjugate vaccine including O antigen-polysaccharides of the most&#xD;
      predominant Klebsiella pneumoniae serotypes, which will be formulated with or without&#xD;
      Adjuvant System, AS03. Study participants will be randomized towards Kleb4V Low dose with or&#xD;
      without AS03, Kleb4V Target dose with or without AS03, or placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be conducted in two steps. In Step1 (safety cohort): safety and tolerability&#xD;
      of Kleb4V without and with Adjuvant AS03 will be evaluated first in adults of 18-40 y, and&#xD;
      subsequently in the target population of older adults 55-70 y. Enrolment will be staggered in&#xD;
      groups of small numbers to the different doses and formulations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Step 2 (target cohort): Older adults (55-70y) will be concomitantly randomized to receive&#xD;
      1 of the 4 different vaccine formulations or placebo.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 5, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>observer-blind</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety: Occurrence, severity and relationship of solicited local and general AEs (Adverse Events)</measure>
    <time_frame>during 7 days following each vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Occurrence, severity and relationship of solicited local and general AEs (Adverse Events)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety: Occurrence, severity and relationship of unsolicited AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>during 28 days following each vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Occurrence, severity and relationship of unsolicited AEs</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety: Occurrence, severity and relationship of medically relevant AEs, AESIs and SAEs</measure>
    <time_frame>through the study completion, on average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Occurrence, severity and relationship of medically relevant AEs, AESIs (Adverse Events of Special Interest) and SAEs (Serious Adverse Events)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenicity: IgG (Immunoglobulin G) titers against the Klebsiella pneumoniae O serotypes included in the vaccine</measure>
    <time_frame>between baseline and 28 days after the second injection</time_frame>
    <description>For each active group vs. placebo: Comparison of geometric mean titers (GMTs) of serum IgG against the four K. pneumoniae O-serotypes included in Kleb4V.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">166</enrollment>
  <condition>Klebsiella Pneumoniae Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Kleb4V target dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Study participants receive 2 target doses of the non-adjuvanted investigational product 2 months apart.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Kleb4V target dose + AS03</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Study participants receive 2 target doses of the adjuvanted investigational product 2 months apart.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Kleb4V low dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Study participants receive 2 low doses of the non-adjuvanted investigational product 2 months apart.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Kleb4V low dose + AS03</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Study participants receive 2 low doses of the adjuvanted investigational product 2 months apart.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo (Diluent)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Study participants receive 2 doses of the Placebo 2 months apart.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Kleb4V target dose</intervention_name>
    <description>Two doses of the non-adjuvanted Kleb4V target dose will be administered intramuscularly 2 months apart</description>
    <arm_group_label>Kleb4V target dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Kleb4V target dose + AS03</intervention_name>
    <description>Two doses of the adjuvanted Kleb4V target dose will be administered intramuscularly 2 months apart</description>
    <arm_group_label>Kleb4V target dose + AS03</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Kleb4V low dose</intervention_name>
    <description>Two doses of the non-adjuvanted Kleb4V low dose will be administered intramuscularly 2 months apart</description>
    <arm_group_label>Kleb4V low dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Kleb4V low dose + AS03</intervention_name>
    <description>Two doses of the adjuvanted Kleb4V low dose will be administered intramuscularly 2 months apart</description>
    <arm_group_label>Kleb4V low dose + AS03</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Two doses of the Placebo will be administered intramuscularly 2 months apart</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo (Diluent)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Good general health by medical history, laboratory findings and physical examination&#xD;
             before receiving vaccination as judged by the investigator (subjects with a minor&#xD;
             controlled illness, such as mild controlled hypertension, asthma or COPD (Chronic&#xD;
             Obstructive Pulmonary Disease), and without fever may be enrolled at the discretion of&#xD;
             the investigator)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject who is willing and able to comply with the requirements of the protocol (e.g.&#xD;
             completion of the diary cards, return for follow-up visits)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Signed written informed consent obtained from the subject&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. For Step 1 Groups 1 and 2 only: Female or male between 18-40 years (inclusive) of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. For Step 1 Groups 3 to 6, and Step 2: Female or male subjects between 55-70&#xD;
             (inclusive) years of age at the time of first vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Female subjects of childbearing potential are eligible, as long as they practice&#xD;
             adequate contraceptive measures from 2 months before the first vaccination until 1&#xD;
             month after the last vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Health condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, may interfere with optimal&#xD;
             participation in the study or place the volunteer at increased risk of adverse events&#xD;
             (AEs) Study clinicians, in consultation with the principal investigator, will use&#xD;
             clinical judgement on a case-by-case basis to assess safety risks under this criterion&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any clinically significant deviation from the normal range in biochemistry or&#xD;
             hematology blood tests in the opinion of the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Clinically significant abnormalities on physical examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Suspected or known hypersensitivity (including allergy) to any of the vaccine&#xD;
             components or to medicinal products or medical equipment whose use is foreseen in this&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of allergy to any vaccine&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Clinical conditions representing a contraindication to intramuscular vaccination and&#xD;
             blood draws (e.g. coagulation disorder)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Acute or chronic, clinically significant cardiovascular, pulmonary, hepatic or renal&#xD;
             abnormality diseases and/or insufficiency as determined by physical examination or&#xD;
             laboratory tests. In particular: unstable current or history of coronary artery&#xD;
             disease or cardiac insufficiency, uncontrolled hypertension, clinically significant&#xD;
             history of myocardial infarction, atrial fibrillation, uncontrolled or clinically&#xD;
             significant type 2 diabetes, current or history of rheumatoid arthritis or temporal&#xD;
             arteritis, current acute or chronic active pulmonary diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note: Subjects may be on chronic or as needed medications if, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             site principal investigator or appropriate sub-investigator, they pose no additional&#xD;
             risk to subject safety or assessment of reactogenicity and immunogenicity and do not&#xD;
             indicate a worsening of medical diagnosis or condition&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Known or suspected impairment of immunological function, documented Human&#xD;
             Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) infection, asplenia/splenectomy, or history of autoimmune&#xD;
             disease or lymphoproliferative disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Positive blood test for HBsAg, HCV (Hepatitis C Virus), HIV-1/2&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Positive test for SARS-CoV-2 (severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus type 2)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of systemic administration of immunosuppressive drugs, i.e. corticosteroids,&#xD;
             (PO/IV/IM) within the last 4 weeks prior to 1st vaccination or for more than 14&#xD;
             consecutive days within 3 months prior to 1st vaccination, until the last blood&#xD;
             sampling visit (i.e. prednisone or equivalent ≥20 mg/day). Inhaled and topical&#xD;
             steroids are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Administration of anti-neoplastic and immune-modulating agents or chemotherapy within&#xD;
             90 days prior to informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Planned administration of a vaccine not foreseen by the study protocol within 4 weeks&#xD;
             prior to 1st vaccination and 4 weeks after last vaccination. Vaccination against&#xD;
             seasonal influenza virus (or CoVID (Coronavirus disease) vaccine if on the market) is&#xD;
             allowed outside of +/- 7 days from each vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Concurrently participating in another clinical study, at any time during the study&#xD;
             period, in which the subject has been or will be exposed to an investigational or a&#xD;
             non-investigational interventional vaccine/product (pharmaceutical product)&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Body Mass Index (BMI) &lt;19 and &gt;30&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. History of any chronic or progressive disease that according to judgement of the&#xD;
             investigator could interfere with the study outcomes or pose a threat to the&#xD;
             participant's health&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Received an investigational or non-registered product (medicinal drug or vaccine),&#xD;
             other than the study vaccine within 3 months prior to 1st administration of study&#xD;
             vaccine, or planned use during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Administration of immunoglobulin and/or any blood products within the three months&#xD;
             preceding the first dose of study vaccine&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Blood donation of at least 500 mL blood draw within 3 months preceding injection or&#xD;
             planned during the study period as reported by subject&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Use of any antibiotic therapy within 1 week preceding each injection&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Subjects with an elective surgical intervention, planned during the study period until&#xD;
             30 days after 2nd vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Females lactating, or pregnancy or intention to become pregnant as reported by subject&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Current and/or history of chronic alcohol consumption and/or drug abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. History of immune-mediated disease (see Table of pIMDs (potential Immune Mediated&#xD;
             Diseases) in Annex).&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Heavy smokers (&gt; 20 cigarettes per day)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Cristina Alaimo</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>LimmaTech Biologics AG</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Steffen Haffner, Dr</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Nuvisan GmbH</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Patricia Martin, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+41447338585</phone>
    <email>patricia.martin@lmtbio.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Cristina Alaimo, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+41447338585</phone>
    <email>cristina.alaimo@lmtbio.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nuvisan GmbH, Standort Gauting, Robert-Koch-Allee 29</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gauting</city>
        <zip>82131</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michael Lyssi</last_name>
      <phone>+49 89 89 35 69 29</phone>
      <email>michael.lissy@nuvisan.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael Lyssi</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nuvisan GmbH, Standort Neu-Ulm, Wegenerstrasse 13</name>
      <address>
        <city>Neu-Ulm</city>
        <zip>89231</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Steffen Haffner, Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 731 9840 452</phone>
      <email>Steffen.Haffner@nuvisan.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Steffen Haffner, Dr</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Klebsiella Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

