<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04953338</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P044</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04953338</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mental Health Associations With Vitiligo</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Mental Health Associations With Vitiligo: a Population-based Cohort Study in the UK</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Momentum Data</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Pfizer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Momentum Data</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This cohort study is a large population-based study in the UK to determine the risks of&#xD;
      comorbid mental health conditions (including depression, anxiety and other potential&#xD;
      psychological complications of vitiligo) in adults with vitiligo compared to controls and to&#xD;
      evaluate whether the relative risks may vary by different ethnicity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study has two primary outcomes 1) Prevalence and incidence of mental health condtions in&#xD;
      people diagnosed with vitiligo compared to matched controls and 2) Primary care and secondary&#xD;
      healthcare utilisation in patients diagnosed with vitiligo and having a prevalent depressive&#xD;
      conditon compared to matched controls. In addition, the study examines risk of time off work&#xD;
      and unemployment in people diagnosed with vitiligo compared to matched controls.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 18, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Describe the prevalence of common mental health conditions in adults diagnosed with vitiligo and matched controls without vitiligo</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of diagnosis in all people diagnosed with vitiligo 2004-2020 inclusive. For matched controls, the date of diagnosis of their matched case.</time_frame>
    <description>Prevalence of common mental health conditions (depressive episodes, recurrent depressive disorder and anxiety disorder) in adult people diagnosed with vitiligo.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Describe the incidence of common mental health conditions in adults diagnosed with vitiligo and matched controls without vitiligo</measure>
    <time_frame>Within two years of vitiligo diagnosis. For matched controls, within two years of the date of diagnosis of their matched case.</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of common mental health conditions (depressive episodes, recurrent depressive disorder and anxiety disorder) in adult people with vitiligo in a contemporary real-world population compared with matched controls.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Describe healthcare utilisation in adults with incident (new onset) vitiligo and matched controls without vitiligo</measure>
    <time_frame>Within one year of vitiligo diagnosis. For matched controls, within one year of the date of diagnosis of their matched case.</time_frame>
    <description>Healthcare utilisation comprises of number of primary care visits.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Describe mental health management patterns in adults with vitiligo and mental health conditions (depressive episodes, recurrent depressive disorder and anxiety disorder)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within one year of vitiligo diagnosis. For matched controls, within one year of the date of diagnosis of their matched case.</time_frame>
    <description>Mental health management comprises of referrals for cognitive behavioural therapy, counselling, psychotherapy, psychiatry, and other psychological intervention either through direct referral or the Improving Access to Psychological Therapies (IAPT) services programme.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Describe the burden of 'sick days' and unemployment in adult people of normal working age diagnosed with vitiligo and matched controls without vitiligo</measure>
    <time_frame>Within one year of vitiligo diagnosis.</time_frame>
    <description>Sick days will be indicated by the issuing of Med 3 certification from primary care (Statement of Fitness for Work) certification. Unemployment will be identified using Read codes relating to unemployment recorded in the clinical record or the issuing of an Incapacity Benefit (IB113) or Employment and Support Allowance (ESA113) form. Normal working age is defined as aged 18 - 65 years.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Describe other potential psychological complications in adult people diagnoses with vitiligo and matched controls without vitiligo</measure>
    <time_frame>Within one year of vitiligo diagnosis.</time_frame>
    <description>Psychological complications comprises of social phobia, adjustment disorder, substance abuse, self-harm, overdose, and parasuicide or suicide attempts.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Describe the incidence of common mental health conditions (depressive episodes, recurrent depressive disorder and anxiety disorder) in adult people with vitiligo stratified by sociodemographic factors compared to matched controls.</measure>
    <time_frame>Within two years of vitiligo diagnosis. For matched controls, within two years of the date of diagnosis of their matched case.</time_frame>
    <description>Sociodemographic groups are defined by 10-year age category, sex, socio-economic status and ethnicity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">45000</enrollment>
  <condition>Vitiligo</condition>
  <condition>Depressive Episode</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Depressive Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Anxiety Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Social Phobia</condition>
  <condition>Adjustment Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Substance Abuse</condition>
  <condition>Self-Harm, Deliberate</condition>
  <condition>Overdose</condition>
  <condition>Suicide, Attempted</condition>
  <condition>Parasuicide</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cases</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with a confirmed diagnosis of Vitiligo within the study period will be included as cases for analysis.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Controls</arm_group_label>
    <description>The controls will be defined by matching cases with people who have never been diagnosed with vitiligo either prior to or during the study period, by age and sex, at General Practice level.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exposure of mental health condtion of interest</intervention_name>
    <description>Common mental health conditions consist of depressive episodes, recurrent depressive disorder and anxiety disorder.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cases</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Controls</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This study will use routinely collected and collated data from OPCRD to provide a broadly&#xD;
        representative sample of the population of the UK.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All eligible adults ≥18 (as at date of vitiligo diagnosis for cases or start of&#xD;
             follow-up for controls) registered with GP practices contributing data to OPCRD&#xD;
             between January 1, 2004 and December 31, 2020, were eligible for inclusion in the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People with less than 1 year of follow up available&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andrew McGovern, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Momentum Data Ltd</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Momentum Data Ltd</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>WC1X 8QT</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vitiligo</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Suicide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Phobia, Social</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Self-Injurious Behavior</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Suicide, Attempted</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adjustment Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>OPCRD data can be accessed by bone fide researchers for specific research projects subject to approval by Anonymised Data Ethics &amp; Protocol Transparency (ADEPT) Committee. The data utilised for this study cannot be made available without such approval.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The data will be available subject to approvals for two years after the study publication date</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Data sharing is subject to ADEPT committee approval</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

