<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04953221</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D2020155</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04953221</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of YJ001 on Diabetic Peripheral Neuropathic Pain.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled, Phase II Clinical Trial to Evaluate the Effectiveness and Safety of Spray YJ001 in the Treatment of Diabetic Peripheral Neuropathic Pain.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Peking University Third Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Peking University Third Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this study, a randomized, double-blind, placebo parallel-controlled design was used to&#xD;
      evaluate the effectiveness and safety of YJ001 spray applied to local skin in patients with&#xD;
      diabetic peripheral neuropathic pain, and to explore the best effective dose.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this study, a randomized, double-blind, placebo parallel-controlled design was used to&#xD;
      evaluate the effectiveness and safety of YJ001 spray applied to local skin in patients with&#xD;
      diabetic peripheral neuropathic pain, and to explore the best effective dose.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The change in the average weekly NRS score of pain from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>at the twelfth week after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Numerical Rating Scale ：0-10 points, the greater the score, the more severe the pain.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The change in the average weekly NRS score of pain from the baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>1-11 weeks after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Numerical Rating Scale ：0-10 points, the greater the score, the more severe the pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes from baseline in the average sleep disturbance scores</measure>
    <time_frame>each week and during the follow-up period from 1 to 12 weeks after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>sleep disturbance scores：0-10 points, the greater the score, the more severe the sleep disturbance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The change from baseline in the SF-36 Quality of Life Scale score</measure>
    <time_frame>at the 12th week after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>SF-36 Quality of Life Scale score：0-100 points, the smaller the score, the more severe the quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>6</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">225</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetic Peripheral Neuropathic Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>M1 Test group</arm_group_label>
    <description>YJ001 for spray, topical application on the skin, drug concentration 100mg/mL, 2 times/day (interval 11-13h), 8 sprays each time, a total of 12 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>M1 control group</arm_group_label>
    <description>YJ001 simulant for spray, topical application on the skin, drug concentration 100mg/mL, 2 times/day (interval 11-13h), 8 sprays each time, a total of 12 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>M2 Test group:</arm_group_label>
    <description>YJ001 for spray, topical application on the skin, drug concentration 150mg/mL, 2 times/day (interval 11-13h), 8 sprays each time, a total of 12 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>M2 control group:</arm_group_label>
    <description>YJ001 simulant for spray, topical application on the skin, drug concentration 150mg/mL, 2 times/day (interval 11-13h), 8 sprays each time, a total of 12 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>M3 Test group</arm_group_label>
    <description>YJ001 for spray, topical application on the skin, drug concentration 200mg/mL, 2 times/day (interval 11-13h), 8 sprays each time, a total of 12 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>M3 control group</arm_group_label>
    <description>YJ001 simulant for spray, topical application on the skin, drug concentration 200mg/mL, 2 times/day (interval 11-13h), 8 sprays each time, a total of 12 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>YJ001</intervention_name>
    <description>Skin spray</description>
    <arm_group_label>M1 Test group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>M2 Test group:</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>M3 Test group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Diabetic peripheral neuropathic pain patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Subjects must meet all of the following criteria to be enrolled in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The age of screening was 18-75 years old, regardless of gender;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Diagnosis of type 1 or type 2 diabetes for at least 1 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Diabetic peripheral neuropathic pain was diagnosed and the duration of pain was 23&#xD;
             months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The level of glycosylated hemoglobin was less than 9%;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. At the screening visit, according to the 11 point digital pain intensity scale (NRS),&#xD;
             the score was greater than or equal to 4; During the 1-week lead-in period, subjects&#xD;
             completed at least 10 NRS pain scores, and the average pain score was greater than or&#xD;
             equal to 4.0;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The subjects are willing and able to comply with the study visit arrangement,&#xD;
             treatment plan, laboratory examination and other study procedures;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Those who agree to participate in the trial and sign the written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Subjects meeting any one or more of the following criteria will not be allowed to&#xD;
        participate in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Have known or suspected the ingredients of spray YJ001, the ingredients of YJ001&#xD;
             simulant, and ASA.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Those who are allergic to aspirin, salicylic acid or yj001 (such as 5-aminosalicylic&#xD;
             acid, sulfasalazine and salicylate) or have serious adverse reactions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Those who have participated in yj001 clinical study and received research drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The subjects have a wide range of systemic pain, which will affect the pain evaluation&#xD;
             of the drug delivery site according to the judgment of the researchers; Or in the hand&#xD;
             or more proximal area than the foot.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The subjects with severe peripheral vascular disease (such as intermittent&#xD;
             claudication) at the time of screening were not suitable for the trial according to&#xD;
             the judgment of the researchers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects suffered from nondiabetic peripheral neuropathy, such as osteoarthritis, II&#xD;
             stage and above peripheral arterial disease, lumbar disc herniation, vitamin B&#xD;
             deficiency, alcoholism, herpes neuralgia, vasculitis, and severe mental disorders such&#xD;
             as depression and anxiety. It will also affect the researchers' evaluation of diabetic&#xD;
             peripheral neuropathic pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. There is skin disease in the affected skin area. According to the judgement of the&#xD;
             researcher, it may affect the evaluation of diabetic peripheral neuropathic pain.&#xD;
             According to the judgment of the researcher, the subjects have tattoos or other skin&#xD;
             abnormalities that may interfere with the purpose of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The score of skin condition evaluation of the administration site was more than 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients with malignant tumors, but have received appropriate treatment or resection&#xD;
             of non metastatic skin basal cell carcinoma or squamous cell carcinoma, or cervical&#xD;
             cancer in situ.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Amputation beyond the end of the fingers and toes.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Diabetic foot ulcers, infection and gangrene were associated with diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. There are metabolic complications of acute diabetes, such as diabetic ketoacidosis or&#xD;
             lactic acidosis or hyperosmolar hyperglycemia syndrome or hyperosmolar diabetic&#xD;
             hyperglycemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. One or more severe hypoglycemia events occurred 6 months before screening or during&#xD;
             the induction period (it means that the subjects need help from others to obtain&#xD;
             carbohydrates, glucagon or other rescue measures).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. The NRS score of subjects with more than two pain scores was less than 3 points in the&#xD;
             1-week lead-in period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patients who had used transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation (TENS), acupuncture&#xD;
             and other treatment measures within 2 weeks before entering the group, or during the&#xD;
             treatment period, subjects need combined transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation&#xD;
             (TENS) or acupuncture treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Local analgesics (such as capsaicin patches and lidocaine patches) used in the&#xD;
             treatment of diabetic peripheral neuropathic pain in the first 2 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Abnormal liver and kidney function: ast or aut &gt; 2.5 times the upper limit of normal&#xD;
             value, creatinine &gt; 1.5 times the upper limit of normal value.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Complicated with severe cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases (such as degree II&#xD;
             or III heart block, congestive heart failure with NYHA cardiac function grade III-IV,&#xD;
             myocardial infarction, and acute stroke).&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Severe diseases of respiratory system, blood and hematopoietic system were found.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. There are other neurological diseases (such as cognitive impairment). The researchers&#xD;
             believe that it may affect the evaluation of diabetic peripheral neuropathic pain or&#xD;
             affect self ratings, or the psychiatric patients who are not suitable for the trial by&#xD;
             the researchers.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Patients with known or suspected history of alcohol abuse, drug abuse or dependence in&#xD;
             the past year.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Pregnant and lactating women; The male subjects (including their female partners) and&#xD;
             the fertile female subjects had the intention of having children or could not&#xD;
             guarantee the use of one or more contraceptives within 3 months from the beginning of&#xD;
             screening to the end of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Those who participated in other clinical trials within 3 months before screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Other cases that the researcher considered unsuitable to participate in this trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Peking University Third Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beijing</city>
        <state>Beijing</state>
        <zip>100098</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetic Neuropathies</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

