<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04953234</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EF-37</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04953234</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Tumor Treating Fields (TTFields, 150 kHz) Concomitant With Best Standard of Care for the Treatment of Hospitalized COVID-19 Patients and Continued Treatment Following Discharge</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pilot, Open-Label Study of NovoTTF-100L (TTFields, 150Hz) in Hospitalized Patients With COVID-19 and Continued Treatment After Hospitalization</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>NovoCure GmbH</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>NovoCure Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study is a prospective, pilot study aimed to test the safety of Tumor Treating Fields&#xD;
      (TTFields) concomitant with best standard of care, for the treatment of hospitalized COVID-19&#xD;
      patients and continued treatment after hospitalization. The device is an experimental,&#xD;
      portable, battery operated device for chronic administration of alternating electric fields&#xD;
      (termed TTFields) to the region of the organ to be treated, by means of surface, insulated&#xD;
      electrode arrays.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PAST PRE-CLINICAL AND CLINICAL EXPERIENCE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tumor Treating Fields (TTFields) are a non-invasive, regional antimitotic treatment modality&#xD;
      with minimal toxicity which have been approved for the treatment of recurrent and newly&#xD;
      diagnosed glioblastoma (GBM) by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) in the United States&#xD;
      and have obtained a CE mark in Europe for the same indications. TTFields concomitant with&#xD;
      chemotherapy were also approved for malignant pleural mesothelioma under FDA's humanitarian&#xD;
      device exemption.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cell culture study demonstrated that TTFields can significantly reduce corona virus infection&#xD;
      and replication in human lung cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DESCRIPTION OF THE STUDY:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients included in this study are patients who are hospitalized due to COVID-19&#xD;
      disease. In addition, all patients must meet all eligibility criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible patients will be enrolled to the study and will receive COVID-19 best standard of&#xD;
      care treatment concomitant with TTFields using the NovoTTF-100L System. The patients will be&#xD;
      treated continuously with the device until discharge from the hospital and until there are no&#xD;
      limitations on activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SCIENTIFIC BACKGROUND:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Electric fields exert forces on electric charges similar to the way a magnet exerts forces on&#xD;
      metallic particles within a magnetic field. These forces cause movement and rotation of&#xD;
      electrically charged biological building blocks, much like the alignment of metallic&#xD;
      particles seen along the lines of force radiating outwards from a magnet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Electric fields can also cause muscles to twitch and if strong enough may heat tissues.&#xD;
      TTFields are alternating electric fields of low intensity. This means that they change their&#xD;
      direction repetitively many times a second. Since they change direction very rapidly (150&#xD;
      thousand times a second), they do not cause muscles to twitch, nor do they have any effects&#xD;
      on other electrically activated tissues in the body (brain, nerves and heart). Since the&#xD;
      intensities of TTFields in the body are very low, they do not cause heating.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The breakthrough finding made by Novocure was that alternating fields of very low intensity,&#xD;
      now termed TTFields (Tumor Treating Fields), attenuate SARS-CoV-2 virus infection and&#xD;
      replication. TTFields can be directed to a certain part of the body, leaving sensitive areas&#xD;
      out of their reach.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In conclusion, TTFields hold the promise of serving as a brand new treatment for COVID-19&#xD;
      disease with very few side effects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 23, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 26, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 26, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency and severity of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 29</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of participants who died by study Day 29.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of intensive care unit admission</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 29</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of non-invasive ventilation or high-flow oxygen use</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 29</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of invasive ventilation</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 29</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of extracorporeal membrane oxygenation</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 29</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient inflammatory status</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 3, 8, and 11</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammatory status measured as the difference in C reactive protein (CRP), D-dimer and ferritin blood levels from baseline on days 3, 8 and 11 until discharge.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 29</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to recovery</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 29</time_frame>
    <description>Day of recovery is defined as the first day on which the subject satisfies one of the following three categories from the ordinal scale: 1) Hospitalized, not requiring supplemental oxygen - no longer requires ongoing medical care; 2) Not hospitalized, limitation on activities and/or requiring home oxygen; 3) Not hospitalized, no limitations on activities.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical status at day 8, 15, 22, 29</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 8, 15, 22, and 29</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical status according to ordinal scale. The scale is as follows: 8) Death; 7) Hospitalized, on invasive mechanical ventilation or extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO); 6) Hospitalized, on non-invasive ventilation or high flow oxygen devices; 5) Hospitalized, requiring supplemental oxygen; 4) Hospitalized, not requiring supplemental oxygen - requiring ongoing medical care (COVID-19 related or otherwise); 3) Hospitalized, not requiring supplemental oxygen - no longer requires ongoing medical care; 2) Not hospitalized, limitation on activities and/or requiring home oxygen; 1) Not hospitalized, no limitations on activities.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NovoTTF-100L</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive TTFields using the NovoTTF-100L System together with COVID-19 best standard of care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>NovoTTF-100L</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients receive continuous TTFields treatment using the NovoTTF-100L device. TTFields treatment will consist of wearing four electrically insulated electrode arrays on the thorax. The treatment enables the patient to maintain regular daily routine.</description>
    <arm_group_label>NovoTTF-100L</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>TTFields</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Hospitalized with diagnosis of COVID-19 infection per reverse transcription polymerase&#xD;
             chain reaction (RT-PCR) within 72 hours prior to treatment start.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. SpO2 ≤ 93% at sea level.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Lung involvement confirmed with chest imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Able and willing to comply with all study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Female participants of childbearing age must use highly effective contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. All patients must understand and voluntarily sign an informed consent document prior&#xD;
             to any study related assessments/procedures being conducted.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Receipt of any experimental treatment for COVID-19 prior to or during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Assisted ventilation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Critical illness: respiratory failure defined as oxygen saturation by pulse&#xD;
             oximetry/inspired oxygen fraction (SpO2/FiO2) ratio &lt; 150, septic shock, and/or&#xD;
             multiple organ dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Significant co-morbidities at baseline as determined by the investigator:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Clinically significant hematological, hepatic and renal dysfunction, defined as:&#xD;
                  Neutrophil count &lt; 1.5 x 10^9/L and platelet count &lt; 100 x 10^9/L; bilirubin &gt;&#xD;
                  1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN); aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and/or&#xD;
                  alanine transaminase (ALT) &gt; 2.5 x ULN; and serum creatinine &gt; 2.5 mg/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. History of significant cardiovascular disease unless the disease is well&#xD;
                  controlled. Significant cardiac disease includes second/third degree heart block;&#xD;
                  significant ischemic heart disease; poorly controlled hypertension; congestive&#xD;
                  heart failure of the New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class IV (unable to carry&#xD;
                  on any physical activity without discomfort. Symptoms of heart failure at rest.&#xD;
                  If any physical activity is undertaken, discomfort increases).&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. History of arrhythmia that is symptomatic or requires treatment. Patients with&#xD;
                  atrial fibrillation or flutter controlled by medication are not excluded from&#xD;
                  participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. History of any psychiatric condition that might impair patient's ability to&#xD;
                  understand or comply with the requirements of the study or to provide consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Implantable electronic medical devices (e.g. pacemaker, defibrillator) in the upper&#xD;
             torso.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnancy or breast-feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Known allergies to medical adhesives or hydrogel.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Unwilling or unable to comply with the requirements of this protocol, including the&#xD;
             presence of any condition (physical, mental, or social) that is likely to affect the&#xD;
             subject's cooperation or other unspecified reasons that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             Investigator or sponsor, make the subject's enrollment incompatible with study&#xD;
             objectives.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hadassah Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jerusalem</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

