<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04955197</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Cancer screening</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04955197</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Exfoliated Cytology in Detection of Oral Premalignant and Malignant Lesions</brief_title>
  <official_title>Accuracy of Exfoliated Cytology in Detection of Oral Premalignant and Malignant Lesions</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Micronuclei have been used since 1937 as an indicator of genetic toxic exposure due to their&#xD;
      association with chromosomal alterations. They can be detected in exfoliated cells and used&#xD;
      as an indicator of recent DNA injury within oral mucosa. The buccal epithelial cells are&#xD;
      first to be interacted with the cancer compounds such as tobacco (nicotine), which in turn&#xD;
      induces the frequency of micronuclei under the influence of saliva. The exfoliated cell&#xD;
      micronuclei assay involves microscopic analysis of oral smears to determine the prevalence of&#xD;
      micro-nucleation. The assay is reliable and technically easy to perform, noninvasive and&#xD;
      sensitive with limited cost.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study will be held at the Faculty of Dentistry Cairo University and the NCI All the&#xD;
      participants will be administrated a standardized questionnaire to obtain demographic data,&#xD;
      medical records and any history of relevant risk factors. The detailed clinical examination&#xD;
      will be performed on each patient to assess the site, size, and the clinical characteristics&#xD;
      of the lesion as well as the extent of local infiltration (if any) and cervical lymph node&#xD;
      metastases (if any).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The entire procedure will be explained to the patients and an informed consent will be&#xD;
      obtained. The participants were asked to rinse their mouth thoroughly with tap water 2-3&#xD;
      times immediately before the sampling procedure to reduce the oral bacterial load.&#xD;
      Pre-moistened separate wooden spatula was used to scrape the oral buccal mucosa cells (right&#xD;
      and left buccal mucosal cells). The cells were then smeared over clean, coded glass slides.&#xD;
      The slides were then air dried and fixed in fixative for 20 minutes and stained. Afterwards&#xD;
      the glass slide was rinsed with aqua dest and dried in the air. The slides will be prepared&#xD;
      for microscopic analysis The criteria parameters for identifying micronucleus:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Rounded smooth perimeter suggestive of a membrane.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Less than one-third the diameter of the associated nucleus, but large enough to discern&#xD;
           shape and color.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Staining intensity similar to the nucleus.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Texture similar to the nucleus.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Same focal plane as the nucleus.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Absence of overlap with or bridge to the nucleus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dead or degenerating cells (karyolysis, karyorrhexis, nuclear fragmentation) were excluded&#xD;
      from the evaluation. Incisional or excisional biopsy will be obtained from subjects diagnosed&#xD;
      with premalignant lesions and histo-pathological examination will be performed as an&#xD;
      additional supportive test .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Micronuclei count</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>a sensitive indicators of genetic damage. They are usually found in the basal cells of epidermis and are shed as exfoliated cells on maturation. Hence micronuclei assay can be used as monitoring of genetic damage, as it is increased in oral neoplastic conditions.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">48</enrollment>
  <condition>Oral Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Diagnoses Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>the histo-pathological picture</arm_group_label>
    <description>In the present study, the exfoliated cytology of group II and III will be compared to the histo-pathological picture of the lesion &quot;reference standard&quot;. That is because the histopathology analysis is the definitive diagnosis of oral mucosal lesions</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>exfoliated cytology</intervention_name>
    <description>Micronuclei (MN) are small chromatin bodies in the cytoplasm formed by chromosome fragments or whole chromosomes that fail to be included in the nuclei during cell division. They are considered as a sensitive indicators of genetic damage. They are usually found in the basal cells of epidermis and are shed as exfoliated cells on maturation. Hence micronuclei assay can be used as monitoring of genetic damage, as it is increased in oral neoplastic conditions. Consequently, an increase in the number of micronuclei in exfoliated cells indicates an increased risk for cancer</description>
    <arm_group_label>the histo-pathological picture</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants with clinically normal oral mucosa and no evidence of any cancer risk factor&#xD;
        as smoking and alcohol consumption. Participants with potentially malignant (leukoplakia,&#xD;
        oral lichen planus, smoker keratosis and erythroplakia) Participants diagnosed with&#xD;
        malignant disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
        • All age range will be included irrespective of their sex.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Control group I: Participants with clinically normal oral mucosa and no evidence of&#xD;
             any cancer risk factor as smoking and alcohol consumption.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Compare group II: Participants with potentially malignant (leukoplakia, oral lichen&#xD;
             planus, smoker keratosis and erythroplakia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Compare group III: Participants diagnosed with malignant disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All age range will be included irrespective of their sex.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Individuals who had a recent viral infection or had undergone radiation therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Those patients were excluded from the control group who had any history of&#xD;
                  tobacco intake or alcohol consumption and under medications.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>alaa elnaggar, MSD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Cairo University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>alaa elnaggar, MSD</last_name>
    <phone>01007802767</phone>
    <email>alaa_hassan@dentistry.cu.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gihane madkour, professor</last_name>
    <email>gihanemadkour@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Faculty of Dentistry</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <zip>11865</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>alaa elnaggar, Master</last_name>
      <phone>01007802767</phone>
      <email>alaa_hassan@dentistry.cu.edu.eg</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jadhav K, Gupta N, Ahmed MB. Micronuclei: An essential biomarker in oral exfoliated cells for grading of oral squamous cell carcinoma. J Cytol. 2011 Jan;28(1):7-12. doi: 10.4103/0970-9371.76941.</citation>
    <PMID>21552400</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Alaa Mostafa Hassan Elnaggar</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>assistant lecturer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>diagnosis</keyword>
  <keyword>screening</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mouth Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Precancerous Conditions</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

