<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04958135</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ALXN2060-HV-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04958135</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Assess the Effect of Food on a Single Dose of Acoramidis in Healthy Adult Participants</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1, Randomized, Open-Label, 2-Period, 2-Sequence, 2-Way Crossover Study to Assess the Effect of Food on the Single Dose Pharmacokinetics of Acoramidis in Healthy Participants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Alexion Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Celerion</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Alexion Pharmaceuticals</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the effect of a high-fat, high-caloric meal on the&#xD;
      pharmacokinetics (PK) of acoramidis in healthy adult participants following an oral single&#xD;
      dose administration of acoramidis. Blood sampling for PK assessment will include measures for&#xD;
      acoramidis and its metabolite, acoramidis acyl glucuronide (acoramidis-AG).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 16, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 17, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 17, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This will be a balanced, 2-period, 2-sequence, 2-way crossover study in healthy participants. All participants will receive 1 treatment in each period.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Observed Plasma Concentration (Cmax) Of Acoramidis: Fed (Test) Versus Fasted (Reference) Conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 336 hours postdose</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under The Plasma Concentration Versus Time Curve From Time 0 To The Last Quantifiable Concentration (AUC0-t) For Acoramidis: Fed (Test) Versus Fasted (Reference) Conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 336 hours postdose</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under The Plasma Concentration Versus Time Curve From Zero To Infinity (AUC0-inf) For Acoramidis: Fed (Test) Versus Fasted (Reference) Conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 336 hours postdose</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax Of Acoramidis-AG: Fed (Test) Versus Fasted (Reference) Conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 336 hours postdose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC0-t For Acoramidis-AG: Fed (Test) Versus Fasted (Reference) Conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 336 hours postdose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC0-inf For Acoramidis-AG: Fed (Test) Versus Fasted (Reference) Conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 336 hours postdose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">18</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sequence 1: Acoramidis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive acoramidis once each period as a single dose under fasted or fed conditions as follows:&#xD;
Period 1: Acoramidis as an immediate-release tablet under fasted conditions.&#xD;
Period 2: Acoramidis as an immediate-release tablet under fed conditions.&#xD;
There will be a washout period of at least 14 days between acoramidis dosing.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sequence 2: Acoramidis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive acoramidis once each period as a single dose under fasted or fed conditions as follows:&#xD;
Period 1: Acoramidis as an immediate-release tablet under fed conditions.&#xD;
Period 2: Acoramidis as an immediate-release tablet under fasted conditions.&#xD;
There will be a washout period of at least 14 days between acoramidis dosing.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acoramidis</intervention_name>
    <description>Film-coated immediate release oral tablet.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sequence 1: Acoramidis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sequence 2: Acoramidis</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ALXN2060</other_name>
    <other_name>AG10</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Key Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who are healthy as determined by medical evaluation with no clinically&#xD;
             significant or relevant abnormalities as determined by medical history, physical&#xD;
             examination, vital signs, 12-lead electrocardiogram, and clinical laboratory&#xD;
             evaluation (hematology, chemistry, urinalysis, and coagulation) that are reasonably&#xD;
             likely to interfere with the participant's participation in or ability to complete the&#xD;
             study, or to potentially confound interpretation of study results, as assessed by the&#xD;
             Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight ≥ 50 to ≤ 100 kilograms (kg) and body mass index within the range ≥ 18 to&#xD;
             &lt; 32 kg/meter squared for all participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Key Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of any clinically significant deviation from normal in clinical laboratory&#xD;
             evaluations, as determined by the Investigator or designee.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of any medical or psychiatric condition or disease that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             Investigator or designee, might limit the participant's ability to complete or&#xD;
             participate in this clinical study, confound the results of the study, or pose an&#xD;
             additional risk to the participant by their participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or presence of clinically significant hypersensitivity or idiosyncratic&#xD;
             reaction to the study interventions or related compounds. History of allergy to other&#xD;
             drugs or food will be evaluated by the Investigator or designee on a case by case&#xD;
             basis and a decision to enroll will be made by the Investigator or designee.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any clinically relevant history or the presence of respiratory, renal, hepatic,&#xD;
             gastrointestinal, hematological, lymphatic, neurological, cardiovascular, psychiatric&#xD;
             disease or diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Disorders of central nervous system, psychiatric disorders, behavioral disturbances&#xD;
             (for example, cerebrovascular events, depression, post-traumatic stress disorder,&#xD;
             anxiety, bipolar disorder, severe migraine, Parkinson's disease).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant disease or condition that could interfere with, or treatment of which&#xD;
             might interfere with, the conduct of the study, or that would, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator, pose an unacceptable risk to the participant in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in any other investigational study drug trial in which receipt of an&#xD;
             investigational study drug occurred within 30 days prior to the first dose of study&#xD;
             intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participants who are pregnant, as evidenced by a positive serum pregnancy test&#xD;
             result at Screening, or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior exposure to ALXN2060.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery or hospitalization within 90 days prior to dosing on Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of tobacco in any form (for example, smoking, chewing or vaping), other&#xD;
             nicotine-containing products in any form (for example, gum, patch, electronic&#xD;
             cigarettes, or vapes), or any recreational inhalational product within 6 months prior&#xD;
             to the planned first day of dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of known drugs of abuse within 6 months prior to the planned first day of dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Regular alcohol consumption within 6 months prior to the study defined as: an average&#xD;
             weekly intake of &gt; 14 units/week for males or &gt; 7 units/week for females. One unit is&#xD;
             equivalent to 8 grams of alcohol: a half pint (~240 milliliters [mL]) of beer, one ~4&#xD;
             ounce glass (125 mL) of wine, or 1 (25 mL) measure of spirits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive urine drug toxicology screen at Screening or check-in (Day -1).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alcohol consumption within 24 hours prior to study intervention administration or&#xD;
             positive alcohol breath test at Screening or check-in (Day -1).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sensitivity to any of the study interventions, or components thereof, or drug or other&#xD;
             allergy that, in the opinion of the Investigator or Medical Monitor, contraindicates&#xD;
             participation in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Celerion</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lincoln</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68502</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Acoramidis</keyword>
  <keyword>ALXN2060</keyword>
  <keyword>AG10</keyword>
  <keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
  <keyword>Food Effect</keyword>
  <keyword>Crossover</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

