<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00144404</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>02-04-376-07</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00144404</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Baseline Sexual Function, Cognitive Function, Body Composition and Muscle Parameters and Pharmacokinetics of Transdermal Testosterone Gel in Women With Hypopituitarism</brief_title>
  <official_title>Baseline Sexual Function, Cognitive Function, Body Composition and Muscle Parameters and Pharmacokinetics of Transdermal Testosterone Gel in Women With Hypopituitarism</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Charles Drew University of Medicine and Science</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Charles Drew University of Medicine and Science</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the blood levels of testosterone gel administered&#xD;
      for a week to women with hypopituitarism and determine if this leads to testosterone&#xD;
      replacement in a normal range for women. An additional objective is to determine the baseline&#xD;
      laboratory abnormalities and physical, brain function, emotional and sexual symptomatology of&#xD;
      these women with hypopituitarism.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The ovaries and the adrenal glands contribute to the daily production of 300 micrograms of&#xD;
      testosterone in healthy, menstruating women. The physiologic role of testosterone in women,&#xD;
      however, remains poorly understood. Previous studies of testosterone supplementation, largely&#xD;
      in surgically or naturally menopausal women, have reported improvements in subjective&#xD;
      measures of sexual function, sense of well being, and variable changes in markers of bone&#xD;
      formation and resorption. However, many of these previous studies used supraphysiologic doses&#xD;
      of testosterone, and insensitive assays for the measurement of total and free testosterone&#xD;
      levels that lacked precision and accuracy in the low range prevalent in women. The effects of&#xD;
      testosterone in women on body composition, muscle performance and physical function have not&#xD;
      been studied. Therefore, the clinical significance of androgen deficiency in women remains&#xD;
      unclear. Thus, we do not know whether physiologic testosterone replacement of women with&#xD;
      androgen deficiency can produce clinically meaningful improvements in sexual and cognitive&#xD;
      functions, fat-free mass, and muscle performance, without virilizing side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Women with hypopituitarism represent an excellent model to study the effects of physiologic&#xD;
      replacement as these patients have severely diminished androgen production from both the&#xD;
      adrenal glands and the ovaries. Estrogen administration, by increasing sex hormone binding&#xD;
      globulin (SHBG) in these women leads to further reduction in free testosterone&#xD;
      concentrations. In fact, a recent study demonstrated very low levels of total and free&#xD;
      testosterone, dehydroepiandrosterone sulfate (DHEAS), its parent steroid&#xD;
      dehydroepiandrosterone (DHEA), and androstenedione in women with hypopituitarism. Therefore,&#xD;
      it is postulated that many women with hypopituitarism suffer from decreased libido, altered&#xD;
      body composition, and impaired quality of life, symptoms possibly related to androgen&#xD;
      deficiency. However, these parameters have not been properly studied in a well-defined group&#xD;
      of women with hypopituitarism. These baseline studies are needed prior to undertaking a study&#xD;
      on treating women with hypopituitarism with a testosterone preparation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to investigating testosterone replacement in a large study of women with&#xD;
      hypopituitarism, we must first determine in this pilot study the amount and interval of&#xD;
      testosterone administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Currently, the only FDA-approved drug for testosterone in women is Estratest, which contains&#xD;
      methyl testosterone, a compound that when given orally is associated with liver toxicity in&#xD;
      animals and humans. Until recently, most hypogonadal men received biweekly intramuscular&#xD;
      injections of testosterone. This regimen gives variable serum testosterone levels depending&#xD;
      on the time of the blood sampling compared to the time of injection. Many male hypogonadal&#xD;
      patients now receive their testosterone replacement via either transdermal testosterone gel&#xD;
      or patch, with much more uniform serum testosterone levels. We have chosen transdermal&#xD;
      testosterone gel for use in this study for several reasons:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Recent studies have shown that stable, reproducible levels of serum testosterone can be&#xD;
           obtained irrespective of application site in hypogonadal men. No skin irritation (which&#xD;
           can be problematic with the testosterone patch) was observed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Graded Double-blinded dosing can easily be implemented.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus, we will use transdermal testosterone gel as it provides predictable and physiologic&#xD;
      levels of testosterone.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    this was not a clinical trial&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>August 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2002</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2002</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The purpose of this study is to determine the pharmacokinetics of testosterone gel 2 mg/d administered for a week to women with hypopituitarism and determine if this leads to testosterone replacement in a physiologic range.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>An additional objective is to determine the baseline laboratory abnormalities and physical, cognitive, emotional and sexual symptomatology of these women with hypopituitarism.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Panhypopituitarism</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women age 18-55&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypopituitarism with documented central adrenal and gonadal deficiencies. Serum&#xD;
             testosterone level of &lt; 20 ng/dl or free testosterone &lt;1.5 pg/ml on conjugated equine&#xD;
             estrogen replacement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No other significant medical condition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight between 80 and 150% of ideal body weight&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All races and ethnicities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients regardless of marital status and relationship status&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physical disabilities that would prevent them from participating in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of testosterone or other androgenic steroids. Patients who are taking&#xD;
             testosterone, DHEA or other androgen precursors will discontinue these&#xD;
             medications/supplements three months prior to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant cardiopulmonary disease, renal disease (creatinine &gt; 1.5 mg/dL), diabetes&#xD;
             mellitus, uncontrolled hypertension, malignancy (other than basal cell skin carcinoma)&#xD;
             or major psychiatric disease. Patients with depression or anxiety on a stable dose of&#xD;
             medication will be allowed to enroll.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current abuse of illicit drugs or heavy ethanol use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of breast or uterine cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with significant liver function abnormalities defined as SGOT, SGPT or alkaline&#xD;
             phosphatase value of greater than one and one-half times the upper limit of normal in&#xD;
             our Clinical Pathology Laboratory or serum bilirubin levels of greater than 2 mg/dl&#xD;
             will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with history of hyperandrogenic disorders such as hirsutism and polycystic ovary&#xD;
             disease will be excluded. These conditions are rare in women with hypopituitarism.&#xD;
             Testosterone administration to these patients may exacerbate the underlying disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant, seeking to become pregnant in the next 6 months, or breast&#xD;
             feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who have previously experienced intolerance to other transdermal systems&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Drugs known to alter testosterone production such as Megace or ketoconazole&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with untreated hyperprolactinemia or active Cushing's disease. Patients with&#xD;
             treated prolactinoma or Cushing's disease will be allowed to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hematocrit &gt; 50%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male sex&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not willing to answer all questions on surveys&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ted C Friedman, M.D., Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Charles Drew University of Medicine and Science</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Charles R. Drew University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90059</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.centerwatch.com</url>
    <description>Clinical Trial Research site</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 1, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 2, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 5, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 15, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 15, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 18, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Theodore C. Friedman, M.D., Ph.D. Principal Investigator</name_title>
    <organization>Charles Drew University of Medicine and Science</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypopituitarism</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

