<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00144430</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GVH 0313</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00144430</nct_id>
    <nct_alias>NCT00228826</nct_alias>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pentostatin for High Risk and Refractory Chronic Graft Versus Host Disease in Children</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Study of Pentostatin For the Treatment of High Risk or Refractory Chronic GVHD in Children</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ann &amp; Robert H Lurie Children's Hospital of Chicago</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Astex Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ann &amp; Robert H Lurie Children's Hospital of Chicago</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter trial through the Pediatric Blood and Marrow Transplant Consortium.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Primary hypothesis of this study is that because of its effect as a potent&#xD;
      immunosuppressive agent targeting lymphocytes, pentostatin will show a sustained response in&#xD;
      pediatric subjects with severe chronic GVHD. Secondary hypotheses include that the infection&#xD;
      and toxicity rate of pentostatin in this setting will be acceptable given its lack of severe&#xD;
      myelosuppression, and subjects with refractory chronic GVHD will have significant QOL&#xD;
      impairment and symptomatology. These may change as subjects are being treated for their&#xD;
      chronic GVHD with pentostatin.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      To participate in this study, subjects must have diagnosed chronic Graft versus Host Disease&#xD;
      that is refractory to therapy or that is considered high risk (i.e. low platelet count,&#xD;
      progressive onset and greater than 50% of body surface area affected). Subjects must have not&#xD;
      failed more than 2 immunosuppressive regimens in order to be considered for this trial.&#xD;
      Eligible subjects will receive intravenous pentostatin every 2 weeks for 24 weeks. If the&#xD;
      subject has had a complete response, the therapy will end at 24 weeks. If the subject has had&#xD;
      a partial or mixed response or stable disease, they will continue on study receiving&#xD;
      pentostatin for 52 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2004</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2008</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2008</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To estimate the response rate (CR and PR) of pentostatin when used to treat refractory-chronic GVHD in children.</measure>
    <time_frame>To end of study</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To gather initial efficacy and safety data in high-risk untreated chronic GVHD in children.</measure>
    <time_frame>To end of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate toxicities of pentostatin when used to treat chronic GVHD in children.</measure>
    <time_frame>To end of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate quality of life (QOL) and symptoms at diagnosis and after therapy with pentostatin in pediatric patients with refractory chronic GVHD.</measure>
    <time_frame>To end of study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Graft vs Host Disease</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pentostatin</intervention_name>
    <description>The drug, Pentostatin, is given every 2 weeks. This drug will be given by intravenous (IV) infusion.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allogeneic BMT or SCT recipients. Includes cord blood and peripheral blood.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 0-21 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
        FOR REFRACTORY GROUP:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of chronic GVHD, confirmed by biopsy of any organ after SCT. Given the&#xD;
             variability among centers, biopsy needs to say, at the very least, &quot;consistent with&#xD;
             GVHD.&quot; If there is a medical contra-indication (such as severe sclerosis with poor&#xD;
             wound healing) or the need for an open procedure to obtain a fascial biopsy then a&#xD;
             photograph documenting the skin and abnormal ROM studies may be submitted instead. If&#xD;
             current GVHD represents the same episode which was previously biopsied, then a new&#xD;
             biopsy is not necessary. If the previous biopsy was for an episode that went into&#xD;
             remission and this is a new episode of GVHD, then a new biopsy is necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
        To be eligible for this portion of the study, a patient's chronic GVHD can be extensive or&#xD;
        limited, as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All subjects with extensive chronic GVHD are eligible. These subjects must meet the&#xD;
             following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Generalized skin involvement (&gt;50% BSA)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  OR Localized skin involvement and/or liver dysfunction plus at least one of the&#xD;
                  following:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Liver histology showing chronic aggressive hepatitis, bridging necrosis,&#xD;
                       cirrhosis, or ductopenia.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Eye involvement (Schirmer's test with &lt; 5 mm wetting)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Involvement of minor salivary glands or oral mucosa on lip biopsy&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Involvement of any other target organs&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  OR Involvement of at least 2 target organs.(Target organs are listed below under&#xD;
                  &quot;Examples of characteristic manifestations)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with limited chronic GVHD (defined as those with skin involvement in less&#xD;
             than 50% BSA or isolated organ involvement 51 are also eligible. Examples of these&#xD;
             subjects would be those with limited sclerodermatous or fascial skin disease or oral&#xD;
             disease that is unresponsive to therapy and may be debilitating to the patient.&#xD;
             Subjects with isolated refractory liver chronic GVHD may go on study provided they&#xD;
             have liver histology as above.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Examples of characteristic manifestations include:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  skin changes - rash, lichenoid changes, sclerodermatous changes, hypopigmentation,&#xD;
             hyperpigmentation, loss of appendages (hair follicles, sweat glands), alopecia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  oral changes - erythema, lichenoid changes, ulceration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hepatic involvement - obstructive jaundice, chronic hepatitis, cirrhosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  GI involvement - nausea, vomiting, weight loss, esophageal dysmotility, malabsorption,&#xD;
             chronic diarrhea, abdominal cramps&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  sicca syndrome - dry eyes and mouth (decreased tearing, keratoconjunctivitis, oral&#xD;
             mucosal erythema and ulcerations)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  other inflammatory conditions - myositis, arthritis, polyserositis&#xD;
&#xD;
        To be eligible for this portion of the study subjects must have refractory disease defined&#xD;
        below:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Development of new sites of disease while being treated for chronic GVHD* (These&#xD;
             criteria can be met at any time post-transplant after treatment for chronic GVHD has&#xD;
             begun. This includes subjects who develop new sites of disease while on steroid&#xD;
             therapy, tapering steroid therapy, or other therapy. The only necessary elements are&#xD;
             TREATMENT of chronic GVHD and NEW area of disease. -OR-&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progression of an initially affected site of chronic GVHD while being treated for&#xD;
             chronic GVHD, the chronic GVHD worsens. This type of patient has worsening of any&#xD;
             initially affected area at any time. This includes subjects that are judged to be&#xD;
             steroid-dependent, and once a taper of steroids is initiated, they flare in the same&#xD;
             organ. -OR-&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure to improve despite at least 1 month of standard therapy (These subjects have&#xD;
             shown no response (not improved but not worse) to cGVHD therapy. These therapies&#xD;
             include, but are not limited to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prednisone at an average of 0.5 mg/kg/day or equivalent steroid.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Another immunosuppressive regimen (e.g.. FK506/MMF or photopheresis).&#xD;
&#xD;
        FOR HIGH-RISK GROUP:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The vast majority of these subjects will be identified at initial diagnosis of chronic&#xD;
             GVHD and will be subjects progressing from acute to chronic. These subjects are likely&#xD;
             to be on steroids for acute GVHD and have skin changes that are rapidly shifting from&#xD;
             simple erythema to a lichenoid/pebbly appearance consistent with chronic GVHD. For&#xD;
             inclusion into this arm, the following are required:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Extensive skin involvement (&gt;50%BSA) with either lichenoid or sclerodermatous&#xD;
                  changes.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Either one or both of the following high-risk features:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Thrombocytopenia (PLT&lt;100,000)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Progressive onset ( i.e. Changes suggestive of progression from acute to&#xD;
                       chronic). This includes, but is not limited to, skin becoming increasingly&#xD;
                       scaly, pebbly, raised, and lymphedematous. It is not unusual to see this&#xD;
                       transition even before day 100, especially in non-myeloablative SCT and DLI.&#xD;
                       If there are any questions regarding these changes and whether they qualify,&#xD;
                       call the PI, Dr. David Jacobsohn, 773-880-3694.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A biopsy after SCT showing acute or chronic GVHD. A biopsy showing acute GVHD is&#xD;
                  acceptable if the clinical picture is progressing to chronic GVHD.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient is on prednisone ≥2 mg/kg/day (or equivalent dose if on another steroid)&#xD;
                  and has received more than 7 days of therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  More than two previous regimens to treat chronic GVHD. A regimen for the purpose of&#xD;
             this study is defined as an adequate trial of an immunosuppressive or&#xD;
             immunosuppressive combination (patient was given drug or drugs for 3 months unless&#xD;
             there was clear progression during regimen).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Calculated Cr. Clearance&lt;30 ml/min/1.73m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection not responding to oral or IV antibiotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects and families unwilling to firmly commit to return for follow-up doses and&#xD;
             appointments.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any investigational agent in the past 30 days (this does not include the use of&#xD;
             licensed agents for indications not listed in the package insert).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or nursing mother; Females of child-bearing potential and sexually active&#xD;
             males should use effective contraception while on study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active veno-occlusive disease of the liver.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bronchiolitis obliterans (defined for the purpose of this study by respiratory&#xD;
             symptoms such as shortness of breath or cough and FEV1&lt;50%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky performance score less than 40 (or Lansky performance less than 40 in&#xD;
             subjects under 16 years of age).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>1 Month</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David Jacobsohn, MD, MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Children's Memorial Hospital, Chicago, IL</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Loma Linda University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Loma Linda</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92350</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pediatric Medical Center for Northern California</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oakland</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94609</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nemour's Children's Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jacksonville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32007</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Miami</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33136</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>All Children's Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>St. Petersburg</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33701</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Healthcare of Atlanta</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60614</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Riley Hospital for Children</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>LSUHSC</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Orleans</city>
        <state>Louisiana</state>
        <zip>70112</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>John's Hopkins</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21287</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Michigan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>DeVos Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Grand Rapids</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>49503</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Mercy Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>64108</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Louis University</name>
      <address>
        <city>St. Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hackensack University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hackensack</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07602</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia Presbyterian Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032-3702</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>New York Medical College</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valhalla</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10595</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rainbow Babies and Children's</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbus Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Penn State Milton S. Hershey Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hershey</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>17033</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Hospital of Philadelphia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Victor Aquino, MD</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75390</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cook Children's Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Worth</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>76104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Southwest Texas Methodist Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Utah</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84132</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 31, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 1, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 5, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 2, 2009</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 2, 2009</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 3, 2009</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>David Jacobsohn, MD</name_title>
    <organization>Children's Memorial Hospital</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>chronic graft versus host disease</keyword>
  <keyword>graft</keyword>
  <keyword>host</keyword>
  <keyword>transplant</keyword>
  <keyword>stem cell</keyword>
  <keyword>pediatric</keyword>
  <keyword>GVH0313</keyword>
  <keyword>leukemia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Graft vs Host Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pentostatin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <pending_results>
    <submitted>September 22, 2021</submitted>
    <returned>October 19, 2021</returned>
  </pending_results>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

