<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00148083</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RIS-EMR-4033</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2005-04081 (UIC)</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00148083</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Risperdal Consta on Ability to Benefit From Social Skills Training in Schizophrenia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Risperidone Consta for Improving Ability to Benefit From Skills Training in Schizophrenia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Illinois at Chicago</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Janssen, LP</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Illinois at Chicago</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The specific aim of this study is to determine whether the new, long-acting, form of&#xD;
      risperidone, Risperdal Consta, improves the ability of schizophrenia patients to benefit from&#xD;
      skills training. The hypothesis guiding this study is that Risperdal Consta, by improving&#xD;
      verbal memory, will improve the ability to benefit from skills training interventions among&#xD;
      schizophrenia patients. The primary objective of this study is to compare patients on&#xD;
      Risperdal Consta to patients on other atypical antipsychotic medications in terms of their&#xD;
      ability to benefit from skills training interventions. A secondary objective of this study is&#xD;
      to determine whether patients taking Risperdal Consta improve in other areas of cognitive&#xD;
      functioning and social functioning.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study will be conducted at the University of Illinois at Chicago and New York&#xD;
      Presbyterian Hospital-Westchester Division. Patients with schizophrenia or schizoaffective&#xD;
      disorder who are considered by their clinicians to not be clinically stable, or to be stable&#xD;
      but still symptomatic, will be referred to the study. After obtaining informed consent,&#xD;
      patients will be randomized either to the Risperdal Consta or control conditions. Patients in&#xD;
      the control condition will remain on their oral antipsychotic medication for the duration of&#xD;
      the study (note - patients currently taking oral risperidone will not be eligible for the&#xD;
      study). Patients randomized to the Consta condition will take oral risperidone for 3 days,&#xD;
      and if there are no adverse effects, they will begin receiving injections of Consta every 2&#xD;
      weeks over the next 6 months. During the first month, they will remain on oral risperidone,&#xD;
      which will be tapered by the end of the month along with other antipsychotic medications&#xD;
      other than Consta. At baseline, and every 4 weeks for 6 months, all patients will complete a&#xD;
      computerized cognitive testing battery (CogTest), and be interviewed about social functioning&#xD;
      and symptomatology. During months 4-6 of study participation, all patients will participate&#xD;
      in a social skills group, the UCLA Basic Conversation Skills Module. Before and after this&#xD;
      group, patients will be interviewed and participate in role-play based assessments regarding&#xD;
      skills to be taught in the group. Patients will also receive physical exams, including and&#xD;
      ECG, at baseline, and be monitored for side effects and adverse events every 2 weeks. The&#xD;
      hypothesis driving this study is that patients in the Consta group will demonstrate greater&#xD;
      improvement in verbal learning, skill acquisition in the training group, and improved social&#xD;
      functioning, over the course of the 6 months. This hypothesis is based on prior data&#xD;
      demonstrating that oral risperidone improves verbal memory, which is a mediator of skill&#xD;
      acquisition in structured skills training groups. If this hypothesis is supported, it would&#xD;
      be an important demonstration that a novel medication preparation (injectable Risperdal&#xD;
      Consta) can, when combined with psychiatric rehabilitation, improve functional outcomes for&#xD;
      patients participating in rehabilitation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Efficacy Measures:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The primary efficacy measure for this study will be the Micro-Module Learning Tests&#xD;
           (MMLT) (Silverstein et al., in press). This is a set of 7 psychometrically equivalent&#xD;
           tests that assess responsiveness to the key components of skills training. Each test has&#xD;
           3 parts: 1) a verbal learning component wherein the patient is read material from an&#xD;
           actual skills training group and then asked questions about the material; 2) a modeling&#xD;
           component in which the patient views a model performing a specific behavior on a&#xD;
           videotape, and is then asked questions about what was viewed; and 3) a role-play&#xD;
           component in which the patient is asked to demonstrate, via a role-play, the behavior&#xD;
           that the model demonstrated in the prior section. The MMLT is a dynamic assessment&#xD;
           measure in that, in addition to measuring what people can recall/perform after an&#xD;
           initial presentation of information, it allows for a determination of learning potential&#xD;
           after repeated exposure to the information. With the MMLT, each time a question is&#xD;
           initially answered incorrectly, a briefer version of the material, that highlights the&#xD;
           most relevant information is presented. If an incorrect answer is given at this point,&#xD;
           an even more focused version of the item is presented. With this scoring system,&#xD;
           responsiveness to skills training as it occurs in the real world (where repetition of&#xD;
           material is built into the teaching method) can be assessed more accurately than when&#xD;
           using a static assessment (where information is only presented once).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. A second primary efficacy measure will be the Comprehensive Module Test for the Basic&#xD;
           Conversation Skills Module. This measure is administered before and after the group.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. A secondary efficacy measure is the CogTest computerized cognitive battery. This battery&#xD;
           was developed by Tonmoy Sharma, M.D. and colleagues, and has been used with over 2000&#xD;
           schizophrenia patients in studies of risperidone or Consta to date.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Another secondary efficacy measure is the Social Functioning Scale (SFS) (Birchwood et&#xD;
           al., 1990). This is a 74 item scale that is rated by the patient. The SFS has seven&#xD;
           subscales: 1) social engagement/withdrawal; 2) interpersonal communication; 3)&#xD;
           independence-performance of activities of daily living; 4) independence-competence to&#xD;
           perform activities of daily living; 5) frequency of engagement in recreational&#xD;
           activities; 6) frequency of participation in social activities; and 7) employment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. A third secondary efficacy measure will be the observational measure of attentiveness in&#xD;
           groups that was developed as part of the PI's current NIMH grant on cognitive&#xD;
           rehabilitation in schizophrenia. This measure will allow us to determine: 1) if&#xD;
           Risperdal Consta is improving a real-world measure of attention; and 2) whether there&#xD;
           are any relationships between skill acquisition, medication, and attention.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. The final efficacy measure will be the Positive and Negative Syndrome Scale, which will&#xD;
           be used to measure symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adverse Events: Side effects and adverse events will be assessed using a semi-structured&#xD;
      interview given by a research nurse or psychiatrist. There are 40 specific side effects in 6&#xD;
      categories (general, neurological, cardiovascular, autonomic, urologic, muscular skeletal).&#xD;
      Adverse events will be rated on an intensity scale of 0 to 4 and a relationship to medication&#xD;
      of 0 to 5. Side effects will be counted as adverse events for scores of 3 or 4 on intensity&#xD;
      (moderate or severe) and scores of 3-5 for relationship (possible to definite). These adverse&#xD;
      events will then be aggregated into one of the 6 groups for analysis across groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Serious adverse events will include those that require medical intervention such as&#xD;
      additional monitoring by the subject's primary physician or medical hospitalization. All&#xD;
      significant adverse events (such as those listed above or any side effect with an intensity&#xD;
      level of 4) will be reviewed with the treating psychiatrist and the independent medical&#xD;
      reviewers. Each site will have two independent medical reviewers (one internist, one&#xD;
      psychiatrist) to examine any serious or significant adverse events and determine if the&#xD;
      subject should be withdrawn from the study. The two reviewers will not be directly connected&#xD;
      to the research group and will not be investigators in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to the assessment of side effects, other scales will be used to measure side&#xD;
      effects commonly associated with antipsychotic medications. Each month, a blinded research&#xD;
      assistant will perform an Abnormal Involuntary Movement Scale (AIMS, to assess for tardive&#xD;
      dyskinesia), Barnes Akathisia Scale, and Simpson-Angus Scale (to assess for dystonia and&#xD;
      parkinsonian side effects). Movement disorders can affect the ability of patients to perform&#xD;
      on cognitive tests and in skills training groups. Patients with akathisia often have reduced&#xD;
      attention and reduced ability to concentrate in groups. Patients with parkinsonian symptoms&#xD;
      can be slower on manual tasks and may have slower mental abilities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laboratory Assessment (to be done at baseline and last month of participation):&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Complete Blood Count (CBC) to determine major hematological indices as some&#xD;
           antipsychotic medications affect the white count.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Complete Chemistries including electrolytes, BUN, creatinine, liver function tests, and&#xD;
           glucose. Some antipsychotic medications may increase the risk of diabetes and some&#xD;
           medications may cause an increase in liver enzymes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Lipid profile including cholesterol, triglycerides, LDL, and HDL. Some antipsychotic&#xD;
           medications cause an increase in lipids particularly triglycerides&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Prolactin: some antipsychotics may increase prolactin leading to menstrual&#xD;
           irregularities, sexual dysfunction, and possibly osteoporosis. Months 0, 3, 6, only.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Thyroid stimulating hormone (TSH): thyroid functioning can affect cognition. Patients&#xD;
           with a history of hypothyroidism will be allowed in the study if they are on stable dose&#xD;
           of replacement and the TSH is in the normal range. Months 0, 3, 6, only.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Glycohemoglobin (HgA1c): to measure the overall level of glucose over the prior 2-3&#xD;
           months. Months 0, 3, 6, only.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laboratory Assessment (monthly)&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. For women of childbearing potential, urine screen for pregnancy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 2006</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2006</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Scores on an analogue measure of responsiveness to skills training.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Scores on a measure of skills acquisition and performance pre-post a 3-month skills training group.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Interview measures of social functioning.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neurocognitive functioning.</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptomatology.</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">5</enrollment>
  <condition>Schizophrenia</condition>
  <condition>Schizoaffective Disorder</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Risperdal Consta (drug)</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Social Skills Training</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ages 18-55&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Ability to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Good general physical health or stable chronic medical conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Ability to be on a single antipsychotic medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of inattentiveness in psychosocial treatment settings&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Poor social skills&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Must be receiving a single antipsychotic medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Must be clinically stable - defined by the absence of prominent delusions,&#xD;
             hallucinations, disorganized speech, or grossly disorganized or catatonic behavior.&#xD;
             However, there must also be continuing evidence of impairment, as indicated by the&#xD;
             presence of negative symptoms or two or more symptoms of schizophrenia listed in&#xD;
             Criterion A of the DSM-IV, in attenuated form (e.g., odd beliefs, unusual perceptual&#xD;
             experiences).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Inability to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Substance dependency in the past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Diagnosis of dementia&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Significant head injury or other brain injury leading to cognitive impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Mental retardation (premorbid IQ &lt; 65)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnant or nursing&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Allergy or other significant adverse reaction to risperidone&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Contraindication to Risperdal Consta as only antipsychotic&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Currently taking risperidone&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Steven M Silverstein, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Illinois at Chicago</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Illinois at Chicago</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>New York Presbyterian Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>White Plains</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10605</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 2, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 2, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 7, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 14, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 14, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 15, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Schizophrenia</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognition</keyword>
  <keyword>Clinical Trial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Risperidone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

