<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04365374</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GTM-102</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04365374</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Post-Surgical Stereotactic Radiotherapy (SRT) Versus GammaTile</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 3 Randomized Controlled Trial of Post-Surgical Stereotactic Radiotherapy (SRT) Versus Surgically Targeted Radiation Therapy (STaRT) With Gamma Tile for Treatment of Newly Diagnosed Metastatic Brain Tumors.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GT Medical Technologies, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>GT Medical Technologies, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This trial will be a randomized controlled study comparing the efficacy and safety of&#xD;
      intraoperative radiation therapy using GammaTilesTM (GT) versus SRS 3-4 weeks following&#xD;
      metastatic tumor resection which is the current standard of care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      GammaTile therapy results in improved clinical outcomes; however the data is a single site&#xD;
      experience with a limited number of subjects, only 12 of which were patients with metastatic&#xD;
      brain tumors. The primary objective of this randomized, controlled trial is to compare the&#xD;
      efficacy and safety of intraoperative radiation therapy using GammaTilesTM (GT) versus SRS&#xD;
      3-4 weeks following metastatic tumor resection which is the current standard of care. The&#xD;
      data collected in this trial design will allow for a direct comparisons of a variety of&#xD;
      outcomes including local control, overall survival, functional status, quality of life,&#xD;
      neurocognitive status and safety in the target population. In order to support direct&#xD;
      comparisons, subjects will be randomized to the two equally sized arms (1:1) based on the&#xD;
      following stratification factors; age (&lt;60 and ≥60), duration of extracranial disease control&#xD;
      (≤3 months vs &gt;3 months), number of metastases (one or two to four), histology (lung and&#xD;
      radiation resistant), and the maximal diameter of the index lesion (≤3 cm and &gt;3 cm).&#xD;
&#xD;
      An index lesion meeting the criteria of 2.5cm to 5cm in diameter and appropriate for gross&#xD;
      total resection (GTR), will be identified and up to three other non-resectable lesions in a&#xD;
      patient will be allowed. After resection of the index lesion the surgical bed will be treated&#xD;
      with adjunct radiation (either GT or SRS) thereby following the standard of care guideline.&#xD;
      (NCCN Guidelines, 2019). Additional unresected metastatic lesions will be treated with with&#xD;
      stereotactic radiosurgery alone, which also adhears to standard of care guidelines.(NCCN&#xD;
      Guidelines, 2019).&#xD;
&#xD;
      GammaTile is an FDA-cleared means of rapid dose delivery of radiation therapy directly to the&#xD;
      tumor bed with predictable dosimetry at the immediate time of re-resection, and a intense but&#xD;
      localized radiation treatment may confer a reduced risk for radiation necrosis compared to&#xD;
      other therapies. It is typically easly placed with minimal additional operative time and&#xD;
      limited staff radiation exposure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given these benefits, the rationale for conducting this randomized control comparison study&#xD;
      is to generate additional data, to further support the use of this new FDA-cleared method of&#xD;
      delivering radiation therapy in the setting of newly diagnosed brain metastases.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 6, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Surgical bed recurrence-free survival (SB-RFS) from the time of randomization up to 2 years post radiation.</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 years post-radiation</time_frame>
    <description>Surgical bed control is defined as the absence of new nodular contrast enhancement in the index lesion surgical bed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Survival of subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-Brain (FACT-Br)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 9 months</time_frame>
    <description>An assessment of quality of life (QOL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Linear Analog Scale Assessments (LASA)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 9 months</time_frame>
    <description>An assessment of quality of life (QOL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hopkins Verbal Learning Test (HVLT-R)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>An assessment of neurocognitive status</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Controlled Oral Word Association Test (COWAT)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>An assessment of neurocognitive status</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Trail Making Tests (TMT) Parts A and B</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>An assessment of neurocognitive status</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Barthel ADL</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>An assessment of physical functioning status</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">180</enrollment>
  <condition>Brain Metastases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Surgical Resection and GammaTile Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Surgical Resection and GammaTile Therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Surgical Resection and Stereotactic Radiation Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Surgical Resection and Stereotactic Radiation Therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Gamma Tile-Surgically Targeted Radiation Therapy (STaRT)</intervention_name>
    <description>GammaTiles are a permanently implanted radiation device consisting of Cs-131 seeds positioned within a collagen tile</description>
    <arm_group_label>Surgical Resection and GammaTile Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Carrier Tile Brachytherapy Therapy (CTBT)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Stereotactic Radiation Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>External Beam Radiation Therapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Surgical Resection and Stereotactic Radiation Therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients aged 18 years old and above. Eligibility is restricted to this age group&#xD;
             given that the battery of neurocognitive tests utilized in this protocol are not&#xD;
             developed or validated for use in a younger population.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. One to four newly diagnosed brain metastases, identified on the screening MRI, from an&#xD;
             extracranial primary tumor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. One lesion, designated the index lesion, is planned for surgical resection and is to&#xD;
             be between 2.5 cm and 5.0 cm on the screening MRI. Index lesions &gt; 2.0 cm but &lt;2.5 cm&#xD;
             are also eligible if surgery is deemed clinically necessary and appropriate for an&#xD;
             attempted gross total resection by the neurosurgeon.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Non-index lesions must measure &lt; 4.0 cm in maximal extent on the screening MRI brain&#xD;
             scan. The unresected lesions will be treated with SRT as outlined in the treatment&#xD;
             section of the concept.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. All metastases must be located &gt; 5 mm from the optic chiasm and outside the brainstem.&#xD;
             Dural based metastasis are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Previous and/or concurrent treatment with systemic therapies (e.g., chemotherapy,&#xD;
             targeted therapeutics, immunotherapy) is permitted and must follow protocol guidelines&#xD;
             as follows: Systemic therapy is allowed a minimum of one week from last systemic&#xD;
             therapy cycle to surgical resection, and one week after surgical resection to allow a&#xD;
             minimum of one week before starting/resuming systemic therapy, depending on the&#xD;
             specific systemic agent(s), as recommended by medical/neuro-oncology. Systemic therapy&#xD;
             is not allowed 1 day before SRT, the same day as the SRT, or 1 day after the&#xD;
             completion of the SRT or longer, depending on the specific systemic agent(s), as&#xD;
             recommended by medical/neuro-oncology. Agents that are delivered by implant or depot&#xD;
             injections (such as hormonal therapies) are excluded from these restrictions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. KPS score of ≥70.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Stable systemic disease or reasonable systemic treatment options predicting a life&#xD;
             expectancy of ≥6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Ability to complete an MRI of the head with contrast&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Adequate renal and hepatic function to undergo surgery, in investigators opinion.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. For women of childbearing potential only, a negative urine or serum pregnancy test&#xD;
             done &lt; 7 days prior to randomization is required. Women must be willing to notify&#xD;
             investigator immediately if they become pregnant at any time during the trial period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Men and women of childbearing potential must be willing to employ adequate&#xD;
             contraception throughout the study and for men for up to 3 months after completing&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subjects must be fluent in English language to allow for completion of neurocognitive&#xD;
             tests and completion of QOL questionnaires. Non-English speaking subjects are not&#xD;
             permitted to participate given that participation in the real time integrated&#xD;
             neurocognitive function tests is mandatory for all patients. The psychometric&#xD;
             properties for translated tests are either not known or not as robust.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Willingness and ability to provide written informed consent and HIPAA authorization&#xD;
             prior to performance of any study-related procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age &lt;18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. KPS&lt;70&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Past radiation or surgical therapy to the index lesion or the newly diagnosed&#xD;
             non-index lesion(s) is exclusionary. However, up to a total of 2 prior courses of SRT&#xD;
             treatment to previously diagnosed lesions are allowed as long as any treated lesions&#xD;
             are were &gt;15mm from the index lesion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with &gt;4 newly diagnosed metastases on screening MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Pregnant patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Primary germ cell tumor, small cell carcinoma, or lymphoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Leptomeningeal metastasis (LMD). Note: For the purposes of exclusion, LMD is a&#xD;
             clinical diagnosis, defined as radiologic or clinical evidence of leptomeningeal&#xD;
             involvement with or without positive cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) cytology.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Prior WBRT for brain metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Concomitant therapy that, in the investigator's opinion, would interfere with the&#xD;
             evaluation of the safety or efficacy of the study device.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Comorbid psychiatric or neurologic disease or injury impacting cognition, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the treating physician, that might impair patient's ability to understand&#xD;
             or comply with the requirements of the study or to provide consent&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects who, in the investigator's opinion, are unable to understand the protocol or&#xD;
             to give informed consent, have a history of poor cooperation, noncompliance with&#xD;
             medical treatment, or difficulty in returning for follow up care.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jeffrey Weinberg, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, TX</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lisa Misell GT Medical Technologies, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>(833) 662-0044</phone>
    <email>lmisell@gtmedtech.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Angela Hall GT Medical Technologies, PT</last_name>
    <email>ahall@gtmedtech.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Piedmont Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30309</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Adam Nowlan, MD,MPH</last_name>
      <phone>404-425-7900</phone>
      <email>adam.nowlan@piedmont.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The University of Texas M. D. Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jeffrey Weinberg, MD</last_name>
      <phone>713-792-2400</phone>
      <email>jweinberg@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 28, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Brain</keyword>
  <keyword>Tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>New Diagnosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Metastases</keyword>
  <keyword>GammaTile</keyword>
  <keyword>Radiation</keyword>
  <keyword>Cs-131</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

