<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04612959</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AkdenizUniv</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04612959</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Psychosexual Caring Program on Sexual Well-being of Infertile Women</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Psychosexual Caring Program on Sexual Well-being of Infertile Women: A Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Akdeniz University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Akdeniz University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The present study aims to examine the effect of the psychosexual caring program on the sexual&#xD;
      well-being of infertile women.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study will be conducted with 70 infertile women. The intervention group (n = 35) will&#xD;
      consist of infertile women who receive a psychosexual caring program, and the control group&#xD;
      will consist of infertile women who receive standard care. Standard care includes the&#xD;
      information given by the nurse about the treatment methods to be applied once. A total of 4&#xD;
      interviews will be held in the intervention group. In the first interviews, pre-test data&#xD;
      will be taken. The psychosexual caring program will be conducted online as a group&#xD;
      intervention. The psychosexual caring program includes interventions to promote body&#xD;
      awareness, the meaning of sexuality, and marital relationships by gaining communication&#xD;
      skills, sexual communication, body knowledge, information about sexual health, and its&#xD;
      dimensions. After online interviews with groups, data will be collected for primary and&#xD;
      secondary outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 11, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 15, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 15, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized controlled double-blind trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The women which participated in the study will not know which group she was in. The data from the groups will be collected by an online survey and the participants will fill form themselves. And data will retreated from the online database by the person who will nt know groups of participants.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change of sexual function</measure>
    <time_frame>Data will be collected two times as pre-intervention and immediately post-intervention. After that, change from baseline sexual function at 4 weeks will be assessed.</time_frame>
    <description>Sexual function level of infertile women will be measured by The Female Sexual Function Index (FSFI). Outcome will be assessed based on change of sexual function from baseline at 4 weeks.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change of sexual satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>Data will be collected two times as pre-intervention and immediately post-intervention. After that, change from baseline sexual satisfaction at 4 weeks will be assessed. .</time_frame>
    <description>Sexual satisfaction of infertile women will be determined by using The Sexual Satisfaction Scale for Women. Outcome will be assessed based on change of sexual satisfaction from baseline at 4 weeks.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change of sexual esteem</measure>
    <time_frame>Data will be collected two times as pre-intervention and immediately post-intervention. After that, change from baseline sexual satisfaction at 4 weeks will be assessed.</time_frame>
    <description>Sexual esteem of infertile women will be measured by The Multidimensional Sexuality Questionnaire-Sexual esteem subscale. Outcome will be assessed based on change of sexual esteem from baseline at 4 weeks.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change of sexual self-efficacy</measure>
    <time_frame>Data will be collected two times as pre-intervention and immediately post-intervention. After that, change from baseline sexual satisfaction at 4 weeks will be assesed.</time_frame>
    <description>Sexual self-efficacy of infertile women will be measured by Sexual Self-Efficacy Scale.Outcome will be assessed based on change of sexual self-efficacy from baseline at 4 weeks.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>change of sense of coherence</measure>
    <time_frame>Data will be collected two times as pre-intervention and immediately post-intervention. After that, change from baseline sense of coherence at 4 weeks will be assessed.</time_frame>
    <description>Sense of coherence of infertile women will be determined by Sense of Coherence Scale.Outcome will be assessed based on change of sense of coherence from baseline at 4 weeks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>change of depression</measure>
    <time_frame>Data will be collected two times as pre-intervention and immediately post-intervention. After that, change from baseline depression at 4 weeks will be assessed .</time_frame>
    <description>Depression level of infertile women will be measured by Beck Depression scale.Outcome will be assessed based on change of depression from baseline at 4 weeks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Sexuality</condition>
  <condition>Nursing Caries</condition>
  <condition>Infertility, Female</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Psychosexual care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The psychosexual caring program will be conducted online psychoeducation as a group intervention. The program includes four sessions with home assignments and home readings papers.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard care includes the information given by the nurse about the treatment methods to be applied once.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Psychosexual care</intervention_name>
    <description>The psychosexual caring program includes interventions to promote body awareness, the meaning of sexuality, and marital relationships by gaining communication skills, sexual communication, body knowledge, information about sexual health, and its dimensions.The psychosexual caring program includes psycho-education and sexual counseling.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Psychosexual care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having been diagnosed with primary infertility as a result of gynecological evaluation&#xD;
             made by experts,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planning an assisted reproductive treatment method for women,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being active in terms of sexual intercourse,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being able to read and write in Turkish,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Volunteering to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having any known illness related to sexual dysfunction (diabetes, hypertension, heart&#xD;
             disease, kidney failure and autoimmune and rheumatic diseases),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having a psychiatric diagnosis, •Not having computer or mobile phone and internet&#xD;
             access&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kamile Kabukcuoglu</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Akdeniz University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ayse Deliktas Demirci</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Akdeniz University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Akdeniz University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Antalya</city>
        <zip>07058</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Aydin S, Beji NK. Sexual function in infertile couples and the role of infertility counselor. Journal of Education and Research in Nursing. 2013; 10(2): 8-14.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mendonça CR, Arruda JT, Noll M, Campoli PMO, Amaral WND. Sexual dysfunction in infertile women: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2017 Aug;215:153-163. doi: 10.1016/j.ejogrb.2017.06.013. Epub 2017 Jun 7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28628848</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Evans DT. Promoting sexual health and wellbeing: the role of the nurse. Nurs Stand. 2013 Nov 6-12;28(10):53-7; quiz 60. doi: 10.7748/ns2013.11.28.10.53.e7654.</citation>
    <PMID>24191835</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Martin, K. M., Woodgate, R. L. 2017. &quot;Concept analysis: The holistic nature of sexual well-being&quot;, Sexual and Relationship Therapy, 1-15.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Read SC, Carrier ME, Boucher ME, Whitley R, Bond S, Zelkowitz P. Psychosocial services for couples in infertility treatment: what do couples really want? Patient Educ Couns. 2014 Mar;94(3):390-5. doi: 10.1016/j.pec.2013.10.025. Epub 2013 Nov 5.</citation>
    <PMID>24290241</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Akdeniz University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ayse Deliktas Demirci</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Research Assistant</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>psychoeducation program</keyword>
  <keyword>infertile women</keyword>
  <keyword>sexual health</keyword>
  <keyword>sexual well-being</keyword>
  <keyword>nursing care</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infertility, Female</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

