<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04610931</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RBHP 2020 BROUSSE</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04610931</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of the Effectiveness of a Virtual Reality Treatment in the Management of Smoking Cessation</brief_title>
  <acronym>3DSmoke</acronym>
  <official_title>Study of the Effectiveness of a Virtual Reality Treatment in the Management of Smoking Cessation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Clermont-Ferrand</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>French National Cancer Institute (Institut National Du Cancer - France)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Clermont-Ferrand</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Tobacco is an addiction with serious consequences: somatic, psychiatric... The number of&#xD;
      requests for treatment for tobacco addiction is gradually increasing from year to year, but&#xD;
      conventional treatments have limited effectiveness. New tools such as virtual reality could&#xD;
      be used in this treatment. We propose to create a virtual reality program based on the&#xD;
      analysis of high-risk relapse situations. The investigator will then evaluate the effect of&#xD;
      this cybertherapy on patients' relapse time and their desire to smoke.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Smoking is the leading cause of morbidity and mortality, making it one of the most serious&#xD;
      public health problems in the world. The majority of smokers would like to stop smoking and&#xD;
      the number of smokers seeking treatment has increased by 25% between 2017 and 2018 in France.&#xD;
      Indeed, many effective interventions have been developed to stop smoking, but many patients&#xD;
      continue to relapse after a quit attempt. Only 10% to 30% achieve long-term abstinence and&#xD;
      the majority relapse.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The therapeutic approach to addiction is based on a bio-psycho-social model. It aims to limit&#xD;
      the runaway of subcortical processes (the cause of craving) via a medicinal approach and to&#xD;
      strengthen the cortical control mechanisms via a psychotherapeutic approach.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As far as psychotherapeutic approaches are concerned, they seek to obtain a modification of&#xD;
      cognitions and emotions related to tobacco through, for example, a relearning of the&#xD;
      management of the product mediated by evocation or exposure. This may involve, for example,&#xD;
      the repeated presentation (or evocation) of a signal (e.g. a place of consumption...),&#xD;
      previously linked to consumption but in the absence of a reinforcer (product consumption).&#xD;
      Most addiction remediation therapies have been developed and practiced with &quot;imagination&quot;&#xD;
      (the patient is asked to think of stimulating situations) but they are difficult to control&#xD;
      (because the patient's imagination can be more or less large) and are rarely used with&#xD;
      situations that induce consumption. In this context the use of a 3Dimension (3D) tool, which&#xD;
      allows a controlled and progressive exposure without confrontation, seems an interesting&#xD;
      perspective. Virtual reality is recognized as a &quot;tool&quot; in the fields of neuroscience and&#xD;
      psychology. It allows a patient-controlled exposure to complex, dynamic and three-dimensional&#xD;
      stimuli.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus, virtual reality has logically been proposed as a tool in exposure therapies and its&#xD;
      benefit has been measured in substance dependencies (Hone-Blanchet et al 2014). Since 2000,&#xD;
      several researchers have successfully used virtual reality applications in addictions, but&#xD;
      there is little data on objective evaluations of the effectiveness of cybertherapy in the&#xD;
      treatment of tobacco addiction, particularly in association with the two reference treatments&#xD;
      for smoking cessation that are nicotine substitution associated with cognitive behavioural&#xD;
      therapy. For tobacco, the results are heterogeneous and did not take into account the&#xD;
      different factors for maintaining tobacco use (Lee et al 2004, Choi et al 2011, Park et al&#xD;
      2014). Virtual therapy appears to be more effective when combined with other relapse&#xD;
      prevention techniques such as cognitive behavioural therapy (CBT).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 2, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Random-sized block randomization, stratified on the number of previous relapses, will be performed for the inclusions of patients within the &quot;cybertherapy&quot; group or &quot;Treatment as usual&quot; group</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients who quit smoking</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 43</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of proportion of patients who quit smoking after 6 weeks after intervention in the 2 arms (declarative status verified by measurement of carbon monoxide level in the expired air) and until one year.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients who quit smoking</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 136</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of proportion of patients who quit smoking after 6 weeks after intervention in the 2 arms (declarative status verified by measurement of carbon monoxide level in the expired air) and until one year.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients who quit smoking</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 229</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of proportion of patients who quit smoking after 6 weeks after intervention in the 2 arms (declarative status verified by measurement of carbon monoxide level in the expired air) and until one year.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients who quit smoking</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 408</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of proportion of patients who quit smoking after 6 weeks after intervention in the 2 arms (declarative status verified by measurement of carbon monoxide level in the expired air) and until one year.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>smoking decreasing</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 229, Day 408</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison between arms of mean/median number of cigarette smoke per day (declarative status and measurement of carbon monoxide level in the expired air)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Craving score</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 43, Day 74, Day 136, Day 229, Day 408</time_frame>
    <description>evaluation of craving score with Tabacco Craving Questionnary sort Form questionnaire (7 to 84; 7 no craving and 84 highest craving) ; comparison between arms at different endpoints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Needing score</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 43, Day 74, Day 136, Day 229, Day 408</time_frame>
    <description>It is evaluated with an analogical visual scale (1 to 10; 1 the lowest 10 the highest); comparison between arms at different endpoints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>e-health score</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 43</time_frame>
    <description>It is evaluated with disease simulation questionnaire (French Speach Spatial en Quality -SSQ-vf- questionnaire)(/16)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Follow-up of all virtual reality sessions</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 43</time_frame>
    <description>Follow-up of all virtual reality sessions is assessed at 6 weeks post-inclusion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Relapse rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 43, Day 74, Day 136, Day 229, Day 408</time_frame>
    <description>Relapse rate is the percentage of participants who are abstinent at the end of treatment and who relapse during the follow-up period; comparison between arms at different endpoints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of anxiety and depression</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 43, Day 74, Day 136, Day 229, Day 408</time_frame>
    <description>It is evaluated with the Hospital Anxiety and Depression - HAD scale (1 to 21; 1 no anxiety and depression , 21 highest symptoms); comparison between arms at different endpoints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Tobacco Use Cessation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cybertherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>use of cybertherapy (6 sessions) in addition to cognitive behavioral therapy (6 sessions) + pharmacological treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treatment as usual is a cognitive behavioral therapy (6 sessions) + pharmacological treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Virtual Reality-Enhanced Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (VR-CBT)</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants are smokers seeking treatment. Patients will be randomized into one of the 2 intervention groups.&#xD;
In all cases, patients will receive nicotine replacement therapy. The second physician in charge of the usual tobacco monitoring will adjust the dosage.&#xD;
Subjects in the usual treatment group will receive 6 weekly individual cognitive behavior therapy sessions lead by a psychologist. The content of CBT is similar in both groups. Subjects in the Virtual Reality group will receive 6 weekly individual CBT sessions followed by 6 virtual therapy sessions. Virtual therapy consists of exposing the patient to 3D situations considered to cause a high risk of smoking relapse and aiming to reduce signal reactivity by extinction. At each session, a neutral exposure will be given at the beginning to facilitate immersion and emergence of the session with a duration determined according to the sensitivity of each patient. Exposure is stopped when the craving approaches the baseline level.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cybertherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>cognitive behavior therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants are smokers seeking treatment. Patients will be randomized into one of the 2 intervention groups. In all cases, patients will receive nicotine replacement therapy. The second physician in charge of the usual tobacco monitoring will adjust the dosage.&#xD;
Subjects in the usual treatment group will receive 6 weekly individual cognitive behavior therapy sessions lead by a psychologist. The content of CBT is similar in both groups.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female between 18 and 75 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who smokes 10 or more cigarettes per day in the month prior to inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who wants to quit smoking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who has a diagnosis of a smoking disorder with &quot;craving&quot; criteria according to DSM 5&#xD;
             criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who is able to speak and read French&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who is covered by the French national health insurance system&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who has a signed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with decompensated psychiatric co-morbidities (DSM 5) or unstable organic&#xD;
             disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects at serious suicide risk&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with other substance use disorders (DSM 5)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Problems that interact with 3D exposure: tendency to dissociation; interceptive&#xD;
             phobias (panic attacks and hypochondria...); severe dizziness.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive problems that limit or prevent the ability to implement coping strategies or&#xD;
             the management of emotions or stimuli and disabilities to complete the questionnaires&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects belonging to a protected population such as pregnant women, breastfeeding&#xD;
             women, guardians&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects deprived of liberty by judicial or administrative decision, subject to&#xD;
             psychiatric treatment under duress, minor subject, or unable to express their consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who refuses to participate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lise LACLAUTRE</last_name>
    <phone>0473754963</phone>
    <email>promo_interne_drci@chu-clermontferrand.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clermont-Ferrand University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Clermont-Ferrand</city>
        <state>Auvergne</state>
        <zip>63000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lise Laclautre</last_name>
      <phone>0473754963</phone>
      <email>promo_interne_drci@chu-clermontferrand.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Georges Brousse</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Aurore Tremey</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Morgane Rude-Bache</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jean Perriot</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 26, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Addiction</keyword>
  <keyword>Tobacco</keyword>
  <keyword>Virtual Reality Exposure Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognitive Behaviour Therapy</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

