<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04616612</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2001957718</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04616612</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Medication Adherence Given Individual SystemCHANGE(TM) in Advancing Nephropathy (MAGICIAN) Pilot Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>MAGICIAN</acronym>
  <official_title>Medication Adherence Given Individual SystemCHANGE(TM) in Advancing Nephropathy (MAGICIAN) Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Indiana University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Indiana University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this 2-group, randomized, controlled trial is to evaluate the refined&#xD;
      SystemCHANGE™ against attention control patient education in CKD patients taking RAAS&#xD;
      medications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this study, the investigators will test a refined SystemCHANGE™ in patients taking RAAS&#xD;
      inhibiting medications. Participants will be recruited from two sources: 1) the largest and&#xD;
      most comprehensive health care system in the state and 2) one of the largest essential health&#xD;
      care systems in the country. Data are collected at baseline, 8 weeks (immediately&#xD;
      post-intervention), and 12 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Two-group, randomized, controlled trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of daily doses of medication taken as prescribed (Medication Adherence)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 8 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Monitored by electronic MEMS caps (AARDEX Group, Belgium) which record the date and time the cap is removed as a proxy for medication being taken.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of daily doses of medication taken as prescribed (Medication Adherence)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Monitored by electronic MEMS caps (AARDEX Group, Belgium) which record the date and time the cap is removed as a proxy for medication being taken.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Personal Systems Behavior</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline to 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>20-item Systems Thinking Survey (adapted for patients) on a 5-point Likert scale. This survey assesses if the participants view on behavior at a personal (motivation) or system level.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of daily doses of medication taken as prescribed (Medication Adherence)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Monitored by electronic MEMS caps (AARDEX Group, Belgium) which record the date and time the cap is removed as a proxy for medication being taken.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The investigator-designed 10-item Acceptability Questionnaire assesses nurse-intervention interaction and mobility technology acceptability.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Response options ranging from 5 (strongly agree) to 1 (strongly disagree). Because this is an investigator designed assessment, will use individual item scores for analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Outcome Expectancy and Credibility</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline to 8 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Scores indicate greater belief that the program will be beneficial (outcome expectancy) or greater belief the program is credible (credibility). For outcome expectancy, participants will indicate how much they a) think and b) feel the program will help improve medication-taking using a 0% to 100% scale, and how much they c) feel it will reduce missing or taking medications late using response options from 1 (not at all) to 9 (very much). For treatment credibility items, participants indicate how a) logical the program is and b) how successfully they think it will help prevent missing or taking medications late, and c) confidence recommending it to a friend on a 1 to 9 scale and responses are standardized and summed to create a total subscale score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Outcome Expectancy and Credibility</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline to 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Scores indicate greater belief that the program will be beneficial (outcome expectancy) or greater belief the program is credible (credibility). For outcome expectancy, participants will indicate how much they a) think and b) feel the program will help improve medication-taking using a 0% to 100% scale, and how much they c) feel it will reduce missing or taking medications late using response options from 1 (not at all) to 9 (very much). For treatment credibility items, participants indicate how a) logical the program is and b) how successfully they think it will help prevent missing or taking medications late, and c) confidence recommending it to a friend on a 1 to 9 scale and responses are standardized and summed to create a total subscale score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Kidney Disease(CKD)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SystemCHANGE (TM)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>SystemCHANGE™ focuses on using patients' already established and reliable systems to support medication-taking, rather than focusing on personal effort and &quot;remembering.&quot;When applied to medication adherence, the goal is to reduce medication-taking variability and move towards consistently taking medication with a 6-hour window of time (for daily medications like RAAS) and avoid missing medications. SystemCHANGE™ improvement cycles rely on efficient use of performance feedback in order to make decisions about whether system solutions work or if there is a need to select other solutions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Attention Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the attention control will receive educational materials about chronic kidney disease (CKD). The content will be focused on diet, exercise, and living with CKD.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SystemCHANGE (TM)</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants randomized to the refined SystemCHANGE™ intervention will receive 7 personalized sessions with a nurse-interventionist (session 1 virtual face-to-face, sessions 2-7 via phone) and weekly feedback MMS message reports delivered to mobile phones.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SystemCHANGE (TM)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Attention Control</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants randomized to attention control will receive nurse-led kidney disease self-care education based on materials developed by The National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases and The National Kidney Foundation. Similar to the intervention, participants will receive one virtual visit from the nurse-interventionist and 6 phone calls (weeks 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 and 7) and weekly educational MMS messages delivered by mobile phone.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Attention Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age &gt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  prescribed at least 1 daily RAAS inhibiting medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CKD diagnosis eGFR category G1 to G4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RAAS inhibiting medication adherence of &lt;.85 documented during the screening phase&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  proteinuria defined as a urine Protein-to-Creatinine ratio &gt; 150 mg/g or urine&#xD;
             Albumin-to-Creatinine ratio &gt;30mg/g&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  able to speak, hear, and understand English determined by the ability to participate&#xD;
             and comprehend conversation about potential inclusion in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  self-reported ability to open a pill cap&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  able to self-administer RAAS inhibiting medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  willing to use a study phone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  has no cognitive impairment as determined by a score of 4 or greater on the 6-item&#xD;
             Telephone Mental Status Screen Derived from the Mini-Mental Status Exam (cognitive&#xD;
             screener)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  has no other diagnoses that may shorten life span, such as metastatic cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  is not currently hospitalized&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  receives nephrology care through two approved study sites&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with kidney failure defined by GFR &lt;15 mL/min/1.73&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants will be excluded if they are receiving dialysis or have dialysis access&#xD;
             placed (e.g. graft or arteriovenous fistula) in anticipation of starting dialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Kidney and kidney-pancreas transplant recipients will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tangkiatkumjai M, Walker DM, Praditpornsilpa K, Boardman H. Association between medication adherence and clinical outcomes in patients with chronic kidney disease: a prospective cohort study. Clin Exp Nephrol. 2017 Jun;21(3):504-512. doi: 10.1007/s10157-016-1312-6. Epub 2016 Jul 20.</citation>
    <PMID>27438073</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Muntner P, Judd SE, Krousel-Wood M, McClellan WM, Safford MM. Low medication adherence and hypertension control among adults with CKD: data from the REGARDS (Reasons for Geographic and Racial Differences in Stroke) Study. Am J Kidney Dis. 2010 Sep;56(3):447-57. doi: 10.1053/j.ajkd.2010.02.348. Epub 2010 May 14.</citation>
    <PMID>20471734</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cedillo-Couvert EA, Ricardo AC, Chen J, Cohan J, Fischer MJ, Krousel-Wood M, Kusek JW, Lederer S, Lustigova E, Ojo A, Porter AC, Sharp LK, Sondheimer J, Diamantidis C, Wang X, Roy J, Lash JP; CRIC Study Investigators. Self-reported Medication Adherence and CKD Progression. Kidney Int Rep. 2018 Feb 2;3(3):645-651. doi: 10.1016/j.ekir.2018.01.007. eCollection 2018 May.</citation>
    <PMID>29854972</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Williams A, Manias E, Walker R, Gorelik A. A multifactorial intervention to improve blood pressure control in co-existing diabetes and kidney disease: a feasibility randomized controlled trial. J Adv Nurs. 2012 Nov;68(11):2515-25. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2648.2012.05950.x. Epub 2012 Feb 15.</citation>
    <PMID>22335395</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ong SW, Jassal SV, Miller JA, Porter EC, Cafazzo JA, Seto E, Thorpe KE, Logan AG. Integrating a Smartphone-Based Self-Management System into Usual Care of Advanced CKD. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2016 Jun 6;11(6):1054-62. doi: 10.2215/CJN.10681015. Epub 2016 May 12.</citation>
    <PMID>27173169</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Conn VS, Ruppar TM, Enriquez M, Cooper P. Medication adherence interventions that target subjects with adherence problems: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Res Social Adm Pharm. 2016 Mar-Apr;12(2):218-46. doi: 10.1016/j.sapharm.2015.06.001. Epub 2015 Jun 15. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26164400</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Easthall C, Song F, Bhattacharya D. A meta-analysis of cognitive-based behaviour change techniques as interventions to improve medication adherence. BMJ Open. 2013 Aug 9;3(8). pii: e002749. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2013-002749. Erratum in: BMJ Open. 2014;4(7). doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2013-002749corr1.</citation>
    <PMID>23935093</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Haynes RB, Ackloo E, Sahota N, McDonald HP, Yao X. Interventions for enhancing medication adherence. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2008 Apr 16;(2):CD000011. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD000011.pub3. Review. Update in: Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;11:CD000011.</citation>
    <PMID>18425859</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ivers NM, Grimshaw JM, Jamtvedt G, Flottorp S, O'Brien MA, French SD, Young J, Odgaard-Jensen J. Growing literature, stagnant science? Systematic review, meta-regression and cumulative analysis of audit and feedback interventions in health care. J Gen Intern Med. 2014 Nov;29(11):1534-41. doi: 10.1007/s11606-014-2913-y. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24965281</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rambod M, Heine GH, Seiler S, Dominic EA, Rogacev KS, Dwivedi R, Ramezani A, Wing MR, Amdur RL, Fliser D, Raj DS. Association of vascular endothelial factors with cardiovascular outcome and mortality in chronic kidney disease patients: a 4-year cohort study. Atherosclerosis. 2014 Oct;236(2):360-5. doi: 10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2014.07.026. Epub 2014 Aug 12.</citation>
    <PMID>25128974</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Go AS, Chertow GM, Fan D, McCulloch CE, Hsu CY. Chronic kidney disease and the risks of death, cardiovascular events, and hospitalization. N Engl J Med. 2004 Sep 23;351(13):1296-305. Erratum in: N Engl J Med. 2008;18(4):4.</citation>
    <PMID>15385656</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Debella YT, Giduma HD, Light RP, Agarwal R. Chronic kidney disease as a coronary disease equivalent--a comparison with diabetes over a decade. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2011 Jun;6(6):1385-92. doi: 10.2215/CJN.10271110. Epub 2011 Mar 10.</citation>
    <PMID>21393492</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jafar TH, Stark PC, Schmid CH, Landa M, Maschio G, de Jong PE, de Zeeuw D, Shahinfar S, Toto R, Levey AS; AIPRD Study Group. Progression of chronic kidney disease: the role of blood pressure control, proteinuria, and angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibition: a patient-level meta-analysis. Ann Intern Med. 2003 Aug 19;139(4):244-52.</citation>
    <PMID>12965979</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Evans M, Bain SC, Hogan S, Bilous RW; Collaborative Study Group participants. Irbesartan delays progression of nephropathy as measured by estimated glomerular filtration rate: post hoc analysis of the Irbesartan Diabetic Nephropathy Trial. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2012 Jun;27(6):2255-63. doi: 10.1093/ndt/gfr696. Epub 2011 Dec 15.</citation>
    <PMID>22172728</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Xie X, Atkins E, Lv J, Bennett A, Neal B, Ninomiya T, Woodward M, MacMahon S, Turnbull F, Hillis GS, Chalmers J, Mant J, Salam A, Rahimi K, Perkovic V, Rodgers A. Effects of intensive blood pressure lowering on cardiovascular and renal outcomes: updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet. 2016 Jan 30;387(10017):435-43. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(15)00805-3. Epub 2015 Nov 7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26559744</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chowdhury R, Khan H, Heydon E, Shroufi A, Fahimi S, Moore C, Stricker B, Mendis S, Hofman A, Mant J, Franco OH. Adherence to cardiovascular therapy: a meta-analysis of prevalence and clinical consequences. Eur Heart J. 2013 Oct;34(38):2940-8. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/eht295. Epub 2013 Aug 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23907142</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Roy L, White-Guay B, Dorais M, Dragomir A, Lessard M, Perreault S. Adherence to antihypertensive agents improves risk reduction of end-stage renal disease. Kidney Int. 2013 Sep;84(3):570-7. doi: 10.1038/ki.2013.103. Epub 2013 May 22.</citation>
    <PMID>23698228</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Magacho EJ, Ribeiro LC, Chaoubah A, Bastos MG. Adherence to drug therapy in kidney disease. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2011 Mar;44(3):258-62. Epub 2011 Feb 4.</citation>
    <PMID>21344138</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Karamanidou C, Clatworthy J, Weinman J, Horne R. A systematic review of the prevalence and determinants of nonadherence to phosphate binding medication in patients with end-stage renal disease. BMC Nephrol. 2008 Jan 31;9:2. doi: 10.1186/1471-2369-9-2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18237373</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chang TI, Gao L, Brown TM, Safford MM, Judd SE, McClellan WM, Limdi NA, Muntner P, Winkelmayer WC. Use of secondary prevention medications among adults with reduced kidney function. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2012 Apr;7(4):604-11. doi: 10.2215/CJN.11441111. Epub 2012 Feb 16.</citation>
    <PMID>22344513</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schmitt KE, Edie CF, Laflam P, Simbartl LA, Thakar CV. Adherence to antihypertensive agents and blood pressure control in chronic kidney disease. Am J Nephrol. 2010;32(6):541-8. doi: 10.1159/000321688. Epub 2010 Nov 2.</citation>
    <PMID>21042012</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Marcum ZA, Sevick MA, Handler SM. Medication nonadherence: a diagnosable and treatable medical condition. JAMA. 2013 May 22;309(20):2105-6. doi: 10.1001/jama.2013.4638.</citation>
    <PMID>23695479</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Crowley MJ, Bosworth HB, Coffman CJ, Lindquist JH, Neary AM, Harris AC, Datta SK, Granger BB, Pereira K, Dolor RJ, Edelman D. Tailored Case Management for Diabetes and Hypertension (TEACH-DM) in a community population: study design and baseline sample characteristics. Contemp Clin Trials. 2013 Sep;36(1):298-306. doi: 10.1016/j.cct.2013.07.010. Epub 2013 Aug 2.</citation>
    <PMID>23916915</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shrestha SS, Shakya R, Karmacharya BM, Thapa P. Medication adherence to oral hypoglycemic agents among type II diabetic patients and their clinical outcomes with special reference to fasting blood glucose and glycosylated hemoglobin levels. Kathmandu Univ Med J (KUMJ). 2013 Jul-Sep;11(43):226-32.</citation>
    <PMID>24442171</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nieuwlaat R, Wilczynski N, Navarro T, Hobson N, Jeffery R, Keepanasseril A, Agoritsas T, Mistry N, Iorio A, Jack S, Sivaramalingam B, Iserman E, Mustafa RA, Jedraszewski D, Cotoi C, Haynes RB. Interventions for enhancing medication adherence. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014 Nov 20;(11):CD000011. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD000011.pub4. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25412402</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Moore SM, Jones L, Alemi F. Family self-tailoring: Applying a systems approach to improving family healthy living behaviors. Nurs Outlook. 2016 Jul-Aug;64(4):306-311. doi: 10.1016/j.outlook.2016.05.006. Epub 2016 May 18.</citation>
    <PMID>27301950</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Institute of Medicine (US) Committee on Quality of Health Care in America; Kohn LT, Corrigan JM, Donaldson MS, editors. To Err is Human: Building a Safer Health System. Washington (DC): National Academies Press (US); 2000.</citation>
    <PMID>25077248</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Russell CL. A clinical nurse specialist-led intervention to enhance medication adherence using the plan-do-check-act cycle for continuous self-improvement. Clin Nurse Spec. 2010 Mar-Apr;24(2):69-75. doi: 10.1097/NUR.0b013e3181cf554d.</citation>
    <PMID>20168141</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Russell CL, Ruppar TM, Matteson M. Improving medication adherence: moving from intention and motivation to a personal systems approach. Nurs Clin North Am. 2011 Sep;46(3):271-81, v. doi: 10.1016/j.cnur.2011.05.004. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21791262</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alemi F, Neuhauswer D. A thinking person's step by step guide to changing your lifestyle: Weight loss and exercise program. . Victoria, Canada: Trafford Publishing. 2005.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Richard AA, Shea K. Delineation of self-care and associated concepts. J Nurs Scholarsh. 2011 Sep;43(3):255-64. doi: 10.1111/j.1547-5069.2011.01404.x. Epub 2011 Jul 25. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21884371</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bronfenbrenner U. Toward an experimental ecology of human development. American psychologist. 1977;32(7):513.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Williams A, Manias E, Liew D, Gock H, Gorelik A. Working with CALD groups: testing the feasibility of an intervention to improve medication self- management in people with kidney disease, diabetes, and cardiovascular disease. Renal Society of Australasia</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Russell CL, Hathaway D, Remy LM, Aholt D, Clark D, Miller C, Ashbaugh C, Wakefield M, Ye S, Staggs VS, Ellis RJ, Goggin K. Improving medication adherence and outcomes in adult kidney transplant patients using a personal systems approach: SystemCHANGE™ results of the MAGIC randomized clinical trial. Am J Transplant. 2020 Jan;20(1):125-136. doi: 10.1111/ajt.15528. Epub 2019 Aug 20.</citation>
    <PMID>31291507</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Russell C, Conn V, Ashbaugh C, Madsen R, Wakefield M, Webb A, Coffey D, Peace L. Taking immunosuppressive medications effectively (TIMELink): a pilot randomized controlled trial in adult kidney transplant recipients. Clin Transplant. 2011 Nov-Dec;25(6):864-70. doi: 10.1111/j.1399-0012.2010.01358.x. Epub 2010 Nov 16.</citation>
    <PMID>21077956</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Matteson M, Russell C, Winn J. Pilot Intervention to Improve Medication Adherence in Nonadherent Inflammatory Bowel Disease Patients: P-3. Inflammatory Bowel Diseases. 2011;17(Suppl_2):S13-S13.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Welch JL, Bartlett Ellis RJ, Perkins SM, Johnson CS, Zimmerman LM, Russell CL, Richards C, Guise DM, Decker BS. Knowledge and Awareness Among Patients with Chronic Kidney Disease Stage 3. Nephrol Nurs J. 2016 Nov-Dec;43(6):513-519.</citation>
    <PMID>30550080</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hertzog MA. Considerations in determining sample size for pilot studies. Res Nurs Health. 2008 Apr;31(2):180-91. doi: 10.1002/nur.20247. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18183564</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Russell CL, Conn VS, Ashbaugh C, Madsen R, Hayes K, Ross G. Medication adherence patterns in adult renal transplant recipients. Res Nurs Health. 2006 Dec;29(6):521-32.</citation>
    <PMID>17131276</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Radhakrishnan K. The efficacy of tailored interventions for self-management outcomes of type 2 diabetes, hypertension or heart disease: a systematic review. J Adv Nurs. 2012 Mar;68(3):496-510. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2648.2011.05860.x. Epub 2011 Oct 20. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22010971</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Finitsis DJ, Pellowski JA, Johnson BT. Text message intervention designs to promote adherence to antiretroviral therapy (ART): a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. PLoS One. 2014 Feb 5;9(2):e88166. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0088166. eCollection 2014.</citation>
    <PMID>24505411</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Horvath T, Azman H, Kennedy GE, Rutherford GW. Mobile phone text messaging for promoting adherence to antiretroviral therapy in patients with HIV infection. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012 Mar 14;(3):CD009756. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD009756. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22419345</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shimohata H, Maruyama H, Ogawa Y, Kobayashi M. Hyperthyroidism associated with obesity-related glomerulopathy-like pathologic features. Intern Med. 2014;53(9):997-9. Epub 2014 May 1.</citation>
    <PMID>24785892</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Callahan CM, Unverzagt FW, Hui SL, Perkins AJ, Hendrie HC. Six-item screener to identify cognitive impairment among potential subjects for clinical research. Med Care. 2002 Sep;40(9):771-81.</citation>
    <PMID>12218768</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Devilly GJ, Borkovec TD. Psychometric properties of the credibility/expectancy questionnaire. J Behav Ther Exp Psychiatry. 2000 Jun;31(2):73-86.</citation>
    <PMID>11132119</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Denhaerynck K, Schäfer-Keller P, Young J, Steiger J, Bock A, De Geest S. Examining assumptions regarding valid electronic monitoring of medication therapy: development of a validation framework and its application on a European sample of kidney transplant patients. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2008 Feb 19;8:5. doi: 10.1186/1471-2288-8-5.</citation>
    <PMID>18284675</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bowling A. Just one question: If one question works, why ask several? J Epidemiol Community Health. 2005 May;59(5):342-5.</citation>
    <PMID>15831678</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bellg AJ, Borrelli B, Resnick B, Hecht J, Minicucci DS, Ory M, Ogedegbe G, Orwig D, Ernst D, Czajkowski S; Treatment Fidelity Workgroup of the NIH Behavior Change Consortium. Enhancing treatment fidelity in health behavior change studies: best practices and recommendations from the NIH Behavior Change Consortium. Health Psychol. 2004 Sep;23(5):443-51.</citation>
    <PMID>15367063</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bronfenbrenner U. The ecology of human development: Experiments by design and nature. In: Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press; 1979.</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Deming E., Orsini J. The Essential Deming: Leadership Principles from the Father of Quality. New York, NY: McGraw-Hill Education; 2012.</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Indiana University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Rebecca Jane Ellis</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <study_docs>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_type>Clinical Study Report</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.usrds.org/annual-data-report/current-adr/</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>United States Renal Data System. USRDS annual data report: Epidemiology of kidney disease in the United States. National Institutes of Health, National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases, Bethesda, MD. 2017.</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_type>Statistics</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.niddk.nih.gov/health-information/health-statistics/kidney-disease</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>US Department of Health &amp; Human Services. Kidney disease statistics for the United States. Bethesda, MD: National Kidney and Urologic Diseases Information Clearinghouse, National Institutes of Health. 2011.</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_type>Clinical Study Report</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://kdigo.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/KDIGO-2012-Blood-Pressure-Guideline-English.pdf</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>KDIGO. Kidney Disease: Improving global outcomes blood pressure work group, KDIGO clinical practice guideline for the management of blood pressure in chronic kidney disease. Kidney International. 2012;Suppl. 2(5):337-414.</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_type>Clinical Study Report</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.niddk.nih.gov/</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases. High Blood Pressure and Kidney Disease. In. NIH Publication No. 14-4572 ed. Bethesda, MD: National Kidney and Urologic Diseases Information Clearinghouse (NKUDIC); 2014:12.</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_type>Pamphlet</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.nhlbi.nih.gov/files/docs/public/sleep/healthysleepfs.pdf</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. National Institutes of Health. In Brief: Your Guide to Healthy Sleep. In. Vol NIH Publication No. 11-5800. Bethesda, MA: NHLBI Health Information Center; 2011:1-4.</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_type>Education</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.kidney.org/nutrition/Kidney-Disease-Stages-1-4</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>National Kidney Foundation. Nutrition and Chronic Kidney Disease (Stages 1-4). Are You Getting What You Need? In. Vol 11-10-1811_HBE. 11-10-1811_HBE ed. New York, NY: National Kidney Foundation; 2013-2014:1-28.</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_type>Education</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.kidney.org/atoz/content/Diabetes-and-Kidney-Disease-Stages1-4</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>National Kidney Foundation. Hidden health risks: Kidney Disease, Diabetes, and High Blood Pressure. In. Vol 11-10-1811_HBE. New York, NY: National Kidney Foundation 2014:1-20.</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
  </study_docs>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

