<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04611438</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>4-2020-0120</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04611438</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Research on Cognitive Effect of Cannabidiol on Dravet Syndrome and Lennox-Gastaut SyndromeGastaut Syndrome</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective Multi-Center Single-Arm Clinical Trial on Cognitive Effect of Cannabidiol (CBD-OS®) on Dravet Syndrome and Lennox-Gastaut Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yonsei University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yonsei University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The clinical trial &quot;A Prospective Single-Center Single-Arm Clinical Trial on Cognitive Effect&#xD;
      of Cannabidiol (CBD-OS®) on Dravet syndrome and Lennox-Gastaut Syndrome&quot; is a single-group&#xD;
      phase III study done in single tertiary referral center in Seoul, Korea.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chief investigator is Dr. Hoon-Chul Kang of Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of&#xD;
      Medicine. Associate investigators are Dr. Heung Dong Kim, Joon Soo Lee, Se Hee Kim, Han Som&#xD;
      Choi, Ji Hoon Na, Dong Hwa Yang, and Hee Jung Kang, of Severance Hospital, Yonsei University&#xD;
      College of Medicine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the study is to evaluate the effect of cannabidiol (CBD-OS®) on cognitive&#xD;
      functions in patients aged from 2 to 18 years old diagnosed with Dravet syndrome or&#xD;
      Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. The duration of study is planned as one year, after patient&#xD;
      recruitment of 6 months. The intervention period in each patient is 24 weeks, with 2 weeks of&#xD;
      medication titration, stabilization period of 10 weeks, and maintenance period of 12 weeks.&#xD;
      The recruitment goal of patient number is 104, considering the study power of 90 percent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcomes are improvement of cognitive and development and improvement of seizure&#xD;
      outcome. Secondary outcomes are improvement in behavior and quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety monitoring criteria are adverse event profiles and physician's and caregiver's global&#xD;
      assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis of outcomes is subject only to the patients who completed the 24-week&#xD;
      medication and 2 times of tests before and after treatment of cannabidiol. Evaluation of&#xD;
      seizure outcomes would include all patients who completed the 24-week medication and those&#xD;
      who dropped out of the study, either by follow-up loss or discontinuation of medication due&#xD;
      to incomplete seizure control or adverse effect of the medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate safety, the investigators would measure adverse events and dropout rates by&#xD;
      percentage. The investigators would analyze overall evaluation of the caregivers and&#xD;
      investigator. Serious adverse events would be noted after causality evaluation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Selection criteria of the patients are as below:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Age: 2 years old to 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Investigation center: Severance hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul,&#xD;
           Korea&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. A) Diagnosed as Dravet syndrome by clinical manifestations and/or genetic test B)&#xD;
           Diagnosed as Lennox-Gastaut syndrome by clinical manifestations and&#xD;
           electroencephalography&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. The diagnosed patients by criteria 3-(1) or 3-(2) with intractable seizures after using&#xD;
           over two antiepileptic medications&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Patients and caregivers who agreed to participation in this trial&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria of the patients are as below:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patients with possibility of progressive central nervous system disease other systemic&#xD;
           disease&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. The patients who started additional antiepileptic medication during the investigation&#xD;
           period, with exception of short-term acute treatment of seizures (e.g. benzodiazepine&#xD;
           for rescue therapy)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Patients with alanine and aspartate aminotransferase and/or total bilirubin levels over&#xD;
           2 times of the normal range, or blood urea nitrogen and creatinine ratio over 3 times of&#xD;
           the normal range&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Patient with hypersensitivity or allergic reactions to cannabidiol&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. patients who are incapable of executing cognitive tests, or cases whom the investigators&#xD;
           consider inappropriate to be enrolled in the trial Overall trial schedule for each&#xD;
           patient is as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A) Baseline Phase (2 weeks)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Baseline Phase starts from the screening visit, where the patient and caregiver write&#xD;
           permission to the trial and goes through laboratory, electroencephalography, and&#xD;
           neuropsychological tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B) Treatment Period : Titration(2 weeks) + stabilization period (10 weeks) + maintenance&#xD;
      period (12 weeks)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Titration: cannabidiol titration up to 10mg/kg/day with the caregiver monitoring the&#xD;
           patient's tolerability&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Stabilization: caregiver monitoring the patient's tolerability, with no change in&#xD;
           medication dosage&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Maintenance: no change in medication dosage&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Statistical analysis of outcomes would be done as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      T-test would be done to compare each test before and after cannabidiol treatment. For&#xD;
      multiple results along the intervention time period, repeated data analyses would be done.&#xD;
      Continuous variables would be evaluated by repeated measures analysis of variance or&#xD;
      generalized estimating equations. Nominal variables would be evaluation by chi-squared test&#xD;
      or trend test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Evaluation of seizure outcomes would include all patients who completed the 24-week&#xD;
      medication and those who dropped out of the study, either by follow-up loss or&#xD;
      discontinuation of medication due to incomplete seizure control or adverse effect of the&#xD;
      medication.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients would be from 2 to 18 years old diagnosed with Dravet syndrome or Lennox-Gastaut syndrome, who are intractable to more than 2 antiepileptic medications. Caregivers would purchase cannabidiol and give it to the patient according to titration schedule. Patients would go through laboratory, neuropsychologic, and electroencephalographic tests before, during and after the intervention.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>development assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of cognition and development would be done by Bayley Scales of Infant Development, Wechsler Preschool and Primary Scale of Intelligence, Wechsler Intelligence Scale for Children, Developmental Test of Visual-Motor Integration, and CCTT according to the patient's age and capability.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Seizure outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Caregivers would report seizure outcome by Caregiver Global Impression of Change in Seizure Duration or Caregiver/patient Global Impression of Change. (CGIC)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Behavior assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Behavior would be evaluated by Child Behavior Checklist (K-CBCL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Tool for evaluation quality of life is Quality of Life in Childhood Epilepsy questionnaire(K-QOLCE).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">107</enrollment>
  <condition>Dravet Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Lennox Gastaut Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CBD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The patient would be on cannabidiol for 24 weeks and would go through laboratory, electroencephalography, and neuropsychological tests before, during, and after intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cannabidiol</intervention_name>
    <description>Intervention schedule for each patient is as follows:&#xD;
Baseline Phase (2 weeks) Baseline Phase starts from the screening visit, where the patient and caregiver write permission to the trial and goes through laboratory, electroencephalography, and neuropsychological tests.&#xD;
Treatment Period: Titration (2 weeks) + stabilization period (10 weeks) + maintenance period (12 weeks)&#xD;
Titration: The patient would start cannabidiol on 5mg/kg/mg for 1 week and titrate dosage up to 10mg/kg/day for second week with the caregiver monitoring the patient's tolerability&#xD;
Stabilization: caregiver monitoring the patient's tolerability, with no change in medication dosage&#xD;
Maintenance: no change in medication dosage</description>
    <arm_group_label>CBD</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age: 2 years old to 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Investigation center: Severance hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine,&#xD;
             Seoul, Korea&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. (1) Diagnosed as Dravet syndrome by clinical manifestations and/or genetic test (2)&#xD;
             Diagnosed as Lennox-Gastaut syndrome by clinical manifestations and&#xD;
             electroencephalography&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The diagnosed patients by criteria 3-(1) or 3-(2) with intractable seizures after&#xD;
             using over two antiepileptic medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients and caregivers who agreed to participation in this trial&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with possibility of progressive central nervous system disease other systemic&#xD;
             disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The patients who started additional antiepileptic medication during the investigation&#xD;
             period, with exception of short-term acute treatment of seizures (e.g. benzodiazepine&#xD;
             for rescue therapy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with alanine and aspartate aminotransferase and/or total bilirubin levels&#xD;
             over 2 times of the normal range, or blood urea nitrogen and creatinine ratio over 3&#xD;
             times of the normal range&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient with hypersensitivity or allergic reactions to cannabidiol&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. patients who are incapable of executing cognitive tests, or cases whom the&#xD;
             investigators consider inappropriate to be enrolled in the trial&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hoon-Chul Kang, MD, Ph.D</last_name>
    <phone>+82-2-2228-2050</phone>
    <email>hipo0207@yuhs.ac</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hoon-Chul Kang, MD</last_name>
      <phone>82-2-2228-2050</phone>
      <email>hipo0207@yuhs.ac</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Devinsky O, Cross JH, Laux L, Marsh E, Miller I, Nabbout R, Scheffer IE, Thiele EA, Wright S; Cannabidiol in Dravet Syndrome Study Group. Trial of Cannabidiol for Drug-Resistant Seizures in the Dravet Syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2017 May 25;376(21):2011-2020. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1611618.</citation>
    <PMID>28538134</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Devinsky O, Patel AD, Cross JH, Villanueva V, Wirrell EC, Privitera M, Greenwood SM, Roberts C, Checketts D, VanLandingham KE, Zuberi SM; GWPCARE3 Study Group. Effect of Cannabidiol on Drop Seizures in the Lennox-Gastaut Syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2018 May 17;378(20):1888-1897. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1714631.</citation>
    <PMID>29768152</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 16, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 26, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 2, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>cannabidiol</keyword>
  <keyword>pediatric</keyword>
  <keyword>Dravet syndrome</keyword>
  <keyword>Lennox-Gastaut syndrome</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epilepsies, Myoclonic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lennox Gastaut Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cannabidiol</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

