<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04617691</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CR108895</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>CNTO1959EDI1001</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04617691</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Intravenous Formulation of Guselkumab Using Prefilled Syringes and Final Vialed Product in Healthy Participants</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-label, Randomized, Parallel-group Study to Assess the Bioequivalence of the Intravenous Formulation of Guselkumab Using Prefilled Syringes Assembled in an UltraSafe Plus Passive Needle Guard and Intravenous Formulation of Guselkumab Using Final Vialed Product in Healthy Participants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the bioequivalence of an intravenous (IV)&#xD;
      administration of the guselkumab formulation using UltraSafe Plus Passive Needle Guard&#xD;
      (PFS-U) to create the IV solution versus the guselkumab formulation using Final Vialed&#xD;
      Product (FVP) (IV) to create the IV solution.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 20, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 20, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Observed Serum Concentration (Cmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>Cmax is defined as maximum observed serum concentration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under The Serum Concentration Versus Time Curve From Time 0 to Infinity Based on Extrapolation of The Terminal Phase (AUC[0-infinity])</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>AUC(0-infinity) is defined as area under the serum concentration vs time curve from time 0 to infinity based on extrapolation of the terminal phase.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Treatment-emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>An adverse event (AE) is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant participating in a clinical study that does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the pharmaceutical/biological agent under study. TEAEs are defined as AEs with onset or worsening on or after date of first dose of study treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>A SAE is an AE resulting in any of the following outcomes or deemed significant for any other reason: death; initial or prolonged inpatient hospitalization; life-threatening experience (immediate risk of dying); persistent or significant disability/incapacity; congenital anomaly.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Clinically Significant Changes in Vital Signs</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with clinically significant changes in vital signs (including temperature (oral), pulse/heart rate, respiratory rate, and blood pressure) will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Clinically Significant Changes in Physical Examinations</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with clinically significant changes in physical examinations (including general appearance, respiratory, cardiovascular, assessment of the skin at or around the intravenous [IV] administration area) will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Clinically Significant Changes in Laboratory Safety Tests</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with clinically significant changes in laboratory safety tests (such as serum chemistry, hematology and urinalysis) will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Antibodies to Guselkumab</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with antibodies to guselkumab will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">140</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Guselkumab PFS-U</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive single intravenous (IV) guselkumab formulation using UltraSafe Plus Passive Needle Guards (PFS-U) to create the IV solution.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Guselkumab FVP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive single IV guselkumab formulation using Final Vialed Product (FVP) to create the IV solution.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Guselkumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Guselkumab will be administered as IV solution derived from FVP or PFS-U.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Guselkumab PFS-U</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Guselkumab FVP</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be healthy on the basis of physical examination, medical history, vital signs and&#xD;
             electrocardiogram (ECG) performed at screening. Any abnormalities must be considered&#xD;
             not clinically significant and this determination must be recorded in the&#xD;
             participant's source documents and initialed by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be healthy on the basis of clinical laboratory tests performed at screening. If the&#xD;
             results of the serum chemistry panel, hematology, or urinalysis are outside the normal&#xD;
             reference ranges, the participant may be included only if the investigator judges the&#xD;
             abnormalities or deviations from normal to be not clinically significant. This&#xD;
             determination must be recorded in the participant's source documents and initialed by&#xD;
             the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A female participant must have a negative pregnancy test result at screening and&#xD;
             baseline (Day -1) and while enrolled in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be a non-user or light user of tobacco products (not smoke more than 10&#xD;
             cigarettes or equivalent a day for at least 6 months prior to screening), including&#xD;
             all nicotine use, example, cigarettes (including e-cigarettes or the equivalent of&#xD;
             e-cigarettes), cigars, chewing tobacco, patch, gum&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is considered eligible according to the following tuberculosis (TB)&#xD;
             screening criteria: (a) have no history of latent or active TB before screening; (b)&#xD;
             have no signs or symptoms suggestive of active TB upon medical history and/or physical&#xD;
             examination; (c) have had no recent close contact with a person with active TB; (d)&#xD;
             have a negative QuantiFERON-TB test result within 28 days prior to the administration&#xD;
             of study intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of any clinically significant medical illness or medical disorders the&#xD;
             investigator considers should exclude the participant, including (but not limited to),&#xD;
             neuromuscular, hematological disease, immune deficiency state, respiratory disease,&#xD;
             hepatic or gastrointestinal disease, neurological or psychiatric disease,&#xD;
             ophthalmological disorders, neoplastic disease, renal or urinary tract diseases, or&#xD;
             dermatological disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of malignancy before screening (exceptions are squamous and basal cell&#xD;
             carcinomas of the skin and carcinoma in situ of the cervix, or malignancy, which is&#xD;
             considered cured with minimal risk of recurrence)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a current chronic infection, prior history of recurrent infection, or an active&#xD;
             infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received any systemic immunosuppressant agent (other than a short course of&#xD;
             corticosteroids for minor inflammatory conditions) within 6 months before and during&#xD;
             screening and administration of study intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a positive urine drug or alcohol screen during screening or at admission (Day -1)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC Clinical Trial</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CRS Clinical Research Services Berlin GmbH</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berlin</city>
        <zip>13353</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Tremfya</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data sharing policy of the Janssen Pharmaceutical Companies of Johnson &amp; Johnson is available at www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency.&#xD;
As noted on this site, requests for access to the study data can be submitted through Yale Open Data Access (YODA) Project site at yoda.yale.edu</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

