<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04616352</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ivucef001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04616352</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cefuroxime Resistance in Pyelonephritis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Inappropriate Therapy With Cefuroxime in Adult Patients Hospitalized With Pyelonephritis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universidad Nacional de Colombia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universidad Nacional de Colombia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Resistance to empirical antibiotic treatment has resulted in increased mortality and&#xD;
      morbidity in serious infections caused by certain common resistant pathogens in the&#xD;
      community. The risk for increased mortality has been also the motivation for recent&#xD;
      guidelines that suggest early empirical antimicrobial treatment with broad spectrum&#xD;
      antibiotics within a few hours of suspecting sepsis, regardless of the potential&#xD;
      microorganism or infection focus. Resistance to second-generation cephalosporins among&#xD;
      patients with community-acquired urinary tract infection by E. coli has exceeded 20% in an&#xD;
      increasing number of institutions and communities, without being clear about the impact of&#xD;
      such resistance on the effectiveness of treatment. This is especially important in urinary&#xD;
      infections, since, in general, mortality is very low. We expect to establish if there is a&#xD;
      relationship between inappropriate empirical therapy and morbidity (in terms of length of&#xD;
      stay or readmission) among hospitalized patients with pyelonephritis treated with empirical&#xD;
      cefuroxime therapy to help to define the need for a change in the current guidelines. These&#xD;
      guidelines will have application not only in Colombia, but also in other countries in Latin&#xD;
      America or other countries that still use this empirical therapy. It will also define the&#xD;
      need for use of broader spectrum antibiotics in this clinical scenario.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Establish the relationship between inappropriate empirical cefuroxime therapy in adult&#xD;
           patients hospitalized with pyelonephritis and hospital stay.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Establish the relationship between inappropriate empirical cefuroxime therapy in adult&#xD;
           patients hospitalized with pyelonephritis and readmission due to pyelonephritis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Establish the relationship between inappropriate empirical therapy with cefuroxime in&#xD;
           adult patients hospitalized with pyelonephritis and the time to readmission caused&#xD;
           pyelonephritis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators proposed a retrospective cohort of hospitalized pyelonephritis patients&#xD;
      with empirical antimicrobial management with cefuroxime in one institution of third&#xD;
      complexity level. Exposure is understood as resistance to cefuroxime, that is, the impact of&#xD;
      inappropriate empirical cefuroxime therapy on patients receiving this antibiotic. Patients&#xD;
      who are admitted to the cohort had the diagnosis of pyelonephritis and were hospitalized for&#xD;
      intravenous antimicrobial treatment and are followed up to the following outcomes: hospital&#xD;
      discharge, or readmission due to pyelonephritis to the same or another institution of the&#xD;
      insurance network.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be conducted following the Good Clinical Practices for Research and approval&#xD;
      by the Research Ethics Committee (REC) or Investigation Research Boards (IRB) of the&#xD;
      participating institutions. The clinical information will be collected through online forms&#xD;
      based on the information in the electronic medical record. Microbiological information will&#xD;
      be taken from clinical laboratory reports (Whonet ver 5.5., WHO). The accuracy of the&#xD;
      information collected will be verified by evaluating 100% of the formats. A pilot test will&#xD;
      be carried out after approval by the IRB (25 february, 2020). The information will be stored&#xD;
      anonymously, discarding from the database personal information of the patient that might&#xD;
      allow the identification. Variables collected from the Electronic Medical Record include&#xD;
      demographic, clinical (comorbidities, clinical status) and microbiological information. Other&#xD;
      variables include time to change antibiotic (if done) and time of use of antibiotic.&#xD;
      Information for the outcomes proposed include length of stay (in days), readmission (new&#xD;
      admission because of pyelonephritis in the following 30 days after the first episode), and&#xD;
      time to readmission (in days).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A propensity score matching will be performed to diminish the risk of selection bias and&#xD;
      unbalanced subjects. Alternatively, and inverse probability treatment weighting can be used&#xD;
      to balance the variables included. Both models will be constructed using a logistic&#xD;
      regression for the probability of cefuroxime resistant. Final comparison between the exposed&#xD;
      population and control population will be done using survival curves for the time to hospital&#xD;
      discharge.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 26, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to hospital discharge</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Time since admission to hospital discharge</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Readmission</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days after discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients admitted to hospital because of new episode of urinary tract infection</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to readmission</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days after discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Time since discharge to readmission</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">973</enrollment>
  <condition>Urinary Tract Infections</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Resistance to cefuroxime</intervention_name>
    <description>Non susceptibility in vitro testing</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patiens with ≥ 18 years with a clinical diagnosis of community acquired pyelonephritis that&#xD;
        require hospitalization and with positive culture for Escherichia coli.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical diagnosis of pyelonephritis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Antibiotic treatment with cefuroxime.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Urine culture positive for Escherichia coli&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of antibiotic for less than 24 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not availability of antimicrobial susceptibility testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of urinary catheter for more than 30 days.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jorge A Cortes, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Univesidad Nacional de Colombia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clínica Reina Sofía</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bogota</city>
        <state>DC</state>
        <zip>111134</zip>
        <country>Colombia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Colombia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nocua-Báez LC, Cortés JA, Leal AL, Arias GF, Ovalle-Guerro MV, Saavedra-Rojas SY, Buitrago G, Escobar-Pérez JA, Castro-Cardozo B. [Antimicrobial susceptibility profile in urinary pathogens causing community-acquired infections in diabetic patients in Colombia]. Biomedica. 2017 Sep 1;37(3):353-360. doi: 10.7705/biomedica.v37i3.3348. Spanish.</citation>
    <PMID>28968012</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Leal AL, Cortés JA, Arias G, Ovalle MV, Saavedra SY, Buitrago G, Escobar JA, Castro BE; GREBO. [Emergence of resistance to third generation cephalosporins by Enterobacteriaceae causing community-onset urinary tract infections in hospitals in Colombia]. Enferm Infecc Microbiol Clin. 2013 May;31(5):298-303. doi: 10.1016/j.eimc.2012.04.007. Epub 2012 Jun 15. Spanish.</citation>
    <PMID>22703702</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universidad Nacional de Colombia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jorge Alberto Cortes Luna</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Primary investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>pyelonephritis</keyword>
  <keyword>urinary tract infections, complicated</keyword>
  <keyword>cefuroxime</keyword>
  <keyword>cephalosporins</keyword>
  <keyword>Escherichia coli</keyword>
  <keyword>Drug Resistance, Microbial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Urinary Tract Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pyelonephritis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cefuroxime</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cefuroxime axetil</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

