<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04619043</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>395018-16</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04619043</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Understanding the Effects of Quantitatively-Prescribing Passive-Dynamic Ankle-Foot Orthosis Bending Stiffness for Individuals Post-Stroke</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of a Prescription Model to Customize Passive-Dynamic Ankle-Foot Orthoses for Persons Post-Stroke</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Delaware</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Delaware</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      When people walk, their ankle joints help to hold them upright and move them forward. Ankle&#xD;
      braces are often given to people who have had a stroke to help their ankle joints work&#xD;
      properly. The investigators have developed a method to design and make a special type of&#xD;
      ankle brace that allows the investigators to control every characteristic of the ankle brace,&#xD;
      allowing the investigators to customize the ankle brace to fit and function just the way the&#xD;
      investigators want it to. The investigators think that ankle braces customized to meet the&#xD;
      needs of each individual person will help the participants walk better. The investigators&#xD;
      have also developed a prescription model that tells the investigators how to customize these&#xD;
      ankle braces to address different levels of two common impairments experienced by people post&#xD;
      stroke -decreased ability to move the ankle joint and weakened calf muscles. The purpose of&#xD;
      this study is to test the prescription model to see if wearing the ankle brace customized&#xD;
      based on the prescription model improves people's ability to walk. To accomplish this goal,&#xD;
      the investigators will first measure each person's ability to move his/her ankle joint and&#xD;
      the strength of his/her calf muscles. The investigators will put this information in to the&#xD;
      prescription model to determine how to customize the ankle brace for each person. The&#xD;
      investigators will then use the method developed to make the customized ankle brace. Finally,&#xD;
      the investigators will measure how each person walks in the ankle brace customized just for&#xD;
      the participants. This study will allow the investigators to validate and/or refine the&#xD;
      prescription model and teach the investigators how persons post-stroke adapt to walking in&#xD;
      ankle braces with different characteristics.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak Plantar Flexion Moment</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The peak plantar flexion moment (Newton - meters per degree) will be measured at 0, 2, and 4 weeks via an instrumented gait analysis while the participant walks at their self-selected walking speed wearing their ankle brace.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Step Length</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Step Length (meters) will be measured via an instrumented gait analysis 0, 2, and 4 weeks while the participant walks at their self-selected walking speed wearing their ankle brace.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Step Ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Step ratio (unitless) will be measured via an instrumented gait analysis 0, 2, and 4 weeks while the participant walks at their self-selected walking speed wearing their ankle brace.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Propulsion Impulse Ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Propulsion Impulse Ratio (unitless) will be measured via an instrumented gait analysis 0, 2, and 4 weeks while the participant walks at their self-selected walking speed wearing their ankle brace.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ankle Power</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Ankle Power (Work) will be measured via an instrumented gait analysis 0, 2, and 4 weeks while the participant walks at their self-selected walking speed wearing their ankle brace.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Propulsion Force</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Propulsion Force (Newtons) will be measured via an instrumented gait analysis 0, 2, and 4 weeks while the participant walks at their self-selected walking speed wearing their ankle brace.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Gait, Hemiplegic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ankle Orthotic</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The participant will wear two different ankle orthotics, their currently prescribed orthotic and the experimental orthotic.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ankle Orthotic</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Ankle Orthotic</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  21-85 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic hemiparesis stroke (&gt; 6 months post stroke)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  prescribed an AFO by a clinician&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  able to walk for at least two minutes without assistance from another person&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  adequate paretic dorsiflexion range-of-motion (RoM ≥ 12°)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  plantar flexor strength deficits (peak paretic plantar flexion moment in gait at least&#xD;
             0.15 Nm/kg lower than the mean speed-matched, height normalized value from our&#xD;
             normative database)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  cerebellar signs (ataxic (&quot;drunken&quot;) gait or decreased coordination during rapid&#xD;
             alternating hand or foot movements)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  neurologic conditions other than stroke&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  more than one stroke&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  sensorimotor neglect&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  intermittent claudication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inability to walk outside the home prior to the stroke&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  total joint replacement and orthopedic problems in the lower limbs or spine that limit&#xD;
             walking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  coronary artery bypass graft or myocardial infarction within past 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unexplained dizziness in last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  cannot understand spoken instruction, communicate with the investigators&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  walk for 2 minutes at a self-selected speed without assistance from another person&#xD;
             (assistive device allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  must have a resting heart rate between 40-100 beats per minute and a resting blood&#xD;
             pressure between 90/60 to 170/90.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Elisa Arch, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>302-831-7268</phone>
    <email>schranke@udel.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Delaware STAR Campus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newark</city>
        <state>Delaware</state>
        <zip>19713</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Elisa Arch, Ph.D.</last_name>
      <phone>302-831-7268</phone>
      <email>schranke@udel.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Olney SJ, Griffin MP, McBride ID. Temporal, kinematic, and kinetic variables related to gait speed in subjects with hemiplegia: a regression approach. Phys Ther. 1994 Sep;74(9):872-85.</citation>
    <PMID>8066114</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nadeau S, Gravel D, Arsenault AB, Bourbonnais D. Plantarflexor weakness as a limiting factor of gait speed in stroke subjects and the compensating role of hip flexors. Clin Biomech (Bristol, Avon). 1999 Feb;14(2):125-35.</citation>
    <PMID>10619100</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Olney SJ, Richards C. Hemiparetic gait following stroke. Part i: Characteristics. Gait Posture 4:136-148, 1996</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Peterson CL, Kautz SA, Neptune RR. Muscle work is increased in pre-swing during hemiparetic walking. Clin Biomech (Bristol, Avon). 2011 Oct;26(8):859-66. doi: 10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2011.04.010. Epub 2011 May 24.</citation>
    <PMID>21605927</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Peterson CL, Hall AL, Kautz SA, Neptune RR. Pre-swing deficits in forward propulsion, swing initiation and power generation by individual muscles during hemiparetic walking. J Biomech. 2010 Aug 26;43(12):2348-55. doi: 10.1016/j.jbiomech.2010.04.027. Epub 2010 May 13.</citation>
    <PMID>20466377</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mulroy S, Gronley J, Weiss W, Newsam C, Perry J. Use of cluster analysis for gait pattern classification of patients in the early and late recovery phases following stroke. Gait Posture. 2003 Aug;18(1):114-25.</citation>
    <PMID>12855307</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Knarr BA, Higginson JS, Binder-Macleod SA. Validation of an adjustment equation for the burst superimposition technique in subjects post-stroke. Muscle Nerve. 2012 Aug;46(2):267-9. doi: 10.1002/mus.23431.</citation>
    <PMID>22806377</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 6, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 6, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gait Disorders, Neurologic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

