<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04619017</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Placeholder</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04619017</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Airway Immune Response to Allergens (Use Lay Language Here)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Airway Dendritic Cells in the Allergic Asthma Phenotype</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>JOSALYN CHO</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Iowa</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Most asthma is allergic in origin. The purpose of this study is to better understand the&#xD;
      airway immune response to inhaled allergens in order to identify factors that promote asthma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Allergy is the strongest risk factor for asthma, and most cases of asthma are allergic in&#xD;
      origin. However, not all allergic patients have asthma. In this study, we will enroll&#xD;
      allergic adults to undergo bronchoscopic segmental allergen challenge in order to identify&#xD;
      differences in the airway immune response to allergen in those with asthma compared to those&#xD;
      without asthma. After a discussion about the study and potential risks, subjects giving&#xD;
      written informed consent will undergo two bronchoscopies. During the first procedure, samples&#xD;
      will be collected from the left lung and allergen will be administered to a small segment of&#xD;
      the right lung. The second procedure will be performed 24 hours later, with collection of&#xD;
      samples from the allergen-challenged lung segment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a single-center, open-label, single-arm, controlled mechanistic study. All participants will receive an investigational product.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dendritic cell number and phenotype</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number, type and activation state of dendritic cells isolated from lung washes and brushings</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dendritic cell function</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Ability of dendritic cells isolated from lung washes to promote T activation (measured by % proliferated)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Immune composition of the airway</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number and type of cluster of differentiation 45 (CD45)-expressing cells from lung brushings</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mediators of organized airway immune tissue formation</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Mediator levels in lung washes</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Organized airway immune tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Quantity of organized immune tissue in airway biopsies (measured by mm^3)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antibodies in lung washes</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Quantification of immunoglobulin E (IgE) and immunoglobulin G (IgG) in lung washes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antibodies in blood</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Quantification of IgE and IgG in blood</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cytokines</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Quantification of type 2 cytokines in lung washes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Allergic Asthma</condition>
  <condition>Allergy to Cats</condition>
  <condition>Allergy to Dust Mites</condition>
  <condition>Allergic Rhinitis</condition>
  <condition>Allergic Conjunctivitis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Segmental allergen challenge</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Allergic individuals with and without asthma will be enrolled.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Segmental allergen challenge</intervention_name>
    <description>All subjects will undergo bronchoscopy with administration of standardized allergen extract to one segment of the lung.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Segmental allergen challenge</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Individuals who meet all of the following criteria are eligible for enrollment as study&#xD;
        participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participant must be able to understand and provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age between 18 and 50 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Clinical history of at least one of the following reactions to cat dander or dust&#xD;
             mite:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Allergic rhinitis, with one or more of nasal congestion, sneezing, runny nose or&#xD;
                  post- nasal drainage,&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Allergic conjunctivitis, with one or more of ocular itching, tearing or swelling,&#xD;
                  or&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Urticarial reactions to contact with cats.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Positive allergen prick test to the allergen causing clinical symptoms. A positive&#xD;
             skin prick test is defined as a wheal sum 3 mm in diameter greater than diluent&#xD;
             control.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Negative urine pregnancy test at all visits for female participants of reproductive&#xD;
             potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Female participants with reproductive potential must agree to use an FDA approved&#xD;
             method of birth control for the duration of the study. A highly effective method of&#xD;
             contraception is defined as one which results in a low failure rate (i.e. less than 1%&#xD;
             per year) when used consistently and correctly and includes, but is not limited to,&#xD;
             abstinence from intercourse with a male partner, monogamous relationship with a&#xD;
             vasectomized partner, male condoms with the use of applied spermicide, intrauterine&#xD;
             devices, and licensed hormonal methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Life-long absence of cigarette smoking, defined as a lifetime total of less than 10&#xD;
             pack-years and none in the past year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Absence of vaping, inhaling or smoking non-cigarette products in the past year.&#xD;
&#xD;
        In addition to inclusion criteria 1-8 above, allergic asthmatic participants must meet all&#xD;
        of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinical history of asthma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Asthma severity requiring no more than step 2 therapy (NHLBI Guideline, 2007 Expert&#xD;
             Panel Report-3 (EPR-3), http://www.nhlbi.nih.gov/guidelines/asthma/asthgdln.pdf).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Validated asthma control test (ACT) score of &gt; 19 at Screening Visit #1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Able to tolerate a 2-week stoppage of inhaled corticosteroids prior to Screening Visit&#xD;
             #2 and both Study Visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Baseline forced expiratory volume in 1 second (FEV1) no less than 75% of the predicted&#xD;
             value after bronchodilator administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Methacholine provocative concentration 20 (PC20) &lt; 16 mg/ml.&#xD;
&#xD;
        In addition to inclusion criteria 1 - 8 above, allergic non-asthmatic control participants&#xD;
        must meet all of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Baseline FEV1 no less than 90% of the predicted value.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Methacholine PC20 ≥ 16 mg/ml.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Individuals who meet any of these criteria are not eligible for enrollment as study&#xD;
        participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Inability or unwillingness of a participant to give written informed consent or comply&#xD;
             with study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Quantitative skin prick titration with a positive reaction to an allergen&#xD;
             concentration of 0.056 bioequivalent allergy units (BAU) or allergy units (AU) per ml.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Other lung diseases, including but not limited to sarcoidosis, bronchiectasis and&#xD;
             active lung infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of a respiratory tract infection within 6 weeks of Study Visits #1 and #2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participant reported current diagnosis or history of diabetes mellitus, congestive&#xD;
             heart failure, ventricular arrhythmias, history of a cerebrovascular accident, renal&#xD;
             failure, history of anaphylaxis, or liver disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participant reported history of coagulopathy, thrombocytopenia or pulmonary&#xD;
             hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Intolerance to albuterol, atropine, lidocaine, fentanyl, or midazolam.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Laboratory values within 12 weeks prior to Study Visits #1 and #2 that demonstrate:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Platelet count less than 80,000/mm3,&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Prothrombin time (PT) more than 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN), or&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Partial thromboplastin time (PTT) more than 1.5 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Females of reproductive potential who are documented to be pregnant (based on urine&#xD;
             beta-human chorionic gonadotropin (b-HCG) testing), are sexually active and not using&#xD;
             contraception, are seeking to become pregnant, or who are breast feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Current or former use of targeted biological therapy for asthma or allergic disorders&#xD;
             including but not limited to benralizumab, dupilumab, mepolizumab, omalizumab, and&#xD;
             reslizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Current or past immunotherapy with cat or dust mite extract.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Antibiotic use within 6 weeks of Study Visits #1 and #2.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Use of systemic steroids within 4 weeks of any Screening or Study Visit. Participants&#xD;
             may be rescreened after completion of steroid treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Current use of beta blockers and monoamine oxidase (MAO) inhibitors.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Current use of anti-coagulants including but not limited to apixaban, clopidogrel,&#xD;
             dabigatran, dalteparin, danaparoid, enoxaparin, heparin, rivaroxaban, tinzaparin, and&#xD;
             warfarin.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Use of aspirin or NSAIDs and inability to stop these medications for 7 days prior to&#xD;
             Study Visits #1 and #2.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Non-English speakers.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Current, diagnosed mental illness or current, diagnosed or self-reported drug or&#xD;
             alcohol abuse that, in the opinion of the investigator, would interfere with the&#xD;
             participant's ability to comply with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Use of investigational drugs within 30 days of participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Past or current medical problems or findings from physical examination or laboratory&#xD;
             testing that are not listed above, which, in the opinion of the investigator, may pose&#xD;
             additional risks from participation in the study, may interfere with the participant's&#xD;
             ability to comply with study requirements or that may impact the quality or&#xD;
             interpretation of the data obtained from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        In addition to exclusion criteria 1-20 above, allergic asthmatic participants who meet any&#xD;
        of these criteria are not eligible for enrollment as study participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Spontaneous asthmatic episode, defined as a worsening of asthma symptoms requiring an&#xD;
             escalation of short-acting bronchodilators and/or inhaled corticosteroids lasting for&#xD;
             2 days or more, within 6 weeks of Screening Visit #1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Increased use of inhaled corticosteroids within 4 weeks of Screening Visit #1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. A history of respiratory failure requiring intubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        In addition to exclusion criteria 1-20 above, allergic non-asthmatic control participants&#xD;
        who meet any of these criteria are not eligible for enrollment as study participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. History of asthma.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Josalyn L Cho, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Iowa</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Josalyn L Cho, MD</last_name>
    <phone>319-335-4594</phone>
    <email>josalyn-cho@uiowa.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Benjamin D Medoff, MD</last_name>
    <email>bmedoff@mgh.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Iowa</name>
      <address>
        <city>Iowa City</city>
        <state>Iowa</state>
        <zip>52242</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Josalyn L Cho, MD</last_name>
      <phone>319-335-4594</phone>
      <email>josalyn-cho@uiowa.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Josalyn L Cho, MD</last_name>
      <phone>3193354594</phone>
      <email>josalyn-cho@uiowa.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Josalyn L Cho, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02214</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Benjamin D Medoff, MD</last_name>
      <email>bmedoff@mgh.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Daniel D Hamilos, MD</last_name>
      <email>dhamilos@mgh.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Benjamin D Medoff, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Daniel D Hamilos, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 26, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 6, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 6, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Iowa</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>JOSALYN CHO</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>asthma</keyword>
  <keyword>allergy</keyword>
  <keyword>allergic rhinitis</keyword>
  <keyword>allergic conjunctivitis</keyword>
  <keyword>cat allergy</keyword>
  <keyword>house dust mite allergy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Conjunctivitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Conjunctivitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

