<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04614870</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DETEC 002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04614870</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>DETEC® Esterase for Screening Wound Infection at Point of Care</brief_title>
  <official_title>Non-interventional, Prospective, Single-blinded, Observational, Multicenter, Cohort, Clinical Study to Evaluate DETEC® Esterase for the Detection of Infections in Chronic Wounds</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Progenitec Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Progenitec Inc.</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This non-interventional, single-blinded, prospective, observational study assesses the planar&#xD;
      distribution of leukocyte esterase in wounds by placing wound exudates soaked wound dressings&#xD;
      in the DETEC® Esterase device during routine wound care. The output of the device is&#xD;
      correlated with clinical determination of infection to assess the device efficacy in&#xD;
      identifying presumptive infections.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      There is no commercial available device to diagnosze infection in chronic wounds. Since&#xD;
      qualitative measures of leukocyte esterase (LE) have been used clinically as a biomarker to&#xD;
      screen for various infectious diseases including urinary tract infections, peritonitis and&#xD;
      joint infections, it is likely that LE can also be used a a biomarker to screen infection in&#xD;
      chronic wounds. To test this hypothesis, an investigational device - DETEC® Esterase - has&#xD;
      been developed to detect elevated LE in wound exudates absorbed wound dressings. With&#xD;
      increasing LE levels, this coloration becomes more intense (from colorless/pink to dark&#xD;
      purple) indicating infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall goals of the study are as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To assess the efficacy of DETEC® Esterase in detecting ulcer wound infection by&#xD;
           comparing device output with the wound care specialist's final determination of&#xD;
           infection&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To evaluate the effect of the subject's age, race, wound size, location, type, and&#xD;
           clinical site on the device's ability to identify non-healing wounds.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To study the sensitivity, specificity, and accuracy of DETEC® Esterase in assessing&#xD;
           infection by testing discarded wound dressings with varying levels of esterase&#xD;
           activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients presenting themselves to the clinic with ulcer wounds will be assessed by the&#xD;
      clinicians. Those with at least one clinical sign and symptom of a wound infection will be&#xD;
      enrolled and recorded in the study. The participant's first visit can be concurrent with&#xD;
      enrollment. During this visit, the participants' wound dressings will be tested using DETEC®&#xD;
      Esterase device by a project nurse/tester not involved with subjects' wound management and&#xD;
      the output recorded. Wounds will be managed by the clinicians who are blinded from the device&#xD;
      output. Consequently, the clinician may adjudicate the presence or absence of infection based&#xD;
      on all available information to make a clinical diagnosis of infection. The device&#xD;
      determination of presumptive infection will then be compared with the results of the doctor's&#xD;
      adjudication.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Positive predictive value of the device in the determination of infection in wounds with clinical signs of infection</measure>
    <time_frame>15 days from enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>The primary endpoint is agreement in infected wound determination between device output and providers' adjudication in wounds with suspected infection.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Positive predictive value of the device in the determination of infection in wounds with various patient and wound conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>15 days from enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>The secondary endpoint is identifying infection in wounds with various biometry and disease conditions (age, gender, race, wound size, wound locations, wound types, infection status, and clinical sites).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Likelihood of infection</measure>
    <time_frame>15 days from enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Another secondary endpoint is the likelihood of infection with positive and negative test results</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetic Foot Ulcer</condition>
  <condition>Venous Leg Ulcer</condition>
  <condition>Pressure Ulcer</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>DETEC® Esterase</intervention_name>
    <description>DETEC® Esterase is a disposable diagnostic device that is used to indicate the presence or absence of infection based on the presence or absence of the evaluated level of leukocyte esterase by testing the freshly recovered wound dressing which are soaked with wound exudate.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants with chronic wounds&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult (21 years), male or female, inpatient/outpatient, presenting with a wound&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic wound open for at least 30 days, including (Diabetic foot ulcers (DFU), Wagner&#xD;
             grade 1 to 3), (Pressure ulcers, stage 2 to 4), (Venous leg ulcers (VLU), confirmed by&#xD;
             venous duplex/Doppler),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For wounds on a lower extremity (i.e. DFU, VLU) an ankle-brachial index (ABI) of&#xD;
             greater than 0.6 for the affected leg to ensure ischemia will not impact healing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For diabetic foot ulcers - confirmed type 1 or type 2 diabetes mellitus with a&#xD;
             hemoglobin A1C less than 10 percentage&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Wound shows clinical signs of infection - pain, erythema, edema, heat, surrounding&#xD;
             erythema, swelling, or purulent exudate&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of autoimmune disease/ acquired immunodeficiency syndrome/Hepatitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Require treatment for primary or metastatic malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any contra-indication to routine wound care and/or monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant, lactating, or of childbearing potential and currently not&#xD;
             taking adequate birth control&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation (less than 30 days prior to baseline) in an interventional trial which&#xD;
             could have a potential effect on the study outcome, as determined by the Investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a dry dressing&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wenjing Hu, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Progenitec Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Wenjing Hu, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>6823658775</phone>
    <email>wenjing.hu@progenitec.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Health Arlington Memorial Wound Care and Limb Preservation Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Arlington</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>76012</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jon Senkowsky, MD</last_name>
      <email>JonSenkowsky@texashealth.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jon Senkowsky, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetic Foot</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Varicose Ulcer</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Foot Ulcer</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leg Ulcer</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pressure Ulcer</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

