<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04618653</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1525759-3</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04618653</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comprehensive Process Model of AA-related Behavior Change</brief_title>
  <official_title>Development of a Comprehensive and Dynamic AA Process Model: One Day at a Time</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of New Mexico</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of New Mexico</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Alcoholics Anonymous (AA) is one of the most popular resources for dealing with&#xD;
      alcohol-related problems, and 12-step therapy (TS), based upon AA doctrine and practice, is&#xD;
      one of the prevailing alcohol treatment approaches in the United States. Two large multisite&#xD;
      trials, one high in internal validity and the second high in external validity came to the&#xD;
      same conclusion, TS was equally effective as more research supported therapies, and may&#xD;
      actually be superior when total abstinence is the treatment goal. A primary objective of TS&#xD;
      is to facilitate AA affiliation and strong evidence suggests that this aim is a major factor&#xD;
      accounting for the effectiveness of TS. High priority has therefore been assigned to the&#xD;
      investigation of what actually occurs in AA, with a special focus on identifying prescribed&#xD;
      AA behaviors and processes that are predictive of drinking reduction. The guiding assumption&#xD;
      of these efforts is that the key to improve TS is to first understand AA better. To this end,&#xD;
      this study will generate, for the first time, a comprehensive and definitive process model of&#xD;
      AA-related behavior change. This objective will be realized through the highly innovative use&#xD;
      of EMA data collection among early AA affiliates. Using real-time daily data, aim 1 will&#xD;
      determine if four MOBC identified by AA researchers (gains in social support, increased&#xD;
      abstinence self-efficacy, spiritual practices, and negative urgency) mediate the linkage&#xD;
      between three types of AA prescribed behaviors and drinking outcome. Noteworthy, these&#xD;
      analyses will include the first rigorous testing of six of seven of criteria to confirm (or&#xD;
      reject) that these four statistical mediators are MOBC. Aim 2 will investigate whether the&#xD;
      actions of the AA active ingredients on mediators (a path) and the actions of the mediators&#xD;
      (b path) are constant over time or, alternatively, if there are critical periods of&#xD;
      influence. Last, aim 3 will determine if the four MOBC operate differently across distinct&#xD;
      subpopulations. To achieve study aims, we propose a two-group randomized longitudinal study&#xD;
      (N = 190). In one group (n = 130) we will collect 6-months of continuous EMA data, allowing&#xD;
      us to examine near real-time associations between AA active ingredients in three domains,&#xD;
      four MOBC, and drinking. In tandem, we will also conduct in-person interviews at baseline, 3,&#xD;
      and 6-months. Assessment reactivity is a concern, especially so because this will be the&#xD;
      first study to use EMA in addition to in-person interviews in AA research. We will therefore&#xD;
      include a traditional fixed assessment group (n = 60) also interviewed at baseline, 3, and&#xD;
      6-months to identify potential measurement biases introduced in our innovative approach.&#xD;
      Achievement of study aims will generate the first empirically validated AA process model that&#xD;
      will inform TS with critical information for improving treatment outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Recruitment. Adults will be recruited at AA clubs and other AA meeting locations in&#xD;
      Albuquerque, NM. We have previously recruited from these AA clubs and have a solid record of&#xD;
      achieving our recruitment goals. We will recruit and consent 4 participants per month.&#xD;
      Recruitment efforts will begin in month 3 (year 01) and will continue until month 49 (year&#xD;
      4). Recruitment will be unrestricted with regard to gender and minorities. We expect that&#xD;
      racial/ethnic diversity will be consistent with our past AA studies with similar&#xD;
      inclusion/exclusion criteria (54-65% male, 41-43% Hispanic. Based on considerable expertise,&#xD;
      research staff will recruit participants from AA club lounge areas (which will result with&#xD;
      the staff member providing a study advertisement flyer to the prospect) or directly through&#xD;
      flyers posted in AA clubs (detailed background information provided). Interested prospects&#xD;
      will first complete a stage 1 eligibility screen via a web-based application (link provided&#xD;
      on flyer) or through a telephone interview with research staff (phone number provided on&#xD;
      flyer). All inclusion/exclusion criteria will be collected in stage 1 screening with the&#xD;
      exceptions of inclusion criterion #1 (ADS) and exclusion criterion #4 (active psychosis/in&#xD;
      ability to provide documented informed consent). Prospects that are deemed eligible and who&#xD;
      remain interested will have an appointment scheduled at CASAA for stage 2 screening. In&#xD;
      addition to verifying stage1 screening information, in stage 2 our research staff will&#xD;
      administrer the ADS and determine if the prospect is actively psychotic and capable (or not)&#xD;
      to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization/Consent. After stage two screening, eligible clients who remain interested will&#xD;
      be told the following by research staff, &quot;It looks like this study is a good fit for you. The&#xD;
      study has two groups, one involves a little time each day for six-months and it requires&#xD;
      three in-person interviews, one today, the second in three-months, and then a six-month&#xD;
      interview. The second group requires less time and effort on your part and, as a result, does&#xD;
      not offer as much compensation. This second group has only three interviews, one today, the&#xD;
      second in three-months, and then a six-month interview. Assignment to one of these groups is&#xD;
      entirely random. To help you decide if you want to participate in this study we can tell you&#xD;
      that you have about a one in three chance of being assigned to the low-effort compensation&#xD;
      group. Do you have any questions? If not, would you like to participate this study?&quot; Eligible&#xD;
      prospects willing to proceed will then be randomized using the urn procedure. Urn variables&#xD;
      are: (1) total ADS score, (2) PDA (past 90 days), and (3) percent days of AA attendance (past&#xD;
      90 days). Using data from two prior AA studies with similar inclusion/exclusion criteria, we&#xD;
      calculated the median for these three variables. Our high-low values for this study are: AA&#xD;
      attendance (8 or fewer days = 1, 9 or more days = 2), ADS (0-47 = 1, 48 and higher = 2), and&#xD;
      PDA (0 to .55 = 1 and .56 to 1.0 = 2). Once group assignment has been determined, the RA will&#xD;
      initiate the consent process with the consent form that corresponds to the assigned group.&#xD;
      Participants electing to provide consent will be administered a breathalyzer test prior to&#xD;
      signing of informed consent (must have a blood alcohol level &lt; .05 to be consented). A&#xD;
      consented person who has not completed the baseline assessment after two weeks of consenting&#xD;
      date will be regarded as inactive and their &quot;slot&quot; in the study will be filled with another&#xD;
      person. We have discussed and developed this consenting procedure in collaboration with the&#xD;
      UNM IRB staff&#xD;
&#xD;
      In-Person Assessments. All study participants will be interviewed and complete self-report&#xD;
      questionnaires at baseline, 3, and 6-months. These battery's (Table 2; Appendix A), have 3&#xD;
      semi-structured interviews and 9 self-report questionnaires. All assessments have strong&#xD;
      psychometric properties and will be administered by trained project research staff in an&#xD;
      office dedicated to research assessment. To reduce the influence of assessment order effects,&#xD;
      self-report questionnaires will be rotated, and the order of self-report and semi-structured&#xD;
      interviews will also be rotated across assessment points.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Table 2. Proposed In-Person Assessment Battery Assessment Type of Assessment Intake 3-mo 6-mo&#xD;
      Screening Form (stage 1 and 2) Structured Interview X Informed Consent Structured Interview X&#xD;
      Locator Form Structured Interview X p.r.n. p.r.n. Demographic Interview Structured Interview&#xD;
      X Alcohol Dependence Severity (ADS) Self-Report X Form 90 - (Healthcare/Substance Use)&#xD;
      Structured Interview X X X Drinker Inventory of Consequences (DrInC) Self-Report X X X&#xD;
      Twelve-Step Participation Questionnaire (TSPQ) Self-Report X X X Important People and&#xD;
      Activities (IPA) Structured Interview X X X Group Environment Scale (GES) Self-Report X X X&#xD;
      What I got From Treatment (WFT) Self-Report X X X General AA Tools of Recover (GAATOR)&#xD;
      Self-Report X X X Religious Practices and Beliefs (RPB) Self-Report X X X Alcohol Abstinence&#xD;
      Self-Efficacy Scale (AASE) Self-Report X X X UPPS Impulsive Behavior Scale Self-Report X X X&#xD;
&#xD;
      D.8.b. Scheduling Follow-up Interviews. At the end of the baseline assessment, research staff&#xD;
      will schedule a date for the 3-month follow-up interview with each participant (N = 190). At&#xD;
      this time, locator and contact information will be reviewed for accuracy. About 2 weeks&#xD;
      before the scheduled 3-month interview, we will initiate a reminder using phone and/or mail,&#xD;
      as necessary. All participants will have access to public transportation fare, if needed. At&#xD;
      the end of the 3-month interview research staff will schedule the 6-month interview, review&#xD;
      contact information with the participant, and repeat the two-week reminder call. Regardless&#xD;
      of whether or not a 3-month interview had been conducted every possible effort will be made&#xD;
      to locate, schedule, and conduct the 6-month interview. All 3 and 6-month interviews will be&#xD;
      conducted at CASAA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      D.8.c. Follow-Up Procedures and Attrition. Our research staff specializes in follow-up&#xD;
      tracking of clinical samples. Specifically, our staff is highly experienced in using&#xD;
      state-of-the-art techniques in locating and scheduling clients for interviews, e.g., multiple&#xD;
      locator information, postal system, MVD checks, reverse phone directories, house calls,&#xD;
      internet credit searches, county, state, and national death registries. All our procedures&#xD;
      are IRB approved, and are explained to prospective study participants before obtaining&#xD;
      informed consent. We are confident that we can achieve an 80-85%% follow-up rate at the three&#xD;
      and six-month follow-up. Explained, when we conducted a 10-year follow-up of the Project&#xD;
      MATCH outpatient sample recruited in Albuquerque, seven years had elapsed without participant&#xD;
      contact of any kind. Of the 181 surviving participants that consented for a long-term&#xD;
      follow-up at the 3-year interview (22 had died) we successfully interviewed 148 (82%).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 28, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Percent abstinent days at baseline, 3 months and six-months</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 3, and 6, months</time_frame>
    <description>calculated as the number of abstinent days in an assessment window divided by the total number of days in an assessment window</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in daily Percent abstinent days baseline to six-months</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline to six-months</time_frame>
    <description>mobile device will provide daily reported drinking</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">190</enrollment>
  <condition>Alcohol Use Disorder (AUD)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Early AA Attenders with Alcohol Use Disorder</arm_group_label>
    <description>observational study that includes three fixed assessments (Baseline, 3, and 6-month). Subset of participants will also provide daily EMA data.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>assessment only</intervention_name>
    <description>Three assessment will include computerized assessments, interviews, and subset will provide daily reports of prescribed AA behaviors and practices</description>
    <arm_group_label>Early AA Attenders with Alcohol Use Disorder</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        community sample&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. ADS score ≥ 8 (past 12 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. alcohol use, past 4 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. attended ≥ 1 AA meeting, past three months&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ≥ 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. speak and read English at the sixth grade level.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. ≥ 4 months of continuous AA attendance (lifetime), with continuous defined as&#xD;
             attending at least 1 AA meeting per week over a 4-month period&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. admitted into inpatient or outpatient substance abuse treatment in the prior 12 months&#xD;
             (currently seeking treatment will not be a basis to exclude)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. unable to provide the names of two locators&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. active psychosis or a condition impairing ability to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. pending legal convictions involving ≥ 90-days incarceration&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. plans to relocate to another state&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. ≥ 3 formal treatment experiences (lifetime) for substance abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. ≥ 12 months of continuous abstinence from alcohol (lifetime) initiated in response to&#xD;
             perceived alcohol-related problems.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>JEFFREY TONIGAN, phd</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UNIVERSITY OF NEW MEXICO (CASAA)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Matthew r Pearson, phd</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>UNIVERSITY OF NEW MEXICO (CASAA)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>JEFFREY TONIGAN, phd</last_name>
    <phone>5056100932</phone>
    <email>jtonigan@unm.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Matthew r Pearson, phd</last_name>
    <phone>7572921799</phone>
    <email>mateo.pearson@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Center on Alcohol, Substance Use, and Addictions (CASAA)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Albuquerque</city>
        <state>New Mexico</state>
        <zip>87106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>JEFFREY TONIGAN, phd</last_name>
      <phone>505-610-0932</phone>
      <email>jtonigan@unm.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Matthew r pearson, phd</last_name>
      <phone>7572921799</phone>
      <email>mateo.pearson@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 5, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 6, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 5, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 5, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 6, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of New Mexico</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Scott Tonigan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>CASAA Director</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

