<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04616235</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>jr. nr. H-20028611</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04616235</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Acute Exercise and NK Cell Regulation in Tissue and Circulation After IL-6R Blockade</brief_title>
  <official_title>Acute Exercise and NK Cell Regulation in Tissue and Circulation After IL-6R Blockade - a Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study is a randomized controlled trial studying the acute effect of intense aerobic&#xD;
      exercise upon NK (Natural Killer) cell activation and appetite-regulation in human&#xD;
      participants with or without concommitant IL-6R receptor blockade (Tocilizumab)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To explore the association between acute exercise, IL-6 blockade and NK regulation in&#xD;
           circulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To explore whether exercise activated NK-cells have a unique phenotype using single cell&#xD;
           RNA sequencing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To explore the effect of acute aerobic exercise on NK cell number and activity in&#xD;
           circulation, muscle and adipose tissue, in healthy young males, in order to indirectly&#xD;
           explore exercise as an anti-cancer remedy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the kinetics of the NK-cell response and, if possible, chronologically&#xD;
           investigate the appearance and whereabouts of the activated NK-cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Explorative Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To establish a reproducible protocol for tracking various immune-cells and their&#xD;
           involvement in the acute exercise response in humans&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To investigate novel signal molecules released from muscle during exercise with&#xD;
           immunological importance.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To investigate the possible role of exercise induced IL-6 on subjective feelings of&#xD;
           hunger and satiety post exercise and food intake. • To explore the effect of IL-6&#xD;
           receptor blockade on the exercise proteome and metabolome, using mass spectrometry&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      30 healthy recreationally active young males will be included in this acute exercise study in&#xD;
      which NK-cell kinetic and regulation will be studied in response to acute aerobic exercise&#xD;
      and IL-6R blockade or placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study consists of 2 visits. At inclusion (visit 1) all subjects will undergo assessment&#xD;
      encompassing: baseline medical screening (auscultation, blood pressure, ECG), determination&#xD;
      of body composition (DXA), cardiovascular fitness (VO2max) and standard fasting&#xD;
      blood-biochemistry which will be analyzed immediately. Visit 2 will consist of a muscle and&#xD;
      fat biopsy from the dominant leg and abdominal subcutaneous-fat depot respectively (both&#xD;
      under resting conditions), which will then act as reference tissue for the further tissue&#xD;
      analysis. Then, a 18G antecubital peripheral venous access will be secured prior to&#xD;
      commencing with IL-6R infusion. 2 hours after the infusion procedure the subjects will&#xD;
      undergo an acute exercise protocol. Subjects will then be challenged by a high intensity&#xD;
      acute aerobic exercise bout, utilizing a bicycle ergometer. Blood samples will be drawn prior&#xD;
      to the infusion and exercise, during exercise, as well as immediately, ½, 1, 1½ and 2h post&#xD;
      exercise and up 4h post exercise in the appetite regulation substudy. Blood samples will&#xD;
      immediately be analyzed for leucocyte count and differentiation as well as plasma&#xD;
      biochemistry. In addition, blood samples will be utilized for NK cell isolation with&#xD;
      subsequent single cell RNA sequencing, immune cell distribution and killing capacity towards&#xD;
      cancer cells. Furthermore, plasma samples will be collected and frozen for later&#xD;
      determination of cortisol, prolactin and circulating cytokines, including but not limited to&#xD;
      IL-6 and G-CSF. Lastly, in the appetite substudy, insulin, GLP-1 and free fatty acids will be&#xD;
      measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tissue samples will be obtained 2h post exercise for optimizing gene-expression analysis.&#xD;
      Both muscle and adipose tissue samples will be analyzed for inflammatory and&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory markers, NK cell content and phenotyping of these NK cells using markers&#xD;
      obtained from single cell sequencing, conducted on the blood-borne NK-cells. Furthermore,&#xD;
      immune cell infiltration will be assessed using histology. All tissue samples will be&#xD;
      obtained using a Bergström needle under sterile conditions during local anesthesia in order&#xD;
      to minimize any sample-related discomfort or infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the tissue sample, an ad libitum meal will be served, the subjects can eat as much can,&#xD;
      but are instructed not to overconsume as any leftover food can be taken home. Paracetamol&#xD;
      (1.5g) will be given to asses gastric emptying.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will undergo the 2 study visits at the same approximate time of the day&#xD;
      (9.00 a.m.) After completion of the study, any left-over material will be transferred to the&#xD;
      CFAS biobank.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects: Included subjects will be 30 recreationally active, moderately trained, healthy&#xD;
      young males aged 18-40 years. Exclusion criteria are: cardiovascular, rheumatologic and&#xD;
      metabolic disease, elite sports or high aerobic training status. Chronic use of nonsteroidal&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory drug (NSAID) or other immunosuppressants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention: Subjects will be randomized to acute exercise, with (n=15) or without (n=15)&#xD;
      prior IL-6R blockade. The exercise intervention will consist of a highly taxing ≈45 minutes&#xD;
      interval based, aerobic exercise bout, conducted on a stationary bicycle ergometer. After an&#xD;
      initial 5-minute warmup at 50-60% of HRmax, subjects will undergo seven, verbally encouraged,&#xD;
      3-minute intervals at above 90% HRmax, interspersed by 3 minutes of low intensity pedaling.&#xD;
      Blood samples will be drawn before, during as well as immediately, ½, 1, 1½ and 2h post&#xD;
      exercise together with tissue sampling at the 2h time-point.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess appetite regulation, further blood samples will be drawn from 2h-4h post exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical considerations: Based on data from our pilot study, we anticipate a ≈ 45 % lower&#xD;
      maximal NK cell mobilization in the IL6R inhibition group compared to CON and a 29 %&#xD;
      difference in NK cell nadir with the lowest values obtained in the IL6R inhibition group.&#xD;
      Assuming a 5%-significance level in two-sided tests, we need to include 9 patients in each&#xD;
      group to achieve 90% power for detecting a relative difference of 45 % in the&#xD;
      intervention-group. To account for potential dropouts/excluded, due to the somewhat invasive&#xD;
      setup, we will include a total of 30 patients (15 per group).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment: Subjects will be recruited through forsøgsperson.dk or similar sites alongside&#xD;
      advertising at relevant sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will contact us at CFAS and will be given the choice whether to receive study&#xD;
      information pr. telephone (thereby denying the option of a bystander) or a face to face&#xD;
      meeting at CFAS. All this information will be given by the primary investigator. If the&#xD;
      subject is interested in hearing more of the study, relevant documents will be emailed. If&#xD;
      the subject is interested in joining the study after having received written or oral&#xD;
      information, he will have 24h to consider study participation. When the subject has been&#xD;
      informed either by telephone or face to face and accepts study participation, he will be&#xD;
      invited to visit 1 where written and informed consent will be obtained (or signed and brought&#xD;
      from home by the participant).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Risks and adverse reactions: Subjects may experience minor discomfort with regard to blood&#xD;
      and tissue samples. The blood volume drawn is negligible and will not be associated with any&#xD;
      health risk. All sampling of tissues will be performed under sterile conditions during local&#xD;
      anesthesia and will thus be associated with little pain or discomfort and very little risk of&#xD;
      infection. During exercise testing, participants may experience shortness of breath.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IL-6R inhibition is generally well tolerated with only few side-effects. The dose of&#xD;
      paracetamol is low and is not associated with any risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Contact information of the involved medical doctor will be given to participants at study&#xD;
      inclusion, so that any adverse event can be reported and solved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dissemination of study results: Both positive, negative and inconclusive results will be&#xD;
      published in relevant international scientific journals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethical consideration: The project is expected to cause limited risks, side effects and&#xD;
      discomfort. All procedures will be performed by experienced physicians and physiologists with&#xD;
      relevant safety. Tocilizumab is generally well tolerated and the dose of paracetamol is low.&#xD;
      Included subjects may at any time, and without justification, retract their consent of study&#xD;
      participation. We believe that the project is important and will contribute with critical new&#xD;
      information on the IL-6 modifiable NK-cell response to acute exercise both in circulation and&#xD;
      in adipose and muscle tissue (as there is currently very limited knowledge on the latter).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is considered a toolbox-study by Lægemiddelstyrelsen, and hence not at&#xD;
      pharmaceutical study&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The IL-6R receptor blockade infusion will have bag concealment so that neither the scientific staff or the subject will know if Tocilizumab or saline (placebo) is given and we do not expect the subjects to &quot;feel&quot; the infusion or the results of the infusion.&#xD;
All scientific staff will be blinded to group allocation using encryption. Only once all data have been obtained (histology, blood analysis, gene-expression, Western Blot, Flow cytometry, single cell RNA sequencing) concealment will be broken so that statistical analysis can be conducted.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Kinetics and regulation of NK (Natural Killer) cells during and following acute exercise</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Change in NK cell and NK cell subset count in circulation before and after acute aerobic exercise with or without IL-6R blockade.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>NK cell phenotype in response to acute exercise with or without IL-6R blockade</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Change in NK-cell phenotype using single cell RNA sequencing. Here, within-group changes of baseline vs. post exercise timepoints as well as between group differences between IL-6 blockade and placebo will be investigated.&#xD;
The focus will be on markers of cytotoxicity, cell adhesion and adrenergic signaling.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in NK cell count in adipose tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Using a combination of histology, western blot and gene-expression analysis for CD56, CD57 and other NK-cell markers, the principal investigator will identify and count the number of NK cells in adipose tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in NK cell phenotype in adipose tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Using a combination of histology, western blot and gene-expression analysis for CD56, CD57 and other NK-cell markers, the principal investigator will identify the phenotype of NK cells in adipose tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in NK cell count in muscle tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Using a combination of histology, western blot and gene-expression analysis for CD56, CD57 and other NK-cell markers, the principal investigator will identify and count the number of NK cells in muscle tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in NK cell phenotype in muscle tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Using a combination of histology, western blot and gene-expression analysis for CD56, CD57 and other NK-cell markers, the principal investigator will identify the phenotype of NK cells in muscle tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in macrophage count in muscle tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Using a combination of histology, western blot and gene-expression analysis for CD68, CD163, CD206, TNF-alpha and other macrophage markers, the principal investigator will identify and count the number of macrophages in muscle tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in macrophage phenotype in muscle tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Using a combination of histology, western blot and gene-expression analysis for CD68, CD163, CD206, TNF-alpha and other macrophage markers, the principal investigator will phenotype (M1/M2) macrophages in muscle tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in macrophage count in adipose tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Using a combination of histology, western blot and gene-expression analysis for CD68, CD163, CD206, TNF-alpha and other macrophage markers, the principal investigator will identify and count the number of macrophages in adipose tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in macrophage phenotype in adipose tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Using a combination of histology, western blot and gene-expression analysis for CD68, CD163, CD206, TNF-alpha and other macrophage markers, the principal investigator will phenotype (M1/M2) macrophages in adipose tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in T-cell count in adipose tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Using a combination of histology, western blot and gene-expression analysis for CD3, CD8, and other T-cell markers, the principal investigator will count the number of T-cells in adipose tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in T-cell phenotype in adipose tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Using a combination of histology, western blot and gene-expression analysis for CD3, CD8, and other T-cell markers, the principal investigator will phenotype the T-cells in adipose (CD3+/CD8+) tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in T-cell count in muscle tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Using a combination of histology, western blot and gene-expression analysis for CD3, CD8, and other T-cell markers, the principal investigator will count the number of T-cells in muscle tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in T-cell phenotype in muscle tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Using a combination of histology, western blot and gene-expression analysis for CD3, CD8, and other T-cell markers, the principal investigator will phenotype (CD3+/CD8+) the T-cells in muscle tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in monocyte count in circulation</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Using flow cytometry we will identify and count monocytes in circulation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in T-cell count in circulation</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Using flow cytometry the investigators will count T-cells in circulation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in B-cell count in circulation</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Using flow cytometry the investigators will count B-cells in circulation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in IL-6 receptor expression on NK-cells in circulation</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>The change in IL-6 receptor surface expression on circulating NK-cells using flow cytometry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating IL-6</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma IL-6 conc. using ELISA assay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating IL-2</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma IL-2 conc. using ELISA assay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating IL-1</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma IL-1 conc. using ELISA assay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating IL-10</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma IL-10 conc. using ELISA assay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating TNF-alpha</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma TNF-alpha conc.using ELISA assay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating G-CSF</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma TNF-alpha conc. using ELISA assay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating epinephrine</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Blood epinephrine conc. using ELISA assay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating norepinephrine</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Blood norepinephrine conc. using ELISA assay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating total leucocytes</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Blood leucocyte count using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating neutrophils</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Blood neutrophil count.using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating reticulocytes</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Blood reticulocytes count.using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating eosinophils</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Blood eosinophil count.using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating basofile leucocytes</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Blood basofile leucocytes count.using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating total lymphocytes</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Blood lymphocyte count.using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating Prolactin</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma Prolactin conc. using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cortisol</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma cortisol conc. using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in metamyelocytes</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Blood metamyelocyte count using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in ACTH</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma ACTH conc. using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circulating lactate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Blood lactate using ABL</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in CRP</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma CRP conc. using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hsCRP</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma CRP conc. using ELISA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Novel myokines during acute exercise</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after acute bout of exercise</time_frame>
    <description>As an explorative outcome the investigators will investigate possible novel signal molecules released during exercise with immunological importance, either in circulation or in tissue (i.e. GDNF [Glial cell Derived Neurotrophic Factor])</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>VO2max</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>VO2max using bicycle ergometer and Oxicon Online system</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lean Body mass</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Lean body mass using dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fat mass</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Fat mass using dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bone Mineral Density</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Bone Mineral Density using dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Appetite assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Hunger, satiety, fullness, and prospective food consumption will be rated using a visual analog scales (VAS). A line of 20 cm is drawn from left to right on A4 paper starting at 0 cm with &quot; not hungry at all&quot; ending at 20 cm with &quot;never been more hungry in my life&quot;. The subject mark somewhere in between according to his subjective feeling, The length is reported and indicates the degree of hunger, eg. the longer the line the more hunger. In general the longer to right the person marks the line, the stronger is the subjective felling within the given question</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ad libitum caloric intake</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Caloric intake will be determined by providing meal consisting of a hot pot of homogeneous pasta Bolognese (1,440 g, 1,912 kcal, 55 E percent carbohydrate, 30 E percent fat, 15 E percent protein; homogeneous composition) served with a glass of water of 150 ml 1 h after exercise. Participants will sit quietly on their own and are asked to eat until comfortably full/satiated and to drink all of the water. The duration of the meal is sat to 30 minutes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gastric emptying</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Gastric emptying will be assessed by the participants drinking 100 ml in which 1,5 g paracetamol is dissolved. The Paracetamol concentration will be determined by Sandwich Electro-Chemiluminescence-Immunoassay (ECLIA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in GLP1</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma GLP1 conc. using ELISA assay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in PYY</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma PYY conc. using ELISA assay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in CCK</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma CCK conc. using ELISA assay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma Glucose conc. using using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Insulin</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma insulin conc. using using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in C-peptide</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma C-peptide conc. using using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in free fatty acids</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma free fatty acids conc. using sysmex XN</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Interleukin-6 Inhibition</condition>
  <condition>Physical Stress</condition>
  <condition>Appetitive Behavior</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CON</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group will do intense aerobic exercise without concomitant IL-6R blockade</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BLOCK</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group will do intense aerobic exercise with concomitant IL-6R blockade</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tocilizumab Injectable Product</intervention_name>
    <description>The intervention group will undergo intense aerobic exercise with prior IL-6R infusion for 1h prior to the exercise bout.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BLOCK</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Saline 0.9% 100 ml NaCl 0.9% will be infused over 1 hour</intervention_name>
    <description>The control group will undergo intense aerobic exercise with saline infusion for 1h prior to the exercise bout</description>
    <arm_group_label>CON</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  recreationally active&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  moderately trained&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  healthy young males aged 18-40 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI from 18-30 kg·m2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiovascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Rheumatologic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metabolic disease,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Elite sports or high aerobically training status (VO2max&gt;60ml O2/min/kg),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Frequent/chronic use of medications affecting physical performance or inflammation&#xD;
             (NSAIDS, DMARDS)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Participants will have to be biological males since hormonal fluctuations in women might have unknown effects on immune cell regulation during acute intense exercise</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andreas K Ziegler, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CFAS (Center For Physical Activity) Rigshospitalet</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jesper F Christensen, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CFAS (Center For Physical Activity) Rigshospitalet</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Claus Brandt, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CFAS (Center For Physical Activity) Rigshospitalet</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andreas K Ziegler, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+4527389539</phone>
    <email>Andreas.kraag.ziegler@regionh.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jesper F Christensen, PhD</last_name>
    <email>Jesper.Frank.Christensen@regionh.dk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Center For Physical Activity (CFAS)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen Ø</city>
        <zip>2100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andreas K Kraag Ziegler, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>27389539</phone>
      <email>andreas.kraag.ziegler@regionh.dk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Jesper F Christensen, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>25136926</phone>
      <email>Jesper.frank.christensen@regionh.dk</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Amar, D., Lindholm, M. E., Norrbom, J., Wheeler, M. T., Rivas, M., &amp; Ashley, E. A. (2020). Differential Response Trajectories to Acute Exercise in Blood and Muscle. SSRN Electronic Journal, 1-43. https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.3508810</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bergstrom J. Percutaneous needle biopsy of skeletal muscle in physiological and clinical research. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 1975 Nov;35(7):609-16. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>1108172</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bigley AB, Rezvani K, Chew C, Sekine T, Pistillo M, Crucian B, Bollard CM, Simpson RJ. Acute exercise preferentially redeploys NK-cells with a highly-differentiated phenotype and augments cytotoxicity against lymphoma and multiple myeloma target cells. Brain Behav Immun. 2014 Jul;39:160-71. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2013.10.030. Epub 2013 Nov 5.</citation>
    <PMID>24200514</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chan CJ, Smyth MJ, Martinet L. Molecular mechanisms of natural killer cell activation in response to cellular stress. Cell Death Differ. 2014 Jan;21(1):5-14. doi: 10.1038/cdd.2013.26. Epub 2013 Apr 12. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23579243</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Christensen JF, Simonsen C, Hojman P. Exercise Training in Cancer Control and Treatment. Compr Physiol. 2018 Dec 13;9(1):165-205. doi: 10.1002/cphy.c180016. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30549018</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dogra P, Rancan C, Ma W, Toth M, Senda T, Carpenter DJ, Kubota M, Matsumoto R, Thapa P, Szabo PA, Li Poon MM, Li J, Arakawa-Hoyt J, Shen Y, Fong L, Lanier LL, Farber DL. Tissue Determinants of Human NK Cell Development, Function, and Residence. Cell. 2020 Feb 20;180(4):749-763.e13. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2020.01.022. Epub 2020 Feb 13.</citation>
    <PMID>32059780</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ghanemi A, St-Amand J. Interleukin-6 as a &quot;metabolic hormone&quot;. Cytokine. 2018 Dec;112:132-136. doi: 10.1016/j.cyto.2018.06.034. Epub 2018 Jul 6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29983356</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gjevestad GO, Holven KB, Ulven SM. Effects of Exercise on Gene Expression of Inflammatory Markers in Human Peripheral Blood Cells: A Systematic Review. Curr Cardiovasc Risk Rep. 2015;9(7):34. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26005511</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gupta P, Bigley AB, Markofski M, Laughlin M, LaVoy EC. Autologous serum collected 1 h post-exercise enhances natural killer cell cytotoxicity. Brain Behav Immun. 2018 Jul;71:81-92. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2018.04.007. Epub 2018 Apr 12.</citation>
    <PMID>29656052</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hanna J, Bechtel P, Zhai Y, Youssef F, McLachlan K, Mandelboim O. Novel insights on human NK cells' immunological modalities revealed by gene expression profiling. J Immunol. 2004 Dec 1;173(11):6547-63. Erratum in: J Immunol. 2015 Mar 1;194(5):2447-8.</citation>
    <PMID>15557145</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kenfield SA, Stampfer MJ, Giovannucci E, Chan JM. Physical activity and survival after prostate cancer diagnosis in the health professionals follow-up study. J Clin Oncol. 2011 Feb 20;29(6):726-32. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2010.31.5226. Epub 2011 Jan 4.</citation>
    <PMID>21205749</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Larrabee RC. Leucocytosis after violent Exercise. J Med Res. 1902 Jan;7(1):76-82.</citation>
    <PMID>19971455</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Larsen SK, Gao Y, Basse PH. NK cells in the tumor microenvironment. Crit Rev Oncog. 2014;19(1-2):91-105. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24941376</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lukaski HC. Soft tissue composition and bone mineral status: evaluation by dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry. J Nutr. 1993 Feb;123(2 Suppl):438-43. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>8429400</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Macpherson RE, Huber JS, Frendo-Cumbo S, Simpson JA, Wright DC. Adipose Tissue Insulin Action and IL-6 Signaling after Exercise in Obese Mice. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015 Oct;47(10):2034-42. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000000660.</citation>
    <PMID>25785928</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Meyerhardt JA, Giovannucci EL, Ogino S, Kirkner GJ, Chan AT, Willett W, Fuchs CS. Physical activity and male colorectal cancer survival. Arch Intern Med. 2009 Dec 14;169(22):2102-8. doi: 10.1001/archinternmed.2009.412.</citation>
    <PMID>20008694</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nieman DC, Miller AR, Henson DA, Warren BJ, Gusewitch G, Johnson RL, Davis JM, Butterworth DE, Nehlsen-Cannarella SL. Effects of high- vs moderate-intensity exercise on natural killer cell activity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1993 Oct;25(10):1126-34.</citation>
    <PMID>8231757</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ostrowski K, Rohde T, Asp S, Schjerling P, Pedersen BK. Pro- and anti-inflammatory cytokine balance in strenuous exercise in humans. J Physiol. 1999 Feb 15;515 ( Pt 1):287-91.</citation>
    <PMID>9925898</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pedersen BK, Hoffman-Goetz L. Exercise and the immune system: regulation, integration, and adaptation. Physiol Rev. 2000 Jul;80(3):1055-81. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>10893431</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pedersen L, Idorn M, Olofsson GH, Lauenborg B, Nookaew I, Hansen RH, Johannesen HH, Becker JC, Pedersen KS, Dethlefsen C, Nielsen J, Gehl J, Pedersen BK, Thor Straten P, Hojman P. Voluntary Running Suppresses Tumor Growth through Epinephrine- and IL-6-Dependent NK Cell Mobilization and Redistribution. Cell Metab. 2016 Mar 8;23(3):554-62. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2016.01.011. Epub 2016 Feb 16.</citation>
    <PMID>26895752</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Perez SA, Mahaira LG, Demirtzoglou FJ, Sotiropoulou PA, Ioannidis P, Iliopoulou EG, Gritzapis AD, Sotiriadou NN, Baxevanis CN, Papamichail M. A potential role for hydrocortisone in the positive regulation of IL-15-activated NK-cell proliferation and survival. Blood. 2005 Jul 1;106(1):158-66. Epub 2005 Mar 8.</citation>
    <PMID>15755904</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Radom-Aizik S, Zaldivar F, Haddad F, Cooper DM. Impact of brief exercise on peripheral blood NK cell gene and microRNA expression in young adults. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2013 Mar 1;114(5):628-36. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.01341.2012. Epub 2013 Jan 3.</citation>
    <PMID>23288554</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rooney BV, Bigley AB, LaVoy EC, Laughlin M, Pedlar C, Simpson RJ. Lymphocytes and monocytes egress peripheral blood within minutes after cessation of steady state exercise: A detailed temporal analysis of leukocyte extravasation. Physiol Behav. 2018 Oct 1;194:260-267. doi: 10.1016/j.physbeh.2018.06.008. Epub 2018 Jun 7.</citation>
    <PMID>29885920</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schlahsa L, Jaimes Y, Blasczyk R, Figueiredo C. Granulocyte-colony-stimulatory factor: a strong inhibitor of natural killer cell function. Transfusion. 2011 Feb;51(2):293-305. doi: 10.1111/j.1537-2995.2010.02820.x. Epub 2010 Aug 16.</citation>
    <PMID>20723170</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Smolen JS, Beaulieu A, Rubbert-Roth A, Ramos-Remus C, Rovensky J, Alecock E, Woodworth T, Alten R; OPTION Investigators. Effect of interleukin-6 receptor inhibition with tocilizumab in patients with rheumatoid arthritis (OPTION study): a double-blind, placebo-controlled, randomised trial. Lancet. 2008 Mar 22;371(9617):987-97. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(08)60453-5.</citation>
    <PMID>18358926</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stewart, B. and Wild, C.P. (eds.), International Agency for Research on Cancer, W. (2014). World Cancer Report 2014. World Cancer Report 2014 [Online].</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vivier E, Tomasello E, Baratin M, Walzer T, Ugolini S. Functions of natural killer cells. Nat Immunol. 2008 May;9(5):503-10. doi: 10.1038/ni1582. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18425107</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wang Y, Jacobs EJ, Gapstur SM, Maliniak ML, Gansler T, McCullough ML, Stevens VL, Patel AV. Recreational Physical Activity in Relation to Prostate Cancer-specific Mortality Among Men with Nonmetastatic Prostate Cancer. Eur Urol. 2017 Dec;72(6):931-939. doi: 10.1016/j.eururo.2017.06.037. Epub 2017 Jul 12.</citation>
    <PMID>28711382</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weber MM, Michl P, Auernhammer CJ, Engelhardt D. Interleukin-3 and interleukin-6 stimulate cortisol secretion from adult human adrenocortical cells. Endocrinology. 1997 May;138(5):2207-10.</citation>
    <PMID>9112422</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wendt K, Wilk E, Buyny S, Buer J, Schmidt RE, Jacobs R. Gene and protein characteristics reflect functional diversity of CD56dim and CD56bright NK cells. J Leukoc Biol. 2006 Dec;80(6):1529-41. Epub 2006 Sep 11.</citation>
    <PMID>16966385</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu J, Lanier LL. Natural killer cells and cancer. Adv Cancer Res. 2003;90:127-56. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>14710949</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yamada M, Suzuki K, Kudo S, Totsuka M, Nakaji S, Sugawara K. Raised plasma G-CSF and IL-6 after exercise may play a role in neutrophil mobilization into the circulation. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2002 May;92(5):1789-94.</citation>
    <PMID>11960925</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zimmer P, Schenk A, Kieven M, Holthaus M, Lehmann J, Lövenich L, Bloch W. Exercise induced alterations in NK-cell cytotoxicity - methodological issues and future perspectives. Exerc Immunol Rev. 2017;23:66-81. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28230531</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dorling J, Broom DR, Burns SF, Clayton DJ, Deighton K, James LJ, King JA, Miyashita M, Thackray AE, Batterham RL, Stensel DJ. Acute and Chronic Effects of Exercise on Appetite, Energy Intake, and Appetite-Related Hormones: The Modulating Effect of Adiposity, Sex, and Habitual Physical Activity. Nutrients. 2018 Aug 22;10(9). pii: E1140. doi: 10.3390/nu10091140. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30131457</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Steensberg A, van Hall G, Osada T, Sacchetti M, Saltin B, Klarlund Pedersen B. Production of interleukin-6 in contracting human skeletal muscles can account for the exercise-induced increase in plasma interleukin-6. J Physiol. 2000 Nov 15;529 Pt 1:237-42.</citation>
    <PMID>11080265</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dantzer R. Cytokine-induced sickness behavior: mechanisms and implications. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2001 Mar;933:222-34. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>12000023</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>van Gameren MM, Willemse PH, Mulder NH, Limburg PC, Groen HJ, Vellenga E, de Vries EG. Effects of recombinant human interleukin-6 in cancer patients: a phase I-II study. Blood. 1994 Sep 1;84(5):1434-41.</citation>
    <PMID>8068939</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Timper K, Denson JL, Steculorum SM, Heilinger C, Engström-Ruud L, Wunderlich CM, Rose-John S, Wunderlich FT, Brüning JC. IL-6 Improves Energy and Glucose Homeostasis in Obesity via Enhanced Central IL-6 trans-Signaling. Cell Rep. 2017 Apr 11;19(2):267-280. doi: 10.1016/j.celrep.2017.03.043.</citation>
    <PMID>28402851</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lang Lehrskov L, Lyngbaek MP, Soederlund L, Legaard GE, Ehses JA, Heywood SE, Wewer Albrechtsen NJ, Holst JJ, Karstoft K, Pedersen BK, Ellingsgaard H. Interleukin-6 Delays Gastric Emptying in Humans with Direct Effects on Glycemic Control. Cell Metab. 2018 Jun 5;27(6):1201-1211.e3. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2018.04.008. Epub 2018 May 3.</citation>
    <PMID>29731416</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ellingsgaard H, Seelig E, Timper K, Coslovsky M, Soederlund L, Lyngbaek MP, Wewer Albrechtsen NJ, Schmidt-Trucksäss A, Hanssen H, Frey WO, Karstoft K, Pedersen BK, Böni-Schnetzler M, Donath MY. GLP-1 secretion is regulated by IL-6 signalling: a randomised, placebo-controlled study. Diabetologia. 2020 Feb;63(2):362-373. doi: 10.1007/s00125-019-05045-y. Epub 2019 Dec 3.</citation>
    <PMID>31796986</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Begg DP, Woods SC. The endocrinology of food intake. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2013 Oct;9(10):584-97. doi: 10.1038/nrendo.2013.136. Epub 2013 Jul 23. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23877425</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Medhus AW, Sandstad O, Bredesen J, Husebye E. Delay of gastric emptying by duodenal intubation: sensitive measurement of gastric emptying by the paracetamol absorption test. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 1999 May;13(5):609-20.</citation>
    <PMID>10233184</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Andreas Kraag Kraag Ziegler</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Natural Killer cells</keyword>
  <keyword>Aerobic exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>IL-6R blockade</keyword>
  <keyword>Human</keyword>
  <keyword>Appetite</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

