<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04614194</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STU-2020-1043</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04614194</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Single Cell Immune and Non-immune Correlates of Response to Neoadjuvant Abemaciclib</brief_title>
  <official_title>Single Cell Immune and Non-immune Correlates of Response to Neoadjuvant Abemaciclib and Letrozole in Hormone Receptor Positive Breast Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eli Lilly and Company</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cancer Prevention Research Institute of Texas</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to better understand how the immune system plays a role in&#xD;
      fighting breast cancer and specifically research if the immune system response against breast&#xD;
      cancer can be improved with endocrine therapy and cyclin dependent kinase inhibitor therapy&#xD;
      in patients with hormone receptor positive breast cancer. This will be studied by collecting&#xD;
      tumor tissue and blood samples before and after 2 weeks of study treatment with commonly used&#xD;
      endocrine therapy and cyclin dependent kinase inhibitor therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 22, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 22, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in T cell activation</measure>
    <time_frame>After treatment ends (14 (+/- 3) days</time_frame>
    <description>Change in T cell activation between matched pre-treatment and on-treatment tissue samples of responder patients treated with abemaciclib and letrozole. T cell activation will be defined as the density of granzyme positive CD8 T cells detected on multiplex immunohistochemistry. Responders are defined as having complete cell cycle arrest by Ki-67.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: Abemaciclib + Letrozole</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient will take twice daily abemaciclib and daily letrozole (Arm A) for 2 weeks prior to your planned standard treatment for breast cancer. In addition to tests and procedures that are part of your standard care, you will have a biopsy and blood draw for study purposes prior to starting study treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: Letrozole</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient will take daily letrozole only (Arm B) according to treatment arm for 2 weeks prior to your planned standard treatment for breast cancer. In addition to tests and procedures that are part of your standard care, you will have a biopsy and blood draw for study purposes prior to starting study treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Letrozole</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral. Tablets should be taken at the same times every day, with or without food.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: Abemaciclib + Letrozole</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: Letrozole</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Abemaciclib</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral. Tablets should be taken at the same times every day, with or without food.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: Abemaciclib + Letrozole</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical stage operable stage I, II, or III invasive mammary carcinoma, which is&#xD;
             estrogen receptor or progesterone receptor positive by immunohistochemistry and HER2&#xD;
             negative by Herceptest (0 or 1+) or not amplified by in situ hybridization as per&#xD;
             routine clinical testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have post-menopausal status, as defined by any of the following: Subjects at least 55&#xD;
             years of age OR Subjects under 55 years of age and amenorrheic for at least 12 months&#xD;
             OR follicule stimulating hormone (FSH) values ≥ 40 IU/L and estradiol levels ≤ 40&#xD;
             pg/mL (140 pmol/L) or in postmenopausal ranges per local or institutional reference&#xD;
             ranges.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breast tumor ≥1cm in diameter by either physical exam or ultrasound and suitable for&#xD;
             pre and post-treatment tissue sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meet either of 2 following criteria, for which neoadjuvant endocrine therapy for 2&#xD;
             weeks is deemed suitable: 1) disease that is planned for surgery as initial therapy,&#xD;
             in which 2 weeks of neoadjuvant endocrine therapy is deemed suitable, 2) Disease for&#xD;
             which neoadjuvant systemic therapy (either chemotherapy or endocrine therapy) may be&#xD;
             planned, in which 2 weeks of neoadjuvant endocrine therapy prior to start of systemic&#xD;
             therapy is deemed suitable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Performance status ECOG ≤ 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have adequate organ function (ANC ≥1,500/mcL, Platelets ≥100,000/mcL, Hemoglobin ≥8&#xD;
             g/dL, Total bilirubin ≤1.5 × upper limit of normal, ALT and AST ≤3 × upper limit of&#xD;
             normal, Creatinine clearance &gt;30 mL/minute&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient is able to swallow oral medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a prior history of contralateral breast cancer are eligible if they have&#xD;
             no evidence of recurrence of their initial primary breast cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women may have been taking tamoxifen or raloxifene as a preventive agent prior to&#xD;
             study entry but must have discontinued the drug for at least 28 days prior to study&#xD;
             enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects have ended hormone replacement therapy at least 7 days prior to receiving the&#xD;
             first dose of randomized therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A female of childbearing potential, must have a negative serum pregnancy test within 7&#xD;
             days of the first dose of abemaciclib and agree to use a highly effective&#xD;
             contraception method during the treatment period and for 3 weeks following the last&#xD;
             dose of abemaciclib. These criteria should not apply to most or all patients on the&#xD;
             trial given the inclusion criteria is for post-menopausal patients only who should not&#xD;
             be of childbearing potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: Contraceptive methods may include an intrauterine device [IUD] or barrier method. If&#xD;
        condoms are used as a barrier method, a spermicidal agent should be added as a double&#xD;
        barrier protection. Cases of pregnancy that occur during maternal exposures to abemaciclib&#xD;
        should be reported. If a patient or spouse/partner is determined to be pregnant following&#xD;
        abemaciclib initiation, she must discontinue treatment immediately. Data on fetal outcome&#xD;
        and breast-feeding are to be collected for regulatory reporting and drug safety evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active metastatic breast cancer, inflammatory breast cancer, or locally recurrent&#xD;
             breast cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has serious and/or uncontrolled preexisting medical condition(s) that, in&#xD;
             the judgment of the investigator, would preclude participation in this study (for&#xD;
             example, interstitial lung disease, severe dyspnea at rest or requiring oxygen&#xD;
             therapy, severe renal impairment [e.g. estimated creatinine clearance &lt;30ml/min],&#xD;
             history of major surgical resection involving the stomach or small bowel, or a&#xD;
             preexisting chronic condition resulting in baseline grade 2 or higher diarrhea).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females who are pregnant, lactating, or premenopausal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe uncontrolled malabsorption condition or disease (i.e. grade 2 or higher&#xD;
             diarrhea, severe malnutrition, short gut syndrome).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dementia, altered mental status, or any psychiatric condition that would prohibit the&#xD;
             understanding or rendering of informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chemotherapy, radiotherapy, or any other cancer therapy for current diagnosis of&#xD;
             breast cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects may not have received or be receiving any other investigational agents for&#xD;
             the treatment of the cancer under study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to abemaciclib or other agents used in study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator, would limit compliance with study requirements.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sangeetha Reddy, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Shahbano Shakeel</last_name>
    <phone>214-648-7097</phone>
    <email>Shahbano.Shakeel@UTSouthwestern.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Parkland Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75039</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75390</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 13, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sangeetha Reddy</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Letrozole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

