<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04617808</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CHRO-2019-02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04617808</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Predictive Score for Non-traumatic Secondary Headache After an Emergency Call</brief_title>
  <acronym>CEPHAREG</acronym>
  <official_title>Predictive Score for Non-traumatic Secondary Headache After an Emergency Call</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Hospitalier Régional d'Orléans</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Hospitalier Régional d'Orléans</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study objective was to identify predictive criteria of severe non-traumatic secondary&#xD;
      headache among the information gathered during telephone interview conducted by the on-call&#xD;
      regulating physician at the Centre15.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Headache accounted for 1% of outpatient consultations, 2% of hospital emergency department&#xD;
      visits and, at the French national level, 1% of complaints motivating calls to the&#xD;
      prehospital emergency medical service units (The French, physician-led Emergency Calls&#xD;
      Centers , called either &quot;Center 15&quot; or Service d'Aide Médicale d'Urgence [SAMU]). In 2009,&#xD;
      the French &quot;SAMU-Urgences de France&quot; society proposed a classification and diagnostic tool&#xD;
      for evaluating the headache patient, which is yet to be validated by a clinical study. Most&#xD;
      patients with headache spontaneously consulted the emergency department (ED) and only 4 to 5%&#xD;
      of patients entered ED through ambulance, fire and rescue department, medicalized ambulance&#xD;
      (SMUR), or police. Patients attending emergency service for unusual sudden headache arriving&#xD;
      by ambulance had a higher frequency of subarachnoid haemorrhage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Headache studies have mainly been conducted in the ED. The Ottawa rule published by Perry et&#xD;
      al. in 2013 proposed criteria for conducting explorations for subarachnoid hemorrhage (SAH)&#xD;
      in patients over 15 years of age with severe, non-traumatic headache, having reached maximum&#xD;
      intensity within one hour.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Unlike the primary headaches, secondary headaches are associated with underlying causes.&#xD;
      Among the severe secondary headaches (SSH) (4 to 5% of headaches), non-traumatic subarachnoid&#xD;
      haemorrhage was not diagnosed in 5.4% to 12% of cases in ED resulting in increase in&#xD;
      mortality from 5 to 14%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In 2018, French guidelines for the emergency management of headache recognized criteria&#xD;
      likely to be at risk of Severe Secondary Headache, requiring explorations in emergencies for&#xD;
      sudden headaches or thunderclaps headaches (i.e. reaching maximum intensity in less than a&#xD;
      minute), recent headaches or progressive worsening (&lt;7 days) and unusual, association with&#xD;
      fever (apart from an obvious cause), association with signs of neurological impairment,&#xD;
      suspicion of carbon monoxide poisoning, immunosuppression (neoplasia, HIV). Any unusual&#xD;
      headache in a patient with recurrent paroxysmal or chronic headache should be considered&#xD;
      secondary until proven otherwise. Subarachnoid hemorrhages were present in 11% of patients&#xD;
      with sudden, intense and unusual headache.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the French department of Loiret, patients with subarachnoid haemorrhage required a&#xD;
      transfer out of the department to the nearest regional referral teaching hospital, by lack of&#xD;
      adequate equipment and expertise for interventional neurology. Early diagnosis was therefore&#xD;
      critical. In fact, an untreated cerebral aneurysm rupture increased bleeding recurrence by&#xD;
      3-4% in the first 24 hours.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 21, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 21, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 21, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients with diagnosis of non-traumatic secondary headache</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 21</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with diagnosis of non-traumatic secondary headache attended by the French emergency services operating</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients requiring an admission to Intensive Care Unit</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients requiring an admission to the Intensive Care Unit between triage in the emergency department (Day 0) and Day 2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients with early mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients who died in hospital at day 7</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2024</enrollment>
  <condition>Headache</condition>
  <condition>Emergencies</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Headache pattern</arm_group_label>
    <description>Telephone call from center 15 for the headache pattern</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaire</intervention_name>
    <description>The regulatory scheme applied to all investigative centers is as follows:&#xD;
Call from Center 15 by a major patient for secondary headache no traumatic. (i.e. not having been the victim of a head trauma during the 48 hours preceding the call)&#xD;
Detection of the pattern of &quot;non-traumatic headache&quot;, by the regulatory assistant medical with registration of the word &quot;cephareg&quot; in the medical regulation software in order to alert the regulator about the possible inclusion of the patient&#xD;
If possible, patient information on the collection of their data for research and possibility of opposing&#xD;
Filling of a medical questionnaire by the regulating doctor&#xD;
Weekly collection of medical questionnaires by investigating doctors</description>
    <arm_group_label>Headache pattern</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The patients presenting all the inclusion criteria and not showing any of the non-inclusion&#xD;
        criteria will be included prospectively and consecutively when calling for medical&#xD;
        regulation from the SAMU 45. The patients will be included in the study by the doctor&#xD;
        regulator.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Telephone call from center 15 for the headache pattern&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-opposition expressed by the patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Or non-opposition delayed (adults with cognitive disorders, protected adults, clinical&#xD;
             situations judged to be serious by the Medical Regulation Assistant, physician&#xD;
             regulator, incoming call flow, call by close or trusted person)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Head trauma &lt; 48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moribund patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-affiliation to a social security scheme&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Opposition to the continuation of the study expressed orally by the patient or by&#xD;
             return mail within 30 days&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>JULIEN PASSERIEUX, Dr</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>CHR ORLEANS</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Aurélie DESPUJOLS</last_name>
    <phone>+33238744071</phone>
    <email>aurelie.despujols@chr-orleans.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Elodie POUGOUE TOUKO</last_name>
    <phone>+33238744086</phone>
    <email>elodie.pougoue-touko@chr-orleans.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Regional Hospital center of Orleans</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orléans</city>
        <zip>45067</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christophe DEVIN, MD</last_name>
      <email>christophe.devin@chr-orleans.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christophe DEVIN, Dr</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHRU de Tours</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tours</city>
        <zip>37044</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Geoffroy ROUSSEAU, Dr</last_name>
      <email>geoffroy.rousseau@chu-tours.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Geoffroy ROUSSEAU, Dr</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Burch RC, Loder S, Loder E, Smitherman TA. The prevalence and burden of migraine and severe headache in the United States: updated statistics from government health surveillance studies. Headache. 2015 Jan;55(1):21-34. doi: 10.1111/head.12482. Review. Erratum in: Headache. 2015 Feb;55(2):356.</citation>
    <PMID>25600719</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Goldstein JN, Camargo CA Jr, Pelletier AJ, Edlow JA. Headache in United States emergency departments: demographics, work-up and frequency of pathological diagnoses. Cephalalgia. 2006 Jun;26(6):684-90.</citation>
    <PMID>16686907</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Valade D. The Emergency Headache Center at the Lariboisière Hospital: 7 years with more than 70,000 patients. Intern Emerg Med. 2008 Oct;3 Suppl 1:S3-7. doi: 10.1007/s11739-008-0191-6.</citation>
    <PMID>18785014</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Perry JJ, Sivilotti MLA, Sutherland J, Hohl CM, Émond M, Calder LA, Vaillancourt C, Thirganasambandamoorthy V, Lesiuk H, Wells GA, Stiell IG. Validation of the Ottawa Subarachnoid Hemorrhage Rule in patients with acute headache. CMAJ. 2017 Nov 13;189(45):E1379-E1385. doi: 10.1503/cmaj.170072. Erratum in: CMAJ. 2018 Feb 12;190(6):E173.</citation>
    <PMID>29133539</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Perry JJ, Stiell IG, Sivilotti ML, Bullard MJ, Hohl CM, Sutherland J, Émond M, Worster A, Lee JS, Mackey D, Pauls M, Lesiuk H, Symington C, Wells GA. Clinical decision rules to rule out subarachnoid hemorrhage for acute headache. JAMA. 2013 Sep 25;310(12):1248-55. doi: 10.1001/jama.2013.278018.</citation>
    <PMID>24065011</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pari E, Rinaldi F, Gipponi S, Venturelli E, Liberini P, Rao R, Padovani A. Management of headache disorders in the Emergency Department setting. Neurol Sci. 2015 Jul;36(7):1153-60. doi: 10.1007/s10072-015-2148-7. Epub 2015 Mar 10. Erratum in: Neurol Sci. 2015 Jul;36(7):1161.</citation>
    <PMID>25754613</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chey WY, Kusakcioglu O, Dinoso V, Lorber SH. Gastric secretion in patients with chronic pancreatitis and in chronic alcoholics. Arch Intern Med. 1968 Nov;122(5):399-403.</citation>
    <PMID>5687926</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>headache</keyword>
  <keyword>Emergency</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Headache</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

