<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04613726</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>B.30.2.ATA.0.01.00/166</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04613726</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Intravenous Granisetron and Ondansetron in Patients Undergoing Cesarean Section</brief_title>
  <official_title>Intravenous Granisetron Provides Less Ephedrine Requirement Than Ondansetron in Patients Undergoing Cesarean Section With Spinal Anesthesia: A Randomised Placebo-controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ataturk University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ataturk University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study compared the effects of prophylactic intravenous (IV) infusion of ondansetron and&#xD;
      granisetron before the spinal anesthesia on hemodynamic parameters in patients undergoing&#xD;
      elective cesarean section.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A total of 120 parturients who agreed to participate in the study with uncomplicated term&#xD;
      pregnancy, aged between 18-45 years, American society of anesthesiologist I or II undergoing&#xD;
      elective cesarean section with combined spinal-epidural anesthesia (CSEA) were included.&#xD;
      Participants with complicated pregnancy such as diabetes, pregnancy-induced hypertension or&#xD;
      chronic hypertension, fetal anomaly, a history of allergy to study drugs, psychiatric&#xD;
      diseases, coagulation abnormalities and mul¬tiple pregnancies were excluded from the study.&#xD;
      Also, patients receiving selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors were excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A day before surgery, detailed anamnesis was obtained from the patients and a general&#xD;
      systemic examination was performed. Also, patients were informed about the study protocol and&#xD;
      written informed consent was obtained. The patients were informed that they should be fasting&#xD;
      for 8 hours before surgery. On the day of operation, peripheral intravenous (IV) access was&#xD;
      provided using a 16-gauge/18-gauge cannula.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After all patients received 500 ml of Ringer Lactate as preload, they were transferred to the&#xD;
      operating room. None of the patients received premedication. Before the anesthesia procedure;&#xD;
      patients' age, weight, height, ASA physical status, baseline systolic blood pressure (SBP),&#xD;
      diastolic blood pressure (DBP) and heart rate (HR) were recorded. The study medications were&#xD;
      prepared by an anesthesia resident who was not involved in the study. Three groups (n=40, for&#xD;
      each group) were formed by randomization using a computer-generated table of random numbers.&#xD;
      The anesthesiologist in charge, and the patient and investigators were blinded to the group&#xD;
      allocation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Five minutes before the CSEA procedure, Group I received IV 8 mg ondansetron diluted in 10 ml&#xD;
      of normal saline, Group II received IV 3 mg granisetron diluted in 10 ml of normal saline,&#xD;
      and Group III received IV 10 ml normal saline. Subsequently, combined spinal-epidural&#xD;
      anesthesia (CSEA) in the sitting position was performed in all patients. Following skin&#xD;
      sterilization and local anesthetic infiltration (2% lidocaine), 18 gauge Tuohy needle (Set&#xD;
      for CSEA, Braun®, Melsungen, Germany) was advanced through the midline L2-3 or L3-4&#xD;
      intervertebral spaces with loss of resistance technique. A 27-gauge pencil point needle was&#xD;
      inserted intrathecally, using the needle-through-needle technique. After free cerebrospinal&#xD;
      fluid flow was observed, 1.8 ml 0.5% isobaric bupivacaine (9 mg) and 15 µg fentanyl was&#xD;
      administered over 30 seconds. Then, the spinal needle was removed and epidural catheter was&#xD;
      advanced 3 to 5 cm into the epidural space. The catheter was secured in place after it was&#xD;
      checked with negative pressure. At the end of the anesthesia procedure, patients were placed&#xD;
      in the supine position for operation and the operating table was tilted 20° to the left.&#xD;
      Sensory block level was evaluated via pinprick test and when the sensory block reached at the&#xD;
      upper level of T6 dermatome, surgery was initiated. If sensory block were not observed within&#xD;
      the first 20 min following the spinal injection, spinal anesthesia was considered as failed.&#xD;
      In this instance, additional 5 ml solution of 2% lidocaine was injected via the epidural&#xD;
      catheter until a T6 level of the sensory block was provided and these patients were excluded&#xD;
      from the study. Motor block level was evaluated with Modified Bromage scale (scale 0 = The&#xD;
      patient is able to move hip, knee, ankle, and toes.; scale 1 = The patient is able to the&#xD;
      full flexion of foot and knee, she is unable to hip flexion; scale 2 = The patient is able to&#xD;
      the full flexion of foot, she is unable to knee and hip flexion; scale 3 = Total motor block&#xD;
      is available). General anaesthesia protocol was planned in case of three unsuccessful&#xD;
      attempts to reach to intrathecal space. Oxygen was delivered during surgery. Intravenous&#xD;
      ephedrine (6 mg) was planned to treat hypotension (a 30% decrease in systolic blood pressure&#xD;
      compared to preoperative values) and intra¬venous atropine (1 mg) was planned in case of&#xD;
      bradycardia (the heart rate &lt; 45 beats/minute) during surgery. In case of nausea and&#xD;
      vomiting, intravenous metoclopramide (10 mg) was administered. Following drug administration&#xD;
      to the intrathecal space, intraoperative hemodynamic changes were recorded every 2 min for 20&#xD;
      min and then every five minutes until the end of the operation by an anesthetist who was&#xD;
      blinded to the group allocation. The operation time (the time from the beginning of the&#xD;
      surgical incision until the end of surgery), anesthetic complications such as pruritus and&#xD;
      nausea-vomiting and the number of patients requiring epidural medication, ephedrine and&#xD;
      atropine during surgery were recorded. Neonatal Apgar scores at 1 and 5 min after delivery&#xD;
      and umbilical artery blood gas values were recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After operation, patients were evaluated in the recovery room for 120 min. Visual analogue&#xD;
      scale (VAS, 0 cm= no pain, 10 cm= worst pain) scores for pain severity, anesthesia-related&#xD;
      side effects (e.g., nausea, vomiting and headache), sensory block time (from the spinal&#xD;
      injection to the recovery of T10 dermatome), and the time requiring supplemental analgesics&#xD;
      was recorded by an independent observer blinded to the group assignment at 30 min and 1st and&#xD;
      2nd hours post-operatively. In the case of VAS &gt; 3 in a patient, 10 ml solution of 0.1%&#xD;
      bupivacaine was given via the epidural catheter. Patients were transferred to the ward,&#xD;
      following the motor block had regressed to the T10 level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary end point of the study was the ephedrine requirement during surgery. The minimum&#xD;
      sample size required for this study was calculated using the Russ Lenth's Power and sample&#xD;
      size calculation application. Thirty-five patients in each group were needed to demonstrate a&#xD;
      mean difference in the requirement of 10 mg ephedrine among groups with a power of 90% and&#xD;
      alpha 5%. However, a sample size was determined as 40 in each group, considering potential&#xD;
      dropouts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data were expressed as mean values ± standard deviation (SD) or number and percentage values.&#xD;
      Comparisons were performed using the ANOVA test. The percentage values were compared using&#xD;
      chi-square, P&lt;0.05 was considered significant statistically.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 3, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 12, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Comparator / control treatment Control group consisted of patients receiving IV 10 ml normal saline. A comparator group consisted of receiving IV 8 mg ondansetron diluted in 10 ml of normal saline, Another comparator group consisted of receivingIV 3 mg granisetron diluted in 10 ml of normal saline.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The anesthesiologist in charge, and the patient and investigators were blinded to the group allocation.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ephedrine requirement</measure>
    <time_frame>Every two minutes during surgery.</time_frame>
    <description>The change in ephedrine requirement during surgery (mg).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>atropine requirement</measure>
    <time_frame>every two minutes during surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The change in atropine requirement during surgery (mg).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>analgesic requirement</measure>
    <time_frame>every five minutes during surgery and postoperative 24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>The change in analgesic requirement during surgery and postoperative 24 hours(mg)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>blood pressure values</measure>
    <time_frame>every two minutes during surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The change in systolic and diastolic blood pressure values (mmHg).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>heart rate values</measure>
    <time_frame>every two minutes during surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The change in heart rate values (bpm).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Vomiting, Postoperative</condition>
  <condition>Postoperative Complications</condition>
  <condition>Hypotension</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IV 10 ml normal saline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control group consisted of patients receiving IV 10 ml normal saline.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IV 8 mg ondansetron in 10 ml of normal saline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group consisted of receiving IV 8 mg ondansetron diluted in 10 ml of normal saline,</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IV 3 mg granisetron in 10 ml of normal saline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group consisted of receiving IV 3 mg granisetron diluted in 10 ml of normal saline.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ondansetron</intervention_name>
    <description>group consisted of receiving IV 8 mg ondansetron diluted in 10 ml of normal saline</description>
    <arm_group_label>IV 8 mg ondansetron in 10 ml of normal saline</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Granisetron</intervention_name>
    <description>Another comparator group consisted of receivingIV 3 mg granisetron diluted in 10 ml of normal saline</description>
    <arm_group_label>IV 3 mg granisetron in 10 ml of normal saline</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Saline</intervention_name>
    <description>Control group consisted of patients receiving IV 10 ml normal saline</description>
    <arm_group_label>IV 10 ml normal saline</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  aged between 18-45 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  uncomplicated term pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA (American society of anesthesiologist) I or II&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  undergoing elective cesarean section with combined spinal-epidural anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  psychiatric diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  preeclampsia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy-induced hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  multiple pregnancies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  fetal anomaly&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  allergy to study drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  receiving selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>women with uncomplicated term pregnancy</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mehmet AKSOY, Assoc.Prof.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Ataturk University, Erzurum, Turkey</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mehmet AKSOY</name>
      <address>
        <city>Erzurum</city>
        <state>string:Turkey</state>
        <zip>25240</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ataturk University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mehmet AKSOY</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assoc. Prof. Dr. Mehmet AKSOY</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>cesarean section</keyword>
  <keyword>granisetron</keyword>
  <keyword>ondansetron</keyword>
  <keyword>spinal anesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>blood pressure</keyword>
  <keyword>pre-treatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypotension</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Postoperative Complications</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ondansetron</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Granisetron</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

