<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04610658</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MCC-20332</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04610658</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Immune Checkpoint Inhibition With Lurbinectedin Relapsed/Recurrent SCLC</brief_title>
  <official_title>Activity and Enhancement of Immune Checkpoint Inhibition With Lurbinectedin in Relapsed/Recurrent Small Cell Lung Cancer (SCLC)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bristol-Myers Squibb</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>PharmaMar</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a single-arm, phase I/II trial to determine the Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD),&#xD;
      Recommended Phase II Dose (RP2D), and the safety and efficacy of the combination of&#xD;
      nivolumab-ipilimumab plus lurbinectedin in patients with relapsed/recurrent small cell lung&#xD;
      cancer after progression with first-line, platinum-based chemotherapy&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 23, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 26, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 1: Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD) of Lurbinectedin with Nivolumab and Ipilimumab</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 weeks per cohort</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum tolerated Dose will be determined by testing increasing doses of Lurbinectedin along with fixed doses of Nivolumab and Ipilimumab.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Disease Control Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Disease Control Rate (DCR) is defined as Complete Response (CR) +Partial Response (PR) +Stable Disease (SD). Best response time will be used for this measurement.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Overall Response Rate is defined as Complete Response + Partial Response using RECIST v1.1 criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Progression Free Survival is defined as the time from enrollment to date of progression or death, or censor at last clinical follow-up date.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Overall Survival is defined as the time from study enrollment to death from any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">57</enrollment>
  <condition>Small-cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Relapsed Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1 Dose Level 1: Nivolumab and Ipilimumab plus Lurbinectedin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be treated at dose level 1: nivolumab 1mg/kg, ipilimumab 3mg/kg plus 1.5 mg/m^2 lurbinectedin. Participants will receive nivolumab, ipilimumab and Lurbinectedin every 3 weeks for 4 cycles. After 4 treatment cycles, ipilimumab will be discontinued and participants will continue treatment with a flat dose of 360 mg nivolumab and Lurbinectedin at dose level 1 every 3 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1 Dose Level 2: Nivolumab and Ipilimumab plus Lurbinectedin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be treated at dose level 2: nivolumab 1mg/kg, ipilimumab 3mg/kg plus 2.6 mg/m^2 lurbinectedin. Participants will receive nivolumab, ipilimumab and Lurbinectedin every 3 weeks for 4 cycles. After 4 treatment cycles, ipilimumab will be discontinued and participants will continue treatment with a flat dose of 360 mg nivolumab and Lurbinectedin at dose level 2 every 3 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1 Dose Level 3: Nivolumab and Ipilimumab plus Lurbinectedin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be treated at dose level 3: nivolumab 1mg/kg, ipilimumab 3mg/kg plus 3.2 mg/m^2 lurbinectedin. Participants will receive nivolumab, ipilimumab and Lurbinectedin every 3 weeks for 4 cycles. After 4 treatment cycles, ipilimumab will be discontinued and participants will continue treatment with a flat dose of 360 mg nivolumab and Lurbinectedin at dose level 3 every 3 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 2: Treatment at Maximum Tolerated Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be treated with nivolumab 1mg/kg, ipilimumab 3mg/kg plus maximum tolerated dose of lurbinectedin. Participants will receive nivolumab, ipilimumab and Lurbinectedin every 3 weeks for 4 cycles. After 4 treatment cycles, ipilimumab will be discontinued and participants will continue treatment with a flat dose of 360 mg nivolumab and Lurbinectedin at MTD every 3 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nivolumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive 1 mg/kg Nivolumab on Day 1 of each treatment cycle for 4 cycles (induction immunotherapy). After 4 treatment cycles, Nivolumab will be continued at a flat dose of 360 mg.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1 Dose Level 1: Nivolumab and Ipilimumab plus Lurbinectedin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1 Dose Level 2: Nivolumab and Ipilimumab plus Lurbinectedin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1 Dose Level 3: Nivolumab and Ipilimumab plus Lurbinectedin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 2: Treatment at Maximum Tolerated Dose</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Opdivo</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ipilimumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive 3mg/kg Ipilimumab on Day 1 of each treatment cycle for 4 cycles (induction immunotherapy). After 4 cycles, Ipilimumab will be discontinued.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1 Dose Level 1: Nivolumab and Ipilimumab plus Lurbinectedin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1 Dose Level 2: Nivolumab and Ipilimumab plus Lurbinectedin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1 Dose Level 3: Nivolumab and Ipilimumab plus Lurbinectedin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 2: Treatment at Maximum Tolerated Dose</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Yervoy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lurbinectedin</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be treated at 1 of 3 dose levels of Lurbinectedin, beginning at 1.5 mg/m^2 and increasing to 3.2 mg/m^2 or the Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1 Dose Level 1: Nivolumab and Ipilimumab plus Lurbinectedin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1 Dose Level 2: Nivolumab and Ipilimumab plus Lurbinectedin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1 Dose Level 3: Nivolumab and Ipilimumab plus Lurbinectedin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 2: Treatment at Maximum Tolerated Dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease based on RECIST v1.1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Performance status of 0-1 on the Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance&#xD;
             scale&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate organ function as defined per protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child bearing potential (WOCBP) must have a negative urine or serum pregnancy&#xD;
             test within 72 hours from receiving first dose of study medication. If the urine test&#xD;
             is positive or cannot be confirmed as negative, a serum pregnancy test will be&#xD;
             required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  WOCBP should agree to use 2 methods of birth control or abstain from heterosexual&#xD;
             activity for the course of the study through 5 months after the last dose of study&#xD;
             medication, or should be surgically sterile. Note: A woman is considered to be of&#xD;
             &quot;reproductive potential&quot; (WOCBP) if she has had menses at any time in the preceding 12&#xD;
             consecutive months. In addition to routine contraceptive methods, &quot;effective&#xD;
             contraception&quot; also includes heterosexual celibacy and surgery intended to prevent&#xD;
             pregnancy (or with a side-effect of pregnancy prevention) defined as a hysterectomy,&#xD;
             bilateral oophorectomy or bilateral tubal ligation. However, if at any point a&#xD;
             previously celibate patient chooses to become heterosexually active during the time&#xD;
             period for use of contraceptive measures, she is responsible for beginning&#xD;
             contraceptive measures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male participants should agree to use an adequate method of contraception starting&#xD;
             with the first dose of study therapy through 7 months after the last dose of study&#xD;
             therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: In addition to routine contraceptive methods, &quot;effective contraception&quot; also includes&#xD;
        heterosexual celibacy and surgery intended to prevent pregnancy (vasectomy). However, if at&#xD;
        any point a previously celibate patient chooses to become heterosexually active during the&#xD;
        time period for use of contraceptive measures, he is responsible for beginning&#xD;
        contraceptive measures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Individuals meeting any of the following criteria will be excluded from participation in&#xD;
        this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently participating in a study of an investigational agent or device and&#xD;
             received or used the investigational agent or device within 4 weeks of the first dose&#xD;
             of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a diagnosis of immunodeficiency or is receiving systemic steroid or any other form&#xD;
             of immunosuppressive therapy within 7 days prior to the first dose of treatment. Note:&#xD;
             Systemic steroid doses of ≤ 10 mg of prednisone daily or its equivalent are allowed in&#xD;
             patients receiving physiologic replacement steroid doses&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of active Bacillus Tuberculosis (TB)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypersensitivity to Lurbinectedin, Ipilimumab and/or nivolumab or any of its&#xD;
             excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has had a prior anti-cancer monoclonal antibody (mAb) within 4 weeks prior to study&#xD;
             Day 1 or who has not recovered (i.e., ≤ Grade 1 or at baseline) from adverse events&#xD;
             due to agents administered more than 4 weeks earlier.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has had targeted small molecule therapy, or standard fractionated radiotherapy within&#xD;
             2 weeks, chemotherapy within 3 weeks and stereotactic radiotherapy within 1 week prior&#xD;
             to study Day 1 or who has not recovered (i.e., ≤ Grade 1 or at baseline) from adverse&#xD;
             events due to a previously administered agent. Note:: Participants with ≤ Grade 2&#xD;
             neuropathy are an exception to this criterion and may qualify for the study. If&#xD;
             participant received major surgery, they must have recovered adequately from the&#xD;
             toxicity and/or complications from the intervention prior to starting therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known additional malignancy that is progressing or requires active treatment.&#xD;
             Exceptions include basal cell carcinoma of the skin or squamous cell carcinoma of the&#xD;
             skin that has undergone potentially curative therapy or in situ cervical cancer. Other&#xD;
             malignancies that remain without evidence of disease or recurrence, 2 years or more&#xD;
             after curative therapy are also considered part of this exception.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has known active central nervous system (CNS) metastases and/or carcinomatous&#xD;
             meningitis. Participants with previously treated brain metastases may participate&#xD;
             provided they are stable (without evidence of progression by imaging for at least 2&#xD;
             weeks prior to the first dose of trial treatment and any neurologic symptoms have&#xD;
             returned to baseline), have no evidence of new or enlarging brain metastases, and are&#xD;
             not using steroids for at least 7days prior to trial treatment. This exception does&#xD;
             not include carcinomatous meningitis which is excluded regardless of clinical&#xD;
             stability.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has any of the following concomitant diseases/conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. History or presence of unstable angina, myocardial infarction, congestive heart&#xD;
                  failure, or clinically significant valvular heart disease within last year.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Symptomatic arrhythmia or any uncontrolled arrhythmia requiring ongoing&#xD;
                  treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. History of idiopathic, pulmonary fibrosis, organizing pneumonia, drug-induced&#xD;
                  pneumonitis, idiopathic pneumonitis or evidence of active pneumonitis on&#xD;
                  screening chest CT-scan. History of radiation pneumonitis in radiation field&#xD;
                  (fibrosis) is permitted, as long as it is asymptomatic and no steroids are&#xD;
                  needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Myopathy or any clinical situation that causes significant and persistent&#xD;
                  elevation of CPK (&gt;2.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) in two different&#xD;
                  determinations performed one week apart).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any diagnosis of autoimmune disease (confirmed by medical records or appropriate&#xD;
             laboratory testing) is not allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an active infection requiring systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history or current evidence of any condition, therapy, or laboratory abnormality&#xD;
             that might confound the results of the trial, interfere with the patient's&#xD;
             participation for the full duration of the trial, or is not in the best interest of&#xD;
             the patient to participate, in the opinion of the treating investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has known psychiatric or substance abuse disorders that would interfere with&#xD;
             cooperation with the requirements of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is pregnant or breastfeeding, or expecting to conceive or father children within the&#xD;
             projected duration of the trial, starting with the pre-screening or screening visit&#xD;
             through 120 days after the last dose of trial treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) (HIV 1/2 antibodies), active&#xD;
             Hepatitis B (e.g., HBsAg reactive) or Hepatitis C (e.g., HCV RNA [qualitative] is&#xD;
             detected).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received a live vaccine within 30 days of start of study therapy. Note: Seasonal&#xD;
             influenza vaccines for injection are generally inactivated flu vaccines and are&#xD;
             allowed; however intranasal influenza vaccines (e.g., Flu-Mist®) are live attenuated&#xD;
             vaccines, and are not allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who had a prior Grade ≥3 immune-related adverse event (e.g. pneumonitis,&#xD;
             hepatitis, colitis, endocrinopathy) with prior immunotherapy (e.g. cancer vaccine,&#xD;
             cytokine, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must not be pregnant or nursing due to risk of fetal or nursing infant harm.&#xD;
             WOCBP must have agreed to use an effective contraceptive method.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with interstitial lung disease that is symptomatic or may interfere with&#xD;
             the detection or management of suspected drug-related pulmonary toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who are compulsorily detained for treatment of either a psychiatric or&#xD;
             physical (e.g., infectious disease) illness&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alberto A Chiappori, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Moffitt Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Deandre White</last_name>
    <phone>813-745-4302</phone>
    <email>Deandre.White@moffitt.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Advent Health - Celebration</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kissimmee</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>34747</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>George R Simon, MD</last_name>
      <phone>407-303-4000</phone>
      <email>George.Simon@moffitt.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>George R Simon, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Moffitt Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christine Sigua</last_name>
      <phone>813-745-6217</phone>
      <email>Christine.Sigua@moffitt.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alberto A Chiappori, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Benjamin C Creelan, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jhanelle E Gray, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Eric B Haura, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Andreas Saltos, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael R Shafique, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tawee Tanvetyanon, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.moffitt.org/research--clinical-trials/clinical-trials</url>
    <description>Moffitt Cancer Center Clinical Trials website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 26, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 26, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ipilimumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

