<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04614584</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-30109</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04614584</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mirtazapine and Methamphetamine Drug-drug Interaction Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 1 Safety-interaction Study of Mirtazapine for the Treatment of Methamphetamine Use Disorder</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>San Francisco Department of Public Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of California, Los Angeles</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>San Francisco Department of Public Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a drug-drug interaction (DDI) study of mirtazapine for methamphetamine (MA) use&#xD;
      disorder (MUD) to ensure the safety of this medication in the presence of a relevant dose of&#xD;
      MA for people actively-using MA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1: To determine if mirtazapine alters the cardiovascular response to IV MA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2: To determine if the pharmacokinetics of IV MA are altered by mirtazapine&#xD;
      administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 3: To evaluate the above aims in the setting of concomitant administration of methadone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study involves two simultaneous within-subject drug-drug interaction studies, each&#xD;
      comprised of 12 participants. A total of 24 subjects will be enrolled who have&#xD;
      methamphetamine use disorder who will be classified into 2 groups: (Group 1: no opioids;&#xD;
      Group 2: opioid use disorder on methadone maintenance). Subjects will be randomized to the&#xD;
      order of mirtazapine and placebo (i.e. one-half will receive mirtazapine first, then placebo;&#xD;
      one-half will receive placebo first, then mirtazapine).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a drug-drug interaction (DDI) study of mirtazapine for methamphetamine (MA) use&#xD;
      disorder (MUD) to ensure the safety of this medication in the presence of a relevant dose of&#xD;
      MA for people actively-using MA. MA is a widely used psychostimulant associated with&#xD;
      substantial morbidity and mortality. MA is more prevalent than many other drugs, including&#xD;
      opioids, with 37 million users of MA and amphetamine worldwide and 1.4 million past-year&#xD;
      users in the U.S. alone in 2016. The number of MA poisoning deaths has steadily risen in&#xD;
      recent years, from &gt;3,700 in 2014 to 10,333 in 2017. Importantly, MA has been recognized as&#xD;
      contributing substantially to the U.S. opioid crisis, with about half of MA poisoning deaths&#xD;
      also caused by opioids. In the U.S., the annual economic cost of MA use is estimated to be&#xD;
      $23.4 billion and use is strongly associated with HIV transmission.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are no FDA-approved pharmacologic treatments for MUD, a major gap in addiction&#xD;
      medicine, especially because behavioral interventions alone have limited efficacy and would&#xD;
      likely benefit from adjunctive pharmacologic therapy. Investigators' prior clinical trials&#xD;
      included a Phase IIa trial (N=60) and a replication Phase IIb trial (N=120) demonstrating&#xD;
      that mirtazapine (an adrenergic, serotoninergic, and dopaminergic generic medication&#xD;
      currently approved to treat depression) 30mg orally once daily reduced MA use among&#xD;
      MA-dependent men who have sex with men (MSM) and transgender women. Investigators were&#xD;
      directed to conduct a DDI study to ensure the safety of mirtazapine with MA. This research is&#xD;
      particularly relevant given the overlap of MA use disorder and opioid use disorder (OUD),&#xD;
      which could raise additional safety concerns.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objectives of this study are as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To determine if mirtazapine 30mg daily alters the cardiovascular response to IV MA. The&#xD;
           interaction of active medication (compared with placebo) with relevant doses of MA (30&#xD;
           mg) on cardiovascular (heart rate, blood pressure, QTc interval) parameters and adverse&#xD;
           events, including serotonergic signs, will be assessed to gather safety information in&#xD;
           the Phase I human laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To determine if mirtazapine alters the pharmacokinetics of IV MA. Pharmacokinetic&#xD;
           parameters for MA and its major metabolites will be assessed over 48 hours under steady&#xD;
           state mirtazapine (30 mg) or placebo, and relevant IV MA challenge (30 mg).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To evaluate the above aims in the setting of concomitant steady-state administration of&#xD;
           morphine or methadone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design This study involves two simultaneous within-subject drug-drug interaction studies,&#xD;
      each comprised of 12 participants. A total of 24 subjects will be enrolled who have MA use&#xD;
      disorder who will be classified into 2 groups: (Group 1: no opioids; Group 2: opioid use&#xD;
      disorder on methadone maintenance). Subjects will be randomized to the order of mirtazapine&#xD;
      and placebo (i.e. one-half will receive mirtazapine first, then placebo; one-half will&#xD;
      receive placebo first, then mirtazapine).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures Screening assessments will be completed across two-to-four visits over 2 weeks.&#xD;
      All screening assessments should be completed within 14 days after labs are drawn.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All subjects will complete the following study visits: screening 1 and 2,&#xD;
      enrollment/admission to inpatient stay, 14-day inpatient stay, 14-day post-discharge&#xD;
      follow-up visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After consent is obtained, eligibility will be determined over the following screening&#xD;
      visits, including medical history and physical examination (including weight and height),&#xD;
      review of systems, vital signs, concomitant medications, EKG, breathalyzer, labwork, SCID.&#xD;
      Additional assessments will include the CDS-12, PSQI, TLFB for substance use, delayed&#xD;
      discounting, BIS-11, Stroop Test, CUDIT-r, COWS, ACSA, BDI-II.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the day of enrollment, study staff will confirm eligibility and transport patient to&#xD;
      hospital for admission. Participant will receive a test infusion of MA 30mg IV. If&#xD;
      participant tolerates test infusion within defined parameters, participant will be formally&#xD;
      enrolled and randomized. First dose of study drug will be administered the evening of&#xD;
      admission. On the fifth hospital day, participant will undergo MA challenge (single-blind&#xD;
      placebo and 30mg IV for subjective, cardiovascular, and PK assessments). PK draws will&#xD;
      continue for 48 hours after infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant will begin the opposite condition on day 8 and complete the MA infusion&#xD;
      procedures on day 12. After completion of PK studies on day 14, participant will be&#xD;
      discharged.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A post-discharge safety check will be completed 10 days after discharge (+/- 7 days).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 12, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety Measures</measure>
    <time_frame>24 Days</time_frame>
    <description>QT interval associated with combined use of methamphetamine and mirtazapine with and without concomitant methadone use</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Metabolism of methamphetamine in presence of steady state mirtazapine</measure>
    <time_frame>14 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Metabolism of methamphetamine in combination with mirtazapine Pharmacokinetics of methamphetamine in combination with mirtazapine with or without concomitant methadone use</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact of mirtazapine on subjective effects of methamphetamine reinforcement</measure>
    <time_frame>14 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Subjective effects questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact of mirtazapine on mood produced by methamphetamine use</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Addiction Research Inventory short form</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Urge for stimulant use in the presence of mirtazapine</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Methamphetamine-based Questionnaire for Stimulant Urges</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Preference for methamphetamine in the presence of mirtazapine</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Drug Purchase Task</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact of mirtazapine on discounting in the presence of methamphetamine</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Delayed Discounting assessment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Methamphetamine Use Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Drug Interaction</condition>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Abnormalities</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mirtazapine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Mirtazapine 30 mg PO daily x 4 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo 30 mg PO Daily x 4 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mirtazapine</intervention_name>
    <description>Mirtazapine 30 mg PO daily x 4 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mirtazapine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Methamphetamine</intervention_name>
    <description>Methamphetamine 30 mg IV once</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mirtazapine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. English-speaking;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. age 18-55 years inclusive;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. meet DSM-V criteria for MA use disorder, as diagnosed via SCID;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. provide MA-positive urine during screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. have a resting heart rate of 50-90&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. have a systolic blood pressure ≤ of 100-150 mm Hg, and diastolic blood pressure of&#xD;
             45-90 Hg within two days prior to admission;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. have a baseline EKG that demonstrates normal sinus rhythm, QTc &lt; 440 msec in men or&#xD;
             QTc &lt; 450 msec in women;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. have acceptable safety lab data, ALT / AST&lt;3x upper limit nL; est GFR &gt;50;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. if female (except females of non-childbearing potential-e.g., at least 1 year&#xD;
             post-menopausal or surgically sterile), not pregnant confirmed by negative pregnancy&#xD;
             test nor lactating and willing to use a medically approved method of birth control to&#xD;
             prevent pregnancy during the trial and for 7 days after the last dose of study&#xD;
             medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
        10) For those who also use opioids and are on methadone maintenance treatment (Group 2),&#xD;
        urine positive for methadone and negative for buprenorphine on admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Have current cocaine, cannabis, or alcohol use disorder by DSM-V SCID;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. current or past history of seizure disorder;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. current ongoing treatment with psychotropic medications (e.g. antidepressants,&#xD;
             antipsychotics, antiepileptics, sedative/hypnotics, narcotic analgesics);&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. urine positive for MA and other unplanned drugs on the day of admission and&#xD;
             breathalyzer results negative for alcohol;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. any prior adverse reaction to MA; including chest pain or epileptic seizure;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. major psychiatric disorder not due to substance abuse (e.g., schizophrenia, bipolar&#xD;
             illness but excepting stable major depressive disorder, generalized anxiety disorder,&#xD;
             etc.) as assessed by the SCID;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. have a current neurological disorder (e.g., organic brain disease, dementia) or&#xD;
             medical condition which would make study compliance difficult or compromise informed&#xD;
             consent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. history of suicide attempt(s) in the past 90 days or current suicidal intent or plan&#xD;
             by SCID;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. evidence of untreated or unstable serious medical illness including: neuroendocrine,&#xD;
             autoimmune, renal, hepatic, or active infectious disease including active tuberculosis&#xD;
             infection;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. seeking treatment for MA problems at the time of the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. any serious medical or psychiatric AE after test infusion of MA 30mg IV (e.g.&#xD;
             sustained SBP&gt;200 or DBP&gt;100; sustained pulse &gt;(220-0.85xAge).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. any other circumstances that, in the opinion of the investigators, would compromise&#xD;
             participant safety and/or successful completion of the trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Phillip Coffin, MD, MIA</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Director, Substance Use Division, San Francisco Department of Public Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Phillip Coffin, MD, MIA</last_name>
    <phone>628-217-6282</phone>
    <email>phillip.coffin@sfdph.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>John Walker, MSN</last_name>
    <phone>628-217-6282</phone>
    <email>john.e.walker@sfdph.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCLA Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90095</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Steven Shoptaw, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>323-461-3106</phone>
      <email>sshoptaw@mednet.ucla.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Jesse Clark, MD, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>323-461-3106</phone>
      <email>jlclark@mednet.ucla.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Steven Shoptaw, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jesse Clark, MD, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>San Francisco Department of Public Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94102</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Phillip Coffin, MD</last_name>
      <phone>628-217-6282</phone>
      <email>phillip.coffin@sfdph.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Substance Use Research Unit</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94102</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>John Walker, MSN</last_name>
      <email>john.e.walker@sfdph.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Phillip Coffin, MD, MIA</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>San Francisco Department of Public Health</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Phillip Coffin, MD, MIA</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of Substance Use Research</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Methamphetamine</keyword>
  <keyword>Mirtazapine</keyword>
  <keyword>Methadone</keyword>
  <keyword>Drug Interaction</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cardiovascular Abnormalities</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mirtazapine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methamphetamine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

