<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04615559</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HS-20-00428</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04615559</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Contrast Enhanced Ultrasound Endoleak Identification and Classification</brief_title>
  <official_title>Contrast Enhanced Ultrasound Endoleak Identification and Classification Compared to Computed Tomography in High-risk Complicated Aneurysm Repair Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Southern California</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Southern California</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Surgery for abdominal aortic pathology usually occurs in the setting of advanced&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease. The repair can be relatively simple or complex with multiple steps&#xD;
      including open repair, placing a stent with a catheter, and placing a complicated stent that&#xD;
      allows for crossing vessels without occluding them. All these repairs require imaging follow&#xD;
      up. The most commonly accepted tool for follow up is Computed Tomography (CT) scan which&#xD;
      involves ionizing radiation and potentially nephrotoxic iodinated contrast. Recommendations&#xD;
      for the time interval for follow up, as well the radiology imaging technique vary. Routine&#xD;
      ultrasound with Doppler, CT, and MRI has all been employed utilizing various imaging&#xD;
      protocols. Clinicians use non-contrast CT, arterial phase and delayed phase CT, ultrasound,&#xD;
      and various combinations based on personal experience and patient pathology. Concerns over&#xD;
      cost, potential nephrotoxicity of contrast agents and repeated radiation exposure has led to&#xD;
      investigation of alternate imaging modalities such as contrast-enhanced ultrasound (CEUS).&#xD;
      CEUS represents an improvement of ultrasound imaging but comparisons against CT report widely&#xD;
      varying results, likely due to technical factors of CEUS and limitations of single-phase CTA.&#xD;
      Contrast ultrasound has been used effectively to diagnose leaks in the aorta post repair and&#xD;
      is without the radiation and potential nephrotoxicity of iodinated contrast. Of yet, no large&#xD;
      prospective studies have compared CT and contrast US and no studies have looked at the more&#xD;
      complicated staged or fenestrated repairs. This study proposes to perform a contrast&#xD;
      ultrasound at the same time as a contrast CT using a standardized protocol. This protocol&#xD;
      would include a non-contrast CT, angiographic CT, and a CT in a delayed phase in all patients&#xD;
      as standard of care. We will compare the results of a contrast US with the various data&#xD;
      derived from a three phase CT.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction: Surgery for abdominal aortic pathology usually occurs in the setting of&#xD;
      advanced cardiovascular disease. The repair can be relatively simple or complex with multiple&#xD;
      steps including open repair, placing a stent with a catheter, and placing a complicated stent&#xD;
      that allows for crossing vessels without occluding them. All these repairs require imaging&#xD;
      follow up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rationale: The most commonly accepted tool for follow up is Computed Tomography (CT) scan&#xD;
      which involves ionizing radiation and potentially nephrotoxic iodinated contrast. Routine&#xD;
      ultrasound with Doppler, CT, and MRI has all been employed utilizing various imaging&#xD;
      protocols. Concerns over cost, potential nephrotoxicity of contrast agents and repeated&#xD;
      radiation exposure has led to investigation of alternate imaging modalities such as contrast&#xD;
      enhanced ultrasound (CEUS). CEUS also allows continuous (dynamic) or real-time monitoring of&#xD;
      the aneurysm and endoleak throughout the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1: To determine the consistency/discrepancy of endoleak detection (positive/negative) for&#xD;
      contrast enhanced ultrasound (CEUS) versus various phases of CTA versus delayed phase CTA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2 (Exploratory): To explore the consistency/discrepancy of endoleak type (type 1-5)&#xD;
      between CEUS and delayed phase CTA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 3 (Exploratory): To explore the consistency/discrepancy of endoleak source detected&#xD;
      (positive/negative for each source) for type II endoleaks between CEUS and CTA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 4 (Exploratory): Re-assess Aims 1-3 for the follow-up scans. The goal for this aim is to&#xD;
      examine whether the consistency/discrepancy patterns discovered in Aims 1-3 can be repeated&#xD;
      at the follow-up scans.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Population: 40 patients who have undergone an EVAR or FEVAR for abdominal aortic aneurysms&#xD;
      and are expected to have CTA as part of their standard of care will be enrolled in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology: Patients will be evaluated with research contrast ultrasound at one month&#xD;
      post-op, six months post-op and at one year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Analysis Plan: Binomial 95% confidence interval will be calculated for sensitivity and&#xD;
      specificity. One- sided binomial test will be conducted to test whether the target&#xD;
      sensitivity and specificity are superior to the null value, e.g. a minimal acceptable level&#xD;
      of sensitivity and specificity. In detecting the rate of endoleak positive on CEUS or other&#xD;
      phases of the CTA but negative on CTA in the delayed phase, we will compute Clopper Pearson&#xD;
      Exact 95% confidence interval since such a rate could be small. To assess consistency of&#xD;
      endoleak type (type 1-5) between CEUS and delayed phase CTA, Kappa coefficient will be used.&#xD;
      In the situation with high agreement biased towards one endoleak type, or extremely&#xD;
      unbalanced distribution of endoleak types, prevalence-adjusted bias-adjusted kappa&#xD;
      coefficient (PABAK) (Byrt, Bishop, and Carlin 1993) will be used. The discrepancy of endoleak&#xD;
      type between CEUS and delayed phase CTA will be reported as rate, for example percent of case&#xD;
      rated as type 1 in CTA but type 2 in delayed phase, with Clopper Pearson Exact 95% confidence&#xD;
      interval. SAS9.4 will be used for all statistical analyses.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the sensitivity and specificity for CEUS and various CTA phases when using delay phase of CTA as the gold standard</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Binomial 95% confidence interval will be calculated for sensitivity and specificity. One- sided binomial test will be conducted to test whether the target sensitivity and specificity are superior to the null value, e.g. a minimal acceptable level of sensitivity and specificity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Is there any endoleak positive on CEUS or various phases of the CTA but negative on CTA in the delayed phase</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>In detecting the rate of endoleak positive on CEUS or other phases of the CTA but negative on CTA in the delayed phase, we will compute Clopper Pearson Exact 95% confidence interval since such a rate could be small. To assess consistency of endoleak type (type 1-5) between CEUS and delayed phase CTA, Kappa coefficient will be used.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Abdominal Aortic Aneurysm</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>contrast enhanced ultrasound</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>CEUS will be performed at one month post-op, six months post-op and at one year.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Contrast enhanced ultrasound</intervention_name>
    <description>CEUS involves the use of microbubble contrast agents and specialized imaging techniques to enhance the signal from blood, thus showing flow in macroscopic vessels as well as tissue perfusion information</description>
    <arm_group_label>contrast enhanced ultrasound</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Aged 18 or over 2. Able to give informed consent 3. Undergone an EVAR or FEVAR for&#xD;
             abdominal aortic aneurysms 4. Expected to have CTA&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to receive CTA (Contrast Allergy, Insufficient renal function for standard&#xD;
             outpatient contrast study (eGFR &lt;30) Overactive thyroid gland)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to receive CEUS contrast, previous reaction to Ultrasound Contrast Agent (UCA)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI &gt;50&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Edward Grant</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Southern California</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bhushan Desai</last_name>
    <phone>323-865-9949</phone>
    <email>bhushan.desai@med.usc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sanjna Mani</last_name>
    <email>sanjna.mani@med.usc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>USC Department of Radiology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90033</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 28, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 28, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Southern California</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Edward Grant</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Clinical Radiology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Aneurysm</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Aortic Aneurysm</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Aortic Aneurysm, Abdominal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endoleak</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

