<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04616118</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-300005184</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04616118</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparing Modes of Telehealth Delivery: Phone vs. Video Visits (ASSIST)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparing Modes of Telehealth Delivery:Phone vs. Video Visits</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alabama at Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alabama at Birmingham</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Given the current public health crisis the use of telehealth consultation visits including&#xD;
      phone-only and video visits has exponentially increased. This study will investigate if the&#xD;
      conduct of telehealth phone only visits is non-inferior in terms of patient&#xD;
      satisfaction/experience, adherence to post-visit recommendations such as medications, blood&#xD;
      work and other medical testing, follow up care, when compared to the conduct of video&#xD;
      delivered telehealth visits. Patients will be randomized to receive a routine care visit via&#xD;
      phone only vs. video.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Telemedicine and an emerging field of novel care delivery modalities, which encompasses all&#xD;
      forms of remote-based care. These include asynchronous (store-and-forward) and consultative&#xD;
      care by specialists, mobile-device based care, and real-time video chat, and synchronous&#xD;
      telemedicine. Health care services delivered remotely through telecommunications and video&#xD;
      technology is steadily increasing as technology evolves and access becomes more widely&#xD;
      available. The increasing availability of personal technology - 89% Americans have internet&#xD;
      access, 77% are online daily - offers patients and clinicians the opportunity to utilize&#xD;
      real-time virtual communication to enhance access for patients when transportation&#xD;
      challenges, schedules, or physical disability make office visits difficult in any geography.&#xD;
      With the increased use of technology in healthcare, much emphasis has been placed on&#xD;
      telemedicine as it can extend the services of providers to remote locations and overcome the&#xD;
      barrier of proximity. This expands access to care and has the potential of making healthcare&#xD;
      services more convenient for many patients who otherwise might suffer access barriers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is increasingly evident that telehealth can improve access to healthcare services and&#xD;
      specialists; prevent unnecessary delays in receiving care, and facilitate coordinated care&#xD;
      and interprofessional collaboration. The World Health Organization affirms the efficacy of&#xD;
      telehealth as an effective service delivery model for professionals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Telemedicine has been shown to improve health outcomes, increase communication with&#xD;
      providers, increase access to high-quality service, decrease travel time, decrease missed&#xD;
      appointments, decrease wait time, decrease repeat admissions, increase self-awareness,&#xD;
      increase medication adherence, and increase self-monitoring of chronic conditions. The&#xD;
      technical quality of telehealth consultation (e.g. audio and visual quality of a&#xD;
      videoconference) has been shown to influence clinicians' willingness to practice in this&#xD;
      manner and the satisfaction of users. A recent systematic review on patient satisfaction with&#xD;
      telemedicine found that patient satisfaction can be associated with the modality of&#xD;
      telehealth, but factors of effectiveness and efficiency are mixed. Telehealth is a feasible&#xD;
      option to expand practices to remote areas without having to relocate or expand.&#xD;
      Understanding the perceived relative value of different modes of healthcare services may help&#xD;
      to shape the use of virtual or remote healthcare technologies. System learning that&#xD;
      demonstrates the value of different types of &quot;visits&quot; for the system and the patient is&#xD;
      essential.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 27, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>36 hours post visit</time_frame>
    <description>Patient satisfaction with type of visit. Satisfaction will be measured using the 11-point ARHQ-CAHPS patient satisfaction instrument.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">269</enrollment>
  <condition>Rheumatic Disease</condition>
  <condition>Cardiac Disease</condition>
  <condition>Primary Care</condition>
  <condition>Infectious Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomized to this arm will receive usual care via telephone only</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Video</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomized to this arm will receive usual care via video call</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Phone Visit</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants randomized to this arm will receive usual care via telephone only</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Video Visit</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants randomized to this arm will receive usual care via video call</description>
    <arm_group_label>Video</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to a phone and video call capacity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A minimum of 1 visits in the last year with their provider&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medicare/Medicaid eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        •Individuals not meeting inclusion criteria&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Maria Danila, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama at Birmingham</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35294</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Donelan K, Barreto EA, Sossong S, Michael C, Estrada JJ, Cohen AB, Wozniak J, Schwamm LH. Patient and clinician experiences with telehealth for patient follow-up care. Am J Manag Care. 2019 Jan;25(1):40-44.</citation>
    <PMID>30667610</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wade V, Smith AC. Research methods and methodology in telemedicine. J Telemed Telecare. 2017 Oct;23(9):757-758. doi: 10.1177/1357633X17733088.</citation>
    <PMID>29070002</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Batsis JA, Pletcher SN, Stahl JE. Telemedicine and primary care obesity management in rural areas - innovative approach for older adults? BMC Geriatr. 2017 Jan 5;17(1):6. doi: 10.1186/s12877-016-0396-x.</citation>
    <PMID>28056832</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wade VA, Eliott JA, Hiller JE. Clinician acceptance is the key factor for sustainable telehealth services. Qual Health Res. 2014 May;24(5):682-94. doi: 10.1177/1049732314528809. Epub 2014 Mar 31.</citation>
    <PMID>24685708</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kruse CS, Soma M, Pulluri D, Nemali NT, Brooks M. The effectiveness of telemedicine in the management of chronic heart disease - a systematic review. JRSM Open. 2017 Feb 1;8(3):2054270416681747. doi: 10.1177/2054270416681747. eCollection 2017 Mar.</citation>
    <PMID>28321319</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Maria Danila, MD, MSc, MSPH</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rheumatic Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Collagen Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

