<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04615273</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TCH-306</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-000929-42</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04615273</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Trial to Compare the Efficacy and Safety of Once-weekly Lonapegsomatropin With Placebo and a Daily Somatropin Product in Adults With Growth Hormone Deficiency</brief_title>
  <acronym>foresiGHt</acronym>
  <official_title>foresiGHt: A Multicenter, Randomized, Parallel-arm, Placebo-controlled (Double- Blind) and Active-controlled (Open-label) Trial to Compare the Efficacy and Safety of Once-weekly Lonapegsomatropin With Placebo and a Daily Somatropin Product in Adults With Growth Hormone Deficiency</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ascendis Pharma Endocrinology Division A/S</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ascendis Pharma A/S</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A 38 week dosing trial of lonapegsomatropin, a long-acting growth hormone product,&#xD;
      administered once-a-week versus placebo-control. A daily somatropin product arm is also&#xD;
      included to assist clinical judgement on the trial results. Approximately 240 adults (males&#xD;
      and females) with growth hormone deficiency will be included. Randomization will occur in a&#xD;
      1:1:1 ratio (lonapegsomatropin : placebo : daily somatropin product). This is a global trial&#xD;
      that will be conducted in, but not limited to, the United States, Europe, and Asia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 3, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel group with subjects randomized into 3 treatment groups (1:1:1); lonapegsomatropin once-weekly, placebo for lonapegsomatropin once-weekly, somatropin daily.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Once-weekly lonapegsomatropin and once-weekly placebo treatment arms will be double-blinded, daily somatropin product will be open-label.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Trunk Percent Fat</measure>
    <time_frame>38 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in trunk percent fat (as assessed by dual-energy x ray absorptiometry [DXA]) at Week 38</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Treatment-Emergent Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>38 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the safety and tolerability of once-weekly lonapegsomatropin in adults with GHD</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate serum hGH, lonapegsomatropin, and mPEG levels</measure>
    <time_frame>38 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the pharmacokinetics (PK) of once-weekly lonapegsomatropin in adults with GHD</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate serum IGF-1 and IGFBP-3 and IGF-1 SDS and IGFBP-3 SDS</measure>
    <time_frame>38 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the pharmacodynamics (PD) of once-weekly lonapegsomatropin in adults with GHD</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Trunk Fat Mass</measure>
    <time_frame>38 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in trunk percent fat (as assessed by dual-energy x ray absorptiometry [DXA]) compared to daily Somatropin at Week 38</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Total Body Lean Mass</measure>
    <time_frame>38 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in total body lean mass (as assessed by dual-energy x ray absorptiometry [DXA]) compared to daily Somatropin at Week 38</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">240</enrollment>
  <condition>Growth Hormone Deficiency</condition>
  <condition>Endocrine System Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Hormone Deficiency</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lonapegsomatropin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Lonapegsomatropin administered once-weekly by subcutaneous injection</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo for Lonapegsomatropin administered once-weekly by subcutaneous injection</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Somatropin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Somatropin administered once-daily by subcutaneous injection</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lonapegsomatropin</intervention_name>
    <description>Due to the different hGH dose requirements, depending on subject's age and concomitant use of oral estrogen, this trial has 3 dosing groups per arm, followed by gradual increasing dose titration to a target maintenance dose.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lonapegsomatropin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>The placebo for lonapegsomatropin drug product will contain the same excipients as lonapegsomatropin drug product but does not contain lonapegsomatropin itself. The placebo solution will be administered by SC injection via syringe and needle. Due to the different hGH dose requirements, depending on subject's age and concomitant use of oral estrogen, this trial has 3 dosing groups and the placebo will receive the same dose volume as if they would have been randomized to once-weekly lonapegsomatropin.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Somatropin</intervention_name>
    <description>Somatropin solution is provided in a pre-filled pen intended for daily subcutaneous injection. Due to the different hGH dose requirements, depending on subject's age and concomitant use of oral estrogen, this trial has 3 dosing groups per arm, followed by gradual increasing dose titration to a target maintenance dose.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Somatropin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age between 23 and 75 years, inclusive, at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. AGHD Diagnosis Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
             For adult-onset AGHD: documented history of structural hypothalamic-pituitary disease,&#xD;
             hypothalamic-pituitary surgery, cranial irradiation, 1-4 non-GH pituitary hormone&#xD;
             deficiencies, a proven genetic cause of GHD, or traumatic brain injury (TBI).&#xD;
&#xD;
             A. For all countries except Japan: Subjects must satisfy at least one of the following&#xD;
             criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Insulin tolerance test: peak GH ≤5 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Glucagon stimulation test according to body mass index (BMI)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  i. BMI ≤30 kg/m2: peak GH ≤3 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  ii. BMI &gt;30 kg/m2: peak GH ≤1 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Three or four pituitary axis deficiencies (i.e., adrenal, thyroid, gonadal,&#xD;
                  and/or vasopressin; not including GH) with IGF-1 SDS ≤ -2.0 at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Macimorelin test: peak GH ≤2.8 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Growth hormone releasing hormone (GHRH) + arginine test according to BMI:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  i. BMI &lt;25 kg/m2, peak GH &lt;11 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  ii. BMI ≥25-≤30 kg/m2, peak GH &lt;8 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  iii. BMI &gt;30 kg/m2, peak GH &lt;4 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
             B. For Japan only: Subjects with adult onset AGHD and deficiency of one or more other&#xD;
             pituitary hormones need to satisfy at least one of the following criteria, while&#xD;
             subjects with isolated GHD and no evidence of intracranial structure disorder&#xD;
             (structural hypothalamic-pituitary disease) or with adult onset AGHD without&#xD;
             deficiency of other pituitary hormones need to satisfy at least 2 of the following&#xD;
             criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Insulin tolerance test: peak GH ≤1.8 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Glucagon test: peak GH ≤1.8 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Growth Hormone Releasing Peptide-2 (GHRP-2) tolerance test: peak GH ≤9 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. IGF-1 SDS ≤ -1.0 at screening as measured by central laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. hGH treatment naïve or no exposure to hGH therapy or GH secretagogue for at least 12&#xD;
             months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. For subjects on hormone replacement therapies for any hormone deficiencies other than&#xD;
             GH (e.g., adrenal, thyroid, estrogen, testosterone) must be on adequate and stable&#xD;
             doses for ≥6 weeks prior to and throughout screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. For subjects not on glucocorticoid replacement therapy, documentation of adequate&#xD;
             adrenal function at screening defined.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. For males not on testosterone replacement therapy: morning (6:00 - 10:00AM) total&#xD;
             testosterone within normal limits for age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. On a stable diet and exercise regime at screening with no intention to modify diet or&#xD;
             exercise pattern during the trial, i.e., no weight reduction program intended during&#xD;
             the trial or within the last 90 days prior to or through screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. No plans to undergo bariatric surgery during the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Normal fundoscopy at screening (without signs/symptoms of intracranial hypertension or&#xD;
             diabetic retinopathy above stage 2 / moderate). For subjects with a diagnosis of&#xD;
             diabetes mellitus at screening, this must be documented with a fundus photograph.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Able and willing to provide a written informed consent and authorization for protected&#xD;
             health information (PHI) disclosure in accordance with Good Clinical Practice (GCP).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Known Prader-Willi Syndrome and/or other genetic diseases that may have an impact on&#xD;
             an endpoint.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Diabetes mellitus at screening if any of the following criteria are met:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Poorly controlled diabetes, defined as HbA1c &gt;7.5% at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Diabetes mellitus (defined as HbA1c ≥6.5% and/or fasting plasma glucose ≥126&#xD;
                  mg/dL and/or plasma glucose ≥200 mg/dL two hours after oral glucose tolerance&#xD;
                  test) diagnosed &lt;26 weeks prior to screening&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Change in diabetes regimen (includes dose adjustment) within &lt;90 days prior and&#xD;
                  throughout screening&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Use of any diabetes drugs other than metformin and/or DPP-4 inhibitors for a&#xD;
                  cumulative duration of greater than 4 weeks within 12 months prior to screening&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Diabetes-related complications at screening (i.e., nephropathy as judged by the&#xD;
                  investigator, neuropathy requiring pharmacological treatment, retinopathy stage 2&#xD;
                  / moderate and above within 90 days prior to screening or during screening)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Active malignant disease or history of malignancy. Exceptions to this exclusion&#xD;
             criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Resection of in situ carcinoma of the cervix uteri&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Complete eradication of squamous cell or basal cell carcinoma of the skin&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Subjects with GHD attributed to treatment of intracranial malignant tumors or&#xD;
                  leukemia, provided that a recurrence-free survival period of at least 5 years&#xD;
                  prior to screening is documented in the subject's file based on a Magnetic&#xD;
                  Resonance Imaging (MRI) result&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Evidence of growth of pituitary adenoma or other benign intracranial tumor within the&#xD;
             last 12 months before screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects with acromegaly without remission / with documented remission less than 24&#xD;
             months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects with Cushing's disease without remission / with documented remission less&#xD;
             than 24 months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects with prior cranial irradiation or hypothalamic-pituitary surgery: the&#xD;
             procedure took place less than 12 months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. eGFR &lt;60 mL/min/1.73m2 determined based on Modification of Diet in Renal Disease&#xD;
             (MDRD) equation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Hepatic transaminases (i.e., AST or ALT) &gt;3 times the upper limit of normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Heart failure NYHA class 3 or greater (NYHA 1994).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. QTcF ≥ 451 milliseconds on 12-lead ECG at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Poorly controlled hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Cerebrovascular accident within 5 years prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Anabolic steroids (other than gonadal steroid replacement therapy) or&#xD;
             oral/intravenous/intramuscular corticosteroids within 90 days prior to or throughout&#xD;
             screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Currently using or have used within 26 weeks prior to screening any weight-loss or&#xD;
             appetite-suppressive medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Known history of hypersensitivity and/or idiosyncrasy to any of the test compounds&#xD;
             (somatropin) or excipients employed in this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Known history of neutralizing anti-hGH antibodies.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Inability to undergo scanning by DXA or a non-interpretable DXA scan at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Female who is pregnant, breast-feeding or intends to become pregnant or is of&#xD;
             childbearing potential and not using adequate contraceptive methods&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Male subjects must use a condom, or his female partner of childbearing potential must&#xD;
             use an effective form of contraception as described above, from the beginning of&#xD;
             screening to the last trial visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Known substance abuse or known (or previous) eating disorders, including anorexia&#xD;
             nervosa, bulimia and severe gastrointestinal disease affecting normal eating (as&#xD;
             judged by the investigator).&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Any disease or condition that, in the judgement of the investigator, may make the&#xD;
             subject unlikely to comply with the requirements of the trial or any condition that&#xD;
             presents undue risk from the investigational product or procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Participation in another interventional clinical trial involving an investigational&#xD;
             compound within 26 weeks prior to screening or in parallel to this trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>23 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Michael Beckert, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+49 172-155-2596</phone>
    <email>mb@ascendispharma.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Aimee D Shu, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+1 650-461-4835</phone>
    <email>ads@ascendispharma.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascendis Pharma Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fresno</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>93720</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascendis Pharma Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90095</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascendis Pharma Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascendis Pharma Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dearborn</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48126</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascendis Pharma Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Las Vegas</city>
        <state>Nevada</state>
        <zip>89148</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascendis Pharma Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Reno</city>
        <state>Nevada</state>
        <zip>89511</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascendis Pharma Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10016</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascendis Pharma Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Morehead City</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28557</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascendis Pharma Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>92739</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascendis Pharma Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15212</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascendis Pharma Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75390</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascendis Pharma Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77074</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascendis Pharma Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Human Growth Hormone</keyword>
  <keyword>hGH</keyword>
  <keyword>rhGH</keyword>
  <keyword>GHD</keyword>
  <keyword>Adult Growth Hormone Deficiency</keyword>
  <keyword>Long Acting Growth Hormone</keyword>
  <keyword>Lonapegsomatropin</keyword>
  <keyword>Prodrug</keyword>
  <keyword>Growth Failure</keyword>
  <keyword>Growth Hormone Replacement Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Sustained Release Growth Hormone</keyword>
  <keyword>Growth Hormone Deficiency</keyword>
  <keyword>TransCon hGH</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dwarfism, Pituitary</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endocrine System Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

