<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03135366</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HarvardU</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03135366</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Self-verification and Support Via Mobile Phones Drastically Improves Tuberculosis Treatment Success in LMIC Settings</brief_title>
  <official_title>Delivering Community-based Interventions and Disease Management Tools Across a Digital Platform in Order to Increase TB Treatment Adherence in LMICs</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United States Agency for International Development (USAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Keheala</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>MIT's Applied Cooperation Team</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Kenya National Tuberculosis, Leprosy and Lung Disease Program</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Each year, 10.4 million patients are diagnosed with and 1.8 million people die from&#xD;
      Tuberculosis (TB). Despite the availability of highly effective and accessible medications in&#xD;
      the developing world where TB is endemic, the 6-18 month treatment regimen is often thwarted&#xD;
      as patients fail to comply due to a lack of knowledge about the disease, desire for privacy,&#xD;
      and/or stigma avoidance. Inappropriate medication use leading to multi-drug resistant (MDR)&#xD;
      TB infects 5% of all TB patients, yet accounts for a significant proportion of all spending.&#xD;
      In Kenya, the burden of TB is among the highest in the world with a prevalence rate of 558&#xD;
      cases per 100,000 people. There is a great need for the development of alternative protocols,&#xD;
      which reduce the costs of treatment and burden of adherence, and more effectively motivate&#xD;
      patients to adhere to the program. A substantial and growing literature in the social&#xD;
      sciences demonstrates the potential of behavioral interventions for generating large&#xD;
      increases in contributions to public goods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This 1200 participant, Randomized Controlled Trial (RCT) explores the capacity of Keheala, a&#xD;
      feature-phone and Internet-based digital platform that uses Unstructured Supplementary&#xD;
      Service Data (USSD) technology, to deliver behavioral interventions for improving treatment&#xD;
      adherence, outcomes and quality of life for TB patients in Nairobi, Kenya. Keheala taps into&#xD;
      this underutilized potential by developing a powerful, cost-effective platform for better&#xD;
      engaging patients' sense of responsibility to their community in order to increase adherence.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Tuberculosis (TB) is the deadliest infectious disease in the world. The latest estimates&#xD;
      suggest there were 10.4 million cases in 2015 and 1.8 million TB deaths. Despite the&#xD;
      availability of highly effective medications for treating TB in the developing world, lack of&#xD;
      adherence to the treatment regimen remains the driving influence leading to multi-drug&#xD;
      resistant (MDR) TB, morbidity and mortality. Conventional treatment is a lengthy process&#xD;
      which depends heavily on patient adherence in seeking and then carrying out the prescribed&#xD;
      treatment. Recognizing this challenge, the World Health Organization has developed a protocol&#xD;
      for treating TB called Direct Observation of Treatments, Short-course (DOTS), but it is&#xD;
      expensive and difficult to institute on a large-scale in resource-constrained regions,&#xD;
      evidenced by its use in only 30% of all cases. This protocol also further burdens TB patients&#xD;
      who are already some of the most marginalized individuals in society by requiring them to&#xD;
      take time off from work in order to travel to the TB clinic for treatment verification. The&#xD;
      patient may find this embarrassing if there is a stigma surrounding the disease in the&#xD;
      community, or at the least, an unwelcomed intrusion into one's privacy. There is therefore&#xD;
      great need for the development of alternative protocols, which reduce the costs of treatment&#xD;
      and burden of adherence, and more effectively motivate patients to adhere to the program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TB is spread through the air when people who are sick with TB excrete the causative bacillus,&#xD;
      Mycobacterium tuberculosis mainly through coughing. Left untreated, a single patient can&#xD;
      infect between 12 and 15 persons per year, a stark contrast to an Ebola patient who will only&#xD;
      infect between 1.5 and 2.5 persons. When a patient adheres to the treatment regime, she makes&#xD;
      it less likely that others will become sick, contributing to the health of her family and&#xD;
      community. Adherence is thus a contribution to a public good--a personally costly action that&#xD;
      benefits others. A substantial and growing literature in the social sciences demonstrates the&#xD;
      potential of behavioral interventions for generating large increases in contributions to&#xD;
      public goods, yet this potential has largely been left untapped in the treatment of TB.&#xD;
      Keheala taps into this underutilized potential by developing a powerful, cost-effective&#xD;
      platform for better engaging patients' sense of responsibility to their community in order to&#xD;
      increase adherence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Keheala is a feature-phone and Internet-based digital platform that uses text message-like&#xD;
      interactions to deliver behavioral interventions that have been demonstrated as remarkably&#xD;
      effective in the social sciences literature on altruism. A patient who participates in the&#xD;
      program is assigned a support-sponsor who receives alerts about the patient's adherence,&#xD;
      allowing a dialogue of support or problem solving. For the pilot RCT, these support-sponsors&#xD;
      will be hired and trained by Keheala. An automated system sends motivational messages and&#xD;
      regular prompts for patients to self-verify their treatment. Messages include reminders about&#xD;
      the community benefits of adherence and a measure of the patient's adherence performance&#xD;
      relative to successful peers. If a patient fails to correctly verify her compliance, the&#xD;
      system automatically alerts the support-sponsor, who then intervenes with a supportive&#xD;
      dialogue. Clinicians can view individual or aggregate patient histories to leverage limited&#xD;
      resources. Combining powerful behavioral interventions with the functionality needed to&#xD;
      lessen the burden of disease on everyday life, Keheala uniquely and comprehensively overcomes&#xD;
      the barriers to appropriate treatment adherence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Problem Statement TB treatment adherence rates suffer due to the burdensome six-month&#xD;
      duration of treatment. During this period, patients endure severe side effects from drug&#xD;
      cocktails, while regular clinical visits often necessitate distant, time-consuming travel and&#xD;
      absenteeism from work. However, non-adherence not only threatens the individuals' health--70%&#xD;
      of those who aren't treated will die within 10 years --it is also a public health concern:&#xD;
      adherence reduces the risk of transmission, usually to nearly zero within less than two&#xD;
      weeks, whereas treatment cessation can lead to recurrence and high transmission rates,&#xD;
      threatening the well-being of affected communities. Keheala's goal is to increase adherence&#xD;
      for the benefit of the infected individual and the community as a whole.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Justification The Keheala solution is based on extensive primary and secondary research.&#xD;
      Interviews with relevant and experienced stakeholders ensured that the functionality provided&#xD;
      is what actually is needed in order to overcome the social drivers of failed treatment&#xD;
      adherence. Additionally, the functionality is designed with principles from the social&#xD;
      sciences literature showing the potent impact invoking an individual's sense of&#xD;
      responsibility to her community can have on affecting behavior. These principles are&#xD;
      well-supported and understood in other contexts, however, exactly how effective these&#xD;
      principles can be at invoking treatment adhering behavior in the resource-constrained TB&#xD;
      context remains to be tested.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Null Hypotheses Ha1: Patients enrolled in the Keheala program achieve a greater proportion of&#xD;
      'Cured' outcomes by at least 7.5%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ho1: Patients enrolled in the Keheala program achieve a greater proportion of 'Cured'&#xD;
      outcomes by no more than 7.5%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ha2: Patients enrolled in the Keheala program achieve an improvement of at least 7.5% on one&#xD;
      of the following outcomes: 'Treatment Completed,' 'Dying while on Treatment,' Out of Control&#xD;
      or Loss to Follow Up' and 'Failing'.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ho2: Patients enrolled in the Keheala program achieve an improvement of no more than 7.5% on&#xD;
      one of the following outcomes: 'Treatment Completed,' 'Dying while on Treatment,' Out of&#xD;
      Control or Loss to Follow Up' and 'Failing'.&#xD;
&#xD;
      General Objectives The goal of the research is to establish the potential of Keheala's&#xD;
      behavioral intervention for positively impacting the process of care and treatment outcomes&#xD;
      for a TB patient and healthcare providers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additional Qualitative Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Measure and compare the frequency and duration of treatment interruption&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Measure and compare perception of 'trust' for the healthcare system, as well as the&#xD;
           doctor-patient relationship&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Measure and compare the perception of community stigma&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design and Methodology Study site The burden of TB in Kenya is among the highest in the world&#xD;
      with a prevalence rate of 558 cases per 100,000 people. Mortality from TB in Kenya is also&#xD;
      above the global average at 21 deaths per 100,000.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Symptomatic patients are identified either in health clinics or by Community Health&#xD;
      Volunteers (CHVs), laypersons employed to screen for TB in the community. Individuals who&#xD;
      show up to the clinic usually do so because they are experiencing a sickness or have been&#xD;
      referred to the clinic. In rural communities, regularly scheduled meetings organized by local&#xD;
      chiefs or administrative officials are used as opportunities to educate the community about&#xD;
      TB and to sometimes distribute questionnaires probing symptoms of TB. Questionnaire&#xD;
      respondents who demonstrate signs of symptoms of TB are requested to give a sputum sample,&#xD;
      which will be tested at a health clinic and feedback given to the CHV in order to communicate&#xD;
      the results back to the individual and link them to a specific clinic if treatment is needed.&#xD;
      There are times, however, when finding the individual is not always possible. Additionally,&#xD;
      these CHVs will sometimes attend market days or go home to home in order to identify sick&#xD;
      individuals in the general population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Symptoms of TB include coughing for three weeks or longer, chest pain, coughing up blood or&#xD;
      sputum (phlegm from deep inside the lungs), weakness or fatigue, weight loss, appetite&#xD;
      suppression, fever and chills. Diagnosis is accomplished with sputum smears and sometimes&#xD;
      x-rays. Any individuals started on TB medication are entered into a paper log at each health&#xD;
      facility. Sub-county TB coordinators compile all of the paper logs every one to four weeks,&#xD;
      transferring them to a cloud-based digital form.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment duration is either six months (first-time patients) or eight months (repeat&#xD;
      patients). During the first two to three months when daily treatment is required, medications&#xD;
      are given for a week at a time or with special permission for longer than a week. For the&#xD;
      latter four or five months of treatment patients are required to return to the clinic every&#xD;
      two weeks for medication refills. Patients are supposed to visit clinics for medication&#xD;
      refills with their treatment supporter - a friend or relative who watches the patient take&#xD;
      their medication. However, clinicians do not go to the full-extent necessary to ensure the&#xD;
      sponsor has been observing a patient's adherence. Follow-up smears are given after two, five&#xD;
      and six months for patients who were initially smear positive. Upon completion of the&#xD;
      prescribed treatment regimen and a negative sputum smear, patients are released from&#xD;
      treatment and told only to come back if symptoms reappear.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will approach clinics in Nairobi in order of size. Clinics will be included&#xD;
      if there is substantial support for the program by the staff and the investigators believe&#xD;
      the intervention can be implemented with local support. The investigators will be randomizing&#xD;
      subjects into a treatment and control group within each clinic. The following clinics will be&#xD;
      approached:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Kasarani Health Centre&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. St. Mary's Mission Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Riruta Health Centre&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Kangemi Health Centre&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Kibera South (MSF Belgium) Dispensary&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Kayole II Sub-District Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Dandora II Health Centre&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Baraka Medical Centre (St. Stephen)&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Mukuru MMM Clinic&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Rhodes Chest Clinic&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Embakasi Health Centre&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Ngara Health Centre (City Council of Nairobi)&#xD;
&#xD;
       13. Umoja Health Centre&#xD;
&#xD;
       14. Kibera DO&#xD;
&#xD;
       15. Mathare North Health Centre&#xD;
&#xD;
       16. Kahawa West Health Centre&#xD;
&#xD;
       17. Kamiti Prison Public Hospital (not for inmates)&#xD;
&#xD;
      At each clinic, 50% of all TB patients will be randomly selected to join the treatment group:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Existing patients will be ordered by date and time admitted, and selected so that every&#xD;
           other patient is included in the treatment group (block design).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  New patients will be similarly selected so that every other new patient is included in&#xD;
           the treatment group (block design).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The control and treatment groups will thus each be made up of half the patients in the&#xD;
      clinics. Overall, the investigators expect the control and treatment group to be comprised of&#xD;
      600 subjects, each. Patients will not be offered a stipend for participation so as not to&#xD;
      introduce any unnecessary bias into the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Management A. Data collection and reduction Clinics will provide paper or digital copies&#xD;
      of patient medical records for Keheala staff to consolidate and digitize. Anonymous platform&#xD;
      usage data and analytics will be obtained from a dashboard.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Qualitative data will be obtained from a digitally administered survey across the mobile&#xD;
      platform and/or through focus group discussions and interviews.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B. Statistical Analysis The simplest possible statistical approach is illustrated in the&#xD;
      power calculations. In this approach, the investigators simply compare outcome rates at the&#xD;
      end of treatment for subjects in the treatment and control groups. This comparison can be&#xD;
      done using a t-test or using an ordinary least squares regression, which can include controls&#xD;
      for time trends, patient demographics, and clinic characteristics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will also employ a more sophisticated (and slightly more statistically&#xD;
      powerful) analysis of hazard rates. The hazard rate is estimated daily as the probability&#xD;
      that a patient who is currently adhering continues to adhere. It is estimated using a&#xD;
      logistical regression of whether the patient adhered on a given week on whether the patient&#xD;
      adhered in all previous weeks and whether the patient is in the treatment group. The&#xD;
      regression can also include controls for time period, patient demographics, and clinic&#xD;
      characteristics. Note that the investigators have based the power calculations on the simpler&#xD;
      regressions of final outcomes on treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      C. Data Storage During the study patient names and clinics are kept in an encrypted and&#xD;
      password protected 'Master Document'. At the end of the pilot, all personal identifying&#xD;
      information will be redacted and patients will be uniquely identified by a randomly generated&#xD;
      identification number. No documents or data containing patient identifying information (name&#xD;
      and/or address) will be available to outside parties.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethical Considerations&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators recognize that dealing with human subjects necessitates the highest level&#xD;
      of respect for persons. Accordingly, in order to ensure the autonomy of the individual, each&#xD;
      patient will receive a full disclosure of the nature of the study, the risks, benefits and&#xD;
      alternatives, with an extended opportunity to ask questions. Patients with diminished&#xD;
      autonomy (children) will not be coerced to participate. Instead, they will be duly protected&#xD;
      through co-consent of the parent and child. No patient will be permitted to participate in&#xD;
      the study without having signed an Informed Consent waiver.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators have given forethought to the maximization of benefits and reduction of&#xD;
      risks that might occur from the research. The equitable selection and fairness in&#xD;
      distribution of participants is only limited by funding; no benefit to which a person is&#xD;
      entitled is denied without good reason or when some burden is imposed unduly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study limitations As with any study of this nature, focusing on a particular subset of&#xD;
      clinics, and excluding some patients limits the generalizability of the results to the&#xD;
      population at large (external validity). However, our within-clinic randomization procedure&#xD;
      ensures robust internal validity and maximizes statistical power, so that we can maximize the&#xD;
      value of this assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Further, the study is limited to a single treatment group, making it impossible to tease&#xD;
      apart the impact of Keheala's various elements, evaluate different messages, or different&#xD;
      frequency of contact. This decision was made to streamline logistics--these questions are&#xD;
      left for a follow-up assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Implications A successful pilot would demonstrate the potential of Keheala's low-cost&#xD;
      mobile platform to increase compliance and save lives. The investigator's goal is to&#xD;
      demonstrate this potential, and also to learn from the implementation in order to maximize&#xD;
      the impact of future iterations of the platform.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TB is a particularly ripe use-case for Keheala's platform due to onerous and extended&#xD;
      treatment, the limits of existing programs (e.g., the WHO's DOTS program), TB's highly&#xD;
      infectious nature, the risk of disease-resistant strains, and its severity. However, Keheala&#xD;
      could eventually be applied to address other public health concerns, such as HIV, which&#xD;
      shares many of these features. A successful pilot would pave the way for such applications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 4, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 14, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>We will employ a randomized controlled trial (RCT) with 600 patients included in the treatment group and 600 patients included in the control group. We have selected this methodology for the following reasons:&#xD;
RCTs are the gold-standard for providing evidence-based evaluation of medical interventions, and recommended when feasible.&#xD;
Keheala is a new program, and cannot be studied using existing data.&#xD;
We are working with researchers from Harvard's Program for Evolutionary Dynamics and Yale's Human Cooperation Lab, who have an established record of designing large-scale RCTs in real-world settings such as ours.&#xD;
This sample size was chosen to achieve 80% power in detecting improvements of 7.5% or more in the relevant health outcomes. To do this calculation, we employed Monte Carlo simulations of patient outcomes, based on the Kenyan Ministry of Health's 2013 TB Case Findings Report.&#xD;
Note: The sample size and outcomes were registered in December 2015 with the IRB.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Unsuccessful Treatment Outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of individuals who failed to successfully complete the treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1190</enrollment>
  <condition>Tuberculosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care (Control)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Keheala Intervention (Treatment)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The intervention consisted of a daily request for self-verification of medication adherence, access to a supporter via a chat client, and information about TB.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Keheala</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Keheala Intervention (Treatment)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard of Care</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients receive medication for a week or two weeks at a time. They are assigned a friend or family member 'supporter' to verify the patient's at-home treatment and instructed to return to the clinic with the patient during medication refills.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care (Control)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically diagnosed with TB by smear microscopy, culture or Gene Xpert.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Communicate in either Swahili or English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Already have access to a mobile phone.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Diagnosed with a drug-resistant strain of TB.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.keheala.com/</url>
    <description>Keheala - A mobile health platform that uses behavioral interventions to improve healthcare access and treatment outcomes.</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Allcott, H. (2011). Social norms and energy conservation. Journal of Public Economics, 95(9), 1082-1095.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Andreoni, J., Rao, J. M., &amp; Trachtman, H. (2011). Avoiding the ask: a field experiment on altruism, empathy, and charitable giving (No. w17648). National Bureau of Economic Research.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ayres, I., Raseman, S., &amp; Shih, A. (2013). Evidence from two large field experiments that peer comparison feedback can reduce residential energy usage. Journal of Law, Economics, and Organization, 29(5), 992-1022.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gehlbach, H., Brinkworth, M. E., King, A., Hsu, L., McIntyre, J., &amp; Rogers, T. T. (2015). Creating birds of similar feathers: Leveraging similarity to improve teacher-student relationships and academic achievement.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gollwitzer, P. M. (1999). Implementation intentions: strong effects of simple plans. American psychologist, 54(7), 493.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hallsworth, M., List, J. A., Metcalfe, R. D., &amp; Vlaev, I. (2015). The Making of Homo Honoratus: From Omission to Commission (No. w21210). National Bureau of Economic Research.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hewstone M, Rubin M, Willis H. Intergroup bias. Annu Rev Psychol. 2002;53:575-604. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11752497</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Karlin B, Zinger JF, Ford R. The effects of feedback on energy conservation: A meta-analysis. Psychol Bull. 2015 Nov;141(6):1205-27. doi: 10.1037/a0039650. Epub 2015 Sep 21. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26390265</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Knutsson, M., Martinsson, P., &amp; Wollbrant, C. (2013). Do people avoid opportunities to donate?: A natural field experiment on recycling and charitable giving. Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization, 93, 71-77.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kraft-Todd, G., Yoeli, E., Bhanot, S., &amp; Rand, D. (2015). Promoting cooperation in the field. Current Opinion in Behavioral Sciences, 3, 96-101.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Malhotra, N., Michelson, M. R., Rogers, T., &amp; Valenzuela, A. A. (2011). Text messages as mobilization tools: The conditional effect of habitual voting and election salience. American Politics Research, 39(4), 664-681.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Prestwich A, Perugini M, Hurling R. Can the effects of implementation intentions on exercise be enhanced using text messages? Psychol Health. 2009 Jul;24(6):677-87. doi: 10.1080/08870440802040715.</citation>
    <PMID>20205020</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rand, D. G., Yoeli, E., &amp; Hoffman, M. (2014). Harnessing reciprocity to promote cooperation and the provisioning of public goods. Policy Insights from the Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 1(1), 263-269.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rege, M., &amp; Telle, K. (2004). The impact of social approval and framing on cooperation in public good situations. Journal of public Economics, 88(7), 1625-1644.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Research Center, Pew (2014, February 13). Emerging Nations Embrace Internet, Mobile Technology. Retrieved December 23, 2015, from http://www.pewglobal.org/2014/02/13/emerging-nations-embrace-internet-mobile-technology/</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rodgers A, Corbett T, Bramley D, Riddell T, Wills M, Lin RB, Jones M. Do u smoke after txt? Results of a randomised trial of smoking cessation using mobile phone text messaging. Tob Control. 2005 Aug;14(4):255-61.</citation>
    <PMID>16046689</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rogers, T., Milkman, K., John, L., &amp; Norton, M. I. (2013). Making the best-laid plans better: how plan making increases follow-through. Cambridge, MA: Work. Pap., Harvard Univ.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Spranca, M., Minsk, E., &amp; Baron, J. (1991). Omission and commission in judgment and choice. Journal of experimental social psychology, 27(1), 76-105.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>TB ARC - Centre for Health Solutions. (n.d.). Retrieved 2015, from http://www.chskenya.org/what-we-do/tb-arc/</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tiemersma EW, van der Werf MJ, Borgdorff MW, Williams BG, Nagelkerke NJ. Natural history of tuberculosis: duration and fatality of untreated pulmonary tuberculosis in HIV negative patients: a systematic review. PLoS One. 2011 Apr 4;6(4):e17601. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0017601. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21483732</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tola HH, Tol A, Shojaeizadeh D, Garmaroudi G. Tuberculosis Treatment Non-Adherence and Lost to Follow Up among TB Patients with or without HIV in Developing Countries: A Systematic Review. Iran J Public Health. 2015 Jan;44(1):1-11. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26060770</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tuberculosis. (2015, October 1). Retrieved December 12, 2014, from http://www.who.int/mediacentre/factsheets/fs104/en/</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>WHO. (2014). Global Tuberculosis Report 2014. World Health Organization.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>WHO. (2015). Global Tuberculosis Report 2015. World Health Organization.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yoeli E, Hoffman M, Rand DG, Nowak MA. Powering up with indirect reciprocity in a large-scale field experiment. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2013 Jun 18;110 Suppl 2:10424-9. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1301210110. Epub 2013 Jun 10.</citation>
    <PMID>23754399</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 27, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 28, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 1, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 18, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 18, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 23, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Erez Yoeli</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Research Scientist and Co-Director of the Applied Cooperation Team</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Tuberculosis</keyword>
  <keyword>TB</keyword>
  <keyword>Adherence</keyword>
  <keyword>Mobile Health</keyword>
  <keyword>mHealth</keyword>
  <keyword>Behavior change</keyword>
  <keyword>Social and Behavior Change Communication (SBCC)</keyword>
  <keyword>Drug-Resistance</keyword>
  <keyword>Keheala</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

