<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03138720</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NABPLAGEM-NEO 2017-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03138720</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pre-operative Treatment for Patients With Untreated Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Study of Paclitaxel Protein Bound + Gemcitabine + Cisplatin + Paricalcitol as Pre-operative Treatment in Patients With Untreated Resectable, Borderline Resectable and Locally Advanced Adenocarcinoma of the Pancreas</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>HonorHealth Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>HonorHealth Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine if the combination of paclitaxel protein bound,&#xD;
      gemcitabine, cisplatin, paricalcitol are effective in individuals with resectable and&#xD;
      unresectable pancreatic cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Neoadjuvant therapy has become the consensus treatment for individuals with locally advanced&#xD;
      unresectable disease and borderline resectable disease. Typical regimens utilize those that&#xD;
      are used in the metastatic setting for pancreatic cancer, such as FOLFIRINOX (5-FU,&#xD;
      Leucovorin, Irinotecan, and Oxaliplatin) and paclitaxel protein bound plus Gemcitabine.&#xD;
      Currently, the recommendation of utilizing neoadjuvant therapy for potentially resectable&#xD;
      pancreatic cancer has been met with controversy. However a recent study published an analysis&#xD;
      of individuals with potentially resectable pancreatic cancer and showed a median overall&#xD;
      survival of 31.5 months with 44.9 months for the 60 individuals who underwent neoadjuvant&#xD;
      therapy and resection compared to 8.1 months for the 9 patients who were not resected.&#xD;
      Another study examined the use of nab-paclitaxel, gemcitabine, capecitabine, and cisplatin&#xD;
      (PAXG regimen) in individuals with unresectable or borderline resectable pancreatic cancer&#xD;
      patients. A partial response was observed in 67% of the patients along with progression-free&#xD;
      survival at 6 months being 96%. Furthermore, a recent study examining stage I or stage II&#xD;
      pancreas cancer patients who received either neoadjuvant therapy followed by resection or&#xD;
      those who received upfront resection was reported. In those receiving neoadjuvant therapy,&#xD;
      overall survival was 26 months compared to 21 months. Neoadjuvant, as opposed to adjuvant&#xD;
      therapy potentially increases the amount of exposure of drug to the tumor. It allows for the&#xD;
      completion of therapy prior to surgery to prevent patient drop-out due to perioperative&#xD;
      complication. Neoadjuvant therapy also acts as a selection tool for optimal surgical&#xD;
      candidates by identifying aggressive tumor biology prior to surgery and therefore selecting&#xD;
      out those who will not benefit from resection. Radiation therapy may be also employed in the&#xD;
      neoadjuvant setting as a means to help with local control and survival in individuals without&#xD;
      micrometastatic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The combination of nab-paclitaxel (now called paclitaxel protein bound) and gemcitabine had a&#xD;
      high response and survival in the phase I and II study in advanced pancreatic cancer. In this&#xD;
      phase I study with expansion at the phase II dose, 67 pts were accrued. The phase II dose was&#xD;
      determined to be weekly nab-paclitaxel 125 mg/m2 with gemcitabine 1000 mg/m2. Therapy was&#xD;
      well tolerated at the phase II dose. For all patients (n=67), the median time for&#xD;
      progression-free survival (PFS) was 7.1 months (95%CI, 5.7 to 8.0 months), and the median&#xD;
      time for overall survival (OS) was 10.3 months (95% CI, 8.4 to 13.6 months). For patients at&#xD;
      the recommended dose of 125 mg/m2 nab-paclitaxel, the median PFS was 7.9 months (95% CI, 5.8&#xD;
      to 11.0 months), and the median OS time was 12.2 months (95% CI, 8.9 to 17.9 months).&#xD;
      Additionally, the 1-year survival is reported at 48% at the maximum tolerated dose (MTD), and&#xD;
      the overall response rate (ORR) was 46% for all patients (n=67). The combination of&#xD;
      nab-paclitaxel and gemcitabine was generally well tolerated and had substantial antitumor&#xD;
      activity in patients with pancreatic cancer, enough to warrant a phase III clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the phase III (MPACT study, n=861) patients were randomly assigned to nab-paclitaxel plus&#xD;
      gemcitabine (431 patients) or gemcitabine (430). The median overall survival was 8.5 months&#xD;
      in the nab-paclitaxel-gemcitabine group as compared with 6.7 months in the gemcitabine group&#xD;
      (P&lt;0.001). The one year survival rate was 35% in the nab-paclitaxel-gemcitabine group versus&#xD;
      22% in the gemcitabine group, and 9% versus 4% at 2 years. The median PFS was 5.5 months in&#xD;
      the nab-paclitaxel-gemcitabine group, as compared with 3.7 months in the gemcitabine group&#xD;
      (P&lt;0.001); the response rate according to independent review was 23% versus 7% in the two&#xD;
      groups (P&lt;0.001). Adverse events were tolerable with grade &gt; 3 events of neutropenia (38% in&#xD;
      the nab-paclitaxel-gemcitabine group vs. 27% in the gemcitabine group), fatigue (17% vs. 7%),&#xD;
      and neuropathy (17% vs. 1%) and febrile neutropenia (3% versus 1%). Based on the results of&#xD;
      this study, nab-paclitaxel plus gemcitabine is a FDA approved regimen for pancreatic cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Building on the design and mechanisms of action of the nab-paclitaxel and gemcitabine&#xD;
      combination, a prior protocol introduced a third cytotoxic agent cisplatin, was added to this&#xD;
      doublet. The rationale for adding cisplatin to nab-paclitaxel and gemcitabine was that in a&#xD;
      study of 1,029 patients whose pancreatic cancer tumors were sent for molecular profiling, 57%&#xD;
      of these tumors were negative for ERCC1, indicating sensitivity to a platinum anti-tumor&#xD;
      agent. In addition to the above, in our whole genome/transcriptome sequencing analysis, we&#xD;
      found that abnormal repair pathways were a feature of all of the pancreatic cancers that were&#xD;
      sequenced. Cisplatin prevents cellular DNA repair by binding to and causing crosslinking of&#xD;
      DNA, triggering apoptosis. Cisplatin has been used in other combination regimens to treat&#xD;
      patients with PDA. For example, the cisplatin, epirubicin, 5-fluorouracil and gemcitabine&#xD;
      (PEFG) regimen had an acceptable toxicity profile and was associated with a 24% partial&#xD;
      response rate, 5 month progression-free survival (PFS) and 8.3 month overall survival as&#xD;
      second line therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to 2015, there were no documented reports of the combination of cisplatin with&#xD;
      paclitaxel protein bound and gemcitabine in the treatment of any human cancer. However,&#xD;
      cisplatin had been combined with paclitaxel and gemcitabine in the treatment of patients with&#xD;
      locally advanced or metastatic non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) patients and had shown&#xD;
      substantial antitumor activity with an acceptable safety profile. In that phase I-II study of&#xD;
      65 patients with advanced NSCLC, the overall response rate was 57%. The aforementioned&#xD;
      neoadjuvant study led by Reni also utilized cisplatin with albumin bound paclitaxel along&#xD;
      with gemcitabine and capecitabine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      More recently there has been even more compelling science indicating that one should consider&#xD;
      DNA repair as an Achilles heel in pancreatic cancer. A team led by Nurse Practitioner Gayle&#xD;
      Jameson recently reported on the phase Ib/II trial of the combination of paclitaxel&#xD;
      protein-bound plus gemcitabine plus cisplatin. In 24 evaluable patients with stage IV&#xD;
      pancreatic cancer they reported a response rate of 71% (Complete Response (CR) + Partial&#xD;
      Response (PR)) along with a 88% disease control rate (CR + PR+ Stable Disease (SD) at 9&#xD;
      weeks). Utilizing this highly active therapy in the neoadjuvant setting may lead to further&#xD;
      improvement in overall survival and progression free survival in patients with pancreatic&#xD;
      cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Most recently the spectacular work of researchers has awakened the world of pancreatic cancer&#xD;
      research to the possibility that Vitamin D could be a substantial player in normalizing the&#xD;
      tumor microenvironment from an immunologically friendly (to the tumor) one to an&#xD;
      immunologically hostile one (e.g. decreased IL6, decreased CXCL12 etc.). In addition, the&#xD;
      vitamin D analog decreased production of collagen, decreased Myeloid Derived Suppressor cells&#xD;
      (MDSCs) and decreased regulating T cells. In an ongoing neoadjuvant trial utilizing&#xD;
      gemcitabine and paclitaxel protein bound with paricalcitol compared to gemcitabine and&#xD;
      paclitaxel protein bound, a modulation of the tumor microenvironment has been seen including&#xD;
      greater infiltration of CD3 positive lymphocytes. Therefore, a trial utilizing gemcitabine,&#xD;
      paclitaxel protein bound, cisplatin and paricalcitol may yield promising results in the&#xD;
      neoadjuvant setting.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 23, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>There will be two treatment groups: those who are deemed resectable and those that are deemed borderline resectable and with locally advanced pancreas cancer.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>No masking</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CA19-9 value</measure>
    <time_frame>approximately 63 days</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory testing will be used to determine if the CA19-9 value has normalized after 3 cycles of treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pathologic Complete Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>approximately 63 days</time_frame>
    <description>Participants will have an MRI completed after 3 cycles to determine if the tumor has responded to treatment. RECIST 1.1 criteria will be used to evaluate response. A confirmatory PET scan may be ordered to confirm complete response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>every 12 weeks after study completion</time_frame>
    <description>Participants will be contacted by telephone every 12 weeks until date of death.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Resectable Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Unresectable Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Neoadjuvant Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Open Label</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients will receive open label medication at set dosages unless the dosage needs to be adjusted to treat an adverse event or dose toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Paclitaxel Protein Bound (Abraxane)</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be treated with the regimen prior to having surgery. Participants will complete 3 cycles (cycle is 21 days) and then will be evaluated for CA19-9 normalization. If CA19-9 is normalized, then participant will be scheduled for surgery and moved to standard of care. If CA19-9 is not normalized then participants will complete another 3 cycles.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Open Label</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cisplatin (Platinal</other_name>
    <other_name>Gemcitabine (Gemzar)</other_name>
    <other_name>Paricalcitol (Zemplar)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient has histologically or cytologically confirmed resectable, borderline&#xD;
             resectable, or locally advanced (unresectable) PDAC (based upon Tempero et al 2016)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Definition of Resectable Pancreatic Cancer includes all of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No evidence of extra pancreatic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No evidence of tumor-arterial abutment (celiac, SMA [superior mesenteric artery]&#xD;
                  or HA [hepatic artery])&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If tumor induced narrowing of the SMV [superior mesenteric vein], PV [portal&#xD;
                  vein] or SMV-PV [superior mesenteric-portal vein] confluence is present, it must&#xD;
                  be &lt;50% of the diameter of the vessel&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Definition of Borderline Resectable Pancreatic Cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  To include at least one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Tumor abutment &lt;180° of the SMA or celiac axis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Tumor abutment or encasement of a short segment of the HA&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Tumor induced narrowing of SMV, PV or SMV-PV of &gt;50% of the diameter of the&#xD;
                  vessel.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Short segment occlusion of the SMV, PV or SMV-PV with a suitable PV above and SMV&#xD;
                  below, for reconstruction&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Biopsy proven N1 disease (regional lymph nodes involved) from pre-referral biopsy&#xD;
                  or EUS-guided FNA&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Definition of Locally Advanced (Unresectable)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Artery: Tumor encasement (&gt; 180°) of SMA or celiac artery&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Vein Occlusion of SMV, PV or SMV-PV without suitable vessels above and below the&#xD;
                  tumor to allow for reconstruction (no distal or proximal target for vascular&#xD;
                  reconstruction)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No extra pancreatic disease: No evidence of peritoneal, hepatic, or&#xD;
                  extra-abdominal metastases&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age ≥ 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. If a female patient is of child-bearing potential, she must have a negative serum&#xD;
             pregnancy test (≥β-hCG) documented within 72 hours of the first administration of&#xD;
             study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. If sexually active, the patient and partner must agree to use contraception considered&#xD;
             adequate and appropriate by the Investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient must have received no prior chemotherapy or radiation therapy for PDAC&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients must have normal organ and marrow function as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  platelets ≥ 100,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hematocrit level &gt; 27%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  total bilirubin within institutional upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST/ALT ≤ 2.5 × institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alkaline phosphatase (AP) ≤ 2.5 x institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine &lt; 1.5 mg/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patient has acceptable coagulation status as indicated by an INR ≤ 1.5 x ULN. Patients&#xD;
             on anticoagulation can be included at the discretion of the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Karnofsky Performance Status (KPS) of ≥70%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Have an elevated CA 19-9&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient will be excluded from this study if any of the following criteria apply:&#xD;
             Evidence of metastatic disease. No metastatic disease defined as any one or more of&#xD;
             the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Suspicious lymphadenopathy outside of the standard surgical field (i.e.&#xD;
                  aortocaval nodes, distant abdominal nodes)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Radiographic evidence for metastatic disease in distant organs, peritoneum, or&#xD;
                  ascites&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Active, uncontrolled bacterial, viral, or fungal infection(s) requiring systemic&#xD;
             therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Known infection with HIV, hepatitis B, or hepatitis C.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Has undergone major surgery, other than diagnostic surgery (i.e. surgery done to&#xD;
             obtain a biopsy for diagnosis without removal of an organ), within 4 weeks prior to&#xD;
             Day 1 of treatment in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of allergy or hypersensitivity to the study drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Serious medical risk factors involving any of the major organ systems such that the&#xD;
             Investigator considers it unsafe for the patient to receive an experimental research&#xD;
             drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Current, serious, clinically significant cardiac arrhythmias as determined by the&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patient is unwilling or unable to comply with study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patient is enrolled in any other therapeutic clinical protocol or investigational&#xD;
             trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patient with a history of interstitial lung disease, history of slowly progressive&#xD;
             dyspnea and unproductive cough, sarcoidosis, silicosis, idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis,&#xD;
             pulmonary hypersensitivity pneumonitis or multiple allergies.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Use of non-FDA approved cannabinoids are prohibited. Total daily usage of up to 40 mg&#xD;
             per day of marinol is acceptable.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Erkut Borazanci, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>HonorHealth Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>HonorHealth Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Scottsdale</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85258</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 1, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 1, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 3, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>IPD will not be shared with outside researchers.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

