<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03136510</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CV185-439</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03136510</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evolution of Coagulation Activity in Non Valvular Atrial Fibrillation Patients Under Apixaban</brief_title>
  <acronym>ECAN</acronym>
  <official_title>Prospective Study With Biological Assessment: Evolution of Coagulation Activity in Non Valvular Atrial Fibrillation Patients Under Apixaban</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hopital Lariboisière</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hopital Lariboisière</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Apixaban is a potent, oral, selective reversible direct inhibitor of factor Xa with a&#xD;
      favorable efficacy and safety profile in the prevention of non valvular (NV) atrial&#xD;
      fibrillation (AF). It has been shown, including by our group, that D-dimers levels (molecular&#xD;
      marker of coagulation activity) are predictive of the events (including mortality) in patient&#xD;
      with AF independently of the antithrombotic treatment. The aim of the study is to evaluate&#xD;
      the changes in plasma levels of biomarkers of coagulation activation: D-dimers, prothrombin&#xD;
      fragments F1+2, von Willebrand factor (vWF) and thrombin-antithrombin complexes (TAT) in&#xD;
      response to apixaban treatment in patients with NVAF.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is a prospective, monocentric study, with biological analyses. The investigational&#xD;
      product will be administered according to French health agency. The duration of the study for&#xD;
      each patient will be 3 months with 3 visits and from 3 to a maximum of 18 months for the&#xD;
      clinical follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: Apixaban significantly decreases D-dimers and other markers of coagulation&#xD;
      activation in patients with NVAF ( paroxysmic and chronic atrial fibrillation).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary endpoint:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Measurement of D-dimers at baseline (before apixaban treatment) and under chronic apixaban&#xD;
      treatment at 3 months in the overall population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Difference of the D-dimers levels between enrollment (V1) and the final visit (V3) at three&#xD;
      months in both subgroups separately. In the subgroup B,comparison of D-dimers in patients&#xD;
      previously treated by VKA (V1) and under apixaban (V3).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Similarly than for D-dimers levels, each following parameters will be analyzed for the&#xD;
      overall population and for both subgroups separately :&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Difference of prothrombin fragments F1+F2 levels between V1 and V3.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Difference of thrombin and antithrombin complexes levels between V1 and V3&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Difference of vWF levels between V1 and V3.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Correlation will be evaluated between:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  AntiXa apixaban activity (at trough) and D-dimers difference&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  D-dimers difference and clinical follow-up (ischemic events and-bleeding events) V2 and&#xD;
           V3 levels of each parameter will be compared to assess the delay of appearance of the&#xD;
           apixaban effect if any. Inflammation parameters ( C reactive protein and fibrinogen)&#xD;
           will be used as explicative for the other parameters.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Effect on APTT( activated partial thromboplastin time) and PT(prothrombin time) will be&#xD;
      compared to specific apixaban anti Xa activity&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subgroup analysis:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Subgroups A and B (newly diagnosed and VKA naïve NVAF and chronic NVAF)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  age &gt;80 years,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  creatinine clearance &lt; 50 ml/min,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  gender Multivariate analysis for the primary endpoint&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis Continuous variables will be analyzed for a normal distribution with the&#xD;
      D'Agostino-Pearson test. They will be presented as mean and standard deviation (SD) and&#xD;
      compared with Student's unpaired t-test if normally distributed, or presented as median and&#xD;
      interquartile range and compared with Mann-Whitney rank-sum test, if not. Categorical&#xD;
      variables will be presented as counts and percentages and will be compared by means of the&#xD;
      χ2-test or Fisher's exact test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Correlations between quantitative variables will be assessed with Pearson correlation&#xD;
      coefficients. Predictive factors will be determined using a stepwise multivariable logistic&#xD;
      regression analysis. In this study, we will expect an initial D-dimers level around 1500ng/ml&#xD;
      with a standard deviation of ±700ng/ml in patients with newly diagnosed NVAF. At 3 month, we&#xD;
      expect a level of D-dimers of 1000±600ng/ml (reduction of 500ng/ml compared to the enrolment&#xD;
      visit). A sample size of 60 patients has been estimated in this pilot study. The study will&#xD;
      include 60 patients with NVAF with 50% of patients with newly diagnosed NVAF (Subgroup A,&#xD;
      n=30) and the other 50% with NVAF previously treated by VKA (Subgroup B, n=30).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All information required by the protocol must be provided in the case report form. The data&#xD;
      will be transferred in the case report forms as and when they are obtained, whether clinical&#xD;
      or biological. The investigators will make the data available strictly necessary for qua lity&#xD;
      control and audit relating to the biomedical research in accordance with the legislative and&#xD;
      regulatory provisions in force (Articles L.1121-3 and R.5121-13 of the French Public Health&#xD;
      Code).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Those responsible for biomedical research quality control (Article L.1121-3 of the French&#xD;
      Public Health Code) will take all necessary precautions to ensure the confidentiality of&#xD;
      information about the experimental medications, the research, the research subjects and in&#xD;
      particular the identity of the subjects and the results obtained. These individuals, as well&#xD;
      as the investigators themselves, are subject to professional secrecy (in accordance with the&#xD;
      conditions set out in Articles 226-13 and 226-14 of the Penal Code).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All Serious Adverse Events (SAEs) that occur following the subject's written consent to&#xD;
      participate in the study through 30 days of discontinuation of dosing must be reported to&#xD;
      Bristol-Myers Squibb Worldwide Safety and to the sponsor.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>60 patients with two subgroups&#xD;
30 patients with new diagnosis of atrial fibrillation (vitamin K antagonist treatment shorter than 1 week) : initiated with Apixaban 5 mg&#xD;
30 patients previously chronically treated by VKA for more than 3 months and switched to Apixaban 5 mg</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change from baseline D-dimers level at 3 months.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>D-dimers levels will be determined using an enzyme immunoassay (ELISA method) on citrated plasma.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prothrombin fragment F1-F2 measurement</measure>
    <time_frame>at enrollment, at one month, and at three months</time_frame>
    <description>Prothrombin fragment F1-F2 will be determined using an enzyme immunoassay (ELISA method) on citrated plasma.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>von Willebrand factor measurement</measure>
    <time_frame>at enrollment, at one month, and at three months</time_frame>
    <description>vWF will be determined using an enzyme immunoassay (ELISA method) on citrated plasma.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Thrombin-antithrombin complex measurement</measure>
    <time_frame>at enrollment, at one month, and at three months</time_frame>
    <description>TAT complex will be determined using an enzyme immunoassay (ELISA method) on citrated plasma.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>High sensitivity CRP measurement</measure>
    <time_frame>at enrollment, at one month, and at three months</time_frame>
    <description>Hs CRP will be measured following usual method of the biochemistry laboratory on EDTA (ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid ) plasma.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prothrombin time measurement, Activated partial thromboplastin time, and fibrinogen</measure>
    <time_frame>at enrollment, at one month, and at three months</time_frame>
    <description>Prothrombin time, a PTT and fibrinogen will be measured following usual method of the hematology laboratory on citrated plasma.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AntiXa apixaban activity measurement</measure>
    <time_frame>at enrollment, at one month, and at three months</time_frame>
    <description>Anti-Xa apixaban levels will be determined using the specific technic with adapted apixaban calibrators on citrated plasma.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Coagulation Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Non Valvular Atrial Fibrillation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Newly diagnosed NVAF: apixaban 5 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>blood collection for biological analyses of 30 patients new diagnosis of NVAF (VKA treatment ≤1 week) initiated with apixaban 5 mg</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Previously diagnosed NVAF: apixaban 5 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>blood collection for biological analyses of 30 patients previously treated by VKA for more than 3 months switched to apixaban 5 mg</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Apixaban 5 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>Bood collection for biological analyses at:&#xD;
inclusion visit&#xD;
follow-up visit at 1 month&#xD;
end of research at 3 month</description>
    <arm_group_label>Newly diagnosed NVAF: apixaban 5 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Previously diagnosed NVAF: apixaban 5 mg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Eliquis</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with NVAF (documented by 12 leads ECG or Holter recording) and having one or&#xD;
             more factor (s) of risk such as: history of stroke or transient ischemic attack ;&#xD;
             age≥75 years; hypertension; diabetes; symptomatic heart failure (NYHA class≥ II) for&#xD;
             prevention of cerebral vascular accident and systemic embolism.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with CHA2DS2-VASc score ≥2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients provided signed written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with age≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients previously treated with VKA or patients newly diagnosed with AF.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  AF or flutter due to reversible causes according to investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant mitral stenosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition than atrial fibrillation that require chronic anticoagulation&#xD;
             (prosthetic heart valve or valve repair, venous thromboembolism)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A need for aspirin at a dose of ≥160 mg a day or for both aspirin and adenosine&#xD;
             diphosphate (ADP) inhibitor (clopidogrel, prasugrel or ticagrelor)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy or adverse reaction to apixaban or any of the excipients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients previously treated by an oral direct anticoagulant in the last 30 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with clinically on going active bleeding or platelet count&lt;100,000/mm3 or&#xD;
             haemoglobin&lt;9 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with serious bleeding in the last 6 months or with high risk of bleeding&#xD;
             (active peptic ulcer disease or gastroduodenal ulceration, known or suspected&#xD;
             esophageal varicoses, recent ischemic stroke, recent brain or spinal injury or&#xD;
             intracranial hemorrhage, recent surgery, arterial or venous malformations, vascular&#xD;
             aneurysms…)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with another cause of increase of D-dimers (active malignant neoplasm, recent&#xD;
             trauma or surgery (less than 1 month), extensive venous malformation…)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled and persistent hypertension (systolic &gt;180 mmHg or diastolic &gt;100 mmHg)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infective endocarditis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  aspartate transaminase (ASAT) or alanine aminotransferase (ALAT) &gt; 2 times upper limit&#xD;
             or hepatic disease with coagulopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe renal insufficiency (creatinine clearance &lt;30ml/min)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women in age of pregnancy without menopause or efficient contraception and pregnant&#xD;
             women or breast feeding women. Men without effective contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any reason that makes the study participation impractical (alcohol abuse, psychosocial&#xD;
             reason, inclusion in another study in the past month, life expectancy≤1 year…)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any contraindications to study treatment (apixaban): hypersensitivity to apixaban or&#xD;
             any of the excipients (see composition), ongoing active bleeding, hepatic disease with&#xD;
             coagulopathy, any condition with high risk of bleeding, concomitant anticoagulant&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ludovic DROUET, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Lariboisiere Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Claire Bal dit Sollier</last_name>
    <phone>(33) 1 49 95 85 78</phone>
    <email>claire.bal@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jean Guillaume DILLINGER, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(33) 1 49 95 85 74</phone>
    <email>jean-guillaume.dillinger@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Cardiology Lariboisiere Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75010</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Claire Bal dit Sollier</last_name>
      <phone>(33) 1 49 95 85 78</phone>
      <email>claire.bal@aphp.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 24, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 27, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 2, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 2, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 2, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 5, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hopital Lariboisière</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr Jean-Guillaume DILLINGER</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Jean Guillaume DILLINGER, MD,PhD, principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hemostatic Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Blood Coagulation Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Apixaban</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

