<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04033159</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DYN101-C101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04033159</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Early Phase Human Drug Trial to Investigate Dynamin 101 (DYN101) in Patients ≥ 16 Years With Centronuclear Myopathies</brief_title>
  <acronym>Unite-CNM</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 1/2 Trial on the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics, Pharmacodynamics and Exploratory Efficacy of DYN101 in Patients ≥ 16 Years of Age With Centronuclear Myopathies Caused by Mutations in DNM2 or MTM1.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dynacure</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dynacure</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There are no available treatments aside from supportive care for patients with Centronuclear&#xD;
      myopathy (CNM). This trial will assess the safety, tolerability, PK and PD/preliminary&#xD;
      efficacy of a new medicine called DYN101 in patients ≥ 16 years of age with CNM caused by&#xD;
      mutations in DNM2 or MTM1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial will consist of a consent, a screening period, a run-in period (if applicable), a&#xD;
      Single dose treatment part (SAD) with 4 weeks of follow-up after the drug administration and&#xD;
      a washout period of at least 12 weeks (followed by follow-up phone calls), a Multiple dose&#xD;
      treatment part (MAD) of 12 weeks of weekly dosing, and a Multiple dose extension part of 12&#xD;
      weeks. All subjects will participate in the SAD, MAD, and MAD extension parts, unless they&#xD;
      withdraw. During this time, multiple test will be performed in order to better understand how&#xD;
      the drug is distributed and then later removed from the body and whether there any signs of&#xD;
      an effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As this trial is investigational, there is no defined, expected benefit for subjects who&#xD;
      participate in this trial except a better knowledge of their disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      There are currently no available treatments aside from supportive care for patients with&#xD;
      Centronuclear myopathy (CNM). This trial will assess the safety, tolerability, PK and&#xD;
      PD/preliminary efficacy of DYN101 in patients ≥ 16 years of age with CNM caused by mutations&#xD;
      in DNM2 or MTM1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DYN101 is a synthetically manufactured constrained ethyl gapmer ASO directed against DNM2&#xD;
      pre-mRNA. DYN101 will be provided as a sterile concentrated solution for reconstitution into&#xD;
      an infusion solution for intravenous (IV) administration, and will be diluted into a 0.9%&#xD;
      sodium chloride solution before administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial will consist of a pre-screening consent, a screening period, a run-in period (if&#xD;
      applicable), a SAD part with 4 weeks of follow-up after IMP administration and a washout&#xD;
      period of at least 12 weeks (followed by follow-up phone calls until the MAD part starts), a&#xD;
      MAD part of 12 weeks, and a MAD extension part of 12 weeks. All subjects will participate in&#xD;
      the SAD, MAD, and MAD extension parts, unless they withdraw. End-of-treatment assessments&#xD;
      will be performed after 24 weeks of MAD treatment have been completed, i.e. at the Week 25&#xD;
      visit. Subjects will be followed up on adverse events (AEs) and concomitant medications 3&#xD;
      months after the last IMP administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An interim analysis will be performed when all subjects in cohort 1 and 2 have completed 12&#xD;
      weeks of MAD treatment. The primary analysis will be performed when all subjects in all&#xD;
      cohorts have completed 12 weeks of MAD treatment or discontinued earlier. The final analysis&#xD;
      will be performed when all subjects have completed 24 weeks of MAD treatment (12 weeks in the&#xD;
      MAD part + 12 weeks in the MAD extension part; Week 25 visit) or discontinued earlier.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As this trial is investigational, there is no defined, expected benefit for subjects who&#xD;
      participate in this trial except a better knowledge of their pathology, and the knowledge&#xD;
      that they contribute to RNA-targeted therapy for CNM patients carrying MTM1 and DNM2&#xD;
      mutations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 9, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Trial consisting of pre-screening consent, screening period, run-in period (if applicable), SAD part with 4 weeks follow-up after IMP and washout period of ≥ 12 weeks, MAD part of 12 weeks and MAD extension part of 12 weeks. All subjects to participate in SAD, MAD, and MAD extension unless they withdraw. Subjects to receive DYN101 in a low (1.5 mg/kg), middle (4.5 mg/kg) or high (9 mg/kg) dose in Cohorts 1, 2 and 3 respectively, and remain on assigned dose throughout the trial (unless IDMC advises otherwise). Each cohort will have 3-4 subjects with a DNM2 mutation and 2-3 subjects with a MTM1 mutation. Cohorts will enroll in a sequential staggered approach with an interval of ≥7 days between dosing of the first and the next subject in a cohort (after Medical Monitor 48hr safety data review).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>incidence of drug-related Treatment Emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline until Week 25</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of drug-related, treatment-emergent AEs during the study period (through to Week 25).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">18</enrollment>
  <condition>Centronuclear Myopathy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>cohort 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>DYN101 in a low dose (1.5 mg/kg), (unless the IDMC advises otherwise). In each cohort, there will be 3-4 subjects with a mutation in DNM2 (subcohort a) and 2-3 subjects with a mutation in MTM1 (subcohort b).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>cohort 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>DYN101 in a middle dose (4.5 mg/kg), (unless the IDMC advises otherwise). In each cohort, there will be 3-4 subjects with a mutation in DNM2 (subcohort a) and 2-3 subjects with a mutation in MTM1 (subcohort b).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>cohort 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>DYN101 in a high dose (9 mg/kg), (unless the IDMC advises otherwise). In each cohort, there will be 3-4 subjects with a mutation in DNM2 (subcohort a) and 2-3 subjects with a mutation in MTM1 (subcohort b).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>DYN101</intervention_name>
    <description>DYN101, is a constrained ethyl gapmer ASO directed against human DNM2 RNA</description>
    <arm_group_label>cohort 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>cohort 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>cohort 3</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>there is no other intervention name</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female aged ≥ 16 years on the date of signing the main Informed Consent Form&#xD;
             (ICF).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have a documented mutation in DNM2 or MTM1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have a symptomatic CNM in the opinion of the investigator, at least mild to moderately&#xD;
             affected, i.e. showing clinical symptoms in at least 2 of the relevant 4 domains that&#xD;
             will be investigated in this trial (respiratory, muscle strength, muscle function, and&#xD;
             dysphagia), and be ambulatory, i.e. being able to walk 10 steps, if needed with&#xD;
             support/assisted. If a subject is non-ambulatory but highly functioning in the view of&#xD;
             the investigator, he/she may be included following discussion with the sponsor.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Have an understanding, ability, and willingness to fully comply with visit frequency,&#xD;
        trial procedures and restrictions, including contraceptive requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Able to provide written, signed and dated informed consent/assent to participate in the&#xD;
        trial. Parental consent (one or both parents) and an assent for subjects &lt; 18 years may be&#xD;
        required per local legislation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinically significant liver disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Clinically significant renal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Presence of significant co-morbidities or conditions other than CNM or clinically&#xD;
             significant (CS) findings during screening of medical history, physical examination,&#xD;
             laboratory testing, vital signs or ECG recording for which, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator and the medical monitor, participation would not be in the best interest&#xD;
             of the subject (e.g. compromise the safety or well-being) or that could prevent,&#xD;
             limit, or confound the protocol-specified assessments (e.g. taking a muscle biopsy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. For female subjects of child-bearing potential: pregnant or breastfeeding, or planning&#xD;
             to become pregnant during the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Current or past abuse of alcohol or recreational/narcotic drugs (with the exception of&#xD;
             caffeine and nicotine), which in the investigator's opinion would compromise the&#xD;
             subject's safety and/or compliance with the trial procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Currently enrolled in any interventional trial or scheduled to participate in such a&#xD;
             trial whilst participating in this trial. Subjects are allowed to participate in&#xD;
             registry studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Current or relevant history of physical or psychiatric illness, any medical disorder&#xD;
             that may require treatment or make the subject unlikely to fully complete the trial,&#xD;
             or any condition that presents undue risk from the IMP or procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Intake of any disallowed therapies as noted in Section 5.5 within 12 weeks before the&#xD;
             planned first IMP administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Known or suspected intolerance or hypersensitivity to IMP ingredients or&#xD;
             closely-related compounds, or history of a significant allergic reaction to IMP&#xD;
             ingredients as determined by the investigator, such as anaphylaxis requiring&#xD;
             hospitalization.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Legally incapacitated or have limited legal capacity. Lack of mental capacity to fully&#xD;
             understand the protocol requirements and complete all study required procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: Retesting of subjects should always be discussed with the sponsor and/or medical&#xD;
        monitor. Retesting of laboratory values that lead to exclusion will be allowed once using&#xD;
        an unscheduled visit during the screening period to assess eligibility. This visit should&#xD;
        be at least 2 weeks later than the original screening visit.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Chris Freitag, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Dynacure</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>N.C. Voermans, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Radboud University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Chris Freitag, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+33 6 98 75 98 44</phone>
    <email>chris.freitag@dynacure.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Antwerp University Hospital (UZA)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edegem</city>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jonathan Baets, Professor</last_name>
      <phone>0032 3821 5760</phone>
      <email>jonathan.baets@uza.be</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen Neuromuscular Center, Neurocentret</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kopenhagen</city>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>John Vissing</last_name>
      <phone>0045 3545 2562</phone>
      <email>vissing@rh.dk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut de Myologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Behin Anthony</last_name>
      <phone>0033 142 163 713</phone>
      <email>anthony.behin@aphp.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Tanya Stojkovic</last_name>
      <phone>0033 142 163 780</phone>
      <email>tanya.stojkovic@aphp.fr</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>universitätsklinikum Essen, Kinderklinik I, Sozialpädiatrisches Zentrum</name>
      <address>
        <city>Essen</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>U. Schara, prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49201-723-85170</phone>
      <email>spz-studienteam@uk-essen.de</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <phone>+49201-723-84601</phone>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Friedrich Baur Institut - Neurologische Klinik LMV, Klinikum Innenstadt</name>
      <address>
        <city>München</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Frederica Montagnese</last_name>
      <phone>0049 089 4400 57400</phone>
      <email>studien.fbi@med.uni-muenchen.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Radboud University Medical Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nijmegen</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>N.C. Voermans, MD PhD</last_name>
      <phone>0031 24 3616 600</phone>
      <email>nicol.voermans@radboudumc.nl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MRC centre for Neuromuscular Disease, National Hospital for Neurology and Neurosurgery</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rosaline Quinlivan, Professor</last_name>
      <phone>0044 7527 442 063</phone>
      <email>r.quinlivan@ucl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Victoria Infirmary</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newcastle Upon Tyne</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sam McDonald</last_name>
      <phone>0044 191 241 8649</phone>
      <email>sam.mcdonald@newcastle.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
    <country>Denmark</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28589938</url>
    <description>Background info published in Nature on: &quot;Antisense oligonucleotide-mediated Dnm2 knockdown prevents and reverts myotubular myopathy in mice.&quot;</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 12, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 24, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 25, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Muscular Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myopathies, Structural, Congenital</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

