<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04035642</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PROSINT II</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04035642</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase II Study of Single-Dose Image-Guided Radiotherapy (SDRT) for Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>PROSINT II</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase II Study of Single-Dose Image-Guided Radiotherapy (SDRT) With Urethral Sparing for Localized Prostate Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fundacao Champalimaud</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fundacao Champalimaud</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The present study evaluates clinical outcomes and treatment-related toxicity following&#xD;
      definitive ultra-high single dose external beam radiotherapy delivered to patients with low-&#xD;
      or intermediate-risk adenocarcinoma of the prostate. Modern computer-driven technology&#xD;
      enables the implementation of ultra-high Single-Dose Image-Guided Radiotherapy (SD-IGRT)&#xD;
      safely.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prostate cancer patients classified according to the current National Comprehensive Cancer&#xD;
      Network (NCCN) guidelines as low or intermediate risk (biopsy Gleason score of ≤7 and/or&#xD;
      Prostate Specific Antigen (PSA) level ≤20 ng/mL and/or Stage T1, T2a, T2b or T2c) are&#xD;
      eligible for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will undergo SD-IGRT with volumetric intensity-modulated arc radiotherapy (VMAT)&#xD;
      with state-of-the-art treatment-planning and quality assurance procedures. Emphasis is placed&#xD;
      on normal tissue sparing and delivery accuracy via the use of devices that ensure stability&#xD;
      and beam location reproducibility. A rectal balloon with air filling will be used for&#xD;
      prostate target immobilization and anatomical reproducibility, while a urethral catheter&#xD;
      loaded with beacon transponders will be used to ensure set-up reproducibility and online&#xD;
      target tracking. Previously untreated patients with low- or intermediate-risk prostate cancer&#xD;
      will receive 24 Gy in a single-dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be followed at one month post-treatment and every 3 months for up to 12 months&#xD;
      (+/- 4 weeks) and every 6 months thereafter. Acute and chronic toxicity evaluations will&#xD;
      focus, though not exclusively, on urinary, rectal and sexual functions and will be assessed&#xD;
      through validated EPIC questionnaires. Serum PSA values will be drawn on the same schedule as&#xD;
      clinical follow-up. A multi-parametric MRI will be performed at baseline, and at 6, 12 and 24&#xD;
      months following intervention. The study will be continuously monitored for a minimum of 5&#xD;
      years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The present phase II study evaluates the clinical outcomes and potential treatment-related&#xD;
      toxicity following definitive ultra-high dose single fraction external beam radiation therapy&#xD;
      (SDRT) in patients with localized adenocarcinoma of the prostate. A large body of data&#xD;
      suggests that extreme hypofractionated radiation schedules, which employ ultra-high dose per&#xD;
      fraction (≥7 Gy) in a small number of fractions (≤5), appear equal or superior to&#xD;
      conventionally-fractionated (1.8-2.0 Gy/fraction) and moderately hypo-fractionated schemes&#xD;
      (2.5-3.5 Gy/fraction) in terms of both tumor control and toxicity profiles. Modern&#xD;
      computer-driven technology enables the implementation of ultra-high hypofractionated&#xD;
      Image-Guided Radiotherapy (IGRT) safely. The Radiation Oncology team at Champalimaud Centre&#xD;
      for the Unknown has been engaged in a large phase II study (HYPO) of extreme&#xD;
      hypofractionation (9Gyx5) which accrued over 200 cases and, with a median follow-up of over 3&#xD;
      years, showed the safety and efficacy of this approach. The feasibility of SDRT in localized&#xD;
      prostate cancer has been tested by the in a randomized phase II trial (PROSINT) comparing&#xD;
      extreme hypofractionation as per the HYPO trial regimen vs. a single dose of 24Gy. While the&#xD;
      long-term results of this study are still pending, its toxicity profile in both arms has been&#xD;
      extremely good with no G3 adverse events at 2 years and superimposable biochemical response&#xD;
      between the two regimens. Taken together, these observations provide the basis for the&#xD;
      prospective clinical studies proposed herein.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients enrolled in the study will undergo image-guided, volumetric intensity-modulated arc&#xD;
      radiotherapy (IGRT-VMAT) with state-of-the-art treatment-planning and quality assurance&#xD;
      procedures with emphasis on normal tissue sparing and delivery accuracy via the use of&#xD;
      devices that ensure stability and beam location reproducibility. A rectal balloon with air&#xD;
      filling will be used for prostate target immobilization and anatomical reproducibility, while&#xD;
      a urethral catheter loaded with beacon transponders will be used to ensure set-up&#xD;
      reproducibility and online target tracking. Previously untreated patients with low and&#xD;
      intermediate risk (NCCN criteria) localized prostate cancer will be treated with 24 Gy SDRT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be followed at one and three months post-treatment, every 3 months for up to 12&#xD;
      months (+/- 4 weeks) and every 6 months thereafter. Acute and chronic toxicity evaluations&#xD;
      will focus, though not exclusively, on urinary, rectal and sexual functions and will be&#xD;
      assessed through validated EPIC questionnaires. Serum PSA values will be drawn on the same&#xD;
      schedule as clinical follow-up. A multiparametric MRI will be performed at baseline, and at&#xD;
      6, 12 and 24 months following intervention. The study will be continuously monitored for a&#xD;
      minimum of 5 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients with treatment-related adverse events as assessed by Common Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Effects v4.0</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of treatment related adverse events as measured by Common Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Effects v4.0 over a 5 year time frame.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Concentration of serum PSA</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in PSA biochemical parameter measurements (Phoenix Definition).</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of imaging response based on multi-parametric MRI</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Expanded Prostate Cancer Index Composite (EPIC) Questionnaire to measure quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of life is measured on a scale of 0 to 100, with higher scores representing a higher quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>International Index of Erectile Function (IIEF) Questionnaire assess sexual function</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Sexual function is measured on a scale of 0 to 75, with higher scores representing higher sexual function.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IGRT 24 Gy Single dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be treated using image-guided, volumetric intensity-modulated arc radiotherapy (IGRT-VMAT) with emphasis on normal tissue sparing and delivery accuracy via the use of devices that ensure stability and beam location reproducibility. Patients will be treated with a single fraction at a prescription dose of 24 Gy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>IGRT 24 Gy Single dose</intervention_name>
    <description>Previously untreated patients with prostate cancer will be treated with 24Gy in in one session.</description>
    <arm_group_label>IGRT 24 Gy Single dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Image-guided, volumetric intensity-modulated arc radiotherapy (IGRT-VMAT)</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients enrolled in the study will undergo IGRT-VMAT with state-of-the-art treatment-planning and quality assurance procedures with emphasis on normal tissue sparing and delivery accuracy via the use of devices that ensure stability and beam location reproducibility.</description>
    <arm_group_label>IGRT 24 Gy Single dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rectal balloon with air filling</intervention_name>
    <description>A rectal balloon with air filling will be used for prostate target immobilization and anatomical reproducibility.</description>
    <arm_group_label>IGRT 24 Gy Single dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Urethral catheter loaded with beacon transponders</intervention_name>
    <description>A urethral catheter loaded with beacon transponders will be used to ensure set-up reproducibility and online target tracking.</description>
    <arm_group_label>IGRT 24 Gy Single dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed study specific informed consent form;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologic confirmation of adenocarcinoma of the prostate by biopsy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Up to 6 months of previous hormonal therapy is allowed (but not required)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PSA ≤ 20 prior to hormone therapy (if given);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biopsy Gleason score ≤ 7&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No direct evidence of regional or distant metastases after appropriate staging studies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Performance Status 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  American Urological Association (AUA) score must be ≤ 20 (alpha blockers allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Computerized Tomography (CT) or Ultrasound-based volume estimation of prostate gland ≤&#xD;
             100 grams&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive lymph nodes or metastatic disease from prostate cancer on imaging studies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior invasive malignancy unless disease free for a minimum of 3 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  MRI evidence of radiographic T3, T4 or N1 disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tumour Clinical stage T3 or T4 on MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PSA &gt; 20 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gleason score &gt; 7&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous pelvic radiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous surgery for prostate cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent transurethral resection of the prostate (TURP) (less than 3 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous hormonal therapy given for more than 6 months prior to therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous significant urinary obstructive symptoms;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant psychiatric illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ultrasound or CT estimate of prostate volume &gt; 100 grams&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe, active co-morbidity.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carlo Greco, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fundacao Champalimaud</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Carlo Greco, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+351210480048</phone>
    <phone_ext>4230</phone_ext>
    <email>carlo.greco@fundacaochampalimaud.pt</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Champalimaud Foundation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lisboa</city>
        <zip>1400-038</zip>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Manuela Seixas</last_name>
      <phone>+351 9675289072</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Portugal</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 23, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 25, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 29, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 25, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 25, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 29, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Fundacao Champalimaud</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Carlo Greco, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

