<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03182231</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NL51980.091.15</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03182231</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>GLP1-imaging Before and After Bariatric Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Visualizing Beta Cells in Patients With T2D Before and After Bariatric Surgery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Radboud University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Rijnstate Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Radboud University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In order to evaluate the difference in beta cell mass in morbidly obese patients with type 2&#xD;
      diabetes mellitus (T2D) before and after Roux-en-Y gastric bypass (RYGB), investigators aim&#xD;
      to compare quantitative PET imaging of the pancreas in this patient group before and after&#xD;
      surgery. Investigators propose to measure the uptake of 68Ga-NODAGA-exendin-4 in the&#xD;
      pancreatic beta cells of these patients. Furthermore, investigators aim to compare uptake of&#xD;
      the radiolabeled tracer to beta cell function measured by laboratory parameters. These highly&#xD;
      relevant data will provide investigators with more information on the contribution of the&#xD;
      beta cells to the mechanisms behind resolution of T2D after bariatric surgery and on the&#xD;
      prognostic value of pre-operative beta cell mass determination to T2D resolution. This might&#xD;
      be of great interest for the assessment of RYGB as an alternative therapy in patients with&#xD;
      T2D and a BMI &lt;35, who currently do not meet the international guidelines for bariatric&#xD;
      surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The prevalence of Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus (T2D) in the Netherlands is 600.000-800.000 and&#xD;
      each year ~70.000 new patients are diagnosed. This increasing number of patients with T2D is&#xD;
      closely correlated with the obesity epidemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Obese patients with T2D are also at risk to develop dyslipidemia and hypertension. This&#xD;
      clustering of cardiovascular risk factors leads to an increased risk of micro-and&#xD;
      macrovascular long-term complications. In fact, patients with T2D have a 2-4 times increased&#xD;
      risk for cardiovascular disease. These complications seriously decrease the quality of life&#xD;
      and life expectancy of T2D patients. The burden of this disease affects our society as well.&#xD;
      Health care costs with respect to diabetes amounted 814 million euro in 2005 in the&#xD;
      Netherlands and indirect costs because of absence of work are unknown but thought to be&#xD;
      substantial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Weight loss is perhaps the most important therapeutic intervention in obese patients with&#xD;
      T2D. Weight loss intervenes in the underlying pathophysiology and restores insulin&#xD;
      sensitivity and sometimes even insulin secretion. In addition, it improves dyslipidemia and&#xD;
      hypertension. In contrast, most pharmacological interventions only relieve the symptoms of&#xD;
      the complex disease process underlying T2D whilst the disease process itself is not addressed&#xD;
      and even progresses in the course of time. Unfortunately, the effect of weight loss&#xD;
      interventions such as diet and lifestyle or even drugs (orlistat, sibutramine) is often&#xD;
      modest (3-5 kg) and short-lived.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Bariatric surgery and T2D remission Weight reducing surgery, i.e. bariatric surgery, is the&#xD;
      only intervention that leads to persistent weight loss and is superior above conventional&#xD;
      (non-surgical) treatment. Bariatric surgery can be divided into restrictive (gastric band or&#xD;
      sleeve) and malabsorptive (biliopancreatic diversion, BD) procedures or a combination of both&#xD;
      (Roux-en-Y gastric bypass, RYGB). Currently, RYGB is the most performed bariatric procedure.&#xD;
      The international indications for bariatric surgery are BMI &gt; 40kg/m2 or BMI &gt; 35 kg/m2 with&#xD;
      co-morbidities (e.g. T2D).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Besides weight loss, spectacular metabolic improvements after bariatric surgery are seen. In&#xD;
      patients with T2D, normalization of fasting plasma glucose and/or HbA1c without medication&#xD;
      (referred as &quot;resolution of T2D&quot;) was observed in 48% and 83% after gastric banding and RYGB,&#xD;
      respectively. Recently, randomized controlled trials showed the superiority of bariatric&#xD;
      surgery in glycemic control above conventional medical treatment. Furthermore, the&#xD;
      improvement in glycemic control is higher in RYGB compared to purely restrictive bariatric&#xD;
      procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The mechanism of diabetes resolution after RYGB is not completely understood and there is&#xD;
      evidence that it might not be dependent on weight loss only. Improvements in glycemic control&#xD;
      have been found within days after surgery, while significant weight loss has not yet been&#xD;
      achieved at this time. There are several hypotheses concerning the weight-independent effects&#xD;
      of bariatric surgery on insulin secretion. The most popular are the 'hindgut-hypothesis',&#xD;
      which states that expedited delivery of nutrients to the distal intestine enhances the&#xD;
      secretion of intestinal peptides like glucagon-like-peptide 1 (GLP1) and peptide YY and the&#xD;
      'foregut hypothesis', which states that the exclusion of the duodenum and proximal jejunum&#xD;
      from the transit of nutrients results in changes in secretion of intestinal peptides.&#xD;
      However, several other mechanisms, both in- and outside the intestines might play a role.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The beta cell function improves after RYGB in individuals with and without T2D, however it is&#xD;
      unclear whether the actual beta cell mass is subject to change after bariatric surgery.&#xD;
      Examination of the beta cell mass on autopsy specimens of persons who did not have bariatric&#xD;
      surgery, showed a decrease in beta cell mass in persons with T2D in one of the studies a&#xD;
      decrease was found in persons with pre-diabetes as well.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Few studies were performed that assessed beta cell mass after bariatric surgery. In&#xD;
      Goto-Kakizaki rats duodenal jejunal bypass was found to increase pancreatic concentrations of&#xD;
      vesicular monoamine transporter type 2 (VMAT2). VMAT2 was used as a biomarker for beta cells,&#xD;
      however later VMAT2 was found to be expressed on pancreatic polypeptide cells (PP cells) as&#xD;
      well. Furthermore, an increase in beta cell mass, beta cell number and extra islet beta cells&#xD;
      was found after RYGB in a porcine model and GK rat model. Studies in humans showed&#xD;
      conflicting results. Long term after gastric bypass, cases of hyperinsulinemic hypoglycemia&#xD;
      have been described, which are related to pancreatic islet hyperplasia or nesidioblastosis,&#xD;
      while this does not occur after purely restrictive surgery. However, beta cell mass was&#xD;
      assessed in six patients after gastric bypass by histological analysis of the pancreas after&#xD;
      pancreatectomy and did not find an increase in beta cell mass. These studies were performed&#xD;
      on pancreas specimen and not in vivo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The benefit of RYGB on glycemic control in morbid obese patients (BMI &gt; 35 kg/m2) with T2D is&#xD;
      confirmed and the Diabetes Surgery Summit Consensus Conference accepted bariatric surgery as&#xD;
      alternative therapy of obesity related T2D. They also consider expanding the indication for&#xD;
      bariatric surgery in obese patients with T2D who currently don't meet the international&#xD;
      guidelines for bariatric surgery. In this regard it would be helpful to identify&#xD;
      preoperatively which T2D patients would benefit from RYGB. Prognostic factors that were&#xD;
      described previously are the duration of diabetes, age, preoperatively HbA1c levels and&#xD;
      fasting C-peptide. However, the underlying cause of T2D resolution and the prognostic value&#xD;
      of these factors are not completely understood. Possibly, T2D resolution depends on the&#xD;
      preoperative available beta cell mass and function and increased beta cell failure or reduced&#xD;
      beta cell ass might decrease the chance of T2D resolution. Therefore, more information on the&#xD;
      effects of bariatric surgery on beta cell function and beta cell mass will be helpful to&#xD;
      further understand T2D resolution and the role of the beta cells. Thereby, preoperative beta&#xD;
      cell mass might be a prognostic factor of T2D resolution and helpful in identifying obese T2D&#xD;
      patients that will benefit from RYGB and expanding the indications for bariatric surgery for&#xD;
      those patients. For this purpose reliable, sensitive and specific visualization of living&#xD;
      pancreatic beta cells in vivo is important.&#xD;
&#xD;
      GLP-1 receptor imaging by PET For specific non-invasive imaging of beta cells, we have&#xD;
      developed a highly beta cell-specific radiolabeled exendin-based GLP-1 analog which, after&#xD;
      radiolabeling, can non-invasively be detected in the human body. GLP-1 is an incretin hormone&#xD;
      that specifically binds to beta cells and is responsible for post-prandial insulin-secretion.&#xD;
      Its specificity for beta cells has been shown and a linear correlation of the beta cell mass&#xD;
      and the signal obtained with this tracer has been established.&#xD;
&#xD;
      GLP-1R imaging has been shown to be suitable for imaging of insulin producing pancreatic&#xD;
      neuroendocrine tumours (IPPNET). Furthermore, the feasibility of visualization of&#xD;
      transplanted beta cells with GLP-1R imaging has been shown by imaging of autologous islets&#xD;
      transplanted into muscle.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 7, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients will receive an 68Ga-NODAGA-exendin-4 PET/CT scan before RYGB and 1 year after RYGB</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pancreatic uptake of 68Ga-NODAGA-exendin-4</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Change in tracer uptake before and after RYGB</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>T2D outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>after 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of tracer uptake with T2D outcome</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Beta cell function</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between tracer uptake and beta cell function</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</condition>
  <condition>Bariatric Surgery Candidate</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RYGB patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients who will receive a RYGB surgery</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>68Ga-NODAGA-exendin-4 PET/CT</intervention_name>
    <description>68Ga-NODAGA-exendin-4 PET/CT</description>
    <arm_group_label>RYGB patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Morbid obese T2D patient who will have RYGB at the Rijnstate in Arnhem&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Mild T2D:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  C-peptide &gt; 1.0 nmol/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Only metformin usage as anti-diabetic medication&#xD;
&#xD;
        Progressive T2D:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  C-peptide &lt; 1.0 nmol/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insulin and/or sulfonylurea (SU) usage&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting glucose &lt; 6 at time C-peptide was determined&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Liver failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI &gt; 50 kg/m-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous treatment with synthetic exendin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breast feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Kidney failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No signed informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rijnstate hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Arnhem</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Laura Deden, MSc</last_name>
      <email>l.deden@rijnstate.nl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Radboudumc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nijmegen</city>
        <zip>6500HB</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marti Boss, Msc</last_name>
      <phone>+312436</phone>
      <phone_ext>67243</phone_ext>
      <email>marti.boss@radboudumc.nl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 29, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 7, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 9, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>exendin</keyword>
  <keyword>GLP1</keyword>
  <keyword>beta cell mass</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Exenatide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

