<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03180034</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCI-2020-08550</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2020-08550</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>999917108</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>17-C-N108</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03180034</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparing One or Two Doses of the Human Papillomavirus Vaccine for the Prevention of Human Papillomavirus Infection, ESCUDDO Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>ESCUDDO</acronym>
  <official_title>A Scientific Evaluation of One or Two Doses of Vaccine Against Human Papillomavirus: the ESCUDDO Study (&quot;Estudio de Comparacion de Una y Dos Dosis de Vacunas Contra el Virus de Papiloma Humano (VPH)&quot;)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase IV trial investigates whether one dose of a human papillomavirus vaccine works as&#xD;
      well as two doses in preventing human papillomavirus (HPV) infection. Certain types of HPV&#xD;
      cause almost all cases of cervical cancer. Vaccines that protect against infection with these&#xD;
      types of human papillomavirus may reduce the risk of cervical cancer. Both Gardasil-9 and&#xD;
      Cervarix protect against HPV 16 and 18, which cause 70% of all cervical cancers. However, HPV&#xD;
      vaccination rates are too low, especially in countries with very high rates of cervical&#xD;
      cancer. HPV vaccines are expensive-many countries cannot afford them-more than one dose is&#xD;
      needed, and giving multiple doses is difficult. Researchers want to find out if one dose&#xD;
      prevents HPV infection. If it does, more people might get the vaccine.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. For each vaccine separately, to evaluate non-inferiority of one compared to two&#xD;
      vaccination doses in the prevention of new HPV16/18 cervical HPV infections that persist 6+&#xD;
      months in girls ages 12-16 years at vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. For each vaccine separately, to evaluate one dose of HPV vaccination compared to no&#xD;
      vaccination in the protection against HPV16/18 cervical HPV infections that persist 6+ months&#xD;
      in girls ages 12-16 years at vaccination; protection resultant from two HPV vaccine doses&#xD;
      compared to no vaccination will also be investigated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. For each vaccine separately, to compare immunogenicity via measurement of serum antibodies&#xD;
      between girls who received one and two doses of the HPV vaccines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. For the nonavalent vaccine, demonstrate non-inferiority of one versus two doses in the&#xD;
      prevention of any new vaccine-type HPV infection (i.e., aggregate HPV 16/18/31/33/45/52/58)&#xD;
      that persist 6+ months (note: HPV6/11, the noncarcinogenic HPV types responsible for genital&#xD;
      warts, will be investigated as an ancillary objective, per item 1, sub-item iv, below).&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. For each vaccine separately, demonstrate non-inferiority of one versus two doses in the&#xD;
      prevention of any new carcinogenic HPV cervical infection (vaccine and/or non-vaccine types)&#xD;
      that persists 6+ months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. Conduct a cost and cost-effectiveness evaluation of HPV vaccination with one versus two&#xD;
      doses of the nonavalent and bivalent vaccines in the setting of Costa Rica.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ANCILLARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. For each vaccine separately, demonstrate non-inferiority of one versus two doses in the&#xD;
      prevention of study endpoints (including but not limited to those listed below) including a&#xD;
      comparison to unvaccinated girls:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ia. Any new HPV16, HPV18, or HPV16/18 infection (i.e., one-time detection). IIb. Any new&#xD;
      carcinogenic-type HPV infection (i.e., one-time HPV detection of aggregate HPV vaccine and/or&#xD;
      non-vaccine HPV types).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ic. Any new vaccine-type HPV infection (i.e., aggregate HPV 16/18/31/33/45/52/58).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Id. Any new HPV6/11 infection (i.e., one-time detection). II. Compare HPV attack rate and&#xD;
      immunogenicity of Merck nonavalent versus (vs.) GlaxoSmithKline (GSK) bivalent vaccines with&#xD;
      respect to number of vaccine doses received in the prevention of six-month persistent&#xD;
      HPV16/18 and any carcinogenic infections, and in the prevention of one-time detection of&#xD;
      these types.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. Conditional on demonstrating inferiority of one versus two doses of the vaccine:&#xD;
&#xD;
      IIIa. To evaluate inferiority of one versus two doses. IIIb. To evaluate reduction in the HPV&#xD;
      attack rate of one and two doses compared to none by time (years 1 through 4).&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. Obtain participants authorization to passively track cervical pre-cancer, carcinoma in&#xD;
      situ and cervical cancer outcomes through the national tumor registry, national cytology&#xD;
      laboratory, social security registries, national cytology laboratory, and other resources&#xD;
      after the trial ends (i.e., to continue indefinitely or until consent is rescinded).&#xD;
&#xD;
      V. Establish a biobank including blood components (for example but not limited to serum, red&#xD;
      blood cells, plasma, peripheral blood mononuclear cells), urine, oral and cervical swab&#xD;
      samples collected from girls in the randomized trial and the epidemiologic HPV survey for&#xD;
      futures analysis related to HPV infection, associated diseases, and effects of the vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: There are two components to the study: (1) a controlled, randomized, double-blinded&#xD;
      non-inferiority clinical trial to compare one-dose to two-dose vaccination among twenty&#xD;
      thousand girls 12 to 16 years old; and (2) a concurrent epidemiologic survey for HPV status&#xD;
      among four thousand unvaccinated women 17-20 years old. Trial participants are randomized to&#xD;
      1 of 4 arms. Survey participants are assigned to Arm V.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM I: Participants receive recombinant human papillomavirus nonavalent vaccine (Gardasil)&#xD;
      intramuscularly (IM) at month 0 and diphtheria toxoid/tetanus toxoid/acellular pertussis&#xD;
      vaccine adsorbed (DTaP) IM at month 6.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM II: Participants receive recombinant human papillomavirus bivalent vaccine (Cervarix) IM&#xD;
      at month 0 and DTaP IM at month 6.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM III: Participants receive Gardasil IM at month 0 and 6.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM IV: Participants receive Cervarix IM at month 0 and 6.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study intervention, trial participants are followed up every 6 months for&#xD;
      up to 4 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM V: A concurrent epidemiologic survey for HPV status among unvaccinated women. Survey&#xD;
      participants are followed for two study visits six months apart to determine their HPV DNA&#xD;
      status, with no further follow-up. These women will be offered HPV vaccination (Cervarix) at&#xD;
      the two study visits.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 29, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of persistent human papillomavirus (HPV)-16 and/or HPV-18 cervical infections</measure>
    <time_frame>Months 42 and 48</time_frame>
    <description>To be considered incident and persistent, an HPV-16 and/or HPV-18 infection must fulfill the following criteria: Two same-type HPV positive (by polymerase chain reaction [PCR]) test results 3+ months apart at consecutive study visits reported after the 6-month visit (i.e. 12-month visit or later); type-specific HPV negative (by urine or, if available, PCR) test results from baseline and 6 month visits.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of persistent HPV-16 and/or HPV-18 cervical infections</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>To be considered incident and persistent, an HPV-16 and/or HPV-18 infection must fulfill the following criteria: Two same-type HPV positive (by PCR) test results 3+ months apart at consecutive study visits reported after the 6-month visit (i.e. 12-month visit or later); type-specific HPV negative (by urine or, if available, PCR) test results from baseline and 6 month visits.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenicity of one or two doses of Cervarix</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be compared between girls who received one or two doses of recombinant human papillomavirus bivalent vaccine (Cervarix). Measured via measurement of serum antibodies.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenicity of one or two doses of Gardasil 9</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be compared between girls who received one or two doses of recombinant human papillomavirus nonavalent vaccine (Gardasil 9). Measured via measurement of serum antibodies.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of any new HPV infection (after Gardasil 9)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Demonstrate non-inferiority of one versus two doses of Gardasil 9 in the prevention of any new vaccine type HPV infection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of any new carcinogenic HPV cervical infection (after Cervarix)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Demonstrate non-inferiority of one versus two doses of Cervarix in the prevention of any new carcinogenic HPV cervical infection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cost and cost-effectiveness evaluation of HPV vaccination in Costa Rica</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">25000</enrollment>
  <condition>Human Papillomavirus Infection</condition>
  <condition>Human Papillomavirus-Related Cervical Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I (Gardasil, DTaP)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive Gardasil IM at month 0 and DTaP IM at month 6.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (Cervarix, DTaP)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive Cervarix IM at month 0 and DTaP IM at month 6.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm III (Gardasil)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive Gardasil IM at month 0 and 6.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm IV (Cervarix)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive Cervarix IM at month 0 and 6.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm V (epidemiologic survey)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>A concurrent epidemiologic survey for HPV status among unvaccinated women. Survey participants are followed for two study visits six months apart to determine their HPV DNA status, with no further follow-up. These women will be offered HPV vaccination (Cervarix) at the two study visits.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Diphtheria Toxoid/Tetanus Toxoid/Acellular Pertussis Vaccine Adsorbed</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IM</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I (Gardasil, DTaP)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (Cervarix, DTaP)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Adacel</other_name>
    <other_name>Daptacel</other_name>
    <other_name>Diphtheria and Tetanus Toxoids and Acellular Pertussis Vaccine Adsorbed</other_name>
    <other_name>Diphtheria Toxoid Tetanus Toxoid Acellular Pertussis Vaccine Adsorbed</other_name>
    <other_name>Diphtheria Toxoid/Tetanus Toxoid/Acellular Pertussis Vaccine</other_name>
    <other_name>DTaP</other_name>
    <other_name>Infanrix</other_name>
    <other_name>Tripedia</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaire Administration</intervention_name>
    <description>Ancillary studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I (Gardasil, DTaP)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (Cervarix, DTaP)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm III (Gardasil)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm IV (Cervarix)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Recombinant Human Papillomavirus Bivalent Vaccine</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IM</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (Cervarix, DTaP)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm IV (Cervarix)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cervarix</other_name>
    <other_name>GSK-580299</other_name>
    <other_name>HPV 16/18 L1 VLP/AS04 VAC</other_name>
    <other_name>HPV-16/18 VLP/AS04 Vaccine</other_name>
    <other_name>Human Papillomavirus 16/18 L1 Virus-Like Particle/AS04 Vaccine</other_name>
    <other_name>Human Papillomavirus Bivalent Types 16 and 18 Vaccine, Recombinant</other_name>
    <other_name>Human Papillomavirus Vaccine L1 16,18</other_name>
    <other_name>Human Papillomavirus Vaccine, L1 Type 16, 18</other_name>
    <other_name>Recombinant HPV Bivalent Vaccine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Recombinant Human Papillomavirus Nonavalent Vaccine</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IM</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I (Gardasil, DTaP)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm III (Gardasil)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Gardasil 9</other_name>
    <other_name>Nonavalent HPV VLP Vaccine</other_name>
    <other_name>Recombinant HPV Nonavalent Vaccine</other_name>
    <other_name>Recombinant Human Papillomavirus 9-valent Vaccine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Living in the study area without plans to move outside the country in the next six&#xD;
             months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to communicate with study personnel&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to participate in the study and sign the informed assent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Supported in study participation by at least one of their parents (or guardians), who&#xD;
             is willing to sign the informed consent document&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In good health as determined by a medical history (physical exam will be conducted if&#xD;
             necessary per the doctor's criterion)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  They have a diagnosis of an autoimmune, degenerative, or neurological disease without&#xD;
             treatment or adequate control; a progressive or severe neurological disease; a genetic&#xD;
             immunodeficiency; or any other serious chronic disease without treatment and / or&#xD;
             adequate control that, according to the principal investigator or designee, for which&#xD;
             vaccination is contraindicated (NOTE: Potential participants with these conditions can&#xD;
             be included after consultation with the external medical advisor of the study or with&#xD;
             an appropriate specialist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  They are allergic to one of the vaccine components, yeast, or latex&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The clinician determining the eligibility in agreement with principal investigator&#xD;
             considers that there is a reason that precludes participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  They have been vaccinated against HPV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The girl or her parent/legal guardian does not have an identification document&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>20 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aimee R Kreimer</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Agencia Costarricense de Investigaciones Biomédicas (ACIB)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Liberia</city>
        <state>Guanacaste</state>
        <country>Costa Rica</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Costa Rica</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 7, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 7, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 8, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Papillomavirus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

