<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00825591</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0804003699</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>TRSH-SAR</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00825591</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Biological Clock Dysfunction in Optic Nerve Hypoplasia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Identification and Treatment of Biological Clock Dysfunction in Optic Nerve Hypoplasia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Children's Hospital Los Angeles</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Optic Nerve Hypoplasia (ONH) is a leading cause of blindness in children. For&#xD;
      unclear reasons, the incidence of ONH is increasing, with ONH affecting about 1 in 10,000&#xD;
      live-born infants. In addition to visual deficits, ONH is associated with varying degrees of&#xD;
      hypopituitarism, developmental delay, brain malformations and obesity. Although genetic&#xD;
      mutations have been rarely observed to result in ONH, the causes of ONH are largely not&#xD;
      known. In limited anatomical observations, the suprachiasmatic nuclei (SCN) located in the&#xD;
      anterior hypothalamus, which generate circadian rhythms, have been observed to be abnormal in&#xD;
      children with ONH. Thus, children with ONH may have biological clock dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In collaborative studies with Dr. Mark Borchert of Childrens Hospital Los Angeles (CHLA), we&#xD;
      have recently discovered that one-half of children with ONH have grossly abnormal sleep-wake&#xD;
      patterns, as assessed by actigraphy. Although not known for children with ONH, abnormal&#xD;
      sleep-wake patterns have been observed to be associated with neurocognitive impairment and&#xD;
      obesity. We also observe that nocturnal melatonin administration can improve abnormal&#xD;
      sleep-wake cycles in these children, raising the possibility that it will be possible to&#xD;
      treat abnormal rhythmicity in children with ONH.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objectives and Hypotheses. Our objectives are to define the scope and problems related to&#xD;
      biological clock disorders in children with ONH and to develop effective treatments for this&#xD;
      condition. Based on our observations, we hypothesize: (1) Daily rest-activity patterns and&#xD;
      sleep will be abnormal in up to 50% of children with ONH. (2) It is possible to identify risk&#xD;
      factors for abnormal circadian system function and sleep problems in ONH. (3) Nocturnal&#xD;
      melatonin administration will improve abnormal sleep and activity patterns in children with&#xD;
      ONH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design: These studies will involve collaborative efforts between Yale University and Dr. Mark&#xD;
      Borchert of Childrens Hospital Los Angeles, who follows the largest population of children&#xD;
      with ONH in the world. We will study children ages 2-10 years with documented ONH using&#xD;
      standard criteria. Based on these criteria, we have more than 100 eligible patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To test our hypotheses, we will: (1) examine expressed rhythmicity in children with ONH.&#xD;
      These studies will use actigraphy, sleep questionnaires, and assessment of melatonin&#xD;
      secretory profiles. (2) We will correlate hypothalamic anatomical abnormalities and the&#xD;
      degree endocrine dysfunction with sleep and expressed rhythmicity. (3) We will test if&#xD;
      short-term administration of melatonin improves sleep-wake patterns in children with&#xD;
      abnormally-expressed rhythmicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential Impact: Our preliminary data raise the possibility that children with ONH will have&#xD;
      circadian system dysfunction resulting in abnormal rhythmicity and sleep. However, to date&#xD;
      there have been no formal attempts to identify children with ONH who are at risk for such&#xD;
      problems, nor have there been efforts aimed at developing potential treatments. The proposed&#xD;
      prospective clinical study will represent an important attempt to identify a group of&#xD;
      children with circadian system dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the completion of this study, we anticipate having determined risk factors for circadian&#xD;
      system dysfunction in children with ONH. Insights gained from these studies should lead to&#xD;
      the development of new approaches for treating circadian clock lesions in ONH, with the hope&#xD;
      of improving the well-being of circadian system function in the boys and girls with this&#xD;
      condition.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of rest-activity patterns</measure>
    <time_frame>two years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Biological Clock Dysfunction</condition>
  <condition>Optic Nerve Hypoplasia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Individuals with abnormal rhythmicity will be treated with melatonin to assess if sleep patterns are improved.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Melatonin</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral administration before bed. We will test two doses (0.5 or 3.0 mg/m2. 6 week duration.)</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo Comparator</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral administration before bed. 6 week duration.</description>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed diagnosis of ONH (Diagnosis will be confirmed by ocular fundus&#xD;
             photography.Disc-macula distance 0.35 or below. In eyes without ONH, the DD/DM ratio&#xD;
             is greater than 0.3581.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ages 2-10 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to ambulate independently&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Under care of endocrinologist if on pituitary hormone replacement therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-ambulatory&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardio-respiratory disorder&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Casandra Fink</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Children's Hospital Los Angeles</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Hospital of Los Angeles</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90027</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 13, 2008</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 19, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 21, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 25, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Esther Nakamura-Reyes</name_title>
    <organization>Childrens Hospital of Los Angeles</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>optic nerve hypoplasia</keyword>
  <keyword>septo-optic dysplasia</keyword>
  <keyword>melatonin</keyword>
  <keyword>circadian rhythm</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Optic Nerve Hypoplasia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Melatonin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

