<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00823186</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>97-0365A3</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00823186</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dose-finding Study of Weekly Paclitaxel and Cisplatin in FIGO IB2 and Bulky IIA Cervical Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>Chemothreapy</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase I Dose Escalation Study Of Weekly Paclitaxel and Cisplatin Followed by Radical Hysterectomy in FIGO IB2 and Bulky IIA Cervical Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Chang Gung Memorial Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sinphar Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Chang Gung Memorial Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I study is designed to establish an optimal dose of paclitaxel, under a fixed&#xD;
      cisplatin dose at 40 mg/m2, delivered every week for three weeks, as neoadjuvant therapy&#xD;
      before radical hysterectomy in bulky (FIGO IB2 or FIGO IIA with primary tumor dimension &gt; 4&#xD;
      cm) squamous cell cervical cancer. This study will be conducted at all branches of Chang Gung&#xD;
      Memorial Hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The starting dose of paclitaxel is 50 mg/m2, and will be escalated by increments of 10 mg/m2&#xD;
      to a maximum dose of 80 mg/m2. The drugs will be administered sequentially (paclitaxel first,&#xD;
      followed by cisplatin) within one day every week for three cycles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A cohort of 3 patients, who are assessable for toxicity, is treated at each dose level. Each&#xD;
      patient receives a fixed dose of paclitaxel and cisplatin, without modification. If none of&#xD;
      the first 3 patients experiences a dose limiting toxicity (DLT, see definition below this&#xD;
      paragraph), then escalation to the next dose level will proceed. If one patient develops a&#xD;
      DLT, the cohort will be expanded to 6 patients. If no more than 1 of these 6 patients&#xD;
      experiences a DLT, then escalation to the next dose level will proceed. The maximum tolerated&#xD;
      dose (MTD) is the highest dose level at which no more than 1 of 6 patients experience a DLT.&#xD;
      This dose level will be considered as the recommended dose for Phase II study. Although&#xD;
      efficacy evaluation is not the main purpose of this study, a response rate of 60%, evaluated&#xD;
      immediately before or at surgery, in all cases who have undergone 2 cycles of therapy is&#xD;
      preset as a requirement for further phase II study using this regimen.The primary goal of NAC&#xD;
      in cervical cancer is to improve the feasibility of surgical treatment, radical hysterectomy,&#xD;
      without delaying the scheduled surgery or increasing the surgical risk or morbidity.&#xD;
      Therefore, the definition of DLT for NAC is responded to this principle, in addition to the&#xD;
      standard dose-limiting toxicity for phase I study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a multi-center, open-label, phase I study of paclitaxel and cisplatin as neoadjuvant&#xD;
      therapy in patients with FIGO IB2 or bulky IIA, squamous cell cervical carcinoma of the&#xD;
      uterine cervix.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is mainly for the dose-finding of paclitaxel, combining with a fixed cisplatinum&#xD;
      dose, as neoadjuvant chemotherapy on a weekly basis. The optimal dose of paclitaxel is&#xD;
      principally defined as the highest dose that allow at least 5/6 patients, after NAC, to&#xD;
      undergo scheduled radical hysterectomy. A subsequent toxicity assessment to evaluate the&#xD;
      impact of this neoadjuvant chemotherapy to the recovery of the following radical&#xD;
      hysterectomy, and efficacy assessment is set as the second purpose of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  to establish an optimal dose of weekly cisplatin plus paclitaxel for 3 cycles as&#xD;
           neoadjuvant chemotherapy (NAC) for FIGO IB2 and bulky IIA, squamous cell cervical&#xD;
           cancer, followed by radical hysterectomy and pelvic lymphadenectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  to evaluate the toxicity of the study regimen and its impact to the radical hysterectomy&#xD;
           after neoadjuvant chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  to evaluate the overall tumor response to the neoadjuvant chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
      An estimated of 8 to 21 patients will be enrolled in this study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Enrolling by invitation</last_known_status>
  <start_date>February 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>to establish an optimal dose of weekly cisplatin plus paclitaxel for 3 cyclesas neoadjuvant chemotherapy (NAC) for FIGO IB2 and bulky IIA, squamous cell cervical cancer, followed by radical hysterectomy and pelvic lymphadenectomy</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>to evaluate the toxicity of the study regimen and its impact to the radical hysterectomy after neoadjuvant chemotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>to evaluate the overall tumor response to the neoadjuvant chemotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">21</enrollment>
  <condition>Cervical Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phyxol,cancer,intra vascular flow</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>weekly cisplatin plus paclitaxel for 3 cycles as neoadjuvant chemotherapy (NAC) for FIGO IB2 and bulky IIA, squamous cell cervical cancer followed by radical hysterectomy and pelvic lymphedectomy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Phyxol(Paclitaxel)</intervention_name>
    <description>Paclitaxel is 5ß,20-Epoxyl-1,2α,4,7,β 10 β,13 α-hexahydroxytax-11-en-9-one 4,10&#xD;
-diacetae 2-benzoate 13-ester with (2R,3S)-N-benzoyl-3-phenylisocerine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phyxol,cancer,intra vascular flow</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        women aged 35-70 years with all of the following criteria: untreated, histologically&#xD;
        confirmed squamous cell carcinoma of the uterine cervix FIGO stage IB2 or bulky IIA, with&#xD;
        tumor extension limited to within the upper one third of the vaginal wall. Bulky tumor is&#xD;
        defined as (a) a visible cervical tumor with the largest diameter &gt;4 cm or (b) a cervix&#xD;
        expanded to &gt; 4 cm as a result of tumor infiltration by pelvic examination and verified by&#xD;
        magnetic resonance image (MRI), 3-dimensional (D) computed tomography (CT), or 3-D&#xD;
        ultrasound study no suspicious lymph node metastasis as no enlarged lymph node or&#xD;
        extrapelvic spread of cancer detected by MRI, or negative cytologic or histologic study of&#xD;
        the suspicious node(s) (for those also participating PET-CT monitoring response trial, only&#xD;
        abnormal FDG uptake in pelvic node(s) without proven nodal or extrapelvic metastasis are&#xD;
        eligible)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Histological or cytological documented pelvic lymph node or extrapelvic metastasis,&#xD;
        concurrent or history of malignant tumor(s) other than treated nonmelanoma skin cancer had&#xD;
        undergone surgical procedure other than cervical biopsy or had received cytotoxic procedure&#xD;
        including chemotherapy, radiotherapy or treatment with biologic response modifier(s) for&#xD;
        the cervical tumor participate in investigational treatment for the cervical cancer history&#xD;
        of allergic reaction to platinum or paclitaxel uncontrolled intercurrent illness including,&#xD;
        but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure,&#xD;
        unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that&#xD;
        would limit compliance with study requirements pregnant or breast feeding women, a urinary&#xD;
        pregnancy test must be performed on all patients who are of child-bearing potential before&#xD;
        entering the study and the result must be negative&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>HAO LIN, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Chang Gung Memorial Hospital, Kaohsiung</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chang Gung Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tao Yuan</city>
        <state>Lin kou</state>
        <zip>333</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chang Gung Memory Hpspital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chia Yi</city>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Taipei Chang Gung Memory Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 13, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 14, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 15, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 3, 2010</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 3, 2010</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 5, 2010</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology</name_title>
    <organization>Chang Gung Memorial Hospital, Kaohsiung</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>cervical carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>neoadjuvant chemotherapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

