<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00827801</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2007-0722</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00827801</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>M. D. Anderson Symptom Inventory - Heart Failure (MDASI-HF) Symptom Management Program</brief_title>
  <official_title>MDASI-HF: Bridging the Symptom Management Gap in Patients With Cancer and Concurrent Heart Failure to Improve Outcomes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Primary Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To determine if there is a reduction in the mean symptom severity scores for the heart&#xD;
      failure specific symptom items between baseline and at the end of three months between&#xD;
      patients whose symptoms are managed using the MDASI-HF symptom assessment scores (treatment&#xD;
      group) as a decision making guide, as compared to patients managed without using the MDASI-HF&#xD;
      symptom assessment scores (control group).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Examine the correlation between mean symptom severity scores and the secondary endpoints&#xD;
           of: a) exercise tolerance ( 6-minute walk), b) NYHA (New York Heart Association)&#xD;
           functional classification, c) B-type natriuretic peptide (a biomarker for heart&#xD;
           failure), and d) dose titration of HF (heart failure) medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Define symptom severity critical values in cancer patients with concurrent heart failure&#xD;
           that trigger clinical intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Identify symptom clusters which may occur in cancer patients with concurrent heart&#xD;
           failure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background for Study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Heart failure means that the heart isn't pumping as well as it should be. Your body depends&#xD;
      on the heart's pumping action to deliver oxygen- and nutrient-rich blood to the body's cells.&#xD;
      When the cells are nourished properly, the body can function normally. With heart failure,&#xD;
      the weakened heart can't supply the cells with enough blood. This results in fatigue and&#xD;
      shortness of breath. Everyday activities such as walking, climbing stairs, or carrying&#xD;
      groceries can become very difficult.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the standard of care, patients tell their healthcare staff about their symptoms and are&#xD;
      treated accordingly. The MDASI-HF program is a tool that is designed to try to improve this&#xD;
      process by measuring how severe symptoms may be in patients with cancer and heart failure, as&#xD;
      well as measuring how these symptoms may be affecting these patients' daily lives.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To take part in the MDASI-HF program, patients complete a questionnaire at clinic visits and&#xD;
      at home. The home questionnaire is done over the phone. The symptom information that the&#xD;
      patients report is provided to the healthcare staff, allowing the healthcare staff to closely&#xD;
      monitor the symptoms and respond as needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You must have permission from your cardiologist in order to take part in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
      If you agree to take part in this study, you will be randomly assigned (as in the flip of a&#xD;
      coin) to 1 of 2 groups. However, for your safety, the doctor may assign you to a certain&#xD;
      group based on factors such as your age, sex, and the status of the heart disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will complete the MDASI-HF questionnaire, which asks about symptoms. If you&#xD;
      are in Group 1, your questionnaire responses will be provided to your doctor so the doctor&#xD;
      can use that information to manage your symptoms. If you are in Group 2, your questionnaire&#xD;
      responses, completed either in person or via phone, will not be provided to your doctor. All&#xD;
      participants in this study will receive appropriate medical care for management of symptoms.&#xD;
      Both groups will have all the same procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
      During this study, you will have a clinic visit to your doctor's office on Day 1 of the study&#xD;
      and at Weeks 4, 8, and 12.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On Day 1, the following tests and procedures will be performed:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  You will watch a patient and family education video while you wait for the doctor. The&#xD;
           video discusses heart failure, drugs, diet, exercise, and emotional issues related to&#xD;
           living with heart failure. The video is less than 15 minutes long.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  You will be given a patient diary and a booklet that explains how to manage heart&#xD;
           failure. You will complete this diary once a day, which should take about 5-10 minutes&#xD;
           each time. In this diary, you will record your weight, blood pressure, and any drugs you&#xD;
           are taking. You should bring the diary back to the clinic at each study visit to have it&#xD;
           reviewed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  You will complete the MDASI-HF questionnaire in the clinic. This questionnaire asks you&#xD;
           to rate your symptoms on a scale of 0 to 10. A score of 0 would mean the symptom is not&#xD;
           happening and a score of 10 means the symptom is at its worst. The symptoms include&#xD;
           heart-related symptoms and other symptoms that may be related to cancer or treatments.&#xD;
           The questionnaire also asks you how the symptoms may have interfered with your daily&#xD;
           life. Completing the questionnaire should take about 15 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The distance you are able to walk in 6 minutes will be measured. You will sign a&#xD;
           separate consent form that will describe this 6-minute walk test in more detail.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood (about 1 teaspoon) will be drawn for routine tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood (about 1 teaspoon) will be drawn for biomarker testing. The biomarker being&#xD;
           studied is a chemical &quot;marker&quot; in the blood that may be related to heart failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If you have not had one in the last 90 days, you will have an echocardiogram performed&#xD;
           to check your heart function as part of your standard of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If you have not had one in the last month, you will have an electrocardiogram (ECG -- a&#xD;
           test that measures the electrical activity of the heart).&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Weeks 4 and 8, you will complete the MDASI-HF questionnaire in the clinic. Blood (about 2&#xD;
      teaspoons) will be drawn for routine tests. Blood (about 1 teaspoon) will be drawn for&#xD;
      biomarker testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phone Questionnaire Completion Between Visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Between study visits (at Weeks 1, 2, 3, 5, 6, 7, 9, 10, and 11), you will receive a phone&#xD;
      call once a week. The phone system is &quot;automated,&quot; and it asks you the same MDASI-HF&#xD;
      questions as the questionnaire that you completed at the clinic. For all of the questions,&#xD;
      you will enter a number on your phone's keypad to answer the questions. Completing the phone&#xD;
      questionnaire should take about 10-15 minutes each time. At the end of the phone&#xD;
      questionnaire, the system will direct you in scheduling your next call.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For Group 1 participants only, if you report that any pain or shortness of breath symptoms at&#xD;
      5, or any other symptom is as severe as 7 or higher, the phone system will automatically&#xD;
      contact the clinic nurse using an alert. The nurse will call you back within 24 hours. Based&#xD;
      on the symptom(s), the nurse will advise you about what to do next (for example, change the&#xD;
      dose of your drugs, come in to the clinic, or go to the emergency center). The nurse will&#xD;
      also contact your doctor right away if necessary. In addition to reviewing these severe&#xD;
      symptoms that you may report, the study staff will be reviewing all of your questionnaire&#xD;
      responses on a routine basis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For Group 2 participants only, your telephone answers will not contact a clinic nurse. If you&#xD;
      experience severe pain, shortness of breath, or your symptoms worsen, please contact the&#xD;
      clinic nurse right away at the numbers in your instruction booklet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Management of Symptoms:&#xD;
&#xD;
      No matter if you are in Group 1 or Group 2, if at any time you notice that any of your&#xD;
      symptoms seem to be getting worse, you should call the clinic nurse right away at the numbers&#xD;
      in your instruction booklet. The clinic nurse will follow up to advise you about what to do&#xD;
      next. For example, the nurse may change the dose of your drugs, tell you to come into the&#xD;
      clinic, or tell you to go to the emergency center. The nurse will also contact your doctor&#xD;
      right away, if necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If you feel your symptoms are severe, visit the emergency room or call 911.&#xD;
&#xD;
      End-of-Study Visit:&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Week 12, the following tests and procedures will be performed:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  You will complete the MDASI-HF questionnaire using the computer in the clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood (about 1 tablespoon) will be drawn for routine tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood (about 1 teaspoon) will be drawn for biomarker testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  You will perform a 6-minute walk test.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  An echocardiogram and ECG will be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the Week 12 visit, your participation in this study will be over.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is an investigational study. At this time, the MDASI-HF program is only being used in&#xD;
      research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up 144 patients will take part in this study. All will be enrolled at M. D. Anderson.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Symptom Severity Scores (MDASI-HF Symptom Assessment Scores)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and at end of 3 Months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">26</enrollment>
  <condition>Heart Failure</condition>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <description>MDASI-HF questionnaire provided to Doctor for symptom management.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <description>MDASI-HF questionnaire collected not provided to Doctor.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MDASI-HF Questionnaire</intervention_name>
    <description>M. D. Anderson Symptom Inventory - Heart Failure (MDASI-HF) questionnaire rating symptoms given in clinic Day 1, Weeks 4 &amp; 8.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>survey</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All cancer patients, 18 years of age or older, with a concurrent diagnosis of heart&#xD;
        failure, newly diagnosed or diagnosed within past 1 year.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. All cancer patients with a concurrent diagnosis of heart failure. Heart failure can be&#xD;
             systolic (&lt;40% ejection fraction) or diastolic (&gt;40% ejection fraction). Functioning&#xD;
             at New York Heart Association class II, III, or IV.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age 18 years and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Able to give informed consent to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Working phone number to contact patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Live within the 100 mile radius of the Houston area while enrolled in the study for&#xD;
             the three month duration&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Younger than 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. With a known diagnosis of dementia or Alzheimer's disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Not familiar with the English language. The MDASI-HF is currently available in the&#xD;
             English language only.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anecita Fadol, PhD, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UT MD Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UT MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>UT MD Anderson Cancer Center website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 22, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 22, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 23, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 19, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 19, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">July 23, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Heart Failure</keyword>
  <keyword>HF</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer and Concurrent Heart Failure</keyword>
  <keyword>MDASI-HF Symptom Management Program</keyword>
  <keyword>MDASI-HF</keyword>
  <keyword>MDASI-HF questionnaire</keyword>
  <keyword>M. D. Anderson Symptom Inventory - Heart Failure</keyword>
  <keyword>Questionnaire</keyword>
  <keyword>Symptom Management Gap</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

