<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04193592</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>14172/2019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04193592</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Pirfenidone Treatment in HPS-ILD</brief_title>
  <acronym>PEARL</acronym>
  <official_title>Pirfenidone in the Treatment of Hermansky Pudlak Syndrome (HPS) - Related Interstitial Lung Disease (ILD)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jesse Roman</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Genentech, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Thomas Jefferson University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research study will explore the safety and efficacy of the drug, pirfenidone, in&#xD;
      patients with a diagnosis of Hermansky-Pudlak Syndrome (HPS) who have an associated&#xD;
      interstitial lung disease (ILD) over a planned period of 56 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      An open-label clinical study designed to evaluate the efficacy and safety of administering&#xD;
      pirfeniodne for 52 weeks to subjects with HPS-ILD. Patients meeting the eligibility criteria&#xD;
      without contraindications for the study will be provided pirfenidone 2403 mg/day. Efficacy&#xD;
      will be evaluated through interval testing of pulmonary function tests, patient reported&#xD;
      outcomes, adverse events and survival. Safety will be assessed by determining adverse events,&#xD;
      hospitalizations, and all-cause mortality.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>open label drug</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Forced Vital Capacity (FVC)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 6 months, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The incidence of decline in percent predicted FVC of 10 % or greater from baseline measured at 6 and 12 months</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Forced Vital Capacity (FVC)</measure>
    <time_frame>week 52</time_frame>
    <description>1. The Incidence of decline from baseline in percent predicted FVC of 10% or greater during the 52 week treatment period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Diffusion Capacity (DLCO)</measure>
    <time_frame>week 52</time_frame>
    <description>2. The Incidence of decline from baseline in percent predicted DLCO of 15% or greater during the 52 week treatment period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Treatment Emergent Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>week 52</time_frame>
    <description>3. The number of participants with and number of treatment emergent adverse events reported by the participant will be collected.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Treatment Emergent Serious Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>week 52</time_frame>
    <description>4. The number of participants with and number of treatment-emergent serious adverse events reported by the participants will be collected.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Hermansky Pudlak Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Interstitial Lung Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Oral Pirfenidone 2403 mg per day</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Enrolled subjects will receive oral pirfenidone 801 mg taken three times a day. Pirfenidone will be supplied in 267 mg capsules.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pirfenidone</intervention_name>
    <description>Pirfenidone will be titrated over 14 days, as tolerated, to the full dose of 2403 mg per day, as follows: Days 1 - 7: one capsule TID; Days 8 - 14: two capsules TID; Days 15 to week 52: three capsules TID. Dose may be reduced to manage an adverse event.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Oral Pirfenidone 2403 mg per day</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Esbriet</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Probable or definite diagnosis of HPS based on confirmed genetic mutation or clinical&#xD;
             picture characterized by oculo-cutaneous albinism, bleeding disorder, and possible&#xD;
             colitis and ILD.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of ILD supported by clinically indicated HRCT prior to Screening, and&#xD;
             presence of fibrotic abnormality affecting more than 5% of the lung parenchyma, with&#xD;
             or without traction bronchiectasis or honeycombing, on Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No features supporting an alternative diagnosis (e.g., infection)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Change in pre-bronchodilator FVC (measured in liters) between Screening (Visit 1) and&#xD;
&#xD;
        Baseline (Visit 2) must be a &lt; 10% relative difference, calculated as:&#xD;
&#xD;
        100%*[absolute value (Screening FVC - Baseline FVC)/Screening FVC&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stable dose (at least three months at the time of Screening) of corticosteroids.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No cytotoxic, immunosuppresive agents, cytokine-modulating, or receptor antagonists&#xD;
             agents are allowed (including but not limited to azathioprine, cyclophosphamide,&#xD;
             cyclosporine, etanercept, iloprost, infliximab, methotrexate, mycophenolate mofetil,&#xD;
             nintedanib, tacrolimus, tetrathiomolybdate, TNF-α inhibitors, rituximab, abatacept,&#xD;
             tofacitintib, tociluzimab).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to understand and sign a written informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not a suitable candidate for enrollment or unlikely to comply with the requirements of&#xD;
             this study, in the opinion of the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cigarette smoking within 3 months of Screening or unwilling to avoid tobacco products&#xD;
             throughout the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of clinically significant environmental exposure known to cause pulmonary&#xD;
             fibrosis (PF), including but not limited to drugs (such as amiodarone), asbestos,&#xD;
             beryllium, radiation, and domestic birds&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent presence of other interstitial lung disease, including but not limited to&#xD;
             radiation, drug toxicity, sarcoidosis, hypersensitivity pneumonitis, bronchiolitis&#xD;
             obliterans organizing pneumonia, human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), viral hepatitis,&#xD;
             and cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent presence of other pleuropulmonary manifestations inconsistent with HPS- ILD&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of pleural effusion occupying more than 10% of the hemithorax on Screening&#xD;
             HRCT&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical diagnosis of a connective tissue disease or overlap syndrome (including but&#xD;
             not limited to rheumatoid arthritis, scleroderma, polymyositis/dermatomyositis,&#xD;
             systemic lupus erythematosus)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Coexistent clinically significant COPD/emphysema or asthma in the opinion of the site&#xD;
             principle investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical evidence of active infection, including but not limited to bronchitis,&#xD;
             pneumonia, sinusitis, urinary tract infection, or cellulitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any history of malignancy diagnosed within 5 years of screening, other than basal cell&#xD;
             carcinoma of the skin, squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, or low grade cervical&#xD;
             carcinoma in situ.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe hepatic impairment or end-stage liver disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of end-stage renal disease requiring dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of unstable or deteriorating cardiac or disease, myocardial infarction within&#xD;
             the previous year, heart failure within the last 3 years, or cardiac arrhythmia&#xD;
             requiring drug therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, might be significantly&#xD;
             exacerbated by the known side effects associated with the administration of&#xD;
             pirfenidone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For women of childbearing potential: agreement to remain abstinent (refrain from&#xD;
             heterosexual intercourse) or use two adequate methods of contraception, including at&#xD;
             least one method with a failure rate of &lt;1% per year, during the 52 weeks of&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. A woman is considered to be of childbearing potential if she is postmenarcheal,&#xD;
                  has not reached a postmenopausal state (≥ 12 continuous months of amenorrhea with&#xD;
                  no identified cause other than menopause), and has not undergone surgical&#xD;
                  sterilization (removal of ovaries and/or uterus).&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Examples of contraceptive methods with a failure rate of &lt;1% per year include&#xD;
                  bilateral tubal ligation, male sterilization, established and proper use of&#xD;
                  hormonal contraceptives that inhibit ovulation, hormone-releasing intrauterine&#xD;
                  devices, and copper intrauterine devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. The reliability of sexual abstinence should be evaluated in relation to the&#xD;
                  duration of the clinical trial and the preferred and usual lifestyle of the&#xD;
                  patient. Periodic abstinence (e.g., calendar, ovulation, symptothermal, or&#xD;
                  postovulation methods) and withdrawal are not acceptable methods of&#xD;
                  contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For men who are not surgically sterile: agreement to remain abstinent (refrain from&#xD;
             heterosexual intercourse) or use contraceptive measures, and agreement to refrain from&#xD;
             donating sperm, as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. With female partners of childbearing potential, men must remain abstinent or use&#xD;
                  a condom plus an additional contraceptive method that together result in a&#xD;
                  failure rate of &lt; 1% per year during the treatment period and for at least 118&#xD;
                  days after the last dose of pirfenidone.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Men must refrain from donating sperm during this same period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Investigational therapy, defined as any drug that has not been approved for marketing&#xD;
             for any indication in the country of the participating site including pirfenidone, at&#xD;
             the time of Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of alcohol or substance abuse in the past 2 years, at the time of Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Family or personal history of long QT syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following liver function test criteria above specified limits:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Total bilirubin above the upper limit of normal (ULN), excluding patients with&#xD;
                  Gilbert's syndrome; aspartate or alanine aminotransferase (AST/SGOT or ALT/SGPT)&#xD;
                  &gt;3 × ULN; alkaline phosphatase &gt;2.5 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Creatinine clearance (CrCl &lt;30) mL/min, calculated using the Cockcroft-Gault&#xD;
                  formula&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Electrocardiogram (ECG) with a QTcB interval &gt;500 msec at Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior use of pirfenidone or known hypersensitivity to any of the components of study&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any of the following therapies within 28 days before Screening:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Investigational therapy, defined as any drug that has not been approved for&#xD;
                  marketing for any indication in the country of the participating site&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Fluvoxamine&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Sildenafil (daily use). Note: intermittent use for erectile dysfunction is&#xD;
                  allowed&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jesse Roman, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Thomas Jefferson University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tamra Perez, BSN</last_name>
    <phone>1-215-955-9181</phone>
    <email>tamra.perez@jefferson.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Melissa McCarey</last_name>
    <phone>267 503-7417</phone>
    <email>Melissa.McCarey@jefferson.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Thomas Jefferson University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19107</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tamra Perez</last_name>
      <phone>215-955-9181</phone>
      <email>tamra.perez@jefferson.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jesse Roman, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayaguez Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mayaguez</city>
        <zip>00680</zip>
        <country>Puerto Rico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rosa Roman, MD</last_name>
      <phone>7874676080</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rosa Roman, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Puerto Rico</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 6, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 6, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 10, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 6, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 6, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 10, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Thomas Jefferson University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jesse Roman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>safety</keyword>
  <keyword>efficacy</keyword>
  <keyword>patient reported outcomes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Interstitial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hermanski-Pudlak Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pirfenidone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

