<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04194255</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HIGH</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04194255</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Different Prebiotics on Iron Absorption From High Dose Iron Supplements</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Single Dose Oral Galacto-oligosaccharides, Fructo-oligosaccharides and Acacia Gum on Iron Absorption From Single 100 mg Oral Iron Doses Given as Ferrous Fumarate in Women Living in Switzerland</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Swiss Federal Institute of Technology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Swiss Federal Institute of Technology</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Iron deficiency (ID) remains the most common global nutrient deficiency, with young women at&#xD;
      high risk. Iron supplements are first line treatment for ID but absorption is often low.&#xD;
      Dietary components that could increase iron absorption would be valuable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prebiotics are among the potential enhancers of non-heme iron absorption.&#xD;
      Galacto-oligosaccharides (GOS), fructo-oligosaccharides and acacia gum are safe and&#xD;
      widely-used prebiotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To our knowledge, no studies have assessed the effect of acacia gum on iron absorption in&#xD;
      human or animal models. Evidence exists about the enhancement of iron absorption when given&#xD;
      in combination with FOS in rats. However, an iron stable isotope study in infants reported&#xD;
      that 7.5 g of GOS improved iron absorption from 5 mg iron from a mixture of ferrous fumarate&#xD;
      and sodium iron EDTA. In a recent iron absorption study in adult women with low iron stores&#xD;
      in our lab we found that 15 g of GOS given with FeFum (14 mg of elemental iron) acutely&#xD;
      increased iron absorption when given with water (+61%) and a meal (+28%).&#xD;
&#xD;
      For prevention of anemia among non-pregnant women, the WHO recommends intermittent (once,&#xD;
      twice or three times a week) oral iron supplementation with 60 mg of elemental iron. This has&#xD;
      been shown to be effective, safe and acceptable for improving hemoglobin concentrations in&#xD;
      women and lowering their risk of anemia. If GOS improves iron absorption from a higher dose&#xD;
      of iron, and if FOS and acacia gum might also enhance iron absorption from FeFum is unclear.&#xD;
      With this study we therefore aim to investigate if consumption of a single oral dose of 15 g&#xD;
      GOS, FOS or acacia gum increase iron absorption from single 100 mg oral iron doses, a common&#xD;
      amount found in supplements on the market for treatment of iron deficiency, given as ferrous&#xD;
      fumarate in otherwise healthy iron depleted women.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Prebiotics are defined as &quot;microbial food supplements that beneficially affect the host by&#xD;
      selectively stimulating the growth and/or activity of one or a limited number of bacterial&#xD;
      species already resident in the colon&quot;. Moreover, prebiotics are potential enhancers of iron&#xD;
      absorption, via several mechanisms: a) increasing gastric residence time allowing for greater&#xD;
      iron dissolution; b) stimulating enterocyte gene expression of proteins involved in iron&#xD;
      absorption; c) stimulating enterocyte proliferation providing a greater surface for iron&#xD;
      absorption; and d) stimulating SCFA production by gut commensal bacteria, decreasing distal&#xD;
      gut luminal pH and increasing iron dissolution.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Galacto-oligosaccharides (GOS), a safe and widely-used prebiotic, are a mixture of glucose-&#xD;
      and galactose-based di- and oligosaccharides of varying structure and may be more selectively&#xD;
      utilized by Bifidobacterium spp. than other prebiotics. Fructo-oligosaccharides (FOS) are&#xD;
      composed by 4 to 9 units of fructose alone or in combination with one unit of glucose. FOS&#xD;
      are widely used as food ingredients/nutritional supplements due to their bifidogenic&#xD;
      properties. Acacia gum is composed by highly branched galactan polymers with galactose and/or&#xD;
      arabinose side chains, possibly terminated by rhamnose or glucuronic acid residues. Both&#xD;
      in-vitro and in-vivo studies have shown that acacia gum supports bifidobacterial growth and&#xD;
      short-chain fatty acids (SCFA) production in the large intestine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      GOS and FOS have received GRAS status in the USA. Acacia gum is extensively used in the food&#xD;
      industry for various functions (emulsification, encapsulation, stabilization, etc.). It is&#xD;
      affirmed as &quot;GRAS&quot; for use in various food items. Acacia gum in human subjects is well&#xD;
      tolerated up to 50 g/day. The European Food Safety Authority stated that there is no safety&#xD;
      concern for the use of Acacia Gum as a food supplement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To our knowledge, no studies have assessed the effect of acacia gum on iron absorption in&#xD;
      human or animal models. Evidence exists about the enhancement of iron absorption when given&#xD;
      in combination with FOS in rats. In humans, studies so far have failed in showing an effect&#xD;
      of FOS on iron absorption. However, an iron stable isotope study in infants reported that 7.5&#xD;
      g of GOS improved iron absorption from 5 mg iron from a mixture of ferrous fumarate and&#xD;
      sodium iron EDTA. Moreover, in a recent iron absorption study in adult women with low iron&#xD;
      stores in our lab we found that 15 g of GOS given with FeFum (14 mg of elemental iron)&#xD;
      acutely increased iron absorption when given with water (+61%) and a meal (+28%). In another&#xD;
      study in our lab (unpublished data) we found that 7 g of GOS given with FeFum (14 mg of&#xD;
      elemental iron) acutely increased iron absorption when given with water (+26%), in iron&#xD;
      depleted women. These effects were found to be iron compound specific and could not be shown&#xD;
      for ferrous sulfate, the iron compound used in the existing human studies with FOS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For prevention of anemia among non-pregnant women, the WHO recommends intermittent (once,&#xD;
      twice or three times a week) oral iron supplementation with 60 mg of elemental iron. This has&#xD;
      been shown to be effective, safe and acceptable for improving hemoglobin concentrations in&#xD;
      women and lowering their risk of anemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If GOS improves iron absorption from a higher dose of iron, and if FOS and acacia gum might&#xD;
      also enhance iron absorption from FeFum is unclear. With this study we therefore aim to&#xD;
      investigate if consumption of a single oral dose of 15 g GOS, FOS or acacia gum increase iron&#xD;
      absorption from single 100 mg oral iron doses, a common amount found in supplements on the&#xD;
      market for treatment of iron deficiency, given as ferrous fumarate in otherwise healthy iron&#xD;
      depleted women.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 20, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 6, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 6, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>fractional iron absorption</measure>
    <time_frame>43 days</time_frame>
    <description>Fractional iron absorption will be calculated based on the shift of the iron isotope ratios in the collected blood samples after the administration of several isotopically labelled iron supplements.Fractional iron absorption will be measured as erythrocyte incorporation of the naturally occurring iron forms with different masses used to label the iron supplements.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hemoglobin (Hb)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 43 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum ferritin</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 43 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>soluble transferrin receptor</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 43 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>serum iron</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 43 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>alpha-1-acid glycoprotein (AGP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 43 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>C-reactive protein (CRP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 43 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Retinol binding protein (RBP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 43 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Iron-deficiency</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ferrous fumarate</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>labelled iron as ferrous fumarate</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ferrous fumarate + 15 g GOS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>labelled iron as ferrous fumarate + prebiotics in the form of 15 g GOS</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ferrous fumarate + 15 g FOS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>labelled iron as ferrous fumarate + prebiotics in the form of 15 g FOS</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ferrous fumarate + 15 g acacia gum</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>labelled iron as ferrous fumarate + prebiotics in the form of 15 g acacia gum</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ferrous fumarate</intervention_name>
    <description>iron (100 mg) supplement in form of ferrous fumarate</description>
    <arm_group_label>ferrous fumarate</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ferrous fumarate + 15 g GOS</intervention_name>
    <description>iron (100 mg) supplement in form of ferrous fumarate with addition of prebiotics (15 g GOS)</description>
    <arm_group_label>ferrous fumarate + 15 g GOS</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ferrous fumarate + 15 g FOS</intervention_name>
    <description>iron (100 mg) supplement in form of ferrous fumarate with addition of prebiotics (15 g FOS)</description>
    <arm_group_label>ferrous fumarate + 15 g FOS</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>labelled iron as ferrous fumarate + 15 g acacia gum</intervention_name>
    <description>iron (100 mg) supplement in form of ferrous fumarate with addition of prebiotics (15 g acacia gum)</description>
    <arm_group_label>ferrous fumarate + 15 g acacia gum</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female, 18 to 45 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SF concentrations ≤ 25 µg/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal body Mass Index (18.5-24.9 kg/m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight &lt;70 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anaemia (Hb &lt; 11,7g/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any metabolic, gastrointestinal, kidney or chronic disease such as diabetes, renal&#xD;
             failure, hepatic dysfunction, hepatitis, hypertension, cancer or cardiovascular&#xD;
             diseases (according to the participants own statement)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Continuous/long-term use of medication during the whole study (except for&#xD;
             contraceptives),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consumption of mineral and vitamin supplements within 2 weeks prior to 1st supplement&#xD;
             administration, including pre- and/or probiotic supplements (excluding foods and&#xD;
             beverages with life cultures such as yoghurt, raw milk cheese and kombucha)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood transfusion, blood donation or significant blood loss (accident, surgery) over&#xD;
             the past 4 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known difficulties with blood sampling&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of antibiotics over the past month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to iron supplements in the given amount, GOS, or lactose&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant or breast feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who intend to become pregnant during the course of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of safe contraception, defined as: Female participants of childbearing potential,&#xD;
             not using and not willing to continue using a medically reliable method of&#xD;
             contraception for the entire study duration, such as oral, injectable, or implantable&#xD;
             contraceptives, or intrauterine contraceptive devices, or who are not using any other&#xD;
             method considered sufficiently reliable by the investigator in individual cases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected non-compliance, drug or alcohol (more than 2 drinks/day) abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smokers (&gt; 1 cigarette per week)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to follow the procedures of the study, e.g. due to language problems,&#xD;
             self-reported psychological disorders, etc. of the participant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Enrolment of the investigator, his/her family members, employees and other dependent&#xD;
             persons&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Only female participants are being studied</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Isabelle Herter-Aeberli, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Laboratory of Human Nutrition ETH Zürich</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Human Nutrition Laboratory, ETH Zurich</name>
      <address>
        <city>Zurich</city>
        <zip>8092</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 9, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 9, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>iron-deficiency</keyword>
  <keyword>Prebiotics</keyword>
  <keyword>galacto-oligosaccharides</keyword>
  <keyword>fructo-oligosaccharides</keyword>
  <keyword>acacia gum</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anemia, Iron-Deficiency</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ferrous fumarate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

