<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02314910</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BAI_040413</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02314910</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Bone Innervation Around Implants</brief_title>
  <official_title>Exploring Bone Innervation Around Osseointegrated Implants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universitaire Ziekenhuizen Leuven</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>KU Leuven</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universitaire Ziekenhuizen Leuven</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      If implants are osseointegrated, there might be innervation of the bone close to the&#xD;
      implants. This event might explain the so-called osseoperception phenomena: Functioning with&#xD;
      implant-supported oral prostheses is better than with removable prostheses due to physiologic&#xD;
      integration and thus sensory feedback.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Several studies confirm improved oral functions in patients who wear dentures on implants,&#xD;
      compared with patients with a removable denture. This could possibly be explained by sensory&#xD;
      innervation around the implant. However, the mechanism of the phenomenon is not yet&#xD;
      completely elucidated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A first step is to identify and describe nerve fibers around implants that are integrated in&#xD;
      human jawbone. The results of this study can then be used to identify the factors that&#xD;
      promote such innervation (implant surface, surgical procedure, patient-related factors, ...).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Goal The purpose of this study is to identify and characterize nerve fibers around&#xD;
      osseogeïntegreerde implants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials and methods Inclusion and exclusion Only implants that were lost due to mechanical&#xD;
      failure or because of severe bone loss will be used. In the case of bone loss, an analysis&#xD;
      will only be performed if sufficient osseointegration took place apical to the implant, at&#xD;
      least about ¼ of the length of the implant. All these failed implants should be removed from&#xD;
      a clinical point of view, but the extensive osseointegration purpose necessitates the&#xD;
      clinical use of a trepanbur, a cylindrical bur to remove jaw bone. All patients will, prior&#xD;
      to surgery, give informed consent to use their implants for further research, as well as the&#xD;
      data from their clinical file.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Collection of samples It is not possible to identify nerve fibers around the implants on the&#xD;
      basis of radiological images, because the resolution is not high enough and because radiology&#xD;
      of material with very high density (titanium) results in a distorted picture, exactly in the&#xD;
      space around the implant . Therefore, a histological analysis will be made on the implants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For this study, over a period of 5 years, as far as possible, implants will be collected with&#xD;
      a minimum of 20. The implants will be collected from patients in three clinical centers where&#xD;
      implants are placed: UZ Leuven, ZOL Genk and a private practice in Leuven.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The implants are removed with a trepanbur and immediately preserved in glutaraldehyde or&#xD;
      formaldehyde.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analysis of the samples The fixed samples are decalcified in 10% EDTA, hydrated through&#xD;
      graded concentrations of ethanol and finally placed in Araldite. They can then be cut with a&#xD;
      bonemicrotome (Reichert Ultracut E Microtome, Vienna, Austria) and further prepared for light&#xD;
      microscopic and ultrastructural analysis. Staining with methylene blue (0.1% aqueous&#xD;
      solution) will be done on sections of 0.5 um. These sections will be viewed with a light&#xD;
      microscope and digitized at a high resolution Mirax Scan (Carl Zeiss Micro-Imaging GmbH,&#xD;
      Germany). The images will be evaluated by an expert at a magnification of 20x, 40x and 100x&#xD;
      on a 30inch LCD screen with custom software (Mirax Viewer 1.1, Göttingen, Germany). For the&#xD;
      analysis of the ultrastructural features, the investigators will make ultrathin sections&#xD;
      (0.06μm) and on plates coated with 0.7% formvar places, contrasted with uranyl acetate and&#xD;
      lead citrate. These sections are EM208S analyzed with a transmission electron microscope&#xD;
      (Philips, Eindhoven, The Netherlands) at 80 kV.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Expected results Following a pilot study, the investigators expect in certain cases to&#xD;
      discover new nerve fibers in bone around implants. These nerve fibers can be described, and&#xD;
      their nature identified. If sufficient fibers are detected with these results, the&#xD;
      investigators can prove the osseoperception phenomena. This information can then be used for&#xD;
      the optimization of therapies with implants, so that the best possible integration, both&#xD;
      biologically and physiologically, can take place.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>5 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Nerve fibre detection</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>To detect a newly formed nerve fibre close to the implant</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Innervation of Bone Around Implants</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Failed implant</arm_group_label>
    <description>There is only one group, being the group of patients of which the oral implant needed to be removed for clinical reasons.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sample histology</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Failed implant</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Implant surrounded by bone material&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients of which the implant needed to be removed&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Implant lost due to clinical reasons&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No osseointegration&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ Leuven</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leuven</city>
        <zip>3000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 5, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 10, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 11, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Innervation</keyword>
  <keyword>Jaw Bone</keyword>
  <keyword>Implants</keyword>
  <keyword>Stereognostic</keyword>
  <keyword>Osseoperception</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

