<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02317887</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>150038</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>15-EI-0038</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02317887</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of RS1 Ocular Gene Transfer for X-linked Retinoschisis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I/IIa Study of RS1 Ocular Gene Transfer for X-linked Retinoschisis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Eye Institute (NEI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - X-linked juvenile retinoschisis (XLRS) is caused by changes in the RS1 gene. These changes&#xD;
      cause abnormal function of the eye protein retinoschisin. Without normal retinoschisin, the&#xD;
      layers of the retina split and vision is lost. Researchers want to try to introduce a healthy&#xD;
      RS1 gene into eye cells, to see if this helps retinal cells make healthy retinoschisin. They&#xD;
      will put the gene in a virus. The gene and virus package is known as a gene transfer vector&#xD;
      (AAV-RS1 vector).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To see if the AAV-RS1 vector is safe to use in people.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Adults 18 and older with a mutation of the RS1 gene, 20/63 vision or worse in one eye, and&#xD;
      XLRS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be screened with genetic tests to confirm XLRS. They will have a&#xD;
           medical history and physical and eye exams.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At visits 1-2, participants will have some or all of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Physical exam&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood and urine tests&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Tuberculosis skin test&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Eye exam&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Vision tests (for one test an intravenous line will be placed in the arm. A dye will be&#xD;
           injected that will travel to the blood vessels in the eye).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At visit 3, the AAV-RS1 vector will be injected with a needle in the study eye.&#xD;
           Participants pupils will be dilated. They will get numbing eye drops.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Visits 4-13 will occur in the 18 months after gene transfer. Many of the above tests&#xD;
           will be repeated. Participants will discuss any side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Visits 14-17 will occur yearly between years 2 and 5.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After year 5, participants will be contacted yearly by phone for up to 15 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objective: To evaluate the safety and tolerability of ocular AAV-RS1 vector&#xD;
      (AAV8-scRS/IRBPhRS) gene transfer to the retina of participants affected with X-linked&#xD;
      juvenile retinoschisis (XLRS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population: Male participants affected with XLRS will receive ocular gene transfer. A&#xD;
      maximum of up to 24 participants may be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design: This is a Phase I/IIa, prospective, dose escalation, single-center study. One eye of&#xD;
      each participant will receive the AAV-RS1 gene vector application by intravitreal injection.&#xD;
      Participants will be closely monitored in conjunction with DSMC oversight. Participants will&#xD;
      be followed for 18 months after which they will continue to be followed for up to 15 years&#xD;
      after enrollment, or per FDA requirements, for further safety analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome Measures: The primary outcome is the safety of ocular AAV-RS1 vector as determined&#xD;
      from assessment of retinal function, ocular structure and occurrence of adverse events and&#xD;
      laboratory tests. Secondary outcomes include changes in visual function, electroretinogram&#xD;
      (ERG) responses, visual field measurements, retinal imaging with optical coherence tomography&#xD;
      (OCT), and the formation of anti-AAV and anti-RS1 antibodies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistics: No formal sample size calculations are used in this Phase I/IIa dose-escalation&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 11, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Retinal function</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 7, Day 14, Month 1, Month 2, Month 3, Month 4, Month 6, Month 9, Month 12, Month 18, Year 2, Year 3, Year 4, Year 5</time_frame>
    <description>maintenance of retinal function</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ocular structure</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 7, Day 14, Month 1, Month 2, Month 3, Month 4, Month 6, Month 9, Month 12, Month 18, Year 2, Year 3, Year 4, Year 5</time_frame>
    <description>maintenance of ocular structure</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurence of AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 7, Day 14, Month 1, Month 2, Month 3, Month 4, Month 6, Month 9, Month 12, Month 18, Year 2, Year 3, Year 4, Year 5</time_frame>
    <description>number and severity of adverse events that differ clinically from the normal progression of XLRS</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ERG</measure>
    <time_frame>Months 1, 3, 6, 12, 18, and annually at years 2-5</time_frame>
    <description>Change in ERG combined response amplitudes from average of baseline 1 and 2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>OCT imaging</measure>
    <time_frame>Months 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 9, 18 and annually at years 2-5</time_frame>
    <description>Change in retinal structure compared to average of baseline 1 and 2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-AAV antibodies</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7, Day 14, Months 1, 2, 3, 6, 9, 12, 18 and annually at years 2-5</time_frame>
    <description>formation of circulating systemic anti-AAV or anti-RS1 antibodies</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual function</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1, 7, 14, Months 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 9, 12, 18 and annually at years 2-5</time_frame>
    <description>Mean median and distribution of change in BCVA compared to average of baseline 1 and 2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Retinoschisis</condition>
  <condition>X-Linked</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>1e9 vg/eye</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>1e10 vg/eye</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>1e11 vg/eye</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>1e11 vg/eye</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Not to exceed 3e11 vg/eye</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 6</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Not to exceed 6e11 vg/eye</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>RS1 AAV Vector</intervention_name>
    <description>Gene transfer by intravitreal injection of the RS1 AAV vector (AAV8-scRS/IRBPhRS)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 6</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is male with a mutation in the RS1 gene identified by genotyping.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must be 18 years of age or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must be able to understand and sign the informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must be medically able to comply with the study treatment, study testing&#xD;
             and procedures and follow-up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has at least one eye that meets the study eye criteria listed below.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must agree not to receive live (attenuated) vaccines prior to dosing and&#xD;
             for some duration following dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must agree to use effective barrier (male or female condom) of&#xD;
             contraception before dosing and continuing one year after gene transfer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If the participant's partner is able to become pregnant, a second form of effective&#xD;
             contraception will be required before dosing and continuing one year after gene&#xD;
             transfer.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Effective methods of contraception for this study include:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hormonal contraception (birth control pills, injected hormones or vaginal ring),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  intrauterine device,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  barrier methods (condom or diaphragm) combined with spermicide,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  surgical sterilization (hysterectomy or tubal ligation in partner or vasectomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant agrees to use appropriate sun protection when on immunomodulatory agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is actively receiving another study medication/investigational product&#xD;
             (IP).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has previously enrolled in another gene therapy trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is currently taking, or has taken in the last three months, a systemic&#xD;
             carbonic anhydrase inhibitor prior to enrollment/baseline 1 testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has any condition that significantly increases risk of systemic&#xD;
             corticosteroids or systemic steroid-sparing immuno-modulatory agents, such as HIV,&#xD;
             syphilis, tuberculosis, hepatitis B, hepatitis C, or diabetes mellitus (DM).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has an underlying serious illness that impairs regular follow-up during&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has had diagnosis or treatment of a malignancy (excluding non-melanoma&#xD;
             skin cancer) within the previous five years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has pre-existing ocular tumors (excluding non-suspicious nevi).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a known allergy to fluorescein dye or other contraindications to&#xD;
             obtaining a fluorescein angiogram.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is on a medication that prevents safe administration of study related&#xD;
             drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has uncontrolled hypertension. (Hypertension judged to be adequately&#xD;
             controlled at baseline medical evaluation is not exclusionary.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has compromised renal function such that cyclosporine or cellcept would be&#xD;
             contraindicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has significant liver disease with elevated liver enzymes (greater than or&#xD;
             equal to 2.5 times ULN).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has low absolute neutrophil count (ANC&lt;1.3 x 10(3)/micro liters).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has used any biologic immunosuppressive agents within the last three&#xD;
             months (within the last six months for rituximab or cyclophosphamide).&#xD;
&#xD;
        STUDY EYE ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The participant must have at least one eye meeting all inclusion criteria and none of the&#xD;
        exclusion criteria listed below.&#xD;
&#xD;
        STUDY EYE INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The study eye must have a best-corrected E-ETDRS visual acuity letterscore of less&#xD;
             than or equal to 63 (i.e., worse than or equal to 20/63). The visual acuity from the&#xD;
             first baseline visit (Baseline 1) will be used for eligibility determination in case&#xD;
             of a change in visual acuity at the second baseline visit (Baseline 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Electroretinogram in the study eye with a scotopic combined response demonstrating a&#xD;
             subnormal b wave, consistent with retinoschisis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        STUDY EYE EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The study eye has a history of other ocular disease likely to contribute significantly&#xD;
             to visual loss or likely to present special risks (e.g., optic neuropathy, advanced&#xD;
             glaucoma, uveitis, large bullous schisis cavities or bullous retinal detachment&#xD;
             precluding safe intravitreal injection).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The study eye has lens, cornea, or other media opacities precluding adequate&#xD;
             visualization and testing of the retina.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The study eye has undergone intraocular surgery within six months prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The study eye is receiving topical carbonic anhydrase inhibitor, or has received&#xD;
             topical carbonic anhydrase inhibitors in the past three months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        STUDY EYE SELECTION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        If both eyes of a participant meet the study eye eligibility criteria, the choice of study&#xD;
        eye will be determined as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The eye with the worse visual acuity will be selected as the study eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If both eyes have the same visual acuity, the choice of study eye will be determined&#xD;
             at the discretion of the investigator in consultation with the participant.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Henry E Wiley, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Eye Institute (NEI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Patti Sherry, C.R.N.O.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 435-4529</phone>
    <email>patti.sherry@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Henry E Wiley, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 451-4260</phone>
    <email>wileyhe@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2015-EI-0038.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 29, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 16, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 16, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 17, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Gene Transfer</keyword>
  <keyword>X-Linked</keyword>
  <keyword>Retinoschisis</keyword>
  <keyword>AAV Vector</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Retinoschisis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

