<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02317367</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999915032</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>15-C-N032</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02317367</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Self-Affirmation: Construct Validity</brief_title>
  <official_title>Self-Affirmation: Construct Validity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - People respond differently when asked about their values. They also respond differently&#xD;
      when they learn about how their actions affect their lives and health. Researchers want to&#xD;
      learn more about these differences. This can help them improve public health messages.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To see how people respond differently to questions about their values and to information&#xD;
      about alcohol and breast cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 1&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Women age 18 and older.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 2 &amp; Study 3&#xD;
&#xD;
      -Women and men aged 18 and older to take part in these studies if they do not meet the US&#xD;
      recommendations of eating 5 or more servings of fruits and vegetables per week.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This study will take place online.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be randomly assigned to a group that will complete a certain task.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Researchers will ask participants to complete 2 small studies:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Values Study. Some participants may write briefly about a value that is important to&#xD;
           them or to someone they are close to. Some participants will complete a short&#xD;
           questionnaire instead of the writing exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Study 1:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Alcohol and Breast Cancer Study. Participants will read a health message. This will be about&#xD;
      the link between alcohol use and increased breast cancer risk. Participants will then answer&#xD;
      questions about what they read and their beliefs about alcohol and breast cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      -Study 2:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fruit and Vegetable Consumption and Health Study. Participants will read a health message&#xD;
      about the fruit and vegetable consumption. Participants will then answer questions about what&#xD;
      they read and their beliefs about fruit and vegetable consumption.&#xD;
&#xD;
      -Study 3:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fruit and Vegetable Consumption and Health Study. Participants will read a health message&#xD;
      about the fruit and vegetable consumption. Participants will then answer questions about what&#xD;
      they read and their beliefs about fruit and vegetable consumption. Complete a follow-up&#xD;
      survey that will be emailed to you through the mTurk system a week after you complete the&#xD;
      main study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Both studies in either Study 1, Study 2 and Study 3 should take about 30 minutes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Self-affirmation, a process by which individuals reflect on cherished personal values is a&#xD;
      potent means of augmenting the effectiveness of threatening health communications.&#xD;
      Individuals tend to be defensive against information suggesting their behavior puts them at&#xD;
      risk for disease or negative health. Previous evidence suggests that self-affirmation may&#xD;
      reduce defensiveness to threatening health information, increasing openness to the message&#xD;
      and resulting in increased disease risk perceptions, disease-related worry, intentions to&#xD;
      engage in preventive behavior, and actual behavioral change. Understanding the mechanisms&#xD;
      that explain these robust effects would yield evidence important for dissemination, including&#xD;
      ways to refine self-affirmation interventions and make them more potent, which could change&#xD;
      the ways that public health messages are constructed. Thus, we aim to elucidate potential&#xD;
      mechanisms underlying the effectiveness of self-affirmation, including self-activation,&#xD;
      general affirmation, and domain-specific affirmation. In study 1, female human subjects will&#xD;
      be randomly assigned to one of eleven affirmation or self- activation conditions. Following&#xD;
      the affirmation or activation task, subjects will read about the documented link between&#xD;
      alcohol and breast cancer. Finally, they will be asked a series of questions about their&#xD;
      intentions to reduce drinking, their perceived risk of breast cancer, and their worry about&#xD;
      breast cancer. Study 2 will replicate study 1, but in a different behavioral domain (physical&#xD;
      activity) and a different sample (both males and females who do not meet physical activity&#xD;
      recommendations). Study 3 will extend Studies 1 and 2 by examining whether the most effective&#xD;
      self-affirmations identified in these studies produce short-term increases in fruit and&#xD;
      vegetable consumption. Drawing on previous research, we hypothesize these inductions will be&#xD;
      effective to the degree that they involve a self-affirmation, but will not be effective if&#xD;
      they involve only other-affirmation or self-activation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 31, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 27, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 15, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intentions to reduce alcohol consumption</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Intentions to reduce alcohol consumption</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intentions to increase physical activity</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Intentions to increase physical activity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">3112</enrollment>
  <condition>Risk Reduction Behavior</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>adult women</arm_group_label>
    <description>Women who drink seven or more drinks per week</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>adults a</arm_group_label>
    <description>Individuals who eat fewer than five servings of fruits and vegetables per day, on average, based on an NCI screener for fruit and vegetable consumption.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>adults b</arm_group_label>
    <description>Individuals who exercise (moderate or vigorous intensity) less than 75 minutes per week.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Convenience sample of online panelists in Amazon's mTurk pool (female alcohol drinkers only&#xD;
        for study 1; guidelines/fruit and vegetable consumption guidelines for study 3).Convenience&#xD;
        sample of online panelists in Prolific's pool (males and females who do not meet physical&#xD;
        activity for Study 2)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study 1:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Amazon mTurk workers will be invited to participate if they are women over the age of 18.&#xD;
        They will also be screened to meet alcohol consumption inclusion criteria. Women will be&#xD;
        eligible to complete the study if they drink seven or more drinks per week (consistent with&#xD;
        the alcohol consumption level the health message links to increased breast cancer risk&#xD;
        (which is based on evidence in the extant breast cancer risk literature). If women report&#xD;
        drinking 7 or more drinks in a sitting, they will be eligible regardless of how many times&#xD;
        they drank in the past year. If they report drinking less than 7 drinks in a sitting, an&#xD;
        average will be calculated to determine whether they meet inclusion criteria. For example,&#xD;
        women who report drinking twice per week on average, and who drink an average of 4 drinks&#xD;
        in a sitting, would be eligible for the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study 2:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Prolific participants will be invited to take part in the study if they are over the age of&#xD;
        18. They will also be screened to meet fruit and vegetable consumption inclusion criteria.&#xD;
        Individuals will be eligible to complete the study if they eat fewer than 5 servings of&#xD;
        fruits and vegetables per day, on average (consistent with the consumption level the health&#xD;
        message, and consistent with US consumption recommendations).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study 3:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Amazon mTurk workers will be invited to participate if they are over the age of 18. They&#xD;
        will also be screened to meet fruit and vegetable consumption inclusion criteria.&#xD;
        Individuals will be eligible to complete the study if they eat fewer than 5 servings of&#xD;
        fruits and vegetables per day, on average (consistent with the consumption level the health&#xD;
        message, and consistent with US consumption recommendations).&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study1&#xD;
&#xD;
        All men, and women who report a lower threshold of alcohol consumption, will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study 2&#xD;
&#xD;
        All individuals who report a higher threshold of physical activity will be excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study3&#xD;
&#xD;
        All individuals who report a higher threshold of fruit and vegetable. consumption, will be&#xD;
        excluded. All individuals who participated in Studies 1 and 2 will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>William M Klein, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Cancer Institute (NCI), 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Crocker J, Niiya Y, Mischkowski D. Why does writing about important values reduce defensiveness? Self-affirmation and the role of positive other-directed feelings. Psychol Sci. 2008 Jul;19(7):740-7. doi: 10.1111/j.1467-9280.2008.02150.x.</citation>
    <PMID>18727791</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 13, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 13, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 16, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Construct Validity</keyword>
  <keyword>Self-Affirmation</keyword>
  <keyword>Alcohol Consumption</keyword>
  <keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

