<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04478838</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>154-2018</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04478838</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>&quot;Extended&quot; (Alternate Day) Antipsychotic Dosing</brief_title>
  <official_title>&quot;Re-examining Maintenance Antipsychotic Treatment in Schizophrenia: &quot;Extended&quot; Antipsychotic Dosing&quot;</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre for Addiction and Mental Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre for Addiction and Mental Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study wishes to examine whether &quot;extended&quot; antipsychotic treatment, in this case,&#xD;
      antipsychotic treatment every other day, is as effective as daily treatment. It is also&#xD;
      evaluating whether there may be differences in terms of side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be randomly assigned to either the treatment as usual group (i.e., taking&#xD;
      antipsychotic daily) or the extended dosing group (i.e., taking antipsychotic one day on, one&#xD;
      day off). That means, like flipping a coin, there is a 50/50 chance that participants will&#xD;
      continue on daily dosing of your antipsychotic or have it switched to every other day dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will last for 1 year. Participants will be evaluated at the beginning and every&#xD;
      two weeks during the first 6 months, with visits once every 4 weeks for the final 6 months.&#xD;
      In total, participants will make 22 visits over 52 weeks to the investigator's office.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that with ED, there will be no change in symptom severity but&#xD;
      improvement in the frequency and severity of side effects, wellbeing, and functioning.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, double-blind, controlled trial that will compare ED, i.e. alternate day&#xD;
      dosing to daily dosing i.e. TAU.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Individuals will be randomized to ED or TAU using a permuted block design with a random&#xD;
      number generator. The size will be fixed and study personnel blinded to the randomization&#xD;
      block size.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To maintain a double-blind design, our pharmacy will provide, on an individualized basis, APs&#xD;
      at the appropriate dose and placebo where necessary in matching gelatin capsules, packaged in&#xD;
      blister packs. The active tablet will be over-encapsulated, and matching placebo will be&#xD;
      prepared using the same capsules (filled with lactose). Thus, from the individual subject's&#xD;
      position, AP treatment is continued according to the same daily schedule. Further, if their&#xD;
      current medication is prescribed in divided doses, this too will be employed during the&#xD;
      study. The minimum and maximum doses for Risperidone will be 1 mg and 16mg respectively. The&#xD;
      minimum and maximum doses for Olanzapine will be 5 mg and 20mg respectively. Other&#xD;
      psychotropic medications prescribed before the study will be permitted, with any changes in&#xD;
      dosing during its course documented&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial is 1 year in duration. To prevent bias, the study code will remain blinded until&#xD;
      the trial's completion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study visits will be scheduled every 2 weeks over the first 6 months, in line with the&#xD;
      earlier investigation. Thereafter, the visits will be decreased to every 4 weeks, aligning&#xD;
      with the schedule routinely observed in our ambulatory clinics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators are asking the following questions:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. (Non-inferiority) Can additional confirmatory evidence support &quot;extended&quot; AP dosing (ED)&#xD;
           as an alternative to continuous administration, i.e. is it as effective clinically?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. (Superiority) Can the investigators establish clinical benefits (e.g. better&#xD;
           tolerability, fewer side effects, such as decreased glucose dysregulation) with ED?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: The investigators hypothesize that with ED, there will be no change in symptom&#xD;
      severity but improvement in the frequency and severity of side effects, wellbeing, and&#xD;
      functioning.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Deterioration using the &quot;Brief Psychiatric Rating Scale - Expanded&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in the Brief Psychiatric Rating Scale - total scores from baseline to 52 weeks. The score values for each item on the BPRS range from 1 to 7. The higher the score for each item the worse the outcome. The values for each item on the BPRS are scored as follows:&#xD;
1- Not Present, 2 - Very Mild, 3- Mild, 4- Moderate, 5 - Moderately Severe, 6- Severe, 7- Very Severe.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Symptoms 1 using &quot;The Clinical Global Impression - Schizophrenia Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Clinical Global Impression - Schizophrenia (CGI-SCH) severity of illness scores from baseline to 52 weeks. The severity of illness score values for each item on the CGI- SCH range from 1 to 7. The higher the score for each item the worse the outcome.&#xD;
The severity of illness values are scored as follows:&#xD;
1- Normal, not ill, 2 -Minimally ill, 3- Mildly ill, 4- Moderately ill, 5 - Markedly ill, 6- Severely ill, 7- Among the most severely ill.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Symptoms/Side Effects using &quot;The Clinical Global Impression - Schizophrenia Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Clinical Global Impression - Schizophrenia Scale (CGI-SCH) degree of change scores from baseline to 52. The values range from 1-7. The higher the score for each item the worse the outcome. The score value of each item are as follows:&#xD;
1 - Very much improved, 2 - Much Improved, 3 - Minimally improved, 4 - No Change, 5 - Minimally Worse, 6- Much Worse, 7 - Very Much Worse</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Symptoms 3 using the &quot;Calgary Depression Scale for Schizophrenia&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Calgary Depression Scale (CDS) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. Scores range from 0-3 as follows: 0- Absent, 1- Mild, 2- Moderate, 3 - Severe. The higher the score for each item, the worse the outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Symptoms 4 using the &quot;Yale-Brown Obsessive-Compulsive Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Yale-Brown Obsessive-Compulsive Scale (YBOCS) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. Scores range from 0-4 with higher scores indicating worsening of outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Symptoms 5 using the &quot;Hamilton Anxiety Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Hamilton Anxiety Scale (HAM-A) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. Scores on each item range from 0-4 as follows: 0- not present, 1- mild, 2 - moderate, 3- severe, 4 - very severe. Higher scores on each item and total score indicate worsening of anxiety outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Side Effects 1 using the &quot;Leibowitz Social Anxiety Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Liebowitz Social Anxiety Scale (LSAS) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. For each item, there are 2 scores; 1) score for fear of anxiety and 2) score for avoidance. For the fear of anxiety component of the scale, score ranges from 0-3 as follows: 0- None, 1- Mild, 2- Moderate, 3 - Severe. The scores for the Avoidance component of the scale ranges from 0-3 as follows: 0 - Never, 1- Occasionally, 2 - Often, 3 - Usually. The higher the score the worse the outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Side Effects 2 using the &quot;Neurological Evaluation Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Neurological Evaluation Scale (NES) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. There are 26 items and scores for each item range from 0-2 with higher scores indicating worsening of outcome. Item 5 does not require a score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Side Effects 3 using the &quot;Glasgow Assessment Side-Effect Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Glasgow Assessment Side-Effect Scale (GASS) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. Scores range from 0-3 as follows: 0 -Never, 1- Once, 2 - A few times, 3 - Everyday. The higher the score for each item and higher total indicates a worse side effect outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Side Effects 4 using the &quot;Drug Attitude Inventory&quot; Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Drug Attitude Inventory (DAI) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. Scores are based on 30 true/false statements.There are 15 items that a patient who is fully adherent to their prescribed medication (and so would be expected to have a positive response to medication would answer true and 15 items such a patient would answer as false. Each positive answer is given a score of plus one, and each negative answer is given a score of minus one. The total positive score would indicate a positive response (adherent to medication) whereas a negative total score would indicate a negative response (non adherent to medication).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Side Effects 5 using the &quot;Barnes Akathisia Rating Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Barnes Akathisia Rating Scale (BARS) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. The total score for the global clinical assessment of akathisia ranges from 0-5 with higher score indicating a worsening of akathisia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Side Effects 6 using the &quot;Simpson Angus Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Simpson Angus Scale (SAS) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. There are 13 items in the scale; scores on each item range from 0-4 with higher scores indicating worse extrapyramidal outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Side Effects 7 using the &quot;Abnormal Involuntary Movement Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Abnormal Involuntary Movement Scale (AIMS) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. There are 13 items in the scale, scores on each item range from 0-4 with higher scores indicating a worse outcome in abnormal movements.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Wellbeing using the &quot;Quality of Life and Satisfaction Questionnaire&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Quality of Life Scale (QLS) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. The scores for each item range from 0-6. The higher the score, the better the outcome. On several items, there is an additional score of &quot;9&quot; to indicate &quot;not applicable&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Wellbeing 2 using the &quot;Quality of Life and Satisfaction Questionnaire - Short Form&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Quality of Life and Satisfaction Questionnaire - Short Form (Q-LES-Q-SF) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. Scores range from 0-6 with lower scores indicating a worse outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Wellbeing 3 using the &quot;Subject Happiness Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>.Change in Subjective Happiness Scale (SHS) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. There are 4 items; scores on each item range from 1-7 with higher scores indicating a happier outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Function 1 using the &quot;Social and Occupational Function Assessment Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in : Social and Occupational Function Assessment Scale (SOFAS). scores from baseline to 52 weeks. A total score ranges from 0-100 with higher scores indicating better social and occupational functioning..</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Function 2 using the &quot;Personal and Social Performance Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Personal and Social Performance scale (PSP) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. The ratings are based on four areas (a) socially useful activities, including work and study; b) personal and social relationships; c) self, and d) disturbing and aggressive behaviours. Overall score range from 1-100. The higher the overall rating, the better the outcome. The breakdown of the total Rating score are as follows: scores ranging from 1-30 reflect functioning so poor that intensive support or supervision is needed; ratings from 31-70 reflect manifest disabilities of various degrees; ratings from 71-100 reflect only mild difficulties.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory Outcomes - Function 3 using the &quot;Recovery Assessment Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Recovery Assessment Scale (RAS) scores from baseline to 52 weeks. There are 41 items with scores on each item ranging from 1-5 with higher scores indicating better outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Schizophrenia and Related Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Drug Administration Schedule</condition>
  <condition>Drug Therapy</condition>
  <condition>Antipsychotic Agents</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Extended Dosing Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants taking olanzapine or risperidone will be switched to an alternate day dosing schedule.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as Usual group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will continue to take their olanzapine or risperidone following the same prescribed daily schedule.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Risperidone</intervention_name>
    <description>0.25 mg, 0.5 mg, 1 mg, 2 mg, 3 mg and 4 mg Tablets</description>
    <arm_group_label>Extended Dosing Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Risperdal</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Olanzapine</intervention_name>
    <description>2.5 mg, 5 mg, 7.5 mg, 10 mg, 15 mg, 20 mg Tablets</description>
    <arm_group_label>Extended Dosing Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Zyprexa</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        (i) A primary diagnosis of a Schizophrenia Spectrum or Other Psychotic Disorder as defined&#xD;
        by the DSM-5 diagnosis and confirmed by the MINI (Version 7.0)&#xD;
&#xD;
        (ii) age 18 or older&#xD;
&#xD;
        (iii) female participants of childbearing potential must be using a reliable method of&#xD;
        contraception and have a negative pregnancy test at the time of enrolment and must, in the&#xD;
        investigator's opinion, practice a clinically accepted, reliable method of contraception&#xD;
        during this study. Male participants must not father a baby during their time in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        (iv) ability to communicate in English&#xD;
&#xD;
        (v) capacity to provide written, informed consent, as assessed using the MacCAT-CR at time&#xD;
        of consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        (vi) stabilized as outpatients with a single oral AP (risperidone or olanzapine*) ≥3 months&#xD;
        i. On a prescribed risperidone dose of between 1-6mg, or a prescribed olanzapine dose of&#xD;
        between 5-20mg&#xD;
&#xD;
        (vii) evidence of adherence with current AP treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        (i) no exposure to a depot AP within 1 year (i.e., no depot AP injection within the last&#xD;
        year)&#xD;
&#xD;
        (ii) no current diagnosis of substance use disorder according to DSM-5 criteria (verified&#xD;
        though the MINI and Drug History Questionnaire (DHQ)77) and a drug screen&#xD;
&#xD;
        (iii) no ECT within the last 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        (iv) pregnancy or lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
        (v) no neurological condition (dementia including Alzheimer's disease, multiple sclerosis,&#xD;
        epilepsy, stroke, or traumatic brain injury)&#xD;
&#xD;
        (vi) no allergy to the study drugs and their excipients&#xD;
&#xD;
        (vii) no allergy or intolerance to lactose&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gary J Remington, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre for Addiction and Mental Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Carol Borlido</last_name>
    <phone>416-535-8501</phone>
    <phone_ext>30547</phone_ext>
    <email>carol.borlido@camh.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Araba Chintoh, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>416-535-8501</phone>
    <phone_ext>36044</phone_ext>
    <email>araba.chintoh@camh.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre for Addiction and Mental Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5T 1R8</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gary J Remington, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>416-535-8501</phone>
      <phone_ext>4750</phone_ext>
      <email>gary.remington@camh.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Carol Borlido</last_name>
      <phone>416-535-8501</phone>
      <phone_ext>30547</phone_ext>
      <email>caro.borlido@camh.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gary J Remington, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 21, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Centre for Addiction and Mental Health</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Gary Remington</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Senior Scientist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Extended Dosing</keyword>
  <keyword>Alternate day dosing</keyword>
  <keyword>Olanzapine</keyword>
  <keyword>Risperidone</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Olanzapine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Risperidone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

