<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04471207</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>00094890</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04471207</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Trial Intelligent Biometrics for PTSD - Clinical Trial</brief_title>
  <official_title>Intelligent Biometrics to Optimize Prolonged Exposure for PTSD</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical University of South Carolina</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Zeriscope</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of South Carolina</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD) is a debilitating mental health condition that increases&#xD;
      suicide risk and affects up to 20% of military veterans and 8% of the general population.&#xD;
      Prolonged Exposure (PE) is a highly effective behavioral (talk therapy) intervention for&#xD;
      PTSD. However, dropout rates are high (25-30%) and an estimated one-third of patients who&#xD;
      complete PE still report symptoms of PTSD at the end of treatment. This study directly&#xD;
      addresses these limitations by using a clinical trial to evaluate the ability of an&#xD;
      innovative technology system to improve PE therapy for veterans with PTSD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD) is a chronic and debilitating psychiatric condition.&#xD;
      Prolonged Exposure (PE) therapy is a highly effective, evidence-based treatment for PTSD;&#xD;
      however, dropout rates are high and approximately one-third of patients who complete&#xD;
      treatment remain symptomatic. The proposed study will employ a randomized clinical trial&#xD;
      (N=40 treatment-seeking veterans with current PTSD) to evaluate the acceptability,&#xD;
      feasibility and preliminary efficacy of a technological enhancement (IB-PE), and investigate&#xD;
      predictors of outcome by accomplishing the following milestones: (1a) Evaluate ability of&#xD;
      IB-PE (therapist guided vs. record only) in reducing PTSD severity from baseline to end of&#xD;
      treatment; and (2b) Use a variety of in vivo exposures (IVEs) to identify biometric and&#xD;
      behavioral indicators (high heart rate, skin conductance) with high predictive value of&#xD;
      treatment response. We will use a technology system of discrete wearables (camera,&#xD;
      microphone) to allow therapists to accompany participants during IVEs. The system will pair&#xD;
      with a cellular application and record information such as heart rate and skin conductance.&#xD;
      This system will also allow the participant to communicate with the study therapist during&#xD;
      the guided in vivo exercises.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 8, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Post Traumatic Stress Disorder symptom severity - clinician rated</measure>
    <time_frame>10-12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Clinician Administered PTSD Scale (CAPS-5) for clinician-rated PTSD symptoms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Post Traumatic Stress Disorder symptom severity - self report</measure>
    <time_frame>10-12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Posttraumatic Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) for self-reported symptoms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>PTSD</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intelligent Biometrics - Prolonged Exposure (Therapist Guided).</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the therapist-guided group, Study Therapists will virtually accompany patients during IVEs and use actionable biometric and subjective data during IVEs (e.g., HR, GSR, SUDS) to modify the assignments in real-time.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intelligent Biometrics - Prolonged Exposure (Record Only).</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the record-only group, passive data collection will be utilized to collect and store biometric and behavioral data for future offline analyses to investigate predictors of outcome.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Therapist Guided Prolonged Exposure with BioWare Device</intervention_name>
    <description>Experimental: Intelligent Biometrics - Prolonged Exposure (therapist guided). In the therapist guided group, Study Therapists will use actionable data during IVEs (e.g., HR, GSR, SUDS) to modify the assignments in real-time.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intelligent Biometrics - Prolonged Exposure (Therapist Guided).</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Record Only Prolonged Exposure with BioWare Device</intervention_name>
    <description>In the record-only group, passive data collection will be utilized to collect and store biometric and behavioral data for future offline analyses to investigate predictors of outcome.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intelligent Biometrics - Prolonged Exposure (Record Only).</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female; any race or ethnicity; aged 18-75 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. U.S. Military veteran, any branch or era.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participants must be able to comprehend English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participants must meet DSM-5 diagnostic criteria for current (i.e., past 6 months)&#xD;
             PTSD (assessed via the Clinician Administered PTSD Scale for DSM-5). Subjects may also&#xD;
             meet criteria for a mood disorder (except bipolar affective disorder, see Exclusion&#xD;
             Criteria) or anxiety disorders (panic disorder, agoraphobia, social phobia,&#xD;
             generalized anxiety disorder, or obsessive compulsive disorder). The inclusion of&#xD;
             subjects with affective and other anxiety disorders is essential because of the marked&#xD;
             frequency of the co-existence of mood and other anxiety disorders among patients with&#xD;
             PTSD.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participants taking psychotropic medications will be required to be maintained on a&#xD;
             stable dose for at least four weeks before study initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participants meeting DSM-5 criteria for a history of or current psychotic or bipolar&#xD;
             affective disorders. Those participants will be referred clinically to ensure they&#xD;
             have appropriate level of clinical care.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participants meeting DSM-5 criteria for a current (past 6 months) moderate to severe&#xD;
             substance use disorder. Those participants will be referred to addiction treatment&#xD;
             centers at the VA, MUSC and in the local community. Individuals with mild SUD will be&#xD;
             included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participants considered an immediate suicidal or homicidal risk or who are likely to&#xD;
             require hospitalization during the course of the study for suicidality. Those&#xD;
             participants will be referred clinically for care.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participants on maintenance anxiolytic, antidepressant, or mood stabilizing&#xD;
             medications, which have been initiated during the past 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participants enrolled in ongoing evidence-based behavioral therapy for PTSD who are&#xD;
             not willing to discontinue these therapies for the duration of the trial. Attendance&#xD;
             at therapeutic activities other than study sessions will be closely monitored using&#xD;
             the Treatment Services Review.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Stacey Sellers, MS</last_name>
    <phone>843-792-5807</phone>
    <email>sellersst@musc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sudie Back, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>843-792-9383</phone>
    <email>backs@musc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical University of South Carolina</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charleston</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29401</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Stacey Sellers, MS</last_name>
      <phone>843-792-5807</phone>
      <email>sellersst@musc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sudie Back, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 15, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sudie E. Back</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>PTSD</keyword>
  <keyword>Military</keyword>
  <keyword>Veterans</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

