<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04321798</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HAS.17.04.144</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04321798</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Promoting Engagement in Physical Activity in Early Rheumatoid Arthritis: Proof of Concept Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>PEPA-RA</acronym>
  <official_title>A Novel, Theory Based Intervention to Promote Engagement in Physical Activity in Early Rheumatoid Arthritis (PEPA-RA): Proof of Concept Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of the West of England</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of the West of England</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      People with rheumatoid arthritis have indicated that they would like better support to remain&#xD;
      physically active following diagnosis and would welcome a physical activity programmes&#xD;
      delivered outside of a secondary care setting by a physiotherapist. With patient input, and&#xD;
      based upon previous research in other long term conditions, a physical activity intervention&#xD;
      was developed by the researchers for delivery by musculoskeletal physiotherapists in a&#xD;
      primary care setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This proposed proof of concept study will investigate the new intervention and inform a&#xD;
      future randomised controlled pilot trial. Four Band 6 musculoskeletal physiotherapists will&#xD;
      be trained to deliver the intervention. Subsequently up to 32 patients with a recent&#xD;
      diagnosis of rheumatoid arthritis (6 -24 months previously) will be recruited. Each&#xD;
      physiotherapist will deliver the 12-week intervention package to a group of 6-8 participants.&#xD;
      The participants will be asked to complete some outcome measures at the beginning of the&#xD;
      12-week intervention and again at the end.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following the 12-week programme some of the patients will be asked what they thought of the&#xD;
      programme and the outcome measures and whether they have any suggestions for improvement.&#xD;
      Those that did and did not complete the programme will be included to ensure a wide range of&#xD;
      views. The treating physiotherapists will also be asked about their experiences of delivering&#xD;
      the programme as well as what they thought of the training.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based upon these findings the programme will be refined and if appropriate further funding&#xD;
      sought to carry out a pilot randomised controlled trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A novel, theory based intervention to promote engagement in physical activity in early&#xD;
      rheumatoid arthritis (PEPA-RA): proof of concept study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      People with rheumatoid arthritis (RA) do less physical activity (PA) than the general&#xD;
      population and this is associated with work disability and reduced physical function. High&#xD;
      intensity training and supervised exercise can improve physical function in RA, while PA&#xD;
      decreases chronic inflammation and reduces pain, all without adversely affecting disease&#xD;
      activity. Despite the benefits, patients do not maintain exercise beyond the supervised&#xD;
      intervention and benefits are not maintained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      People with RA report a range of barriers to PA and are often reluctant to participate for&#xD;
      fear of exacerbating their symptoms. It is therefore essential that they are provided with&#xD;
      appropriate support to overcome these barriers soon after diagnosis, in order to optimise PA,&#xD;
      minimise inappropriate health beliefs and prevent unnecessary reductions in function.&#xD;
      Patients have also expressed a desire for more information relating to exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physiotherapists are best placed to provide this support as their approach is person-centred,&#xD;
      taking into account the individual's health and wellbeing needs and supporting&#xD;
      self-management through patient education and the facilitation of behaviour change. Whilst&#xD;
      the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) guidelines indicate that people&#xD;
      with RA should have access to specialist physiotherapy to encourage regular PA this rarely&#xD;
      occurs in practice with a third of patients waiting over a year for physiotherapy. The&#xD;
      British Society of Rheumatology suggests that conversations regarding health promotion,&#xD;
      including PA, need to occur early in the patient pathway and are best delivered via primary&#xD;
      care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To explore the opinions of people with RA in relation to support for PA programmes the&#xD;
      investigators carried out focus groups. Based upon these findings, in combination with&#xD;
      existing evidence and input from patient research partners, the researchers designed an&#xD;
      intervention for delivery in a primary care setting for people with recently diagnosed RA.&#xD;
      The focus group participants were in agreement that the intervention should be delivered in&#xD;
      an accessible location within their local community. The intervention is informed by a&#xD;
      theoretical framework for health behaviour change. The overall purpose of this new&#xD;
      intervention is to support long term engagement with PA in order to optimise maintenance of&#xD;
      physical function. The researchers plan to investigate the effectiveness of the intervention&#xD;
      in a future trial, but initially need to carry out a proof of concept study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim: to test the feasibility of a novel intervention and inform a future randomised&#xD;
      controlled pilot trial of the refined intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To explore acceptability and feasibility of the intervention to patients and&#xD;
           physiotherapists including the format, delivery method and location, content and support&#xD;
           materials.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To explore the acceptability of the physiotherapists training package.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To refine the physiotherapists training and patient intervention packages.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine acceptability and completeness of all the outcome measures. Up to 36 people&#xD;
           with a recent diagnosis of RA will be recruited to take part in one of 4 PA intervention&#xD;
           groups with 6-8 participants per group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be recruited from secondary care Rheumatology outpatient clinics. Nursing staff&#xD;
      will receive a familiarisation session about the study and be encouraged to briefly discuss&#xD;
      it with all recently diagnosed RA patients. If patients express interest in taking part, a&#xD;
      full information sheet will be provided. Those declining the trial will be offered a copy of&#xD;
      the 'Keep Moving' booklet published by Arthritis Research UK. Where possible, reasons for&#xD;
      declining will be gathered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Those interested will receive a brief telephone screening interview at a time of their&#xD;
      convenience (conducted by the Research Fellow). During the telephone call, patients will be&#xD;
      given an opportunity to ask questions about the study. Patients who confirm verbally that&#xD;
      they would like to enter the study will be referred to the physiotherapists delivering the&#xD;
      intervention. Following screening and informed consent potential participants will be invited&#xD;
      to enrol in the study. Written consent will be obtained when the patients attend for the&#xD;
      initial session.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Four Band 6 musculoskeletal physiotherapists from primary care settings will be trained, via&#xD;
      two half day workshops, to deliver the PA intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physiotherapist Training will be led by a musculoskeletal physiotherapist with experience of&#xD;
      delivering similar interventions to groups of RA and OA patients, as well as practical&#xD;
      experience of working in a regional rheumatology centre. They will be supported by a&#xD;
      Rheumatology Clinical Specialist Physiotherapist as well as experts in the delivery of&#xD;
      similar PA health behaviour change interventions. Following training the four&#xD;
      physiotherapists will each deliver the intervention to a group of 6-8 people with a recent&#xD;
      diagnosis of RA (diagnosed 6 months to 2 years prior to recruitment).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intervention consists of four group sessions and one individual session delivered over a&#xD;
      period of 12 weeks in a primary care setting. Each session includes patient education and&#xD;
      support for behaviour change as well as a supervised practical exercise component. The&#xD;
      intervention is based upon a combination of self-determination theory and COM-B framework&#xD;
      (capability, opportunity, motivation and behaviour) and employs motivational interviewing&#xD;
      techniques. Motivational interviewing has been used successfully by a range of health&#xD;
      professionals to promote behaviour change. The combination of group and individualised&#xD;
      sessions is intended to facilitate peer support (providing relatedness) and ensure that&#xD;
      participants are provided with individual support to meet specific needs (enhancing autonomy&#xD;
      and competence).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Week 0 and 2 (2 hours each): The group (n=6-8) intervention commences with 2 sessions to set&#xD;
      and review goals, facilitate engagement and motivation, create an autonomy supportive&#xD;
      environment and facilitate relatedness (connection with others 'like me').&#xD;
&#xD;
      Week 4 (45 mins): Individualised session at a location that is agreed between the patient and&#xD;
      physiotherapist. This will be guided by the patient's goals as well as practicalities faced&#xD;
      by the physiotherapist including insurance issues and travel time. Example locations for the&#xD;
      individual session may include the patient's home, a community gym or swimming pool.&#xD;
      Participants will be supported to identify community facilities for PA (opportunity). The&#xD;
      individualised session will facilitate discussion of individual barriers to PA and&#xD;
      identification of strategies to overcome them that may be unique to the individual and their&#xD;
      setting. Patients will be given the opportunity to invite a supportive 'other' to attend this&#xD;
      session.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Weeks 8 &amp; 12 (90 mins/session): Group consolidation sessions include discussion on problem&#xD;
      solving in relation to barriers and setbacks, as well as relapse prevention. Due to the&#xD;
      flare-up and remission pattern of RA there are periods when continued PA at the usual level&#xD;
      is not practicable; recovery strategies and re-engagement methods are thus incorporated into&#xD;
      the intervention. These sessions will also include 30 minutes of supervised exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be asked to complete a range of outcomes at baseline and 12 weeks. All&#xD;
      participants will be asked to attend for one hour prior to the week 0 session commencing and&#xD;
      remain for one hour after the week 12 session to allow time for completion of outcomes. The&#xD;
      Research Fellow will oversee the completion of the outcome measures to reduce the risk of&#xD;
      bias from the physiotherapist delivering the intervention. The purpose of including these&#xD;
      outcomes within this 'proof of concept' study is to explore their acceptability to patients,&#xD;
      as well as to provide an indication of the interventions potential for benefit. Acceptability&#xD;
      of the outcomes package (primary and secondary outcomes) will be explored through the&#xD;
      subsequent patient interviews (described below), as well as through the percentage of data&#xD;
      that is analysable. Our patient research partner completed the baseline patient reported&#xD;
      outcomes and reported that they only took 14 minutes. They felt that this would be acceptable&#xD;
      to most participants in the study in addition to the completion of the objective measures.&#xD;
      The secondary outcomes are those proposed for the future definitive study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to the intervention outcomes the following data will be collected:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Reasons for declining to take participate in the intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient attendance at each of the five sessions&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adverse events - data collected by the treating physiotherapist based upon events&#xD;
           occurring during the sessions as well as events reported by the patient to have occurred&#xD;
           between sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Queries received by the research team from the treating physiotherapists will be logged.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following the three-month intervention, qualitative semi-structured face to face individual&#xD;
      interviews will be undertaken with the four physiotherapists to explore their views regarding&#xD;
      the training and support provided; the method of delivery of the intervention including&#xD;
      number of sessions and time between sessions; content of the intervention and any other&#xD;
      issues relating to the training, the intervention or the future study that they deem&#xD;
      important. The physiotherapists will be encouraged to keep a reflective diary throughout the&#xD;
      intervention that they may refer to during the interview. The interviews will be carried out&#xD;
      by a Research Associate who has not had previous involvement in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be invited to participate in semi-structured interviews (approximately n=12&#xD;
      dependent upon data saturation), in order to explore their experiences of the intervention,&#xD;
      the support material and outcome measures. They will also be asked about any other outcomes&#xD;
      that they experienced as a result of the study and about any contact that they made with the&#xD;
      rheumatology team during the study period. The aim will be to recruit 2-3 people from each&#xD;
      intervention group to participate including representation from those that dropped out before&#xD;
      week 12, males and females, and a range of ages. Where possible face to face interviews will&#xD;
      be carried out, but if this is not convenient for the patients then telephone interviews will&#xD;
      be offered. The Research Associate employed to carry out the interviews with the&#xD;
      physiotherapists will also conduct the patient interviews.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Quantitative outcome data will be reported using descriptive statistics including the&#xD;
      percentage of patients with analysable data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inductive thematic analysis will be carried out on the data from the physiotherapy and&#xD;
      patient interviews. The findings will then be used to help refine the physiotherapist&#xD;
      training and the intervention package. This information will ultimately inform the design of&#xD;
      a future randomised controlled pilot trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 29, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 29, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention Attendance</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>minimum 0 maximum 5; higher is better</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>International Physical Activity Questionnaire - Short Form</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>scores are categorised as low, moderate or high; high is better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>6-minute walk distance</measure>
    <time_frame>6 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Distance walked in 6 minutes, minimum is 0, no maximum. Higher is better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>modified Health Assessment Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>measures function. Scores are categorised mild, moderate or severe. Mild is better.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bristol Rheumatoid Arthritis Fatigue - Numerical Rating Scales</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>three scales covering severity, effect and coping all scored from 0-10 with 10 being worst</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self-efficacy for Exercise</measure>
    <time_frame>7-days</time_frame>
    <description>0-100 with higher indicating better self efficacy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Motivation to exercise: Behavioural Regulation In Exercise Questionnaire version 2</measure>
    <time_frame>7-days</time_frame>
    <description>minimum 0 maximum 76; higher score is better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Generic quality of life: EuroQoL - EQ-5D-5L</measure>
    <time_frame>day of completion</time_frame>
    <description>Only the VAS values were reported with 0 minimum and 100 maximum; higher is better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Short Form 12</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>physical and mental component subscales scored separately. Both range from 0 minimum to 100 maximum with higher scores indicating better outcome</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Rheumatoid Arthritis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Physical Activity</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Promoting Engagement in Physical Activity</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Physical Activity</intervention_name>
    <description>Four group sessions and one individual session delivered over a period of 12 weeks in a primary care setting. Each session includes patient education and support for behaviour change as well as a supervised practical exercise component. The intervention is based upon a combination of self-determination theory and COM-B framework (capability, opportunity, motivation and behaviour) and employs motivational interviewing techniques.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Physical Activity</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adults with RA diagnosed in the previous 6-24 months. Able to undertake a PA programme.&#xD;
        Able to understand and speak English. Able to understand the purpose of the research&#xD;
        Provides informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Diagnosis of RA less than 6 months or more than 2 years previously. Unable to participate&#xD;
        for medical reasons.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of the West of England</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bristol</city>
        <zip>BS16 1DD</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 25, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 25, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 24, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 24, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 25, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>fatigue</keyword>
  <keyword>physical activity</keyword>
  <keyword>quality of life</keyword>
  <keyword>function</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>We do not have ethical approval to share IPD</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

