<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04324359</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>C-201-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04324359</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to See How Well an Eye Drop, SURF-201, Works and What Side Effects There Are in Cataract Surgery Subjects</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Randomized, Double-Masked Study To Compare The Ocular Safety, Tolerability, And Efficacy Of A Topical 0.2% Ophthalmic Corticosteroid Solution (SURF-201) To Vehicle In Cataract Surgery Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Surface Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Surface Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      SURF-201 is being studied for the treatment of eye inflammation and pain in people who are&#xD;
      undergoing cataract surgery. SURF-201 is an investigational drug (which means the study drug&#xD;
      is currently being tested) in the form of a sterile eye drop.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this research study is to see how well SURF-201 works and what side effects&#xD;
      there are, and to compare it with Vehicle (placebo). This study will involve about 80 study&#xD;
      participants at several different research sites in the United States.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 3, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 20, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 3, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Anterior Chamber Cell grade</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 15</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of subjects with an anterior chamber cell grade of 0 in the SURF-201 active treatment group compared to Vehicle at Day 15.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Analog Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1, Day 8, Day 15, Day 22 and Day 32</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of subjects who achieve a pain score of 0 at each post-surgical Visual Analog Scale (0-100 mm scale) assessment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">91</enrollment>
  <condition>Post-surgical Ocular Inflammation</condition>
  <condition>Post-surgical Ocular Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SURF-201</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>0.2% topical corticosteroid solution</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vehicle</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SURF-201</intervention_name>
    <description>One drop twice daily (BID) in the study eye for 16 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SURF-201</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>0.2% topical corticosteroid solution</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>One drop twice daily (BID) in the study eye for 16 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vehicle</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Vehicle</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adult subjects age 18 years or older scheduled for uncomplicated unilateral cataract&#xD;
             surgery with posterior chamber intraocular lens implantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects must be able to understand and sign the Informed Consent Form (ICF).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Female subjects of childbearing potential must agree to and submit a negative urine&#xD;
             pregnancy test before any study-specific procedures are performed. The subjects must&#xD;
             be using and continue to use a suitable method of contraception for the duration of&#xD;
             the study: spermicide with barrier, oral contraceptive, transdermal contraceptive,&#xD;
             injectable or implantable contraceptive, intrauterine device (IUD), abstinence or&#xD;
             surgical sterilization of a partner. If a subject is not of childbearing potential&#xD;
             (e.g., has been postmenopausal for at least 12 months or is premenarchal, or has&#xD;
             undergone a hysterectomy, bilateral oophorectomy or a bilateral tubal ligation), a&#xD;
             urine pregnancy test and use of a suitable method of contraception for the duration of&#xD;
             the study will not be required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects must have a best-corrected visual acuity (BCVA) of at least +1.0 log of the&#xD;
             minimum angle of resolution (logMAR) (Snellen equivalent of 20/200) in the non-study&#xD;
             eye (fellow eye).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects must have an intraocular pressure (IOP) of &gt;8 mmHg and ≤22 mmHg in the study&#xD;
             eye (surgery eye).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject must agree to maintain their current dosing regimen throughout the study&#xD;
             period (from Screening through Day 32) if they are currently using topical&#xD;
             cyclosporin-A or Xiidra (lifitegrast 5%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects must be willing and able to attend all study visits and follow all&#xD;
             instructions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects must be able to self-instill the study drug (if unable, a caregiver must be&#xD;
             available to instill all doses of the study drug).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects must agree to avoid any medications which are disallowed (as defined by the&#xD;
             protocol).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject has any intraocular inflammation (cells and flare in the anterior chamber) or&#xD;
             ocular pain (pain score of &gt;0) in either eye prior to surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject has any extraocular inflammation in the study eye prior to surgery&#xD;
             (blepharitis is allowed if only scurf is present without any concurrent conjunctivitis&#xD;
             or lid erythema/edema) or ongoing uveitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject has a history of diabetic retinopathy and/or previous vitrectomy in the study&#xD;
             eye within the last 2 years prior to Screening which, in the investigator's opinion,&#xD;
             is clinically significant and could impact the normal outcome of an uncomplicated&#xD;
             cataract surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject has a diagnosis of severe dry eye in the study eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject has any sign of iritis or scleritis in the study eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject has a history of glaucoma surgery in the study eye within the last 2 years&#xD;
             prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject has a history of retinal surgery in the study eye within the last 2 years or&#xD;
             plans to undergo retinal surgery in the study eye during the study period (from&#xD;
             Screening through Day 32)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject has a history of Fuchs' dystrophy in the study eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subject has guttata or chalazion in the study eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subject has undergone radial keratotomy, photorefractive keratotomy, advanced surface&#xD;
             ablation, corneal transplant, or LASIK in the study eye within the last 2 years prior&#xD;
             to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subject plans to undergo cataract surgery in the non-study (fellow) eye during the&#xD;
             study period (from Screening through Day 32).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subject plans to undergo additional ocular surgery (including femtosecond&#xD;
             laser-assisted cataract surgery, minimally invasive glaucoma surgery, astigmatic&#xD;
             keratotomy, limbal relaxing incision surgery, mechanical pupillary expanders,&#xD;
             conjunctival incisions, and vitrectomy) in either eye during the study period (from&#xD;
             Screening through Day 32).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subject has a history of intraocular injections in the study eye within 6 months prior&#xD;
             to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subject has a history of herpes simplex infection in either eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Subject has active corneal, conjunctival or canalicular pathology (including ocular&#xD;
             infection [bacterial, viral or fungal]) in the study eye. Specifically, active viral&#xD;
             diseases of the cornea and conjunctiva including epithelial herpes simplex keratitis&#xD;
             (dendritic keratitis), vaccinia, and varicella, and also in mycobacterial infection of&#xD;
             the eye and fungal diseases of the ocular structures (such as fungal keratitis).&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Subject has thinning of the cornea or sclera.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Subject plans to undergo uncomplicated unilateral cataract surgery with the aid of&#xD;
             anterior capsular staining products (e.g., Trypan blue) or with the aid of a femto&#xD;
             (femtosecond) laser.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Subject has undergone anti-neoplastic therapy within the last 2 years prior to&#xD;
             Screening or plans to undergo anti-neoplastic therapy during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Subject has a history of use of medications to treat benign prostatic hyperplasia&#xD;
             that, in the opinion of the investigator, limits adequate dilation of the pupil to&#xD;
             safely perform uncomplicated cataract removal and IOL implantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Subject has a history of liver disease within the last 5 years prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Subject has a history of previous ocular trauma in the study eye that places the study&#xD;
             eye at risk of increased post-surgical complications or inflammation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Subject has or had a known blood dyscrasia or bone marrow suppression.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Subject has an active or chronic/recurrent ocular or systemic disease that is not&#xD;
             controlled and may have an impact on would healing (e.g., diabetes mellitus, systemic&#xD;
             connective tissue disease, severe atopic disease).&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Subject is suffering from alcohol and/or drug abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Subject has a known hypersensitivity or poor tolerance to corticosteroids or any&#xD;
             component of the study drug or any of the procedural medications such as anesthetic&#xD;
             and/or fluorescein drops, dilating drops, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Female subjects who are currently pregnant or nursing or are planning to become&#xD;
             pregnant during the study or have a positive pregnancy test.&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. Subject has previously participated in this study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
         28. Subject used (within 30 days of initiation of study treatment) or is anticipating&#xD;
             concurrent use of an investigational drug or device.&#xD;
&#xD;
         29. Subject has a condition or a situation which, in the investigator's opinion, might put&#xD;
             the subject at increased risk, confound the study data or interfere significantly with&#xD;
             the subject's study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         30. Subject would be wearing contact lens in either eye during the dosing period of Day -1&#xD;
             to Day 14.&#xD;
&#xD;
         31. Subject is taking a medication that the investigator feels might interfere with the&#xD;
             study parameters.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kamran Hosseini, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Surface Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Inland Eye Specialists</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hemet</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92545</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>LoBue Laser and Eye Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Murrieta</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92562</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hernando Eye Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brooksville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>34613</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Levenson Eye Associates</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jacksonville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32204</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>East Florida Eye Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stuart</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>34994</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alterman, Modi &amp; Wolter</name>
      <address>
        <city>Poughkeepsie</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>12603</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Eye Care Specialists</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kingston</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>18704</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VRF Eye Specialty Group</name>
      <address>
        <city>Memphis</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>38120</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texan Eye Care, PA - Keystone Research, Ltd.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78731</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>R and R Eye Research, LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <disposition_first_submitted>October 13, 2021</disposition_first_submitted>
  <disposition_first_submitted_qc>October 15, 2021</disposition_first_submitted_qc>
  <disposition_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2021</disposition_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cataract</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted, but a results disposition has been submitted           -->
</clinical_study>

