<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04323020</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HS23646 (B2020:017)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04323020</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>CT Perfusion (CTP) for Assessment of Poor Neurological Outcome in Comatose Cardiac Arrest Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>CANCCAP</acronym>
  <official_title>CT Perfusion (CTP) for Assessment of Poor Neurological Outcome in Comatose Cardiac Arrest Patients (CANCCAP)-a Prospective Cohort Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Manitoba</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Manitoba Medical Service Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Manitoba</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      ABSTRACT&#xD;
&#xD;
      Brief Overview: Neurological assessment of comatose cardiac arrest patients (CCAP) is&#xD;
      challenging because most of these patients are treated with sedatives and therapeutic&#xD;
      hypothermia that prevent complete neurological/clinical assessment. A complete and reliable&#xD;
      neurological assessment is needed for patient's long-term function and survival. A&#xD;
      poor-quality clinical assessment results in resource-intensive treatment that may not benefit&#xD;
      the patient. An ancillary test of head CT scan is often used for additional information.&#xD;
      However, this additional information still limits the quality of the assessment. In a small&#xD;
      pilot study, we explored an advanced CT scan of brain called CT Perfusion (CTP) relative to&#xD;
      clinical assessment in CCAP as a predictor of neurological outcome (severe disability or&#xD;
      death) at hospital discharge. The preliminary results suggested that CTP was both valid and&#xD;
      reliable, relative to clinical assessment, while meeting many of the criteria of an ideal&#xD;
      test (fast, safe, accessible, valid, reliable). This project aims to carry out a fully&#xD;
      powered study to confirm these findings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of this project is to validate CTP for predicting neurological outcome at hospital&#xD;
      discharge in CCAP. We will conduct a prospective cohort study to validate the use of CTP in&#xD;
      CCAP.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis- Computed Tomographic Perfusion (CTP) can reliably diagnose potentially fatal&#xD;
      brain injury in CCAP in early stage upon hospital admission, which may or may not be&#xD;
      recognized in the usual clinical practice due to inadequate clinical examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective: To validate CTP, relative to the reference standard of clinical&#xD;
      assessment, for characterizing poor neurological outcome at hospital discharge in CCAP.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To establish the safety and inter-rater reliability of CTP in CCAP.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will be conducted in our tertiary care cardiac center. The cohort will consist of&#xD;
      newly admitted comatose adults (&gt;18 years of age) who have suffered an OHCA and are treated&#xD;
      with standard TTM to 36°C. Just before admission to the intensive care unit (ICU), CCAP&#xD;
      undergo CT scan of head. Our plan is to add CTP of whole head at the time of their standard&#xD;
      of care CT scan of head. CCAP will then be transferred to ICU for further standard management&#xD;
      including TTM.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Immediately after acute care, CCAP usually undergo a CT scan of the head, as per standard&#xD;
      protocol, to assess for any intracranial pathology. CTP will be performed at the same time as&#xD;
      this standard-of-care CT scan of head. CTP images will be acquired according to a&#xD;
      standardized stroke imaging protocol in order to ensure whole brain coverage. The CTP data&#xD;
      will be transferred to the study imaging core lab at the department of Radiology, University&#xD;
      of Manitoba, Winnipeg for interpretation. The CTP results will not be available to the&#xD;
      treating physicians and the routine care of the patient will continue as per local practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CTP analysis will be performed in the imaging core lab using a semiautomatic deconvolution&#xD;
      algorithm on a vendor neutral software package. CTP will be assessed both quantitatively as&#xD;
      well as qualitatively.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Quantitative assessment: Brain death will be defined as CBF &lt;5 mL/100g/min and CBV &lt;2&#xD;
           mL/100g in the brainstem.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Qualitative assessment: Brain death will be defined as matched decrease of CBF and CBV&#xD;
           in the brainstem. The perfusion maps for CBF and CBV will be assessed for binary outcome&#xD;
           of 'dead' or 'not-dead', according to our previously published methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The perfusion maps will be assessed by the two independent neuroradiologists, who are blinded&#xD;
      to each other's assessment and to the clinical history of each patient. If the two&#xD;
      neuroradiologists disagree, a consensus agreement will be achieved for the final analysis.&#xD;
      Consensus decision reflects the real-life scenario faced in such situations. CTP parameters&#xD;
      (CBF and CBV) will be qualitatively assessed for the presence or absence of matched decrease&#xD;
      of CBF and CBV.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participant will be comatose cardiac arrest</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To validate CTP, relative to the reference standard of initial clinical assessment, for predicting poor neurological outcome (≥4 on modified Rankin scale) at hospital discharge in CCAP.</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome is to check the accuracy of CTP compared to the clinical assessment in predicting the poor neurological outcome in comatose cardiac arrest patients at hospital discharge.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Cardiac Arrest</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Comatose cardiac arrest patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Comatose cardiac arrest patients will be undergoing CT perfusion test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CT Perfusion</intervention_name>
    <description>CT Perfusion</description>
    <arm_group_label>Comatose cardiac arrest patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Newly admitted comatose adults (≥18 years old) who have suffered an Out of Hospital&#xD;
             Cardiac Arrest (OHCA)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treating physicians plan on instituting post cardiac arrest Targeted Temperature&#xD;
             Management (TTM) therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No substitute decision maker available for consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known contraindication to CT contrast agent, such as a history of allergy or&#xD;
             anaphylactic reaction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known chronic kidney disease, stage 4-5 (eGFR &lt; 30 mL/min/1.73 m2)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jai Shankar, MD FRCPC</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Manitoba</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jai Shankar, MD FRCPC</last_name>
    <phone>4313734164</phone>
    <email>shivajai1@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Susan K Alcock, MN</last_name>
    <phone>2047893996</phone>
    <email>salcock@hsc.mb.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Boniface Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winnipeg</city>
        <state>Manitoba</state>
        <zip>R2H 2A6</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Allan Schaffer, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 26, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Manitoba</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jai Shankar</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Comatose cardiac arrest patients</keyword>
  <keyword>Computed Tomographic Perfusion</keyword>
  <keyword>Targeted Temperature Management</keyword>
  <keyword>Out of hospital cardiac arrest</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Arrest</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

