<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04328116</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CS.O.008</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04328116</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Neodent Implantable Devices of GM Zygomatic Line</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prospective Case Series Study of Neodent Implantable Devices of GM Zygomatic Line</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Neodent</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Neodent</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      GM Zygomatic implant is intended to be surgically placed in the posterior region of the&#xD;
      maxilla and zygoma. It is indicated for multiple prostheses in case of severe resorption in&#xD;
      the maxilla and total edentulism (situations in which the installation of convectional&#xD;
      implants is contraindicated).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of the study is to confirm the long-term safety and clinical performance of GM&#xD;
      Zygomatic implants and GM Zygomatic abutments in daily dental practice setting, by means of a&#xD;
      prospective collection of clinical data concerning the success and survival rates of these&#xD;
      devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Devices will be used according to standard routine in daily practice, according to all&#xD;
      indications as specified by the manufacturer in the instructions for use (IFU). Ten patients&#xD;
      will be followed for 36 months and monitored for Adverse Events by the Investigators until&#xD;
      the last protocol-related procedure of a patient is completed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study protocol was reviewed and approved by an Ethics Committee (CE) in Brazil.&#xD;
&#xD;
      GM Zygomatic implants present an optimized design with adapted treatment protocol, allowing&#xD;
      for treatment of patients with severely resorbed maxilla and complete edentulism in which&#xD;
      conventional implants placement is contraindicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of the study is to confirm the long-term safety and clinical performance of&#xD;
      implants and abutments of GM Zygomatic System in a daily dental practice setting, by means of&#xD;
      a prospective collection of clinical data in a study using these devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additionally, from the collected data, the study aims to identify previously unknown&#xD;
      side-effects and monitor the known side-effects and contraindications stated on the&#xD;
      Instructions for Use with the intent to verify that the intended purpose is adequate for all&#xD;
      Neodent products involved in the procedure that come into contact with the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample will be prospectively selected and will consist of 10 patients with atrophic&#xD;
      edentulous maxillae, for whom the responsible surgeon elects the rehabilitation by means of&#xD;
      placement of zygomatic implants as having the best risk-benefit ratio for the patient (e.g.,&#xD;
      shorter treatment time and lower biological cost than the associated with reconstructive&#xD;
      surgeries for the insertion of conventional implants). Informed consent in writing will be&#xD;
      obtained from each patient participating in the study prior to any study-related procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neodent GM Zygomatic implants will preferably be placed under local anesthesia and sedation&#xD;
      (according to the surgeon's assessment of the patient's general health), with adequate bone&#xD;
      bed preparation, as recommended by the manufacturer. Size, position, and quantity of implants&#xD;
      (2 to 4) will be select considering the anatomy, region of rehabilitation, bone quality and&#xD;
      quantity and available space. Together with the Zygomatic Implants, 2 to 4 conventional&#xD;
      implants of Neodent GM line shall be inserted in the anterior region, if enough bone is&#xD;
      available.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data concerning the studied variables will be collected following the procedures and&#xD;
      assessments plan by fulfilling the Case Report Form (CRF), in the following stages: First&#xD;
      visit (Screening); T0 - Implants placement; TF - final prosthesis (may coincide with TL); TL&#xD;
      - Implant loading; T6, T12, T24 and T36 - 6, 12, 24 and 36 months, respectively, after&#xD;
      implant placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Computed tomography (CT) scans with prototyping will be obtained from the region of interest&#xD;
      prior to surgery, for the surgical planning and implant selection, as well as post-surgery&#xD;
      (T0 - immediately or within 1 week after implant placement; T36) to verify zygomatic implants&#xD;
      anchorage. Prototypes of the region of interest in the maxilla will be obtained from the&#xD;
      initial CT scans for diagnostic purposes. Additionally, standardized digital periapical&#xD;
      radiographs will be taken in a usual daily practice frequency, as determined by the&#xD;
      investigator: after implants placement (T0) and during the post-operative stages (TL, TF, T6,&#xD;
      T12, T24, and T36) to assess the osseointegration process, changes in peri-implant bone level&#xD;
      as well as prosthetic settlement and integrity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Implant survival rate</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months after implant placement.</time_frame>
    <description>Implant survival will be defined as no loss of the implant at each follow-up.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Implant success rate</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months after implant placement.</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of implant success will be assessed based on the criteria by Byser et al (1990).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Implant survival rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 12, and 24 months after implant placement.</time_frame>
    <description>Implant survival will be defined as no loss of the implant at each follow-up.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Implant success rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 12, and 24 months after implant placement.</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of implant success will be assessed based on the criteria by Byser et al (1990).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prosthetic survival rate</measure>
    <time_frame>12, 24, and 36 months after implant placement.</time_frame>
    <description>Prosthetic survival will be assessed as the prosthesis remaining in situ at each follow-up, irrespective of its condition.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prosthetic success rate</measure>
    <time_frame>12, 24, and 36 months after implant placement.</time_frame>
    <description>Success will be defined as the prosthesis that remained unchanged and did not require any intervention during the entire observational period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>Before implant placement and 6, 12, 24, and 36 months after implant placement.</time_frame>
    <description>The portuguese translation of OHIP-14 [12,13] questionnaire will be used to assess Oral Health Related Quality of Life (OHRQoL), as a measure of patient satisfaction with treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinician Satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after implant placement, 12, 24, and 36 months after implant placement.</time_frame>
    <description>The assessment will be performed by means of a questionnaire using a visual analog scale (VAS) in the form of a 10 cm horizontal line, where 0 (left end) indicates minimum satisfaction and 10 (right end) indicates maximum satisfaction.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events related to the implant.</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after implant placement, 6, 12, 24, and 36 months after implant placement.</time_frame>
    <description>Determined by inquiring with the patient and clinical evaluation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events related to the prosthesis.</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after implant placement, 6, 12, 24, and 36 months after implant placement.</time_frame>
    <description>Determined by inquiring with the patient and clinical evaluation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events related to the surgery.</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after implant placement, 6, 12, 24, and 36 months after implant placement.</time_frame>
    <description>Determined by inquiring with the patient and clinical evaluation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events related to the oral health</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after implant placement, 6, 12, 24, and 36 months after implant placement.</time_frame>
    <description>Determined by inquiring with the patient and clinical evaluation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Jaw, Edentulous</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Study Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Neodent GM Zygomatic Dental Implants will be placed. Multiple implants may be placed in a single subject.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dental Implants</intervention_name>
    <description>Dental Implants will be used according to standard routine in daily practice, according to all indications as specified by the manufacturer in the IFU (informations for use)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Study Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The sample will be prospectively selected and will consist of 10 patients with atrophic&#xD;
        edentulous maxillae, for whom the responsible surgeon elects the rehabilitation by means of&#xD;
        placement of zygomatic implants as having the best risk-benefit ratio for the patient&#xD;
        (e.g., shorter treatment time and lower biological cost than the associated with&#xD;
        reconstructive surgeries for the insertion of conventional implants).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years of age or more;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Opposing dentition (natural teeth or teeth/implant-supported fixed restorations).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptomatology related to the facial sinuses (maxillary sinusitis, polyps or any other&#xD;
             sinus pathologies);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unfavorable maxillary relations;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signs of allergy or hypersensitivity to the chemical ingredients of the material:&#xD;
             titanium;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of acute inflammatory or infectious processes in live tissue;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unsuitable bone volume and/or quality;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic complications or diseases such as bone metabolism disorders, blood clotting&#xD;
             disorders, unsuitable healing capacity, incomplete jawbone growth, uncooperative and&#xD;
             not motivated patient, abuse of drugs or alcohol, psychosis, prolonged functional&#xD;
             disorders which resist any treatment with medications, xerostomia, weakened&#xD;
             immunological system, diseases which require the use of steroids, endocrine diseases,&#xD;
             insufficient oral hygiene, and pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additionally, subjects will be excluded if they present systemic complications that may&#xD;
        expose them to an eventual surgical risk if submitted to surgery under general anesthesia&#xD;
        or under local anesthesia and sedation (decompensated diabetics, immunosuppressed, patients&#xD;
        who were submitted to radiotherapy and chemotherapy less than 4 years or who had a heart&#xD;
        attack less than 1 year previously, patients with clinical signs and/or symptoms of&#xD;
        sinusitis and congestion and/or nasal secretion.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Larissa Trojan, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Neodent</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Waleska Furquim, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>55 41 21604000</phone>
    <phone_ext>4159</phone_ext>
    <email>waleska.furquim@neodent.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Roberta Rocha, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>55 41 21604000</phone>
    <phone_ext>4121</phone_ext>
    <email>roberta.rocha@neodent.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Instituto Latino Americano de Pesquisa e Ensino Odontológico</name>
      <address>
        <city>Curitiba</city>
        <state>Paraná</state>
        <zip>80710-150</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Luis Eduardo Padovan, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+55 41 3595-6000</phone>
      <email>padovan@iocp.com.br</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 26, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Dental Implants</keyword>
  <keyword>Zygomatic Implants</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Jaw, Edentulous</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

