<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03380923</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>N000141613159</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03380923</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Precision High-Intensity Training Through Epigenetics (PHITE)</brief_title>
  <acronym>PHITE</acronym>
  <official_title>Precision High-Intensity Training Through Epigenetics (PHITE)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alabama at Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Wright State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Salk Institute for Biological Studies</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alabama at Birmingham</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The PHITE collaborative team, consisting of Tim Broderick, MD (Overall PI), Wright State&#xD;
      University (WSU); Marcas Bamman, PhD (Site PI), The University of Alabama at Birmingham&#xD;
      (UAB); and Ron Evans, PhD and Joe Ecker, PhD, Salk Institute for Biological Studies, are&#xD;
      working with funding from the US Department of Defense (DoD), Office of Naval Research (ONR),&#xD;
      to explore the link between physical training and epigenetics. This is a key interest area&#xD;
      for the DoD ONR because it provides high-impact optimization of force readiness in&#xD;
      warfighters with diverse backgrounds.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The term epigenetics refers to heritable changes in gene expression (active versus inactive&#xD;
      genes) that does not involve changes to the underlying DNA sequence; a change in phenotype&#xD;
      (the set of observable characteristics of an individual resulting from the interaction of its&#xD;
      genotype with the environment) without a change in genotype (the genetic constitution of an&#xD;
      individual organism) . This in turn affects how cells read the genes. Epigenetic change is a&#xD;
      regular and natural occurrence but can also be influenced by several factors including age,&#xD;
      the environment/lifestyle, and disease state. Epigenetic modifications can manifest as&#xD;
      commonly as the manner in which cells terminally differentiate to end up as skin cells, liver&#xD;
      cells, brain cells, etc. New and ongoing research is continuously uncovering the role of&#xD;
      epigenetics in a variety of human conditions. This study is designed to assess whether&#xD;
      epigenetics is a primary mechanism modulating how individuals adapt to specific exercise&#xD;
      training prescriptions designed to produce a warfighter phenotype.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The PHITE team is organized around a shared test population of human subjects for which UAB&#xD;
      will oversee recruitment, training, testing, and sampling. Healthy but untrained volunteers,&#xD;
      both men and women, 18-27 y of age-phenotypical of the US warfighter-will participate in a&#xD;
      12-wk, two-arm, single-blind, randomized, exercise dose-response trial comparing two&#xD;
      intensities of combined training: Moderate-Intensity vs. High-Intensity. Biospecimens are&#xD;
      collected before and after an acute exercise bout in the pre-training state, and again after&#xD;
      12 weeks of 3 d/wk combined exercise training. Numerous phenotyping assessments are collected&#xD;
      before after the 12-week intervention period to associate exercise training outcomes with&#xD;
      molecular changes in the skeletal muscle and blood biospecimens.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Overview:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The US military relies on physical training to increase and maintain force readiness. In this&#xD;
      study, we hypothesize that epigenetic modification is a primary mechanism by which specific&#xD;
      physical exercise training prescriptions transduce warfighter genotype into warfighting&#xD;
      phenotype. Our aim with this program is 3- fold. We will (1) identify training methodologies&#xD;
      that modify epigenetic responses; (2) characterize epigenetic regulation of physiological&#xD;
      processes, pathways and mechanisms associated with moderate and high-intensity physical&#xD;
      training, and (3) produce real-time biomarkers of cardiorespiratory and neuromuscular&#xD;
      performance that predict physical training outcomes. We will satisfy these goals through the&#xD;
      following six research projects:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Phenotyping the Exercise Dose-Response&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Determine the effect of exercise Intensity on neuromuscular and cardiorespiratory&#xD;
           performance&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Assess the impact of baseline, pre-training phenotype on acute responsiveness and&#xD;
           adaptability to different intensity exercise regimens&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Determine the effect of exercise intensity on mechanisms regulating muscle protein&#xD;
           metabolism, myofiber hypertrophy, and muscle oxidative capacity&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. Real-time Genetic and Epigenetic Biomarkers of Performance&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Identify muscle miRNA that are differentially expressed in response to varying exercise&#xD;
           intensities&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Identify circulating muscle-derived miRNA that are differentially expressed in response&#xD;
           to varying exercise intensities&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Genotype individual athletic potential for biomarker optimization&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. Epigenomic Signatures of Human Performance&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Identify and correlate exercise induced methylation changes in blood and muscle&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Functionally link changes in gene expression signatures and physiologic outcomes&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Define nuclear receptor induced epigenetic signatures in metabolically active tissues&#xD;
&#xD;
      V. Exercise Induced Histone Modifications and Chromatin Remodeling&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Profile histone modification and histone subunit usage signatures&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Assess chromatin as a signal integration platform for long-term stability&#xD;
&#xD;
      VI. Integrative Epigenomics&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Categorize baseline performance and group subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Characterize epigenetic changes in response to varied exercise intensities&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Develop forecasting models from miRNA biomarkers of performance&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Develop epigenetic regulatory network models using Deep Belief Networks&#xD;
&#xD;
           UAB will enroll healthy, untrained men and women who resemble the US soldier. They&#xD;
           participate in an exercise dose response training trial that lasts approximately 12&#xD;
           weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
           There are 2 randomly assigned exercise prescriptions: MOD - 3 days per week on treadmill&#xD;
           or stationery cycle ergometer, combined with 2 days per week of resistance training; HI&#xD;
           - 3 days per week high intensity interval training similar to military high intensity&#xD;
           tactical training, combined with high intensity resistance training 2 days per week.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Physical performance is evaluated pre-training, mid-training and post-training.&#xD;
           Additionally, body composition is evaluated pre-training and post-training. Muscle&#xD;
           biopsies and blood draws are performed at pre-training and post-training acute exercise&#xD;
           response bouts, and samples are sent to additional study sites for specific evaluations.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Recruitment:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Participants are recruited through IRB approved advertisements.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Informed Consent:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Once an individual is identified; meets the inclusion/exclusion criteria (pre-screen);&#xD;
           and expresses interest in the study, a member of the research team provides the&#xD;
           individual with a consent form to review. A member of the team follows up with the&#xD;
           individual to further explain the study and provide an opportunity for the prospective&#xD;
           participant to ask any questions. If the person decides to participate, he/she is&#xD;
           scheduled for the initial visit. He/she is encouraged to ask any further questions prior&#xD;
           to giving written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Participant Procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
           MOD exercise regimen - 3 days per week of endurance exercise at 70% heart rate reserve&#xD;
           for 30 mins on a stationary cycle or treadmill, combined with resistance exercise on 2&#xD;
           of the 3 days. The resistance training prescription involves 3 sets x 10-14 repetitions&#xD;
           for each movement, with 1 minute rest between set. The movements include leg press or&#xD;
           squat, knee extension, chest press, overhead press, seated row, wide grip pull down, ab&#xD;
           crunch, heel raise, triceps push down, bicep curls. Resistance loads are progressed when&#xD;
           14 repetitions are achieved for 2 of 3 sets. Heart rate is monitored throughout each&#xD;
           session.&#xD;
&#xD;
           HI Exercise regimen - 3 days per week of maximum intensity interval exercise, combined&#xD;
           with resistance exercise on 2 of the 3 days. Instead of moderate intensity endurance&#xD;
           exercise, participants in this group perform 10 high-intensity intervals (30 sec of&#xD;
           work, 30 sec of rest) including box jumps, burpees, split squat jumps, kettle bell&#xD;
           swings, cycling sprints, battle ropes, wall ball, dips, etc. The resistance training&#xD;
           prescription involves 3 sets x 8-10 repetitions for the same movements as MOD, but with&#xD;
           supersets of two movements. Resistance loads are progressed when 10 repetitions are&#xD;
           achieved for 2 of 3 sets. Rest periods are 30-45 seconds between supersets. Heart rate&#xD;
           is monitored throughout each session.&#xD;
&#xD;
           DXA Scan -The dual energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA) procedure for determination of body&#xD;
           composition (muscle, fat, bone) involves minor x-ray exposure. DXA will be performed at&#xD;
           weeks 0, and 12. The effective dose exposure is comparable to 4 hours of sun exposure&#xD;
&#xD;
           Urine Pregnancy Test - All females who have had at least one menstrual cycle have a&#xD;
           urine pregnancy test at initial assessment and prior to each DEXA scan. All females who&#xD;
           have had at least one menstrual cycle are asked questions pertaining to their menstrual&#xD;
           cycle. Because hormone levels may have significant impact on biospecimen analysis, the&#xD;
           acute exercise bout with muscle and blood collections after the intervention period will&#xD;
           be timed to occur in the same phase of the menstrual cycle as the pre-training acute&#xD;
           response exercise bout.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Muscle Sampling - A total of 7 muscle samples are collected by percutaneous needle&#xD;
           muscle biopsy from the vastus lateralis using established procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
           3 collected before and after the first acute response exercise bout in the pre-training&#xD;
           state (pre-exercise, 3 h post-exercise, 24 h post-exercise); 3 collected before and&#xD;
           after the acute response exercise bout in the post-training state (pre-exercise, 3 h&#xD;
           post-exercise, 24 h post-exercise);&#xD;
&#xD;
           1 collected at a follow up visit 4 weeks after the conclusion of the intervention&#xD;
           period.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Blood Sampling - A total of 9 blood samples are collected by venipuncture using&#xD;
           established procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
           4 collected before and after the first acute response exercise bout in the pre-training&#xD;
           state (pre-exercise, 15 min post-exercise, 3 h post-exercise, 24 h post-exercise); 3&#xD;
           collected before and after the acute response exercise bout in the post-training state&#xD;
           (pre-exercise, 15 min post-exercise, 3 h post-exercise, 24 h post-exercise);&#xD;
&#xD;
           1 collected at a follow up visit 4 weeks after the conclusion of the intervention&#xD;
           period.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Exercise Performance Evaluations - 1-repetition maximum (1RM) strength on upper and&#xD;
           lower body movements, peak aerobic capacity (VO2peak) on a cycle ergometer, Wingate&#xD;
           anaerobic power test, peak muscle power of the knee extensors using a&#xD;
           computer-controlled dynamometer, and vertical jump test are conducted before and after&#xD;
           the intervention period. Some performance tests are also conducted mid-intervention&#xD;
           (approximately week 6).&#xD;
&#xD;
           Dietary Intake - Dietary intake will be monitored using a validated 24 hour recall at&#xD;
           weeks 0 and 12.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Quality Assurance:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Exercise Sessions: Subjects will be carefully instructed in proper methods and are&#xD;
           monitored continuously. All exercise sessions are performed under full supervision by&#xD;
           experienced, certified staff [Certified Strength and Conditioning Specialist (National&#xD;
           Strength and Conditioning Association) and/or Certified Exercise Specialist (American&#xD;
           College of Sports Medicine)].&#xD;
&#xD;
           Biospecimens Collection: All muscle biopsies and blood draws are performed by trained,&#xD;
           professional clinician's and research staff who are experienced and locally certified.&#xD;
&#xD;
           DXA scans: All DXA scans are performed by trained technicians at UAB.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Genetic Testing: Genetic testing of samples will be linked to a unique participant ID&#xD;
           that will not identify a participant in any way. Linkages to personal health information&#xD;
           are kept secure at the clinical site (UAB).&#xD;
&#xD;
           The research will be conducted by well trained and experienced personnel who will be&#xD;
           identified to the IRB prior to working on this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
           PI will be ultimately responsible for data and safety monitoring: (i) Keeping all study&#xD;
           documents updated and available for inspection by the sponsor, UAB IRB, and other&#xD;
           authorized reviewers; (ii) Ensuring that appropriate mechanisms to protect the safety of&#xD;
           study participants are being followed; (iii) Ensuring adherence to protocol&#xD;
           requirements; and (iv) Ensuring that data are accurate, complete, and secure. All&#xD;
           documents pertaining to the conduct of the study will be kept on file by the PIs.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Even though this trial does not meet the requirements for a Data and Safety Monitoring&#xD;
           Board, we will follow a proactive, Data and Safety Monitoring Plan as described below.&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Weekly reviews at investigators/staff team meetings of recruitment progress notes,&#xD;
                updates/reports from the exercise facility, laboratories, and data management&#xD;
                staff, and newly available data.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. PIs' quarterly review of safety and interim data analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Annual review performed by the UAB IRB.&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Semi-annual patient safety review by the study team.&#xD;
&#xD;
           All non-serious AEs will be documented, and a summary delivered to the UAB IRB at&#xD;
           pre-determined intervals (at least annually). Any SAEs will be reported to the UAB IRB&#xD;
           within 3 days of their discovery. Aggregate reports of AEs/SAEs will be delivered to the&#xD;
           sponsor as mandated. If an AE (serious or non-serious) occurs, the PI will be&#xD;
           immediately notified. Depending on the event, follow up may require additional tests or&#xD;
           medical procedures as indicated, and/or referral to a specialist. The study physicians&#xD;
           will make such decisions. Depending on the type of AE/SAE, the PIs may opt to&#xD;
           discontinue the subject from the study. The PIs will be ultimately responsible for&#xD;
           evaluating each AE for relationship to the protocol, seriousness and expectedness, any&#xD;
           impact on the risk-to-benefit ratio, and whether modifications are needed to the&#xD;
           informed consent document and/or protocol. The PIs will also have the responsibility of&#xD;
           determining whether the protocol must be suspended until satisfactory modifications are&#xD;
           made; however, ultimate authority in such cases will rest with the UAB IRB.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 23, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized to moderate intensity vs. high-intensity exercise training prescription.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Outcomes assessors analyzing biospecimen samples are blinded to the arm to which each participant has been randomly assigned when doing analysis.&#xD;
Investigators are blinded to each participant's randomized assignment.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in muscle mass</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Muscle mass is assessed using DXA (dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cardiorespiratory fitness (VO2max)</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>VO2max is assessed using via indirect calorimetry during a graded cycle ergometry protocol</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">239</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Moderate Intensity (MOD)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Endurance Training (ET): 3 d/wk x 30 minutes (min) of steady-state, moderate-intensity exercise on a treadmill or stationary cycle ergometer at target heart rate (HR) = 65-75% of maximum oxygen consumption rate (VO2max). The two modes (treadmill, bicycle) are offered for variety, and each subject is required to use each mode at least 1 d/wk to prevent bias.&#xD;
Resistance training (RT): 2 d/wk consisting of a prescription engaging all major muscle groups in 10 movements. Excluding abdominal crunches, target intensity is 12 repetitions/set to volitional fatigue. Subjects complete 3 sets of each movement, with ~60 seconds (s) rest between sets. For each movement, resistance increases when 14 repetitions are achieved for 2 of 3 sets.&#xD;
HR is monitored throughout each session and stored for analysis.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>High Intensity (HI)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>RT: The 2 d/wk RT prescription differs from the MOD arm only in intensity and rest intervals. The same approach to progression applies, but HI RT intensity targets 8-10 repetitions per set; thus, resistance loads increase when 10 repetitions are achieved for 2 of 3 sets. The HI arm performs &quot;superset&quot; training, pairing movements stressing different muscle groups, with only 30-45 s between.&#xD;
ET: In lieu of steady-state endurance exercise, the HI arm performs high-intensity interval training (HIIT) 3 d/wk using a mix of challenging, explosive movements at maximal intensity. 10 x 30 s maximal intensity intervals are separated by 30 s rest intervals.&#xD;
HR is monitored throughout each session and stored for analysis.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Moderate Intensity</intervention_name>
    <description>Exercise prescription intensity is moderate</description>
    <arm_group_label>Moderate Intensity (MOD)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MOD</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>High Intensity</intervention_name>
    <description>Exercise prescription intensity is high</description>
    <arm_group_label>High Intensity (HI)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>HI</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Healthy 18-27 year olds who are not in the US armed forces&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of regular endurance or resistance training in past 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI&gt;30&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to tolerate intense exercise&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unstable or exercise induced angina pectoris or myocardial ischemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurologic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Musculoskeletal disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mental health disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any chronic or infectious disease that would preclude full participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lidocaine allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>27 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marcas Bamman, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama at Birmingham, Center for Exercise Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 15, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 19, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 21, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Marcas M. Bamman, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Site Principle Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>epigenetics</keyword>
  <keyword>exercise dose-response</keyword>
  <keyword>inter-individual response heterogeneity</keyword>
  <keyword>exercise training adaptations</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified data will be available 12 months after completion of the trial. Data will be publicly available indefinitely. Data will include phenotyping test results and molecular mapping results.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>De-identified data will be available 12 months after completion of the trial. Data will be publicly available indefinitely.</ipd_time_frame>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

