<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03380754</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>11180</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03380754</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Preoperative Carbohydrate Rich Drinks on Immediate Postoperative Outcome in Total Knee Arthroplasty</brief_title>
  <acronym>PONV</acronym>
  <official_title>Effects of Preoperative Carbohydrate Rich Drinks on Immediate Postoperative Outcome in Total Knee Arthroplasty</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Henry Ford Health System</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Henry Ford Health System</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to investigate the effect of preoperative carbohydrate rich drinks&#xD;
      on postoperative nausea and vomiting in total knee arthroplasty. This is a prospective,&#xD;
      double blinded, randomized controlled trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Postoperative nausea and vomiting (PONV) continues to pose serious challenge to orthopaedic&#xD;
      adult reconstructive surgeons, even after recent advances in anesthesia and improvements in&#xD;
      perioperative care. Preoperative carbohydrate loading has been well studied in&#xD;
      non-arthroplasty surgical fields. It has been shown to benefits which include decreased&#xD;
      postoperative catabolism and insulin resistance, dampened metabolic stress response, thus&#xD;
      decreased postoperative pain, anxiety, nausea, and vomiting. To the investigators knowledge,&#xD;
      there is currently no literature describing the effects of preoperative carbohydrate rich&#xD;
      drinks (CHO) in the setting of elective total joint arthroplasty. Using a prospective,&#xD;
      randomized, double blind, placebo controlled model, the investigators aim to determine the&#xD;
      effect of CHO on PONV in total knee arthroplasty.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators plan to include a total of 150 patients in this study. All the arthroplasty&#xD;
      surgeons at HF Main Campus expect to participate. Estimating approximately 20 patients&#xD;
      enrolled per month, enrollment would likely occur over time span of 8 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who are scheduled for elective, primary total knee arthroplasty will be recruited&#xD;
      and consented in preoperative clinic visit according to the inclusion and exclusion criteria&#xD;
      as outlined. Screening and consenting will be performed by the orthopaedic surgeon, resident,&#xD;
      physician assistant, or nurse practitioner in clinic, who will be trained for this study.&#xD;
      Patients who elect to participate will be randomized to CHO drink (Group A), placebo drink&#xD;
      (Group B), or traditional fasting/no drink (Group C). Randomization will occur prior to&#xD;
      enrollment in batches of twenty. Patients and treatment team will be blinded to the&#xD;
      assignment. Enrolled subjects will be given a kit which will include study information,&#xD;
      instructions for participation, data collection questionnaire (included with this&#xD;
      submission), multiple-alarm timer, and two beverage bottles (labeled Drink 1 and Drink 2) for&#xD;
      those in Group A or B. Group C will receive the kit, but without beverage. A research&#xD;
      assistant who is not involved in any of the subjects' care will be responsible for&#xD;
      preparation of the kits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Beverage in Group A will consist of a clear, non-carbonated lemon-flavored, iso-osmolar&#xD;
      carbohydrate drink (Nutricia preOp; 12.5% carbohydrates, 50kcal/100mL, 260mOsm/kg, pH 5.0).&#xD;
      This drink has been previously used in studies supporting Enhanced Recovery After Surgery&#xD;
      (ERAS) Society Consensus Guidelines. Beverage in Group B will consist of the same quantity of&#xD;
      clear, lemon flavored water (Nestle Splash Lemon; 0kcal/100mL). All beverages will be bottled&#xD;
      in clear PET plastic IPEC tamper evident bottles. Bottles will be labeled Drink 1 (800 mL) or&#xD;
      Drink 2 (400 mL). Neither subjects nor treatment team will be able to identify type of&#xD;
      beverage, however each drink label will include a special code, available only to research&#xD;
      assistant to be able to identify contents of bottle (treatment vs placebo).&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the evening before surgery (8:00-10:00 PM), subjects in Group A and B will consume&#xD;
      Drink 1 (800 mL) of their respective drink. After midnight, nothing will be allowed by mouth,&#xD;
      except for except for single morning dose of appropriate drink (Drink 2, 400 mL) in Group A&#xD;
      and Group B. Subjects will be instructed to consume morning drink 3 hours prior to scheduled&#xD;
      time of surgery, and be completely consumed at least 2 hours prior to surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Remainder of perioperative care will be standardized and occur according to routine care for&#xD;
      Henry Ford Joints Protocol. Henry Ford Main Campus Perioperative Primary Total Joints&#xD;
      Protocol is included with this submission for reference. All patients will receive epidural&#xD;
      for anesthesia. All patients will receive dexamethasone 10mg IV x 1 dose preoperatively. All&#xD;
      patients will have ondansetron 4mg IV Q6 hours as needed available postoperatively.&#xD;
      Multimodal perioperative pain management regimen will be standardize according to protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Postoperatively, data points will be recorded by nurse in electronic medical record: events&#xD;
      of nausea and vomiting, medication consumption, and pain VAS scores. These data points will&#xD;
      be collected and separated by postop 0-4 hours, 4-12 hours, and 12-24 hours. Additionally,&#xD;
      subjects will be reminded to fill out their questionnaire in preop, 4 hours postop, 12 hours&#xD;
      postop, and 24 hours postop (questionnaire is included in this submission). Primary goal is&#xD;
      to compare incidence and timing of postoperative nausea and vomiting between groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The drink/placebo will be supplied to the patient by the treating surgeon, physician&#xD;
      assistant, or orthopaedic resident in clinic at the time of the last preoperative clinic&#xD;
      visit prior to surgery. The appropriate drink will be included in a &quot;kit&quot; that will be given&#xD;
      to the patient at that time. The kit will include study information, instructions for&#xD;
      participation, the data collection questionnaire (included with this submission), a&#xD;
      multiple-alarm timer, and two beverage bottles (labeled Drink 1 and Drink 2) for those in&#xD;
      Group A or B. Group C will receive the same kit with all the same contents, but without a&#xD;
      beverage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The drinks will be mixed and bottled by the research assistant, and will be &quot;ready to drink&quot;&#xD;
      upon receipt by the participant. This will be performed in batches of 20 to prevent any&#xD;
      shelf-life errors. The carbohydrate rich drink (Nutricia preOp) is purchased in powder form&#xD;
      with included instructions on mixing. Each patient package comes with 6 powder packs. The&#xD;
      powder will be mixed in appropriate plastic beverage container with purified drinking water.&#xD;
      Purified water will be room temperature at time of mixing, per Nutricia instructions. Drinks&#xD;
      will be mixed in their respective beverage container according to manufacturer instruction:&#xD;
      Drink 1 is 800 cc (4 powder packs), and drink 2 is 400 cc (2 powder packs). This drink will&#xD;
      therefore appear clear and similar to the placebo group. For the placebo group, the&#xD;
      appropriate amount of Nestle Splash Lemon flavored water will be poured into the appropriate&#xD;
      bottles. Bottles will be capped with tamper evident caps. &quot;Ready to drink&quot; beverages will&#xD;
      then be included in the appropriate kits by the research assistant. The kits will then be&#xD;
      stored in a cool place, locked, away from light, in one of the K12 clinic offices. All mixing&#xD;
      and bottling will be performed with use of standard sanitary precautions by one person, the&#xD;
      research assistant. The research assistant will also be responsible for labelling and coding&#xD;
      the drinks to allow for identification of the drinks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The questionnaire will be included in the kit, which is given to the patient at their last&#xD;
      preoperative visit prior to surgery. The kit will also include a handheld multiple-alarm&#xD;
      timing device, which will be used to ensure patients complete the appropriate sections of&#xD;
      their questionnaire at the requested time points. In the preoperative holding area, the&#xD;
      patients will simply be reminded by the staff, resident, or surgeon, to complete the &quot;preop&quot;&#xD;
      portion of the questionnaire. Post-operatively, the multiple-alarm timer will be utilized to&#xD;
      standardize timing of responses. The timer will be programmed appropriately before surgery,&#xD;
      and will be &quot;started&quot; by the orthopaedic resident postoperatively once the patient is dropped&#xD;
      off in the recovery unit following surgery. The handheld timer will be pre-programmed to&#xD;
      sound an alarm at time points 4 hours, 12 hours, and 24 hours post surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients themselves will be mostly responsible for ensuring they comply with the requested&#xD;
      time points in completing the questionnaire. However, the orthopaedic floor nurses will also&#xD;
      be educated on this study and will encourage/assist in administration of the questionnaire&#xD;
      when needed. The nurse will collect the questionnaire once it is complete, prior to patient&#xD;
      discharge. The nursing station will have a specific folder where each questionnaire will be&#xD;
      placed following completion. The research assistant will check folder daily, and items will&#xD;
      be collected.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 15, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 1, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 1, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective, randomized, double blinded, placebo controlled trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Research assistant who is not involved in any of the patients clinical care is responsible for randomization collection of data. All others are blinded to the groups involved.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post operative nausea</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Nausea, assess by questionnaire, 10 point scale (0 = no nausea, 10 = very nauseous, and medical record.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post operative nausea</measure>
    <time_frame>12 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Nausea, assess by questionnaire, 10 point scale (0 = no nausea, 10 = very nauseous, and medical record.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post operative nausea</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Nausea, assess by questionnaire, 10 point scale (0 = no nausea, 10 = very nauseous, and medical record.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post operative vomiting</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Vomiting, assess by questionnaire, 10 point scale (0 = no vomiting, 10 = copious emesis, and medical record notes of emesis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post operative vomiting</measure>
    <time_frame>12 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Vomiting, assess by questionnaire, 10 point scale (0 = no vomiting, 10 = copious emesis, and medical record notes of emesis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post operative vomiting</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Vomiting, assess by questionnaire, 10 point scale (0 = no vomiting, 10 = copious emesis, and medical record notes of emesis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>From the time of hospital admission following surgery, until the time of hospital discharge as recorded in EMR, assessed up to 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Length of stay recorded in hours</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post operative opiate consumption</measure>
    <time_frame>From the time of surgery until the time of hospital discharge, assessed up to 72 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Morphine equivalents, opiates assessed by medical record</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post operative pain scores</measure>
    <time_frame>From the time of surgery until the time of hospital discharge, assessed up to 72 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Pain, 10 point visual analog pain scale (0 = no pain, 10 = worst pain ever)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peri operative hunger and discomfort</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours, 12 hours, and 24 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Hunger and discomfort, 10 point hunger scale (0 = satiated and comfortable, 10 = very hungry and uncomfortable)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of secondary adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>From the time of surgery until the time of hospital discharge, assessed up to 1 month postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>pulmonary aspiration, delay of surgery due to consumption of drink.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Post Operative Nausea and Vomiting</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Carbohydrate Rich Drink</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group A will receive the carbohydrate rich drink, Nutricia preOp. This is the intervention group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Drink</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group B will receive placebo, Nestle Splash Lemon Flavor Water (Placebo) (similarly flavored and appearing water, however with no calorie, carbohydrate or nutritional content).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No Drink</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group C will not receive any drink. This group will follow normal protocol.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nutricia preOp</intervention_name>
    <description>A clear, non-carbonated lemon-flavored, iso-osmolar carbohydrate drink for preoperative surgical patients. Used in studies supporting the Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS) Society Consensus Guidelines.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Carbohydrate Rich Drink</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Carbohydrate rich drink</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nestle Splash Lemon Flavor Water (Placebo)</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo control drink. PURIFIED WATER, NATURAL FLAVORS, CITRIC ACID, SODIUM POLYPHOSPHATE, POTASSIUM SORBATE (PRESERVE FRESHNESS), POTASSIUM BENZOATE (PRESERVE FRESHNESS), SUCRALOSE, ACESULFAME POTASSIUM, CALCIUM DISODIUM EDTA, MAGNESIUM SULFATE.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Drink</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients (&gt;18 years of age) scheduled for elective, unilateral, primary total&#xD;
             knee arthroplasty&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to give valid consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impaired gastrointestinal motility&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  On pro-motility medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HbA1c &gt; 7.5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting glucose &gt;200&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acquired immunodeficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal failure (creatinine &gt; 2 mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cirrhosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe malnutrition.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael Charters, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Henry Ford Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Henry Ford Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 31, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 19, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 21, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 13, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 13, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Henry Ford Health System</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michael Charters, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator, MD, Adult Joint Reconstruction</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Nausea</keyword>
  <keyword>Vomiting</keyword>
  <keyword>Knee Arthroplasty</keyword>
  <keyword>PONV</keyword>
  <keyword>TKA</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nausea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>There are currently no plans to share participant data with other researchers.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

