<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03389126</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H-1708-040-876</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03389126</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase II Study of Avelumab in Patients With Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma After Prior Sorafenib Treatment</brief_title>
  <acronym>AvelumabHCC</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase II Study of Avelumab in Patients With Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma After Prior Sorafenib Treatment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Seoul National University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Merck KGaA, Darmstadt, Germany</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Seoul National University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      An open label, single arm, Phase II study of avelumab in patients with advanced&#xD;
      hepatocellular carcinoma after prior sorafenib treatment&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an open label study of avelumab monotherapy. Patients with advanced hepatocellular&#xD;
      carcinoma after prior sorafenib treatment are eligible. Patients should have failed to&#xD;
      sorafenib or be intolerant to sorafenib.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>RECIST v1.1</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Avelumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Avelumab 10 mg/kg every 2 wks until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Avelumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Avelumab 10 mg/kg intravenous injection every 2 weeks until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity</description>
    <arm_group_label>Avelumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Bavencio</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Ability to understand the purpose of the study, provide signed and dated informed&#xD;
             consent, and able to comply with all procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Male or female subjects aged ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Histologically or cytologically proven advanced hepatocellular carcinoma not eligible&#xD;
             for surgical and/or locoregional therapies; or progressive disease after surgical and&#xD;
             /or locoregional therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients who were intolerant to sorafenib or for whom sorafenib failed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. At least one RECIST 1.1 measurable untreated lesion. All subjects must have at least&#xD;
             one previously untreated, unidimensionally measurable lesion by contrast-enhanced&#xD;
             spiral computed tomography (CT) ≥ 10 mm or contrast enhanced dynamic magnetic&#xD;
             resonance imaging (MRI) scan ≥ 10 mm (malignant lymph nodes must be ≥ 15 mm on short&#xD;
             axis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. ECOG performance status of 0 to 1 at trial entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Child-Pugh Class A&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects are eligible to enroll if they have non-viral-HCC, or if they have HBV-HCC,&#xD;
             or HCV-HCC defined as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
             i) HBV-HCC: Resolved HBV infection (as evidenced by detectable HBV surface antibody,&#xD;
             detectable HBV core antibody, undetectable HBV DNA, and undetectable HBV surface&#xD;
             antigen) or Chronic HBV infection (as evidenced by detectable HBV surface antigen or&#xD;
             HBV DNA). Subjects with chronic HBV infection must have HBV DNA &lt; 100 IU/mL and must&#xD;
             be on antiviral therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
             ii) HCV-HCC: Active or resolved HCV infection as evidenced by detectable HCV RNA or&#xD;
             antibody&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy&#xD;
             test. Highly effective contraception for both male and female subjects throughout the&#xD;
             study and for at least 30 days after last avelumab treatment administration if the&#xD;
             risk of conception exists.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Males who are sexually active with WOCBP must agree to follow instructions for method&#xD;
             of contraception as indicated in the informed consent form, for the duration of&#xD;
             treatment with study drug plus 5 half-lives of the study drug plus 90 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Known fibrolamellar HCC, sarcomatoid HCC, or mixed cholangiocarcinoma and HCC&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Prior liver transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Active, known, or suspected autoimmune disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pregnancy or lactation period&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participation in another clinical trial within the past 30 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Inadequate hepatic function defined by a total bilirubin level &gt; 3.0 mg/dl, an AST&#xD;
             level &gt; 5 × the upper limit of normal range (ULN), and an ALT level &gt; 5 × ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Inadequate renal function defined by an estimated creatinine clearance &lt; 50 mL/min&#xD;
             according to the Cockcroft-Gault formula or by measure of creatinine clearance from 24&#xD;
             hour urine collection&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Inadequate hematologic function defined by WBC &lt; 2000/μL, Platelets &lt; 60,000/μL,&#xD;
             Hemoglobin &lt; 8.5 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Active brain metastases or leptomeningeal metastases, requiring immunosuppressive&#xD;
             doses of corticosteroids (&gt; 10 mg/day prednisone equivalents).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. IMMUNOSUPRESSANTS: &quot;Current use of immunosuppressive medication, EXCEPT for the&#xD;
             following: a. intranasal, inhaled, topical steroids, or local steroid injection (e.g.,&#xD;
             intra-articular injection); b. Systemic corticosteroids at physiologic doses ≤ 10&#xD;
             mg/day of prednisone or equivalent; c. Steroids as premedication for hypersensitivity&#xD;
             reactions (e.g., CT scan premedication).&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. AUTOIMMUNE DISEASE: &quot;Active autoimmune disease that might deteriorate when receiving&#xD;
             an immuno-stimulatory agent. Patients with diabetes type I, vitiligo, psoriasis, or&#xD;
             hypo- or hyperthyroid diseases not requiring immunosuppressive treatment are&#xD;
             eligible.&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. ORGAN TRANSPLANTATION: &quot;Prior organ transplantation including allogenic stem-cell&#xD;
             transplantation.&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. INFECTIONS: &quot;Active infection requiring systemic therapy. &quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. HIV/AIDS: &quot;Known history of testing positive for HIV or known acquired&#xD;
             immunodeficiency syndrome.&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. VACCINATION: &quot;Vaccination within 4 weeks of the first dose of avelumab and while on&#xD;
             trials is prohibited except for administration of inactivated vaccines &quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. HYPERSENSITIIVTY TO STUDY DRUG: &quot;Known prior severe hypersensitivity to&#xD;
             investigational product or any component in its formulations, including known severe&#xD;
             hypersensitivity reactions to monoclonal antibodies (NCI CTCAE v4.03 Grade ≥ 3)&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. CARDIOVASCULAR DISEASE: &quot;Clinically significant (i.e., active) cardiovascular disease:&#xD;
             cerebral vascular accident/stroke (&lt; 6 months prior to enrollment), myocardial&#xD;
             infarction (&lt; 6 months prior to enrollment), unstable angina, congestive heart failure&#xD;
             (≥ New York Heart Association Classification Class II), or serious cardiac arrhythmia&#xD;
             requiring medication.&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. OTHER PERSISTING TOXICITIES: &quot;Persisting toxicity related to prior therapy (NCI CTCAE&#xD;
             v. 4.03 Grade &gt; 1); however, alopecia, sensory neuropathy Grade ≤ 2, or other Grade ≤&#xD;
             2 not constituting a safety risk based on investigator's judgment are acceptable.&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Other severe acute or chronic medical conditions including immune colitis,&#xD;
             inflammatory bowel disease, immune pneumonitis, pulmonary fibrosis or psychiatric&#xD;
             conditions including recent (within the past year) or active suicidal ideation or&#xD;
             behavior; or laboratory abnormalities that may increase the risk associated with study&#xD;
             participation or study treatment administration or may interfere with the&#xD;
             interpretation of study results and, in the judgment of the investigator, would make&#xD;
             the patient inappropriate for entry into this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Any history of clinically meaningful variceal bleeding within the last three months&#xD;
             21, Prior treatment with anti-PD-1, anti-PD-L1, anti-PD-L2, anti-CD137, or anti-CTLA-4&#xD;
             antibodies (or other agents specifically targeting immune checkpoint pathway)&#xD;
&#xD;
        22. Prior malignancy active within the previous 3 years except for locally curable cancers&#xD;
        that have been apparently cured, such as basal or squamous cell skin cancer, superficial&#xD;
        bladder cancer, or carcinoma in situ of the prostate, cervix, or breast.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kyung-Hun Lee, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Seoul National University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seoul National University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>03080</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 27, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 27, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 3, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Seoul National University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kyung-Hun Lee</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Avelumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data sharing should be decided upon formal documented requests.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

