<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04569461</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00103396</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04569461</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Trimodality Approach to Localized Prostate Cancer: Pembrolizumab, ADT, and SBRT Followed by Prostatectomy</brief_title>
  <acronym>TALON</acronym>
  <official_title>Trimodality Approach to Unfavorable Localized Prostate Cancer: a Prospective Trial of Neoadjuvant Pembrolizumab, ADT, and Prostate SBRT Followed by Radical Prostatectomy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Daniel George, MD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Duke University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will enroll prostate cancer patients with an unfavorable diagnosis. Subjects will&#xD;
      receive a combination of pembrolizumab, Stereotactic Body Radiation Therapy (SBRT) to the&#xD;
      prostate, and short-term androgen deprivation therapy (STADT or Short-term ADT). After&#xD;
      receiving this &quot;trimodal therapy&quot;, subjects will undergo a radical prostatectomy. The&#xD;
      prostate tissue will be analyzed for differences in pathology and local immune cell&#xD;
      infiltration, and subjects will be followed for 2 years to watch for prostate specific&#xD;
      antigen (PSA) recurrence. The PSA results will be analyzed by comparing them to historical&#xD;
      controls that have already been published, to learn if this therapy approach delays PSA rise.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of subjects who achieve biochemical progression-free survival (BPFS) at 24 months (2 years)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>BPFS will be defined as at least two PSAs 6+ weeks apart with first PSA &gt; 0.2 ng/ml and second PSA &gt;0.2 ng/ml occurring at least 3 months after surgery</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pathologic response in prostatectomy tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, up to 1 year after last prostatectomy</time_frame>
    <description>Pathologic response will be graded using a published 3-point scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>12 week post-operative PSA</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after prostatectomy</time_frame>
    <description>12 week post-operative PSA after pembrolizumab/SBRT/STADT/ RP,</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">39</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects with unfavorable localized prostate cancer will be enrolled.This is a single arm, phase II study of pembrolizumab (Keytruda), SBRT, and Short-term Androgen Deprivation Therapy (STADT), known together as trimodality therapy, followed by radical prostatectomy 8 weeks after SBRT.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>200 mg of Pembrolizumab (KEYTRUDA) will be given by IV every 3 weeks for 5 cycles, a total of 15 weeks of treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>KEYTRUDA</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Stereotactic body radiation therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>SBRT will begin on week 7 of the study. The radiation will be given every other day in 5 fractions of 6 Gy for a total of 30 Gy of radiation exposure.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SBRT</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Short-term androgen deprivation therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Short-term ADT will last for five months. It will consist of treatment with a 1 month dose beginning on Day 0 of the study. Then it will continue with either a single 4 month dose on week 5, or 4 additional 1 month doses, depending on patient and physician preference.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>STADT</other_name>
    <other_name>Short-term ADT</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Radical Prostatectomy</intervention_name>
    <description>Radical prostatectomy surgery will be performed between week 17 and week 20 of the study, as scheduling permits.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>RP</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Histologic evidence of adenocarcinoma of the prostate who are deemed candidates for&#xD;
             radical prostatectomy. Variants such as neuroendocrine components or ductal carcinoma&#xD;
             are allowed. Pure small cell carcinoma is not allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. At least two intermediate risk factors or classified as high risk or very high risk&#xD;
             clinically localized disease as defined by NCCN guidelines:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Very high risk. At least one of the following: i. cT3b-T4 disease ii. Primary&#xD;
             Gleason pattern of 5 iii. More than 4 cores with a Gleason sum of 8, 9 or 10 b. High&#xD;
             risk: At least one of the following: i. cT3a disease ii. Gleason sum of 8, 9 or 10&#xD;
             iii. PSA ≥ 20 ng/ml c. At least two of the following intermediate risk factors: i.&#xD;
             cT2b or cT2c disease ii. Gleason sum of 7 (either 3+4 or 4+3) iii. PSA 10-20 ng/ml&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of ≤1 (See Appendix A)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. International Prostate Symptom Score (IPSS) of &lt;18 within 28 days of Cycle 1 Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Adequate normal organ and marrow function as defined below by the following criteria&#xD;
             within 10 days prior to first dose of study treatment. :&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC ≥1.5 x 109/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Platelet count ≥100 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Serum bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x Institutional Upper Limit of Normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. AST/SGOT and ALT/SGPT ≤ 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Measured creatinine clearance (CL) &gt;50 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patient is willing and able to comply with the protocol for the duration of the study&#xD;
             including undergoing treatment and scheduled visits and examinations including follow&#xD;
             up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of or known bone, brain, visceral, or soft tissue metastasis, including lymph&#xD;
             nodes based on standard of care imaging with CT or pelvic MRI showing no LNs greater&#xD;
             than 1.5cm and bone scan showing no evidence of bone metastasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Prior pelvic radiation or prostate cryotherapy or high-intensity focused ultrasound&#xD;
             (HIFU)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any prior treatment with PD-1 or PD-L1 checkpoint inhibitors or with an agent directed&#xD;
             to another stimulatory or co-inhibitory T-cell receptor (eg, CTLA-4, OX 40, CD137,&#xD;
             PD-L2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Is currently participating in or has participated in a study of an investigational&#xD;
             agent (or used an investigational device) within 4 weeks prior to the first dose of&#xD;
             study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Note: Participants who have entered the follow-up phase of an investigational study&#xD;
             may participate as long as it has been 4 weeks after the last dose of the previous&#xD;
             investigational agent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Prior therapy for prostate cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Exceptions: Previous alpha-reductase inhibitor use allowed IF patient has not been&#xD;
             taking for at least 30 days prior to study treatment initiation, OR if alpha reductase&#xD;
             inhibitor was not used as a primary treatment of prostate cancer and the PSA on&#xD;
             alpha-reductase inhibitor remains within eligibility when doubled. ]&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any concurrent chemotherapy, investigational product, biologic, or hormonal therapy&#xD;
             for cancer treatment. Concurrent use of hormonal therapy for non-cancer-related&#xD;
             conditions (e.g., hormone replacement therapy) is acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Has active autoimmune disease that has required systemic treatment in the past 2 years&#xD;
             (i.e. with use of disease modifying agents, corticosteroids beyond prednisone 10mg&#xD;
             daily or equivalent, or other immunosuppressive drugs). Replacement therapy (eg.,&#xD;
             thyroxine, insulin, or physiologic corticosteroid replacement therapy for adrenal or&#xD;
             pituitary insufficiency, etc.) is not considered a form of systemic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Presence of a condition requiring chronic steroid use (equivalent to &gt;10 mg of&#xD;
             prednisone daily) or other immunosuppressive drugs (i.e., for organ transplant). The&#xD;
             following are exceptions to this criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Intranasal, inhaled, topical steroids, or local steroid injections (e.g., intra&#xD;
                  articular injection)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Steroids as premedication for hypersensitivity reactions (e.g., CT scan&#xD;
                  premedication)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness, including but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, uncontrolled hypertension, unstable&#xD;
             angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, interstitial lung disease, serious chronic&#xD;
             gastrointestinal conditions associated with diarrhea, or psychiatric illness/social&#xD;
             situations that would limit compliance with study requirement, substantially increase&#xD;
             risk of incurring AEs or compromise the ability of the patient to give written&#xD;
             informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of another primary malignancy except for:&#xD;
&#xD;
             c. Malignancy treated with curative intent and with no known active disease ≥5 years&#xD;
             before the first dose of IP and of low potential risk for recurrence d. Adequately&#xD;
             treated non-melanoma skin cancer or lentigo maligna without evidence of disease e.&#xD;
             Adequately treated carcinoma in situ without evidence of disease&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of allogenic stem cell transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. History of active primary immunodeficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Known history of human immunodeficiency virus&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Has a known history of Hepatitis B (defined as Hepatitis B surface antigen [HBsAg]&#xD;
             reactive) or known active Hepatitis C virus (defined as HCV RNA [qualitative] is&#xD;
             detected) infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Has received a live vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose of study drug.&#xD;
             Examples of live vaccines include, but are not limited to, the following: measles,&#xD;
             mumps, rubella, varicella/zoster (chicken pox), yellow fever, rabies, Bacillus&#xD;
             Calmette-Guérin (BCG), and typhoid vaccine. Seasonal influenza vaccines for injection&#xD;
             are generally killed virus vaccines and are allowed; however, intranasal influenza&#xD;
             vaccines (eg, FluMist®) are live attenuated vaccines and are not allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Has a history of (non-infectious) pneumonitis that required steroids or has current&#xD;
             pneumonitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Any condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, would preclude participation&#xD;
             in this trial&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Daniel George, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Duke University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Julia Hurrelbrink, RN, BSN</last_name>
    <phone>919-681-1030</phone>
    <email>julie.hurrelbrink@duke.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Daniel George, MD</last_name>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Julia Hurrelbrink, RN, BSN</last_name>
      <phone>919-681-1030</phone>
      <email>julia.hurrelbrink@duke.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bridget Koontz, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Duke University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Daniel George, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Medicine and Professor in Surgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>prostate cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>KEYTRUDA</keyword>
  <keyword>pembrolizumab</keyword>
  <keyword>androgen deprivation therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>prostatectomy</keyword>
  <keyword>localized prostate cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>ADT</keyword>
  <keyword>SBRT</keyword>
  <keyword>stereotactic</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Androgens</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

