<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04565054</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>WSG-AM11</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2019-001488-60</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04565054</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Adj. Dyn. Marker-adjusted Personalized Therapy Comparing Abemaciclib + SOC ET vs. SOC ET in Clinical or Genomic High Risk, HR+/HER2- EBC</brief_title>
  <acronym>ADAPTlate</acronym>
  <official_title>Adjuvant Dynamic Marker - Adjusted Personalized Therapy Comparing Abemaciclib Combined With Standard Adjuvant Endocrine Therapy Versus Standard Adjuvant Endocrine Therapy in (Clinical or Genomic) High Risk, HR+/HER2- Early Breast Cancer (ADAPTlate)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>West German Study Group</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eli Lilly and Company</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Genomic Health®, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>West German Study Group</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients with breast cancer, who have completed first line therapy (e.g., radiotherapy,&#xD;
      chemotherapy, surgery), and who have to be identified with having a high risk of recurrence&#xD;
      of cancer, will be eligible for the study. This patient group is currently offered a standard&#xD;
      of care chemotherapy plus endocrine therapy (ET). The study investigates whether the patient&#xD;
      group with high-risk early breast cancer benefits from treatment with the medication&#xD;
      abemaciclib in combination with ET compared to ET alone.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The WSG ADAPT trial program is one of the first new generation trials addressing the issue of&#xD;
      individualization of (neo)-adjuvant decision-making in early breast cancer (EBC) in a&#xD;
      subtype-specific manner. The first WSG ADAPT umbrella trial (NCT01779206) aimed to establish&#xD;
      early predictive molecular surrogate markers for response after a short 3-week induction&#xD;
      treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goals of the WSG ADAPT trial program - early response assessment and subtype-specific&#xD;
      therapy tailoring to those patients who are most likely to benefit - have contributed to the&#xD;
      positive national and international feedback regarding the ADAPT-concept as a whole.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this ADAPTlate phase-III-trial is to gain further knowledge of the group of&#xD;
      patients at high risk for disease recurrence, who have completed definite locoregional&#xD;
      therapy (with or without neoadjuvant or adjuvant chemotherapy). This patient group is&#xD;
      currently offered an adjuvant chemotherapy plus endocrine therapy. Yet, the high-risk&#xD;
      population only receives suboptimum benefit from standard ET and often develops resistance&#xD;
      against ET at time of recurrence. With ADAPTlate it is planned to investigate if the&#xD;
      high-risk patient group identified during the screening phase derives additional benefit from&#xD;
      treatment with abemaciclib in combination with ET compared to ET alone.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 2, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>multicenter, interventional, prospective, two-arm, randomized, open-label, controlled adjuvant, phase-III trial evaluating the efficacy and safety of abemaciclib with endocrine therapy (ET) versus standard-of-care endocrine therapy in early breast cancer (EBC) patients with molecular HR+/HER2- subtype.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>invasive disease-free survival (iDFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>at end of study, 3-6 years after start of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>superiority in invasive disease-free survival (iDFS) of abemaciclib + endocrine therapy vs. standard-of-care endocrine therapy in patients with HR+/HER2- high risk breast cancer.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>at end of study, 3-6 years after start of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>assessment of overall survival (OS) and distant DFS (dDFS) in both arms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>differences in overall survival (OS) and dDFS</measure>
    <time_frame>at end of study, 3-6 years after start of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>differences in overall survival (OS) and dDFS between arms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>subgroup and multivariable survival analyses</measure>
    <time_frame>at end of study, 3-6 years after start of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>subgroup and multivariable survival analyses</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CNS metastases</measure>
    <time_frame>at end of study, 3-6 years after start of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>occurrence of CNS metastases</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EORTC QLQ-C30</measure>
    <time_frame>at end of study, on average 3-6 years after start of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>quality of life (QoL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EORTC QLQ-BR23</measure>
    <time_frame>at end of study, on average 3-6 years after start of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>quality of life (QoL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EQ-5D-5L</measure>
    <time_frame>at end of study, on average 3-6 years after start of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>quality of life (QoL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1250</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer Female</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Abemaciclib plus ET</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Abemaciclib 150 mg, 2 x daily, resulting in 300 mg/day, oral, 24 months plus endocrine treatment of physician´s choice</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard-of-care ET</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard-of-care ET according to clinical guidelines.&#xD;
Premenopausal patients:&#xD;
Either aromatase inhibitor + GnRH agonist&#xD;
or Tamoxifen +/- GnRH-agonist (as per investigator´s decision) or&#xD;
Postmenopausal patients:&#xD;
Either Aromatase inhibitor&#xD;
or Tamoxifen OR</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Abemaciclib 50 MG; 150mg 1-0-1 per os</intervention_name>
    <description>Experimental: Abemaciclib plus ET Abemaciclib 150 mg, 2 x daily, resulting in 300 mg/day, oral, 24 months plus endocrine treatment of physician´s choice</description>
    <arm_group_label>Abemaciclib plus ET</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A. Prior to REGISTRATION&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Written informed consent prior to any study procedures (outcomes of standard-of-care&#xD;
             procedures performed before signing of informed consent by the patient but within&#xD;
             allowed screening period can be used for screening of patient).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Female.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. ≥ 18 years of age. 4a. EITHER: (Post)menopausal status at the time of initiation of&#xD;
             adjuvant study medication&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  patient underwent bilateral oophorectomy, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  age ≥ 60, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  age &lt; 60 and amenorrhea for 12 or more months (in the absence of chemotherapy,&#xD;
                  tamoxifen, or ovarian suppression) and/or FSH and estradiol in the postmenopausal&#xD;
                  range per local normal range.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  4b. OR: Pre-menopausal patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  confirmed negative serum or urine pregnancy test (β-hCG) before starting study&#xD;
                  treatment, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  patient has had a hysterectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Histologically confirmed diagnosis of primary estrogen-receptor positive and/or&#xD;
        progesterone-receptor positive early breast cancer by local laboratory. In case the&#xD;
        receptor status from local pathology is unclear a central pathology review is obligatory.&#xD;
        Results must be known prior to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Patient has HER2-negative breast cancer defined as&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a negative in-situ hybridization test or an IHC status of 0, 1+, or 2+,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  if IHC is 2+, a negative in-situ hybridization (FISH, CISH, or SISH) test is required&#xD;
             (based on the analyzed tissue sample at initial diagnosis by a local laboratory).&#xD;
&#xD;
             7. Completed local therapy of breast cancer according to current guidelines. 8.&#xD;
             Completed or ongoing endocrine therapy for 2-6 years after primary diagnosis without&#xD;
             any signs of distant or local relapse as well secondary malignancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
             9a. Known high clinical risk, defined as either one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  c/pN 2-3,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pN 0-1 and high CTS5 score,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  cN 1 or G3 tumor and non-pCR after neoadjuvant chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pN0-1 and G3 with Ki-67 pre-treatment &gt; 40%; OR 9b. Known high genomic risk, defined&#xD;
             as either one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  c/pN 1 with RS (Oncotype Dx®) &gt;18,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  c/pN 0 with RS &gt;25,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  high risk by PROSIGNA® (score &gt; 60 in N 0 and &gt;40 in N+) or EPclin® (Score &gt;3.3287),&#xD;
             or MammaPrint® within clinical routine; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
        In case the tumor is of intermediate clinical risk, but genomic risk is not known at&#xD;
        registration:&#xD;
&#xD;
        9c. Intermediate clinical and unknown genomic risk c/pN 0-1 in luminal-B-like tumor (G3&#xD;
        and/or Ki-67 pre-treatment ≥ 20%), AND&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RS &gt;18 (Oncotype Dx® in screening phase) in patients with c/pN 1, or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RS &gt;25 (Oncotype Dx® in screening phase) in patients with c/pN 0.&#xD;
&#xD;
        B. Prior to RANDOMIZATION in the study 10. No clinical evidence of distant metastasis&#xD;
        (confirmation recommended prior to randomization by CT thorax / abdomen, chest X-ray, liver&#xD;
        ultrasound, bone scan, or PET-CT, respectively).&#xD;
&#xD;
        11. Patient has available tumor tissue from primary diagnostic biopsy. 12. No&#xD;
        contraindication for adjuvant ET. 13. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance&#xD;
        status 0-1. 14. Patient has adequate bone marrow and organ function as defined by the&#xD;
        following laboratory values:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1.5 × 109/L (without administration of any growth&#xD;
             stimulation factors within 30 days prior to inclusion),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  platelets ≥ 100 × 109/L,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hemoglobin ≥ 8.0 g/dL (without any RBC transfusion within 30 days prior to inclusion),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  total bilirubin &lt;1.5 ULN, except for patients with Gilbert's Syndrome who may only be&#xD;
             included if the total bilirubin is ≤ 2.0 × ULN or direct bilirubin within normal&#xD;
             ranges,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  aspartate transaminase (AST) &lt; 3 × ULN,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  alanine transaminase (ALT) &lt; 3 × ULN,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN. 15. Ability to swallow abemaciclib tablets or to&#xD;
             administer other study medication, respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
             16. Ability to communicate with the investigator and comply with study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
             17. Willing to receive therapy by the clinical site, as required by the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients eligible for inclusion in this study must not meet any of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient with distant metastases of breast cancer beyond regional lymph nodes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Previously received CDK 4/6 inhibitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient with a known hypersensitivity to any of the excipients of abemaciclib or&#xD;
             standard-of-care endocrine therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient has had major surgery within 14 days prior to starting study drug or has not&#xD;
             recovered from major side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient has not recovered from clinical and laboratory acute toxicities related to&#xD;
             prior anticancer therapies to NCI CTCAE version 5.0 Grade ≤ 1 (polyneuropathy ≤ 2 is&#xD;
             allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patient has a concurrent malignancy or non-breast malignancy within 5 years prior to&#xD;
             randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patient has impairment of gastrointestinal (GI) function or GI disease that may&#xD;
             significantly alter the absorption of the study drugs (e.g., uncontrolled ulcerative&#xD;
             diseases, uncontrolled nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, malabsorption syndrome, or&#xD;
             small-bowel resection).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patient has any active systemic bacterial infection (requiring intravenous antibiotics&#xD;
             at time of initiating study treatment), fungal infection, or detectable viral&#xD;
             infection (such as known human immunodeficiency virus positivity or with known active&#xD;
             hepatitis B or C [for example, hepatitis B surface antigen positive]. Screening is not&#xD;
             required for enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patient has any other concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled medical condition that&#xD;
             would, in the investigator´s judgment, cause unacceptable safety risks, contraindicate&#xD;
             patient participation in the clinical study, or compromise compliance with the&#xD;
             protocol (e.g., interstitial lung disease, severe dyspnea at rest or requiring oxygen&#xD;
             therapy, severe renal impairment [e.g. estimated creatinine clearance &lt;30ml/min],&#xD;
             history of major surgical resection involving the stomach or small bowel, or&#xD;
             preexisting Crohn's disease or ulcerative colitis or a preexisting chronic condition&#xD;
             resulting in baseline Grade 2 or higher diarrhea, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patient has a personal history of any of the following conditions: syncope of&#xD;
             cardiovascular etiology, ventricular arrhythmia of pathological origin (including, but&#xD;
             not limited to, ventricular tachycardia and ventricular fibrillation), or sudden&#xD;
             cardiac arrest.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patient is currently receiving any of the following substances, which cannot be&#xD;
             discontinued 7 days prior to day 1 of study treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
             o concomitant medications and herbal supplements, that are strong inducers or&#xD;
             inhibitors of CYP3A4.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Participation in a prior investigational study within 30 days prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Not able to understand and to comply with study instructions and requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Pregnant or nursing (lactating) woman.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Woman of child-bearing potential defined as woman physiologically capable of becoming&#xD;
             pregnant, unless she is using highly effective methods of contraception during the&#xD;
             study treatment and for 21 days after stopping the treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. total abstinence (when this is in line with the preferred and usual lifestyle of&#xD;
                  the patient).&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. female sterilization (have had surgical bilateral oophorectomy with or without&#xD;
                  hysterectomy), total hysterectomy, or tubal ligation at least 6 weeks before&#xD;
                  taking study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. male partner sterilization (at least 6 months prior to study screening). For&#xD;
                  female patients on the study, the vasectomized male partner should be the sole&#xD;
                  partner for that patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. placement of an intrauterine device (IUD).&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. use of condom + spermicide.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Use of oral (estrogen and progesterone), transdermal, injected, or implanted hormonal&#xD;
             methods of contraception as well as hormonal replacement therapy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Oleg Gluz, PD Dr. med.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Westdeutsche Studiengruppe GmbH</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Anja Braschoß, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+4917682119153</phone>
    <email>anja.braschoss@wsg-online.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Bettina Bonn, Dr.</last_name>
    <phone>+4921615662328</phone>
    <email>bettina.bonn@wsg-online.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Praxis für interdisziplinäre Onkologie &amp; Hämatologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Freiburg</city>
        <state>Baden-Württemberg</state>
        <zip>79110</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Matthias Zaiss, Dr</last_name>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Norbert Marschner, Dr</last_name>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brustzentrum, LMU Klinikum, Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität,</name>
      <address>
        <city>Muenchen</city>
        <state>Bayern</state>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nadia Harbeck, Prof. Dr. med.</last_name>
      <email>nadia.harbeck@med.uni-muenchen.de</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tom Degenhardt, Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nadia Harbeck, PRof. Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Niels-Stensen-Kliniken Franziskus-Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Georgsmarienhütte</city>
        <state>Niedersachsen</state>
        <zip>49124</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kerstin Lüdtke-Heckenkamp, Dr. med.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 541 5022466</phone>
      <email>jost.wamhoff@niels-stensen-kliniken.de</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Jost Wamhoff, Dr. med.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 541 5022466</phone>
      <email>jost.wamhoff@niels-stensen-kliniken.de</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kerstin Lüdtke-Heckenkamp, Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jost Wamhoff, Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Diakovere Henriettenstift Frauenklinik</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hannover</city>
        <state>Niedersachsen</state>
        <zip>30559</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Angela Kentsch, Dr. med.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 511 2893455</phone>
      <email>angela.kentsch@diakovere.de</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Sabine Anolke</last_name>
      <phone>+49 511 2893455</phone>
      <email>sabine.anolke@diakovere.de</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kristina Lübbe, Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Angela Kentsch, Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Krankenhaus Köln Holweide, Brustzentrum</name>
      <address>
        <city>Köln</city>
        <state>Nordrhein-Westfalen</state>
        <zip>51067</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mathias Warm, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+49 221 8907</phone>
      <phone_ext>6707</phone_ext>
      <email>warmm@kliniken-koeln.de</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mathias Warm, Prof. Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Myriam Vincent, Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Aachen, Frauenklinik - Senologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aachen</city>
        <state>NRW</state>
        <zip>52074</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Katja Krauss, Dr</last_name>
      <phone>+49-241-8080700</phone>
      <email>kkrauss@ukaachen.de</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Katja Krauss, Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Elmar Stickeler, Prof. Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kliniken Essen-Mitte, Klinik für Senologie/Interdisziplinäres Brustzentrum</name>
      <address>
        <city>Essen</city>
        <state>NRW</state>
        <zip>45136</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sherko Kuemmel, Prof. Dr</last_name>
      <phone>+49-201-17433005</phone>
      <email>s.kuemmel@kliniken-essen-mitte.de</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Dorothea Schindowski</last_name>
      <phone>+49-201-17433005</phone>
      <email>d.schindowski@kliniken-essen-mitte.de</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sherko Kuemmel, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mattea Reinisch, Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brustzentrum Niederrhein, Johanniter Bethesda Krankenhaus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moenchengladbach</city>
        <state>NRW</state>
        <zip>41061</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Oleg Gluz, PD. Dr. med.</last_name>
      <email>oleg.gluz@wsg-online.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Iris Scheffen, Dr. med.</last_name>
      <email>iris.scheffen@wsg-online.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Oleg Gluz, PD Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mammazentrum HH am Krankenhaus Jerusalem</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>20357</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Felix Hilpert, Prof. Dr. med.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 40 44190671</phone>
      <email>hilpert@mammazentrum.eu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Silke Kassner</last_name>
      <phone>+49 40 44190557</phone>
      <email>kassner@mammazentrum.eu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Felix Hilpert, Prof. Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christian Schem, Prof. Dr. med.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 25, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>early breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>ADAPT</keyword>
  <keyword>endocrine therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>abemaciclib</keyword>
  <keyword>high risk</keyword>
  <keyword>HER2 negative</keyword>
  <keyword>HR positive</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

