<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04562493</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FMBSUREC/01122019/Hussein</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04562493</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparative Effect of Transforaminal Injection of Magnesium Sulphate Versus Ozone Therapy on Oxidative Stress Biomarkers in Lumbar Disc Related Radicular Pain</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparative Effect of Transforaminal Injection of Magnesium Sulphate Versus Ozone Therapy on Oxidative Stress Biomarkers in Lumbar Disc Related Radicular Pain</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Beni-Suef University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Beni-Suef University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic lumbar radicular (CLR) pain is a term used to describe neuropathic pain symptoms in&#xD;
      the distribution of a particular lumbar nerve root due to disc protrusion, spinal stenosis,&#xD;
      facet hypertrophy, or fibrosis after previous surgery. The pathophysiology of CLR pain&#xD;
      involves mechanical, inflammatory, and immunologic factors that affect the function of the&#xD;
      dorsal root ganglion (DRG).1Treatment methods include oral pain medications, physical&#xD;
      therapy, epidural steroid injection (ESI) and surgery, among others. Both ESI and surgery&#xD;
      appear to result in short-term pain relief relative to more conservative measures, yet&#xD;
      neither is clearly superior to observation at 1-year follow-up (2,3).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lumbar epidural steroid injection (LESI) was first suggested as a conservative treatment for&#xD;
      radicular pain in 1952 by Robecchi and Capra,4 and it has since become one of the most&#xD;
      commonly utilized conservative interventions for radiculopathy.5 Steroids are used to reduce&#xD;
      inflammation in the epidural space.6-10 LESI is performed via a transforaminal (TF), caudal&#xD;
      (C), or interlaminar (IL) approach in the lumbar spine; these approaches offer different&#xD;
      advantages and disadvantages, which may result in different outcomes.11-14 The TF approach is&#xD;
      perhaps the most favored because the injection site is adjacent to the nerve root, and only a&#xD;
      small volume of medication is required for injection.15 The C route is both the easiest and&#xD;
      the safest route and also seems to provide the most favorable analgesic effects. However,&#xD;
      this approach requires relatively large volumes of medication and is less specific to the&#xD;
      site of pathology.16 Previous studies have described the effectiveness of these methods in&#xD;
      the management of radiculopathy.17-22 Magnesium sulfate has not been familiar to&#xD;
      anesthesiologists until recently. It has drawn much attention in the field of&#xD;
      anesthesiology,23,24 resulting in numerous publications of clinical studies, 25 review&#xD;
      articles, and meta-analyses. 26 Based on its diverse roles in cellular functions, magnesium&#xD;
      sulfate has been suggested to prevent excitotoxicity by its neuroprotective effects.27&#xD;
      Magnesium can antagonize NMDA receptor channels by blocking calcium influx in a voltage-gated&#xD;
      manner. Intravenous administration of magnesium is efficacious in the management of various&#xD;
      conditions associated with neuropathic pain. 28,29 Collins and colleagues reported that 70&#xD;
      mg/kg magnesium sulphate infusions in 4 hours for 5 days reduced pain in patients with&#xD;
      complex regional pain syndrome. 30 Neuraxial administration of magnesium is an &quot;off-label&quot;&#xD;
      use However, animal studies 31,32 showed that intrathecally administered magnesium was free&#xD;
      of neurotoxicity, and recent studies have demonstrated the safety of magnesium administration&#xD;
      via the epidural route in humans33,34.35 Recently, ozone therapy has emerged as an&#xD;
      alternative or additional treatment option for patients with lumbar disc prolapse. Ozone (O 3&#xD;
      ) is an allotropic form of oxygen, primarily known for its ecological properties, industrial&#xD;
      application and therapeutic effects. Questions persist concerning its potential toxicity as&#xD;
      an oxidant agent versus its reported clinical efficacy. Several mechanisms of action have&#xD;
      been proposed to explain the efficacy of ozone therapy including analgesic, anti-inflammatory&#xD;
      and oxidant action. The O2-O3 gas mixture injected proximal to the root ganglion is thought&#xD;
      to normalize the levels of cytokines and prostaglandins, increase superoxide dismutase levels&#xD;
      minimize reactive oxidant species and improve local periganglionic circulation with eutropic&#xD;
      effect on the nerve root36,37 Much concern was directed towardsthe contribution of oxidative&#xD;
      stress to the pathophysiology of disc prolapse. More and more researchers devote themselves&#xD;
      to elucidating the association between oxidative stress and disc degeneration. Antioxidative&#xD;
      therapy is suggested as a promising therapeutic approach for preventing or retarding the&#xD;
      establishment and progression of disc degeneration. The effect of interventional pain&#xD;
      procedures for lumbar disc prolapse on oxidative stress biomarkers such as Glutathione and&#xD;
      superoxide dismutase (SOD) remains unknown. 38&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 5, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 5, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 5, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxidative stress biomarkers</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>(Glutathione (GSH) and superoxide dismutase (SOD))</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain relief</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Numeric Rating Scale</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Disability improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Numeric Rating Scale</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The Short Assessment of Patient Satisfaction (SAPS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Effect of Drug</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Magnesium sulphate group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Effect of transforaminal Magnesium sulphate on oxidative stress markers and radicular pain</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ozone Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Effect of transforaminal Ozone on oxidative stress markers and radicular pain</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Steroid group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Effect of transforaminal steroids on oxidative stress markers and radicular pain</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Transforaminal Epidural injection</intervention_name>
    <description>Transforaminal injection will be performed under fluoroscopy guidance. The patient will be placed in the prone position and draped in the sterile manner. A 22-gauge, 3.5-inch spinal needle will be used. The selected patients will receive transforaminal epidural injection of the drug</description>
    <arm_group_label>Magnesium sulphate group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Ozone Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Steroid group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients diagnosed as having symptomatic lumbar disc prolapse based on the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinical evidence of disc pulge in the form of disc related radicular pain of &gt;3&#xD;
             months duration, not responding to conservative treatment and interfering with daily&#xD;
             activities&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Radiological demonstration of posterolateral lumbar disc pulge by MRI lumbosacral&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Age range is between 30-80 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The following patients will be excluded from the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with spinal deformities&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with a previous history of spinal trauma&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with previous spinal surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with radiological evidence of any inflammatory or neoplastic lesion affecting&#xD;
             the spinal cord or vertebral column&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients with severe lumbar disc herniation causing lower limb weakness or sphincteric&#xD;
             troubles&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patient with pain rather than radicular neuropathic pain as Facet osteoarthritis,&#xD;
             Sacroiliitis, Hip osteoarthritis, Discogenic, Pyriformis syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients with contraindications to interventions (coagulopathy, sepsis, or allergy to&#xD;
             the used drugs)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients with contraindications for MRI examination (e.g., metallic implants such as&#xD;
             pacemakers, surgical aneurysm clips, or known metal fragments embedded in the body).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of G6PD deficiency in patients who are candidates to receive ozone therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Suspected spondylodiscitis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wael Fathy Hassan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Banī Suwayf</city>
        <zip>62511</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Wael Fathy, Lecturer</last_name>
      <phone>01006527133</phone>
      <email>drwaelfathy@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 3, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 18, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 18, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Beni-Suef University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Wael Fathy Hassan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Lecturer of Anaesthesia and pain</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

