<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04562454</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20200920-JS-2450</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04562454</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Exploratory Study on the Application of Continuous Glucose Monitoring System in the Measurement of Individual Glycemic Index After Eating Different Diets</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Exploratory Study on the Application of Continuous Glucose Monitoring System in the Measurement of Individual Glycemic Index After Eating Different Diets</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Peking Union Medical College Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Peking Union Medical College Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The glycemic index (GI) is used to evaluate the level of elevated blood sugar immediately&#xD;
      after carbohydrate intake and is a classified indicator of the glycemic potential of&#xD;
      carbohydrate-containing test foods relative to reference foods. At present, more and more&#xD;
      clinical studies have proved that a low-GI diet is beneficial to health, and can improve&#xD;
      blood glucose control, weight and blood lipid levels in patients with type 1 diabetes&#xD;
      mellitus (T1DM) and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). GI is currently widely used to provide&#xD;
      guidance on food choices for people with diabetes. However, there are great differences in&#xD;
      blood glucose response among different individuals after eating the same food, which is&#xD;
      related to a variety of factors，including individual gastrointestinal digestion and&#xD;
      absorption rate,islet function,insulin resistance and region. A large number of foreign&#xD;
      studies suggest that race affects the determination of GI, but different regions of our&#xD;
      country have different dietary culture and different ability to digest and absorb different&#xD;
      foods. Therefore, the traditional GI reference value does not necessarily fully reflect the&#xD;
      blood glucose response of diabetic patients after eating a food. In this study, continuous&#xD;
      blood glucose monitoring was carried out through CGM to monitor the overall fluctuation level&#xD;
      of blood glucose, the time to peak and the range of blood glucose fluctuation after eating&#xD;
      specific foods, and to obtain individual GI, after eating different diets to guide the future&#xD;
      diet.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this study, subjects with diabetes or impaired glucose tolerance were given continuous&#xD;
      glucose monitoring (CGM) for 3 consecutive days, given a standard meal containing 50g&#xD;
      carbohydrates and foods to be tested for GI. The purpose of this study was to explore the&#xD;
      fluctuation of blood glucose, the time and range of blood glucose peak after eating different&#xD;
      diets, and to guide the individual dietary choices of the subjects. And try to find the best&#xD;
      time and dose of hypoglycemic strategy for subjects during meals. At the same time, during&#xD;
      the follow-up period, we observed whether the subjects could achieve better blood glucose&#xD;
      control after adjusting their diet according to the GI of different foods. At the same time,&#xD;
      the GI results of the same food were compared between people with normal glucose metabolism&#xD;
      and those with abnormal glucose metabolism.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>fluctuation of blood glucose after eating different food</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>use the CGM to get the area under the curve of blood glucose of different food</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Normal group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Specific diet with CGM for 5days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>T1DM group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Specific diet with CGM for 5days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>T2DM group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Specific diet with CGM for 5days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>other type of diabetes group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Specific diet with CGM for 5days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Specific diet</intervention_name>
    <description>use a specific diet in different days with CGM to konw GI of different food in diabetes</description>
    <arm_group_label>Normal group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>T1DM group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>T2DM group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>other type of diabetes group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. the experimental group: patients with diabetes or impaired glucose tolerance diagnosed&#xD;
             clinically according to the World Health Organization's (WHO) diagnostic criteria of&#xD;
             diabetes in 1999; the control group: according to the participants of the experimental&#xD;
             group, matched the people with normal glucose metabolism in sex, age and region.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age: 18-80 years old; 3) patients or family members who can understand the research&#xD;
             plan and are willing to participate in this study and sign a written informed consent&#xD;
             form and questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. severe acute complications of diabetes (diabetic ketoacidosis, hyperglycemia and&#xD;
             hyperosmotic state, diabetic lactic acidosis) in the past 6 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. serious chronic complications of diabetes, such as peripheral vascular disease leading&#xD;
             to amputation or chronic foot ulcers, end-stage renal disease, etc., the researchers&#xD;
             do not think it is suitable to participate in this study.；&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. patients with two or more episodes of severe hypoglycemia in the past year (such as&#xD;
             disturbance of consciousness caused by hypoglycemia, coma, etc.), or severe&#xD;
             unconscious hypoglycemia;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. patients with severe impairment or circulatory disturbance of cardiac function (NYHA&#xD;
             grade III or above), liver function (ALT, AST or TBil above the upper limit of the&#xD;
             normal value), renal function (serum creatinine above the upper limit of the normal&#xD;
             value) or circulatory disturbance.；&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. patients with mental illness, confusion and inability to take care of themselves;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. patients with gastrointestinal diseases;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. patients or their families cannot understand the conditions and objectives of this&#xD;
             study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Weigang Zhao, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Peking Union Medical College Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Weigang Zhao, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+86 69151876</phone>
    <email>xiehezhaoweigang@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Shuoning Song</last_name>
    <phone>15117977900</phone>
    <email>937546635@qq.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 19, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

