<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04565184</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MARCAD/UYI/NPTN/12/16</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04565184</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness and Safety of Artesunate-Amodiaquine and Artemether-Lumefantrine for the Treatment of Malaria in Yaounde</brief_title>
  <official_title>Monitoring the Effectiveness and Safety of Artesunate-Amodiaquine and Artemether-Lumefantrine During the Treatment of Uncomplicated Plasmodium Falciparum Malaria Among Children in Yaounde, Cameroon</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Yaounde 1</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Malaria Research Capacity Development in West and Central Africa Consortium</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Developing Excellence in Leadership, Training and Science Africa Initiative</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Wellcome Trust United Kingdom</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United Kingdom Department for International Development</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Yaounde 1</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Artesunate-amodiaquine and artemether-lumfantrine are currently being used for the treatment&#xD;
      of uncomplicated Plasmodium falciparum in Cameroon. Globally, many studies have reported high&#xD;
      efficacy and safety of artemisinin-based combination therapies (ACTs) mostly under strict&#xD;
      supervision of drug intake and limited to children less than 5 years of age. Patients over 5&#xD;
      years of age are usually not involved in such studies. The main objective of this study is to&#xD;
      assess the genetic markers of antimalarial drug resistance and drug metabolism subsequent to&#xD;
      the efficacy and safety of artesunate-amodiaquine and artemether-lumefantrine during a 28-day&#xD;
      follow-up period in children with acute uncomplicated P. falciparum malaria in Yaounde,&#xD;
      Cameroon. A randomized, open-labelled, controlled clinical trial comparing&#xD;
      artesunate-amodiaquine (ASAQ) and artemether-lumefantrine (AL) will be carried out from 9th&#xD;
      May 2019 to 30th November 2020 at two secondary health centres (Cité Verte and Minkoameyos)&#xD;
      in Yaounde. The study participants shall include febrile patients aged 6 months to 10 years,&#xD;
      with confirmed uncomplicated P. falciparum infection. Eligible children for whom&#xD;
      parent/guardian informed consents are obtained will be randomized to receive either&#xD;
      artesunate-amodiaquine (group A) or artemether-lumefantrine (group B) in the ratio 1:1. A&#xD;
      minimum sample of 76 patients will be required for the study. With a 20 % increase to allow&#xD;
      loss to follow-up and withdrawals during the 28-day follow-up period, 92 patients will be&#xD;
      enrolled for each of the two study arms. The study will recruit a total of 184 patients. Drug&#xD;
      intake will be partially supervised only for the first dose and subsequent doses administered&#xD;
      unsupervised as pertains in routine practice in the field. Patients or their&#xD;
      parents/guardians will be advised on the time and mode of administration for the 3 days (D0,&#xD;
      D1 and D2) treatment unobserved at home. Follow-up visits will be performed on days 3, 7, 14,&#xD;
      21, and 28 to evaluate clinical and parasitological resolution of their malaria episode as&#xD;
      well as adverse events. Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) genotyping of merozoite surface&#xD;
      proteins 1 and 2 (msp-1, msp-2) as well as glutamate rich protein (GLURP) will be used to&#xD;
      differentiate between recrudescence and new infection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background: Artesunate-amodiaquine and artemether-lumfantrine are currently being used for&#xD;
      the treatment of uncomplicated Plasmodium falciparum in Cameroon. Globally, many studies have&#xD;
      reported high efficacy and safety of artemisinin-based combination therapies (ACTs) mostly&#xD;
      under strict supervision of drug intake and limited to children less than 5 years of age.&#xD;
      Patients over 5 years of age are usually not involved in such studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: To assess the genetic markers of antimalarial drug resistance and drug metabolism&#xD;
      subsequent to the efficacy and safety of artesunate-amodiaquine and artemether-lumefantrine&#xD;
      during a 28-day follow-up period in children with acute uncomplicated P. falciparum malaria&#xD;
      in Yaounde, Cameroon.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study sites: District Hospital Cité Verte and District Medical Centre Minkoa Meyos in&#xD;
      Yaounde, Cameroon. The two drugs, artesunate-amodiaquine and artemether-lumefantrine will be&#xD;
      tested in each site.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study period: 9th May 2019 to 30th November 2020.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: This surveillance study is a two-arm, open-label, randomized controlled&#xD;
      clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient population: Febrile patients aged 6 months to 10 years, with confirmed uncomplicated&#xD;
      P. falciparum infection. Eligible children for whom parent/guardian informed consents are&#xD;
      obtained will be randomized to receive either artesunate-amodiaquine (group A) or&#xD;
      artemether-lumefantrine (group B) in the ratio 1:1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size: A minimum sample of 76 patients will be required for the study. With a 20 %&#xD;
      increase to allow loss to follow-up and withdrawals during the 28-day follow-up period, 92&#xD;
      patients will be enrolled for each of the two study arms. The study will recruit a total of&#xD;
      184 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment (s) and follow-up: Drug intake will be partially supervised only for the first dose&#xD;
      and subsequent doses administered unsupervised as pertains in routine practice in the field.&#xD;
      Patients or their parents/guardians will be advised on the time and mode of administration&#xD;
      for the 3 days (D0, D1 and D2) treatment unobserved at home. Follow-up visits will be&#xD;
      performed on days 3, 7, 14, 21, and 28 to evaluate clinical and parasitological resolution of&#xD;
      their malaria episode as well as adverse events. Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) genotyping&#xD;
      of merozoite surface proteins 1 and 2 (msp-1, msp-2) as well as glutamate rich protein&#xD;
      (GLURP) will be used to differentiate between recrudescence and new infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Classification of treatment outcomes Classification of treatment outcomes will be done based&#xD;
      on the WHO 2009 guidelines: treatment failure (Early Treatment Failure-ETF, Late Clinical&#xD;
      failure-LCF and Late Parasitological Failure-LPF) and treatment success (Adequate Clinical&#xD;
      and Parasitological Response-ACPR).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 9, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 30, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Eligible children for whom parent/guardian informed consent are obtained will be randomized to receive either artesunate-amodiaquine (group A) or artemether-lumefantrine (group B) in the ratio 1:1.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with treatment success and adverse events following treatment with artesunate-modiaquine and artemether-lumefantrine during 28 days follow-up period in children with acute uncomplicated P. falciparum malaria in Yaounde</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Eligible children for whom parent/guardian informed consents are obtained will be randomized to receive either artesunate-amodiaquine (group A) or artemether-lumefantrine (group B) and follow-up will be done for a duration of 28 days.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients with early treatment failure, late clinical failure, late parasitological failure or an adequate clinical and parasitological response as indicators of efficacy according to the WHO 2009 guidelines</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Eligible children for whom parent/guardian informed consents are obtained will be randomized to receive either artesunate-amodiaquine (group A) or artemether-lumefantrine (group B) and follow-up will be done for a duration of 28 days. Recrudescence will be distinguished from re-infection by polymerase chain reaction (PCR) analysis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events as assessed by CTCAE v4.0</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Eligible children for whom parent/guardian informed consents are obtained will be randomized to receive either artesunate-amodiaquine (group A) or artemether-lumefantrine (group B) and follow-up will be done for a duration of 28 days.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of children with single nucleotide polymorphisms of P. falciparum genes responsible for AS-AQ and AL resistance</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Pre-treatment and recrudescence/reinfection samples during follow-up shall be used to characterize the molecular markers of Plasmodium falciparum chloroquine resistant transporter(Pfcrt), Plasmodium falciparum multi-drug resistant 1 (Pfmdr1), and Plasmodium falciparum K13 (Pfk13) propellar domain conferring resistance to artemisinins or partner drugs.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of children haboring single nucleotide polymorphisms in key genes involved in the metabolism of AS-AQ and AL</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Pre-treatment samples shall be used to characterize the human pharmacogenomic biomarkers (N-acetyl transferase 2-NAT2 and cytochrome P450: CYP2A6, CYP2B6, CYP2C8, CYP2C9, CYP2C19, CYP3A4, and CYP3A5)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">242</enrollment>
  <condition>Malaria,Falciparum</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Artesunate-amodiaquine (Arm A)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Artesunate-amodiaquine (Coarsucam®: Sanofi-Aventis, France) is co-packaged as artesunate 50 mg and amodiaquine hydrochloride USP equivalent to amodiaquine base of 153.1 mg. Each child shall be given one, two or three tablets depending on the weight.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Artemether-lumefantrine (Arm B)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Artemether-lumefantrine (Coartem®: Novartis, Switzerland) is formulated as tablets and will be provided in blister packs. Each tablet contains 20 mg artemether and 120 mg lumefantrine. Every pack has a picture showing how the drug should be given and contains two blisters for each day with one, two or three tablets depending on the weight of the child.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Artesunate-amodiaquine combination</intervention_name>
    <description>Artesunate-amodiaquine (Coarsucam®: Sanofi-Aventis, France) is co-packaged as artesunate 50 mg and amodiaquine hydrochloride USP equivalent to amodiaquine base of 153.1 mg. Each child shall be given one, two or three tablets depending on the weight.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Artesunate-amodiaquine (Arm A)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Coarsucam</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Artemether, Lumefantrine Drug Combination</intervention_name>
    <description>Artemether-lumefantrine (Coartem®: Novartis, Switzerland) is formulated as tablets and will be provided in blister packs. Each tablet contains 20 mg artemether and 120 mg lumefantrine. Every pack has a picture showing how the drug should be given and contains two blisters for each day with one, two or three tablets depending on the weight of the child</description>
    <arm_group_label>Artemether-lumefantrine (Arm B)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Coartem®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children of either gender, aged 6 months to 120 months will be recruited.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute uncomplicated P. falciparum malaria confirmed by microscopy using Giemsa-stained&#xD;
             thick film with an asexual parasite density within the range 1000 to 200000&#xD;
             parasites/μl.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presenting with fever (axillary temperature ≥ 37.5oC) or having a history of fever in&#xD;
             the preceding 24 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to ingest tablets orally (either suspended in water or uncrushed with food).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to participate in the study with written informed consent from&#xD;
             parent/guardian.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to attend the clinic on stipulated regular follow-up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mixed with another Plasmodium species detected by microscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children who are currently suffering or had the following within the last 2 months:&#xD;
             tuberculosis, HIV, schistosomiasis, diabetes mellitus, cardiovascular disease, gout,&#xD;
             rheumatoid arthritis, underlying chronic hepatic or renal disease, hypoglycaemia,&#xD;
             jaundice, respiratory distress, and other inflammatory related diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signs/symptoms indicating severe/complicated malaria&quot; according to WHO criteria (WHO&#xD;
             definition) such as:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Not able to drink or breast feed. Persistent vomiting (&gt;2 episodes within previous 24&#xD;
        hours). Convulsions (&gt;1 episode within previous 24 hours). Lethargic/unconscious. Severe&#xD;
        anaemia (haemoglobin &lt; 5 g/dl).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious gastrointestinal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of severe malnutrition defined as a child aged between 6-60 months whose&#xD;
             weight-for-high is below -3 z-score (W/H &lt; 70%) or has symmetrical edema involving at&#xD;
             least the feet or has a mid-upper arm circumference &lt; 115 mm).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Regular medication, which may interfere with anti-malarial pharmacokinetics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hypersensitivity reactions or contraindications to any of the medicine (s)&#xD;
             being tested or used as alternative treatment (s).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who have taken part in anti-malarial efficacy and safety studies in the&#xD;
             last 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have taken anti-malarial drugs in the last one month.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>120 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wilfred Fon Mbacham, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Biotechnology Centre, University of Yaounde I</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>District Medical Center Minkoa Meyos</name>
      <address>
        <city>Yaoundé</city>
        <state>Center</state>
        <zip>+237</zip>
        <country>Cameroon</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Cameroon</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 25, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Yaounde 1</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Professor Wilfred Fon Mbacham</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Malaria</keyword>
  <keyword>Plasmodium falciparum</keyword>
  <keyword>Artesunate-amodiaquine</keyword>
  <keyword>Artemether-lumefantrine</keyword>
  <keyword>Effectiveness</keyword>
  <keyword>Safety</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Malaria, Falciparum</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Artesunate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lumefantrine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Artemether</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Amodiaquine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Artemether, Lumefantrine Drug Combination</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Amodiaquine, artesunate drug combination</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Research findings will be communicated with the scientific community and policymakers. This will be done through public engagements and publications in peer-review journals.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>30th November 2020 for at least 10 years</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Not available for now</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

