<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04561271</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RBHP 2020 GUASTELLA</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-A01880-39</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04561271</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Feasability of Foot Reflexology to Alleviate Anxiety in Palliative Care Unit (RPASP)</brief_title>
  <acronym>RPASP</acronym>
  <official_title>Feasability of Foot Reflexology to Alleviate Anxiety in Palliative Care Unit : a Pilot Randomised Double Blind Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Clermont-Ferrand</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Clermont-Ferrand</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary purpose of the study is to know if foot reflexology can be accepted by patients&#xD;
      hospitalized in palliative unit care (assessed by the number of patient who accept to&#xD;
      participate), and if it is feasible (assessed by the realization of one session in normal&#xD;
      condition : duration of 15-20 min, in supine position/seated or half-seated position).The&#xD;
      investigators make the hypothesis that patients will accept to receive foot reflexology, and&#xD;
      maybe feel less anxious after one session.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The patients will receive an informative content about the study and will have 24 hours of&#xD;
      reflexion. If they accept to participate to the study, they will be randomised in one of the&#xD;
      two groups : foot reflexology or &quot;toucher massage&quot; (for those randomised in the &quot;toucher&#xD;
      massage&quot; group, a session of foot reflexology will be proposed in a second time). The&#xD;
      investigators will assess the level of anxiety, the quality of the sleep and the pain using&#xD;
      the ESAS scale, before and after the session. 24 hours after the session, they will be&#xD;
      interviewed about what they felt with the session. The investigators will also have a look on&#xD;
      the anxiolytic and antagic medication they consume before and after the session.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>2 arms, one called &quot;foot reflexology&quot; who receive one session, the second called &quot;toucher massage&quot;.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>acceptability of foot reflexology in palliative care unit</measure>
    <time_frame>day 0</time_frame>
    <description>the acceptability will be assessed by the number of patient who accept to participate to the study</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>feasibility of foot reflexology in palliative care unit</measure>
    <time_frame>day 0</time_frame>
    <description>The feasibility will be assessed by the conditions of realization of one session : for the study, the normal conditions will be : duration (15-20 min) and possibility for the patient to remain in the good position (supine position/seated or half-seated position).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effects of foot reflexology on anxiety</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the session (day 0) and 24 hours after</time_frame>
    <description>investigator will assess the anxiety, using the Edmonton Symptom Assessment System (ESAS scale), before and after the session. This scale permits the patient to choose a number from 0 to 10, 0 corresponding to the lowest level of anxiety, and 10 corresponding to the highest level of anxiety</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effects of foot reflexology on pain</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the session (day 0) and 24 hours after</time_frame>
    <description>investigators will assess the pain using the Edmonton Symptom Assessment System (ESAS scale), before and after the session. This scale permits the patient to choose a number from 0 to 10, 0 corresponding to the lowest level of pain, and 10 corresponding to the highest level of pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effects of foot reflexology on sleep quality</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the session (day 0) and 24 hours after</time_frame>
    <description>investigators will assess the sleep quality using the Edmonton Symptom Assessment System (ESAS scale), before and after the session. This scale permits the patient to choose a number from 0 to 10, 0 corresponding to the lowest level of tiredness, and 10 corresponding to the highest level of tiredness.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effects of foot reflexology on anxiolytic intake</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the session (day 0) and 24 hours after</time_frame>
    <description>investigators will write down the anxiolytic intake before the session, and until 24 hours after the session, using redcap software. There will be a &quot;yes/no&quot; question for &quot;benzodiazepine&quot; and &quot;neuroleptic&quot;. If &quot;yes&quot; is chosen, there will be a free text box to be more specific</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effects of foot reflexology on pain killers intake</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the session (day 0) and 24 hours after</time_frame>
    <description>investigators will write down the pain killer intake before the session, and until 24 hours after the session, using redcap software. There will be a &quot;yes/no&quot; question for &quot;paracetamol&quot;, &quot;weak opioids&quot;, &quot;strong opioids&quot; and &quot;co-analgesics&quot;. If &quot;yes&quot; is chosen, there will be a free text box to be more specific.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>patients' experience</measure>
    <time_frame>day 1</time_frame>
    <description>24 hours after the session, investigators will collect patients' experience and feeling about the session they undergone. Key words and verbatims will be reported on a free text box with redcap</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">43</enrollment>
  <condition>End Stage Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>foot reflexology</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients will receive one session of foot reflexology with a nurse who received a specific formation. The session lasts 15 to 20 minutes, patients seated, half seated or in supine position. The technique consists in stimulating reflex zones of foot, each zone corresponding to a specific organ. Almond oil will be used. The session is accompanied by relaxing music</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>toucher massage</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients will receive one session of toucher massage with a nurse (this technique is taught during the formation of every nurse in palliative care units). The session lasts 15 to 20 minutes, patients seated, half seated or in supine position. It consists in a simple massage and effleurage, with fluid and progressive movements. Almond oil will be used. The session is accompanied by relaxing music.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>foot reflexology</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive one session of foot reflexology with a nurse who received a specific formation. The session lasts 15 to 20 minutes, patients seated, half seated or in supine position. A neutral oil will be used. The technique associates specific movements of foot reflexology. The session is accompanied by relaxing music.</description>
    <arm_group_label>foot reflexology</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>toucher massage</intervention_name>
    <description>one session of toucher massage with a nurse (this technique is taught during the formation of every nurse in palliative care units). The session lasts 15 to 20 minutes, patients seated, half seated or in supine position. It consists in a simple massage and effleurage, with fluid and progressive movements. Almond oil will be used. The session is accompanied by relaxing music.</description>
    <arm_group_label>toucher massage</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult able to give consent, man or woman, hospitalized in palliative care unit, with&#xD;
             vigilance criteria from +1 to -3 on the Richmond scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Affiliated to Social Security&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Painfull bone metastasis on the feet&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  foot amputation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  foot bedsore&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  peripheral distal neuropathy, trouble of foot sensibility&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  agonic or pre agonic state&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under juridical protection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refusal to participate to the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Virginie Guastella</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Clermont-Ferrand</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lise LACLAUTRE</last_name>
    <phone>+33473754963</phone>
    <email>promo_interne_drci@chu-clermontferrand.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU de Clermont-Ferrand</name>
      <address>
        <city>Clermont-Ferrand</city>
        <zip>63000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lise Laclautre</last_name>
      <phone>+33473754963</phone>
      <email>promo_interne_drci@chu-clermontferrand.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Viginie Guastella</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 8, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 17, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 23, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 28, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 28, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 29, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Palliative care</keyword>
  <keyword>Foot reflexology</keyword>
  <keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>Acceptability</keyword>
  <keyword>Feasability</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

