<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04562987</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>736-19</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1U54GM115458</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04562987</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Patterns of Activity and Cognition During Treatment (PACT) Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>PACT</acronym>
  <official_title>The Patterns of Activity and Cognition During Treatment (PACT) Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Nebraska</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of General Medical Sciences (NIGMS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Wake Forest University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Nebraska</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aim 1: This pilot study tests the feasibility and acceptability of a mobile app-based&#xD;
      behavioral intervention in 40 women receiving chemotherapy for breast cancer. Participants&#xD;
      will be randomized to receive app components following a 2x2 factorial design. Feasibility&#xD;
      will be assessed by participant recruitment yield, intervention adherence, contamination, and&#xD;
      retention. Acceptability will be assessed by participant ratings and perceptions of&#xD;
      intervention components as measured at post-intervention (1 month post-chemotherapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2: Examine preliminary efficacy of the intervention components (i.e., Move, Exercise,&#xD;
      Core) delivered alone (i.e., main effects) and in combination (i.e., interaction effects;&#xD;
      Move+Exercise) on executive function and working memory at post-intervention. These data will&#xD;
      inform the sample size needed for a fully-powered randomized controlled trial. Aim 2 outcomes&#xD;
      will be measured at pre-intervention (before the first or second chemotherapy cycle) and&#xD;
      post-intervention, and include accelerometry and neurocognitive testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory Aim: Explore the effects of the intervention components on correlates of&#xD;
      cancer-associated cognitive decline. Exploratory outcomes will be measured at pre- and&#xD;
      post-intervention and include patient-reported outcomes, specifically cancer-related fatigue.&#xD;
      Participants will also completed brief ecological momentary assessments (EMAs) their mobile&#xD;
      phones across four 14-day measurement bursts at pre-intervention, mid-chemotherapy, and 1&#xD;
      month post-chemotherapy to further explore associations among behavioral patterns, cognition,&#xD;
      and correlates.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cancer-related cognitive impairment (CRCI) is a research priority due to its rising&#xD;
      prevalence and dramatic impacts on survivors' quality of life and health long-term. Strong&#xD;
      evidence supports the efficacy of physical activity (PA) for improving cognitive function and&#xD;
      key CRCI correlates. The aim of the proposed study is to pilot test an innovative, mHealth&#xD;
      intervention designed to ameliorate CRCI in women receiving chemotherapy for breast cancer.&#xD;
      This study will employ an efficient 2x2 factorial design to compare PA prescriptions&#xD;
      targeting frequent PA of any intensity and reduced daily sitting (Move); aerobic exercise&#xD;
      (consistent with PA guidelines for cancer survivors; Exercise); both (Move+Exercise); or none&#xD;
      (Core). The main and interactive effects of these intervention components on CRCI and its&#xD;
      underlying mechanisms will be tested across the breast cancer trajectory. Aim 1: This pilot&#xD;
      study aims to test the feasibility and acceptability of the mHealth intervention in 40 women&#xD;
      receiving chemotherapy for breast cancer. Feasibility will be assessed by participant&#xD;
      recruitment yield, intervention adherence, contamination, and retention. Acceptability will&#xD;
      be assessed by participant ratings and perceptions of intervention components as measured at&#xD;
      a baseline orientation and at post-intervention (1 month post-chemotherapy). Aim 2: Examine&#xD;
      preliminary efficacy of the intervention components (i.e., Move, Exercise, Core) delivered&#xD;
      alone (i.e., main effects) and in combination (i.e., interaction effects) on executive&#xD;
      function and working memory at post-intervention. These data will inform the sample size&#xD;
      needed for a fully-powered randomized controlled trial. Aim 2 outcomes will be measured at&#xD;
      pre-intervention (before the first or second chemotherapy cycle) and post-intervention, and&#xD;
      include accelerometry and neurocognitive testing. Exploratory Aim: Explore the effects of the&#xD;
      intervention components on CRCI correlates. Exploratory outcomes will be measured at pre- and&#xD;
      post-intervention and include patient-reported outcomes (e.g., fatigue, depressive symptoms).&#xD;
      Participants will also complete brief ecological momentary assessments (EMAs) on their mobile&#xD;
      phones across four 14-day measurement bursts to further explore associations among behavioral&#xD;
      patterns, cognition, and CRCI correlates. To test the specific aims, women diagnosed with&#xD;
      breast cancer and scheduled to receive 3-6 months of chemotherapy (N=40) will be randomized&#xD;
      to receive select mHealth intervention components, including Core (attentional control),&#xD;
      Move, Exercise, or Move+Exercise (n=10 each condition). Data will be analyzed using&#xD;
      descriptive statistics and axial coding (Aim 1); analysis of covariance and standard mean&#xD;
      difference (Aim 2 and Exploratory); and hierarchical linear modeling (Exploratory). Findings&#xD;
      will provide the necessary pilot data to support a grant application for a fully-powered&#xD;
      trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>intervention attendance</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month post-chemotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>completion of telecoaching sessions</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Participant satisfaction: survey</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month post-chemotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>usability survey</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>recruitment yield</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>number of women who enroll compared to the number of contacts of eligible women required to obtain target sample size</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>retention</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month post-chemotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of participants providing post-intervention data</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>acceptability of intervention: in-depth interview</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month post-chemotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>in-depth interview to gather participant perceptions on the acceptability and usefulness of the mobile app features</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Stroop task performance</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month post-chemotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>Interference score on Stroop task</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Task-Switch task performance</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month post-chemotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>Reaction time on Task-Switch</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Trails task performance</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month post-chemotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>Completion time of Trails</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in N-Back task performance</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month post-chemotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>Correct responses on N-back</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Spatial Working Memory task performance</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month post-chemotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>Correct responses on Spatial Working Memory task</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Auditory Verbal Learning Task (AVLT) performance</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month post-chemotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>Total numbered recalled on AVLT</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in objective physical activity behavior</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month post-chemotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>Objective activity behavior (average minutes of physical activity per day) will be measured using actigraphy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cancer-related Fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month post-chemotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>The Functional Assessment in Chronic Illness Therapy (FACIT) - Fatigue Scale will be used to measure cancer-related fatigue. Scores range from 0-52, with higher scores indicating less cancer-related fatigue.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Momentary symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days 4 times per day at each of the following time points: baseline, mid-intervention (2-3 months from baseline), 1 month post-chemotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>A brief ecological momentary assessment prompted to participants' smartphones will be used to measure momentary symptoms, including anxiety, stress, fatigue, focus, pain, and nausea.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Neoplasms</condition>
  <condition>Breast Cancer Female</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Core</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>All participants will receive the Core component, which includes access to weekly telecoaching, weekly emails from the interventionist, a smartphone app, and a Fitbit monitor. Telecoaching will include discussion of general cancer-related and wellness topics, and the smartphone app will have basic activity monitoring features.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Move</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Telecoaching calls for Move participants will be based in social cognitive theory to encourage behavior adoption and goal setting focused on reducing prolonged sitting. Smartphone app features include activity monitoring that visualizes progress toward Move-based goals and goal achievement badges specific to Move.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Exercise</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Telecoaching calls for Exercise participants will be based in social cognitive theory to encourage behavior adoption and goal setting focused on engaging in 30 minutes of moderate-intensity physical activity per day (in 10+ minute bouts). Smartphone app features include activity monitoring that visualizes progress toward Exercise-based goals and goal achievement badges specific to Exercise.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Combo (Move+Exercise)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Includes telecoaching that encourages behavior adoption and goal setting focused on reducing prolonged sitting and engaging in 30+ minutes of physical activity per day. Participants are able to visualize progress toward Move and Exercise goals and are eligible to receive achievement badges for Move and Exercise.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Physical Activity</intervention_name>
    <description>Mobile app intervention delivered during chemotherapy for breast cancer that combines goal setting, behavioral monitoring, and goal achievement badges with telecoaching to achieve physical activity prescriptions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Combo (Move+Exercise)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Exercise</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Move</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Attentional Control</intervention_name>
    <description>Mobile app intervention delivered during chemotherapy for breast cancer that includes telecoaching on general and cancer-related health topics and basic physical activity monitoring.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Core</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 21 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  First, primary diagnosis of Stage I-III breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Scheduled to receive chemotherapy for 3-6 months. While evidence suggests declines in&#xD;
             cognition and brain health due to cancer may be evident both in women who receive and&#xD;
             who do not receive chemotherapy, those receiving chemotherapy consistently experience&#xD;
             the greatest changes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received no more than one cycle of chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agree to be randomized to one of the intervention components&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Owns an Android or iPhone smartphone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fitbit specific criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Compatible mobile device, laptop computer, or desktop computer&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Willingness to continuously wear the Fitbit device during waking hours for the&#xD;
                  duration of the study period. Individuals not willing to wear the Fitbit during&#xD;
                  sleep will be eligible to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Willingness and ability to charge the Fitbit device at home every 3-4 days and&#xD;
                  synchronize the Fitbit device multiple times daily.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English reading and speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receive physician's clearance to participate in an exercise program&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provide written informed consent to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No history or evidence of dementia (score &gt;21 on the Modified Telephone Interview for&#xD;
             Cognitive Status [TICS-M].73&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males. Breast cancer is often classified specifically as female breast cancer, as 99%&#xD;
             of cases occur in women. Our small sample size does not statistically justify the&#xD;
             inclusion of males in this study. As such, only female subjects will be included in&#xD;
             this research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is scheduled to receive &lt;3 months or &gt;6 months of chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received 2+ cycles of chemotherapy at enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stage 0 breast cancer diagnosis or metastatic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Second cancer diagnosis (excluding non-invasive skin cancers; including breast cancer&#xD;
             recurrence)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is not cleared to participate in exercise by a physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to complete baseline behavioral, neurocognitive, and patient-reported&#xD;
             assessments (accelerometry, cognitive tasks, questionnaires)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to be randomized&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to continuously wear and regularly sync/charge the Fitbit device during the&#xD;
             study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to read and speak in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to provide written informed consent to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive impairment (score &lt;21 on the TICS-M) prior to baseline assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of stroke, transient ischemic attack, other neurological disorders, or brain&#xD;
             surgery involving tissue removal&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Diane K Ehlers, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Nebraska</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nicholas Foggia, MS</last_name>
    <phone>4025599468</phone>
    <email>nicholas.foggia@unmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Nebraska Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Omaha</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68198-8440</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nicholas Foggia</last_name>
      <email>nicholas.foggia@unmc.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Nebraska</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Diane Ehlers</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>physical activity</keyword>
  <keyword>cognition</keyword>
  <keyword>chemotherapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified individual participant data will be available to other researchers upon request and approval by the PI.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>After primary manuscripts have been published.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>To be determined upon research request.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

