<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04569240</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-698</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04569240</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Accuracy of the Dexcom G6 Continuous Glucose Monitoring System Following Cardiac Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Accuracy of the Dexcom G6 Continuous Glucose Monitoring System Following Cardiac Surgery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The Cleveland Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>DexCom, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The Cleveland Clinic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective longitudinal study to study the agreement between a novel continuous&#xD;
      glucose monitoring system (CGMS) versus current blood glucose monitoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects in this study will have their blood glucose measured regularly every 1-3 hours with&#xD;
      current methods in the cardiovascular intensive care unit (CVICU), and by point of care&#xD;
      glucose using the Accuchek Inform II on the regular floors, and the CGMS at the same time&#xD;
      will be captured. Subjects will have measurements taken throughout their stay in the CVICU&#xD;
      and on the regular floors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Maintaining tight blood glucose control following surgery is imperative to reducing&#xD;
      infections and neurologic dysfunction. This requires frequent blood sampling while in the&#xD;
      intensive care unit, leading to increased waste of blood and utilizing time and resources to&#xD;
      collect samples and wait for results. Additionally, when on the regular floors, frequent&#xD;
      point of care fingersticks for glucose levels are needed for therapeutic intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Continuous glucose monitoring systems (CGMS) are now available for ambulatory use in patients&#xD;
      with diabetes. The potential of using such a system in the hospital, including during the&#xD;
      postoperative critical care setting and upon transfer to the regular floor, may reduce&#xD;
      personnel burden, produce rapid results, and decrease blood waste. However, these systems&#xD;
      have not yet been validated for hospital use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a prospective longitudinal study to study the agreement between a novel continuous&#xD;
      glucose monitoring system (CGMS) versus current blood glucose monitoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects in this study will have their blood glucose measured regularly every 1-3 hours with&#xD;
      current methods in the CVICU, and by point of care glucose using the Accuchek Inform II on&#xD;
      the regular floors, and the CGMS at the same time will be captured. Subjects will have&#xD;
      measurements taken throughout their stay in the CVICU and on the regular floors. Agreement&#xD;
      and correlation between systems will be calculated, and error will be classified using the&#xD;
      Surveillance Error grid. The proportion of errors of at least moderate risk will be&#xD;
      calculated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject characteristics including demographics, comorbidities and baseline disease severity&#xD;
      will be summarized using means and standard deviations for continuous measures and&#xD;
      frequencies and percentages for categorical factors. To evaluate agreement between methods,&#xD;
      concordance correlation coefficients will be calculated, using the method that adjusts for&#xD;
      repeated measures as described by King and implemented in software by Carrasco. Analysis will&#xD;
      be performed overall, and then stratifying by type of current measure, if the type of&#xD;
      measurement varies across settings. Correlations will be calculated using the methods&#xD;
      described by Bland and Altman and implemented by Bakdash and Marusich. Differences will also&#xD;
      be evaluated for errors according to the Surveillance Error Grid. Rates of moderate or more&#xD;
      severe errors will be calculated. For each measure above, 95% confidence intervals will be&#xD;
      calculated, accounting for the clustering within subject.. Analyses will be performed using&#xD;
      SAS software (version 9.4; Cary, NC) and R software (version 3.5; Vienna Austria).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Glucose readings obtained from the CGMS will be compared with&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. blood glucose from the arterial blood gas (ABG) or peripheral/central venous catheter if&#xD;
           arterial catheter not in use (standard of care in CVICU) while patients are in the CVICU&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. fingerstick point of care (POC) glucose when patients are on the regular floors&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Glucose readings from CGM versus from blood</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Glucose readings in mg/dL from the Dexcom CGMS will be compared with blood glucose in mg/dL from the arterial blood gas (ABG) or peripheral/central venous catheter</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Glucose readings from CGM versus point of care glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Glucose readings in mg/dL from the Dexcom CGMS will be compared with fingerstick point of care glucose levels in mg/dL</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cost comparison of Dexcom CGMS versus blood glucose testing</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>The cost of the Dexcom CGMS device including the sensor and transmitter will be compared to the cost of measuring glucose from arterial blood gas</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cost comparison of Dexcom CGMS versus fingerstick point of care glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>The cost in US$ of the Dexcom CGMS device including the sensor and transmitter will be compared to the cost in US$ of measuring glucose from point of care fingerstick testing (Accuchek Inform II meter, test strips, and lancets)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Blood volume waste by arterial blood gas</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Blood sample amounts in milliliters required for measurement of glucose by arterial blood gas</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Blood volume waste by fingerstick</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Blood sample amounts in milliliters required for measurement of glucose by fingerstick</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Surgery--Complications</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dexcom G6 continuous glucose monitor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients will have a Dexcom G6 continuous glucose monitor placed pre-operatively. The glucose readings will be collected for 10 days or upon discharge from the ICU and data will be compared with arterial blood glucose readings or venous Accu-Check Inform II glucose readings</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexcom G6 continuous glucose monitor</intervention_name>
    <description>Dexcom G6 continuous glucose monitor will be applied to the upper outer arm before cardiovascular surgery. Data will be collected for 10 days or upon discharge from the ICU.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dexcom G6 continuous glucose monitor</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 years and above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned cardiovascular surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned admission to Cleveland Clinic Main Campus J5 or J6 or Q5 cardiovascular ICU&#xD;
             (CVICU) post-operatively&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With or without known diabetes; if with known diagnosis of diabetes, diabetes can be&#xD;
             type 1, type 2, or secondary&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to the material of the CGMS or the adhesive to be used&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Skin conditions precluding the use of the CGMS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other conditions that investigators deem inappropriate for the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>M. Cecilia Lansang, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The Cleveland Clinic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kimberly Jenkins</last_name>
    <phone>216-316-2889</phone>
    <email>jenkink@ccf.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cleveland Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kimberly Jenkins</last_name>
      <phone>216-316-2889</phone>
      <email>jenkink@ccf.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>M. Cecilia Lansang, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Steven Insler, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>King TS, Chinchilli VM, Carrasco JL. A repeated measures concordance correlation coefficient. Stat Med. 2007 Jul 20;26(16):3095-113.</citation>
    <PMID>17216594</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carrasco JL, Phillips BR, Puig-Martinez J, King TS, Chinchilli VM. Estimation of the concordance correlation coefficient for repeated measures using SAS and R. Comput Methods Programs Biomed. 2013 Mar;109(3):293-304. doi: 10.1016/j.cmpb.2012.09.002. Epub 2012 Sep 29.</citation>
    <PMID>23031487</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bland JM, Altman DG. Calculating correlation coefficients with repeated observations: Part 1--Correlation within subjects. BMJ. 1995 Feb 18;310(6977):446.</citation>
    <PMID>7873953</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bakdash JZ, Marusich LR. Repeated Measures Correlation. Front Psychol. 2017 Apr 7;8:456. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00456. eCollection 2017. Erratum in: Front Psychol. 2019 May 28;10:1201.</citation>
    <PMID>28439244</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Klonoff DC, Lias C, Vigersky R, Clarke W, Parkes JL, Sacks DB, Kirkman MS, Kovatchev B; Error Grid Panel. The surveillance error grid. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2014 Jul;8(4):658-72. doi: 10.1177/1932296814539589. Epub 2014 Jun 13.</citation>
    <PMID>25562886</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 8, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The Cleveland Clinic</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>M. Cecilia Lansang, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Staff Physician, Director - Endocrinology Main Campus</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

