<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04568538</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AkdenizUnv</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04568538</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of a Shaken Baby Syndrome Prevention Program</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of a Shaken Baby Syndrome Prevention Program on Turkish Mothers' Awareness and Knowledge: A Randomized Controlled Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Akdeniz University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Akdeniz University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Objective: This randomized controlled study aims to examine whether the education program&#xD;
      prepared to prevent shaken baby syndrome has an effect on mothers' knowledge and attitudes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method: Simple randomization will be used to evaluate the intervention and control groups.&#xD;
      The study will be carried out with 90 mothers babies of 2-4 months, who applied to Akdeniz&#xD;
      University Hospital Healthy Child Outpatient Clinic (intervention group: 45, control group:&#xD;
      45). After the pre-test, the mothers in the intervention group will be trained and a booklet&#xD;
      will be given. Tele-consultancy service will be provided to mothers during the 2-month&#xD;
      follow-up period. After 2 months of follow-up, a post-test will be applied to the mothers in&#xD;
      the intervention group. The mothers in the control group will not be intervened after the&#xD;
      pretest is applied. A post test will be applied 2 months after the pre-test. After the&#xD;
      post-test, the mothers in the control group will be trained and a booklet will be given.&#xD;
      Ethics committee approval and institutional permission were obtained for the study. Verbal&#xD;
      and written consent will be obtained from the mothers during the data collection phase.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Method: The study will be conducted with 90 mothers with 2-4 months old babies who applied to&#xD;
      Akdeniz University Hospital Healthy Children Polyclinic (intervention group: 45, control&#xD;
      group: 45). Personal Information Form, Shaken baby syndrome assessment survey will be used to&#xD;
      collect data. Simple randomization will be used to evaluate the intervention and control&#xD;
      groups. In order to identify mothers in intervention groups, sealed-envelope randomization&#xD;
      method will used. Mothers and statistician group will be unaware of the evaluation. The&#xD;
      researcher will not be blind because of the role he plays in the research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following the pretest, the intervention group will be trained to prevent shaken baby&#xD;
      syndrome. Expert opinion was obtained from 10 expert faculty members for the content of the&#xD;
      training. After the training, the booklet prepared in line with expert opinions will be given&#xD;
      to the mother in the intervention group. The booklet will remain with the mother.&#xD;
      Tele-consultancy will be given to the mother for 2 months after the pre-test. The control&#xD;
      group will also be tested beforehand and will not be intervened afterwards. 2 months after&#xD;
      the pre-test, a post-test will be applied to the control group and training will be given to&#xD;
      prevent shaken baby syndrome. A training booklet will be given to the mothers in the control&#xD;
      group after the final test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis will be done using SPSS 23.0 and statistical significance will be set at&#xD;
      p &lt;0.05.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Support will be received in the analysis phase of the Statistical Information Unit of Akdeniz&#xD;
      University.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 20, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 20, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 20, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Single-blind randomized controlled study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>The statistician will be blind in evaluating the results. The intervention and control group will be defined as group 1 and group 2 for statistical analysis. Scales will be evaluated by the researcher who cannot be blinded due to the nature of the study.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Shaken baby syndrome knowledge level</measure>
    <time_frame>2-4 months</time_frame>
    <description>The increase in the mother's level of knowledge about shaken baby syndrome is the outcome measure.This increase will be measured with &quot;Shaken baby syndrome assessment survey&quot;. This form was developed by researchers. After the forms were developed, expert opinions were received from 10 academic members who are experts in the field of child health. It will be evaluated whether there is a statistically significant increase in the post-test data. Statistical analysis will be done using SPSS 23.0 and statistical significance will be set at p &lt;0.05. Support will be received in the analysis phase of the Statistical Information Unit of Akdeniz University.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">77</enrollment>
  <condition>Shaken Baby Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Mothers</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>İntervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Randomization with a sealed envelope will be applied to mothers who have 2-4 months old babies who apply to Akdeniz University Hospital Pediatric Outpatient Clinic for health control and who accept the study. A pre-test application will be made in the intervention group. The Researcher will fill in the Personal Information Form and the Shaken baby syndrome assessment survey at this stage.&#xD;
The training prepared to prevent shaken baby syndrome, which was prepared immediately after the end of the pre-test application, will be given to the mothers in the intervention group. The training will be given with mothers using one-to-one face-to-face interview method. Necessary equipment will be provided for training. At the end of the training, the questions of the mothers will be answered and a booklet prepared to prevent shaken baby syndrome will be given and tele-consultancy will be provided for 2 months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>No application will be made to the mothers in the control group after the pre-test application. After 2 months, the final test application will be made. After the last test, the mothers in the control group will be given a training and a booklet prepared to prevent shaken baby syndrome.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Training program</intervention_name>
    <description>A training program and booklet content for the education to be given to mothers includes the following topics.&#xD;
What is shaken baby syndrome and what is its cause?&#xD;
What are the harms caused by shaken baby syndrome?&#xD;
How is shaken baby syndrome understood?&#xD;
What problems can shaken baby syndrome cause?&#xD;
What are the measures to be taken? For the training and the content of the booklet, expert opinion was obtained from 10 academic members who are experts in the field of Child Health. An evaluation form was created for pre-test and post-test measurements. Expert opinions were also received for these forms.&#xD;
Mothers of 2-4 months old babies who applied to Akdeniz University Hospital Pediatric Outpatient Clinic for check-up were randomized with a sealed envelope and accepted the study. In this way, intervention and control groups can be determined. After the pre-test is done in the intervention group, 2-month training, booklet and tele-consultancy services will be provided.</description>
    <arm_group_label>İntervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Having a baby of 2-4 months, Free from physical or mental disability&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Unhealthy (mother or baby), Any SBS education in the last 2 years&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>4 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ayla KAYA, Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Akdeniz University, Faculty of Nursing</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Akdeniz University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Antalya</city>
        <zip>07058</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rideout L. Nurses' Perceptions of Barriers and Facilitators Affecting the Shaken Baby Syndrome Education Initiative: An Exploratory Study of a Massachusetts Public Policy. J Trauma Nurs. 2016 May-Jun;23(3):125-37. doi: 10.1097/JTN.0000000000000206.</citation>
    <PMID>27163220</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bechtel K, Le K, Martin KD, Shah N, Leventhal JM, Colson E. Impact of an educational intervention on caregivers' beliefs about infant crying and knowledge of shaken baby syndrome. Acad Pediatr. 2011 Nov-Dec;11(6):481-6. doi: 10.1016/j.acap.2011.08.001. Epub 2011 Sep 21.</citation>
    <PMID>21940233</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fujiwara T, Yamada F, Okuyama M, Kamimaki I, Shikoro N, Barr RG. Effectiveness of educational materials designed to change knowledge and behavior about crying and shaken baby syndrome: a replication of a randomized controlled trial in Japan. Child Abuse Negl. 2012 Sep;36(9):613-20. doi: 10.1016/j.chiabu.2012.07.003. Epub 2012 Sep 4.</citation>
    <PMID>22954642</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lynøe N, Elinder G, Hallberg B, Rosén M, Sundgren P, Eriksson A. Insufficient evidence for 'shaken baby syndrome' - a systematic review. Acta Paediatr. 2017 Jul;106(7):1021-1027. doi: 10.1111/apa.13760. Epub 2017 Mar 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28130787</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Squier W. The &quot;Shaken Baby&quot; syndrome: pathology and mechanisms. Acta Neuropathol. 2011 Nov;122(5):519-42. doi: 10.1007/s00401-011-0875-2. Epub 2011 Sep 24. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21947257</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Narang SK, Estrada C, Greenberg S, Lindberg D. Acceptance of Shaken Baby Syndrome and Abusive Head Trauma as Medical Diagnoses. J Pediatr. 2016 Oct;177:273-278. doi: 10.1016/j.jpeds.2016.06.036. Epub 2016 Jul 22.</citation>
    <PMID>27458075</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Akdeniz University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ayla Kaya</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Research Assistant Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>awareness</keyword>
  <keyword>knowledge</keyword>
  <keyword>mothers</keyword>
  <keyword>nursing</keyword>
  <keyword>shaken baby syndrome</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Shaken Baby Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

