<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04565691</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MalmoUniv</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04565691</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Bacteremia From Periodontal Treatment to Elucidate the Underpinnings of Sepsis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Bacteremia From Periodontal Treatment to Elucidate the Underpinnings of Sepsis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Malmö University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Skane University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Swedish Dental Service Organisation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Malmö University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Approximately 40,000 Swedes suffer from sepsiseach year, about 20% die. Biomarkers that are&#xD;
      sensitive to current or previous bacteremia are needed in the treatment of sepsis. Bacteremia&#xD;
      from periodontal treatment is predictive and occurs in 13-75%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study's hypothesis is to utilize bacteremia from periodontal treatment to evaluate&#xD;
      biological markers for current or previous bacteremia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A. What are the long term clinical, and 'omics related CVD-phenotypical effects from treating&#xD;
      periodontal disease compared to an untreated group? B. Can biomarkers be used for detecting a&#xD;
      bacteremia or previous bacteremia? C. Are the effects from bacteremia on cardiovascular&#xD;
      biomarkers related to the individual's antimicrobial peptide profile? D. Does the presence of&#xD;
      bacterial proteases, such as gingipain, relate to having a bacteremia from periodontal&#xD;
      treatment and the systemic response from a bacteremia?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Significance: The project has the potential to shorten the time to treat sepsis, which in&#xD;
      turn shortens hospital stay and higher survival. The possible definition of protective&#xD;
      AMP-profile could translate to future pharmacologic intervention and improve the treatment of&#xD;
      sepsis as well as prophylactic treatment at dental treatments.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Bacteremia from periodontal treatment to elucidate the underpinnings of sepsis Hypothesis In&#xD;
      the context of cardiovascular disease (CVD) and sepsis this study hypothesise that (1)&#xD;
      periodontal disease causes a specific CVD phenotype that can, to some extent, be reversed by&#xD;
      treating periodontal disease; (2) that non-surgical periodontal treatment can be used as a&#xD;
      human bacteremia model for evaluating biomarkers that can be used in the sepsis clinic; (3)&#xD;
      that endogenous antimicrobial peptide profile dictate the severity of a bacteremia; (4) that&#xD;
      proteinases from the oral biofilm can impact the severity of a bacteremia induced by oral&#xD;
      bacteria and their products.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims A. What are the long term clinical, and 'omics related CVD-phenotypical effects from&#xD;
      treating periodontal disease compared to an untreated group? B. Can biomarkers be used for&#xD;
      detecting a bacteremia or previous bacteremia? C. Are the effects from bacteremia on&#xD;
      cardiovascular biomarkers related to the individual's antimicrobial peptide profile? D. Does&#xD;
      the presence of bacterial proteases, such as gingipain, relate to having a bacteremia from&#xD;
      periodontal treatment and the systemic response from a bacteremia? Project description To&#xD;
      answer the clinical problems from the dental chair and the sepsis intensity care unit the&#xD;
      investigators have designed the Bacteremia Study. Aim 1 is an intervention study, while Aim 2&#xD;
      and 3 are investigating the pathophysiological underpinnings of the association. When&#xD;
      studying the long term effects of periodontal treatment on CVD phenotype Malmö Offspring&#xD;
      Dental Study (MODS) participants who have not sought dental care despite being told they have&#xD;
      periodontal disease, will be invited as non-treated controls. The primary outcome variable&#xD;
      will be changes in total carotid plaque area (TPA) per year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Aim 2 and 3 the parameters used to dissect the different aspects of the bacteremia. The&#xD;
      AMP profile may be different in subjects with more severe bacteremia (measured by blood&#xD;
      culturing) versus no bacteremia. The primary outcome will be concentration of CVD biomarkers&#xD;
      during and following bacteremia (positive blood culture) compared to those who have negative&#xD;
      blood culture.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment The participants are recruited at the Swedish Dental Service of Skåne in Lund, at&#xD;
      the Department for Periodontics. The inclusion criteria is having periodontal disease - one&#xD;
      quadrant with ≥2 teeth with &gt; 5mm pocket depth (PD) and this quadrant will be treated when&#xD;
      the blood samples are taken. The treatment is mechanical non-surgical periodontal treatment.&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria is having a conditions that require prophylactic antibiotics at&#xD;
      periodontal treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Number of recruited participants The study will recruit 100 participants plus reexamination&#xD;
      of MODS participants who have not sought periodontal treatment. Unfortunately, the available&#xD;
      literature on bacteremia at periodontal treatment is very heterogeneous (13-75%), making it&#xD;
      difficult to perform a meaningful power calculation. The investigators have decided on 100&#xD;
      participants and this has been approved by the Ethical Review Authority.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiovascular phenotyping At baseline and after 1 year and 2 years the participants undergo&#xD;
      cardiovascular phenotyping at Clinical Research Unit at Skåne University Hospital (Kliniska&#xD;
      Forskningsenheten, KFE). The cardiovascular phenotyping in this project is based on several&#xD;
      subclinical parameters mentioned bellow, however the most important is carotid artery&#xD;
      ultrasound for assessment of carotid plaque area and stability. Associate Professor Jönsson&#xD;
      is the first author and Olle Melander co-author of a publication investigating the&#xD;
      association between periodontal disease and carotid total plaque area has. The carotid&#xD;
      imaging in this project is performed by the same personal using the same equipment as in&#xD;
      Jönsson et al..&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Carotid artery ultrasound (GE logiq E9) of both carotids.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Presence of carotid plaque.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Number of carotid plaques.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Area of carotid plaque(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Visual cap.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Degree of stenosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Gray scale medium (GSM) of carotid plaque.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Statistical geometric feature (SGF) - spottiness of the plaque. The GSM and SGF&#xD;
           (actually SGF/plaque area or SGF/degree of stenosis) is an expression of heterogeneity&#xD;
           of the plaque on ultrasound and is correlated to plaque area stained for lipids,&#xD;
           macrophages and hemorrhage as well as cytokine expression. While GSM gives the overall&#xD;
           echogenicity in the plaque, SGF is a measurement that describe the distribution of grey&#xD;
           scale levels within the plaque.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other parameters in cardiovascular phenotyping included in the project:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood pressure - sitting blood pressure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  BMI and hip/waist measurement.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Total cholesterol (TC), LDL-C and HDL-C.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Fasting blood glucose (FBG) and HbA1c.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  GWAS for genes associated with CVD. Blood culture and blood 16S sequencing At all&#xD;
           time-points blood is drawn for culturing and blood 16S-sequencing analysis. For&#xD;
           culturing the phlebotomists in the study have been trained by the nurses at the&#xD;
           infection clinic on how to draw blood for culturing - 4 blood culturing flasks per time&#xD;
           point - one anaerobe and one aerobe on each arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood will be drawn and DNA will be extracted from PBMCs. For subsequent sequencing 16S&#xD;
      amplicon sequencing will be used with amplicon sequencing variants (ASV) based bioinformatics&#xD;
      pipeline, which increases the resolution and allows a larger fraction of the bacteria to be&#xD;
      identified with species resolution. The results from the blood 16S sequencing will then be&#xD;
      compared to the content of the oral biofilm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biomarkers The biomarkers play two important roles in this project - firstly, they are&#xD;
      biomarkers of bacteremia that the investigators evaluate, and the sequencing of blood&#xD;
      bacteria is also considered to be a biomarker of previous bacteremia, as described above.&#xD;
      Secondly, and perhaps even more importantly, they collectively reflect the systemic response.&#xD;
      Bacteremia can initiate sepsis, but the host response is what causes the condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the analysis the biomarkers are divided into those immediately sent to the hospital lab,&#xD;
      and biomarkers that the investigators analyze when all samples are collected. The biomarkers&#xD;
      analyzed immediately are&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Procalcitonin (PCT)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  High sensitivity troponin T (hsTNT)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  High sensitivity C-reactive protein (hs-CRP)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  N-terminal prohormone of brain natriuretic peptide (NT-proBNP)&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a later phase, the investigators will also analyze:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Mid-regional pro-adrenomedullin (MR-pro-ADM)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  C-terminal pro-endothelin-1 (CT-pro-ET-1)&#xD;
&#xD;
      When the investigators collected all samples, the investigators will utilize a multiplex&#xD;
      approach for novel biomarker detection, such as OLINK proteomics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Antimicrobial peptides Antimicrobial peptides will be analyzed by quantitative selected&#xD;
      reaction monitoring mass spectrometry (SRM-MS), in accordance with previously published work&#xD;
      from the group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Proteases Proteases, and especially gingipain form Porphyromonas gingivalis has gained&#xD;
      attention through a recent publication reporting on the effects from gingipain on the disease&#xD;
      progression of Alzheimer's disease. Proteinases and gingipain specifically, will be analyzed&#xD;
      in GCF, and also in plasma. Thanks to previous funding the investigators have, in&#xD;
      collaboration with Innovagen, created anti-gingipain antibodies that will be evaluated in&#xD;
      collaboration with Associate Professors Bertil Kinnby and Claes Wickström at Malmö&#xD;
      University.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistics Aim 1 statistics - The intervention trial aspect will be primarily based on&#xD;
      changes in carotid total plaque area (TPA). The annual change in TPA will first be assessed&#xD;
      in the non-treated subjects from MODS. Changes in TPA will be treated as a dependent variable&#xD;
      in a linear regression. Periodontal treatment versus untreated control will be used as&#xD;
      independent variable. Other independent variables will be confounding factors, such as age,&#xD;
      smoking status, education, medication, blood pressure etc. The investigators will then&#xD;
      continue by using 'omics related biomarkers, such as OLINK proteins, as independent&#xD;
      variables.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2 statistics - To investigate the association between cardiovascular biomarkers and&#xD;
      bacteremia the investigators will investigate each time-point (Figure 1) separately. To&#xD;
      investigate the association between bacteremia and CVD biomarkers, positive blood culture /&#xD;
      previous blood culture / colony forming units (CFU) will be used as dependent variables and&#xD;
      the biomarkers as independent variables in logistic/linear regressions, adjusting for&#xD;
      confounders. ROC-curves will be constructed to test biomarkers of bacteremia at the&#xD;
      respective time-points, to predict positive blood culture / previous blood culture.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 3 statistics - To assess the impact of the AMP-profile, individual peptides will be&#xD;
      included in a principal component analysis (PCA). A linear regression model with biomarkers&#xD;
      as dependent variables and blood culture and PCA factors as independent variables will be&#xD;
      constructed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 4 statistics - Proteases will be included as independent variables in logistic and linear&#xD;
      regression models with blood culture and biomarkers as dependent variables, respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results from sequencing blood for microbiome will be analyzed in relation to the effects&#xD;
      on biomarkers and blood culture, respectively, in the aims of 3 and 4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Significance A thorough investigation of the underpinning of the association between CVD and&#xD;
      periodontal disease and how periodontal disease may impact the course of CVD will be&#xD;
      important in understanding the association. Decades of frequent low grade bacteremia may have&#xD;
      caused more severe damages to the cardiovascular system in need of more personalized&#xD;
      attention from cardiologists. This study elucidates what that cardiologist should look for.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the context of sepsis the current project has the potential to contribute to more sepsis&#xD;
      patients surviving the disease through a more precise and faster targeting of the bacteria&#xD;
      initiating the condition. A biomarker that is more sensitive to bacteremia than blood culture&#xD;
      and allows fast analysis would contribute to shorter time to correct antibiotics, which is&#xD;
      the most important factor for shorter hospital stay and less deaths from sepsis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 25, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>We study the impact of bacteremia. The subjects will be their own controls at the different time-points.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>No masking.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Bacteremia</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, periodontal treatment (within 5 min) and 1 hour, 1 day, 1 week and 1 year after periodontal treatment.</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in positive blood culture</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in levels of biomarkers in relation to bacteremia</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, periodontal treatment (within 5 min) and 1 hour, 1 day, 1 week and 1 year after periodontal treatment.</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in levels of biomarkers following bacteremia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Bacteremia</condition>
  <condition>Periodontal Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Sepsis</condition>
  <condition>Heart Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Bacteremia inducing arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>As mentioned the participants will be their own controls at the different time-points.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Non-surgical periodontal treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Non-surgical periodontal treatment that is accepted to cause bacteremia in about 50% of the cases.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Bacteremia inducing arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Periodontal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recently used antibiotics.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Daniel Jonsson, DDS PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Malmo University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Daniel Jonsson, DDS, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+46462759180</phone>
    <email>daniel.jonsson@mau.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Josefine Gay, DDS</last_name>
    <phone>+46462759180</phone>
    <email>josefine.gay@folktandvardenskane.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Folktandvarden Skane</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lund</city>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Daniel Joensson, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+46704830346</phone>
      <email>daniel.jonsson@skane.se</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 29, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 22, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 25, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 22, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 22, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 25, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Malmö University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Daniel Joensson</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Bacteremia</keyword>
  <keyword>Periodontal disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Sepsis</keyword>
  <keyword>Heart Disease</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sepsis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Toxemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bacteremia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Periodontal Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

