<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04569500</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19-133</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04569500</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>FRENCH THERAPEUTIC EDUCATION PROGRAM AIMING TO IMPROVE LARYNGECTOMIZED PATIENTS' AND THEIR FAMILY CAREGIVER'S QUALITY OF LIFE</brief_title>
  <acronym>PETAL2</acronym>
  <official_title>FRENCH THERAPEUTIC EDUCATION PROGRAM AIMING TO IMPROVE LARYNGECTOMIZED PATIENTS' AND THEIR FAMILY CAREGIVER'S QUALITY OF LIFE</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Caen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Caen</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The therapeutic education of patients and their close relations is, as yet, poorly developed&#xD;
      in France in the field of oncology (Pérol2007), in particular for cancers of the upper&#xD;
      aerodigestive tract (Allison2010). In the case of pharyngeal and laryngeal cancer, total&#xD;
      laryngectomy associated with radiotherapy remains a reference treatment for advanced stage&#xD;
      cancers. This mutilating surgical procedure has a major impact on the patient's life, due to&#xD;
      its physical and functional sequelae: phonatory (loss of physiological voice), feeding,&#xD;
      olfactory and aesthetic (tracheostomy). Its psychosocial consequences are also important,&#xD;
      owing to the biographical disruption and the identity-related metamorphoses associated with&#xD;
      illness and its treatment, which alter the quality of life not only of patients, but also of&#xD;
      their close relations. Indeed, transformation is not only at individual level, it also&#xD;
      impacts the life of close relations, in particular spouses, who share the day-to-day lives of&#xD;
      patients (Babin 2010). Currently, care for laryngectomized patients consist essentially in&#xD;
      informing and educating them on certain technical procedures (cannula replacement, mucosity&#xD;
      aspiration, tracheostomy or phonatory implant cleaning) during hospital admission. Such&#xD;
      education may be formalized and dispensed within the context of a therapeutic education&#xD;
      program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The issue of this study will be to determine what therapeutic education program we should&#xD;
      offer patients and their close relations in order to accompany them throughout their&#xD;
      experience of laryngectomy and to reduce its impact on social and professional aspects of&#xD;
      life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life score (PSS-HN scale) of patients with total laryngectomy</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in gain observed at six months in the mean quality of life score (PSS-HN scale) of patients with total laryngectomy and their close relatives, having benefited from the PTE program and those having benefited from usual care.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life score (EVA scale) of patient's close relatives</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>difference in gain observed at six months in the mean quality of life score (EVA scale) between close relations having benefited from the PTE program and those having benefited from usual support.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">264</enrollment>
  <condition>Patients With Total Laryngectomy and Their Close Relatives</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PETAL program</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with total laryngectomy and their close relatives, benefiting from the therapeutic education program PETAL</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with total laryngectomy and their close relatives, benefiting from the usual care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PETAL program</intervention_name>
    <description>patients and their close relations will benefit from the therapeutic education program PETAL in order to accompany them throughout their experience of laryngectomy and to reduce its impact on social and professional aspects of life.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PETAL program</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Patient inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients over 18 having been treated by total laryngectomy for cancer of the larynx,&#xD;
             pharynx or cervical esophagus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients accepting to participate in the study (informed consent form explained and&#xD;
             signed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient having not been undergone a PTE&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person affiliated with an appropriate social security system.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Close relation inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person over 18 designated as being a close relation by the laryngectomized patient&#xD;
             (confidential person, spouse, parent, natural support person or any person whose&#xD;
             quality of life may be impacted by the patient's laryngectomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Close relation accepting to participate in the study (informed consent form explained&#xD;
             and signed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person authorized by the patient to be contacted by the investigator, in order to&#xD;
             propose his/her participation in the research study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person affiliated with an appropriate social security system.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient exclusion criteria - Physical, psychical, psychiatric or cognitive incapacity to&#xD;
        answer to questions or participate in interviews/sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Close relation exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Physical, psychical, psychiatric or cognitive incapacity to answer to questions or&#xD;
        participate in interviews/sessions.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Emmanuel PH BABIN</last_name>
    <phone>+33231064866</phone>
    <email>babin-e@chu-caen.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>François FOURNEL</last_name>
    <phone>+33231065488</phone>
    <email>fournel-f@chu-caen.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

