<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04569591</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>200048</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>20-N-0048</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04569591</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Corticotrophin-releasing Hormone (CRH) Stimulation for 18F-FDG-PET Detection of Pituitary Adenoma in Cushing s Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Corticotrophin-Releasing Hormone (CRH) Stimulation for 18F-FDG-PET Detection of Pituitary Adenoma in Cushing's Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cushing s disease is caused by a pituitary gland tumor. Patients with Cushing s disease&#xD;
      suffer obesity, diabetes, osteoporosis, weakness, and hypertension. The cure is surgery to&#xD;
      remove the pituitary tumor. Currently, MRI is the best way to find these tumors. But not all&#xD;
      tumors can be seen with an MRI. Researchers hope giving the hormone CRH before a PET scan can&#xD;
      help make these tumors more visible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To test whether giving CRH before a PET scan will help find pituitary gland tumors that might&#xD;
      be causing Cushing s disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People ages 8 and older with Cushing s disease that is caused by a pituitary gland tumor that&#xD;
      cannot be reliably seen on MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with their medical history, a physical exam, an MRI, and blood&#xD;
      tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have at least one hospital visit. During their time in the hospital, they&#xD;
      will have a physical exam and a neurological exam. They will have a PET scan of the brain. A&#xD;
      thin plastic tube will be inserted into an arm vein. A small amount of radioactive sugar and&#xD;
      CRH will be injected through the tube. Participants will lie in a darkened room for about an&#xD;
      hour and be asked to urinate. Then they will lie inside the scanner for about 40 minutes.&#xD;
      After the scan, they will be asked to urinate every 2-3 hours for the rest of the day. Blood&#xD;
      will be drawn through a needle in the arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have surgery to remove their tumor within 3 months after the scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will then continue regular follow-up in the clinic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed as a single institution trial. The study utilizes safe and&#xD;
      clinically-validated tools for preoperative workup of patients with small pituitary tumors.&#xD;
      CRH stimulation and 18F-FDG uptake in PET imaging will be used to detect MRI-negative&#xD;
      pituitary adenomas in patients with Cushing s disease. Patients who have MRI-negative&#xD;
      pituitary microadenomas will undergo 18F-FDG PET-imaging with CRH stimulation. Intravenous&#xD;
      18F-FDG will be given approximately four hours following CRH administration. Within 12 weeks&#xD;
      after completion of the last 18F-FDG high-resolution PET-imaging scan, patients will undergo&#xD;
      surgical resection of the pituitary adenoma. Surgical and histological confirmation of&#xD;
      adenoma location will be noted. All images will be read independently by neuroradiologists&#xD;
      blinded to clinical and histopathological outcomes. The diagnostic and localization accuracy&#xD;
      of PET-imaging will be assessed by comparing the PET findings with histopathology.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CRH-stimulated PET imaging demonstrates tumor in MRI-negative cases.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome measure will be defined as whether or not CRH- stimulated PET imaging demonstrates tumor in MRI-negative cases. This will be demonstrated by assessing the accuracy and sensitivity of 18F-FDG high-resolution PET-imaging detection of ACTH-adenomas that could not be reliably detected on MR-imaging. Measures will include determining the rate of true tumor detection using PET-imaging compared to histologically-confirmed tumor location.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Elevation of SUV of 18F-FDG</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>To measure the elevation of SUV of 18F-FDG within adenomas compared to surrounding normal gland following CRH stimulated PET imaging.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">22</enrollment>
  <condition>Cushing's Disease</condition>
  <condition>Pituitary Adenoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients aged 8 or older with Cushing's Disease who are surgical candidates for resection of ACTH producing pituitary adenoma within 12 weeks of PET imaging</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acthrel</intervention_name>
    <description>Intravenous administration of ovine CRH (Acthrel (Registered Trademark) 1 mcg/kg up to a maximum dose of 100 mcg) results in selective increase in ACTH activity of pituitary adenomas within two minutes and peaks between 10-15 minutes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In order to be eligible to participate in this study, an individual must meet all of the&#xD;
        following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients aged 8 or older with biochemical evidence of Cushing s disease and a clinical&#xD;
             MRI pituitary neuroradiology result of negative or possible adenoma (e.g. 'no tumor'&#xD;
             or 'possible tumor' around)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. MRI of the Pituitary gland with and without contrast obtained within 9 months of&#xD;
             screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Ability to undergo PET-imaging without general anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Ability to provide informed consent for study participation (parents or guardians in&#xD;
             the case of minors)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Clinical diagnosis of Cushing s disease based on documented medical records&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Surgical candidate for resection of ACTH producing pituitary adenoma within 1 weeks of&#xD;
             PET-imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Normal liver function as evidenced by liver enzyme tests completed within 14 days&#xD;
             before injection of radiopharmaceutical: SGOT, SGPT &lt;= 5 x upper limit of normal;&#xD;
             bilirubin &lt;= 2 x upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Enrolled in 03-N-0164, Evaluation of Neurosurgical Disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        An individual who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from participation&#xD;
        in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnancy or lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Severe chronic renal insufficiency (glomerular filtration rate &lt; 30 mL/min/1.73 m&#xD;
             squared), hepatorenal syndrome or post-liver transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Elevated blood glucose level above 200 mg/dL on the day of the scan prior to 18F-FDG&#xD;
             administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Known intolerance to CRH&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION OF VULNERABLE PARTICIPANTS:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children: Children age 8 and older are included in this protocol. More than half of&#xD;
             the patients with CD requiring transsphenoidal surgery at the NIH are children.&#xD;
             Furthermore, the knowledge gained by the use of CRH PET imaging in children with&#xD;
             MR-invisible tumors will provide direct benefit to the individual child and will&#xD;
             provide generalizable knowledge in the treatment of CD in this population. Children&#xD;
             under the age of 8 usually require anesthesia for a PET scan, which involves greater&#xD;
             risk. Therefore, children under the age of 8 will be excluded from participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  NIH Employees: Protections for employees and staff participating in this study&#xD;
             include:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1) assuring that the participation or refusal to participate will have no effect,&#xD;
             either beneficial or adverse, on the subject s employment or position at the NIH, 2)&#xD;
             giving employees and staff who are interested in participating the 'NIH Information&#xD;
             Sheet on Employee Research Participation' prior to obtaining consent, and 3) assuring&#xD;
             that there will be no direct solicitation of employees or staff. 4) Independent&#xD;
             consent monitoring will be provided by the NIH HSPU. 5) The PI will train study staff&#xD;
             regarding obtaining and handling potentially sensitive and private information about&#xD;
             co-workers through staff discussions and written branch/section procedures. No&#xD;
             compensation will be provided for this protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating women: Pregnant and lactating women will be excluded from&#xD;
             participation. The PET radiopharmaceutical used in this study can be harmful to a&#xD;
             developing fetus. Therefore women who are able to become pregnant will have a&#xD;
             pregnancy test performed within 24 hours before PET-imaging. Individuals will not be&#xD;
             able to participate in PET scanning if the pregnancy test results positive.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Prashant Chittiboina, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Isaac J Pomeraniec, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-2921</phone>
    <email>jonathan.pomeraniec@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?B_2020-N-0048.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 6, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Corticotropinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Pituitary Microadenoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Acthrel</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pituitary Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>ACTH-Secreting Pituitary Adenoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pituitary Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pituitary ACTH Hypersecretion</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

