<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03221751</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>B2180-P</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1I21RX002180-01</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03221751</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prazosin and CSF Biomarkers in mTBI</brief_title>
  <acronym>PoND</acronym>
  <official_title>Prazosin and CSF Biomarkers in mTBI</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Mild traumatic brain injury (mTBI) from explosions is the &quot;signature injury&quot; of Veterans who&#xD;
      have deployed to the wars in Afghanistan and Iraq. Although the immediate effects of a single&#xD;
      mTBI usually resolve over days or weeks, multiple mTBIs can lead to both persistent symptoms&#xD;
      and, years later, to two fatal progressive brain diseases, chronic traumatic encephalopathy&#xD;
      (CTE) and Alzheimer's disease (AD). It is believed that CTE and AD are caused by nerve&#xD;
      damaging chemicals called tau and beta amyloid produced by the brain but which are not&#xD;
      removed from the brain in a normal manner in persons with mTBIs. The investigators will&#xD;
      determine in Veterans who experienced mTBIs whether a clinically available drug called&#xD;
      prazosin increases removal of tau and beta amyloid from the brain. This will be accomplished&#xD;
      by seeing if prazosin reduces the amount of tau and beta amyloid in the spinal fluid that&#xD;
      surrounds the brain. If the investigators find such reductions, prazosin will be evaluated as&#xD;
      a preventative treatment for CTE and AD in future studies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A majority of neurodegenerative dementing disorders, including Alzheimer's disease, (AD),&#xD;
      dementia with Lewy bodies (DLB) and chronic traumatic encephalopathy (CTE), now appear to be&#xD;
      caused by the accumulation and aggregation of proteins that cause progressive damage to the&#xD;
      brain. Recent preclinical results suggest that clearance of such neurotoxic proteins from the&#xD;
      brain may be greatly increased during states where noradrenergic (NA) tone is decreased or&#xD;
      blocked, such as anesthesia and normal sleep, but impaired in animal models of mild Traumatic&#xD;
      Brain Injury (mTBI). These results also suggest that clearance through this mechanism, which&#xD;
      has been termed the 'glymphatic' system, is likely to be decreased in conditions where NA&#xD;
      signaling is inappropriately maintained during sleep, such as posttraumatic stress disorder&#xD;
      (PTSD). Importantly, the rate at which toxins are cleared through the glypmhatic system has&#xD;
      been found to be under alpha-1 adrenergic receptor (AR) control, and the application of&#xD;
      noradrenergic blockers such as the alpha-1 AR antagonist drug, prazosin, has been shown to&#xD;
      increase waking clearance of these proteins to levels normally found during sleep or&#xD;
      anesthesia. This suggests two important possibilities: first, that conditions in which the&#xD;
      brain NA signaling is increased and sleep is impaired, such as posttraumatic stress disorder&#xD;
      (PTSD) and mTBI, may predispose people to decreased clearance of neurotoxic proteins&#xD;
      associated with the development and progression of dementia; and second, that the use of&#xD;
      prazosin may be able to prevent such effects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CSF total-tau</measure>
    <time_frame>10 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>an established biomarker of neurodegeneration in Alzheimer's disease.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>p-tau181</measure>
    <time_frame>10 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>an established biomarker of neurodegeneration in Alzheimer's disease.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>amyloid beta 42</measure>
    <time_frame>10 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>an established biomarker of neurodegeneration in Alzheimer's disease.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Dementia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prazosin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be titrated up to the maximum dose or the maximum tolerated dose based on a dosing algorithm. The maximum dose is 5 mg in the morning, 5 mg in the afternoon and 15 mg at bedtime.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be titrated up to the maximum dose or the maximum tolerated dose based on a dosing algorithm. The maximum dose is 5 mg in the morning, 5 mg in the afternoon and 15 mg at bedtime.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>prazosin hydrochloride</intervention_name>
    <description>Prazosin is an oral capsule identical in appearance to prazosin capsules titrated in the same manner as prazosin.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prazosin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Minipress</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Prazosin is an oral capsule identical in appearance to prazosin capsules titrated in the same manner as prazosin.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>inactive drug; sugar pill; dummy pill</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 21 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to complete psychometric and other clinical assessments in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No clinically significant laboratory abnormalities at screen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &gt;100,000/mm2 within two weeks of lumbar puncture (LP)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI) between 18 and 36 inclusive (BMIs outside this range affect CSF&#xD;
             biomarker measurements and/or make LPs for CSF collection difficult to perform).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential must agree to abstain from sexual relations that could&#xD;
             result in pregnancy or use an effective method of birth control acceptable to both&#xD;
             participant and the study clinician during the study. Men are not required to use&#xD;
             contraception during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meeting criteria for at least one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. History of mild or moderate TBI:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exposure to at least one blast or experiencing at least one collision of the head&#xD;
             associated with acute symptoms that meet VA/DoD criteria for mild or moderate TBI&#xD;
             (loss of consciousness, if present, &lt;24 hours; posttraumatic amnesia, if present, &lt;1&#xD;
             week; Glasgow Coma Scale (if available) 9-15) -&gt;6 months since last TBI. 2. Documented&#xD;
             diagnosis of PTSD related to combat trauma (from any conflict)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Medical&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe TBI (Glasgow Coma Scale (if available) &lt;9, loss of consciousness &gt;24&#xD;
             hours, posttraumatic amnesia &gt;1 week)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute or unstable chronic medical illness, including unstable angina, recent&#xD;
             myocardial infarction (within 6 months), congestive heart failure, preexisting&#xD;
             hypotension (systolic &lt;110) or orthostatic hypotension (systolic drop &gt; 20mmHg after&#xD;
             two minutes standing or any drop accompanied by dizziness), autoimmune disorders;&#xD;
             insulin-dependent diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic renal or hepatic failure, acute pancreatitis, Meniere's disease, benign&#xD;
             positional vertigo, narcolepsy, or diagnosed untreated sleep apnea (sleep apnea&#xD;
             currently being treated is not exclusionary).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindications to LP (e.g., spinal cord injury; deformity, severe disease or&#xD;
             infection in the region of the lumbosacral spine; bleeding tendency, clotting&#xD;
             abnormalities, use of anticoagulant medications, or platelet count &lt;100,000/mm2);&#xD;
             trauma or infection in the 4 weeks before LP&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current pregnancy or lactation. Women of childbearing potential must agree to abstain&#xD;
             from sexual relations that could result in pregnancy or use an effective method of&#xD;
             birth control acceptable to both participant and the study clinician during the study.&#xD;
             Men are not required to use contraception during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Psychiatric/Behavioral&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meets DSM(IV or 5, depending on what evaluative method was used in this subject)&#xD;
             criteria for current schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder, other specified or&#xD;
             unspecified psychotic disorder, delirium, or any DSM cognitive disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current substance use disorder (except caffeine-related disorders, tobacco-related&#xD;
             disorders, or cannabis intoxication) other than in remission for at least 3 months.&#xD;
             The use of cannabis other than that meeting criteria for cannabis use disorder is not&#xD;
             exclusionary. Use of cannabis will be documented.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of any stimulant, including prescribed stimulant medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use (within the past 1 month, ongoing, or expected during the study period) of&#xD;
             any drugs that are illegal under Washington state law.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe psychiatric instability or severe situational life crises, including evidence&#xD;
             of being actively suicidal or homicidal, or any behavior which poses an immediate&#xD;
             danger to participant or others.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Medications/Therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of prazosin or other alpha-1 antagonist or trazodone, or use of such agent&#xD;
             within the 3 month period prior to when the baseline 2 visit would be scheduled (a&#xD;
             3-month washout is required due to the potential effects it may have on the biomarker&#xD;
             measurements).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy or previous adverse reaction to prazosin or other alpha-1 antagonist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of exclusionary medications in the 4 weeks prior to screening: selected CNS-acting&#xD;
             medications; antipsychotics, anti-Parkinson's disease medications and CNS stimulants;&#xD;
             Coumadin or other medications affecting coagulation and/or inflammation (low-dose&#xD;
             aspirin and use of NSAIDs for pain will not be exclusionary); potent immune-modulating&#xD;
             medications, such as hydrocortisone or methotrexate; anti-HIV medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of avanafil (Stendra), sildenafil (Viagra), tadalafil (Cialis), and vardenafil&#xD;
             (Levitra) will be not be permitted during the study dose titration period because of&#xD;
             increased risk of hypotension in combination with alpha-1 blockers, but will be&#xD;
             allowed at 1/2 the usual starting dose following dose titration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of stimulants or nitrates, or of alternative medications or supplements&#xD;
             with stimulant properties (e.g., ephedra) or vasodilatory properties (e.g., nitrate&#xD;
             containing supplements)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent evidence based trauma- or sleep-focused psychotherapy, such as Prolonged&#xD;
             Exposure therapy (PE), Cognitive Processing Therapy (CPT), Eye Movement&#xD;
             Desensitization and Reprogramming (EMDR), Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Insomnia&#xD;
             (CBTi) or Image Rehearsal and Rescripting therapy for nightmares. These therapies must&#xD;
             have been completed &gt; 4 weeks before first baseline assessment visit (study visit 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Other&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy or previous adverse reaction to prazosin or other alpha-1 antagonist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving another medication in another interventional study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Murray A. Raskind, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>VA Puget Sound Health Care System Seattle Division, Seattle, WA</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA Puget Sound Health Care System Seattle Division, Seattle, WA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98108</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 13, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 17, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 19, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>randomized controlled trial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prazosin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

