<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01238432</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>08-103</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01238432</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Genetics of Severe Asthma in Children</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Genetics of Severe Asthma in Children</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Connecticut Children's Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>UConn Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Connecticut Children's Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Near fatal asthma exacerbations are one of the most common causes of critical illness in&#xD;
      children, accounting for approximately ten thousand intensive care unit (ICU) admissions per&#xD;
      year in the United States. Even children with intermittent or mild baseline asthma can&#xD;
      develop these severe exacerbations; however, there are few studies evaluating the risk&#xD;
      factors associated with the development of near fatal asthma exacerbations in children.&#xD;
      Inhaled β2-adrenergic receptor (ADRβ2) agonist therapy is the foundation of therapy for acute&#xD;
      asthma and genetic variations of this receptor have been shown to affect response to ADRβ2&#xD;
      agonist therapy in this population. The investigators hypothesis is that a child's ADRβ2&#xD;
      genotype is associated with the development of a near fatal asthma exacerbation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Our primary outcome measure is the development of a near fatal asthma exacerbation. Secondary&#xD;
      outcome measures will include the duration of continuously nebulized ADRβ2 agonist therapy&#xD;
      and the duration of IV ADRβ2 agonist therapy. Children will be stratified by ADRβ2 genotype&#xD;
      at amino acid position 16 and outcomes compared.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We propose to investigate two separate populations in this study: (1) children admitted to&#xD;
      the hospital with an acute asthma exacerbation, and (2) children with asthma who have never&#xD;
      had an acute near fatal asthma exacerbation. In addition, in order to replicate findings in&#xD;
      an independent cohort, we will examine the genotypes of a third cohort of age-matched&#xD;
      children without asthma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the population of children admitted to the hospital with an acute asthma exacerbation,&#xD;
      the following inclusion criteria will be met: (1) admission to the hospital with a primary&#xD;
      admission diagnosis of asthma exacerbation and (2) age between 4 years and 18 years. Near&#xD;
      fatal asthma exacerbations will be defined as (1) treatment with intubation and mechanical&#xD;
      ventilation, (2) presence of respiratory acidosis (arterial pCO2 &gt; 45), or (3) Modified&#xD;
      Pulmonary Index Score &gt; 12 after 2 hours of at least 20 mg/hour of continuously nebulized&#xD;
      albuterol therapy. Children will be excluded if they have a (1) pre-existing chronic disease&#xD;
      (other than asthma) including: (a) bronchopulmonary dysplasia, (b) bronchomalacia, (c)&#xD;
      tracheomalacia, (d) laryngomalacia, (e) vocal cord dysfunction, (f) chronic restrictive lung&#xD;
      disease, (g) recurrent aspiration pneumonia, or (h) congenital heart disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the population of children with asthma who have never had an acute near fatal asthma&#xD;
      exacerbation, the following inclusion criteria will be met: (1) diagnosis of asthma and (2)&#xD;
      age between 4 years and 18 years. Children will be excluded if (1) that child ever required&#xD;
      admission to the hospital for a near fatal asthma exacerbation and (2) if they have a&#xD;
      pre-existing chronic disease (other than asthma) as listed above. We propose to enroll 158&#xD;
      children, recruited from Pulmonary Clinic at the study institution, matched by age, by&#xD;
      gender, and by NHLBI asthma classification to the population of children with near fatal&#xD;
      asthma exacerbations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to replicate these findings in an independent cohort, we will also examine these&#xD;
      genetic markers in a reference group of 80 healthy children without asthma, matched by age,&#xD;
      gender and race/ethnicity to the group of children with near fatal asthma exacerbations. The&#xD;
      following inclusion criteria will be met for this group: (1) age between 4 and 18 years.&#xD;
      Children will be excluded if they have any pre-existing chronic disease. This population of&#xD;
      children will be recruited from the Primary Care Clinic at CCMC and if necessary for&#xD;
      racial/ethnic matching, from a private practice in suburban Hartford.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the population of children hospitalized with an asthma exacerbation, patients will be&#xD;
      approached, consented and enrolled upon admission to the hospital. In this observational&#xD;
      study, patients will be treated according to the current asthma treatment protocol in effect&#xD;
      at Connecticut Children's Medical Center. This protocol has been previously published 13 and&#xD;
      titrates therapy based on a clinical asthma score (MPIS) 51 that has been shown to be highly&#xD;
      reproducible between groups of physicians, nurses and respiratory therapists. This&#xD;
      around-the-clock adjustment of therapy by nurses and respiratory therapists produces less&#xD;
      variation in care due to non-medical reasons. This protocol includes thresholds for&#xD;
      admission/discharge to the hospital and for admission/discharge to the ICU based on MPIS. For&#xD;
      the populations of children with no history of a near fatal asthma exacerbation and no asthma&#xD;
      diagnosis, patients will be approached, consented and enrolled upon confirmation of&#xD;
      eligibility in the Pulmonary Clinic and the Primary Care Clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Genotyping of the ADRβ2 gene will be performed at the University of Connecticut Health Center&#xD;
      (UCHC) Clinical and Translational Research Core Lab. Genotyping will be performed either from&#xD;
      saliva or from whole blood collected during routine blood sampling for clinical care.&#xD;
      Children will be stratified based on their genotype and outcomes compared. Providers will be&#xD;
      blinded to genotype at the time of treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary end point is the development of a near fatal asthma exacerbation.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The secondary end point is hospital length of stay.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Asthma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Inpatient population</arm_group_label>
    <description>Children with asthma who are admitted to the hospital with an exacerbation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Outpatient population</arm_group_label>
    <description>Children with asthma who have not been admitted to the hospital with an exacerbation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy controls</arm_group_label>
    <description>Children without asthma or any other chronic condition.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      saliva and blood&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Children with asthma&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria, inpatient asthmatics:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Admission to study institution with a primary admission diagnosis of asthma&#xD;
             exacerbation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age between 4 and 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria, inpatient asthmatics:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Pre-existing chronic disease (other than asthma), including: i. bronchopulmonary&#xD;
        dysplasia ii. bronchomalacia iii. tracheomalacia iv. laryngomalacia v. vocal cord&#xD;
        dysfunction vi. chronic restrictive lung disease vii. recurrent aspiration pneumonia viii.&#xD;
        impaired mucous clearance ix. congenital heart disease x. pulmonary hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria, outpatient asthmatics:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age between 4 and 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria, outpatient asthmatics:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous admission to the hospital for a near fatal asthma exacerbation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existing chronic disease (other than asthma) including i. bronchopulmonary&#xD;
             dysplasia ii. bronchomalacia iii. tracheomalacia iv. laryngomalacia v. vocal cord&#xD;
             dysfunction vi. chronic restrictive lung disease vii. recurrent aspiration pneumonia&#xD;
             viii. impaired mucous clearance ix. congenital heart disease x. pulmonary hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria, healthy controls:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Age between 4 and 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria, healthy controls:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Pre-existing chronic disease including: i. asthma ii. bronchopulmonary dysplasia iii.&#xD;
        bronchomalacia iv. tracheomalacia v. laryngomalacia vi. vocal cord dysfunction vii. chronic&#xD;
        restrictive lung disease viii. recurrent aspiration pneumonia ix. impaired mucous clearance&#xD;
        x. congenital heart disease xi. pulmonary hypertension&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christopher L Carroll, MD, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Connecticut Children's Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Connecticut Children's Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hartford</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06103</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 10, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Connecticut Children's Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Christopher Carroll, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Pediatrics</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pediatric</keyword>
  <keyword>Polymorphism, Genetic</keyword>
  <keyword>Adrenergic beta-Agonists</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

