<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04785794</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FLUGEN-H3N2-V005</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>DMID 20-0025</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04785794</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Immunogenicity of the Sing2016 M2SR H3N2 Monovalent Influenza Vaccine in Adults Ages 50 to 85 Years Old</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 1b Clinical Study to Investigate the Safety and Immunogenicity of the Sing2016 (A/Singapore/INFIMH-16-0019/2016) M2SR H3N2 Monovalent Influenza Vaccine in Adults Ages 50 to 85 Years Old.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>FluGen Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>FluGen Inc</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled Phase 1b study to evaluate safety and&#xD;
      immunogenicity of the investigational Sing2016 M2SR H3N2 influenza vaccine delivered&#xD;
      intranasally to a healthy adult population age 50 to 85 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled Phase 1b study to evaluate safety and&#xD;
      immunogenicity of the investigational Sing2016 M2SR H3N2 influenza vaccine delivered&#xD;
      intranasally to a healthy adult population age 50 to 85 years. Eligible subjects will be&#xD;
      randomized 2:1 to receive one administration of Sing2016 M2SR or placebo followed by a dose&#xD;
      of age-appropriate licensed inactivated influenza vaccine (IIV) at least 28 days later. Two&#xD;
      lead-in groups of adults ages 50-64 years (Cohort 1) and 65 - 85 years (Cohort 2) will be&#xD;
      followed by enrollment of an expansion group, ages 65 - 85 (Cohort 3). Safety data will be&#xD;
      reviewed between enrollment of successive cohorts.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Three Cohorts will be enrolled sequentially with safety data reviewed between enrollment of successive cohorts.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Solicited AEs during 7 days after experimental treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 8</time_frame>
    <description>The number and percentage of study participants who experience solicited local and systemic reactions during the 7 days after administration of investigational M2SR vaccine or placebo</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Unsolicited AEs during 28 days after experimental treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 29</time_frame>
    <description>The number and percentage of study participants who experience unsolicited AE during the 28 days after administration of investigational M2SR vaccine or placebo</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SAEs through 28 days after licensed IIV treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 29 post-IIV</time_frame>
    <description>The number and percentage of study participants who experience SAEs from the time of study entry through 28 days after receipt of IIV</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Influenza Vaccine</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>M2SR dose, 50-64 years of age</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intranasal M2SR vaccine followed by standard, licensed IIV</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo dose, 50-64 years of age</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intranasal physiological saline followed by standard, licensed IIV</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>M2SR dose, 65-85 years of age</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intranasal M2SR vaccine followed by licensed IIV recommended for people 65 years and older</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo dose, 65-85 years of age</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intranasal physiological saline followed by licensed IIV recommended for people 65 years and older</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sing2016 M2SR H3N2 influenza vaccine</intervention_name>
    <description>This group will receive a dose of the Sing2016 M2SR H3N2 monovalent influenza vaccine administered intranasally on Day 1 followed by IIV at least 28 days later.</description>
    <arm_group_label>M2SR dose, 50-64 years of age</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>M2SR dose, 65-85 years of age</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>This group will receive saline placebo administered intranasally on Day 1 followed by IIV at least 28 days later.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo dose, 50-64 years of age</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo dose, 65-85 years of age</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects must be willing and able to provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Cohort 1: age 50-64 years at time of enrollment; Cohorts 2 and 3: age 65 to 85 years&#xD;
             at time of enrollment (signing of informed consent form).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject willing to adhere to the requirements of the study and willing and able to&#xD;
             communicate with the Investigator and understand the requirements of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Healthy adults and those with stable chronic conditions as determined by medical&#xD;
             history, physical examination, vital signs, clinical safety laboratory examinations&#xD;
             and clinical judgment of the investigator to be eligible for study inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Women of child-bearing potential must agree to abstain from sexual intercourse or to&#xD;
             correctly use an acceptable method of contraception from 30 days prior to vaccination&#xD;
             until 30 days after the last study vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative urine pregnancy test within 24&#xD;
             hours prior to vaccination with investigational product.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any acute or chronic physical or mental condition that would limit the subject's&#xD;
             ability to complete the study, increase risk of study participation or participant, or&#xD;
             may interfere with interpretation of study results as based on the assessment by the&#xD;
             Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Acute or chronic medical condition or history of a medical condition that, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the Investigator, would render the study procedures unsafe or would&#xD;
             interfere with the evaluation of the responses.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Abnormal screening hematology or chemistry value per the FDA Guidance: Toxicity&#xD;
             Grading Scale for Healthy Adult and Adolescent Volunteers Enrolled in Preventative&#xD;
             Vaccine Clinical Trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Currently receiving, or planned to receive during the study, any immunosuppressive&#xD;
             therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Had a flu-like illness, influenza treatment, influenza vaccination, or prophylactic&#xD;
             influenza viral drug administered in the previous 6 months before investigational&#xD;
             product administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Females who are pregnant or nursing; non-vasectomized males, with female partners of&#xD;
             child-bearing potential, who are unwilling to use a highly effective form of&#xD;
             contraception from the time of enrollment through at least 28 after administration of&#xD;
             the investigational product.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of receipt of any investigational vaccine within 28 days of visit 1 or&#xD;
             investigational drug within the past six months. An exception is made for receipt of a&#xD;
             Covid-19 vaccine whether licensed or under emergency use authorization (EUA) as long&#xD;
             as the second dose was given at least 28 days prior to dosing with investigational&#xD;
             vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Acute febrile illness within 72 hours prior to investigational product vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Receipt of blood/plasma products or immunoglobulin within 6 months before&#xD;
             administration of the investigational product or planned for during the period of&#xD;
             study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Planned donation of blood or blood product of at least approximately 1 pint within 3&#xD;
             months after investigational product administration.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pamuk Bilsel</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>FluGen Inc</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Pamuk Bilsel</last_name>
    <phone>6084426562</phone>
    <email>pbilsel@flugen.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Anaheim Clinical Trials</name>
      <address>
        <city>Anaheim</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92801</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Karol Keller</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Accel Clinical</name>
      <address>
        <city>DeLand</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32127</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Crystal Paccione</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johnson County Clin Trials</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lenexa</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66219</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mazen Zari</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 3, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 3, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

