<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04789161</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IMAEETH-2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04789161</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of Double-kissing Crush and Double-kissing Culotte Stenting</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison of Double-kissing Crush and Double-kissing Culotte Stenting in Patients With True Bifurcation Lesion</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istanbul Mehmet Akif Ersoy Educational and Training Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istanbul Mehmet Akif Ersoy Educational and Training Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      True bifurcation lesions (TBLs) are not rare clinical conditions and may be associated with&#xD;
      adverse cardiovascular outcomes due to their complex anatomy and the variety of&#xD;
      interventional therapy. Although the provisional stenting is still effective in suitable&#xD;
      lesions, double stent techniques can be required in selected patients. In previous studies,&#xD;
      double kissing crush (DK-crush) stenting was revealed as superior to provisional stenting in&#xD;
      TBL of left main coronary artery. Additionally, in recent studies, double kissing approach&#xD;
      facilitates and highlights double kissing culotte (DK-culotte) stenting with lower stent&#xD;
      malapposition compared to DK-crush stenting. However, to the best of our knowledge, there is&#xD;
      no study about comparing DK-crush and DK-culotte stenting in TBLs. Our aim in this study is&#xD;
      to compare DK-crush and DK-culotte stenting in patients with TBL.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 4, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 4, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 4, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>12 Months</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>MACE (major adverse cardiovascular events)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>target vessel revascularization, myocardial infarction and cardiac death</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MACCEs (major adverse cerebral and cardiovascular events)</measure>
    <time_frame>12, 24, 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>all cause death, myocardial infarction, target lesion revascularization, target lesion revascularization, in-stent thrombosis and/or restenosis, stroke</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>target lesion failure</measure>
    <time_frame>24, 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>myocardial infarction, cardiac death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>contrast induced nephropathy</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>25 percent (%) increase in serum creatinine level from baseline or a 0.5 mg/dL increase in absolute serum creatinine value within 72 hours after percutaneous coronary intervention</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronary Artery Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>double kissing crush stenting</arm_group_label>
    <description>patients with true bifurcation lesion undergoing double kissing crush stenting</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>double kissing culotte stenting</arm_group_label>
    <description>patients with true bifurcation lesion undergoing double kissing culotte stenting</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>double kissing crush stenting</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients with true bifurcation lesion treating with double kissing crsuh stenting technique</description>
    <arm_group_label>double kissing crush stenting</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>double kissing culotte stenting</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients with true bifurcation lesion treating with double kissing culotte stenting technique</description>
    <arm_group_label>double kissing culotte stenting</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with stable or unstable angina pectoris or patients with non-ST segment elevation&#xD;
        myocardial infarction undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention and performing double&#xD;
        stent techniques (DK-crush or DK-culotte) are included in this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with de novo true bifurcation lesion (Medina classification 1,1,1 or 0,1,1 or&#xD;
             1,0,1)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The main vessel diameter is least 2.5 mm and the side branch diameter is at least 2.25&#xD;
             mm&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients presenting with ST segment elevation myocardial infarction, cardiogenic shock&#xD;
             and Killip class III-IV heart failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of coronary artery bypass grafting surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a chronic total occlusion in the bifurcation area&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lesions with severe calcification that needs additional intervention such as&#xD;
             atherectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are not suitable to use long term dual antiplatelet therapy and patients&#xD;
             not participating in clinical follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with hematological disorders, malignancy, end stage renal (GFR&lt;30 ml/min) and&#xD;
             hepatic failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active bleeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with life-expectancy &lt; 1 year&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Serkan Kahraman, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+905053825921</phone>
    <email>serkankahraman_86@outlook.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istanbul Mehmet Akif Ersoy Training and Research Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <zip>34303</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Serkan Kahraman, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+905053825921</phone>
      <email>serkankahraman_86@outlook.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Serkan Kahraman, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mehmet Erturk, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Steigen TK, Maeng M, Wiseth R, Erglis A, Kumsars I, Narbute I, Gunnes P, Mannsverk J, Meyerdierks O, Rotevatn S, Niemelä M, Kervinen K, Jensen JS, Galløe A, Nikus K, Vikman S, Ravkilde J, James S, Aarøe J, Ylitalo A, Helqvist S, Sjögren I, Thayssen P, Virtanen K, Puhakka M, Airaksinen J, Lassen JF, Thuesen L; Nordic PCI Study Group. Randomized study on simple versus complex stenting of coronary artery bifurcation lesions: the Nordic bifurcation study. Circulation. 2006 Oct 31;114(18):1955-61. Epub 2006 Oct 23.</citation>
    <PMID>17060387</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Colombo A, Bramucci E, Saccà S, Violini R, Lettieri C, Zanini R, Sheiban I, Paloscia L, Grube E, Schofer J, Bolognese L, Orlandi M, Niccoli G, Latib A, Airoldi F. Randomized study of the crush technique versus provisional side-branch stenting in true coronary bifurcations: the CACTUS (Coronary Bifurcations: Application of the Crushing Technique Using Sirolimus-Eluting Stents) Study. Circulation. 2009 Jan 6;119(1):71-8. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.108.808402. Epub 2008 Dec 22.</citation>
    <PMID>19103990</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hildick-Smith D, de Belder AJ, Cooter N, Curzen NP, Clayton TC, Oldroyd KG, Bennett L, Holmberg S, Cotton JM, Glennon PE, Thomas MR, Maccarthy PA, Baumbach A, Mulvihill NT, Henderson RA, Redwood SR, Starkey IR, Stables RH. Randomized trial of simple versus complex drug-eluting stenting for bifurcation lesions: the British Bifurcation Coronary Study: old, new, and evolving strategies. Circulation. 2010 Mar 16;121(10):1235-43. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.109.888297. Epub 2010 Mar 1.</citation>
    <PMID>20194880</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chen SL, Zhang JJ, Han Y, Kan J, Chen L, Qiu C, Jiang T, Tao L, Zeng H, Li L, Xia Y, Gao C, Santoso T, Paiboon C, Wang Y, Kwan TW, Ye F, Tian N, Liu Z, Lin S, Lu C, Wen S, Hong L, Zhang Q, Sheiban I, Xu Y, Wang L, Rab TS, Li Z, Cheng G, Cui L, Leon MB, Stone GW. Double Kissing Crush Versus Provisional Stenting for Left Main Distal Bifurcation Lesions: DKCRUSH-V Randomized Trial. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2017 Nov 28;70(21):2605-2617. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2017.09.1066. Epub 2017 Oct 30.</citation>
    <PMID>29096915</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Toth GG, Sasi V, Franco D, Prassl AJ, Di Serafino L, Ng JCK, Szanto G, Schneller L, Ang HY, Plank G, Wijns W, Barbato E. Double-kissing culotte technique for coronary bifurcation stenting. EuroIntervention. 2020 Oct 9;16(9):e724-e733. doi: 10.4244/EIJ-D-20-00130.</citation>
    <PMID>32338608</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Istanbul Mehmet Akif Ersoy Educational and Training Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Serkan Kahraman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

