<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04785612</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HVO-CS-005</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04785612</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of RSVpreF Vaccination and RSV Challenge in Healthy Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2a, Randomised, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Study to Evaluate the Safety, Immunogenicity and Efficacy of A Respiratory Syncytial Virus Vaccine (RSVpreF) in A Virus Challenge Model in Healthy Adults</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hvivo</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Pfizer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hvivo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this randomised, placebo-controlled, double-blind Phase 2a study, healthy male and female&#xD;
      participants 18-50 years of age will be given an investigational RSV vaccine (RSVpreF) and&#xD;
      challenged with RSV one month later. The purpose of this research study is to assess the&#xD;
      safety, immunogenicity and efficacy of RSVpreF using a human viral challenge model.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Respiratory Syncytial Virus (RSV) is a common virus that affects all human age groups and can&#xD;
      cause a range of respiratory disease such as bronchitis and lower respiratory infections.&#xD;
      These serious illnesses affect infants and adults who are older especially if they are over&#xD;
      65, have chronic heart or lung disease or have a weakened immune system. Vaccination against&#xD;
      RSV has the potential to be a highly beneficial and effective approach to reduce RSV disease&#xD;
      in older adults and pediatric populations, however there is no current vaccine approved for&#xD;
      the prevention of RSV infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      RSVpreF is being developed to prevent RSV-associated moderate to severe lower respiratory&#xD;
      tract disease in adults 60 years of age and in infants by active immunization of pregnant&#xD;
      women.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is an exploratory proof-of-concept to assess the safety, immunogenicity and&#xD;
      efficacy of RSVpreF using a human challenge model. The RSV challenge model is developed to&#xD;
      help understanding the RSV disease and assess new vaccines by testing them in participants&#xD;
      deliberately infected with the virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, approximately 62 (up to 72) participants will be vaccinated with the&#xD;
      investigational RSVpreF to account for withdrawals between vaccination and challenge.&#xD;
      Participants will be randomised 1:1 to receive RSVpreF or placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will consist of a vaccination phase, quarantine phase and a follow-up phase.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 10, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 16, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 8, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>This is a double blinded, placebo-controlled study</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the viral load-time curve (VL-AUC) of RSV</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>The VL-AUC of RSV determined by qRT-PCR from nasal samples collected twice daily starting two days post-viral challenge (Day +2) up to discharge from quarantine.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>RT-PCR-confirmed symptomatic RSV infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>RT-PCR-confirmed symptomatic RSV infection defined as:&#xD;
Two detectable qRT-PCR reported on 2 or more consecutive days and&#xD;
Either one or more positive clinical symptoms from different categories in the symptom scoring system or one Grade 2 symptom from any category</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sum total symptoms diary card score (TSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>TSS is measured by graded symptom scoring system collected three times daily starting one day post-viral challenge (Day +1) up to discharge from quarantine</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>RT-PCR confirmed incidence of symptomatic infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>RT-PCR confirmed RSV infection defined as&#xD;
Two quantifiable PCR measures reported on 2 or more consecutive days, and&#xD;
Either one or more positive clinical symptoms from different categories in the symptom scoring system or one Grade 2 symptom from any category</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Culture lab-confirmed reduction of symptomatic RSV infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Culture lab-confirmed symptomatic RSV infection defined as:&#xD;
One quantifiable viral culture and&#xD;
Either one or more positive clinical symptoms from different categories in the symptom scoring system or one Grade 2 symptom from any category</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak viral load of RSV by qRT-PCR</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Reduction in Peak viral load of RSV determined by quantifiable qRT-PCR from nasal samples collected twice daily starting two days post-viral challenge (Day +2) up to discharge from quarantine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak viral load of RSV by viral culture</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Peak viral load of RSV determined by quantifiable viral culture from nasal samples collected twice daily starting two days post-viral challenge (Day +2) up to discharge from quarantine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of quantifiable qRT-PCR measurements</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Duration (time in hours) of quantifiable qRT-PCR measurements from nasal samples collected twice daily starting two days post-viral challenge (Day +2) up to discharge from quarantine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of quantitative viral culture measurements</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Duration (time in hours) of quantitative viral culture measurements from nasal samples collected twice daily starting two days post-viral challenge (Day +2) up to discharge from quarantine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>VL-AUC determined by quantitative viral culture</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>VL-AUC of RSV as determined by quantitative viral culture on nasal samples starting two days post-viral challenge (Day +2) up to discharge from quarantine</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the curve over time of total clinical symptoms (TSS-AUC)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>TSS-AUC as measured by graded symptom scoring system collected three times daily starting one day post-viral challenge (Day +1) up to discharge from quarantine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak symptoms diary card score</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Peak TSS as measured by graded symptom scoring system collected three times daily starting one day post-viral challenge (Day +1) up to discharge from quarantine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak daily symptom score</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Individual maximum daily sum of symptom score starting one day post-viral challenge (Day +1) up to the end of quarantine</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage number of participants with Grade 2 or higher symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Number (%) of participants with Grade 2 or higher symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of at least two positive quantifiable qRT-PCR measurements on 2 or more consecutive days</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2 to Day 12</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of at least two positive detectable qRT-PCR measurements on 2 or more consecutive days</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2 to Day 12</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of at least one positive quantitative cell culture measurements on 2 or more consecutive days</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 2 to Day 12</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total mucus weight</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Total weight of mucus produced starting one day post-viral challenge (Day +1) up to discharge from quarantine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total tissue number</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Total number of tissues used by participants starting one day post-viral challenge (Day +1) up to discharge from quarantine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of solicited local reactions within 7 days after vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of systemic events within 7 days after vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of unsolicited adverse events (AEs) post vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of unsolicited adverse events (AEs) within 30 days after vaccination</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of medically attended AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of medically attended AEs from vaccination to study end</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of SAEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of SAEs from vaccination to study end</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of unsolicited AEs related to viral challenge</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0 to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Number of unsolicited AEs within 30 days post-viral challenge (Day 0) up to Day +28 follow up.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of haematological and biochemical laboratory abnormalities during the quarantine period.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -2 to Day12</time_frame>
    <description>Number of Safety Laboratory Assessment Abnormalities reported as AEs</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Use of concomitant medication</measure>
    <time_frame>within 30 days post viral challenge</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">62</enrollment>
  <condition>Respiratory Syncytial Virus Infections</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RSVPreF</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A single intramuscular injection at a dose of 120 mcg reconstituted with sterile water for an 0.5 mL injection volume</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>A single intramuscular injection of Placebo to match active vaccine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>RSVPreF</intervention_name>
    <description>A single dose of 120 mcg RSVpreF for intramuscular injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>RSVPreF</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>A single Placebo dose for intramuscular injection to match experimental vaccine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An informed consent document signed and dated by the participant and the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged between 18 and 50 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In good health with no history, or current evidence, of clinically significant medical&#xD;
             conditions, and no clinically significant test abnormalities that will interfere with&#xD;
             participant safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A documented medical history prior to enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The following criteria are applicable to female participants participating in the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Females of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test prior to&#xD;
                  enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Females of non-childbearing potential:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Post-menopausal females; defined as having a history of amenorrhea for &gt;12 months&#xD;
                  with no alternative medical cause, and /or by FSH level &gt;40mIU/mL, confirmed by&#xD;
                  laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Documented status as being surgically sterile (e.g. tubal ligation, hysterectomy,&#xD;
                  bilateral salpingectomy and bilateral oophorectomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The following criteria apply to female and male participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Female participants of childbearing potential must use one form of highly&#xD;
                  effective contraception. Hormonal methods must be in place from at least 2 weeks&#xD;
                  prior to the first study visit. The contraception use must continue until 28 days&#xD;
                  after the date of viral challenge/last dosing with IMP (whichever occurs last).&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Male participants must agree to the contraceptive requirements below at entry to&#xD;
                  quarantine and continuing until 28 days after the date of Viral challenge / last&#xD;
                  dosing with IMP (whichever occurs last): a. Use a condom with a spermicide to&#xD;
                  prevent pregnancy in a female partner or to prevent exposure of any partner (male&#xD;
                  and female) to the IMP. b. Male sterilisation with the appropriate post vasectomy&#xD;
                  documentation of the absence of sperm in the ejaculate (please note that the use&#xD;
                  of condom with spermicide will still be required to prevent partner exposure).&#xD;
                  This applies only to males participating in the study. c. In addition, for female&#xD;
                  partners of child bearing potential, that partner must use another form of&#xD;
                  contraception such as one of the highly effective methods mentioned above for&#xD;
                  female participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  In addition to the contraceptive requirements above, male participants must agree&#xD;
                  not to donate sperm following discharge from quarantine until 28 days after the&#xD;
                  date of Viral Challenge/last dosing with IMP (whichever occurs last).&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. True abstinence - sexual abstinence is considered a highly effective method only&#xD;
                  if defined as refraining from heterosexual intercourse during the entire period&#xD;
                  of risk associated with the study treatments. The reliability of sexual&#xD;
                  abstinence needs to be evaluated in relation to the duration of the clinical&#xD;
                  trial and the preferred and usual lifestyle of the participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sero-suitable to the challenge virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of, or currently active, symptoms or signs suggestive of upper or lower&#xD;
             respiratory tract infection within 4 weeks prior to the first study visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a) Any history or evidence of any other clinically significant or currently active&#xD;
             systemic comorbidities including psychiatric disorders (includes participants with a&#xD;
             history of depression and/or anxiety).&#xD;
&#xD;
             b) And/or other major disease that, in the opinion of the Investigator, may put the&#xD;
             participant at undue risk, or interfere with a participant completing the study and&#xD;
             necessary investigations (e.g autoimmune disease or immunodeficiency).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have smoked ≥ 10 pack years at any time [10 pack years is equivalent&#xD;
             to one pack of 20 cigarettes a day for 10 years].&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A total body weight ≤ 50 kg and Body Mass Index (BMI) ≤18 kg/m2 and ≥30kg/m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females who:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Are breastfeeding, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Have been pregnant within 6 months prior to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of anaphylaxis-and/or a history of severe allergic reaction or significant&#xD;
             intolerance to any food or drug or vaccine, including hypersensitivity to any of the&#xD;
             constituents of the study vaccine, as assessed by the PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Venous access deemed inadequate for the phlebotomy and cannulation demands of the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a) Any significant abnormality altering the anatomy of the nose in a substantial way&#xD;
             b) Any clinically significant history of epistaxis (large nosebleeds) within the last&#xD;
             3 months c) Any nasal or sinus surgery within 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a) Evidence of vaccinations with licensed live attenuated vaccines within the 4 weeks&#xD;
             prior to the planned date of viral challenge/first dosing with IMP (whichever occurs&#xD;
             first). Evidence of vaccinations with licensed vaccines which are not live attenuated&#xD;
             within the 2 weeks prior to the planned date of viral challenge/first dosing with IMP&#xD;
             (whichever occurs first).&#xD;
&#xD;
             b) Intention to receive any vaccination(s) before at least 28 days after the viral&#xD;
             challenge (NB. No travel restrictions will apply after the Day 28 Follow-up visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of blood or blood products, or loss (including blood donations) of 550 mL or&#xD;
             more of blood during the 2 months prior to the planned date of viral challenge/first&#xD;
             dosing with IMP (whichever occurs first) or planned during the 2 months after the&#xD;
             viral challenge.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a) Receipt of any investigational drug within 3 months prior to the planned date of&#xD;
             viral challenge/first dosing with IMP (whichever occurs first).&#xD;
&#xD;
             b) Previous vaccination with any licensed or investigational RSV vaccine before&#xD;
             enrolment into the study. c) Receipt of three or more investigational drugs within the&#xD;
             previous 12 months prior to the planned date of viral challenge/first dosing with IMP&#xD;
             (whichever occurs first).&#xD;
&#xD;
             d) Prior inoculation with a virus from the same virus-family as the challenge virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
             e) Prior participation in another human viral challenge study with a respiratory virus&#xD;
             in the preceding 3 months, taken from the date of viral challenge in the previous&#xD;
             study to the date of expected viral challenge in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             f) Receipt of treatment with immunosuppressive therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a) Confirmed positive test for drugs of abuse and cotinine on first study visit. One&#xD;
             repeat test allowed at PI discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
             b) History or presence of alcohol addiction, or excessive use of alcohol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A forced expiratory volume in 1 second (FEV1) &lt; 80%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), active hepatitis A (HAV), B (HBV), or C&#xD;
             (HCV) test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those employed or immediate relatives of those employed at hVIVO, Pfizer or any&#xD;
             vendor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other finding that, in the opinion of the Investigator, deems the Participant&#xD;
             unsuitable for the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alex Mann</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Hvivo</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Golam Kabir, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hvivo</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Golam Kabir</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>E1 2AX</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Syncytial Virus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

