<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04787926</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>003</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04787926</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>DuraLock-C Catheter Lock Solution</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Open-Label Study to Evaluate the Safety and Performance of DuraLock-C 4.0%, 30.0%, and 46.7% for the Maintenance of Central Venous Catheter Patency in Adult Hemodialysis Subjects Treated in Clinic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical Components, Inc dba MedComp</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Syneos Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Veeva Systems</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical Components, Inc dba MedComp</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the safety and performance of DuraLock-C 4.0%, 30.0%, and 46.7% for the&#xD;
      maintenance of central venous catheter (CVC) patency in adult hemodialysis (HD) patients&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is a multicenter, open-label, post-market study to evaluate the safety and&#xD;
      performance of DuraLock-C 4.0%, 30.0%, and 46.7% in the maintenance of catheter patency of an&#xD;
      indwelling HD CVC in adult HD patients treated in clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On Day 0, patients to be instilled who meet all of the inclusion criteria and none of the&#xD;
      exclusion criteria will be enrolled in the study to receive 1 of the 3 DuraLock-C solutions.&#xD;
      It is expected that a minimum of 3 sites will enroll patients to the study in order to cover&#xD;
      the 3 solutions to be tested; each site will enroll to 1 unique DuraLock-C solution only,&#xD;
      until the sample size for the solution has been reached.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DuraLock-C 4.0%, 30.0%, or 46.7% solutions will be instilled to lock the catheter as part of&#xD;
      the routine care of the patient. Individual patients will receive the catheter locking&#xD;
      solution (CLS) as a catheter lock post-HD session until catheter dysfunction is observed or&#xD;
      until the end of the study period (Calendar Day 90). The CLSs are commercially available and&#xD;
      will not be provided as part of the study design.&#xD;
&#xD;
      End of Study (EOS) will take place at the patient's next scheduled session.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary Catheter Patency</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Catheter Flow</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CRBSI</measure>
    <time_frame>90 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of catheter-related bloodstream infection (CRBSI) over the course of the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Hemodialysis Catheter Patency</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Duralock-C 4%</arm_group_label>
    <description>DuraLock-C 4.0%: Pouch Contains: (2) 3 mL Syringes w/ 2.5 mL Trisodium Citrate Dihydrate 40 mg/mL Solution Contains: Trisodium Citrate Dihydrate, Citric Acid Anhydrous, Water</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Duralock-C 30%</arm_group_label>
    <description>DuraLock-C 30.0%: Pouch Contains: (2) 3 mL Syringes w/ 2.5 mL Trisodium Citrate Dihydrate 300 mg/mL Solution Contains: Trisodium Citrate Dihydrate, Citric Acid Anhydrous, Water</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Duralock-C 46.7%</arm_group_label>
    <description>DuraLock-C 46.7%: Pouch Contains: (2) 3 mL Syringes w/ 2.5 mL Trisodium Citrate Dihydrate 467 mg/mL Solution Contains: Trisodium Citrate Dihydrate, Citric Acid Anhydrous, Water</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Locking Solution</intervention_name>
    <description>The total duration of the study treatment period will be 90 calendar days, from Visit 1 Pre-Instillation to the last study-related assessment. Two to 3 instillations (1 per lumen per visit) of DuraLock-C 4.0%, 30.0%, or 46.7% (equivalent to the catheter manufacturer's prescribed priming volume) will be instilled 1 to 3 days apart (with a HD schedule of 3 to 4 times per week); each instillation of CLS will remain in the CVC for approximately 24 to 72 hours ± 12 hours, based on their practice preferences. EOS will take place at the patient's next scheduled dialysis session.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Duralock-C 30%</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Duralock-C 4%</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Duralock-C 46.7%</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients who are undergoing hemodialysis (HD) via a central venous cathter (CVC).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males and non-pregnant females will be eligible for study entry provided that all&#xD;
             inclusion/exclusion criteria are satisfied.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients must fulfill all of the following inclusion criteria to be eligible for&#xD;
        participation in the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Able to give informed consent after an explanation of the proposed study, and who are&#xD;
             willing to comply with the study requirements for therapy during the entire study&#xD;
             treatment period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients undergoing HD 3 or 4 times per week in clinic (expected to continue for the&#xD;
             length of the study) with an established or newly placed non-tunneled or tunneled HD&#xD;
             CVC as primary vascular access.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Adult male or female patients, aged ≥18 years at the time of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Clinically stable as judged by the treating physician and as demonstrated by stable&#xD;
             medical history for 30 days prior to enrollment, physical examination, and laboratory&#xD;
             testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Expected to survive for the next 6 months and the patient is likely to require the use&#xD;
             of a CVC for at least 90 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Females of childbearing potential must have a negative serum human chorionic&#xD;
             gonadotropin (hCG) pregnancy test at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Patients with an arteriovenous fistula or arteriovenous graft in use at the time of&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Patients with a history of thromboembolic disease. 3. Patients with a history of HD&#xD;
             catheter dysfunction due to thrombosis or a blood pump speed rate &lt;300 mL/min during&#xD;
             HD in the past 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Patients with uncontrolled abnormal coagulation parameters and are at additional&#xD;
             risk for clotting or excessive bleeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. Patients who received antibiotics within the last 14 days. 6. Have had an acute&#xD;
             infection ≤ 30 days prior to enrollment. 7. Known allergy to heparin, including HIT.&#xD;
             8. Patients who received thrombolytic treatment (ie, tissue plasminogen activator&#xD;
             [tPA]) within 4 weeks of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
             9. Patients using any type of antimicrobial-coated or heparin-coated catheter. 10.&#xD;
             Have a positive serology test for human immunodeficiency virus or hepatitis infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
             11. Current requirement for systemic immunosuppression that would increase risk of&#xD;
             infection or any form of immunosuppressive disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
             12. Patient is currently taking another medication with known systemic drug&#xD;
             interaction with citrate or heparin.&#xD;
&#xD;
             13. Patient is anticipated to receive a renal transplant within the study period&#xD;
             should be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
             14. Patients with known or suspected liver failure. 15. Are female and pregnant,&#xD;
             lactating, or planning to become pregnant during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
             16. Are currently participating in another interventional clinical study or has&#xD;
             participated in another interventional clinical study in the past 3 months or previous&#xD;
             enrollment in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             17. Patient has a condition the investigator believes would interfere with the ability&#xD;
             to provide informed consent or comply with study instructions, or that might confound&#xD;
             the interpretation of the study results or put the patient at undue risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
             18. Patient has an active malignancy of any type, or has been diagnosed with cancer&#xD;
             within 5 years prior to screening (excluding squamous or basal cell carcinoma of the&#xD;
             skin).&#xD;
&#xD;
             19. Patient has a known allergy or history of significant adverse reaction to&#xD;
             trisodium citrate or related compounds or to any of the excipients (citric acid).&#xD;
&#xD;
             20. Any clinically significant abnormal laboratory test results found during medical&#xD;
             screening, as determined by the investigator. NOTE: A test value above or below the&#xD;
             normal range does not necessarily indicate that the value is &quot;clinically significant.&quot;&#xD;
             The determination should be made by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
             21. Have a history of noncompliance with HD as assessed by an investigator. 22. Have&#xD;
             had a major cardiovascular or cerebrovascular event within 3 months of study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
             23. Are scheduled for living-donor transplantation within the study period, plan to&#xD;
             change to peritoneal dialysis (PD) therapy within the study period, plan to change to&#xD;
             a home HD treatment, or plan to relocate to an area where no study center is located.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Publication undecided</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

