<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04789239</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ESR-19-20262</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04789239</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>OPtimizing Aldosterone Receptor Antagonist Therapy by Sodium Zirconium Cyclosilicate in Heart Failure</brief_title>
  <acronym>OPRA-HF</acronym>
  <official_title>OPtimizing Aldosterone Receptor Antagonist Therapy by Sodium Zirconium Cyclosilicate in Heart Failure - Efficacy and Safety of Sodium Zirconium Cyclosilicate in Optimizing Mineralocorticoid Receptor Antagonists Therapy in Heart Failure</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Michael Fu</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Göteborg University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Sweden</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Mineralocorticoid receptor antagonists (MRA) is one of cornerstones in the treatment of heart&#xD;
      failure with reduced ejection fraction (HFrEF). However, MRA has been extremely under-used&#xD;
      globally. The main reason for this seems to be increased risk of hyperkalemia in individuals&#xD;
      on MRA. Theoretically, by limiting the risk of hyperkalemia it could thus be possible to&#xD;
      optimize MRA therapy. This is studied in this randomized controlled trial in which it is&#xD;
      investigated whethere adding a potassium-binder in combination with MRA treatment prevent&#xD;
      hyperkalemia to a greater extent than only using MRA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The specific aim of this study is to demonstrate the efficacy and safety of Sodium Zirconium&#xD;
      Cyclosilicate (SZC) in optimizing MRA in symptomatic patients with HFrEF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A multicenter, randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blinded study in Sweden (n=230)&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study consists of 2 phases: 1) open-label run-in within maximum 2 months, where all are&#xD;
      treated with SZC to test tolarability, and 2) a 1:1 randomized, double-blinded and&#xD;
      placebo-controlled treatment during 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The open-label phase, in turn, consists of three periods: run-in (1 - 2 weeks), correc-tion&#xD;
      (maximum 72 hours) and maintenance (at least 4 weeks)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sodium Zirconium Cyclosilicate (SZC) (Lokelma)®, 5 g, 10 g, orally, is an approved drug in&#xD;
      Sweden. For correction of hyperkalemia, the recommended starting dose is 10 g, three times&#xD;
      daily. Once normokalemia has been achieved, the maintenance reg-imen should be started with 5&#xD;
      g once daily. The dose can be titrated up to 10 g once daily or lowered to 5 g once every&#xD;
      other day as needed, to maintain a normal level of potassium.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To demonstrate the efficacy of Sodium Zirconium Cyclosilicate (SZC) on optimiz-ing MRA in&#xD;
      HFrEF, SZC vs Placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Outcome Measure:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Whether a patient maintains MRA at a dose ≥ 25 mg daily and S-K level in the normal range&#xD;
      (3.5-5.0 mmol/L) at the end of study, without rescue therapy due to hyperkalemia at any point&#xD;
      during the randomization phase.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A multicenter, 1:1 randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blinded study in Sweden of 230 heart failure patients with reduced ejection fraction.&#xD;
This study consists of 2 phases: 1) open-label run-in within maximum 2 months, and 2) randomized, double-blinded and placebo-controlled treatment during 6 months.&#xD;
The open-label phase, in turn, consists of three periods: run-in (1 - 2 weeks), correction (maximum 72 hours) and maintenance (at least 4 weeks).&#xD;
After the open-label run-in phase, upon randomization (1:1 ratio to receive investigational product (IP), either Sodium Zirconium Cyclosilicate (SZC) or placebo, in a blinded manner), SZC will be switched to investigational drug (IP) but with the same dose individually as for SZC before randomization (pre-randomization dose).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>For the 2nd part of study, ie randomized treatment, it is double-blinded with blinding for subjects, endpoint assessors and study personnel. Pharmacy is responsible for masking of differences in appearance, smell and taste, and also packaging and label-ling to ensure blinding.&#xD;
Individual treatment codes, indicating the treatment randomisation for each random-ised subject, will be available to Pharmacy where the personnel are independent to the study evaluation.&#xD;
The treatment code should not be broken except in medical emergencies when the appropriate management of the subject requires knowledge of the treatment randomisation. The Investigator documents and reports the action to PI, without revealing the treatment given to subject to the PI.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Optimization of MRA usage by Sodium Zirconium Cyclosilicate in HFrEF</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days during randomization phase</time_frame>
    <description>The efficacy will be assessed by difference in the proportion of patients who may or may not maintain MRA at a dose ≥ 25 mg daily and S-K level in the normal range (3.5-5.0 mmol/L) at the end of study, without rescue therapy due to hyperkalemia at any point during the randomization phase.&#xD;
Subjects who require rescue therapy because of hyperkalemia are considered as &quot;failures&quot; even if they will be able to continue in the study.&#xD;
Temporary hyperkalemia secondary to dehydration or other temporary predisposing factors during study as per physician´s judgement should not be regarded as &quot;fail-ure&quot;.&#xD;
A subject with Optimization success MUST meet with 3 criteria:&#xD;
Subjects who are able to maintain MRA at a daily dose ≥ 25 mg in the End of Study&#xD;
AND in the normal range of S-K (3.5-5.0 mmol/L) in the End of Study&#xD;
AND without experiencing rescue therapy due to hyperkalemia at any time throughout the study</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maintainance of MRA-dose by Sodium Zirconium Cyclosilicate</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days during randomization phase</time_frame>
    <description>Measuring whether a patient is able to maintain at least the same MRA dose at the end of study as at the point of randomization without receiving rescue therapy. SZC vs Placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The impact of MRA-optimization on quality of life by Sodium Zirconium Cyclosilicate</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days during randomization phase</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of life is measured by KCCQ (the Kansas City Cardiomyopathy Questionnaire): a change in the clinical summary score ( from 0 to 100) with higher scores indicating fewer symptoms and physical limitations, end of study vs at the point of randomizaiton.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The impact of MRA-optimization on symptomatic relief by Sodium Zirconium Cyclosilicate</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days during randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Symptomatic relief is evaluated by a composite of change either in NYHA or Lickert Scale as prespecified below:&#xD;
change in the NYHA functional classifi-cation (I-IV) with higher class indicating more symptomatic and physical limita-tions, or&#xD;
change in the 5-point Likert scale (5PLS) with higher score indicating the worst possible shortness of breath</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The safety of Sodium Zirconium Cyclosilicate</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days during randomization phase</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in safety between two groups is assessed by percent of occurrence of any following prespecified safety endpoints (during the randomization phase):&#xD;
Patient with S-K &lt;3.0 mmol/l (yes/no)&#xD;
Patient with S-K ≥6.0 mmol/l (yes/no)&#xD;
Patient in need of rescue therapy be-cause of hyperkalemia (yes/no)&#xD;
Patient with fluid retention (general edema, peripheral edema, unrelated to heart failure) (yes/no)&#xD;
Patient with gastrointestinal events such as constipation, diarrhea, abdominal pain, nausea or vomiting) (yes/no)&#xD;
Patient with any AE, SAE or DAE (yes/no)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">230</enrollment>
  <condition>Heart Failure</condition>
  <condition>Hyperkalemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SZC + MRA treated heart failure patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Optimal dose of SZC, which is an approved drug for hyperkalemia in Sweden.&#xD;
The subject is treat with 5 mg daily however it can be reduced to once every second day, or inreased to as much as as 10 mg daily, depending on measured potassium levels. This is combined with a mineralcorticoid receptor antagonist (spironolacton or eplerenon), 25 mg or 50 mg depending on what dose they could tolerate.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo + MRA treated heart failure patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The subject is treat with placebo drug, 5 mg once daily, however it can be reduced to once every second day, or increased to as much as as 10 mg daily, depending on measured potassium levels. This is combined with the dose of mineralcorticoid receptor antagonist (spironolacton or eplerenon) 25 mg or 50 mg depending on what dose they could tolerate.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sodium zirconium cyclosilicate</intervention_name>
    <description>SZC is an approved drug in Sweden and subsidized for patients with chronic kidney disease in stages 3 to 5, with or without chronic heart failure, for whom treatment with Resonium is not suitable and for patients with chronic heart failure without con-comitant chronic kidney disease</description>
    <arm_group_label>SZC + MRA treated heart failure patients</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lokelma</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Treatment with the same dose of placebo medicine as they would have received had they been treated with the interventional drug (SZC).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo + MRA treated heart failure patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Recruiting will take place mainly from specialist care at University hospitals or Province&#xD;
        hospitals in Sweden. But some of patients might have simultaneous follow-up at primary care&#xD;
        as well.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Each subject should meet all of the inclusion criteria and none of the exclusion criteria&#xD;
        for this study. Under no circumstances can there be exceptions to this rule.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        For inclusion in the study subjects should fulfil the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Obtain signed informed consent prior to any study specific procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. &gt;18 yrs, irrespective of sex&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. LVEF ≤ 40%, with echocardiography within last 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. NYHA II-IV&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Stable heart failure as judged by local Investigator. Patients may be en-rolled as an&#xD;
             outpatient or in-hospital at, or close to, the time of hospital dis-charge&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. On optimal treatment with GDMT (Guideline-Directed Medical Treatment including&#xD;
             ACE/ARB/ARNI and beta blockers) as per physician´s judgement&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. AND one of followings:&#xD;
&#xD;
        (1) Prior hyperkalemia due to MRA therapy and current S-K ≤ 5.0 mmol/L; (2) Risk of&#xD;
        hyperkalemia as indicated by eGFR 30-45 ml/min/1.73m2 and S-K 4.5-5.0 mmol/L; (3) Mild&#xD;
        hyperkalemia (S-K 5.1-5.5 mmol/L) and MRA below target dose (target doses for&#xD;
        spironolactone: 25-50 mg daily, and for eplerenone: 50 mg daily)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Depending on the S-K status during screening, patients are divided into two groups before&#xD;
        treatment initiation /run-in:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Group 1: Patients who are hyperkalemic (S-K 5.1 - 5.5 mmol/L measured within last 2&#xD;
             weeks)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Group 2: Patients who are normokalemic (S-K 3.5 - 5.0 mmol/L) during screening but are&#xD;
             at a high risk of developing hyperkalemia associated with MRA initiation / increase.&#xD;
             Namely, one (or both) of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prescription of MRA within last 12 months and documented hyperkalemia after MRA&#xD;
                  prescription&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  S-K 4.5-5.0 mmol/L and GFR &lt; 45 mL/min/1,73 m2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: All S-K related limits in this protocol concern serum measurements. In Sweden it is&#xD;
        plasma that is analyzed, which makes 4.8 mmol/l (plasma) equivalent to 5.0 mmol/L(serum)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects should not enter the study if any of the following exclusion criteria are&#xD;
        ful-filled:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Symptomatic hypotension (&lt; 90/60 mmHg)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. eGFR &lt; 30 ml/min/1,73 m2 (modified MDRD formula)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. HF due to restrictive cardiomyopathy, hypertrophic (obstructive) cardio-myopathy or&#xD;
             primary valvular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Current/recent (within 3 months) hospitalization due to myocardial infarc-tion,&#xD;
             unstable angina pectoris, coronary revascularization (percutaneous coronary&#xD;
             intervention or coronary artery bypass grafting), or other interven-tions (valvular&#xD;
             repair/replacement, cardiac transplantation or implantation of a ventricular&#xD;
             assistance device)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Ongoing or planned dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Prior history of hypersensitivity (other than hyperkalemia) to a MRA, or SZC&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Advanced malignancy requiring treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of QT prolongation associated with other medications that required&#xD;
             discontinuation of that medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Congenital long QT syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Symptomatic or uncontrolled atrial fibrillation despite treatment, or asymp-tomatic&#xD;
             sustained ventricular tachycardia. Subjects with atrial fibrillation controlled by&#xD;
             medication are permitted&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. QTc(f) &gt; 550 msec&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Currently pregnant (confirmed with positive pregnancy test) or planned pregnancy or&#xD;
             breast-feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Can not sign informed consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael Fu, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Sweden</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Michael Fu, Professor</last_name>
    <phone>0046313421000</phone>
    <phone_ext>34850</phone_ext>
    <email>michael.fu@gu.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Erik Thunström, asso. prof</last_name>
    <phone>0046313421000</phone>
    <email>erik.thunstrom@vgregion.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sahlgrenska University Hospital-Ostra Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gothenburg</city>
        <zip>41650</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michael LX Fu, MD</last_name>
      <phone>0046313421000</phone>
      <phone_ext>34850</phone_ext>
      <email>michael.fu@gu.se</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Erik Thunström, MD</last_name>
      <phone>0046313421000</phone>
      <email>erik.thunstrom@vgregion.se</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Carmen Basic, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Erik Thunström, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Sweden</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michael Fu</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor, MD, PhD, FESC</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Mineralocorticoid receptor antagonists</keyword>
  <keyword>Sodium Zirconium Cyclosilicate (SZC)</keyword>
  <keyword>Heart failure with reduced ejection fraction</keyword>
  <keyword>Treatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hyperkalemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Qualified researchers can request access to anonymized individual patient-level data with approved ethical permission. All requests will be evaluated but this does not mean all requests will be shared.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>We will share the study protocol once a manuscript relating to results of the trial is published in a peer-reviewed medical journal.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Researchers that ask for access to the study information, were the intention is to evaluate the study and were the anonymity of the study participants is not jeopardized will all be considered for access.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

