<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04146467</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>VP-1902</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04146467</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Renuvion APR Device to Improve the Appearance of Lax Tissue in the Neck and Submental Region</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Multi-Center, Evaluator-Blinded Study Evaluating the Safety and Effectiveness of the Renuvion APR Device to Improve the Appearance of Lax Tissue in the Neck and Submental Region</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Apyx Medical</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Apyx Medical</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, multi-center, multi-phase, evaluator-blinded study of subjects&#xD;
      undergoing a procedure with the Renuvion APR Device to improve the appearance of lax tissue&#xD;
      in the neck and submental region.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, multi-center, multi-phase, evaluator-blinded study of subjects&#xD;
      undergoing a procedure to improve the appearance of lax tissue in the neck and submental&#xD;
      region. All study subjects will be treated with the Renuvion APR Device.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase I (n=17) of this study will be conducted primarily to provide safety data, however,&#xD;
      effectiveness data will also be collected at the above stated timepoints through 6 months&#xD;
      post-procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase II (n=65) of this study is the expansion of the study to a pivotal study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 26, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Independent Photographic Review</measure>
    <time_frame>180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement in the appearance of lax tissue in the neck and submental region at 6 months as determined by qualitative 2D photography assessment by blinded Independent Photographic Reviewers.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Subject reported pain through Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Through the 7-day visit</time_frame>
    <description>Level of pain and discomfort after treatment as reported by the subject on a 11-point Numeric Rating Scale where 0 is &quot;No Pain&quot; and 10 is &quot;Worst Possible Pain&quot;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Independent Photographic Review</measure>
    <time_frame>90-days</time_frame>
    <description>Change in the appearance of lax tissue in the neck and submental region at 90-days as determined by qualitative 2D photography assessment by blinded Independent Photographic Reviewers.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subject Modified Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale (GAIS)</measure>
    <time_frame>90-days &amp; 180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Subject Modified Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale (GAIS): Very Much Improved, Much Improved, Improved, No Change, Worse, Much Worse, Very Much Worse</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Investigator Modified GAIS</measure>
    <time_frame>90-days &amp; 180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Investigator Modified GAIS:Very Much Improved, Much Improved, Improved, No Change, Worse, Much Worse, Very Much Worse</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subject Satisfaction Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Three YES or NO questions pertaining to satisfaction with study treatment. One question rating overall satisfaction from 1 - 10 (1 is the worst, 10 is the best)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantitative improvement in overall lift of the neck and submental area</measure>
    <time_frame>180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Quantitative improvement in overall lift of the neck and submental area as determine by quantitative assessment based on 2D photography. Fixed landmarks on the subject's face will be used.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantitative improvement in submental volume</measure>
    <time_frame>180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Quantitative improvement in submental volume at 180 days as determined by quantitative assessment based on 3D photography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of Adverse Events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subject reported pain through Day 30</measure>
    <time_frame>Through Day 30</time_frame>
    <description>The evaluation of pain scores through the 30-day follow-up visit as reported by the subject on a 11-point Numeric Rating Scale (NRS) where 0 is &quot;No Pain&quot; and 10 is &quot;Worst Possible Pain&quot;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">82</enrollment>
  <condition>Lax Skin</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be treated with the Renuvion APR device.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Renuvion APR Device</intervention_name>
    <description>The Renuvion APR Handpiece is a sterile, single use electrosurgical (monopolar) device intended to be used in conjunction with compatible generators for the percutaneous delivery of radiofrequency energy and/or helium plasma for cutting, coagulation and ablation of soft tissue. Radiofrequency energy is delivered to the handpiece by the generator and used to energize the electrode. When helium gas is passed over the energized electrode, a helium plasma is generated for soft tissue cutting, coagulation or ablation. The Renuvion APR Handpiece has a non-extendable electrode to generate helium plasma.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female subjects 35-65 years of age (inclusive).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Healthy as determined by the investigator examining the subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Seeking improvement of the appearance of lax tissue in the neck and submental region.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Females of childbearing potential who are sexually active must be willing to use an&#xD;
             approved method of birth control during study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willing and able to comply with protocol requirements, including obtaining&#xD;
             study-required images/photos and assessments, and returning for follow-up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Willing to release rights for the use of study photos, including in potential&#xD;
             publication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Understands and accepts the obligation not to have significant weight loss or weight&#xD;
             gain (≥8 pounds) post the treatment, and for the duration of participation in the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Willing to abstain from the use of blood thinners (including, but not limited to,&#xD;
             Coumadin, NSAIDS, Ibuprofen, vitamin K, other) for 2 weeks (14 days) prior to the&#xD;
             procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Willing to abstain from smoking, vaping, or the use of e-cigarettes for 1 year prior&#xD;
             to and for the entire duration of participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Willing to abstain from the use of marijuana for 2 weeks prior to and for the duration&#xD;
             of participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Able to read, understand, sign and date the informed consent document (English only).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pregnancy within 12 months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Use within 24 hours preceding surgery of ibuprofen, acetaminophen, any other&#xD;
             analgesics, anti-inflammatory products, or any products including herbals and&#xD;
             supplements that could interfere with the clinical assessments of this study (other&#xD;
             than drugs used for anesthesia).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Allergy to tumescent anesthetic (lidocaine/epinephrine).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Excessive subcutaneous fat in the treatment area (as determined by the treating&#xD;
             investigator).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Active systemic or local skin disease that may alter wound healing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Significant or uncontrolled medical condition that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator, participation in the study may compromise the patient's health.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Severe solar elastosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of autoimmune disease (excluding Hashimoto's thyroiditis).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Known hypersensitivity or adverse reaction to anesthetics.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Known susceptibility to keloid formation or hypertrophic scarring.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Cancerous or pre-cancerous lesions in the area to be treated.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. History or current diagnosis of cancer of any type (excluding skin cancer).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. History of uncontrolled cardiovascular disease (i.e. myocardial infarction,&#xD;
             hypertension, hypercholesterolemia, peripheral vascular disease, other).&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. History, or current bleeding disorders (i.e. hemophilia or von Willebrand disease), or&#xD;
             anticipated treatment with prescription anticoagulants.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Possesses a surgically implanted electronic device (i.e. pacemaker).&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. History of AIDs/HIV.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Serious mental health illness such as dementia or schizophrenia; psychiatric&#xD;
             hospitalization in the past two years.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Chronic hypoxia or dependence on supplemental oxygen.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Participation in any other investigational study within 30 days prior to consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Any surgical or transdermal neck/submental aesthetic procedures or plans to undergo&#xD;
             any other aesthetic procedure during study participation. Such procedures include, but&#xD;
             are not limited to, submentoplasty, liposuction, ultrasound, cryolipolysis,&#xD;
             radiofrequency, and laser.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. History of or current injury to the head and neck or any area of the body being&#xD;
             treated as a part of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Presence of more than mild platysmal banding as per the Geister, et al Validated&#xD;
             Assessment Scale for Platysmal Bands.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Subject requiring removal of adipose tissue prior index procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. A family member of the investigator or sponsor; an employee of the investigator or&#xD;
             sponsor.&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Subject who, in the opinion of the investigator, is not an appropriate candidate for&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Paul G Ruff IV, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>West End Plastic Surgery</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Faces+ Plastic Surgery</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92121</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jason Emer MD</name>
      <address>
        <city>West Hollywood</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90069</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>West End Plastic Surgery</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20037</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>New Jersey Clinical Research Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montclair</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07042</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Luxurgery</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10021</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>H/K/B Cosmetic Surgery</name>
      <address>
        <city>Huntersville</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28078</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Facial Plastic &amp; Aesthetic Laser Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Youngstown</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44512</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 29, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 29, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 31, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Submental, Neck</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cutis Laxa</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

