<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04147819</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19829</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2019-001741-40</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04147819</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A First in Human Study of BAY2701439 to Look at Safety, How the Body Absorbs, Distributes and Excretes the Drug, and How Well the Drug Works in Participants With Advanced Cancer Expressing the HER2 Protein</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1 Open-label, First-in-human, Multi-center Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics and Anti-tumor Activity of Thorium-227 Labeled Antibody-chelator Conjugate BAY2701439, in Participants With Advanced HER2-expressing Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bayer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bayer</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this study, researchers want to learn about the safety of drug BAY2701439 and how well the&#xD;
      drug works in patients with advanced cancer that has the protein HER2 (Human Epidermal growth&#xD;
      factor Receptor 2) and cannot be cured by currently available treatment options. The study&#xD;
      will include patients with HER2 expressing breast, gastric (stomach) or gastroesophageal&#xD;
      (stomach and esophagus) cancer, as well as other cancers that have HER2. Researchers want to&#xD;
      find the best dose of BAY2701439 for patients and look at the way the body absorbs,&#xD;
      distributes and excretes the drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study drug is a type of therapy called a 'targeted alpha therapy' which uses an antibody&#xD;
      to deliver a radioactive particle to cancer cells. BAY2701439 contains thorium-227 which&#xD;
      emits radiation (a lot of energy that moves from one place to another with damaging effects).&#xD;
      The thorium-227 in the drug is attached to an 'antibody' (large protein) that specifically&#xD;
      binds to HER2 on the cancer cells and will emit its radiation in the form of alpha particles.&#xD;
      The alpha particles are expected to damage the tumor cells and cause them to die, but spare&#xD;
      surrounding tissue as alpha particles travel only very short distances in the body. This is&#xD;
      the first study in humans for drug BAY2701439. Patients participating in this study will&#xD;
      receive the drug by injection every 6 weeks a maximum 6 times. Observation after treatment&#xD;
      last up to 3 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 2, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 24, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 24, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose escalation: Incidence of TEAEs including TESAEs</measure>
    <time_frame>After first administration of study intervention up to 42 days after the last dose of study intervention</time_frame>
    <description>TEAE: Treatment-emergent adverse event TESAE: Treatment-emergent serious adverse event</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose escalation: Severity of TEAEs including TESAEs</measure>
    <time_frame>After first administration of study intervention up to 42 days after the last dose of study intervention</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose escalation: Frequency of DLTs at each dose level</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 42 days after first administration of study intervention on cycle 1 (42 days) day 1</time_frame>
    <description>DLT:Dose limiting toxicity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose expansion: ORR by RECIST 1.1 based on Investigator review</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months after End of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>ORR: Objective response rate</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose expansion: Frequency of TEAEs</measure>
    <time_frame>After first administration of study intervention up to 42 days after the last dose of study intervention</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose expansion: Severity of TEAEs</measure>
    <time_frame>After first administration of study intervention up to 42 days after the last dose of study intervention</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose escalation: Recommended dose level(s) of BAY2701439 for the dose expansion cohorts</measure>
    <time_frame>Maximum 6 cycles (each cycle is 42 days)</time_frame>
    <description>The dose level(s) recommended for the dose expansion cohorts will be defined after evaluation of incidence and severity of TEAEs, PK, and ORR by RECIST 1.1, collected in the cycles of treatment during the dose escalation part of the study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose escalation: Recommended treatment schedule of BAY2701439 for the dose expansion cohorts</measure>
    <time_frame>Maximum 6 cycles (each cycle is 42 days)</time_frame>
    <description>The treatment schedule recommended for the dose expansion cohorts will be defined after evaluation of incidence and severity of TEAEs, PK, and ORR by RECIST 1.1, collected in the cycles of treatment during the dose escalation part of the study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose expansion: Recommended dose for further clinical development of BAY2701439</measure>
    <time_frame>Maximum 6 cycles (each cycle is 42 days)</time_frame>
    <description>The dose recommended for further clinical development will be defined after evaluation of incidence and severity of TEAEs, PK, and ORR by RECIST 1.1, collected in the cycles of treatment during the dose escalation and expansion parts of the study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax of thorium-227</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 (42 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Cmax: Maximum observed exposure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax of radium-223</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 (42 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Cmax: Maximum observed exposure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax of total antibody</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 (42 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Cmax: Maximum observed exposure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC(0-42 days) of thorium-227</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 (42 days)</time_frame>
    <description>AUC: Area under the curve</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC(0-42 days) of radium-223</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 (42 days)</time_frame>
    <description>AUC: Area under the curve</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC(0-42 days) of total antibody</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 (42 days)</time_frame>
    <description>AUC: Area under the curve</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">213</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancers With HER2 Expression</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose escalation of BAY2701439</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The target population consists of participants with advanced HER2-expressing/amplified breast, gastric or gastroesophageal cancer.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HER2 overexpressing breast cancer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose expansion of BAY2701439</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HER2 low expressing breast cancer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose expansion of BAY2701439</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Other HER2 overexpressing advanced carcinomas</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose expansion of BAY2701439</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BAY2701439</intervention_name>
    <description>Intravenous (IV) injection on Day 1 of each cycle.The duration of each cycle will be 6 weeks (42 days).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dose escalation of BAY2701439</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>HER2 low expressing breast cancer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>HER2 overexpressing breast cancer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Other HER2 overexpressing advanced carcinomas</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BAY2701438</intervention_name>
    <description>Intravenous (IV) injection on Day 1 of each cycle and 1 hour before the start of administration of BAY2701439. The duration of each cycle will be 6 weeks (42 days).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dose escalation of BAY2701439</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>HER2 low expressing breast cancer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>HER2 overexpressing breast cancer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Other HER2 overexpressing advanced carcinomas</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female participants at least 18 years of age on the day of signing informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must meet the study phase-specific disease requirements:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Dose escalation:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pathologically documented, HER2-expressing (IHC3+, 2+, or 1+ and/or ISH+), unresectable&#xD;
        locally advanced or metastatic gastric, gastroesophageal, or breast cancer that has&#xD;
        relapsed after standard treatment options, or for which no standard treatment is available.&#xD;
        Participants with gastric or gastroesophageal cancer must not have had prior definitive&#xD;
        radiotherapy. Participants in the dose escalation cohorts must have evaluable disease by&#xD;
        RECIST 1.1, assessed by local imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Dose expansion: Group A: Pathologically documented unresectable, locally advanced or&#xD;
        metastatic breast cancer with HER2 overexpression or amplification (IHC3+ or IHC2+/ISH+)&#xD;
        that has relapsed that has relapsed after standard treatment options, or for which no&#xD;
        standard treatment is available.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Group B: Pathologically documented unresectable locally advanced or metastatic breast&#xD;
        cancer with HER2 low expression (IHC2+/ISH-, IHC1+/ISH-, or IHC1+/ISH untested) that has&#xD;
        relapsed after standard treatment options, or for which no standard treatment is available.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Group C: Pathologically documented, unresectable locally advanced or metastatic carcinomas&#xD;
        other than breast cancer with HER2 overexpression or amplification/mutation (IHC3+ or&#xD;
        IHC2+/ISH+), that has relapsed after standard treatment options or for which no standard&#xD;
        treatment is available.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants in the dose expansion cohorts must have measurable disease by RECIST 1.1,&#xD;
        assessed by local imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Availability of fresh or archival tumor samples - archival tumor samples obtained&#xD;
             after disease progression on the most recent anti-cancer treatment may be accepted;&#xD;
             those obtained prior to the last anti-cancer treatment may be accepted, upon agreement&#xD;
             between the Sponsor and the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status (ECOG PS) of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of at least 6 months, as estimated by the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate bone marrow, hepatic, and renal function, as assessed by the following&#xD;
             laboratory requirements, to be conducted within 28 days before start of BAY2701439&#xD;
             administration:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1500/mm*3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm*3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 X the upper limit of normal (ULN), except if confirmed&#xD;
                  history of Gilbert's disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ˂ 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
                  (≤ 5 x ULN for participants with liver involvement)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants on a stable dose of anti-coagulation therapy will be allowed to&#xD;
                  participate if they have no sign of bleeding or clotting, and Prothrombin&#xD;
                  time/International normalized ratio (PT/INR) and aPTT test results are compatible&#xD;
                  with the acceptable benefit-risk ratio at the Investigator's discretion&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN and glomerular filtration rate (GFR)≥ 45 mL/min/1.73&#xD;
                  m*2, according to the Modified Diet in Renal Disease (MDRD)abbreviated formula.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A negative serum pregnancy test in women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) performed&#xD;
             within 7 days before the start of BAY2701439 administration. Women and men of&#xD;
             reproductive potential must agree to use highly effective methods of contraception,&#xD;
             when sexually active, during the time period between signing the informed consent form&#xD;
             until at least 6 months after the last administration of BAY2701439.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and/or female who meet the requirements for contraception and breastfeeding as&#xD;
             follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Male participants: A male participant must agree to use highly effective contraception&#xD;
        during the intervention period and for at least 6 months after intervention and refrain&#xD;
        from donating sperm during this period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Female participants: A female participant is eligible to participate if she is not pregnant&#xD;
        (confirmed by a negative serum pregnancy test within 7 days of first study treatment), not&#xD;
        breastfeeding, or is not a woman of childbearing potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) must agree to use highly effective contraception&#xD;
        during the intervention period and for at least 6 months after the last dose of study&#xD;
        treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Contraceptive use by men or women should be consistent with local regulations regarding the&#xD;
        methods of contraception for those participating in clinical studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Capable of giving signed informed consent which includes compliance with the requirements&#xD;
        and restrictions listed in the informed consent form (ICF) and in this protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impaired cardiac function or clinically significant cardiac disease (i.e. congestive&#xD;
             heart failure (CHF) New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class II, III or IV).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt; 50% (as measured at screening by&#xD;
             echocardiogram).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or concurrent condition of interstitial lung disease/pneumonitis or severely&#xD;
             impaired pulmonary function.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants known to be affected by genetic defects linked to radiation&#xD;
             hypersensitivity, such as ataxia-telangiectasia (A-T; Online Mendelian Inheritance in&#xD;
             Man [OMIM] #208900) and A-T-like disorder (meiotic recombination 11 homolog [MRE11]),&#xD;
             Nijmegen breakage syndrome (OMIM #251260) and Nijmegen breakage Syndrome-like disorder&#xD;
             (RAD50), Fanconi anemia (OMIM #227650), DNA ligase IV deficiency (OMIM #606593),&#xD;
             RIDDLE syndrome (RNF168), radiosensitive severe combined immunodeficiency (RS-SCID),&#xD;
             DNA-PK radiosensitive combined immunodeficiency (DNA-PK-RS-SCID), Cornelia de Lange&#xD;
             syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of Myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS)/treatment-related acute myeloid leukemia&#xD;
             (t-AML) or with features suggestive of MDS/AML.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infections of Common terminology criteria for adverse events (CTCAE) version 5.0 Grade&#xD;
             2 not responding to therapy or active clinically serious infections of CTCAE Grade &gt;2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hypersensitivity or severe infusion related reaction to any&#xD;
             Trastuzumab-containing drug (e.g. trastuzumab, T-DM1) or any other ingredients&#xD;
             contained in BAY2701439.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chemotherapy, experimental cancer therapy, biologic therapy or immunotherapy within 4&#xD;
             weeks before start of BAY2701439 administration. Start of study treatment is allowed&#xD;
             in shorter timeframes provided 5 half-lives of the prior drug(s) have elapsed before&#xD;
             the start of BAY2701439 administration. Previous high-dose chemotherapy needing&#xD;
             hematopoietic-stem-cell-rescue is prohibited.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bayer Clinical Trials Contact</last_name>
    <phone>(+)1-888-84 22937</phone>
    <email>clinical-trials-contact@bayer.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins Hospital/Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21287</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington University School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10022</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Southampton General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Southampton</city>
        <state>Hampshire</state>
        <zip>SO16 6YD</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Marsden NHS Trust (Surrey)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sutton</city>
        <state>Surrey</state>
        <zip>SM2 5PT</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 25, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 31, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 1, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Human epidermal growth factor receptor 2(HER2)</keyword>
  <keyword>Targeted alpha therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Thorium-227</keyword>
  <keyword>HER2 low</keyword>
  <keyword>HER2-low</keyword>
  <keyword>HER2 positive</keyword>
  <keyword>HER2-positive</keyword>
  <keyword>HER2 expressing</keyword>
  <keyword>HER2-expressing</keyword>
  <keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Gastric cancer</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Availability of this study's data will be determined according to Bayer's commitment to the EFPIA/PhRMA &quot;Principles for responsible clinical trial data sharing&quot;. This pertains to scope, timepoint and process of data access.&#xD;
As such, Bayer commits to sharing upon request from qualified researchers patient-level clinical trial data, study-level clinical trial data, and protocols from clinical trials in patients for medicines and indications approved in the US and EU as necessary for conducting legitimate research. This applies to data on new medicines and indications that have been approved by the EU and US regulatory agencies on or after January 01, 2014.&#xD;
Interested researchers can use www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com to request access to anonymized patient-level data and supporting documents from clinical studies to conduct research. Information on the Bayer criteria for listing studies and other relevant information is provided in the Study sponsors section of the portal.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

