<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04143074</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NKBBN/228/2012</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NKBBN/228/2012</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04143074</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Community Based Obesity Prevention and Treatment Programme &quot;6-10-14 for Health&quot;</brief_title>
  <official_title>&quot;Population Activities in the Field of Prevention, Early Identification and Treatment of Overweight and Obesity in Gdansk Children and Youth Population&quot;</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Michał Brzeziński</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Clinical Centre, Gdansk</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      &quot;6-10-14 for Health&quot; is an integrated weight-loss intervention programme for obese children&#xD;
      from Gdansk municipality. Both participants of the programme and their family members are&#xD;
      offered a 12-month integrated intervention, including medical, dietetic and psychological&#xD;
      counselling, as well as educational workshops for parents.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      &quot;6-10-14 for Health&quot; is an integrated weight-loss intervention programme for obese children&#xD;
      from Gdansk municipality. Both participants of the programme and their family members are&#xD;
      offered a 12-month integrated intervention, including medical, dietetic and psychological&#xD;
      counselling, as well as educational workshops for parents.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The programme, financed by the municipality of Gdansk, is devided in three phases:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Screening - all children aged 6, 9-11, 14 years of age from the City of Gdansk are being&#xD;
           screened yearly. All children attending primary and grammar schools in Gdansk are&#xD;
           subjected to a screening. The population size is between 9.000-10.000 children yearly.&#xD;
&#xD;
           All children have anthropometric measurements (body mass, body height, waist&#xD;
           circumference), blood pressure, cardiorespiratory fitness.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Anthropometry: Body weight and body height are determined with a digital scale (Mensor&#xD;
           WE150, Poland), with the child wearing an underwear and standing barefoot. Body height&#xD;
           is measured to the nearest 0.001 m, and body weight to the nearest 0.1 kg. The scale is&#xD;
           calibrated every day. Waist and hip circumferences are measured on a horizontal plane by&#xD;
           an Ergonomic Circumference Measuring Tape (model 201; Seca GmbH &amp; Co, KG, Hamburg,&#xD;
           Germany).&#xD;
&#xD;
           Blood pressure measurement: Arterial blood pressure is determined oscillometrically&#xD;
           (Omron) on the left arm, with a cuff of an adequate size placed at the level of the&#xD;
           heart, in the child seated with uncrossed legs, following at least a 5-min rest in the&#xD;
           seated position. The width of the inflatable cuff corresponds to at least 40% of arm&#xD;
           circumference. Three separate measurements of blood pressure are taken and averaged.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Kasch pulse recovery step test: The participants are subjected to a 3-minute Kasch pulse&#xD;
           recovery (KPR) step test. The test consists of climbing a 0.305 m step at a rate of 24&#xD;
           steps-up/-down per minute. The rate of climbing is defined by a metronome set at 96&#xD;
           beats (signals) per minute. Heart rate (HR) is monitored continuously with &quot;Polar&quot;&#xD;
           (Finland) electronic analyser for 3 minutes of the exercise (step-test) and during 1&#xD;
           minute and 5 seconds of recovery in a seated position. Only post-exercise HR recorded&#xD;
           within one minute, starting 5 seconds after completing the test, is subjected to&#xD;
           analysis. All HR characteristics are recorded during restitution in a seated position&#xD;
           (subjects are instructed to sit still, breath normally and not involve in a&#xD;
           conversation). An arithmetic mean calculated from these values (HRmean post-ex) is&#xD;
           subjected to further analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Intervention - Participants whose anthropometric parameters correspond to overweight&#xD;
           (BMI between the 85th and 95th percentile) or obesity (BMI &gt; =95th percentile),&#xD;
           according to the percentile charts developed within the framework of the OLAF project,&#xD;
           for Poland were qualified to a complex educational and medical intervention for children&#xD;
           at increased risk of civilization-related disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Weight- loss intervention programme:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dietetic consultation - analysis of nutritional behaviours and dietary habits, selection&#xD;
           of appropriate diet. Dietetic consultation takes place at enrolment and 3, 6 and 12&#xD;
           months thereafter.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Psychological consultation - reinforcement of changes in health behaviours of the child&#xD;
           and his/her parents.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Consultation with a physical education specialist - defining optimal level of physical&#xD;
           activity, adjusted to the subject's body weight, abilities and preferences, development&#xD;
           of a training programme with increasing intensity and volume of physical activity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Measurements:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anthropometry: Body weight and body height are determined with a digital scale (Mensor WE150,&#xD;
      Poland), with the child wearing an underwear and standing barefoot. Body height is measured&#xD;
      to the nearest 0.001 m, and body weight to the nearest 0.1 kg. The scale is calibrated every&#xD;
      day. Waist and hip circumferences are measured on a horizontal plane by an Ergonomic&#xD;
      Circumference Measuring Tape (model 201; Seca GmbH &amp; Co, KG, Hamburg, Germany).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood pressure measurement: Arterial blood pressure is determined oscillometrically (Omron)&#xD;
      on the left arm, with a cuff of an adequate size placed at the level of the heart, in the&#xD;
      child seated with uncrossed legs, following at least a 5-min rest in the seated position. The&#xD;
      width of the inflatable cuff corresponds to at least 40% of arm circumference. Three separate&#xD;
      measurements of blood pressure are taken and averaged [42].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Kasch pulse recovery step test: The participants are subjected to a 3-minute Kasch pulse&#xD;
      recovery (KPR) step test [43,44]. The test consists of climbing a 0.305 m step at a rate of&#xD;
      24 steps-up/-down per minute. The rate of climbing is defined by a metronome set at 96 beats&#xD;
      (signals) per minute. Heart rate (HR) is monitored continuously with &quot;Polar&quot; (Finland)&#xD;
      electronic analyser for 3 minutes of the exercise (step-test) and during 1 minute and 5&#xD;
      seconds of recovery in a seated position. Only post-exercise HR recorded within one minute,&#xD;
      starting 5 seconds after completing the test, is subjected to analysis. All HR&#xD;
      characteristics are recorded during restitution in a seated position (subjects are instructed&#xD;
      to sit still, breath normally and not involve in a conversation). An arithmetic mean&#xD;
      calculated from these values (HRmean post-ex) is subjected to further analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dietetic assessment: Dietary records from three consecutive days (2 weekdays + 1 day of a&#xD;
      weekend), collected prior to enrolment and at the end of the intervention are analysed, and&#xD;
      dietary intakes of calcium and vitamin D are calculated with Dieta 5.0 software (Institute of&#xD;
      Food and Nutrition, Warsaw).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pubertal status is determined on based on the results of physical examination and expressed&#xD;
      using the Tanner stage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DXA: Total body bone mineral content (TBBMC), total body bone mineral density (TBBMD), lean&#xD;
      body mass (LBM), fat mass (FT) (Hologic Discovery Wi)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laboratory parameters:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Complete blood count Lipid profile determined with an enzymatic method Oral glucose tolerance&#xD;
      test (OGTT) with glucose concentration determined with hexokinase method Concentration of&#xD;
      insulin determined by means of an immunochemiluminescence assay Concentration of creatinine&#xD;
      ALT, TSH, fT4, PTH, Ca, P&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 1 (enrolment):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  medical history, physical examination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  interpretation of laboratory findings (tests conducted during screening + concentration&#xD;
           of vitamin D),&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  anthropometric evaluation and analysis of body composition (bioimpedance method)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  consultation with a dietician, psychologist and specialist in physical activity, and&#xD;
           defining detailed protocol of the intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Kasch Pulse Recovery Test&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 2 (3 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  medical history, physical examination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  anthropometric evaluation and analysis of body composition (bioimpedance method)&#xD;
           consultation with a dietician, psychologist and specialist in physical activity, and&#xD;
           defining detailed protocol of the intervention. Within a week prior to Visit II -&#xD;
           obtaining blood (ca. 5 ml) for laboratory testing (complete blood count, lipid profile,&#xD;
           hs-CRP, OGTT, insulin, TSH, fT4).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  consultation with a dietician, psychologist and specialist in physical activity, and&#xD;
           defining detailed protocol of the intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 3 (6 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  medical history, physical examination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  interpretation of laboratory findings&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  anthropometric evaluation and analysis of body composition (bioimpedance method)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  consultation with a dietician, psychologist and specialist in physical activity, and&#xD;
           defining detailed protocol of the intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  obtaining blood for laboratory testing&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  termination of active compound/placebo administration&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 4 (12 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  medical history, physical examination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  anthropometric evaluation and analysis of body composition (bioimpedance method)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  consultation with a dietician, psychologist and specialist in physical activity, and&#xD;
           defining detailed protocol of the intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the programme is to reduce baseline body weight of participating children by at&#xD;
      least 5% .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>single multidisciplinary intervention</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>body mass change</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months from begining of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Number (percentage) of participants with change of: body mass of 5% or centiles of BMI by 5 percentile points or z-score BMI change by 0,25</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>body fat reduction</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months from begining of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Number (percentage) of participants with change of body fat by at least 5%</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">6000</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <condition>Obesity, Childhood</condition>
  <condition>Health Program</condition>
  <condition>Body Weight Changes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>multidisciplinary intervention arm - behavioral intervention by physician, dietician, psychologist and physical activity trainer</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>multidisciplinary behavioral intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>behavioral intervention - 4 visits with each of the specialist team (pediatrician, dietician, psychologist, physical activity specialist), (4 visits x 4 specialists). Each specialist ap. 30 min time. Wisits in 0-3m-6m-12m time frame. Visits focused on behavioral intervention - motivation for change and basic tools (dietician, physical activity specialist, psychologist) to implement change in nutrition and physical activity based on individual reediness for change (based on Prochaska model).</description>
    <arm_group_label>intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  children living in Gdansk (for screening phase)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  children with BMI above 85 percentile (for intervention phase)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  consent of parent/ caregivers&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  confirmed congenital or metabolic diseases connected with obesity risk&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  lack of consent of parent/ caregivers&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gdańsk</city>
        <zip>80-952</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michal Brzezinski, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>501762172</phone>
      <phone_ext>+48</phone_ext>
      <email>brzezinski@gumed.edu.pl</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Paulina Metelska, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>603814314</phone>
      <phone_ext>+48</phone_ext>
      <email>pmetelska@uck.gda.pl</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.appet.2014.01.029</url>
    <description>protocol abd primary results</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 24, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 28, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 28, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 28, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University Clinical Centre, Gdansk</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michał Brzeziński</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor, Primary Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Body Weight</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Body Weight Changes</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>anyone contacting the programme with be assessed and data will be given to researchers/public authorities</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

