<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04145895</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2019-224</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04145895</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Postoperative Activity Restrictions in Children</brief_title>
  <acronym>PARC</acronym>
  <official_title>Postoperative Activity Restrictions in Children</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>William Beaumont Hospitals</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>William Beaumont Hospitals</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will investigate the need for and length of postoperative activity restrictions in&#xD;
      children following a laparoscopic appendectomy or inguinal hernia repair. Currently, no&#xD;
      consensus exists and restrictions are based on doctors' experience and preference. Children&#xD;
      and their parents/guardians will decide if they wish to participate in this study. Those who&#xD;
      wish to participate and who are eligible to participate will decide which postoperative&#xD;
      activity restrictions they would like the child to follow. The child will follow either 1)&#xD;
      doctor-directed restrictions or 2) self-directed restrictions.A parent or guardian will&#xD;
      complete a survey 1-3 months after the procedure, to assess patient and family satisfaction&#xD;
      and patient outcome.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Postoperative activity restrictions minimize the risk of surgical complications and prevent&#xD;
      stress on the operative site. In the pediatric population, surgeons may restrict school&#xD;
      attendance, participation in playground or gym, and participation in contact sports or heavy&#xD;
      lifting. Currently, surgeons give pediatric patients postoperative restrictions following&#xD;
      routine pediatric procedures (laparoscopic appendectomy and inguinal hernia repair) without&#xD;
      evidence-based clinical practice guidelines. However, there is considerable variability&#xD;
      amongst surgeons. It is common practice to provide some level of postoperative restrictions,&#xD;
      which are primarily based on the surgeon's experience.While many surgeons prescribe specific&#xD;
      postoperative instructions, some recommend self-directed restrictions. Self-directed&#xD;
      restrictions instruct that the child return to school and normal physical activity when they&#xD;
      and parents feel they are able to do so. There is no evidence that this practice is&#xD;
      associated with any adverse outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will utilize a convenience sample of pediatric patients treated at Beaumont Royal&#xD;
      Oak and Troy for routine inguinal hernia repair and laparoscopic appendectomy. There will be&#xD;
      two populations: patients undergoing the procedures (Patient population) and their&#xD;
      parents/guardians (Parent population) who will be completing the postoperative survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Principal Investigator will review the operating room schedule and identify patients who&#xD;
      are scheduled for either of the two procedures.Parents and patients who are eligible to&#xD;
      participate in the study will be approached, the study explained and voluntary consent&#xD;
      obtained. The participants will be provided an information sheet detailing the study, the&#xD;
      risks, and the benefits. The researchers will describe the two groups the participant can&#xD;
      enroll in. If the parents decide to enroll their child in the study they will then choose to&#xD;
      be in either the control group (physician-directed) or the variable group (self-directed).&#xD;
      The control group will be those individuals who choose physician-directed instructions which&#xD;
      detail that they can resume all normal activity 2 weeks after their procedure. The&#xD;
      experimental group will be those individuals who choose self-directed instructions which&#xD;
      specify that they may return to full activity when their pain is improving and the parent&#xD;
      feels comfortable with them doing so. For each group, the family will be provided with&#xD;
      discharge instructions, a copy of these discharge instructions are provided in the study&#xD;
      documents. A parent or guardian will complete a postoperative survey 1-3 months post&#xD;
      procedure. The survey will assess: time of pain medication, time to return to school, time to&#xD;
      resume full activity, wound healing, postoperative complications, changes in pain, compliance&#xD;
      with instructions, patient satisfaction, time parent took off from work, if additional&#xD;
      childcare was needed following the procedure, and parental satisfaction with the procedure&#xD;
      and postoperative instructions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective, nonrandomized, parallel</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post operative Outcomes - Clinical Complications</measure>
    <time_frame>six weeks post op</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who developed post op complications</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post operative Outcomes - Patient Satisfaction (combination of child, parent and satisfaction with discharge guidelines)</measure>
    <time_frame>six weeks post op</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants scoring a cumulative 12 or greater using a satisfaction scale ranging from Very Satisfied = 5 to Very Dissatisfied = 1 for each of the three satisfaction factors (child, parent, and satisfaction with discharge guidelines).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post operative Outcomes - Length of time to return to full activity</measure>
    <time_frame>six weeks post op</time_frame>
    <description>Mean/SD number of days to return to full activity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of families choosing self-directed post operative instructions</measure>
    <time_frame>six weeks post op</time_frame>
    <description>Number of families who chose self-directed post operative instructions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of families choosing physician-directed post operative instructions</measure>
    <time_frame>six weeks post op</time_frame>
    <description>Number of families who chose physician-directed post operative instructions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of parental days off work taken in the self-directed post operative course group versus physician-directed course group</measure>
    <time_frame>six weeks post op</time_frame>
    <description>Mean/SD number of days parents took off work during the post operative period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Pediatric Post-operative Time to Return to Full Activity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Physician-directed Postoperative Activity Restriction</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Postoperative activity restrictions prescribed by physician.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Self-directed Postoperative Activity Restriction</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Postoperative activity restrictions self-determined (parent/guardian and/or patient).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Postoperative activity restrictions</intervention_name>
    <description>Recommendations for return to full activity including return to school, sports, exercise, etc.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Physician-directed Postoperative Activity Restriction</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Self-directed Postoperative Activity Restriction</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria for Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient being treated at Royal Oak or Troy Beaumont for a routine inguinal hernia&#xD;
             repair or appendectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For inguinal hernia repair: 2-13 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For appendectomy: less than 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria for Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Older than 18 years of age upon admission&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with perforated or complicated appendicitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For laparoscopic appendectomy: patient required a conversion to open appendectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient experienced a complicated procedure or concomitant operation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria for Parent/Guardians:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Their child meets the inclusion criteria for participation in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria for Parent/Guardians:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Their child does not meet the inclusion criteria for participation in this study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pavan Brahmamdam, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>William Beaumont Hospitals</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Pavan Brahmamdam, MD</last_name>
    <phone>248-551-2400</phone>
    <email>Pavan.Brahmamdam@beaumont.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>William Beaumont Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Royal Oak</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48073</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pavan Brahmamdam, MD</last_name>
      <phone>248-551-2400</phone>
      <email>Pavan.Brahmamdam@beaumont.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>William Beaumont Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Troy</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>44201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pavan Brahmamdam, MD</last_name>
      <phone>248-551-2400</phone>
      <email>Pavan.Brahmamdam@beaumont.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Baumann LM, Williams K, Ghomrawi H, Abdullah F. Current practice patterns for postoperative activity restrictions in children. J Pediatr Surg. 2019 Jul;54(7):1432-1435. doi: 10.1016/j.jpedsurg.2018.06.025. Epub 2018 Jun 26.</citation>
    <PMID>30146309</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 25, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 28, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 31, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>William Beaumont Hospitals</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Pavan Brahmamdam</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Pediatric Surgeon</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Post-operative activity restriction</keyword>
  <keyword>Pediatric inguinal hernia repair</keyword>
  <keyword>Pediatric laparoscopic appendectomy</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

