<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04886934</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-004776-17</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04886934</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Temporary Epicardial Pace Wire With Integrated Sensor for Continuous Postoperative Monitoring of Myocardial Function</brief_title>
  <official_title>Open Clinical Investigation to Assess Performance of a Temporary Epicardial Pace Wire With Integrated Sensor for Continuous Postoperative Monitoring of Myocardial Function After Heart Surgery Compared to Ultrasound</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cardiaccs AS</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>European Commission</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cardiaccs AS</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Transesophageal echocardiography is used to monitor cardiac wall motion at various time&#xD;
      points during open-heart surgery. After surgery, the measurements are made at various time&#xD;
      points by transthoracic echocardiography.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The CS1 system enables continuous, direct measurement of cardiac wall motion. This is&#xD;
      achieved through use of temporary pacemaker wires incorporating a motion detector called an&#xD;
      accelerometer. Use of TMEs during and after open-heart surgery is part of the normal clinical&#xD;
      routine. Continuous monitoring of cardiac wall motion during and after surgery can quickly&#xD;
      highlight the need for medical intervention with cardiac drugs and allow very early detection&#xD;
      of potentially serious complications leading to abnormal cardiac wall motion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiac wall motion activity registered by the CS1 system and echocardiography at specific&#xD;
      time points during and after surgery will be analyzed to see how well they compare.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Echocardiography is currently the most important and most widely used tool in cardiology&#xD;
      besides electrocardiography (ECG). It is reliable for assessing all stages of cardiovascular&#xD;
      disease, and it is commonly used to detect heart (cardiac) wall motion dysfunction during and&#xD;
      after open-heart surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During open-heart surgery, transesophageal echocardiography (when the echocardiography sensor&#xD;
      is introduced into the esophagus) is used to monitor cardiac wall motion at various time&#xD;
      points during surgery. After surgery, the measurements are made at various time points by&#xD;
      transthoracic echocardiography (when the echocardiography sensor is placed on the chest&#xD;
      wall).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Use of the CS1 system enables continuous, direct measurements of cardiac wall motion. This is&#xD;
      achieved through use of temporary pacemaker wires (also called temporary myocardial&#xD;
      electrodes or TMEs) incorporating a motion detector called an accelerometer. Use of TMEs&#xD;
      during and after open-heart surgery is part of the normal clinical routine. Continuous&#xD;
      monitoring of cardiac wall motion during the surgery and the post-surgical recovery period&#xD;
      can, for example, quickly highlight the need for medical intervention with cardiac drugs and&#xD;
      allow very early detection of potentially serious complications such as ischemia (heart&#xD;
      muscle is not receiving enough oxygen) and myocardial dysfunction (cardiac wall motion&#xD;
      appears abnormal).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The key feature of the CS1 system is that the cardiac wall motion activity registered by the&#xD;
      novel TMEs incorporating the accelerometer are displayed visually on a standard medical&#xD;
      monitor and synchronized with the patient's ECG data. These data can easily be viewed by&#xD;
      medical staff to check if the patient's condition is satisfactory or whether medical&#xD;
      intervention is needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the study, the CS1 system will be used in addition to the standard monitoring procedures&#xD;
      that include ECG, blood pressures and intermittent echocardiography. Cardiac wall motion&#xD;
      activity registered by the CS1 system and echocardiography at specific time points during and&#xD;
      after surgery will be analyzed to see how well they compare.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline Peak Systolic Velocity (PSV) after increasing heart rate by 25 percent</measure>
    <time_frame>After surgery: before extubation, while patient is in the intensive care unit (ICU)</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between relative changes in PSVs measured by CS1 and echocardiography</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline PSV after increasing heart rate by 25 percent</measure>
    <time_frame>After surgery: after extubation and removal of drains, before patient is transferred from ICU to general ward</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between relative changes in PSVs measured by CS1 and echocardiography</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of non-serious and serious adverse events rated for causality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Device Effects</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to removal of device at a maximum of 7 days after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of non-serious and serious adverse device-related effects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Device Deficiencies</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to removal of device at a maximum of 7 days after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of device deficiencies</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">38</enrollment>
  <condition>Cardiac Disease</condition>
  <condition>Myocardial Dysfunction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Safety and clinical performance of the CS1 system</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placement of the CS1 device on the left ventricle and externalization of the associated leads through the chest wall during open-heart surgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CS1 System</intervention_name>
    <description>Placement of CS1, a temporary bipolar myocardial electrode (TME) with an integrated motion sensor (accelerometer), on the left ventricle and externalization of the associated leads through the chest wall during open-heart surgery. CS1 will remain in place for up to 7 days after surgery and closure of the chest wall.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Safety and clinical performance of the CS1 system</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with heart disease requiring surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Above 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients suitable for study participation without safety concerns based on the&#xD;
             Investigator's evaluation of medical history and physical examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The patient must be able to understand the aims and objectives of the trial, willing&#xD;
             and able to comply with all study related procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The patient must be willing and able to provide written informed consent prior to&#xD;
             participation in the clinical investigation&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The patient agrees to abstain from enrollment in any other clinical investigation for&#xD;
             the duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Esophageal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Atrial fibrillation&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oslo University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oslo</city>
        <zip>4950</zip>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Norway</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 3, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

