<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04882969</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-12914</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04882969</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Thulium Laser and KeraFactor for the Treatment of Androgenetic Alopecia</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pilot Study Evaluating the Safety and Efficacy of a Fractionated Thulium Laser and KeraFactor for the Treatment of Alopecia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Montefiore Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Montefiore Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this clinical study is to assess the safety and efficacy of using a laser&#xD;
      and hair growth factors in the treatment of male-pattern hair loss. Participating subjects&#xD;
      will receive up to two (2) treatments per month for 6 months with the laser and&#xD;
      post-treatment topically applied hair growth factors and will have a 6 month follow-up&#xD;
      period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a single-center, open-label, baseline-controlled, study evaluating the use of a&#xD;
      Thulium laser (1927nm) and post-treatment topically applied KeraFactor, which contain&#xD;
      hair-stimulating growth factors, in the treatment of androgenetic alopecia. The study may&#xD;
      enroll up to 20 subjects looking for improvement in their hair loss. Multiple treatment areas&#xD;
      per subject may be included. Each subject will receive up to two (2) treatments per month&#xD;
      over a 3-month period. Follow Up Visits are planned for 3, and 9 months post last treatment.&#xD;
      Standardized photography of the treatment areas will be recorded Pre and Post Treatment at&#xD;
      each visit. Measurement outcomes will be compared to baseline. During the initial visit,&#xD;
      subjects who meet the study's eligibility criteria will receive the first treatment after&#xD;
      signing informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The follow up phase will consist of before and after photographs graded by blinded observers.&#xD;
      Subjects are instructed to inform clinical staff after the treatment if they experience any&#xD;
      adverse events.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Changed Indication&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Each participating subject will serve as his or her baseline control and will receive up to two (2) treatments per month for 3 months with Thulium laser and post-laser treatment topically applied Kerafactor.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>No masking.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of subjects with score of 2 or 3 on Clinician Global Aesthetic Improvement (CGAIS) scale at week 12 of treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Clinician Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale (CGAIS) is a Likert scale, ranging from &quot;greatly decreased (-3)&quot; hair growth to &quot;greatly increased (+3)&quot; hair growth.&#xD;
Greatly decreased (-3)&#xD;
Moderately decreased (-2)&#xD;
Slightly decreased (-1)&#xD;
No change (0)&#xD;
Slightly increased (+1)&#xD;
Moderately increased (+2)&#xD;
Greatly increased (+3)&#xD;
Based on a live assessment of the subject while referring to the subject's pre-treatment scalp photographs, the clinician will make an assessment of post-treatment hair growth.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of subjects with score of 2 or 3 on Subject Global Aesthetic Improvement at week 12 of treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Subject Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale (SGAIS) is a Likert scale, ranging from &quot;greatly decreased (-3)&quot; hair growth to &quot;greatly increased (+3)&quot; hair growth.&#xD;
Greatly decreased (-3)&#xD;
Moderately decreased (-2)&#xD;
Slightly decreased (-1)&#xD;
No change (0)&#xD;
Slightly increased (+1)&#xD;
Moderately increased (+2)&#xD;
Greatly increased (+3)&#xD;
Subjects will be given a hand mirror for self-assessment of post-treatment hair growth compared to subject's pre-treatment scalp photographs.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of subjects with score of 2 or 3 on Patient Satisfaction Questionnaire at week 12 of treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Patient Satisfaction Questionnaire will use Lickert scale, ranging from &quot;greatly decreased (-3)&quot; to &quot;greatly increased (+3)&quot;.&#xD;
Greatly decreased (-3)&#xD;
Moderately decreased (-2)&#xD;
Slightly decreased (-1)&#xD;
No change (0)&#xD;
Slightly increased (+1)&#xD;
Moderately increased (+2)&#xD;
Greatly increased (+3)&#xD;
The seven point Lickert scale will apply to following patient satisfaction questions:&#xD;
Please choose the option that better represents the change in how your hair looks OVERALL in the area treated?&#xD;
Please choose the option that better represents the change in your hair THICKNESS in the area treated?&#xD;
Please choose the option that better represents the change in your hair SHEDDING/LOSS in the area treated?&#xD;
Please choose the option that better represents the change in your hair DARKNESS in the area treated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reported pain score on Numeric Rating Scale for Pain</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The Numeric Rating Scale for Pain is an 11-point scale scored from 0-10, with 0 = no pain, 5 = moderate pain, and 10 = worst possible pain. Subjects select a value that is most in line with the intensity of their pain experienced during and after treatment with Thulium Laser and topical Kerafactor.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Androgenetic Alopecia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fractionated Thulium Laser and KeraFactor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All participating subjects will serve as their own baseline control and will receive treatment of their androgenetic alopecia with LaseMD, a 1927nm Fractionated Thulium laser and post-treatment topically applied KeraFactor every 2 weeks for 12 week period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fractionated Thulium laser</intervention_name>
    <description>LaseMD Lutronic Laser is a 1927-nm fractionated thulium laser, which is better absorbed by water than non-ablative 1,540-nm erbium glass laser energy. The laser energy and power can be customized to target a specific penetration depth and achieve selective photothermolysis in skin while mitigating injury to surrounding tissue. The thermal energy generated by the laser has been shown to facilitate the delivery of kerafactor, which contain hair growth factors to stimulate follicular progenitor cell proliferation and differentiation into follicular keratinocytes to promote hair growth.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Fractionated Thulium Laser and KeraFactor</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>LaseMD Lutronic Laser</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject must voluntarily sign and date an IRB approved informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with diagnosis of androgenetic alopecia with hair loss recorded over the past&#xD;
             6 months. (Ludwig Savin Scale: Class I-4, II-1, II-2 for females and Norwood Hamilton&#xD;
             Class 3-4 for males&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to read, understand and voluntarily provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy male or female, ≥ 18 years of age at time of informed consent up to 65 years&#xD;
             of age, seeking treatment for hair loss.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is determined to be healthy, non-smoker who agrees not to make any changes to&#xD;
             their daily hair treatment regime during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects able and willing to comply with the treatment protocol and follow-up schedule&#xD;
             and requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Understands and accepts the obligation not to undergo any other procedures in the&#xD;
             areas to be treated through the follow-up period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child-bearing age are required to be using a reliable, non-hormonal method of&#xD;
             birth control for the duration of the study. Subjects will be asked to have a negative&#xD;
             Urine Pregnancy test at baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects does not have the capacity to consent to the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has other types of alopecia of the scalp (i.g., alopecia areata, scarring&#xD;
             alopecia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of minoxidil or 5-alpha reductase inhibitors (i.e., finasteride, dutasteride) 3&#xD;
             months prior to screening date.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any medical condition that in the consideration of the investigator, would present an&#xD;
             increased risk of a photosensitivity reaction to the subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant in the last 12 months, intending to become pregnant, postpartum or nursing in&#xD;
             the last 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any previous surgical procedure in the treatment area in the past 12 months, or major&#xD;
             surgery in the last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of immunosuppression/immune deficiency disorders (including AIDS and HIV&#xD;
             infection), and/or any history of systemic chemotherapy for prior 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or current use of the following prescription medications: Immunosuppressive&#xD;
             medications/biologics, 6 months prior to and during the study. Accutane or other&#xD;
             systemic retinoids within the past twelve months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smoking or vaping in the past 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hyperlipidemia, diabetes mellitus, hepatitis, or bleeding disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of major depressive disorders or endocrine disorders including but not limited&#xD;
             to; hypothyroidism, Hashimoto's thyroiditis, or hyperthyroidism as well as Polycystic&#xD;
             Ovarian Syndrome (PCOS) in females.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kseniya Kobets, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Montefiore Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Montefiore Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bronx</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10467</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Montefiore Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kseniya Kobets</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor, Department of Medicine (Dermatology)</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>alopecia</keyword>
  <keyword>androgenetic</keyword>
  <keyword>laser</keyword>
  <keyword>hair loss</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alopecia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alopecia Areata</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

