<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04885517</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2782</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04885517</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Breathing Effort in Covid-19 Pneumonia: Effects of Positive Pressure, Inspired Oxygen Fraction and Decubitus</brief_title>
  <official_title>Dynamic Transpulmonary Pressure in Covid-19 Pneumonia: Effects of Positive Pressure, Inspired Oxygen Fraction and Decubitus</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>San Luigi Gonzaga Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>San Luigi Gonzaga Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study investigates the role of positive pressure, inspired oxygen fraction and different&#xD;
      decubiti (seated, supine, prone) on breathing effort (as assessed by esophageal pressure&#xD;
      swings) in Covid-19 pneumonia (at different disease stages) and in other causes of&#xD;
      respiratory failure. The hypothesis is that positive pressure might be deleterious in terms&#xD;
      of breathing effort if the main pathological mechanism associated with Sars-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
      in the lung is not alveolar damage (as in other causes of respiratory failure) but vascular&#xD;
      impairment as previously reported. The effects of high inspired oxygen fractions and decubiti&#xD;
      might also be different with respect to other causes of respiratory failure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In spite of the overwhelming numbers of the current pandemic, many questions remain open&#xD;
      regarding the pathophysiology of Covid-19 associated pneumonia. While some features of the&#xD;
      disease (such as the oxygenation improvement associated with proning and/or continuous&#xD;
      positive airway pressure) seem to line up with other causes of pneumonia characterized by&#xD;
      primary alveolar damage, specific characteristics have been reported about Sars-CoV-2 lung&#xD;
      infection which suggest a certain degree of parenchymal preservation and a predominant role&#xD;
      of vascular impairment: the dissociation between lung volume and gas exchange, and the so&#xD;
      called &quot;happy hypoxemia&quot; both evoke the possibility of mechanisms other than the loss of&#xD;
      aeration as causes of hypoxia. Accordingly, evidence are now growing on the role of vascular&#xD;
      dysregulation in this regard. It is probable, as previously put forward, that different&#xD;
      stages exist in the disease which may account for the discordant findings of previous studies&#xD;
      seeking to either associate or separate Covid-19 pneumonia and other causes of respiratory&#xD;
      failure. In the present study we will compare the effects of three currently used approaches&#xD;
      to improve gas exchange (continuous positive airway pressure, external oxygen administration&#xD;
      and decubiti variations) in three different populations (1) early Covid-19 pneumonia, 2)&#xD;
      severe late Covid-19 pneumonia and 3) non-Covid-19 pneumonia) in terms of breathing effort as&#xD;
      assessed by esophageal pressure swings: our aim is to evaluate, in these populations, the&#xD;
      real benefits (beyond the previously reported ones on gas exchange) of such strategies on&#xD;
      lung rest. Our hypothesis is that, at least in the early stages of Covid-19 (and as opposed&#xD;
      to other causes of respiratory failure), the application of positive pressure might be&#xD;
      deleterious if no potential for recruitment, but rather a primary vascular impairment, is&#xD;
      associated with hypoxia. If this will be the case the same (or a similar) degree of&#xD;
      oxygenation improvement and a safer pattern of ventilation might be attained with the simple&#xD;
      administration of oxygen or decubiti variations without the application of positive pressure,&#xD;
      thus completely changing the current standards for the treatment of Covid-19 pneumonia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Esophageal pressure swings at different levels of positive end-expiratory pressure (PEEP)</measure>
    <time_frame>160 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The main outcome of the study is represented by the difference in esophageal pressure swings (expiratory minus inspiratory) between the three levels of end expiratory pressure applied (0-7-12 cmH2O)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Esophageal pressure swings at different levels of inspired oxygen fraction</measure>
    <time_frame>160 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>One of the secondary outcomes of the study is represented by the difference in esophageal pressure swings (expiratory minus inspiratory) between the two levels of FiO2 applied (0.5-1)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Esophageal pressure swings at different decubiti</measure>
    <time_frame>160 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>One of the secondary outcomes of the study is represented by the difference in esophageal pressure swings (expiratory minus inspiratory) between the three decubiti applied (seated, supine, prone)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>8</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">72</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19 Pneumonia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Spontaneous breathing, Venturi Mask FiO2 0.5, seated decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient will be evaluated after 20 minutes of spontaneous breathing, with FiO2 0.5 (Venturi Mask), during seated decubitus. Respiratory, haemodynamics, and data on blood gas analysis will be obtained.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Spontaneous breathing, Non Rebreathing Mask, seated decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient will be evaluated after 20 minutes of spontaneous breathing, with FiO2 1 (Non Rebreathing Mask), during seated decubitus. Respiratory, haemodynamics, and data on blood gas analysis will be obtained.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) 7 cmH2O, FiO2 0.5, seated decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient will be evaluated after 20 minutes of CPAP (7 cmH2O), with FiO2 0.5, during seated decubitus. Respiratory, haemodynamics, and data on blood gas analysis will be obtained.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) 7 cmH2O, FiO2 0.5, supine decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient will be evaluated after 20 minutes of CPAP (7 cmH2O), with FiO2 0.5, during supine decubitus. Respiratory, haemodynamics, and data on blood gas analysis will be obtained.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) 7 cmH2O, FiO2 0.5, prone decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient will be evaluated after 20 minutes of CPAP (7 cmH2O), with FiO2 0.5, during prone decubitus. Respiratory, haemodynamics, and data on blood gas analysis will be obtained.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) 7 cmH2O, FiO2 1, seated decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient will be evaluated after 20 minutes of CPAP (7 cmH2O), with FiO2 1.0, during seated decubitus. Respiratory, haemodynamics, and data on blood gas analysis will be obtained.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) 12 cmH2O, FiO2 0.5, seated decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient will be evaluated after 20 minutes of CPAP (12 cmH2O), with FiO2 0.5, during seated decubitus. Respiratory, haemodynamics, and data on blood gas analysis will be obtained.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) 12 cmH2O, FiO2 1, seated decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient will be evaluated after 20 minutes of CPAP (7 cmH2O), with FiO2 1.0, during seated decubitus. Respiratory, haemodynamics, and data on blood gas analysis will be obtained.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Esophageal catheter</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients are equipped with an esophageal catheter: positioning is performed after accurate nasopharyngeal anesthesia with lidocaine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) 12 cmH2O, FiO2 0.5, seated decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) 12 cmH2O, FiO2 1, seated decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) 7 cmH2O, FiO2 0.5, prone decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) 7 cmH2O, FiO2 0.5, seated decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) 7 cmH2O, FiO2 0.5, supine decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) 7 cmH2O, FiO2 1, seated decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Spontaneous breathing, Non Rebreathing Mask, seated decubitus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Spontaneous breathing, Venturi Mask FiO2 0.5, seated decubitus</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Group 1 (Covid-19 early pneumonia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive Sars-CoV 2 nasal swab&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  interstitial pneumonia at either CT scan or chest X-ray&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Respiratory failure requiring CPAP for less than 48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  FiO2 ≤0.5 and CPAP≤10 cmH2O&#xD;
&#xD;
        Group 2 (Covid-19 severe pneumonia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive Sars-CoV 2 nasal swab&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  interstitial pneumonia at either CT scan or chest X-ray&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Respiratory failure requiring CPAP&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signs of severity with CPAP 10 cmH2O and FiO2 0.5: pulse oximetry (SpO2) ≤ 93%&#xD;
             associated to either:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Dyspnea&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Two or more signs of increased respiratory effort (respiratory rate ≥25 bpm, use&#xD;
                  of accessory inspiratory muscles , tirage, intercostal space depression, nasal&#xD;
                  flaring, expiratory abdominal efforts, PaCO2 &lt; 35)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Group 3 (Non Covid-19 pneumonia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative Sars-CoV 2 nasal swab&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CT scan or chest X-ray non compatible with Covid-19 associated pneumonia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Respiratory failure requiring CPAP&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Group 1 (Covid-19 early pneumonia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant chronic pulmonary disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic heart failure New York Heart Association (NYHA) 3-4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bacterial pulmonary associated infection (diagnosed or suspected)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pulmonary embolism&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute cardiogenic pulmonary edema&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signs of severity with CPAP 10 cmH2O and FiO2 0.5: SpO2≤ 93% associated to either:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Dyspnea&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Two or more signs of increased respiratory effort (respiratory rate ≥25 bpm, use&#xD;
                  of accessory inspiratory muscles , tirage, intercostal space depression, nasal&#xD;
                  flaring, expiratory abdominal efforts, PaCO2 &lt; 35)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one sign of respiratory fatigue/decompensation (pH&lt;7.30 with PaCO2 &gt;45,&#xD;
             respiratory rate &lt;15 bpm, paradoxal abdominal breathing, mental status alteration)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Group 2 (Covid-19 severe pneumonia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant chronic pulmonary disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic heart failure NYHA 3-4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bacterial pulmonary associated infection (diagnosed or suspected)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pulmonary embolism&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute cardiogenic pulmonary edema&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one sign of respiratory fatigue/decompensation (pH&lt;7.30 with PaCO2 &gt;45,&#xD;
             respiratory rate &lt;15 bpm, paradoxal abdominal breathing, mental status alteration)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Group 3 (Non Covid-19 pneumonia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant chronic pulmonary disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic heart failure NYHA 3-4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bacterial pulmonary associated infection (diagnosed or suspected)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pulmonary embolism&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute cardiogenic pulmonary edema&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one sign of respiratory fatigue/decompensation (pH&lt;7.30 with PaCO2 &gt;45,&#xD;
             respiratory rate &lt;15 bpm, paradoxal abdominal breathing, mental status alteration)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pietro Caironi, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>San Luigi Gonzaga Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lorenzo Giosa, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>San Luigi Gonzaga Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Pietro Caironi, Pr</last_name>
    <phone>+390119026386</phone>
    <email>pietro.caironi@unito.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>A.O.U. San Luigi Gonzaga Di Orbassano</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orbassano</city>
        <state>Italy/Turin</state>
        <zip>10043</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pietro Caironi, Pr</last_name>
      <phone>+390119026386</phone>
      <email>pietro.caironi@unito.it</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Gattinoni L, Coppola S, Cressoni M, Busana M, Rossi S, Chiumello D. COVID-19 Does Not Lead to a &quot;Typical&quot; Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020 May 15;201(10):1299-1300. doi: 10.1164/rccm.202003-0817LE.</citation>
    <PMID>32228035</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Couzin-Frankel J. The mystery of the pandemic's 'happy hypoxia'. Science. 2020 May 1;368(6490):455-456. doi: 10.1126/science.368.6490.455.</citation>
    <PMID>32355007</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Aliberti S, Radovanovic D, Billi F, Sotgiu G, Costanzo M, Pilocane T, Saderi L, Gramegna A, Rovellini A, Perotto L, Monzani V, Santus P, Blasi F. Helmet CPAP treatment in patients with COVID-19 pneumonia: a multicentre cohort study. Eur Respir J. 2020 Oct 15;56(4). pii: 2001935. doi: 10.1183/13993003.01935-2020. Print 2020 Oct.</citation>
    <PMID>32747395</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Elharrar X, Trigui Y, Dols AM, Touchon F, Martinez S, Prud'homme E, Papazian L. Use of Prone Positioning in Nonintubated Patients With COVID-19 and Hypoxemic Acute Respiratory Failure. JAMA. 2020 Jun 9;323(22):2336-2338. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.8255.</citation>
    <PMID>32412581</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chiumello D, Busana M, Coppola S, Romitti F, Formenti P, Bonifazi M, Pozzi T, Palumbo MM, Cressoni M, Herrmann P, Meissner K, Quintel M, Camporota L, Marini JJ, Gattinoni L. Physiological and quantitative CT-scan characterization of COVID-19 and typical ARDS: a matched cohort study. Intensive Care Med. 2020 Dec;46(12):2187-2196. doi: 10.1007/s00134-020-06281-2. Epub 2020 Oct 21.</citation>
    <PMID>33089348</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Marini JJ, Gattinoni L. Management of COVID-19 Respiratory Distress. JAMA. 2020 Jun 9;323(22):2329-2330. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.6825.</citation>
    <PMID>32329799</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Poston JT, Patel BK, Davis AM. Management of Critically Ill Adults With COVID-19. JAMA. 2020 May 12;323(18):1839-1841. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.4914.</citation>
    <PMID>32215647</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Gattinoni L, Giosa L, Bonifazi M, Pasticci I, Busana M, Macri M, Romitti F, Vassalli F, Quintel M. Targeting transpulmonary pressure to prevent ventilator-induced lung injury. Expert Rev Respir Med. 2019 Aug;13(8):737-746. doi: 10.1080/17476348.2019.1638767. Epub 2019 Jul 5. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31274034</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Brochard L, Slutsky A, Pesenti A. Mechanical Ventilation to Minimize Progression of Lung Injury in Acute Respiratory Failure. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2017 Feb 15;195(4):438-442. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201605-1081CP.</citation>
    <PMID>27626833</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tonelli R, Fantini R, Tabbì L, Castaniere I, Pisani L, Pellegrino MR, Della Casa G, D'Amico R, Girardis M, Nava S, Clini EM, Marchioni A. Early Inspiratory Effort Assessment by Esophageal Manometry Predicts Noninvasive Ventilation Outcome in De Novo Respiratory Failure. A Pilot Study. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020 Aug 15;202(4):558-567. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201912-2512OC.</citation>
    <PMID>32325004</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Goligher EC, Jonkman AH, Dianti J, Vaporidi K, Beitler JR, Patel BK, Yoshida T, Jaber S, Dres M, Mauri T, Bellani G, Demoule A, Brochard L, Heunks L. Clinical strategies for implementing lung and diaphragm-protective ventilation: avoiding insufficient and excessive effort. Intensive Care Med. 2020 Dec;46(12):2314-2326. doi: 10.1007/s00134-020-06288-9. Epub 2020 Nov 2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>33140181</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Apigo M, Schechtman J, Dhliwayo N, Al Tameemi M, Gazmuri RJ. Development of a work of breathing scale and monitoring need of intubation in COVID-19 pneumonia. Crit Care. 2020 Jul 31;24(1):477. doi: 10.1186/s13054-020-03176-y.</citation>
    <PMID>32736637</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vaporidi K, Akoumianaki E, Telias I, Goligher EC, Brochard L, Georgopoulos D. Respiratory Drive in Critically Ill Patients. Pathophysiology and Clinical Implications. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020 Jan 1;201(1):20-32. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201903-0596SO.</citation>
    <PMID>31437406</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Gattinoni L, Chiumello D, Caironi P, Busana M, Romitti F, Brazzi L, Camporota L. COVID-19 pneumonia: different respiratory treatments for different phenotypes? Intensive Care Med. 2020 Jun;46(6):1099-1102. doi: 10.1007/s00134-020-06033-2. Epub 2020 Apr 14.</citation>
    <PMID>32291463</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>San Luigi Gonzaga Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Pietro Caironi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19 Pneumonia</keyword>
  <keyword>Esophageal Pressure</keyword>
  <keyword>Respiratory Drive</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

