<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04889755</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>5870E</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R03CA259898</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04889755</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SibACCESS: Developing a Telehealth Intervention to Address Unmet Psychosocial Needs of Siblings of Children With Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>R03 CA259898</acronym>
  <official_title>SibACCESS: Developing a Telehealth Intervention to Address Unmet Psychosocial Needs of Siblings of Children With Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Boston University Charles River Campus</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Boston University Charles River Campus</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to address barriers to psychosocial care for siblings of children with cancer&#xD;
      by piloting a group-based telehealth program for adolescent siblings of youth with cancer.&#xD;
      The pilot trial will be preceded by a treatment development stage during which study staff&#xD;
      will interview English- and Spanish-speaking families and psychosocial providers to assess&#xD;
      preferences for program content, format, timing, and cultural feasibility and acceptability,&#xD;
      while considering ideas to minimize participation barriers. Information from interviews will&#xD;
      inform any revisions to the proposed pilot program. Then, the new SibACCESS program will be&#xD;
      tested with a small group of families located in Massachusetts or Rhode Island using&#xD;
      video-teleconferencing technology. Families will complete exit interviews to assess program&#xD;
      acceptability and perceived benefits.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prolonged, complicated, and intensive pediatric cancer treatment regimens challenge and&#xD;
      disrupt the entire family. Siblings of youth with cancer are a psychosocially at-risk and&#xD;
      underserved group. Siblings frequently report strong negative emotions, disruptions to family&#xD;
      life, poorer academic functioning, more school absenteeism (school-aged siblings), and&#xD;
      riskier health behaviors and poorer health outcomes than comparisons (adult siblings).&#xD;
      Approximately one-quarter of siblings meet diagnostic criteria for cancer-related&#xD;
      posttraumatic stress disorders. Outcomes are worse for siblings from under-represented&#xD;
      minority groups and those with fewer socioeconomic resources. Additionally, siblings report&#xD;
      low social support and indicate a strong desire to connect with other siblings. The need for&#xD;
      sibling support is well established, as outlined in the recently developed evidence- and&#xD;
      consensus-based Standards for Psychosocial Care for Children with Cancer and Their Families.&#xD;
      Unfortunately, the Sibling Standard is among those least likely to be met within pediatric&#xD;
      oncology programs nationwide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SibACCESS Program Description:&#xD;
&#xD;
      SibACCESS (Acceptance, Coping, Communication, Engagement, and Social Support) targets the&#xD;
      proposed mechanisms of sibling difficulties. The primary goal is to increase siblings'&#xD;
      exposure and opportunities to process cancer-related cues to decrease the onset or&#xD;
      intensification of posttraumatic stress (PTS). Treatment targets include emotional&#xD;
      acceptance, treatment involvement, family communication (via between-session assignments),&#xD;
      and social support (fostered by the group format).&#xD;
&#xD;
      SibACCESS is based on acceptance-based cognitive-behavioral frameworks, drawing primarily on&#xD;
      trauma-focused CBT (TF-CBT). TF-CBT is a structured, short-term treatment that incorporates&#xD;
      cognitive-behavioral approaches to promote recovery from trauma. It is a logical starting&#xD;
      point for the present study for multiple reasons: (a) TF-CBT was developed specifically for&#xD;
      children and adolescents; parent participation is recommended but not required; (b) it has&#xD;
      been tested in a group format and using telehealth; (c) it has demonstrated effectiveness&#xD;
      across cultural groups; and (d) it is appropriate for youth who meet diagnostic criteria for&#xD;
      PTSD and those with sub-clinical PTS. TF-CBT has not yet been evaluated in the context of&#xD;
      childhood cancer and may require some adaptations. Thus, SibACCESS also includes skills from&#xD;
      Dialectical and Behavioral Therapy (i.e., self-validation of emotions, communication,&#xD;
      mindfulness, radical acceptance) to better address distress tolerance and acceptance of the&#xD;
      aspects of cancer that are beyond siblings' control.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SibACCESS group sessions will be facilitated remotely using Zoom. The intervention includes&#xD;
      one parent session and seven bi-weekly sibling sessions. The 90-minute parent session will&#xD;
      provide a program overview, psychoeducation, and brief skills training. Parents will be given&#xD;
      &quot;discussion starter&quot; questions to facilitate communication throughout the program. Sibling&#xD;
      group sessions are 60-90 minutes and will include an ice breaker, review of last week's&#xD;
      homework (sessions 2-7), introduction of new topics, interactive practice of new skills, and&#xD;
      assignment of home practice (sessions 1-6). Exposure to cancer-related emotions and cues will&#xD;
      be emphasized; in addition to emotion exposures and trauma narratives, siblings will confront&#xD;
      information about cancer, uncomfortable thoughts and feelings, and communication about cancer&#xD;
      throughout the program.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Parent Pre-session: Supporting siblings Sibling Session 1: Psychoeducation Sibling Session 2: Adaptive Thinking Sibling Session 3: Distress tolerance &amp; Acceptance Sibling Session 4: Communication &amp; introduction to exposures Sibling Session 5: Exposures part 2 &amp; problem-solving Sibling Sessions 6: Exposures part 3 Sibling Session 7: Wrap-up</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Child Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Symptom Scale for DSM-5</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measure of youth posttraumatic stress symptoms (score range: 0-80; higher scores reflect more posttraumatic stress)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">25</enrollment>
  <condition>Siblings</condition>
  <condition>Childhood Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Pediatric Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Posttraumatic Stress Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SibACCESS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is a single-arm trial of a group-based, posttraumatic stress intervention for adolescent siblings of children with cancer. The intervention includes one parent session and seven bi-weekly sibling sessions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SibACCESS</intervention_name>
    <description>The primary goal of the 8-session, SibACCESS program is to increase siblings' exposure and opportunity to process cancer-related cues to decrease onset or intensification of posttraumatic stress. Parents will participate in an initial 90-minute session where they will receive psychoeducation and brief skills training to support siblings enrolled in the program. Siblings will participate in 7-sessions where they will receive skills and strategies to confront information about cancer and tolerate uncomfortable thoughts and feelings, as well as how to communicate about cancer.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SibACCESS</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SibACCESS (Acceptance, Coping, Communication, Engagement, and Social Support)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  2 or more children in the family (i.e., child with cancer and &gt;1 sibling)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Sibling(s) and child with cancer each under the age of 18 at the time of cancer&#xD;
                  diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Sibling(s) can be biologically-related, step-siblings, foster-siblings, or&#xD;
                  adopted-siblings&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parent and sibling(s) fluent in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sibling(s) 12-17 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sibling report of at least mild posttraumatic stress (score &gt;11 on the Child&#xD;
             Posttraumatic Stress Scale for DSM-5)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Child with cancer must have received cancer diagnosis at least 3 months prior to the&#xD;
             family's enrollment in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A cognitive impairment that would interfere with pilot program and interview&#xD;
             completion (as reported by parent)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bereavement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant externalizing behaviors that would interfere with group participation (as&#xD;
             reported by parent)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kristin A. Long, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Boston University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kristin Long, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>617-358-4296</phone>
    <email>kalong@bu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Marcella Mazzenga, BA</last_name>
    <phone>857-302-0830</phone>
    <email>childfam@bu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

