<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04883346</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10000241</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>000241-CH</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04883346</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Liraglutide (Saxenda(R)) in Adolescents With Obesity After Sleeve Gastrectomy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Trial of Liraglutide (Saxenda(R), Novo Nordisk) in Adolescents With Obesity After Sleeve Gastrectomy: A Pilot Open-Label Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Metabolic Bariatric Surgery, including a surgery called vertical sleeve gastrectomy, is the&#xD;
      most effective weight loss treatment for severe obesity. However, many adolescents who have&#xD;
      this surgery still have obesity 1 year later or regain weight. Researchers want to see if a&#xD;
      drug can help.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To learn if liraglutide can help adolescents who still have obesity 1 year or more after&#xD;
      vertical sleeve gastrectomy lose additional weight.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy adolescents ages 12-20.99 years who are 1-10 years post vertical sleeve gastrectomy&#xD;
      and have a BMI of 30 kg/m2 or &gt;=95th percentile for age and sex.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical exam&#xD;
&#xD;
      Questionnaires about their mood and feelings about their weight&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood and urine tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nutrition counseling. They will keep a diet log.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A test where they view and respond to pictures of food&#xD;
&#xD;
      Wrist accelerometer set-up. They will wear an accelerometer (a device like a watch) on their&#xD;
      wrist for 14 days. It will measure their physical activity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some screening tests will be repeated during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have an oral glucose tolerance test. They will ingest a sweet liquid. Blood&#xD;
      samples will be taken.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will take liraglutide daily for 16 weeks. They will learn how to inject it under&#xD;
      their skin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have a body scan to measure muscle and fat.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be invited to eat as much as they want at a buffet meal at NIH. How much&#xD;
      food they eat will be calculated. They will assess their appetite and mood before and after&#xD;
      the meal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation will last for 7 months. Participants will have 7 study visits....&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label Phase II non-randomized pilot study conducted at the NIH Clinical&#xD;
      Center to investigate the efficacy of daily subcutaneous injection of liraglutide, a&#xD;
      glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP1) analogue to promote reduction of body mass index (BMI) in&#xD;
      adolescents who continue to have obesity (BMI greater than or equal to 30 or BMI greater than&#xD;
      or equal to 95th percentile for age and sex) 1 year or more after vertical sleeve gastrectomy&#xD;
      (SG). We hypothesize that administration of liraglutide will be associated with reduction in&#xD;
      BMI in such adolescents.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Primary objective is to determine the effect size for the change in BMI of liraglutide&#xD;
      3.0 mg daily subcutaneously at 16 weeks in adolescents who have obesity after SG, in order to&#xD;
      use the observed changes to determine the sample size of a subsequent randomized, controlled&#xD;
      investigation. Up to 50 adolescents and young adults (age 12-20) will be recruited to treat&#xD;
      up to 40 with liraglutide for 16 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 21, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in BMI</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The change in BMI (kg/m2) measured from the baseline visit to the week 16 visit will be used to inform a power calculation for a subsequent trial.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Fat Mass</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in fat mass (in kg) from baseline to the week 16 visit</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in BMI</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The change in BMI (kg/m2) from baseline to the week 16 visit</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <condition>Status Post Sleeve Gastrectomy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Liraglutide</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treated with Liraglutide</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Liraglutide</intervention_name>
    <description>Liraglutide by subcutaneous injection administered daily. Dose will be initiated at 0.6mg per day and increased to a maximum of 3.0 mg per day as tolerated.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Liraglutide</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In order to be eligible to participate in this study, an individual must meet all of the&#xD;
        following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female, 12-20.999 years at screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. 12 months or more status-post vertical sleeve gastrectomy with a maximum of 10 years&#xD;
             after surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. BMI 30 kg/m2 or greater than or equal to 95th percentile for age and sex&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. In good general health as evidenced by medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Ability to take subcutaneous medication and be willing to adhere to the daily&#xD;
             subcutaneous liraglutide regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Ability to provide consent/assent before any trial-related activities as required per&#xD;
             protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Stated availability for the duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        An individual who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from participation&#xD;
        in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Current or recent (within 3 months of start of study drug initiation) use of weight&#xD;
             loss medications such as phentermine, topiramate, lisdexamfetamine (prescribed&#xD;
             specifically for weight loss; when prescribed for ADHD and dose is stable for last 3&#xD;
             months this medication will be allowed), orlistat, and naltrexone HCl/bupropion HCl,&#xD;
             or liraglutide&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Weight of more than 450 lbs. (because Dual-Energy X-ray Absorptiometry (DXA) scanning&#xD;
             cannot be done in those exceeding this weight)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current use of insulin or sulfonylurea or other medication affecting insulin secretion&#xD;
             or GLP1 clearance such as a DPPIV inhibitor&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Weight loss of more than 3% of body weight in the past 2 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Current pregnancy, desire to become pregnant within study period, current lactation&#xD;
             or, if sexually active, not willing to use adequate contraceptive measures&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of recurrent pancreatitis (greater than 2 episodes)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of chronic kidney disease (eGFR &lt;60)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of gastroparesis&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Personal or family history of medullary thyroid carcinoma or multiple endocrine&#xD;
             neoplasia syndrome type 2&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of prior metabolic and bariatric surgery other than vertical sleeve&#xD;
             gastrectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Current or prior use of any GLP-1 agonist medication during the 6 months before&#xD;
             screening, including liraglutide.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Known or suspected allergy to trial medication, excipients, or related products&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Treatment with another investigational drug or other experimental intervention within&#xD;
             3 months prior to enrollment in this trial&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Individuals who have current substance abuse or a DSM 5 Axis I psychiatric disorder or&#xD;
             DSM Axis II Mental Retardation diagnosis that in the opinion of the investigators&#xD;
             would impede competence, compliance, or participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Suicidal ideation type 4 or 5, history of past suicide attempt, and suicidal behavior&#xD;
             in the past month&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Presence of a major medical illness not listed above&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>20 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jack A Yanovski, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Anna Zenno, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 451-0396</phone>
    <email>anna.zenno@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_000241-CH.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kelly AS, Auerbach P, Barrientos-Perez M, Gies I, Hale PM, Marcus C, Mastrandrea LD, Prabhu N, Arslanian S; NN8022-4180 Trial Investigators. A Randomized, Controlled Trial of Liraglutide for Adolescents with Obesity. N Engl J Med. 2020 May 28;382(22):2117-2128. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1916038. Epub 2020 Mar 31.</citation>
    <PMID>32233338</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pi-Sunyer X, Astrup A, Fujioka K, Greenway F, Halpern A, Krempf M, Lau DC, le Roux CW, Violante Ortiz R, Jensen CB, Wilding JP; SCALE Obesity and Prediabetes NN8022-1839 Study Group. A Randomized, Controlled Trial of 3.0 mg of Liraglutide in Weight Management. N Engl J Med. 2015 Jul 2;373(1):11-22. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1411892.</citation>
    <PMID>26132939</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Inge TH, Courcoulas AP, Jenkins TM, Michalsky MP, Helmrath MA, Brandt ML, Harmon CM, Zeller MH, Chen MK, Xanthakos SA, Horlick M, Buncher CR; Teen-LABS Consortium. Weight Loss and Health Status 3 Years after Bariatric Surgery in Adolescents. N Engl J Med. 2016 Jan 14;374(2):113-23. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1506699. Epub 2015 Nov 6.</citation>
    <PMID>26544725</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 30, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Children</keyword>
  <keyword>glucagon-like peptide</keyword>
  <keyword>Weight Loss</keyword>
  <keyword>pharmacotherapy for obesity</keyword>
  <keyword>Bariatric Surgery</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

