<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04888455</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>633491 - DOLORisk WP4</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04888455</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>DOLORisk: Research on Risk Factors and Determinants for Neuropathic Pain</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Influence of Sensory Phenotype on the Risk of Developing Neuropathic Pain</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Kiel</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Horizon 2020 - European Commission</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut National de la Santé Et de la Recherche Médicale, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Oxford</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Imperial College London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Technion, Israel Institute of Technology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Aarhus</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Aarhus University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Kiel</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients with neuropathic pain of multiple etiologies and a control cohort of patients with&#xD;
      the same neuropathic entities who did not develop neuropathic pain are examined clinically,&#xD;
      phenotyped with QST and questionnaires. Both groups are analyzed in order to find risk&#xD;
      factors for painful neuropathy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients with probable (presence of a combination of symptoms and signs of neuropathy include&#xD;
      any two or more of the following: neuropathic symptoms, decreased distal sensation, or&#xD;
      unequivocally decreased or absent ankle reflexes) or confirmed (presence of an abnormality of&#xD;
      NC or validated measure of small fiber neuropathy with class 1 evidence with corresponding&#xD;
      symptoms) neuropathy are included. Patients are then further divided into those with painful&#xD;
      and painless neuropathy according to the NeuPSIG algorithm. Patients with probable or&#xD;
      definite neuropathic pain are classified as painful neuropathy, those with unlikely&#xD;
      neuropathic pain classified as painless neuropathy (with concomitant nociceptive pain of&#xD;
      other origin, e.g. headache etc.). Patients with possible neuropathic pain are excluded from&#xD;
      analysis as are patients with skin lesions or dermatological disorders in the areas to be&#xD;
      tested upon QST, with any painful or neurological comorbidity that could otherwise influence&#xD;
      testing results such as vascular disease, radiculopathy, spinal canal stenosis etc. Inclusion&#xD;
      was restricted to patients with polyneuropathy to make the investigated patient sample as&#xD;
      homogenous as possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age, gender, BMI, ethnicity, years in education, family history of chronic pain, etiology of&#xD;
      neuropathy, presence of early traumatic events and hospital admissions, smoking and alcohol&#xD;
      habits, pain characteristics (von Korff, BPSI, NPSI), emotional well-being (PROMIS&#xD;
      depression/ anxiety), personality (TIPI, IPIP, PCS), severity of neuropathy are assessed and&#xD;
      QST performed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Day</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>to identify possible risk factors or predictors for a painful polyneuropathy</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>to retrospectively analyse questionnaires, clinical findings and quantitative sensory testing in patients with painful and painless neuropathy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1550</enrollment>
  <condition>Neuropathic Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Painful neuropathy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with presence of probable (presence of a combination of symptoms and signs of neuropathy include any two or more of the following: neuropathic symptoms, decreased distal sensation, or unequivocally decreased or absent ankle reflexes) or confirmed (presence of an abnormality of NC or validated measure of small fiber neuropathy with class 1 evidence with corresponding symptoms) neuropathy AND with probable or definite neuropathic pain according to the NeuPSIG algorithm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Painless neuropathy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with presence of probable (presence of a combination of symptoms and signs of neuropathy include any two or more of the following: neuropathic symptoms, decreased distal sensation, or unequivocally decreased or absent ankle reflexes) or confirmed (presence of an abnormality of NC or validated measure of small fiber neuropathy with class 1 evidence with corresponding symptoms) neuropathy AND with unlikely neuropathic pain according to the NeuPSIG algorithm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Quantitative sensory testing (QST)</intervention_name>
    <description>Demographic data, pain characteristics, health status, emotional well-being, personality and lifestyle are assessed by questionnaires. Additionally, all patients underwent a clinical neurological examination and quantitative sensory testing (QST) according to the German Research Network on Neuropathic Pain (DFNS).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Painful neuropathy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Painless neuropathy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Different Questionnaires</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        In- and outpatients with presence of probable (presence of a combination of symptoms and&#xD;
        signs of neuropathy include any two or more of the following: neuropathic symptoms,&#xD;
        decreased distal sensation, or unequivocally decreased or absent ankle reflexes) or&#xD;
        confirmed (presence of an abnormality of NC or validated measure of small fiber neuropathy&#xD;
        with class 1 evidence with corresponding symptoms) neuropathy. Patients are then further&#xD;
        divided into those with painful and painless neuropathy according to the NeuPSIG algorithm.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Diagnosis of Polyneuropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with polyneuropathy and possible neuropathic pain&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with skin lesions or dermatological disorders in the areas to be tested upon&#xD;
             QST&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any painful or neurological comorbidity that could otherwise influence&#xD;
             testing results such as vascular disease, radiculopathy, spinal canal stenosis etc.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David Bennett, Prof.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University of Oxford</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kiel</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kiel</city>
        <state>Schleswig-Holstein</state>
        <zip>24105</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30756091/</url>
    <description>Study protocol</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pascal MMV, Themistocleous AC, Baron R, Binder A, Bouhassira D, Crombez G, Finnerup NB, Gierthmühlen J, Granovsky Y, Groop L, Hebert HL, Jensen TS, Johnsen K, McCarthy MI, Meng W, Palmer CNA, Rice ASC, Serra J, Solà R, Yarnitsky D, Smith BH, Attal N, Bennett DLH. DOLORisk: study protocol for a multi-centre observational study to understand the risk factors and determinants of neuropathic pain. Version 2. Wellcome Open Res. 2019 Feb 1 [revised 2019 Jan 1];3:63. doi: 10.12688/wellcomeopenres.14576.2. eCollection 2018.</citation>
    <PMID>30756091</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Kiel</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Janne Gierthmuhlen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prof. Dr. med.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>pain prevention</keyword>
  <keyword>painful neuropathy,</keyword>
  <keyword>painless neuropathy</keyword>
  <keyword>QST</keyword>
  <keyword>patient-reported outcomes</keyword>
  <keyword>PRO</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

