<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04883619</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CR109008</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-005568-79</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>80202135LUN2001</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04883619</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Nipocalimab in Adult Participants With Active Lupus Nephritis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2, Multicenter, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Study of Nipocalimab in Adult Participants With Active Lupus Nephritis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of nipocalimab versus placebo in&#xD;
      participants with active Lupus Nephritis (LN).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      LN is a heterogeneous autoimmune disease that includes a broad spectrum of clinical forms,&#xD;
      ranging from those with lesions confined to the skin (cutaneous lupus erythematosus [CLE]) to&#xD;
      others that involve one or more vital internal organs (systemic lupus erythematosus [SLE]).&#xD;
      Renal involvement due to SLE is termed LN. Nipocalimab (also referred to as JNJ-80202135 or&#xD;
      M281) is a fully human aglycosylated immunoglobulin (Ig) G1 monoclonal antibody designed to&#xD;
      selectively bind, saturate, and block the IgG binding site on the endogenous neonatal&#xD;
      fragment crystallizable receptor (FcRn). By targeting the IgG binding site on FcRn,&#xD;
      nipocalimab is expected to block the binding and, hence, recycling of IgG into circulation,&#xD;
      resulting in a decrease in circulating IgG antibody levels, including pathogenic IgG&#xD;
      autoantibodies and alloantibodies. The study will consist of a screening period (less than or&#xD;
      equal to [&lt;=] 8 Week), double-blind treatment period (52 Week), and a safety follow-up period&#xD;
      (6 Week). Safety assessment will include adverse events (AEs), serious adverse events (SAEs),&#xD;
      laboratory parameters (hematology and chemistry) and vital signs. The total duration of the&#xD;
      main study is up to 66 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 26, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 27, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 11, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Achieving Complete Renal Response (CRR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants achieving complete renal response will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Achieving CRR</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 24</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants achieving CRR will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Achieving at Least 50 Percent (%) Decrease in Proteinuria from Baseline, Week 24 and Week 52</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 24 and Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants achieving at least 50% decrease in proteinuria will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Achieving a Sustained Reduction in Steroid Dose Less Than or Equal to (&lt;=)10 milligram (mg)/day of Prednisone or Equivalent</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 16 to Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants achieving a sustained reduction in steroid dose &lt;= 10 mg/day of prednisone or equivalent will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Treatment-emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 66</time_frame>
    <description>An adverse event (AE) is any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical study participant administered a pharmaceutical (investigational or non investigational) product. An AE does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the pharmaceutical/biological agent under study. TEAEs are defined as AEs with onset or worsening on or after date of first dose of study treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Treatment-emergent Serious Adverse Events (TESAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 66</time_frame>
    <description>A serious adverse event is any untoward medical occurrence that at any dose results in death, is life-threatening, requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of existing hospitalization, results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity, is a congenital anomaly/birth defect, is a suspected transmission of any infectious agent via a medicinal product. TESAEs are defined as SAEs with onset or worsening on or after date of first dose of study treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Treatment-emergent AEs Leading to Discontinuation of Study Intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with treatment-emergent AEs leading to discontinuation of study intervention will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Treatment-emergent Adverse Events of Special Interests (AESIs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 58</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with treatment-emergent AESIs will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Change from Baseline in Laboratory Parameters Over Time</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to week 58</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with change from baseline in laboratory parameters (hematology and chemistry) will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Change from Baseline in Vital Sign Parameters Over Time</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to week 58</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with change from baseline in vital sign parameters (temperature, pulse/heart rate, respiratory rate, and blood pressure) will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum Concentration of Nipocalimab Over Time</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 58</time_frame>
    <description>Serum concentrations of nipocalimab over time in participants receiving active study intervention will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Antibodies to Nipocalimab (Anti-Drug Antibodies [ADAs] and Neutralizing Antibodies [Nabs])</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 58</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with antibodies to nipocalimab (ADAs and Nabs) in participants receiving active study intervention will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Lupus Nephritis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive placebo intravenously (IV) every two weeks (q2w) from Week 0 through Week 50 along with standard-of-care treatment of mycophenolate mofetil (MMF) or mycophenolic acid (MPA) and glucocorticoid. Participants who will complete the assessments at Week 52 and have achieved complete renal response (CRR) may have the option to participate in the long-term extension (LTE) until unblinding of the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Nipocalimab Dose 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive nipocalimab dose 1 IV q2w from Week 0 through Week 50 along with standard-of-care treatment of MMF or MPA and glucocorticoid. Participants who will complete the assessments at Week 52 and have achieved CRR may have the option to participate in the LTE of the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3: Nipocalimab Dose 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive nipocalimab dose 2 IV q2w from Week 0 through Week 50 along with standard-of-care treatment of MMF or MPA and glucocorticoid. Participants who will complete the assessments at Week 52 and have achieved CRR may have the option to participate in the LTE of the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo will be administered intravenously.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nipocalimab</intervention_name>
    <description>Nipocalimab dose 1 and dose 2 will be administered intravenously.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Nipocalimab Dose 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3: Nipocalimab Dose 2</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>JNJ-80202135</other_name>
    <other_name>M281</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard-of-care treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard-of-care treatment including MMF or MPA and glucocorticoids will be administered intravenously through Week 52.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Nipocalimab Dose 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3: Nipocalimab Dose 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Kidney biopsy documentation of International Society of Nephrology (ISN)/Renal&#xD;
             Pathology Society (RPS) proliferative nephritis: Class III or IV (with or without&#xD;
             concomitant Class V) within the last 6 months prior to screening or performed during&#xD;
             screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Urine Protein to Creatinine Ratio (UPCR) greater than or equal to (&gt;=) 1.0&#xD;
             milligram/milligram (mg/mg) measured twice during screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently receiving prednisone equivalent dose of 1 milligram/kilogram/day (mg/kg/day)&#xD;
             or less than or equal to (&lt;=) 60 mg/day whichever is lower, or less. Must be receiving&#xD;
             prednisone equivalent of 10 mg/day or more at screening and randomization. Treated for&#xD;
             &gt;= 6 weeks with stable dosing &gt;= 2 weeks prior to first administration of study&#xD;
             intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If receiving angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitor/angiotensin II receptor&#xD;
             blockers (ARB), a stable dose for at least 2 weeks prior to first administration of&#xD;
             study intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is recommended to be up-to-date on all age-appropriate vaccinations prior to screening&#xD;
             per routine local medical guidelines. For study participants who received&#xD;
             locally-approved (and including emergency use-authorized) coronavirus disease 2019&#xD;
             (COVID-19) vaccines recently prior to study entry, follow applicable local vaccine&#xD;
             labelling, guidelines, and standards-of-care for patients receiving immune-targeted&#xD;
             therapy when determining an appropriate interval between vaccination and study&#xD;
             enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Comorbidities (other than Lupus Nephritis, example, asthma, chronic obstructive&#xD;
             pulmonary disease) which have required 3 or more courses of systemic glucocorticoids&#xD;
             within the previous 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has other inflammatory diseases that might confound the evaluations of efficacy,&#xD;
             including but not limited to rheumatoid arthritis (RA), psoriatic arthritis (PsA),&#xD;
             RA/lupus overlap, psoriasis, Crohn's disease, or active Lyme disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received oral cyclophosphamide within 3 months or intravenous (IV)&#xD;
             cyclophosphamide within 6 months prior to first administration of study intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of latent or active granulomatous infection, including histoplasmosis or&#xD;
             coccidioidomycosis, before screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 infection: During the 6 weeks prior to baseline, have had any of the&#xD;
             following (a) confirmed severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2)&#xD;
             infection (test positive), or (b) suspected SARS-CoV-2 infection (clinical features of&#xD;
             COVID-19 without documented test results), or (c) close contact with a person with&#xD;
             known or suspected SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC Clinical Trial</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Study Contact</last_name>
    <phone>844-434-4210</phone>
    <email>JNJ.CT@sylogent.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Arizona Arthritis and Rheumatology Research, PLLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Glendale</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85306</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Arizona Arthritis &amp; Rheumatology Research, PLLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mesa</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Arthritis &amp; Osteoporosis Medical Center - La Palma</name>
      <address>
        <city>La Palma</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90623</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Valerius Medical Group &amp; Research Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Alamitos</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90720</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Florida</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32610</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Integral Rheumatology &amp; Immunology Specialists</name>
      <address>
        <city>Plantation</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33324</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Davita Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>El Paso</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>79925</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Next Innovative Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77021</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hopital Henri Mondor</name>
      <address>
        <city>Creteil</city>
        <zip>94010</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Pitié-Salpétrière</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75013</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>APHP - Hopital Bichat - Claude Bernard</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75877</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Rangueil</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse</city>
        <zip>31400</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Bretonneau</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tours</city>
        <zip>37000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Klinikum der Universität München</name>
      <address>
        <city>München</city>
        <zip>80336</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Münster</name>
      <address>
        <city>Münster</city>
        <zip>48149</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Prince Of Wales Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hong Kong</city>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Queen Mary Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hong Kong</city>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tuen Mun Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hong Kong</city>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Carmel Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hifa</city>
        <zip>34362</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rabin Medical Center, Beilinson Campus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Petah Tikva</city>
        <zip>49100</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sheba Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ramat Gan</city>
        <zip>5265601</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Policlinico di Bari</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bari</city>
        <zip>70124</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AOU Careggi</name>
      <address>
        <city>Firenze</city>
        <zip>50134</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ospedale San Raffaele, IRCCS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milan</city>
        <zip>20132</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Federico II</name>
      <address>
        <city>Napoli</city>
        <zip>80131</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AOU di Padova</name>
      <address>
        <city>Padova</city>
        <zip>35128</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istituti Clinici Scientifici Maugeri</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pavia</city>
        <zip>27100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ospedale San Giovanni Bosco</name>
      <address>
        <city>Torino</city>
        <zip>10125</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kyungpook National University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Daegu</city>
        <zip>42415</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Keimyung University Dongsan Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Daegu</city>
        <zip>42601</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Severance Hospital, Yonsei University Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>03722</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Konkuk University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>05030</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ajou University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Suwon-si</city>
        <zip>16499</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chbv - Hosp. Infante D. Pedro</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aveiro</city>
        <zip>3810-193</zip>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ccab - Hosp. de Braga</name>
      <address>
        <city>Braga</city>
        <zip>4710-243</zip>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chlo - Hosp. Egas Moniz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lisboa</city>
        <zip>1349-019</zip>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chln - Hosp. Santa Maria</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lisboa</city>
        <zip>1649-035</zip>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Panorama Medical Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cape Town</city>
        <zip>7500</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Umhlanga Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durban</city>
        <zip>4321</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Research Unit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pretoria</city>
        <zip>0001</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kaohsiung Chang Gung Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kaohsiung</city>
        <zip>83301</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>China Medical University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taichung</city>
        <zip>40447</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Taichung Veterans General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taichung</city>
        <zip>40705</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Communal Noncommercial Enterprise 'Cherkasy Regional Hospital of Cherkasy Regional Council'</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cherkasy</city>
        <zip>18009</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Municipal Non-Profit Enterprise 'Chernihiv Regional Hospital' of Chernihiv Regional Council</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chernihiv</city>
        <zip>14029</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ce 'Dnipropetrovsk Regional Clinical Hospital N.A. Mechnikov' of Dnipropetrovsk Rc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dnipro</city>
        <zip>49005</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City Clinical Emergency Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kharkiv</city>
        <zip>61103</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Municipal Non-Profit Enterprise of Kharkiv Regional Council 'Regional Clinical Hospital'</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kharkiv</city>
        <zip>61204</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Municipal Enterprise &amp;#39;Kryvyi Rih City Clinical Hospital #2&amp;#39; Kryvyi Rih City Council</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kryvyi Rig</city>
        <zip>50056</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical Center LLC 'Harmony of Beauty'</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kyiv</city>
        <zip>01135</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical Center of 'Institute of Rheumatology', LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kyiv</city>
        <zip>02081</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical Center 'Ok Clinic' of International Institute of Clinical Research LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kyiv</city>
        <zip>02091</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kyiv Railway Clinical Hospital #2 Of Branch 'Health Center' Of The Company 'Ukrainian Railway'</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kyiv</city>
        <zip>03049</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Volyn Regional Clinical Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lutsk</city>
        <zip>43000</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Communal Nonprofit Enterprise of Lviv Regional Council 'Lviv Regional Clinical Hospital'</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lviv</city>
        <zip>79010</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Municipal Non-profit Enterprise 'Odesa Regional Clinical Hospital' Odesa Regional Council</name>
      <address>
        <city>Odesa</city>
        <zip>65025</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>ME 'Poltava Regional Clinical Hospital named after M.V. Sklifosovsky of Poltava Regional Consuil'</name>
      <address>
        <city>Poltava</city>
        <zip>36011</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Municipal Non-commercial Enterprise 'Ternopil University Hospital' of Ternopil Regional Council</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ternopil</city>
        <zip>46002</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MNCE Zakarpatska Regional Clinical Hospital named after A Novak of Zakarpatska Regional Council</name>
      <address>
        <city>Uzhgorod</city>
        <zip>88000</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical Center LLC 'Modern Clinic'</name>
      <address>
        <city>Zaporizhzhya</city>
        <zip>69600</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
    <country>Israel</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
    <country>Portugal</country>
    <country>South Africa</country>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
    <country>Ukraine</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
    <country>Panama</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://pam.sylogent.com/cr/CR109008</url>
    <description>To learn how to participate in this trial please click here.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nephritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lupus Nephritis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data sharing policy of the Janssen Pharmaceutical Companies of Johnson &amp; Johnson is available at www.janssen.com/clinical trials/transparency. As noted on this site, requests for access to the study data can be submitted through Yale Open Data Access (YODA) Project site at yoda.yale.edu</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

