<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04884633</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>17-29009A</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04884633</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Novel Method of Pancreatic Islet Transplantation Into the Omentum</brief_title>
  <official_title>Novel Method of Pancreatic Islet Transplantation Into the Omentum</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Frantisek Saudek</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institute for Clinical and Experimental Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators propose to conduct a pilot clinical study in 10 type 1 diabetic subjects&#xD;
      suffering from hypoglycemia unawareness syndrome and episodes of severe hypoglycemia, in&#xD;
      which therapy with transplantation of allogeneic pancreatic islets would be indicated&#xD;
      according to current criteria at the Institute for Clinical and Experimental Medicine (IKEM).&#xD;
      Pancreatic islets will be isolated and prepared for transplantation using the established&#xD;
      laboratory technique with minor modifications corresponding to latest knowledge. In contrast&#xD;
      to present routine, the islet preparation will not be administered percutaneously into the&#xD;
      portal vein but will be placed on the surface of an omental pouch using a (mini) laparoscopic&#xD;
      approach. Cell adherence will be achieved by addition of clinical-grade human thrombin that&#xD;
      reacts with plasma to create a biocompatible, degradable gel containing the islet graft. The&#xD;
      study will be performed in close collaboration with the Diabetes Research Institute (DRI) in&#xD;
      Miami, which will provide expert assistance and technical training if needed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Despite continuing progress in pharmacological insulin substitution, insulin administration&#xD;
      and monitoring of glucose levels, type 1 diabetes has been still associated with specific&#xD;
      late organ complications. While the main pathophysiological factor for their development is&#xD;
      chronic hyperglycemia, the critical limiting factor for achieving normal or near-normal blood&#xD;
      glucose levels remains to be the risk of hypoglycemia. Stable glucose levels near the normal&#xD;
      range maintained without the fear of low excursions have been so far achieved only by organ&#xD;
      pancreas or islet transplantation, however at the cost of surgical procedure and lifelong&#xD;
      immunosuppression to prevent rejection of the graft and recurrence of the autoimmune process.&#xD;
      Transplantation is therefore considered only in patients with serious complications of&#xD;
      diabetes in whom the quality of life is unacceptable. This group now includes also subjects&#xD;
      with hypoglycemia unawareness syndrome complicated by severe life-threatening hypoglycemic&#xD;
      episodes, in whom qualified medical treatment including available technological support&#xD;
      failed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Most islet transplantations are currently performed by a minimally invasive technique via&#xD;
      infusion into the portal vein with subsequent seeding in the liver. This way of implantation,&#xD;
      however, still bares significant risks of bleeding during the percutaneous portal&#xD;
      catheterization or portal thrombosis. Several other factors suggest that the liver may not be&#xD;
      the optimal site for islet infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The optimal place for the islet graft should be based on minimally-invasive transplant&#xD;
      procedure, allow to use relatively large volumes of tissue (e.g., for low purity&#xD;
      preparations), enable noninvasive longitudinal monitoring and access for biopsy. Portal blood&#xD;
      drainage would be preferable to reproduce physiological metabolic responses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These requirements might fulfill implantation into the omentum as it represents a large,&#xD;
      well-vascularized surface and the capillary beds lie directly under the mesothelium. Omentum&#xD;
      is easily accessible and venous blood is drained into the portal system (as from the native&#xD;
      islets). A technique for human islet transplantation into the omentum has recently been&#xD;
      developed in the Diabetes Research Institute in Miami under the leadership of C. Ricordi. The&#xD;
      Miami group demonstrated, that the islets re-suspended in either donor or autologous plasma&#xD;
      and distributed in the omental pouch did not stick together and allowed regular distribution&#xD;
      on the omentum surface. Better cell adherence was achieved by addition of clinical-grade&#xD;
      human thrombin which supported development of a biocompatible, degradable gel containing the&#xD;
      islet graft. This technology, which does not include any ex vivo biological manipulation with&#xD;
      the islet cells (and does not therefore fall under the term &quot;modern therapy&quot; in EU], does not&#xD;
      require the use of any officially yet not approved drugs or medical instruments, could be&#xD;
      directly applied in a pilot clinical experiment and help to speed up the development of a&#xD;
      more efficient and safer method for islet transplantation in type 1 diabetic subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators propose to conduct a pilot clinical study in 10 type 1 diabetic subjects&#xD;
      suffering from hypoglycemia unawareness syndrome and episodes of severe hypoglycemia, in&#xD;
      which therapy with transplantation of allogeneic pancreatic islets would be indicated&#xD;
      according to current criteria at the Institute for Clinical and Experimental Medicine (IKEM).&#xD;
      Pancreatic islets will be isolated and prepared for transplantation using the established&#xD;
      labora¬tory technique with minor modifications corresponding to latest knowledge. In contrast&#xD;
      to present routine, the islet preparation will not be administered percutaneously into the&#xD;
      portal vein but will be placed on the surface of an omental pouch using a (mini) laparoscopic&#xD;
      approach. Cell adherence will be achieved by addition of clinical-grade human thrombin that&#xD;
      reacts with plasma to create a biocompatible, degradable gel containing the islet graft.&#xD;
      Study procedures will be based on the protocol developed by the DRI with modifications&#xD;
      resulting from experience of the applicant´s team and equipment of local facilities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is expected to include altogether 10 type-1 diabetic subjects with either&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. problematic hypoglycemia refractory to medical therapy including intensive insulin&#xD;
      therapy, education and use of technological aids, or 2. end-stage kidney disease, who are&#xD;
      eligible for kidney transplantation, but not eligible for whole organ pancreas&#xD;
      transplantation due to a too high surgical risk&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria (in brief) The inclusion and exclusion criteria of the study meet the&#xD;
      standard inclusion and exclusion criteria for islet transplantation with the following&#xD;
      specifications and are listed (abbreviated) in the Eligibility section. Excluded will be&#xD;
      subjects with Body Mass Index (BMI) &gt;30 kg/m2 or patient weight ≤50 kg and glomerular&#xD;
      filtration rate &lt;80 mL/min/1.73 m2. Additional exclusion criteria specified in the full&#xD;
      protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Islet isolation from a compatible donor will be performed following standardized isolation&#xD;
      protocol used in IKEM. The islets will be cultivated for up to 36 hours at 37°C in CMRL&#xD;
      medium without any biological modification. The eligibility of the candidate will be&#xD;
      reassessed by clinical and laboratory examination. Should a sufficient amount of islets&#xD;
      (allowing to transplant 4000 IEQ/kg of the recipient) be obtained, the candidate will be&#xD;
      prepared for the surgical mini-laparotomy procedure and the induction immunosuppressive&#xD;
      therapy will be initiated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After cultivation the islet cells will be collected, centrifuged, and after removing the&#xD;
      su-pernatant, reconstituted in recipient's own plasma, the final ratio being 2:1 plasma to&#xD;
      pellet. The operation will be conducted in general anesthesia by laparoscopic approach or&#xD;
      under general anesthesia during the kidney transplant procedure (combined islet and kidney&#xD;
      transplantation). The islet suspension will be aspired with a pipette and distributed on a&#xD;
      suitable part of the omental surface (approx. 9x9 cm). Human thrombin, reconstituted from&#xD;
      routinely used &quot;surgical glue&quot; preparation Tisseel Lyo® (Baxter) (or by another clinically&#xD;
      approved preparation of thrombin) approximately in the same volume as the islet suspension,&#xD;
      will be spread as another layer onto the islets to promote formation of a biodegradable gel&#xD;
      containing the islet graft. This should facilitate the adherence to the omental surface and&#xD;
      prevent the islets of pelleting. Omentum will then be gently folded to create a pouch and&#xD;
      secured in place with stiches if necessary. The operation should last no more than 1-2 hours.&#xD;
      The patients will be followed at the intensive care unit for a short time after the surgery&#xD;
      with subsequent care at the intermediate care unit as usual after islet transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As for the immunosuppression regimen, the induction will consist of 3 doses of&#xD;
      anti-T-lymphocyte globulin starting the day before transplant. Prophylactic immunosuppression&#xD;
      will consist of a combination of tacrolimus (target trough levels 10-12 ng/ml tapered after 3&#xD;
      months to 6-10 ng/ml) and mycophenolate mofetil (1-2 g per day). In addition, etanercept (a&#xD;
      TNF-α inhibitor) will be administered before the transplant (50 mg sc.) with subsequent doses&#xD;
      of 25 mg on day 3, 7 and 10. Only a single dose of corticosteroids will be used before the&#xD;
      first ATG infusion. All these drugs represent standard medical therapy after pancreas or&#xD;
      islet transplantation in IKEM. A standard antibiotic and antiviral therapy will be&#xD;
      administered according to the local policy in IKEM.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood glucose will be closely monitored and insulin administered with the aim to achieve&#xD;
      near-normal glucose levels to prevent islet exhaustion. Continuous subcutaneous glucose&#xD;
      monitors will be used after the dismissal from the hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The post-transplant study follow-up will include 16 clinical visits. In addition, the&#xD;
      recipients will be medically supervised as needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The clinical trial will aim at testing the safety and efficacy of the transplantation method.&#xD;
      The primary safety endpoint will be demonstrating patient ´s safety throughout all stages of&#xD;
      the trial. Primary efficacy endpoints will be achieving glycosylated HbA1c 53 mmol/mol at 1&#xD;
      year post-transplant and no severe hypoglycemia events from day 28 to 365 inclusive after the&#xD;
      islet transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary efficacy endpoints (in brief) will be the following: the percent of reduction in&#xD;
      insulin requirement, HbA1c levels, and response of C-peptide to stimulation by mixed meal&#xD;
      test. Glucose variability and hypoglycemia duration data acquired from the continuous glucose&#xD;
      monitoring system, quality of life measures (SF 36 questionnaire and diabetes treatment&#xD;
      satisfaction questionnaire). Standard procedures to evaluate the quality of diabetes control&#xD;
      (HYPO score, Clarke score, mixed meal test).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary safety endpoints: Safety, including incidence of post-transplant infections,&#xD;
      malignancies, morbidity, and other AEs (e.g., increased body weight and hypertension)&#xD;
      associated with conventional immunosuppression. Renal function as measured by serum&#xD;
      creatinine, GFR and other relevant laboratory parameters. Lipid profiles (triglycerides,&#xD;
      total cholesterol, LDL cholesterol, HDL cholesterol) over time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment of the incidence and severity of adverse effects related to the transplantation&#xD;
      procedure and immunosuppressive therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical evaluation Insulin needs will be estimated from the one-week self-report values.&#xD;
      Estimates of population means and confidence intervals for those means will be reported for&#xD;
      each follow-up visit. Numbers of severe hypoglycemic events will be estimated from the&#xD;
      self-report values obtained at each follow-up visit. HbA1c and serum creatinine levels will&#xD;
      be measured at study entry and at each follow-up visit. GFR will be estimated using the&#xD;
      updated CKD-MDRD method. Estimates of population means and confidence intervals for those&#xD;
      means will be reported for each follow-up visit. Linear mixed model methods will be used to&#xD;
      describe trends with time. Incidence of serious adverse experiences will be tabulated by body&#xD;
      system and graded by international Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events. In animal&#xD;
      experiments islet survival rates (fed normoglycemia), areas under the curves of blood glucose&#xD;
      and insulin during the intraperitoneal glucose tolerance test will be compared between the&#xD;
      groups using nonparametric Wilcoxon and Mann-Whithey tests and Caplan-Mayer survival plots if&#xD;
      applicable.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 15, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Treatment-Emergent Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The rate of serious adverse events</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Achieving good metabolic control of diabetes</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>achieving glycosylated HbA1c 53 mmol/mol at 1 year post-transplant and no severe hypoglycemia events from day 28 to 365 inclusive after the islet transplant.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insulin requirement</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The number of recipients with reduction of insulin dose by 50 percent or more</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>C-peptide</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The number of recipients with C-peptide response to stimulation by mixed meal test over 0.5 pmol/ml</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life assessed by the Short Form 36 questionnaire score</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the Quality of Life Questionnaire SF 36 and comparison the score with th pre-transplant status (only observational outcome) Diabetes treatment satisfaction questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Infections</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The number of recipients with severe or moderate treatment-related infections</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The rate of significat glomerula filtration rate reduction</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months and 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The number of recipients with a reduction of the estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) by 30 percent or more as compared with the pretransplant level</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">6</enrollment>
  <condition>Islets of Langerhans Transplantation</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pancreatic islet transplantation</intervention_name>
    <description>New method of pancreatic islet transplantation into the omentum using a biodegradable scaffold</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 20 to 65 years, ability to comply with the procedures of the study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical history of type 1 diabetes with onset at &lt; 40 years of age,&#xD;
             insulin-dependence for &gt; 5 years at the time of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absent stimulated C-peptide (&lt;0,3 ng/l) in response to mixed meal test measured at 60&#xD;
             and 90 minutes after the start of consumption.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Involvement in intensive diabetes management, defined as self-monitoring of glucose&#xD;
             values no less that mean of three times each day averaged over each week and by the&#xD;
             administration of three or more insulin injections each day or in-sulin pump.&#xD;
             Management under the direction of a diabetologist with at least 3 clin¬ical&#xD;
             evaluations during the12 months prior to study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least on episode of severe hypoglycemia in the 12 months prior to the study&#xD;
             enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reduced awareness of hypo glycaemia (as specified in detail in the full protocol)&#xD;
             during the screening period OR marked glycemic lability characterized by wide swings&#xD;
             in blood glucose despite optimal diabetes therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body Mass Index (BMI) &gt;30 kg/m2 or patient weight ≤50 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insulin requirement of &gt;1.0 IU/kg/day or &lt;15 U/day.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  glomerular filtration rate &lt;80 mL/min/1.73 m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Additional exclusion criteria specified in the full protocol&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Frantisek Saudek</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Institute for Clinical and Experimental Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Frantisek Saudek</last_name>
    <phone>603804597</phone>
    <email>frsa@medicon.cz</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lenka Nemétová</last_name>
    <email>neml@ikem.cz</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institute for Clinical and Experimental Medicine, Department of Diabetes</name>
      <address>
        <city>Prague</city>
        <zip>14021</zip>
        <country>Czechia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Frantisek Saudek, MD.</last_name>
      <email>frsa@medicon.cz</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Frantisek Saudek, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Zuzana Hladíková, MD.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Barbora Hagerf, MD.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Czechia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Institute for Clinical and Experimental Medicine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Frantisek Saudek</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD., prof.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pancreatic islets</keyword>
  <keyword>Transplantation</keyword>
  <keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Omentum</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

