<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04889807</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PO21031*</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04889807</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of End Tidal Carbon Dioxide (EtCO2) Variation After an End- Expiratory Occlusion Test as a Predictive Criteria of Fluid Responsiveness in Mechanically Ventilated Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>CapnoPause</acronym>
  <official_title>Study of End Tidal Carbon Dioxide (EtCO2) Variation After an End- Expiratory Occlusion Test as a Predictive Criteria of Fluid Responsiveness in Mechanically Ventilated Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>CHU de Reims</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>CHU de Reims</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Hypovolemia is one of major factor of haemodynamic instability. Fluid administration is not&#xD;
      totally riskless. Indeed, it can create or inflate pulmonary oedema, alter gaz exchanges and&#xD;
      increase post operative respiratory complications. Furthermore, fluid administration is not&#xD;
      always followed by a cardiac output increase.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Predicting preload responsiveness before administering fluid by reliable and reproductible&#xD;
      methods is necessary in critically ill patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dynamic indicators are approved at the bedside such as passive raising leg test, pulse&#xD;
      pressure variation, respiratory variation of the diameter of the superior vena cava. However,&#xD;
      all these tests cannot be used for all patients. For example in the cases of spine or pelvis&#xD;
      injury, or traumatic brain injury, patients with difficult condition for transthoracic&#xD;
      echography.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that EtCO2 (end tidal carbon dioxide) variation after an 15&#xD;
      seconds end-expiratory occlusion test could predict fluid responsiveness in mechanically&#xD;
      ventilated patients in the intensive care units.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EtCO2 is a parameter which can be easy to collect, reproductible, and totally non invasive.&#xD;
      This method could be especially appropriate for patients for whom the classical test of fluid&#xD;
      responsiveness cannot be used&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      For each patient under mechanical ventilation, answering inclusions and non inclusions&#xD;
      criteria, and eligible to a fluid perfusion, the physician in charge collect vital parameters&#xD;
      such as cardiac frequency, blood pressure, cardiac output and end tidal carbon dioxide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The cardiac output is measured by transthoracic echography, or invasive devices such as&#xD;
      transpulmonary thermodilution or pulmonary arterial catheter.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The physician achieve a 15 seconds interruption of mechanical ventilation at end expiration,&#xD;
      and collect the end tidal carbon dioxide variation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fluid perfusion of 500 ml of crystalloid is performed. Then the physician collect the same&#xD;
      vital parameters, including a new cardiac output measure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patients for whom the cardiac output increased about more than 15 percent are considered&#xD;
      as responders, the others are considered as non responders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Furthermore, socio demographic parameter, reason for admission, parameters of mechanical&#xD;
      ventilation, use of vasopressor drugs and water balance are collected.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Predictive capacity of the variation of end tidal carbon dioxide after an end expiratory occlusion test</measure>
    <time_frame>15 seconds</time_frame>
    <description>A receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve analysis will be performed to determine the sensitivity, the specificity, the positive and negative predictive values.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Preload Responsiveness</condition>
  <condition>Fluid Responsiveness</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients who need fluid perfusion</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>measure of EtCO2 variation</intervention_name>
    <description>measure of EtCO2 (end tidal carbon dioxide) variation after an 15 seconds end-expiratory occlusion test</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients who need fluid perfusion</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients in intensive care unit, under mechanical ventilation and eligible to a fluid&#xD;
        administration, who are capable to hold a 15 seconds end expiratory occlusion test.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  older than 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  critically ill patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  under mechanical ventilation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  whose cardiac output is measurable by transthoracic echography, or monitored by a&#xD;
             transpulmonary thermodilution catheter or pulmonary arterial catheter&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  eligible to a fluid perfusion, by the physician in charge appreciation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  younger than 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnant patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Elodie GELISSE</last_name>
    <phone>03 26 83 27 58</phone>
    <phone_ext>0033</phone_ext>
    <email>egelisse@chu-reims.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chu Reims</name>
      <address>
        <city>Reims</city>
        <zip>51092</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Damien JOLLY</last_name>
      <phone>326788472</phone>
      <phone_ext>33</phone_ext>
      <email>djolly@chu-reims.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

