<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04882306</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PROTOCOL-P2-054</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04882306</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The ABC Study: Assessment of Breast Density Classification</brief_title>
  <official_title>The ABC Study: Assessment of Breast Density Classification Via Algorithm Development Using Microwave Imaging in Breast Clinics</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Micrima, Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Micrima, Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The MARIA® breast imaging system is a CE-marked radiofrequency (RF) medical imaging device.&#xD;
      The system employs an electromagnetic imaging technique that exploits the dielectric contrast&#xD;
      between normal and cancerous tissues. It is the intention that MARIA® will be able to offer a&#xD;
      breast density classifier to clinician's but for this project to be successful, data is&#xD;
      required. This study will collect the data required for the classifier to be developed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The creation of the required dataset to develop the breast density classification algorithm</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Dataset of information containing ground truth breast density from mammogram</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The creation of that algorithm</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Using the current breast density algorithm developed for MARIA to analyse the MARIA images and compare that to the mammographic ground truth</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The assessment of the performance of that algorithm to measure breast density when compared to the ground truth of the Boyd score</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Analyse the values obtained from both the MARIA algorithm and the mammographic ground truth, and look for correlation using the Boyd percentage score of breast density.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Understand participant acceptability of the MARIA® scan</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Using a specially-designed patient questionnaire, analyse feedback on the MARIA scan experience using a scale from Very acceptable-Acceptable-Neither acceptable or unacceptable-Unacceptable-Very unacceptable.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">800</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Main study group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bilateral MARIA scan</intervention_name>
    <description>After consent has been given, the participant's breast will be fitted by the operator using a clear plastic cup to determine their corresponding MARIA® cup insert size. Once this has been determined, participants will be required to lie prone with their breast pendent through an aperture in the MARIA® patient bed. The cup insert will contain a layer of coupling fluid. The hemispherical cup inserts, and array are brought into contact with the breast. Depending on the patient's breast size, one or more cup inserts may be placed in the array to ensure a good but non-compressing fit between the breast and the system interface. The scan sequence will then be performed, this takes a couple of minutes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Main study group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  To be eligible to participate in this study, a subject must meet all the following&#xD;
             criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Attending a symptomatic or assessment breast clinic at the study site&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Female sex&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Able to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Not in any identified, vulnerable group&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A potential subject who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from&#xD;
             participation in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unable to mount MARIA® patient bed&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unable to lie in the prone position for a period of up to 15 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients who have undergone biopsy less than 5 days before the MARIA® scan&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with implanted electronics&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with breast implants&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with nipple piercings (unless they are removed prior to the MARIA® scan)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Breast sizes too small or too large to be suitable for the array&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants recruited the same day are not subject to any additional screening criteria&#xD;
        other than that described above. However, participants being recruited and consenting to&#xD;
        the use of previously- taken mammography will need to provide information on key points in&#xD;
        order to assess the eligibility of their mammograms for use. This will include information&#xD;
        on:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Whether they have initiated or discontinued use of a hormonal contraceptive since&#xD;
             their last mammogram&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Whether they have initiated or discontinued use of hormone replacement therapy since&#xD;
             their last mammogram&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Whether they believe that they have had a change in menopausal status since their last&#xD;
             mammogram Participants who answer yes to any of the above will not be eligible for&#xD;
             participation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

