<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04882774</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RECAP001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04882774</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Telemonitoring to Treat Group 2 Pulmonary Hypertension</brief_title>
  <acronym>RECAPTURE</acronym>
  <official_title>Telemonitoring to Treat Group 2 Pulmonary Hypertension: A Personalized Approach</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mardi Gomberg -Maitland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ohio State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Allegheny Singer Research Institute (also known as Allegheny Health Network Research Institute)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>George Washington University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to decrease elevated pressure in the lungs of patients with pulmonary&#xD;
      hypertension from left heart with elevated pulmonary vascular resistance by utilizing&#xD;
      aggressive fluid management with ReDS Pro System and CardioMEMS device. Participants with&#xD;
      persistently elevated pulmonary pressure at Week 16 will begin oral treprostinil in&#xD;
      combination with the fluid management plan while those with improved pressures maintain their&#xD;
      fluid management plan for an additional 16 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study hypothesizes that monitoring with ReDS-Pro System (ReDS), aggressive fluid&#xD;
      management, and the CardioMEMS device (a 3-prong approach) will improve CpcPH (combined pre&#xD;
      and post capillary pulmonary hypertension) hemodynamics (Total Pulmonary Resistance [TPR] and&#xD;
      mPAP). For patients who continue to have an elevate pulmonary vascular resistance (TPR) at&#xD;
      Week 16, with ReDS, aggressive fluid management, and the CardioMEMS device should allow&#xD;
      successful titration of oral treprostinil by preventing titration related pulmonary edema and&#xD;
      by improving hemodynamics, activity monitoring and six minute walk test (6MWT) after 16 weeks&#xD;
      of therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>32 week study in 30 subjects. Those who meet certain hemodynamic criteria at Week 16 will begin study drug and continue diuresis protocol while the remaining participants continue with the diuresis protocol only.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with normal lung impedance as measured by the ReDS vest in Ohms at Week 16</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants reaching normal lung impedance (&lt; 34 Ω) based on ReDS vest management.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with normal total pulmonary resistance as measured by CardioMEMS in Woods Units at Week 16</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants reaching normal total pulmonary resistance (&lt; 5 Woods Units) as measured by CardioMEMS.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants reaching normal lung impedance with oral treprostinil at Week 32</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants reaching normal lung impedance (&lt;34 Ω) from Week 16 to Week 32 with oral treprostinil administration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants reaching normal total pulmonary resistance with oral treprostinil at Week 32</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants reaching normal total pulmonary resistance (goal &lt; 5 U) from Week 16 to Week 32 with oral treprostinil administration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants decreasing six-minute walk distance with oral treprostinil at Week 32</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with a six-minute walk distance decrease of &gt;15% from Week 16 to Week 32 with oral treprostinil administration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants maintaining normal lung impedance as measured by the ReDS vest at Week 32</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants maintaining normal lung impedance (&lt; 34 Ω) from Week 16 to Week 32 as measured by ReDS vest.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants maintaining total pulmonary resistance as measured by CardioMEMS at Week 32</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants maintaining normal TPR (&lt; 5 U) from Week 16 to Week 32 as measured by CardioMEMS.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>WHO Functional Class</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Functional Class (FC) Week 16, 32.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cardiac output</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in cardiac output (L/min) as measured by CardioMEMS from Baseline to Week 16, 32.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cardiac index</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in cardiac index (L/min/m2) as measured by CardioMEMS from Baseline to Week 16, 32.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in right ventricular stroke volume</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in right ventricular stroke volume (mL) as measured by CardioMEMS from Baseline to Week 16, 32.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in stroke volume index</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in stroke volume index (mL/m2) as measured by CardioMEMS from Baseline to Week 16, 32.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in elastance</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in elastance (mmHg/mL) as measured by CardioMEMS from Baseline to Week 16, 32.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in compliance</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in compliance (mL/mmHg) as measured by CardioMEMS from Baseline to Week 16, 32.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in right ventricular power</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in right ventricular power (W) as measured by CardioMEMS from Baseline to Week 16, 32.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cardiac efficiency</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in cardiac efficiency (mL/mmHg) as measured by CardioMEMS from Baseline to Week 16, 32.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in right ventricular stroke work</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in right ventricular stroke work (mmHg/mL) as measured by CardioMEMS from Baseline to Week 16, 32.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in stroke work index</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in stroke work index (g x m/m2) as measured by CardioMEMS from Baseline to Week 16, 32.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in NT-proBNP</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in N-terminal pro-brain natriuretic peptide (NT-proBNP) levels from Baseline to Week 16, 32.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Kansas City Cardiomyopathy Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement in Kansas City Cardiomyopathy Questionnaire (KCCQ) at Baseline to Week 16 and baseline to Week 32. Scores are scaled from 0 to 100 and summarized in quartiles representing health status with higher scores indicating better status: 0 to 24=very poor to poor; 25 to 49=poor to fair; 50 to 74=fair to good; and 75 to 100= good to excellent.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension-Symptoms and Impact (PAH-SYMPACT) Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement in PAH-SYMPACT at Baseline to Week 16, Baseline to Week 32. Measured using the Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension-Symptoms and Impact (PAH-SYMPACT) Questionnaire with higher scores indicating greater symptom severity or worse impact: scale of 0=no, 1=mild, 2=moderate, 3=severe, and 4=very severe.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with heart failure exacerbation</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Adjudicated hospitalization or emergency department visits due to a heart failure decompensation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Six-minute walk test</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Decrease in 6MWT &gt;15% from Baseline (or too ill to walk) directly related to disease under study at 2 consecutive visits on different days.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants who experienced mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>32 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Heart failure related deaths and all-cause mortality.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Pulmonary Hypertension Due to Left Heart Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fluid Management</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Fluid management protocol only</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Oral Treprostinil</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drug - oral treprostinil</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Treprostinil Diolamine</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral treprostinil 0.125 mg TID titrated as clinically indicated and tolerated to a maximum of 6 mg TID</description>
    <arm_group_label>Oral Treprostinil</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject voluntarily gives informed consent to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject is 18 to 85 years of age (inclusive) at Baseline (i.e., date of providing&#xD;
             written informed consent).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has a diagnosis of heart failure with a LVEF ≥45% by ECHO completed prior&#xD;
             to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has a CardioMEMS device implanted as standard of care for a minimum of 30&#xD;
             days at Baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has pulmonary function tests conducted within 12 months of Baseline or to&#xD;
             confirm the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Total lung capacity is ≥ 60% of the predicted value.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Forced expiratory volume at 1 second (FEV1) is ≥50% of the predicted value.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Diffusing capacity of the lungs for carbon monoxide (DLCO) is ≥ 32% of the&#xD;
                  predicted value (unadjusted or adjusted for alveolar volume).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects should be on maximally tolerated HFpEF therapies (e.g., ACE inhibitors, ARBs,&#xD;
             beta blockers, SLG2 inhibitors) for ≥30 days prior to enrollment unless&#xD;
             contraindicated. The exception is with changes of anticoagulants and/or diuretics;&#xD;
             these medications should not be newly started or stopped within 14 days of enrollment&#xD;
             and no healthcare provider prescribed dose change should occur within 7 days of&#xD;
             enrollment, with the exception of the withholding of doses of anticoagulants for the&#xD;
             conduct of the RHC when required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the opinion of the Investigator, the subject is able to communicate effectively&#xD;
             with study personnel, and is considered reliable, willing, and likely to be&#xD;
             cooperative with protocol requirements, including attending all study visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects on chronic medications (e.g. inhaled corticosteroids, long-acting&#xD;
             beta2-adrenergic agonist, long-acting muscarinic antagonists, combination inhaled&#xD;
             drugs, anti-inflammatory drugs, oral/parenteral corticosteroids, or biologic agents)&#xD;
             for any underlying respiratory condition must be on a stable dose for ≥30 days prior&#xD;
             to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject is pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the opinion of the Principal Investigator, the subject has a primary diagnosis of&#xD;
             PH other than WHO Group 2 PH.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has shown intolerance or significant lack of efficacy to a prostacyclin or&#xD;
             prostacyclin analogue that resulted in discontinuation of therapy or inability to&#xD;
             effectively titrate that therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has received PAH therapies, including prostacyclin therapy (i.e.,&#xD;
             epoprostenol, treprostinil, iloprost, or beraprost; except for acute vasoreactivity&#xD;
             testing), nonprostanoid IP receptor agonist (selexipag), ERA, or soluble guanylate&#xD;
             cyclase stimulator, within 30 days of enrollment. If the Investigator does not intend&#xD;
             to keep a subject on their PDE5-I therapy, it must be stopped at least 30 days prior&#xD;
             to enrollment. Intermittent use of a PDE5-I (≤3 times per week) to treat erectile&#xD;
             dysfunction is permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has been hospitalized for a cardiopulmonary indication within 30 days of&#xD;
             randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject had a myocardial infarction within 90 days of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject had cardiac resynchronization therapy within 90 days of enrollment or&#xD;
             anticipated resynchronization therapy during the study treatment period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has liver function tests (aspartate aminotransferase [AST] or alanine&#xD;
             aminotransferase [ALT]) greater than 3 times the upper limit of normal at Screening,&#xD;
             clinically significant liver disease/dysfunction per Investigator's clinical&#xD;
             judgement, known Child-Pugh Class C hepatic disease or noncirrhotic portal&#xD;
             hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has uncontrolled systemic hypertension, defined as a systolic blood&#xD;
             pressure &gt;160 mmHg or a diastolic blood pressure &gt;110 mmHg at Baseline on more than&#xD;
             one occasion during screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has a systolic blood pressure &lt;100 mmHg at Baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has a resting heart rate &gt;110 beats per minute at Baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has sarcoidosis or cardiac amyloidosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has a known history of any LVEF less than 40% by ECHO within 3 years of&#xD;
             enrollment. Note: a transient decline in LVEF below 40% that occurred and recovered&#xD;
             more than 6 months before the start of Screening and was associated with an acute&#xD;
             intercurrent condition (e.g., atrial fibrillation) is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has hemodynamically significant valvular heart disease as determined by&#xD;
             the Investigator, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Greater than mild aortic and/or mitral stenosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Severe mitral and/or aortic regurgitation (&gt;Grade 3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has a body mass index &gt;45 kg/m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has any musculoskeletal disorder (e.g., arthritis affecting the lower&#xD;
             limbs, recent hip or knee joint replacement, artificial leg), or has any other&#xD;
             condition that would likely be the primary limit to ambulation as opposed to the&#xD;
             disease under study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has end-stage renal disease requiring/receiving dialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has used any investigational drug/device, or participated in any&#xD;
             investigational study, within 30 days prior to the Baseline visit.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mardi Gomberg-Maitland, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>George Washington University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Raymond Benza, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ohio State University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mardi Gomberg-Maitland, MD</last_name>
    <phone>202-795-2792</phone>
    <email>mgomberg@mfa.gwu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Raymond Benza, MD</last_name>
    <phone>614-247-7779</phone>
    <email>Raymond.Benza@osumc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>George Washington University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20037</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mardi Gomberg-Maitland, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ohio State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Raymond Benza, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Allegheny Singer Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15212</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Amresh Raina, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>George Washington University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mardi Gomberg -Maitland</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director, Pulmonary Hypertension Program</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertension, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Treprostinil</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

