<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04888039</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RC31/20/0482</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>N° ID RCB: 2020-A03527-32</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04888039</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Follow-up of Patients With Multiple Myeloma in the West-Occitanie Region &quot;Living With a Myeloma in West-Occitanie&quot;</brief_title>
  <acronym>VAMOS</acronym>
  <official_title>Therapeutic and Support Oncologic Medical Care Evaluation in Patients With Multiple Myeloma in West-Occitanie Region. Factors Influencing Medical Care and Predictive and Prognostic Impact.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Toulouse</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut National de la Santé Et de la Recherche Médicale, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Takeda</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sanofi</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Toulouse</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Actually very few real life data are available for patients with multiple myeloma (MM),&#xD;
      whereas they're playing a more and more important role in health care decisions. Treatments&#xD;
      choice for medical care of patient with MM depends of their age, their general status, their&#xD;
      eligibility to high dose treatment (autograft), and also based on cytogenetic risk&#xD;
      (standard/high risk). Therapeutic strategies are multple and based on drugs associations&#xD;
      including proteasome inhibitors, immuno-modulators and monoclonal antibodies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therapeutic medical care objective is to improve quality and response duration through more&#xD;
      effective induction schemas, systematic consolidation for patients who have undergone high&#xD;
      dose therapy and/or maintenance treatment, ensuring patients safety and well-being in the&#xD;
      health care pathway.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Quality of life evaluation has to take in consideration disease outcome and secondary effects&#xD;
      impact from treatments prescribed for MM.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With clinical trials, new therapeutic strategies are proposed with innovative drugs but&#xD;
      participants are selected and do not represent all patients with MM. Therefore, there is a&#xD;
      large gap between clinical trials and real life data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      That's why the CHU Toulouse intends to set up a prospective cohort to evaluate the health&#xD;
      care pathway of patients with MM in West-Occitanie region and studies impact of treatments&#xD;
      prescribed on the disease and on the patients' quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With this research, standard of care practices for patients with MM will be followed,&#xD;
      prognostic scores and clinical trials results will be validated in real life, impact of&#xD;
      outpatient support procedure will be assessed (AMA procedure) and sociodemographic/quality of&#xD;
      life data will be available for research teams.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Primary objective :&#xD;
&#xD;
      Describe health care pathways of patients with MM living in West Occitanie according to&#xD;
      socio-demographic patients' caracteristics, their comorbidities and their initial disease&#xD;
      severity. These pathways will be described until the patients' death if the death occurs&#xD;
      before the end of their follow-up in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives :&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The best response at each line of therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The progression free survival and overall survival&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Quality of life of patients with MM along their health care pathway&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Second primary malignancy and neuropathy grade 3 or more occurrence during patients'care&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Socio-demographic, clinic and biology factors identification to predict response to&#xD;
           treatments, progression free survival, overall survival and quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study size calculation :&#xD;
&#xD;
      With the hypothesis of 80% of patients informed about the study will agree to participate and&#xD;
      will accept to have their health care data collected, and with 500 to 550 patients' medical&#xD;
      files presented each year for MM care to West Occitanie multidisciplinary committee meeting&#xD;
      (approximately 400 different patients), a 5-years recruitment period will lead to 1600&#xD;
      patients enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This size will be able to generate enough precisions for descriptive analyses. Indeed, as&#xD;
      example, with a percentage of 50%, conservative situation to estimate percentages, expected&#xD;
      precision should be more or less 2.5% according to Clopper-Pearson exact method.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Precision of more or less 5% should be also obtained for sub-groups of 400 persons.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2031</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2031</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment lines and procedures followed by the patients</measure>
    <time_frame>5 to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Different treatment lines and procedures followed by the patients with drugs involved, number of cycles performed in each treatment phase (induction, consolidation, maintenance) and for each therapeutic line</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Transplants</measure>
    <time_frame>5 to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Transplants carrying out</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatments discontinuation</measure>
    <time_frame>5 to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Reasons for treatments administered discontinuation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Therapeutic medical care description</measure>
    <time_frame>5 to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Supportive care and the type of care set up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Unconventional alternative medicine</measure>
    <time_frame>5 to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Use and description of unconventional alternative medicine</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Outpatient support structure</measure>
    <time_frame>5 to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Support from an outpatient support structure (AMA)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Best response (BR)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>BR evaluated according to IMWG criteria at each treatment line. This takes into account the MRD as part of the response criteria since this date.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Time between date of first intake of treatment until 1st progression according to the IMWG criteria or until death if it occurs before progression</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PFS after the second therapeutic line</measure>
    <time_frame>5 to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Time between date of 1st dose of treatment until 2nd progression according to the IMWG criteria or until death if it occurs before the 2nd progression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS);</measure>
    <time_frame>5 to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Time between date of first intake of treatment and death from any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life (QOL) during the treatment course</measure>
    <time_frame>5 to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>QOL assessed by the EORTC questionnaires QLQ-C30, QLQMY20 and EQ-5D-5L, at the start of treatment then at the end of induction and consolidation periods and once a year for patients undergoing maintenance for the first 2 lines of treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Second primary cancers (SPC) and grade 3 and higher neuropathies</measure>
    <time_frame>5 to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>-SPC and grade 3 and higher neuropathies (depending on the applicable version of the CTCAE)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2000</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Myeloma</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>quality of life questionnaires (EORTC QLQ-C30 ; EORTC QLQMY20 ; EQ-5D-5L ; Cohen's stress scale)</intervention_name>
    <description>Excepted the delivery of quality of life questionnaires (a maximum of 5 times during the course of treatment) specific to this study, only the data available during the course of patient care will be collected.&#xD;
The quality of life questionnaires and the perceived stress questionnaire will be given to patients :&#xD;
At diagnosis (before starting 1st line of treatment),&#xD;
after the induction phase (before autologous transplantation for patients who will be transplanted),&#xD;
after the consolidation phase,&#xD;
after the maintenance phase : 1 year and 2 years after the start of the maintenance.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adult patients with a diagnosis of symptomatic multiple myeloma and living in the&#xD;
        west-Occitanie region.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient living in the West-Occitanie region&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with a diagnosis of symptomatic multiple myeloma (Rajkumar et al, Lancet&#xD;
             Oncology 2014)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient opposed to this research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient under legal protection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aurore PERROT, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>IUCT-Oncopole - Toulouse University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Aurore PERROT, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+33 5 31 15 64 90</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>perrot.aurore@iuct-oncopole.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sandrine ROLLET, PM</last_name>
    <phone>+33 5 31 15 63 39</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>rollet.sandrine@iuct-oncopole.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IUCT-Oncopole - Toulouse University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse</city>
        <state>West-Occitanie</state>
        <zip>31059</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sandra BERNARD, PM</last_name>
      <phone>+33 5 61 77 85 73</phone>
      <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
      <email>bernard.s@chu-toulouse.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Aurore PERROT, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
  <keyword>Real life</keyword>
  <keyword>Health care pathways</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

