<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04883645</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AAAT5562</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>CA252441</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04883645</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Topical Aldara (Imiquimod) for Oral Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Exploratory Clinical Trial of Topical Imiquimod 5% Cream as Window-of-opportunity Monotherapy for Early-stage Oral Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Columbia University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Columbia University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this research study is to find out what effects, good and/or bad, topical&#xD;
      application of the drug Aldara will have on patients and on their oral cancer. Aldara is a&#xD;
      drug that activates toll-like receptor (TLR) in oral cancer cells causing self-destruction of&#xD;
      tumor cells. It also activates immune cells to attack and eliminate cancer cells. Aldara is&#xD;
      currently approved by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for treatment of skin cancer and&#xD;
      melanoma. Its use in this study is 'off-label' (use of a drug approved by FDA for skin cancer&#xD;
      to treat oral cancer in this study).&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess the preliminary efficacy of topical imiquimod in neoadjuvant setting in patients&#xD;
      with early-stage oral squamous cell carcinoma as determined by best response rate (CR and&#xD;
      PR). To assess local and systemic safety and tolerability by CTCAE v5 criteria. To explore&#xD;
      the effect of imiquimod on the tumor immune microenvironment by performing quantitative&#xD;
      multiplex immunofluorescence.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The researchers propose an exploratory clinical trial to evaluate the efficacy of topical&#xD;
      imiquimod, a TLR-7 agonist, in patients with early-stage oral squamous cell carcinoma. The&#xD;
      analysis of pre- and post-treatment tumor specimen collected from patients treated on this&#xD;
      study will be used for quantitative immunoflourescence analysis to assess the&#xD;
      immunomodulatory activity of imiquimod in human tumor samples. The researchers hypothesize&#xD;
      that TLR-7 stimulation will reduce the size of the tumor in patients with early-stage oral&#xD;
      squamous cell carcinoma. The researchers anticipate that activation of CD4+ (cluster of&#xD;
      differentiation 4+) T-cell and macrophage will correlate with response to therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 17 months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary endpoint is the overall response rate as defined as the best response (CR and PR), confirmed at 4 weeks of the start of study therapy, using RECIST v1.1 criteria neoadjuvant setting in patients with early-stage oral squamous cell carcinoma.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall rate of toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 17 months</time_frame>
    <description>The secondary endpoint is defined as safety and toxicity assessed using CTCAE v5.0 criteria. CTCAE v5 criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Responsoe Rate of topical imiquimod</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 17 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will estimate response rate to topical imiquimod using the exact 95% confidence interval based on the binomial distribution. microenvironment by performing quantitative multiplex immunofluorescence.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">18</enrollment>
  <condition>Oral Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental: Topical Aldara</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients receive the same treatment (there is no &quot;placebo&quot; arm). Treatment will be self-administered by the patients on an outpatient basis. All patients with untreated and biopsy confirmed oral squamous cell carcinoma (OSCC) who meet the inclusion criteria.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Imiquimod 5% Cream,Top,Pkt,0.25Gm</intervention_name>
    <description>Imiquimod as a 5% cream is being used to treat several skin cancers, including malignant melanoma, basal cell carcinoma (BCC) and SCC26-28. With respect to SCC treatment, it has been demonstrated that imiquimod stimulates tumor destruction by recruiting T cells (cells in the immune system) from blood and by inhibiting tonic anti-inflammatory signals within the tumor. The patient will be instructed to apply imiquimod cream, 7 nights a week for 4 weeks to the oral tumor at bedtime.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental: Topical Aldara</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previously untreated and biopsy confirmed oral squamous cell carcinoma (OSCC)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical (TNM) stage I or II&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;= 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) =&lt; 2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients associated with prior therapy requiring treatment with systemic&#xD;
             immunosuppressive treatments with the exception of vitiligo, childhood asthma that has&#xD;
             resolved, residual endocrinopathies requiring replacement therapy, or psoriasis that&#xD;
             does not require systemic treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with any other investigational agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Requirement for immunosuppressive intraoral topical or systemic corticosteroids prior&#xD;
             to the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with&#xD;
             study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV positive patients on combination antiretroviral therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have evidence of any other significant oral mucosal condition, clinical disorder,&#xD;
             physical examination finding, or laboratory finding that, as judged by the&#xD;
             investigator, makes it undesirable for the patient to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women are excluded from this study because imiquimod may have adverse effect&#xD;
             on the fetus (FDA pregnancy risk category C). Because there is an unknown but&#xD;
             potential risk for adverse events in nursing infants secondary to treatment of the&#xD;
             mother with imiquimod, breastfeeding should be discontinued if the mother is receiving&#xD;
             study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male patients unwilling or unable to comply with pregnancy prevention measures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects not receiving initial surgical treatment at Columbia University Irving&#xD;
             Medical Center (CUIMC).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Angela Yoon, DDS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Columbia University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Angela Yoon, DDS</last_name>
    <phone>212-305-7676</phone>
    <email>ajk55@cumc.columbia.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Research Nurse Navigator</last_name>
    <phone>212-342-5162</phone>
    <email>cancerclinicaltrials@cumc.columbia.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University Irving Medical Center, Herbert Irving Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Angela Yoon, DDS</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Columbia University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Angela Yoon</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Oral Pathology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mouth Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lip Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Imiquimod</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

