<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04880148</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21-HONEY-CUT</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04880148</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effectiveness of a Thyme and Honey Spray for Oral Toxicities</brief_title>
  <acronym>HONEY</acronym>
  <official_title>The Effectiveness of a Thyme and Honey Spray for the Management of Oral Mucositis and Xerostomia in Head and Neck Cancer Patients Undergoing Radiotherapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cyprus University of Technology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>German Oncology Center, Cyprus</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cyprus University of Technology</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aim: To evaluate the effectiveness of thymus honey on radiation induced-oral mucositis and&#xD;
      xerostomia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background: Oral mucositis and xerostomia are two of the most severe side effects that head&#xD;
      and neck cancer patients confront during and after the completion of radiotherapy. Although&#xD;
      several medications are used for their treatment, these fail to provide a fully effective and&#xD;
      comprehensive management. Honey and thyme have been studied for the management of various&#xD;
      treatment-related side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design: Α double blinded randomised controlled trial will be used for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: 200 head and neck cancer patients who receive radiotherapy will be included in this&#xD;
      study. Patients will be randomised and divided into two equal groups of 100 participants; the&#xD;
      intervention group (oral spray with thyme and honey + standard care) and the control group (&#xD;
      placebo spray + standard care). Assessments with xerostomia and oral mucositis scales&#xD;
      additionally to 4 self-administered questionnaires will occur in both groups at baseline and&#xD;
      then weekly and 6 months following completion of treatment. The duration of the study will be&#xD;
      3 years from the day of approval of this research protocol.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 3, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Mucositis Grade (RTOG) at weekly assessments</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week 4), week 5, week 6, week 7, week 8 and week 24</time_frame>
    <description>The scale includes 5 grades (from 0 to IV). Higher grade denotes more severe mucositis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Xerostomia Grade (CTCAE) at weekly assessments</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week 4), week 5, week 6, week 7, week 8 and week 24</time_frame>
    <description>he scale includes 5 grades (from 0 to IV). Higher grade denotes more severe xerostomia</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Xerostomia Questionnaire (Dirix et al)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, on completion of radiotherapy, 4 weeks and 24 weeks after radiotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>consists of three parts. In the first part, patients rate on a 4-likert scale (0, 1, 2, 3) the intensity of xerostomia, oral pain, taste, and dysphagia they experience and whether they suffered from more intense tooth decay or other related problems. Secondly, patients evaluate the impact of xerostomia on their Quality of Life. The Quality of Life (QoL) scales contains 15 items (ranging from 1 to 5) with a higher score indicating a worst QoL level (minimum score is 15 and the maximum is 75). Finally, patients rate the degree to which they suffered from xerostomia on a 100-mm Visual Analogue Scale (VAS).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Oral Mucositis Questionnaire (OMWQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, on completion of radiotherapy, 4 weeks and 24 weeks after radiotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>The 12-item questionnaire is designed to evaluate the overall wellbeing of the patient relating to OM during the last week. Possible answers are scored on Likert scales containing 5, 7 and 11 points. The first 2 questions assess global health and quality of life (QOL). The questions are rated on a 7-point scale, with 1 indicating very poor and 7 indicating excellent. The fourth question, which is made up of 6 items, addresses the impact of MTS on patient function and includes a 5-point scale, with 0 indicating not limited and 4 indicating unable to do. The remaining 3 questions assess the degree of mouth and throat pain and soreness using an 11-point scale, with 0 indicating no pain or soreness and 10 indicating the worst pain or soreness imaginable or possible.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in health-related QoL (EORTC QLQ-C30) questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, on completion of radiotherapy, 4 weeks and 24 weeks after radiotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>The EORTC QLQ-C30 is a cancer-specific self-report questionnaire and comprises a global QOL scale (two items), five functional scales, three symptom scales and six single items. Scores QLQ-C30 are linearly transformed to a scale of 0-100, with a higher score indicating a better level of functioning or global QOL, or a worse level of symptoms or problems</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in health-related QoL (EORTC QLQ-H&amp;N43) questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, on completion of radiotherapy, 4 weeks and 24 weeks after radiotherapy</time_frame>
    <description>The EORTC QLQ-H&amp;N35 module covers specific head and neck issues, comprises ten single items and seven subscales: swallowing, senses, speech, social eating, social contact and sexuality. QLQ-H&amp;N35 are linearly transformed to a scale of 0-100, with a higher score indicating a better level of functioning or global QOL, or a worse level of symptoms or problem.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer of the Head and Neck</condition>
  <condition>Xerostomia</condition>
  <condition>Oral Mucositis</condition>
  <condition>Radiation Toxicity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Thyme and Honey-based oral spray</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Thyme and Honey-based oral spray</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo oral spray</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo oral spray</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Thyme and Honey-based oral spray</intervention_name>
    <description>4 X Sprays in the oral cavity before, immediately after and 6 hours following the radiotherapy session</description>
    <arm_group_label>Thyme and Honey-based oral spray</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo oral spray</intervention_name>
    <description>4 X Sprays in the oral cavity before, immediately after and 6 hours following the radiotherapy session</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo oral spray</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a confirmed histologic diagnosis of head and neck cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients referred to non-palliative radiotherapy to the oral cavity will be included&#xD;
             in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Synchronous or induction chemotherapy, or both, will be permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients aged over 18,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients able to provide informed consent,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients having radiotherapy for at least three weeks (lower limit has been set at 50&#xD;
             Gy),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients able to complete records accurately&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a confirmed and medically treated diabetes mellitus,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with allergy to honey, thyme or any other ingredient,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who will refuse to take part in this study and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with previous radiotherapy or presence of systemic disease.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andreas Charalambous, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Cyprus University of Technology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andreas Charalambous, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>25002011</phone>
    <email>andreas.charalambous@cut.ac.cy</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>German Oncology Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Limassol</city>
        <zip>4108</zip>
        <country>Cyprus</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Konstantinos Ferentinos, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>25208000</phone>
      <email>Konstantinos.Ferentinos@goc.com.cy</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Constantina Cloconi, MSc, RN</last_name>
      <phone>25208000</phone>
      <email>Constantina.Cloconi@goc.com.cy</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bank of Cyprus Oncology Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nicosia</city>
        <zip>2006</zip>
        <country>Cyprus</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dimitrios Vomvas, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>22847408</phone>
      <email>Dimitrios.Vomvas@bococ.org.cy</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Morfo Georgiou, MD</last_name>
      <phone>22847601</phone>
      <email>Morfo.Georgiou@bococ.org.cy</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Cyprus</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thrasyvoulou S, Tsitsi T, Katodritis N, Vomvas D, Charalambous M, Charalambous A. Reliability and Validity of the Greek Version of the Oral Mucositis Weekly Questionnaire in the Head and Neck Cancer Context. J Nurs Meas. 2021 Aug 1;29(2):317-333. doi: 10.1891/JNM-D-19-00096. Epub 2021 Mar 19.</citation>
    <PMID>33741726</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Charalambous A. Hermeneutic phenomenological interpretations of patients with head and neck neoplasm experiences living with radiation-induced xerostomia: the price to pay? Eur J Oncol Nurs. 2014 Oct;18(5):512-20. doi: 10.1016/j.ejon.2014.04.007. Epub 2014 May 27.</citation>
    <PMID>24877858</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Charalambous M, Raftopoulos V, Paikousis L, Katodritis N, Lambrinou E, Vomvas D, Georgiou M, Charalambous A. The effect of the use of thyme honey in minimizing radiation - induced oral mucositis in head and neck cancer patients: A randomized controlled trial. Eur J Oncol Nurs. 2018 Jun;34:89-97. doi: 10.1016/j.ejon.2018.04.003. Epub 2018 Apr 30.</citation>
    <PMID>29784145</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Charalambous A, Lambrinou E, Katodritis N, Vomvas D, Raftopoulos V, Georgiou M, Paikousis L, Charalambous M. The effectiveness of thyme honey for the management of treatment-induced xerostomia in head and neck cancer patients: A feasibility randomized control trial. Eur J Oncol Nurs. 2017 Apr;27:1-8. doi: 10.1016/j.ejon.2017.01.001. Epub 2017 Jan 16.</citation>
    <PMID>28279391</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cyprus University of Technology</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Andreas Charalambous</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mucositis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stomatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Xerostomia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

