<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03396068</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NRX101_002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03396068</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>NRX-101 for Maintenance of Remission From Severe Bipolar Depression in Patients With Suicidal Ideation</brief_title>
  <acronym>SBD-ASIB</acronym>
  <official_title>NRX-101 for Maintenance of Remission From Severe Bipolar Depression in Patients With Acute Suicidal Ideation and Behavior: The SBD-ASIB Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>NeuroRx, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Target Health Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Vanguard, Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>NeuroRx, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      NMDA antagonist drugs have increasingly been demonstrated to reduce symptoms of depression&#xD;
      and suicidal ideation. NeuroRx has developed a sequential therapy consisting of IV NRX-100&#xD;
      (ketamine HCL) for rapid stabilization of symptoms of depression and suicidal ideation&#xD;
      followed by oral NRX-101 (fixed dose combination of D-cycloserine and lurasidone) for&#xD;
      maintenance of stabilization from symptoms of depression and suicidal ideation. NRX-101 has&#xD;
      been awarded Fast Track and Breakthrough Therapy Designation by the US Food and Drug&#xD;
      Administration. The SevereBD study will test the hypothesis that NRX-101 is superior to&#xD;
      lurasidone alone in maintaining remission from symptoms of depression (primary endpoint),&#xD;
      clinical relapse (declared secondary endpoint), and suicidal ideation or behavior (declared&#xD;
      secondary endpoint) over a six week period of twice-daily oral dosing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      NeuroRx is developing NRX-101, a fixed-dose combination oral capsule composed of&#xD;
      D-cycloserine (DCS) and lurasidone for the maintenance of remission from Severe Bipolar&#xD;
      Depression with Acute Suicidal Ideation or Behavior (ASIB) in adults with Bipolar Depression&#xD;
      following initial stabilization with ketamine. NRX-101 has been awarded Fast Track and&#xD;
      Breakthrough Therapy Designation by the US Food and Drug Administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In recent years, intravenous and intranasal ketamine have demonstrated rapid and potent&#xD;
      effects in achieving remission from both depression and suicidal ideation in both bipolar&#xD;
      depression and major depressive disorder. However ketamine is will understood to induce&#xD;
      hallucination and other dissociative side effects, to be addictive and have high abuse&#xD;
      potential, and to have potential neurotoxic effects. Moreover, ketamine can only be&#xD;
      administered in a monitored hospital or clinic setting. NRX-101 was developed with the&#xD;
      objective of seeking a safe, non-hallucinogenic, non-addictive, oral medication that might&#xD;
      maintain the effects of ketamine in patients with severe depression and acute suicidal&#xD;
      ideation and which might be considered as initial therapy for patients with depression and&#xD;
      non-acute suicidal ideation. The D-cycloserine component of NRX-101 is believed to act by&#xD;
      inhibiting the brain's NMDA receptor and raising levels of glutamate/glutamine (Glx) in the&#xD;
      anterior cingulate cortex. Increased Glx, as measured by magnetic resonance spectroscopy, has&#xD;
      been associated with clinical improvement following electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) and&#xD;
      following administration of IV ketamine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To test the hypothesis that following successful response to a single infusion of ketamine&#xD;
      (NRX-100), treatment with NRX-101 is superior to lurasidone in maintaining improvement in&#xD;
      symptoms of depression as measured by the MADRS-10 total score.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Key secondary: To test the hypothesis that following response to a single infusion of&#xD;
      NRX-100, daily oral NRX-101 is superior to lurasidone in delaying time to relapse of&#xD;
      suicidality or depression in patients with Severe Bipolar Depression and Acute Suicidal&#xD;
      Ideation and Behavior (ASIB). Avoiding relapse will be defined as being relapse-free, without&#xD;
      experiencing a 50% or greater return to pre-infusion baseline levels of depression, or&#xD;
      suicidality, or the need to implement a new treatment plan.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To demonstrate that following NRX-100 response, treatment with NRX-101 are less likely&#xD;
           to suffer from akathisia than those treated with lurasidone.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To demonstrate that following NRX-100 response, other efficacy advantages observed in&#xD;
           NRX-100 responders are more favorable for NRX-101 vs. lurasidone&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To demonstrate safety and tolerability of NRX-101 vs. lurasidone.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To demonstrate that following successful NRX-100 response, NRX-101 diminishes the length&#xD;
           of stay for index hospitalization vs. lurasidone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology: A multi-center, randomized, stratified, double-blind, adaptive trial conducted&#xD;
      under a Special Protocol Agreement with the FDA that enrolls patients demonstrating&#xD;
      successful response in NCT03396601. Randomization will be 2:1 favoring NRX-101 (n=48) vs.&#xD;
      lurasidone alone (n=24).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participants and Care Providers will be masked with regard to medication administered. Outcomes Assessors will not be present during IV infusion of medication.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>MADRS-10</measure>
    <time_frame>Six weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in Montgomery Asberg Depression Rating Scale 10 Item Total Score between NRX-101 and lurasidone groups as measured by mixed model</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Relapse (stage 2)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Relapse is defined as a 50% or greater return to baseline level of depression, an increase in suicidality to C-SSRS 4 or higher, or the need to implement a new treatment plan.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">72</enrollment>
  <condition>Bipolar Depression</condition>
  <condition>Suicidal Ideation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NRX-101</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be treated with oral NRX-101 (fixed dose combination of D-Cycloserine/lurasidone) that will be titrated to a combined dose of 950mg/66mg per day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lurasidone comparator</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be treated with oral lurasidone in a matched placebo capsule that will be titrated to a dose of 66 mg per day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>NRX-101</intervention_name>
    <description>NRX-101, a fixed dose combination of D-cycloserine+lurasidone will be given twice a day by mouth</description>
    <arm_group_label>NRX-101</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cyclurad</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lurasidone HCl</intervention_name>
    <description>Lurasidone HCl will be given twice a day by mouth</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lurasidone comparator</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A subject will be eligible for inclusion in this study based on successful response to&#xD;
             infusion under NCT03396601 and the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. 18 to 65 years of age, inclusive, at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Able to understand and provide written and dated informed consent prior to&#xD;
                  screening. Deemed likely to comply with study protocol and communicate AEs and&#xD;
                  other clinically important information, and agree to be hospitalized to complete&#xD;
                  screening and initiate experimental treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Resides in a stable living situation, in the opinion of the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Has an identified reliable informant, in the opinion of the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Diagnosed with bipolar disorder (BD) according to the criteria defined in the&#xD;
                  DSM-5. The diagnosis of BD will be made by a psychiatrist and supported by the&#xD;
                  MINI 7.0.2.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. In good general health, as ascertained by medical history, physical examination&#xD;
                  (including measurement of seated vital signs), clinical laboratory evaluations,&#xD;
                  and electrocardiogram&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. If female, a status of non-childbearing potential or use of an acceptable form of&#xD;
                  birth control per the following specific criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  a. Non-childbearing potential (e.g., physiologically incapable of becoming&#xD;
                  pregnant, i.e., permanently sterilized [status post hysterectomy, bilateral tubal&#xD;
                  ligation], or post-menopausal with last menses at least one year prior to&#xD;
                  screening); or b. Childbearing potential, and meets the following criteria: i.&#xD;
                  Using any form of hormonal birth control, on hormone replacement therapy started&#xD;
                  prior to 12 months of amenorrhea, using an intrauterine device (IUD), having a&#xD;
                  monogamous relationship with a partner who has had a vasectomy, or sexually&#xD;
                  abstinent.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  ii. Negative urinary pregnancy test at screening, confirmed by a second negative&#xD;
                  urinary pregnancy test at randomization prior to receiving study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  iii. Willing and able to continuously use one of the following methods of birth&#xD;
                  control during the course of the study, defined as those which result in a low&#xD;
                  failure rate (i.e., less than 1% per year) when used consistently and correctly:&#xD;
                  implants, injectable or patch hormonal contraception, oral contraceptives, IUD,&#xD;
                  double-barrier contraception, sexual abstinence. The form of birth control will&#xD;
                  be documented at screening and pre-ketamine baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Body mass index between 18-35kg/m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Concurrent psychotherapy will be allowed if the type and frequency of the therapy&#xD;
                  (e.g., weekly or monthly) has been stable for at least three months prior to&#xD;
                  screening and is expected to remain stable for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. Concurrent hypnotic therapy (e.g., with zolpidem, zaleplon, melatonin,&#xD;
                  benzodiazepines, or trazodone) will be allowed if the therapy has been stable for&#xD;
                  at least four weeks prior to screening and if it is expected to remain stable&#xD;
                  during the course of the subject's participation in the study. Subjects can also&#xD;
                  continue treatment with benzodiazepines used for anxiety if therapy has been&#xD;
                  stable for at least four weeks prior to screening and if it is expected to remain&#xD;
                  stable during the course of the subject's participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  A subject will not be eligible for inclusion in this study if any of the&#xD;
                  following criteria apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Female of childbearing potential who is not willing to use one of the specified&#xD;
                  forms of birth control during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Female who is pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Female with a positive pregnancy test at screening or before oral dosing of&#xD;
                  investigational product.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Current DSM-5 diagnosis of moderate or severe substance use disorder (except&#xD;
                  marijuana or tobacco use disorder) within the 12 months prior to screening.&#xD;
                  Substance abuse cannot be the precipitant of entry to treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Subjects with a lifetime history of PCP/ketamine drug use, or failed use of&#xD;
                  ketamine for depression.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. History of schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder, or any history of psychotic&#xD;
                  symptoms when not in an acute bipolar mood episode.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. History of anorexia nervosa, bulimia nervosa, or eating disorder NOS (OSFED)&#xD;
                  within five years of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Has dementia, delirium, amnestic, or any other cognitive disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Any major psychiatric disorder, including a personality disorder, which is&#xD;
                  clinically predominant to BD at screening, or has been the primary focus of&#xD;
                  treatment predominant to BD at any time within six months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. Current major psychiatric disorder, diagnosed at screening with the MINI 7.0.2,&#xD;
                  that is the primary focus of treatment, with BD as the secondary focus of&#xD;
                  treatment, within the past six months.&#xD;
&#xD;
              11. A clinically significant abnormality on the screening physical examination that&#xD;
                  might affect safety or study participation, or that might confound interpretation&#xD;
                  of study results according to the study clinician.&#xD;
&#xD;
              12. Current episode of:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    1. Untreated hypertension, (Stage 1 or greater) as defined by a systolic blood&#xD;
                       pressure ≥140 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure ≥90 mmHg at screening on two&#xD;
                       of three measurements at least 15 minutes apart. If untreated due to missing&#xD;
                       medication dose/s this is not exclusionary.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    2. Hypertension, Stage 2, as defined by a systolic blood pressure ≥155 mmHg or&#xD;
                       diastolic blood pressure ≥99 mmHg within 1.5 hours prior to ketamine&#xD;
                       infusion on two of three measurements at least 15 minutes apart at the&#xD;
                       pre-ketamine assessment (on Day 0 at Visit 1).&#xD;
&#xD;
                    3. Recent myocardial infarction (within one year).&#xD;
&#xD;
                    4. Syncopal event within the past year.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    5. Congestive heart failure (CHF) New York Heart Association Criteria &gt;Stage 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    6. Angina pectoris.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    7. Heart rate &lt;50 or &gt;105 beats per minute at screening, pre-ketamine infusion&#xD;
                       (Day 0) or at randomization (Day 1).&#xD;
&#xD;
                    8. QTcF ≥450 msec at screening for men, ≥ 470 msec for women, pre-ketamine&#xD;
                       infusion (Day 0), or at randomization (Day 1), on two of three measurements&#xD;
                       at least 15 minutes apart.&#xD;
&#xD;
              13. History of hypertension, or on antihypertensives for the purpose of lowering&#xD;
                  blood pressure, with either an increase in antihypertensive dose or increase in&#xD;
                  the number of antihypertensive drugs used to treat hypertension over the last two&#xD;
                  months.&#xD;
&#xD;
              14. Chronic lung disease, excluding asthma.&#xD;
&#xD;
              15. Lifetime history of surgical procedures involving the brain or meninges,&#xD;
                  encephalitis, meningitis, degenerative central nervous system (CNS) disorder&#xD;
                  (e.g., Alzheimer's or Parkinson's Disease), epilepsy, mental retardation, or any&#xD;
                  other disease/procedure/accident/intervention that, according to the screening&#xD;
                  clinician, is deemed associated with significant injury to or malfunction of the&#xD;
                  CNS; or history of significant head trauma within the past two years.&#xD;
&#xD;
              16. Presents with any of the following lab abnormalities:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  a. Subjects with diabetes mellitus fulfilling any of the following criteria: i.&#xD;
                  Unstable diabetes mellitus defined as glycosylated hemoglobin (HbA1c) &gt;8.0 % at&#xD;
                  screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  ii. Admitted to hospital for treatment of diabetes mellitus or diabetes&#xD;
                  mellitus-related illness in the past 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  iii. Not under physician care for diabetes mellitus. iv. Has not been on the same&#xD;
                  dose of oral hypoglycemic drug(s) and/or diet for the four weeks prior to&#xD;
                  screening. For thiazolidinediones (glitazones) this period should not be less&#xD;
                  than eight weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  b. Any other clinically significant abnormal laboratory result (as determined by&#xD;
                  the investigator and medical monitor) at the time of the screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
              17. Any current or past history of any physical condition which, in the&#xD;
                  investigator's opinion, might put the subject at risk or interfere with study&#xD;
                  results interpretation.&#xD;
&#xD;
              18. Subjects on exclusionary concomitant psychotropic medications (see Appendix 1) as&#xD;
                  defined in the study manual.&#xD;
&#xD;
              19. At randomization, subjects prescribed more than one agent in each category;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    1. Approved antidepressants (e.g., SSRIs, SNRIs, TeCAs, fluoxetine), but not&#xD;
                       5-HT-2a antagonists (lurasidone, aripiprazole, olanzapine, quetiapine)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    2. Mood stabilizers (e.g., lithium, carbamazepine, valproic acid)&#xD;
&#xD;
              20. Subjects with exclusionary laboratory values (see Table 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
              21. Known allergies to lurasidone or Latuda, cycloserine or Seromycin, or the&#xD;
                  excipients mannitol, croscarmellose sodium, magnesium stearate, silicon dioxide,&#xD;
                  and/or HPMC (hydroxypropylmethylcellulose).&#xD;
&#xD;
              22. Participation in any clinical trial with an investigational drug or device within&#xD;
                  the past month or concurrent to study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
              23. Study site personnel and/or persons employed by NeuroRx, Inc. or Target Health or&#xD;
                  by the investigator or study site (i.e., permanent, temporary contract worker, or&#xD;
                  designee responsible for the conduct of the study), or an immediate family member&#xD;
                  (i.e., spouse or parent, child, or sibling [biological or legally adopted]) of&#xD;
                  such persons.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Martin Brecher, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>VP, Clinical Development, NeuroRx, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Martin Brecher, MD</last_name>
    <phone>484-254-6134</phone>
    <email>mbrecher@neurorxpharma.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site, Birmingham</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35294</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Centers of America</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hollywood</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33024</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Peter Ventre, MD</last_name>
      <phone>954-990-7649</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>JP Smith Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Worth</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>76104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alan Podawiltz, DO, MS, FAPA</last_name>
      <phone>817-702-3100</phone>
      <email>APodawil@JPSHealth.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Cindy Claassen, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>817-702-5647</phone>
      <email>CClasse@JPSHealth.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site, Houston</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 2, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 4, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 10, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Suicidal Ideation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lurasidone Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

