<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03399578</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MERS001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03399578</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Immunogenicity of a Candidate MERS-CoV Vaccine (MERS001)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Study to Determine the Safety and Immunogenicity of the Candidate Middle East Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus (MERS-CoV) Vaccine ChAdOx1 MERS in UK Healthy Adult Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Oxford</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Oxford</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a clinical trial in which healthy volunteers will be administered an experimental&#xD;
      MERS vaccine. The vaccine ChAdOx1 MERS will be administered alone both as a single&#xD;
      administration and with a homologous prime-booster.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      All vaccinations will be administered intramuscularly. In Groups 1-3, each volunteer will&#xD;
      receive one vaccination in total. In Groups 4 and 5, each volunteer will receive two&#xD;
      vaccinations in total.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are five different vaccine schedules:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 1 (n=6) will receive 5 x 10^9 vp ChAdOx1 MERS .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 2 (n=9) will receive 2.5 x 10^10 vp ChAdOx1 MERS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 3 (n=9) will receive 5 x 10^10 vp ChAdOx1 MERS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 4 (n=6-12) will receive 2.5 x 10^10 vp ChAdOx1 MERS at week 0 followed by a boost of&#xD;
      2.5 x 10^10 vp ChAdOx1 MERS at week 26.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 5 (n=6-12) will receive 2.5 x 10^10 vp ChAdOx1 MERS at week 0 followed by a boost of&#xD;
      2.5 x 10^10 vp ChAdOx1 MERS at week 4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will assess the safety of the vaccines, and the immune responses to the&#xD;
      vaccinations. Immune responses are measured by tests on blood samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy adult volunteers will be recruited in Oxford, England.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    The scientific questions proposed remain relevant, but will now be addressed in a larger phase&#xD;
    II immunogenicity trial of the ChAdOx1 MERS vaccine given at 2 doses.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 14, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 17, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 17, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of solicited and unsolicited local and systemic adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 28 days following vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>The specific endpoints for safety and reactogenicity will be actively and passively collected data on adverse events. Change from baseline for safety laboratory measures will also be collected. Occurrence of serious adverse events will be collected during the whole study duration</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measures of immunogenicity to the ChAdOx1 MERS vaccine</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>ELISA to quantify antibodies to MERS Spike protein antigen Ex vivo ELISpot responses to MERS Spike protein antigen</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">29</enrollment>
  <condition>MERS (Middle East Respiratory Syndrome)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group 1 volunteers (n= 6) will be administered ChAdOx1 MERS, 5 x 10^9 vp through intramuscular route.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group 2 volunteers (n= 9) will be administered ChAdOx1 MERS, 2.5 x 10^10 vp through intramuscular route.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group 3 volunteers (n= 9) will be administered ChAdOx1 MERS, 5 x 10^10 vp through intramuscular route.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group 4 volunteers (n=6-12) will be administered ChAdOx1 MERS, 2.5 x 10^10 vp at week 0, followed by ChAdOx1 MERS, 2.5 x 10^10 vp at week 26. Both administrations will be given through intramuscular route.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group 5 volunteers (n=6-12) will be administered ChAdOx1 MERS, 2.5 x 10^10 vp at week 0, followed by ChAdOx1 MERS, 2.5 x 10^10 vp at week 4. Both administrations will be given through intramuscular route.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ChAdOx1 MERS</intervention_name>
    <description>The ChAdOx1 MERS vaccine consists of the replication-deficient simian adenovirus vector ChAdOx1, containing the MERS Spike protein antigen.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 5</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The volunteer must satisfy all the following criteria to be eligible for the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy adults aged 18 to 50 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able and willing (in the Investigator's opinion) to comply with all study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Willing to allow the investigators to discuss the volunteer's medical history with&#xD;
             their General Practitioner or access this medical history electronically.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. For females only, willingness to practice continuous effective contraception during&#xD;
             the study and a negative pregnancy test on the day(s) of screening and vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Agreement to refrain from blood donation during the course of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The volunteer may not enter the study if any of the following apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participation in another research study involving receipt of an investigational&#xD;
             product in the 30 days preceding enrolment, or planned use during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Prior receipt of an investigational vaccine likely to impact on interpretation of the&#xD;
             trial data (e.g. Adenovirus vectored vaccine).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within the three months&#xD;
             preceding the planned administration of the vaccine candidate&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient state, including HIV&#xD;
             infection; asplenia; recurrent, severe infections and chronic (more than 14 days)&#xD;
             immunosuppressant medication within the past 6 months (inhaled and topical steroids&#xD;
             are allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of allergic disease or reactions likely to be exacerbated by any component of&#xD;
             the vaccine&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any history of hereditary angioedema, acquired angioedema, or idiopathic angioedema.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any history of anaphylaxis in relation to vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Pregnancy, lactation or willingness/intention to become pregnant during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of cancer (except basal cell carcinoma of the skin and cervical carcinoma in&#xD;
             situ)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of serious psychiatric condition likely to affect participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Bleeding disorder (eg. factor deficiency, coagulopathy or platelet disorder), or prior&#xD;
             history of significant bleeding or bruising following IM injections or venepuncture&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Any other serious chronic illness requiring hospital specialist supervision&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Suspected or known current alcohol abuse as defined by an alcohol intake of greater&#xD;
             than 42 units every week&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Suspected or known injecting drug abuse in the 5 years preceding enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Seropositive for hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg)&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Seropositive for hepatitis C virus (antibodies to HCV)&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Any clinically significant abnormal finding on screening biochemistry or haematology&#xD;
             blood tests or urinalysis&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Any other significant disease, disorder or finding which may significantly increase&#xD;
             the risk to the volunteer because of participation in the study, affect the ability of&#xD;
             the volunteer to participate in the study or impair interpretation of the study data&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Inability of the study team to contact the volunteer's GP to confirm medical history&#xD;
             and safety to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Prior exposure to MERS-CoV (serology will be requested at the discretion of the&#xD;
             investigator)&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. History of allergic reaction to Aminoglycoside antibiotics&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adrian V Hill, DPhil FRCP</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre for Clinical Vaccinology and Tropical Medicine, Churchill Hospital, Oxford, United Kingdom</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre for Clinical Vaccinology and Tropical Medicine, Churchill Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 8, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 12, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 16, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

