<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01263340</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SCO115217</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01263340</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Characterisation of People With COPD</brief_title>
  <acronym>CoCO</acronym>
  <official_title>Observational, Multi-centre, Retrospective Cohort Study to Evaluate Prevalence, Incidence, Severity, Co-morbidities and Burden of Disease in Patients With a Diagnosis of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) by Close Scrutiny of the Patient Journey</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Services for Health Improvement Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Services for Health Improvement Ltd</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators will describe the characteristics, prevalence, incidence, severity&#xD;
      co-morbidity and management of patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) in&#xD;
      the UK. 100 practices will be sampled amounting to a total study population of about 10 000&#xD;
      patients. Information will be collected electronically and, where necessary, by a hand search&#xD;
      of patient records.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Research questions:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. What is the recorded prevalence of COPD in the UK? [numerator: the prevalence of COPD&#xD;
           defined as ANY current READ code for COPD or inclusion in a COPD register denominator:&#xD;
           the whole population]&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of this population has documented spirometry to confirm the&#xD;
                diagnosis?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion has documented spirometry in the last year?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion has ever had a documented history of asthma?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion currently has a documented history of asthma?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion currently smokes?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of smokers has a record of receiving smoking cessation advice?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of smokers has had a prescription for smoking cessation therapy?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of people with COPD has a READ code for exception reporting?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What are their demographic features? (height weight, BMI, age, smoking status,&#xD;
                forced expiratory flow in 1st second (FEV1_, DOSE)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of people with COPD has a READ code for exception reporting from&#xD;
                spirometry?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What are their demographic features? (height, weight, body mass index (BMI), age,&#xD;
                smoking status, FEV1, DOSE)&#xD;
&#xD;
           Sub analysis: descriptions and comparison of prevalence by • Age&#xD;
&#xD;
           • geographical location of participating practices&#xD;
&#xD;
           • primary care training practice&#xD;
&#xD;
           • number of performing general practitioners (GPs) in practice (&lt;3 v &gt;/= 3)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. What is the incidence of COPD in the UK&#xD;
&#xD;
           • number of people with a new diagnosis of COPD in the last year as a proportion of the&#xD;
           whole population&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. What is the distribution of severities of COPD?&#xD;
&#xD;
           • Description of severity of airflow obstruction by FEV1 measurement:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Mild (FEV1 ≥ 80% predicted):&#xD;
&#xD;
           Moderate (FEV1 50% to 79% predicted) Severe (FEV1 30% to 49% predicted) Very severe&#xD;
           (FEV1 ≤ 30% predicted)&#xD;
&#xD;
           • And by DOSE&#xD;
&#xD;
           Compare the severity of disease (exacerbation rate) according to DOSE &quot;high risk&quot; and&#xD;
           &quot;low risk&quot; and compare this to the stratification of severity in the study population by&#xD;
           degree of airflow limitation.&#xD;
&#xD;
           • And by COPD Assessment Test (CAT)&#xD;
&#xD;
           Explore the use of CAT in clinical practice and the availability and spread of data&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. What is the exacerbation rate?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  In the last year in people with a diagnosis of COPD &gt; 1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  In the last three years in people with a diagnosis of COPD &gt; 3years (as a&#xD;
                proportion of the population with COPD).&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What is the seasonal variation of COPD exacerbations: what proportion of&#xD;
                exacerbations occurs in each month of the year?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Do recurrent primary care managed exacerbations predict hospital admissions? What&#xD;
                is the prior exacerbation rate in patients admitted to hospital? Population of&#xD;
                interest: those with hospital admissions for COPD: what is the exacerbation rate&#xD;
                (and time frame of exacerbations) prior to a hospital admission?&#xD;
&#xD;
                4a. What proportion of the COPD population had at least one exacerbation?&#xD;
&#xD;
           Hospital attendance: Any documented visit to any secondary care (not primary care out of&#xD;
           hours) site with no overnight stay&#xD;
&#xD;
           Hospital admission: Any documented visit to any secondary care site with an overnight&#xD;
           stay with a principal diagnosis of COPD or chest infection or pneumonia or exacerbation&#xD;
           of asthma ICU admission: Any documented admission to any high dependency unit (note, AN&#xD;
           EXPLORATORY EXERCISE. Validity of this data in primary care record is questionable)&#xD;
&#xD;
           Death: Any death with COPD documented as the primary cause or within 14 days of the&#xD;
           onset of an exacerbation (EXPLORATORY)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Does DOSE predict undesirable outcomes (death, hospital admission, exacerbation&#xD;
                rate)?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Does FEV1 predict undesirable outcomes (death, hospital admission, exacerbation&#xD;
                rate)?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Does medical research council dyspnoea (MRC) score (or other component of DOSE)&#xD;
                predict undesirable outcomes?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Possible exploratory analysis: does ADO index (Age, Dyspnoea (MRC score)&#xD;
                Obstruction (FEV1 % pred)) predict undesirable outcomes?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Does number of patients in a practice receiving a Tiotropium prescription predict&#xD;
                hospital admission at a practice level?&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Therapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of patients (without a diagnosis of asthma) receives inhaled&#xD;
                glucocorticosteroids at unlicensed doses (any steroid (fluticasone, budesonide,&#xD;
                beclometasone, ciclesonide) or combination Seretide, Symbicort, Fostair) EXCEPT&#xD;
                Seretide Accuhaler 50/500 or Symbicort?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of patients with FEV1&gt; 50 and no diagnosis of asthma receive any&#xD;
                steroid preparation? (Note: Seretide Accuhaler 50/500 is licensed for use in&#xD;
                patients with COPD and (pre-bronchodilator) FEV1 &lt; 60% predicted and is therefore&#xD;
                not subject to off label use in this instance). The approach outlined here is a&#xD;
                consensus for the purposes of identifying a pragmatic approach to data collection.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of patients with FEV&lt;50 do not receive any inhaled steroid?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of patients with 1 or more exacerbation in the last year does not&#xD;
                receive any inhaled steroid?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of patients with FEV1 &lt;50 do not receive Seretide 50/500 or&#xD;
                Symbicort?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of patients are on &quot;triple therapy&quot; i.e. Seretide or Symbicort PLUS&#xD;
                Tiotropium, classified by severity (FEV1)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What is the refill rate for prescriptions by class (all above and SABA) in the&#xD;
                previous year?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of patients have an MRC dyspnoea score &gt;/= 3?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of these patients has been referred for pulmonary rehabilitation?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion has received pulmonary rehabilitation?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion has documented evidence of receiving a self management plan?&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Co-morbidities:&#xD;
&#xD;
           What proportion of patients with COPD have any READ code ever for the following&#xD;
           co-morbidities:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Cardiovascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Cerebrovascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Diabetes Mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Lung cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Depression&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Osteoporosis What proportion of patients with at least one comorbidity has attended&#xD;
                a specialist chest service / clinic in the last year? What is the exacerbation rate&#xD;
                in this group v patients without comorbidity? What is the hospital admission rate&#xD;
                in this group v the rest? What proportion of the population has a record of NEVER&#xD;
                smoking? What are the features of this group (age, sex, geography, exacerbation&#xD;
                rate, medication, comorbidities&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Newly diagnosed patients&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What are the characteristics (demographics: height weight, BMI, age, smoking&#xD;
                status, FEV1, DOSE) of newly diagnosed patients (first READ code for COPD within&#xD;
                the last year)?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of these patients received a prescription for Tiotropium within 1&#xD;
                month of diagnosis?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of these patients received a prescription for an inhaled&#xD;
                corticosteroid / longa acting beta-agonist fixed dose (ICS / LABA) combination&#xD;
                within 1 month of diagnosis?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  In patients FEV1 &lt;50% predicted, what proportion receive a) Tiotropium and b) an&#xD;
                ICS / LABA combination first&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of these patients with FEV1&gt;50 received a prescription for ICS /&#xD;
                LABA combination within 1 month of diagnosis?&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. General Practice Research database (GPRD)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  What proportion of our sample currently contributes to the GPRD database?&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Are their differences in the features of the two groups: Age geographical location&#xD;
                of participating practices, primary care training practice, number of performing&#xD;
                GPs in practice (&lt;3 v &gt;/= 3), disease severity (DOSE, FEV1) exacerbation rate&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. What changes have there been at practice level to the above parameters in the last year?&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence and characterisation of people with COPD</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10000</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>People with COPD</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        People with a Read code diagnosis of COPD&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  people with a read code diagnosis of COPD&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  none&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>John Haughney, FRCPE FRCGP</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>NSHI Ltd</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NHS primary care centres</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nationwide</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 16, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 17, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 20, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 4, 2013</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 4, 2013</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 5, 2013</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COPD</keyword>
  <keyword>observational study</keyword>
  <keyword>prevalence</keyword>
  <keyword>characterisation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

