<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01762709</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2012080</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2012082</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01762709</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Low Tidal Volume and EVLWI During OLV</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Different Tidal Volumes on Extravascular Lung Water Content During One-lung Ventilation for Video-assisted Thoracoscopic Surgery: Dammam University Experience</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dammam University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dammam University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The use of low tidal volume (TV) during one lung ventilation (OLV) for thoracic surgery&#xD;
      decreases the incidence of postoperative acute lung injury (ALI). We postulated that the use&#xD;
      of low TV during OLV for video-assisted thoracoscopic surgery (VATS) would decrease the&#xD;
      extravascular lung water content index (EVLWI). After local ethics committee approval and&#xD;
      informed consent, we will randomly allocate 60 patients scheduled for elective VATS to&#xD;
      ventilate the dependent lung with VT of 4, 6, or 8 mL/kg (n= 20 for each), I: E ratio 1: 2.5,&#xD;
      PEEP of 5 cm H2O, recruitment maneuvers and respiratory rate will be adjusted to maintain&#xD;
      normocapnia. Perioperative changes in EVLWI, hemodynamics, oxygenation index will be&#xD;
      recorded. Also, the incidence of postoperative ALI, morbidity, hospitalization and mortality&#xD;
      will be recorded&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Nowadays most thoracic procedures are performed via video-assisted thoracoscopic surgery&#xD;
      (VATS) which necessitates the use of one lung ventilation (OLV).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Acute lung injury (ALI) is the most serious pulmonary complication after lung resection which&#xD;
      may be aggravated with the use of large tidal volume (TV) and high peak airway pressures&#xD;
      (Paw) during one-lung ventilation (OLV). In a large multicenter trial included 861 patients&#xD;
      at 10 university centers of the Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome Network of the National&#xD;
      Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, the use of lower tidal volumes from 4 to 6 ml/kg of the&#xD;
      predicted body weight (PBW) during ventilation in patients with acute lung injury and the&#xD;
      acute respiratory distress syndrome may reduce injurious lung stretch, the release of&#xD;
      inflammatory mediators, days of mechanical ventilation and mortality (P=0.007).&#xD;
&#xD;
      By the late 1990s the standard VT for managing thoracic surgical patients had already been&#xD;
      adjusted downwards [from 10 to 12 ml/kg in the 1980s] to 8 to 10 ml/kg, although no specific&#xD;
      guidelines existed for one-lung ventilation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The implementation of lung protective strategy during OLV using low TV [5-6 ml/kg PBW],&#xD;
      pressure-controlled ventilation, limiting inspiratory plateau pressures and adding&#xD;
      end-expiratory positive pressure (PEEP) with or without recruitment maneuvers has been shown&#xD;
      to attenuate the incidence of ALI by 76-82% and satisfactory gas exchange after lung surgery&#xD;
      without inducing a possible inflammatory/remodeling response.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The use of lower tidal volumes for OLV with subsequently decreased peak airway pressures may&#xD;
      be associated with less production of tumor necrosis factor (TNF)-alpha and soluble&#xD;
      intercellular adhesion molecule (sICAM)-1.8 Recent data have highlighted the role of extra&#xD;
      vascular lung water index (EVLWI) as a useful good parameter for early diagnosis of pulmonary&#xD;
      complication including acute lung injury after thoracic surgery. The diagnosis of&#xD;
      postoperative ALI is often delayed because clinical signs of pulmonary edema present only&#xD;
      once the extra vascular lung water (EVLW) exceeds 7 ml/kg (ideal body weight).&#xD;
&#xD;
      EVLWI may be measured with thermal dilution pulse index continuous cardiac output (PiCCO)&#xD;
      (pulse contour cardiac output, Pulsion Medical Systems; Munich, Germany). The EVLWI&#xD;
      represents both interstitial and alveolar fluid.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Many studies used the ratio of EVLWI and the intrathoracic blood volume (ITBV) within the&#xD;
      lungs to derive the pulmonary vascular permeability index. A high EVLW/ITBV ratio will&#xD;
      support an increased permeability as the cause of ALI, whereas a low ratio will suggest&#xD;
      hydrostatic pulmonary edema.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up to our knowledge, there is no available study of the efficacy of low tidal volumes during&#xD;
      OLV in reducing the EVLWI, incidence of acute lung injury and the hospital cost of stay after&#xD;
      thoracoscopic surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators assume that the changes in tidal volume during OLV by 1 ml/kg (e.g. 70 ml&#xD;
      in a 70 kg body weight patient) make no sense. So, they hypothesize that the use of lower&#xD;
      tidal volumes of 4 ml/kg and 6 ml/kg will be associated with less lung water content than the&#xD;
      use of larger tidal volume of 8 ml/kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interventions:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In all patients, standard monitors including three leads electrocardiograph, noninvasive&#xD;
      pressure and pulse oximeter, will be applied, fentanyl (1.0 μg/kg) and midazolam (0.03 mg/kg)&#xD;
      will be given and femoral artery will be catheterized with a 5 Fr. Thermodilution catheter&#xD;
      under local anesthesia and will be connected to a computer for pulse contour monitor (PiCCO2,&#xD;
      Pulsion Medical Systems; Munich, Germany). This catheter will be used for blood gasometry and&#xD;
      beat to beat monitoring of arterial blood pressure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anesthetic technique will be standardized in all studied patients. Anesthesiologists who will&#xD;
      give the anaesthetic will be not involved in the patient's assessment. General anaesthesia&#xD;
      will be induced with propofol (2-3 mg/kg), fentanyl (2-3 µg/kg), and cisatracurium (0.2&#xD;
      mg/kg) will be given to facilitate tracheal intubation with a left-sided double-lumen tube&#xD;
      (DLT). The correct position of its tip will be confirmed with a fiberoptic bronchoscope after&#xD;
      intubation and after positioning the patient in the lateral decubitus position (LDP).&#xD;
      Anesthesia will be maintained with sevoflurane 1-1.5 MAC and fentanyl increments of 0.5 µg/kg&#xD;
      to maintain the response entropy (RS) values &lt; 50 and the difference between RE and state&#xD;
      entropy (SE) &lt; 10. Suppression of the second twitch in the train-of-four stimulation of the&#xD;
      ulnar nerve will be maintained with 0.03 mg/kg increments of cisatracurium.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patients' lungs will be mechanically ventilated using fraction of inspired oxygen (FiO2)&#xD;
      of 0.5 in air, tidal volume (VT) of 8 mL/kg (predicted body weight), inspiratory to&#xD;
      expiratory [I: E] ratio of 1:2.5, a positive end-expiratory pressure (PEEP) of 5 cm H2O,&#xD;
      respiratory rate (R.R) will be adjusted to achieve an PaCO2 of 35-45 mm Hg, peak inspiratory&#xD;
      pressures (Ppk) will be limited to 35 cm H2O and a low fresh gas flow (FGF) (&lt;2 L/min) in a&#xD;
      semi closed circuit system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A central venous catheter will be inserted in the right internal jugular vein with&#xD;
      ultrasonography guidance. EVLWI and ITBV will be calculated with the PiCCO2 monitor. Three 20&#xD;
      ml blouses of iced saline will be injected through the central venous catheter and the change&#xD;
      in the temperature will be measured with the thermistor-tipped femoral arterial catheter.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All operations will be performed by the same surgeons. The VATS procedure will begin with the&#xD;
      exploration of the pleural cavity using a 30° video thoracoscopic camera through a 1.5-cm&#xD;
      single skin incision with the use of 1-3 trocars which enables the thoracoscopic instruments&#xD;
      to move the lung.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intraoperative fluid therapy will include intravenous infusion of 2 ml/kg/hour of Lactated&#xD;
      Ringer's solution and blood losses will be compensated with colloids and with red blood cell&#xD;
      concentrates if the hemoglobin levels decreases below 8 to 9 g/dL. Mean arterial blood&#xD;
      pressure will be maintained greater than 60 mm Hg using boluses of ephedrine 5 mg or&#xD;
      phenylephrine 100 ug. Urine output will be maintained greater than 0.5 ml/kg/hour.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of surgery, the nondependent will be re-expanded and TLV will be resumed as before&#xD;
      surgery. At the end of surgery, sevoflurane will be discontinued, the residual neuromuscular&#xD;
      block will be antagonized, and the patient will be extubated. Postoperative analgesia will be&#xD;
      accomplished with the use of patient-controlled morphine analgesia, lornoxicam and&#xD;
      paracetamol. A restrictive fluid and transfusion policy will be adopted throughout the study&#xD;
      periods, with targeted fluid balance of maximum 500 ml/day and transfusion triggers ranging&#xD;
      between 8 and 9 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The development of ALI, defined according to the American-European Consensus Conference&#xD;
      criteria as sudden onset of respiratory distress within the first 48 hours after surgery;&#xD;
      infiltrates on the chest radiograph consistent with pulmonary edema; impaired oxygenation&#xD;
      with an PaO2/FIO2 ratio less than 300 mmHg for ALI; and absence of cardiac insufficiency or&#xD;
      fluid overload, based on PICCO2, echocardiogram and/or clinical evaluation&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be tested for normality using the Kolmogorov-Smirnov test. Fisher exact test will&#xD;
      be used for categorical data. Repeated measure analysis of variance (ANOVA) and Tukey's&#xD;
      Honestly Significant Difference post hoc tests will be used to evaluate the effects of time,&#xD;
      group, and interaction in the continuous data of the primary (EVLWI and EVLWI/LTBV ratio) and&#xD;
      secondary endpoints in each group. Kruskal-Wallis one-way ANOVA and posthoc Wilcoxon rank sum&#xD;
      tests will be done for intergroup comparisons for the nonparametric variables. univariate&#xD;
      analysis for the risk factors for increases in EVLWI after OLV for VATS will be done&#xD;
      including age, sex, preoperative pulmonary function, duration of surgery and OLV, tidal&#xD;
      volume, and FiO2. Data will be expressed as mean ± SD, number (%), or median [range]. A value&#xD;
      of P &lt; 0.05 will be considered to be statistically significant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Extra vascular lung water (EVLW)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline up to 3 hours after surgery.</time_frame>
    <description>extra vascular lung water (EVLW)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Arterial tension to inspired fraction of oxygen (PaO2/FiO2) ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline up to 3 hours after surgery.</time_frame>
    <description>Arterial tension to inspired fraction of oxygen (PaO2/FiO2) ratio</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Arterial carbon dioxide tension (PaCO2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline up to 3 hours after surgery.</time_frame>
    <description>Arterial carbon dioxide tension (PaCO2)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative complications</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline up to 3 hours after surgery.</time_frame>
    <description>pulmonary complications</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">39</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The VT 4 ml/kg group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Use of tidal volume of 4 ml/kg during one lung ventilation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The VT 6 ml/kg group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Use of tidal volume of 6 ml/kg during one lung ventilation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The VT 8 ml/kg group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Use of tidal volume of 8 ml/kg during one lung ventilation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The VT 4 ml/kg group</intervention_name>
    <description>the dependent lung will be ventilated with a TV of 4 mL/kg (predicted body weight), respectively, whereas FiO2, I: E ratio, PEEP, frequency, Ppk, and a FGF will be maintained as during two-lung ventilation (TLV) and the lumen of the nondependent lung will be left open to air. Dependent lung recruitment maneuvers will be repeated at 30-minute intervals by raising the inspiratory pressure up to 35 cmH2O for 10 seconds.</description>
    <arm_group_label>The VT 4 ml/kg group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The VT 6 ml/kg group</intervention_name>
    <description>the dependent lung will be ventilated with a TV of 6 mL/kg (predicted body weight), respectively, whereas FiO2, I: E ratio, PEEP, frequency, Ppk, and a FGF will be maintained as during two-lung ventilation (TLV) and the lumen of the nondependent lung will be left open to air. Dependent lung recruitment maneuvers will be repeated at 30-minute intervals by raising the inspiratory pressure up to 35 cmH2O for 10 seconds.</description>
    <arm_group_label>The VT 6 ml/kg group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The VT 8 ml/kg group</intervention_name>
    <description>the dependent lung will be ventilated with a TV of 8 mL/kg (predicted body weight), respectively, whereas FiO2, I: E ratio, PEEP, frequency, Ppk, and a FGF will be maintained as during two-lung ventilation (TLV) and the lumen of the nondependent lung will be left open to air. Dependent lung recruitment maneuvers will be repeated at 30-minute intervals by raising the inspiratory pressure up to 35 cmH2O for 10 seconds.</description>
    <arm_group_label>The VT 8 ml/kg group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  American Society of Anesthesiologists physical classes from II to III&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  decompensated cardiac diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pulmonary diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hepatic diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  renal diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pulmonary hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  obesity with a body mass index &gt;35 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  preoperative mechanically ventilated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  urgent procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  previous history of pneumonectomy, bilobectomy, or lobectomy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hatem Qutub, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Associate Professor</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mohamed R El Tahan, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Assistant Professor</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Anesthesiology Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Al Khubar</city>
        <state>Eastern</state>
        <zip>31592</zip>
        <country>Saudi Arabia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Saudi Arabia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 30, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 7, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 8, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 24, 2013</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 24, 2013</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">July 25, 2013</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Video-assisted thoracoscopic surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>one lung ventilation</keyword>
  <keyword>low tidal volume</keyword>
  <keyword>acute lung injury</keyword>
  <keyword>lung water content</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

