<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00187759</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ISIS placebo</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00187759</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Placebo Controlled Study of Antibiotic Treatment of Soft Tissue Infection</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Placebo Controlled, Randomized, and Blinded Study of Antibiotic Treatment of Patients With Uncomplicated Soft Tissue Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, San Francisco</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, San Francisco</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is to determine whether antibiotic therapy is needed for patients with non-life&#xD;
      threatening soft tissue infections. Most patients with these soft tissue infections are&#xD;
      presently treated with antibiotics. Many of these infections resolve without proper&#xD;
      antibiotic treatment. Treatment of patients with antibiotics after surgical drainage of an&#xD;
      abscess may not be necessary and indiscriminate use of antibiotics may lead to colonization&#xD;
      by drug-resistant organisms. Subsequent infection by drug resistant organisms may limit the&#xD;
      choice of antibiotics in more complicated infections. A comparison between antibiotic&#xD;
      treatment and no antibiotic treatment in surgically treated, uncomplicated soft tissue&#xD;
      infections is needed to address this very important question.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Integrated Soft Tissue Infection Service (ISIS) Clinic at San Francisco General Hospital&#xD;
      treats a large number of patients with soft tissue infections, and our data suggest that&#xD;
      antibiotics may be overused for these infections. Most of these infections are treated by&#xD;
      surgical drainage of an abscess (77%). When microbiologic cultures were performed, 88% of the&#xD;
      abscesses were infected with Staphylococcus aureus (S. aureus), and 55% of the abscesses&#xD;
      contained methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA). Recently, the high prevalence&#xD;
      of MRSA infection has been documented in San Francisco and throughout the country. Presently,&#xD;
      most patients are treated with antibiotics after drainage of the abscess. Our retrospective&#xD;
      analysis found that 60% of these infections resolved without appropriate antibiotic&#xD;
      treatment. These were patients infected with MRSA who were treated with an antibiotic that&#xD;
      was not active against that organism. This implies that surgical drainage of these abscesses&#xD;
      was probably the important treatment and antibiotic treatment was probably not necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Unnecessary use of antibiotics has adverse consequences. Some patients have allergic&#xD;
      reactions to antibiotics. Patients can develop serious gastrointestinal infections from&#xD;
      antibiotic use. Antibiotics are costly. But most importantly, overuse of antibiotics may be&#xD;
      the significant factor in the spread of antibiotic resistant organisms. The increased&#xD;
      prevalence of MRSA has made it extremely difficult to treat patients with appropriate&#xD;
      antibiotics in life threatening infections (i.e. bacterial endocarditis, osteomyelitis, and&#xD;
      necrotizing soft tissue infections).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The experience in the ISIS Clinic has brought into question our present practice of&#xD;
      antibiotic use in patients with surgically managed abscesses. Many surgeons practicing in the&#xD;
      ISIS clinic believe that antibiotics have little or no effect on the clinical course of these&#xD;
      uncomplicated infections. Elimination of antibiotic use for these uncomplicated infections&#xD;
      would certainly simplify care for these patients. It is even possible that decreased&#xD;
      antibiotic use may decrease the prevalence of MRSA colonization in this population. However,&#xD;
      decreased prevalence of MRSA colonization will not be specifically addressed in this limited&#xD;
      study. A randomized, prospective and blinded trial comparing standard antibiotic treatment&#xD;
      with no treatment should help determine whether antibiotics are really needed for these&#xD;
      infections.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2004</start_date>
  <completion_date>March 2005</completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cure of soft tissue infection.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment>500</enrollment>
  <condition>Soft Tissue Infections</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>cephalexin</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Patients must have a complicated skin or skin-structure infection that meets&#xD;
             disease diagnostic criteria (severity, definition of complicated, and disease).&#xD;
&#xD;
        SEVERITY: Complicated soft tissue infections must be of sufficient severity to anticipate&#xD;
        five or more days of antibiotic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        DEFINITION OF COMPLICATED (one or more of the following criteria must be met): Infection&#xD;
        requires(ed) significant surgical intervention (such as debridement of devitalized tissue,&#xD;
        drainage of abscess, removal of foreign body implicated in infection) at the time of&#xD;
        enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        DISEASE: Major Abscess (no open wound). The patient must have all of the following: i)&#xD;
        Acute onset within seven days prior to enrollment. ii) Purulent drainage or purulent&#xD;
        aspirate. iii) Erythema, induration, or tenderness. iv) Evidence of loculated fluid by&#xD;
        physical examination, blind aspiration, or ultrasound that requires intervention (such as&#xD;
        aspiration, incision and drainage, excision) at the time of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. A culture must be obtained at the time of enrollment. 3. Patients must be at least 18&#xD;
        years of age. 4. The patient must sign and date a Committee on Human Research-approved&#xD;
        informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any of the following conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients unlikely to survive through the treatment period and evaluations.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Conditions such as toxic shock syndrome or toxic-like syndrome (Mandell et al.&#xD;
                  2000), shock or hypotension (supine systolic blood pressure &lt;80 mmHg) refractory&#xD;
                  to fluid or short course pressor challenge (four hours or less) or oliguria&#xD;
                  (urine output &lt;20 mL/hr) not responsive to fluid challenge.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Incisional wound that extends into visceral compartments.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Suspected or proven contiguous bony or joint involvement.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Malignant otitis externa.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Ischemic ulcers or wounds associated with sever arterial insufficiency or&#xD;
                  gangrene.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Infection of prosthetic materials or venous catheters that cannot be removed as&#xD;
                  part of the treatment of the current infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Infection of a full-thickness burn wound or burn wound that is &gt;20% total body&#xD;
                  area.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Surgical/nonsurgical debridement of devitalized tissue, removal of prosthetic&#xD;
             material, incision and drainage, suture removal, percutaneous aspiration, packing,&#xD;
             dressings, or irrigation (including with antibiotics) that cannot be instituted at the&#xD;
             time of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any known sensitivity to cephalexin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with renal compromise.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David M Young, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, San Francisco</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>San Francisco General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 15, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 15, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 16, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 6, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 6, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 7, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Abscess</keyword>
  <keyword>Antibitoics</keyword>
  <keyword>Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Soft Tissue Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cephalexin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

