<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03670602</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>5UH3DK109543-05</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>5UH3DK109543-05</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03670602</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prediabetes and Weight Loss</brief_title>
  <acronym>MINDD4</acronym>
  <official_title>Delay Discounting as a Target for Self-Regulation in Prediabetes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>State University of New York at Buffalo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>State University of New York at Buffalo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goals of the UH3 are to assess the effectiveness of adding Episodic Future Thinking (EFT)&#xD;
      to the investigators standard behavioral weight control program to improve weight loss, delay&#xD;
      discounting (DD), working memory, glycemic control (HbA1c) and behavioral medication&#xD;
      adherence over a 6 month period in persons with prediabetes and comorbid hypertension and/or&#xD;
      hyperlipidemia. This will be accomplished by a randomized trial (N = 71 randomized) comparing&#xD;
      the effects of EFT versus control that matches attention and use of technology.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Participants in both groups will first attend weekly group meetings followed by monthly group&#xD;
      meetings for up to 6 months. They will be provided general information on healthy diet,&#xD;
      physical activity and medication adherence that the investigators will develop combining&#xD;
      strengths of the investigators well validated family-based behavioral treatment for obesity&#xD;
      and the Diabetes Prevention Program (DPP) lifestyle intervention for prediabetes. The&#xD;
      behavioral treatment (BT) is a rigorously tested, multi-component intervention that targets&#xD;
      diet, activity, and behavioral skills. The treatment will include: 1) a modified version of&#xD;
      the Traffic Light Diet, which utilizes RED, YELLOW, GREEN labels for food to guide&#xD;
      participants toward the goal of consuming low energy dense, low glycemic, high nutrient dense&#xD;
      foods; 2) the Traffic Light Activity Program, which also utilizes RED, YELLOW and GREEN&#xD;
      labels for different levels of caloric expenditure, and 3) a variety of behavioral&#xD;
      techniques, including stimulus control, self-monitoring, goal setting, problem solving,&#xD;
      resetting rewarding mechanisms by reducing need for immediate gratification, finding&#xD;
      behavioral substitutes for highly reinforcing food, and EFT. The investigators have used a&#xD;
      traffic light-based intervention in combination with EFT in a pilot study to demonstrate&#xD;
      therapeutic effects of EFT on BMI and dietary intake beyond the effects of BT alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During treatment meetings, participants will be weighed and have a 30-60 minute group session&#xD;
      (up to 20 per group) either preceded or followed by an individualized session with an&#xD;
      interventionist. The group sessions review information about weight loss and maintenance and&#xD;
      engage in group problem solving for participants who are struggling with behavior change.&#xD;
      During the individual meeting with their interventionist, participants are taught behavior&#xD;
      change techniques and review and address diet and activity self-monitoring and any barriers&#xD;
      to adherence with the weight-loss behaviors. A study website will be developed that will be&#xD;
      used to provide information about the intervention, downloadable manuals for the Traffic&#xD;
      Light Diet and Activity Program, manage the EFT component of the intervention, and provide&#xD;
      tools for cooking, and getting more physical activity. Quizzes to assess mastery of&#xD;
      educational materials will be implemented on the study website, with multiple versions of&#xD;
      quizzes on each module available to account for those participants who will acquire the&#xD;
      information more slowly than others. Participants will have access to traditional paper and&#xD;
      pencil self-monitoring, and consistent with current implementation of BT, after&#xD;
      self-monitoring skill is acquired, participants can choose to use traditional or&#xD;
      technology-based recording. Participants will have access to the study website for feedback,&#xD;
      and interventionists will have access to the website to assess patient progress, assist with&#xD;
      problem solving and to communicate with participants to structure solutions. The website will&#xD;
      also contain password protected sections that are for internal use by study personnel. This&#xD;
      section will be a repository for study documents and a communications hub for the study. The&#xD;
      website will not contain protected health information.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in both groups will meet with an interventionist to review progress. One group&#xD;
      will be trained to implement EFT using the ecological momentary intervention (EMI) computer&#xD;
      based program that the investigators have developed. This program can be accessed by&#xD;
      smartphone, tablet or computer. This application stores self-generated EFT cues, prompts&#xD;
      their use, asks questions about use, and records their use. EFT training will include&#xD;
      developing individualized future event cues to use in implementing EFT in the natural&#xD;
      environment. In the control group, participants may use non-future cues, recall previous&#xD;
      events, and not use prospection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cues are stimuli that prompt engaging in EFT. Cues can be signs, reminder cards, audio cues,&#xD;
      or physical cues. Subjects will practice using these cues and learn to envision that the&#xD;
      &quot;future is now&quot; when making decisions in the laboratory as they are engaged in a variety of&#xD;
      DD and food decision training tasks such as the opportunity to have a very enticing snack now&#xD;
      or larger portions of healthier food later, earning a small amount of money now or more&#xD;
      later, etc. In this way, participants will learn to generate episodic future cues and&#xD;
      practice EFT skills in situations where they usually would choose the more immediate reward.&#xD;
      Episodic future cues may include audio and written cues that can be accessed during tempting&#xD;
      situations in the natural environment. During individual sessions interventionists will&#xD;
      review habit changes and medication adherence, and use of EFT. In the control group&#xD;
      participants will use the cues to recall previous behaviors and not use prospection, but will&#xD;
      otherwise engage in the same tasks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in both groups will be weighed at the beginning of each session, and height will&#xD;
      also be collected at baseline. Data to be collected at baseline, 3 and 6 months include delay&#xD;
      discounting tasks, working memory, measures of medication and behavioral adherence, weight,&#xD;
      glycemic control, blood pressure and cholesterol, eating and activity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 17, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants will engage in EFT or control while using The Traffic Light Diet, The Traffic Light Activity Program, and a variety of behavioral techniques including stimulus control, self-monitoring, goal setting, problem solving, resetting rewarding mechanisms by reducing need for immediate gratification, finding behavioral substitutes for highly reinforcing food.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Research personnel who will be conducting assessment sessions, including weight measurements, will not be informed of participant's group assignment</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Delay Discounting</measure>
    <time_frame>Delay Discounting will be measured at baseline, 3 months, and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Delay Discounting will be assessed using Delay Discounting tasks</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Body Weight</measure>
    <time_frame>Delay Discounting will be measured at baseline, 3 months, and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Body weight will be measured using a digital scale</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Glycemic Control</measure>
    <time_frame>Hemoglobin A1c will be measured at baseline, 3 months, and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Glycemic control will be measured as hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Medical Adherence via Self-Report Medication Adherence Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Medication Adherence will be measured at baseline, 3 months, and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Adherence to prescribed medication for co-morbid hypertension and/or hyperlipidemia will be assessed using a self-report questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Behavioral Health Adherence via Actigraph Accelerometer</measure>
    <time_frame>Behavioral Adherence will be measured at baseline, 3 months, and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Behavioral adherence will be assessed by monitoring physical activity. Participants will be asked to wear an Actigraph Accelerometer for at least 10 hours per day for approximately one week. Adherence to wear-time will be measured in minutes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Behavioral Health Adherence via Dietary Records.</measure>
    <time_frame>Behavioral Adherence will be measured at baseline, 3 months, and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Behavioral adherence will be assessed by monitoring dietary intake. Participants will be asked to record all dietary intake into an online diary. Adherence to recording intake will be measured per day that items are recorded.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Working Memory</measure>
    <time_frame>Working memory will be measured at baseline, 3 months, and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visuospatial working memory will be measured using the Backwards Corsi block-tapping task.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Minutes of Physical Activity via Actigraph Accelerometer</measure>
    <time_frame>Physical activity will be measured at baseline, 3 months, and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Minutes of physical activity will be assessed using an Actigraph accelerometer that participants will wear for approximately one week.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Food Purchasing</measure>
    <time_frame>Food purchasing will be measured at baseline, 3 months, and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Food purchasing demand will be assessed with a hypothetical purchase task with different prices.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">64</enrollment>
  <condition>PreDiabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Episodic Future Thinking (EFT)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will generate positive future cues that will be accessed via an electronic app to engage in EFT.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Thinking</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will generate or be provided with non-future cues.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Episodic Future Thinking (EFT)</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will practice using these cues when making decisions about health choices. Participants will implement EFT while using The Traffic Light Diet, The Traffic Light Activity Program, and a variety of behavioral techniques including stimulus control, self-monitoring, goal setting, problem solving, resetting rewarding mechanisms by reducing need for immediate gratification, finding behavioral substitutes for highly reinforcing food.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Episodic Future Thinking (EFT)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control Thinking</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants may see non-future cues that do not require prospection while using The Traffic Light Diet, The Traffic Light Activity Program, and a variety of behavioral techniques including stimulus control, self-monitoring, goal setting, problem solving, resetting rewarding mechanisms by reducing need for immediate gratification, finding behavioral substitutes for highly reinforcing food.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Thinking</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Overweight or obese (BMI ≥ 25)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prediabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Type 2 Diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of diabetic drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not ambulatory&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intellectual impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unmanaged mood disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current substance use disorder (excluding nicotine and caffeine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of eating disorders (Except binge eating disorder)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal blood glucose related to medications&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Leonard H Epstein, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>State University of New York at Buffalo</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Warren K Bickel, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University at Buffalo, Department of Pediatrics, Division of Behavioral Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Buffalo</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>14214</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 7, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 12, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 13, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>State University of New York at Buffalo</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Leonard Epstein</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prediabetic State</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Glucose Intolerance</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

