<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03678246</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017-2135</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03678246</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Low Skill Fibreoptic Glottis View in Obese Patients: Ramp vs Supine Sniffing Air Position</brief_title>
  <official_title>Low Skill Fibreoptic Glottis View in Obese Patients: Ramp vs Supine Sniffing Air Position</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Singapore General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Singapore General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aims: The investigators are employing a feasibility study to determine whether fibreoptic&#xD;
      view of the glottis (vocal cords) during low skill fibreoptic intubation (FOI) via a&#xD;
      laryngeal mask airway (LMA) in obese and severely obese patients is appropriate and feasible&#xD;
      for future full-scale research. Obese, and severely and morbidly patients in Asia are classed&#xD;
      as body mass index (BMI) of ≥ 30, ≥35 and ≥40 kg/m2, respectively.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aims: The investigators are employing a feasibility study to determine whether fibreoptic&#xD;
      view of the glottis (vocal cords) during low skill fibreoptic intubation (FOI) via a&#xD;
      laryngeal mask airway (LMA) in obese and severely obese patients is appropriate and feasible&#xD;
      for future full-scale research. Obese, and severely and morbidly patients in Asia are classed&#xD;
      as body mass index (BMI) of ≥ 30, ≥35 and ≥40 kg/m2, respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: The glottis view during low skill FOI in obese and severely obese patients (BMI&#xD;
      ≥30, and BMI ≥35 &lt;40 kg/m2) is better in the ramp than in the standard supine 'sniffing air'&#xD;
      position. Low skill FOI is a term for FOI via an LMA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology: As a feasibility study, the investigators will recruit 18 adult patients&#xD;
      scheduled for elective surgery in obese and severely obese patients requiring tracheal&#xD;
      intubation. A non-randomized cross over design in selected. The investigators will assess&#xD;
      acceptability, implementation and practicality of such a study and also set criteria for&#xD;
      success of this feasibility study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Importance of proposed research: Obese patients present many anaesthetic challenges. The ramp&#xD;
      position facilitates easier tracheal intubation and prolongs apnoea time. In cases of failed&#xD;
      intubation, guidelines recommend insertion of an LMA to faciliate ventilation and&#xD;
      oxygenation, allowing the option of low skill FOI to secure the airway. It may be performed&#xD;
      in unanticipated difficult airway ('rescue' intubation after failed intubation by&#xD;
      conventional techniques) and so may decrease patient morbidity and mortality. There is a&#xD;
      knowledge gap regarding whether the glottis view during low skill FOI is superior in the ramp&#xD;
      or standard supine sniffing position. It will help determine whether the study methodology&#xD;
      and protocol needs modification and assess what changes may occur, before implementing a&#xD;
      full-scale study. This will help form recommendations for future guidelines in difficult&#xD;
      airway management.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcome is to measure feasibility of this study. The areas of focus addressed by this&#xD;
      study are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the investigators will assess how many obese and severely obese patients we can recruit&#xD;
           in the Pre-Operative Evaluation Clinic (PEC)&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Patient reaction and recruitment rate (accepting or declining invitation to the&#xD;
                study)&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Patient dropout rate&#xD;
&#xD;
                Integration: Previous studies evaluating FOI via the LMA have proved less&#xD;
                straightforward than anticipated. Standard rostering of anaesthetic study members&#xD;
                does not allocate the latter to the operating theatre where study patients are&#xD;
                listed; this means the anaesthetic study team member needs to leave their own&#xD;
                operating list elsewhere to deliver the study intervention leading to poor&#xD;
                workflow. Also, the investigators used operating intubating fibrescopes, which had&#xD;
                priority allocation to other (nonstudy) patients due to clinical reasons. In&#xD;
                addition, the number of fibrescopes was greatly reduced due to maintenance and&#xD;
                repair work. As such, our study protocol incorporates different workflows. As soon&#xD;
                as a participant is recruited, the investigators will inform the roster consultant&#xD;
                to allocate one of the anaesthetic study member to the operating theatre where a&#xD;
                participant is listed to improve workflow. The investigators will also use grant&#xD;
                funded disposable fibrescopes and grant funded fibrescope monitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
                Assessment will be made of:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  1. Percentage of lists that contain study participants that have an allocated&#xD;
                     study team member, aiming for 80% allocation.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  2. Any workflow availability.&#xD;
&#xD;
                Practicality: The investigators will assess for any difficulties when the patient&#xD;
                is changed from a ramp to standard supine sniffing position by a coordinated team&#xD;
                effort by theatre personnel.&#xD;
&#xD;
                Secondary outcome measures will evaluate the technique of FOI via the LMA in our&#xD;
                study population, comparing ramp and standard 'sniffing air' positions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Success of LMA insertion rate (after LMA insertion, an adequate capnography trace is&#xD;
           obtained under study ventilation parameters, whilst in ramp position)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  LMA insertion times (time from picking up the LMA for insertion until adequate&#xD;
           capnography trace is obtained, whilst in ramp position)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Fibreoptic intubation times (time from picking up the fibrescope, after the patient has&#xD;
           been place in the standard supine sniffing position, until adequate capnography trace is&#xD;
           obtained)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Airway manoeuvers to optimize glottis view&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Any complications&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 13, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 30, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 30, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Ramped vs Supine position</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Images are reviewed by two senior anaesthetists who is not directly involved in the study.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility study</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>patient recruitment rate and ability to complete the study</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Positioning challenges</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>descriptive scale with free text comments on difficulties encountered during positioning from ramped to supine</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Success of LMA insertion rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Success of LMA insertion rate with number of attempts stated</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>LMA insertion times</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>LMA insertion times</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fibreoptic intubation times</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Fibreoptic intubation times</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Airway manoeuvres to optimize glottis view</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>options include jaw thrust and withdrawal of LMA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Any complications</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>descriptive scale listing the problems/complications encountered during the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">16</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LSFOI (Ramped)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>LSFOI (Ramped)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LSFOI (Supine)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>LSFOI (Supine)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ramped position</intervention_name>
    <description>LSFOI glottis view</description>
    <arm_group_label>LSFOI (Ramped)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>LSFOI (Supine)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Supine position</intervention_name>
    <description>LSFOI glottis view</description>
    <arm_group_label>LSFOI (Ramped)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>LSFOI (Supine)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  obese and severely obese patients (BMI ≥30, and ≥35 but &lt;40 kg/m2, respectively)&#xD;
             undergoing elective bsurgery under general anaesthesia who require endotracheal&#xD;
             intubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Morbidly obese patients (BMI ≥40 kg/m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with history of previous difficult endotracheal intubation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with two or more predictors of difficult face or laryngeal mask ventilation,&#xD;
             or difficult intubation or the combination of both&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mallamapatti score III-IV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Interdental distance &lt;3cm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thyromental distance &lt;6cm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate to severe limitation of neck movement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous head and neck radiotherapy or surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Supraglottic lesion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with loose teeth&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with ASA grade III (other than due to obesity) and grade IV are excluded from&#xD;
             the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients needing a rapid sequence induction for rapid securement of the airway e.g.&#xD;
             patients with symptoms of reflux (&gt;1 episode per week), not starved as per standard&#xD;
             nil by mouth guidelines, hiatus hernia, previous gastric surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients below the age of 21 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unfit to give consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Singapore General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Singapore</city>
        <zip>169608</zip>
        <country>Singapore</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Singapore</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 17, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 19, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 12, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 12, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 14, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

