<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03679975</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>17MO1R-0012</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03679975</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Riluzole Oral Soluble Film (ROSF) Swallowing Safety in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS)</brief_title>
  <acronym>ROSF</acronym>
  <official_title>A Single Center Study to Evaluate the Effect of Riluzole Oral Soluble Film on Swallowing Safety in Individuals With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Aquestive Therapeutics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>inVentiv Health Clinical</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Covance</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Aquestive Therapeutics</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective is to evaluate the effect, if any, of a single 50 mg dose of Riluzole&#xD;
      Oral Soluble Film (ROSF) on swallowing safety in individuals with amyotrophic lateral&#xD;
      sclerosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This was a single site, single dose, open-label study with one group of male or female&#xD;
      patients between 18-80 years old with a diagnosis of Probable or Definite Amyotrophic Lateral&#xD;
      Sclerosis (ALS) according to revised El-Escorial Criteria. Patients seen in the ALS Clinic at&#xD;
      the University of Florida were screened to determine eligibility for participation in the&#xD;
      study according to the specified inclusion/exclusion criteria. Following informed consent and&#xD;
      enrollment, subjects were given a complete physical and neurological examination including&#xD;
      the validated Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale-Revised (ALSFRS-R).&#xD;
      Swallowing safety was assessed using the gold standard Videofluoroscopic Swallowing Study&#xD;
      (VFSS) to allow direct visualization of the swallowing process and any episodes of&#xD;
      penetration or aspiration were quantified using the validated Penetration Aspiration Scale&#xD;
      (PAS). Subjects participated in a standardized protocol that includes 11 bolus stimuli&#xD;
      presentations of different liquid and food materials to test swallowing function using a&#xD;
      progression of textures and materials. Immediately following this assessment, subjects were&#xD;
      given a single dose of ROSF 50 mg, placed on the median lingual sulcus of the dorsum of the&#xD;
      tongue (area under the tongue on the midline groove that separates the surface of the tongue&#xD;
      into right and left halves). Three minutes after the administration of ROSF, the identical&#xD;
      standardized VFSS protocol was re-administered to allow a comparison of swallowing safety&#xD;
      (using the PAS scale) pre- versus post-ROSF administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The original plan was to enroll 30 patients for a final sample size of 25 completed patients.&#xD;
      The protocol stipulated that, depending upon the study enrollment rate, the Sponsor could&#xD;
      elect to perform an interim analysis using available data from the subset of subjects who had&#xD;
      completed the study at that time. An interim assessment of the data was performed after 8&#xD;
      subjects had completed the study and a ninth patient had been screened and was awaiting VFSS.&#xD;
      With agreement from the FDA, the Sponsor decided to terminate the study after 9 completed&#xD;
      patients, based on the analysis of the first 8 completed patients showing no evidence of a&#xD;
      harmful effect of one dose of ROSF 50 mg on swallowing function.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    The study is no longer required&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 4, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 21, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 26, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The original plan was to enroll 30 patients for a final sample size of 25 completed patients. With agreement from the FDA, the Sponsor decided to terminate the study after 9 completed patients, based on an interim analysis of the first 8 completed patients with no evidence of a harmful effect of one dose of 50 mg Riluzole Oral Film on swallowing function.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants Categorized by Differences From Baseline in Penetration Aspiration Scale (PAS) - Sum of Scores Method</measure>
    <time_frame>Before and after administration of ROSF 50 mg on day 1 (visit 1)</time_frame>
    <description>Swallowing safety was assessed using the gold standard Videofluoroscopic Swallowing Study (VFSS) to allow direct visualization of the swallowing process and any episodes of penetration or aspiration were quantified using the validated Penetration Aspiration Scale (PAS). The PAS is an 8-point validated scale of swallowing safety that takes into account both degree/level of airway invasion during swallowing and the patients' response to the penetration or aspiration episode. The assessment is performed via videofluoroscope. Scores of 1 and 2 indicate airway safe swallowing with no airway invasion or ability to clear airway invasion. Scores 3 through 8 indicate airway unsafe swallowing based on penetration of the airway, level of penetration, and the patient's ability to respond. An increase in score/higher score means a worse outcome. A decrease in score/lower score means a better outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">9</enrollment>
  <condition>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Subjects with ALS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects with a diagnosis of probable or definite ALS in accordance with the Revised El-Escorial Criteria were administered a single dose of the Riluzole Oral Soluble Film (ROSF) 50 mg.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Riluzole Oral Soluble film (ROSF) 50 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>Enrolled subjects underwent an instrumental evaluation of swallowing safety before and after administration of a single dose of the ROSF formulation containing 50 mg of riluzole.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Subjects with ALS</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ROSF</other_name>
    <other_name>Riluzole Orodispersible Film (ROF)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female subjects between 18-80 years of age, inclusive&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects with a diagnosis of probable or definite ALS in accordance with the Revised&#xD;
             El-Escorial Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects must be currently on an oral diet and able to take foods and liquids by mouth&#xD;
             equivalent to a score of 3 or above on the Functional Oral Intake Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects with no known allergy to barium, riluzole or inactive ingredients in ROSF&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject or subject's legally authorized representative must be willing and able to&#xD;
             give informed consent/assent and HIPAA authorization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject must have the ability to comprehend and be informed of the nature of the&#xD;
             study, as assessed by the Principal Investigator or Sub-Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects prescribed riluzole at or before the dose of study drug. (The study was open&#xD;
             to subjects currently taking riluzole at screening, subjects who were not currently&#xD;
             taking riluzole at screening who had taken riluzole in the past, and subjects to be&#xD;
             newly started on riluzole (given as ROSF in this study).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Availability to volunteer for the entire study duration and willing to adhere to all&#xD;
             protocol requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Female subjects of childbearing potential (i.e. not surgically sterile, not 2 years&#xD;
             postmenopausal, or not with a sterile partner) must have a negative pregnancy test at&#xD;
             Screening and Visit 1, agree to abstinence, be practicing double barrier contraception&#xD;
             or using an FDA approved barrier method contraceptive (e.g., licensed hormonal or&#xD;
             barrier methods) for more than 2 months prior to the screening visit and commit to an&#xD;
             acceptable form of birth control for the duration of the study and for 30 days after&#xD;
             participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects who score 2 or below on the Functional Oral Intake Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects with a prior swallowing study that has shown a Penetration Aspiration Scale&#xD;
             score of 3 or greater&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects with a history of 2 or more episodes of aspiration pneumonia requiring&#xD;
             hospitalization&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects with a history of clinically significant liver disease, renal disease, or any&#xD;
             other medical condition judged to be exclusionary by the Investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects who were unwilling to sign informed consent or subjects who for any other&#xD;
             reason in the judgment of investigator were unable to complete the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Female subjects who had a positive urine pregnancy test (βhCG) at screening or Visit&#xD;
             1, were trying to become pregnant, or were breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects with active cancer within the previous 2 years, except treated basal cell&#xD;
             carcinoma of the skin&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects who had taken any experimental drug within 30 days prior to enrollment or&#xD;
             within 5 half-lives of the investigational drug -whichever was the longer period.&#xD;
             However, subjects who had previously completed other Aquestive Therapeutics-sponsored&#xD;
             ROSF clinical studies within the last 30 days prior to enrollment could be eligible&#xD;
             for consideration for entry into this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects with known history of moderate or severe renal impairment as defined by a&#xD;
             calculated creatinine clearance of ≤50 mL/minute&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects currently taking riluzole with alanine aminotransferase levels greater than 5&#xD;
             times upper limit of normal or with evidence of clinical jaundice. (Riluzole should be&#xD;
             discontinued in these patients.)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects who would be receiving riluzole for the first time who exhibited baseline&#xD;
             elevations of several liver function tests (especially elevated bilirubin). (These&#xD;
             findings at baseline should preclude the use of riluzole including ROSF).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Use of potentially hepatotoxic drugs: (e.g., allopurinol, methyldopa, sulfasalazine).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subjects with clinically significant abnormal laboratory values in the judgment of the&#xD;
             Investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Use of strong or moderate CYP1A2 inhibitors (e.g., ciprofloxacin, enoxacin,&#xD;
             fluvoxamine, methoxsalen, mexiletine, thiabendazole, vemurafenib, zileuton) and CYP1A2&#xD;
             inducers (e.g. rifampin and barbiturates) in the previous 30 days before first drug&#xD;
             administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Anything else that, in the opinion of the Investigator, would place the subject at&#xD;
             increased risk or preclude the subject's full compliance with or completion of the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Employee or immediate relative of an employee of the investigator, Aquestive&#xD;
             Therapeutics, any of its affiliates or partners, or inVentiv Health.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Cassie Jung</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Aquestive Therapeutics</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Florida Center for Movement Disorders &amp; Neuroscience</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32607</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 19, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 19, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 21, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>June 24, 2020</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>July 30, 2020</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Actual">August 10, 2020</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 18, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Motor Neuron Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Riluzole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>October 18, 2017</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/75/NCT03679975/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>October 12, 2018</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/75/NCT03679975/SAP_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <recruitment_details>Eleven subjects were screened for the study: Two subjects withdrew after signing informed consent but prior to any study procedure. Nine subjects were enrolled and received study medication and completed the study. There were no discontinuations.</recruitment_details>
      <pre_assignment_details>Planned enrollment was 30 patients for a final sample size of 25 completed patients. The Sponsor decided to terminate the study after 9 completed patients (with agreement from the FDA), based on an interim analysis of the first 8 completed patients with no evidence of a harmful effect of 1 dose of 50 mg Riluzole Oral Film on swallowing function.</pre_assignment_details>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Patients With ALS With Single 50 mg Dose ROSF</title>
          <description>Single group of patients with a diagnosis of probable or definite ALS in accordance with the Revised El-Escorial Criteria.&#xD;
They participated in a Videofluoroscopic Swallowing Study (VFSS) with 11 bolus trials and were scored by two independent raters on the Penetration Aspiration Scale (PAS). They were then given a single dose of 50 mg Riluzole Oral Film, and the Videofluoroscopic Swallowing Study was repeated at three minutes after dosing.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="9"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="9"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Subjects With ALS</title>
          <description>Subjects with a diagnosis of probable or definite ALS in accordance with the Revisited El-Escorial Criteria will be administered a single dose of the Riluzole Oral Soluble Film (ROSF) 50 mg.&#xD;
Riluzole Oral Soluble film (ROSF) 50 mg: Enrolled subjects will undergo an instrumental evaluation of swallowing safety before and after administration of a single dose of the ROSF formulation containing 50 mg of riluzole.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="9"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>years</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Full Range</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="61" lower_limit="37" upper_limit="77"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="6"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="3"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Ethnicity (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="2"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Not Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="7"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Race (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>American Indian or Alaska Native</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Asian</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Black or African American</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>White</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="7"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>More than one race</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Region of Enrollment</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>United States</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Change in Penetration Aspiration Scale Score on Videofluoroscopic Study before and after a single do</title>
          <description>Subjects participated in a Videofluoroscopic Swallowing Study (VFSS) with 11 bolus trials and were scored by two independent raters on the Penetration Aspiration Scale (PAS). They were then given a single dose of 50 mg Riluzole Oral Film, and the Videofluoroscopic Swallowing Study was repeated at three minutes after dosing. The primary outcome was change on PAS scores from pre- to post-dose.</description>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="5"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Number of Participants Categorized by Differences From Baseline in Penetration Aspiration Scale (PAS) - Sum of Scores Method</title>
        <description>Swallowing safety was assessed using the gold standard Videofluoroscopic Swallowing Study (VFSS) to allow direct visualization of the swallowing process and any episodes of penetration or aspiration were quantified using the validated Penetration Aspiration Scale (PAS). The PAS is an 8-point validated scale of swallowing safety that takes into account both degree/level of airway invasion during swallowing and the patients' response to the penetration or aspiration episode. The assessment is performed via videofluoroscope. Scores of 1 and 2 indicate airway safe swallowing with no airway invasion or ability to clear airway invasion. Scores 3 through 8 indicate airway unsafe swallowing based on penetration of the airway, level of penetration, and the patient's ability to respond. An increase in score/higher score means a worse outcome. A decrease in score/lower score means a better outcome.</description>
        <time_frame>Before and after administration of ROSF 50 mg on day 1 (visit 1)</time_frame>
        <population>Safety Population comprising all enrolled subjects who received the single ROSF 50 mg administration.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Subjects With ALS</title>
            <description>Subjects with a diagnosis of probable or definite ALS in accordance with the Revised El-Escorial Criteria will be administered a single dose of the Riluzole Oral Soluble Film (ROSF) 50 mg.&#xD;
Riluzole Oral Soluble film (ROSF) 50 mg: Enrolled subjects will undergo an instrumental evaluation of swallowing safety before and after administration of a single dose of the ROSF formulation containing 50 mg of riluzole.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Number of Participants Categorized by Differences From Baseline in Penetration Aspiration Scale (PAS) - Sum of Scores Method</title>
          <description>Swallowing safety was assessed using the gold standard Videofluoroscopic Swallowing Study (VFSS) to allow direct visualization of the swallowing process and any episodes of penetration or aspiration were quantified using the validated Penetration Aspiration Scale (PAS). The PAS is an 8-point validated scale of swallowing safety that takes into account both degree/level of airway invasion during swallowing and the patients' response to the penetration or aspiration episode. The assessment is performed via videofluoroscope. Scores of 1 and 2 indicate airway safe swallowing with no airway invasion or ability to clear airway invasion. Scores 3 through 8 indicate airway unsafe swallowing based on penetration of the airway, level of penetration, and the patient's ability to respond. An increase in score/higher score means a worse outcome. A decrease in score/lower score means a better outcome.</description>
          <population>Safety Population comprising all enrolled subjects who received the single ROSF 50 mg administration.</population>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="9"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Increase in sum of scores post dose</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Same sum of scores post dose</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="7"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Decrease in sum of scores post dose</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="2"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>From screening until 1 day post-dose</time_frame>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Subjects With ALS</title>
          <description>Subjects with a diagnosis of probable or definite ALS in accordance with the Revisited El-Escorial Criteria will be administered a single dose of the Riluzole Oral Soluble Film (ROSF) 50 mg.&#xD;
Riluzole Oral Soluble film (ROSF) 50 mg: Enrolled subjects will undergo an instrumental evaluation of swallowing safety before and after administration of a single dose of the ROSF formulation containing 50 mg of riluzole.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="9"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="9"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>0</frequency_threshold>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="9"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>Principal Investigators are NOT employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>The only disclosure restriction on the PI is that the sponsor can review results communications prior to public release and can embargo communications regarding trial results for a period that is more than 60 days but less than or equal to 180 days. The sponsor cannot require changes to the communication and cannot extend the embargo.</restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Gary Slatko, Chief Medical Officer</name_or_title>
      <organization>Aquestive Therapeutics</organization>
      <phone>908-941-7050</phone>
      <email>clinicaltrials@aquestive.com</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

