<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03671642</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H-18006334</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03671642</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Perioperative Perfusion Measurement - a Feasibility and Usability Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Perioperative Perfusion Measurement - a Feasibility and Usability Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will investigate a new method to assess tissue perfusion during surgery for&#xD;
      esophageal cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When a tumor in the distal esophagus is removed, the ends of the esophagus and the stomach&#xD;
      must be reconnected by an anastomosis. An optimal perfusion is essential to ensure a good&#xD;
      healing of the anastomosis. If anastomotic leakage occurs, it may prolong hospital stay,&#xD;
      increase the risk of serious complications and death, delay start-up of chemotherapy and&#xD;
      worsen the long-term survival prognosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the operation the blood supply to the ends of the esophagus and stomach will be&#xD;
      assessed in different ways; The traditional where the surgeon looks and feels on the tissue,&#xD;
      and newer methods with an indocyanine green and cameras that illuminate the tissue with&#xD;
      near-infrared light. The surgeon will assess whether these methods change the decision on&#xD;
      where the ends should be sewn together.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction:&#xD;
&#xD;
      An optimal perfusion is essential in gastrointestinal surgery when resection of a cancerous&#xD;
      tissue requires an anastomosis, since impaired perfusion seems to be associated with&#xD;
      increased risk of anastomotic leakage (AL). AL is a severe complication with the risk of;&#xD;
      prolonged hospital stay, cancer recurrence, permanent stoma in colorectal surgery, and&#xD;
      increased short and long-term mortality. To avoid poor perfusion of an anastomosis, perfusion&#xD;
      assessment is necessary during the operative procedure. Traditionally, perfusion is assessed&#xD;
      visually and manually by the surgeon by judging the; color of the tissue, bleeding from the&#xD;
      resection line, and the arterial supply pulse by palpation. These methods have earlier been&#xD;
      shown to be unreliable and prone to observer bias. Furthermore, palpation of arterial supply&#xD;
      is not possible in laparoscopic or robot-assisted surgery, and the increased use of staplers&#xD;
      to divide the bowel leaves no bleeding resection lines. Therefore newer methods for perfusion&#xD;
      assessment have been investigated, and fluorescence angiography (FA) and laser speckle&#xD;
      contrast imaging (LSCI) has shown very promising results. In a systematic review of&#xD;
      nonrandomized studies, the leakage rate in 916 colorectal resections was significantly lower&#xD;
      when using FA compared to controls (3.3%, [95% CI: 1.97-4.63%] vs 8.5%, [95% CI: 4.8-12.2%],&#xD;
      p=0.0055).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In FA, the tissue of interest is exposed to near-infrared (NIR) light simultaneously with&#xD;
      intravenous injection of a fluorescent dye. When the dye reaches the illuminated area, it&#xD;
      fluoresces, and a camera with a special filter can visualize the microcirculation of the&#xD;
      tissue on a monitor. Many NIR-camera systems are on the market, combining the technique with&#xD;
      conventional laparoscopic or robotic equipment, and several non-randomized studies have&#xD;
      indicated that FA may reduce the anastomotic leakage rate in gastrointestinal surgery. Most&#xD;
      surgeons are using only a visual subjective assessment of the FA, which may be prone to&#xD;
      observer bias. Moreover, if the camera is not held at a standard distance from the tissue, or&#xD;
      a different concentration of dye is used, a false negative or positive assessment of the&#xD;
      perfusion may be made. Therefore, it has been argued that there is a need for an objective&#xD;
      unbiased quantitative assessment tool in FA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A quantification algorithm that provides a fluorescence-time curve and a quantitative&#xD;
      parameter of perfusion, the normalized slope has previously been published, where a nearly&#xD;
      linear correlation to regional flow was found. Until now measurements has been performed as&#xD;
      analyses of video-recordings after the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to use the method in a clinical setting, development and testing of a tool that may&#xD;
      be operated by the surgeon during the procedure to perform perioperative measurements is of&#xD;
      high importance. A touchscreen tablet has been developed, in order to perform live&#xD;
      perioperative quantitative perfusion assessment using FA. The tool may be used with several&#xD;
      systems including Karl Storz fluorescence laparoscopic equipment and the daVinci SI or XI&#xD;
      from Intuitive. This tool is essential in order to implement the technology into daily&#xD;
      practice, as it allows the surgeon to get an immediate quantitative parameter of perfusion&#xD;
      (normalized slope) at desired regions of interest. The interface of the tool should be easy&#xD;
      to use and provide fluorescence-time curves to control the automated calculation of the&#xD;
      normalized slope. In addition, a color-coded map of perfusion intensity should be provided as&#xD;
      an overlay on the white light picture of the bowel investigated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The touchscreen tablet has currently only been tested in animal surgery. The aim of the&#xD;
      present study is to investigate if the use of a perioperative quantitative perfusion&#xD;
      assessment tool may improve the perfusion assessment during surgery in humans.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypotheses:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Perioperative perfusion assessment with FA will change the point of resection determined&#xD;
           by conventional visual perfusion assessment in GI junctional procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Quantitative perfusion assessment with FA (Q-ICG) will further change the point of&#xD;
           resection determined by visual assessment of the FA and conventional visual assessment&#xD;
           of perfusion in GI junctional procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Feasibility of perfusion assessment with traditional visual, visual FA, and Q-ICG -&#xD;
           complied by completion rates.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The feasibility and usability of the tool, the surgeons' experiences with the&#xD;
           Q-ICG-tablet interface - rated on a validated questionnaire, the System Usability Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Differences in the distance from the determined resection points using traditional&#xD;
      assessment, FA, and Q-ICG.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be conducted as an observational feasibility and usability trial in patients&#xD;
      undergoing open or robot-assisted resection of the gastroesophageal junction (GI junction) in&#xD;
      a single university hospital center (Rigshospitalet, Department of Surgical&#xD;
      Gastroenterology). Patients will serve as their own control. Demographic information&#xD;
      (tumor-staging, gender, age, BMI, neoadjuvant treatment, ASA-classification, smoking,&#xD;
      alcohol, medication etc.) will be collected from the electronic patient records. In addition,&#xD;
      postoperative events, especially the presence of an anastomotic leakage, will be noted 30&#xD;
      days postoperatively. No formal sample size calculation has been performed as the study is a&#xD;
      feasibility study. 20 patients will be included. Participating patients will receive the same&#xD;
      standard post- and peri-operative care and follow-up as patients not included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Indocyanine green Indocyanine green (ICG) is a well-described nontoxic tricarbocyanine dye&#xD;
      used for decades in ophthalmology, cardiology, and hepatology. Very few mild adverse&#xD;
      reactions have been reported, but caution in patients with thyrotoxicosis, allergy towards&#xD;
      iodine or indocyanine green should be made. When injected intravenously it binds to blood&#xD;
      lipoproteins and is solely metabolized by the liver and excreted in the bile, with a short&#xD;
      half-life of approximately 4-5 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgical procedure and perfusion assessment When the dissection and division of the feeding&#xD;
      blood vessels are complete and the gastric conduit established and drawn to the thorax, the&#xD;
      gastrointestinal surgeon will choose the most proximal point possible on the conduit for the&#xD;
      anastomosis (Anastomotic point surgeon, APS) by pointing while a picture is captured, blinded&#xD;
      for the thoracic surgeon. A sterile paper ruler will be introduced to the thorax, in order to&#xD;
      measure the distance between the chosen resection points. Then, LSCI measurement of the&#xD;
      conduit is performed, and finally, a bolus of ICG (0.25 mg/kg body weight) will be injected&#xD;
      intravenously and flushed with 5 mL of saline, and the tissue of interest exposed to&#xD;
      NIR-light (excitation wavelength 750-800 nm) and emission observed at 800 nm (FA). During the&#xD;
      video-captures of LSCI and ICG-FA, the respiration will be paused for a maximum of 20 seconds&#xD;
      initiated at the moment of saline injection. After the FA the thoracic surgeon will by visual&#xD;
      assessment determine and mark a new anastomotic point by pointing at the most proximal point&#xD;
      possible on the conduit for the anastomosis, while a picture is taken (anastomotic point&#xD;
      fluorescence angiography, APFA). After the quantitative FA the surgeon will again mark an&#xD;
      anastomotic point (APQFA). The final anastomotic point will be chosen by the primary&#xD;
      gastrointestinal and the thoracic surgeon, and if the assessment of FA or quantitative FA&#xD;
      will influence this decision is solely up to the surgeon. The same points will be marked on&#xD;
      the LSCI picture but not revealed to the surgeon since the quantitative assessment of the&#xD;
      LSCI demands on post hoc data-analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When the surgeon decides how much tissue to resect to ensure an optimal anastomotic&#xD;
      perfusion, care must be taken not to cause tension to the anastomosis by resecting too much&#xD;
      of the gastric conduit or the esophagus, as tension is a known risk factor of anastomotic&#xD;
      leakage. Again, the level of resection is solely decided by the surgeon and this decision&#xD;
      should, as always, be made by balancing factors of tension, perfusion, and excessive tissue&#xD;
      loss - all combined to ensure an optimal anastomotic healing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laparoscopic fluorescence angiography A laparoscope (ICG-Hopkins telescope 30°, 10 mm, Karl&#xD;
      Storz Gmbh and Co. KG, Tüttlingen, Germany) will be connected to a camera system (IMAGE1,&#xD;
      Karl Storz Gmbh and Co. KG, Tüttlingen, Germany) and a light-source (D-light P, Karl Storz&#xD;
      Gmbh and Co. KG, Tüttlingen, Germany) will supply the excitatory light and record the FA. The&#xD;
      laparoscope will be fixed in a mechanical holding arm 10 cm from the tissue of interest,&#xD;
      ensuring a stable position throughout the experiment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Robot-assisted fluorescence angiography A surgical robot DaVinci SI (Intuitive Surgical Inc.,&#xD;
      Sunnyvale, CA, USA) and the Firefly Fluorescence Imaging system will be used. The camera will&#xD;
      be fixed 10 cm from the tissue of interest, ensuring a stable position throughout the&#xD;
      experiment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Quantitative fluorescence angiography (Q-ICG) A video capture device (Av.io HD™, Epiphan&#xD;
      video, California, USA) will be connected to the surgical robot or the laparoscopic camera&#xD;
      system and transfer the video capture to a tablet (Microsoft Surface Pro4 I5, Microsoft,&#xD;
      Redmond, WA, USA). A program developed to quantify the FA will be installed. Here the&#xD;
      operator can choose regions of interest to quantify from the captured video sequence. A color&#xD;
      grading of perfusion will be provided as well as quantitative values from specific points.&#xD;
      From this assessment, the surgeon will again determine a new resection point (APQFA).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Comparison of resection points The distance from the tumor to the RPS will be measured before&#xD;
      the FA using the paper ruler. In addition, the distance from the APS to APFA and APQFA will&#xD;
      be measured using the ruler, either during the procedure or post hoc using the video-capture.&#xD;
      The comparison of the distance will be made on the distance of each point from the tumor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Feasibility The feasibility will be investigated by comparison of completion rates of the&#xD;
      different perfusion assessment methods; traditional, FA, Q-ICG.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Usability The usability of the quantitative perfusion assessment tool will be investigated&#xD;
      with a validated questionnaire, the System Usability Scale, answered by the surgeon&#xD;
      immediately after the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistics Comparison of data will be performed using Mann Whitney U test or a paired sample&#xD;
      t-test depending on distribution normality. P-values &lt; 0.05 is considered significant. No&#xD;
      formal sample size calculation has been made, as the study is considered a feasibility trial.&#xD;
      20 patients will be recruited. Statistic evaluation was performed using IBM SPSS Statistics ©&#xD;
      (v 22.0 SPSS Inc. Chicago, IL, USA).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adverse events, risks, and disadvantages Adverse events associated with the use of ICG are&#xD;
      extremely rare and severe anaphylactic reactions are almost never occurring. However, safety&#xD;
      precautions have been made by excluding patients with allergy to iodine, ICG or shellfish. In&#xD;
      addition, no patients with liver insufficiency, thyrotoxicosis, ongoing pregnancy, or&#xD;
      lactating women will be included.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 8, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 11, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 11, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Device Feasibility</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Completion rates</measure>
    <time_frame>during surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Feasibility of perfusion assessment with traditional visual, visual FA, and Q-ICG</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences in resection points</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Differences in the distance from the determined resection points using traditional assessment, LSCI, FA, and quantitative FA.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>System Usability Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>up to one week</time_frame>
    <description>The feasibility and usability of the tool, the surgeons' experiences with the Q-ICG tablet interface - rated on a validated questionnaire, the System Usability Scale - https://www.usability.gov/how-to-and-tools/methods/system-usability-scale.html.&#xD;
Scores ranges from 0-100, where a score of 68 is considered average.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Esophageal Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Perfusion assessment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Q-ICG: quantitative perfusion assessment with FA White light perfusion assessment FA: fluorescence angiography without quantification</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Q-ICG</intervention_name>
    <description>Quantitative perfusion assessment with indocyanine green on a touch screen tablet</description>
    <arm_group_label>Perfusion assessment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>White light perfusion assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>Traditional visual perfusion assessment in white light</description>
    <arm_group_label>Perfusion assessment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fluorescence angiography</intervention_name>
    <description>Perfusion assessment with fluorescence angiography - without quantification</description>
    <arm_group_label>Perfusion assessment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients (above 18 years) scheduled for planned open or robot-assisted resection of&#xD;
             the gastroesophageal junction (GI junction) for GI junctional cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy towards; iodine, indocyanine green or shellfish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Liver insufficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thyrotoxicosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Legally incompetent for any reason&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Withdrawal of inclusion consent at any time&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael P Achiam, MD,PhD,DMSci</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Surgical Gastroenterology, Rigshospitalet</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Surgical Gastroenterology - Rigshospitalet</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen Ø</city>
        <zip>2100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nerup N, Andersen HS, Ambrus R, Strandby RB, Svendsen MBS, Madsen MH, Svendsen LB, Achiam MP. Quantification of fluorescence angiography in a porcine model. Langenbecks Arch Surg. 2017 Jun;402(4):655-662. doi: 10.1007/s00423-016-1531-z. Epub 2016 Nov 15.</citation>
    <PMID>27848028</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 8, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 13, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 14, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 11, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 11, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 12, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nikolaj Albeck Nerup</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PhD-fellow, senior resident</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>perfusion</keyword>
  <keyword>indocyanine green angiography</keyword>
  <keyword>feasibility study</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

