<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01225536</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ARQ 736-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01225536</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dose Escalation Study of ARQ 736 in Adult Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors Harboring BRAF and/or NRAS Mutations</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1 Dose Escalation Study of ARQ 736 in Adult Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors Harboring BRAF and/or NRAS Mutations</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>ArQule, Inc. (a wholly owned subsidiary of Merck Sharp and Dohme, a subsidiary of Merck &amp; Co., Inc.)</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>ArQule, Inc. (a wholly owned subsidiary of Merck Sharp and Dohme, a subsidiary of Merck &amp; Co., Inc.)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label, Phase 1, dose escalation study of oral ARQ 736 administered to&#xD;
      subjects with advanced solid tumors harboring the mutation. The study is designed to explore&#xD;
      the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of ARQ 736 and to define a&#xD;
      recommended Phase 2 dose of ARQ 736.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Treatment will be initiated at a dose level of 450 mg twice daily (900 mg/daily). All&#xD;
      cycles/cohorts of therapy will consist of the oral administration of ARQ 736 twice or four&#xD;
      times a day, one hour prior to or two hours after the meal for 28 days continuously. Tumor&#xD;
      assessments (CT scan or MRI) will be performed at Baseline, and every two cycles (every eight&#xD;
      weeks) thereafter or as otherwise clinically indicated. For early assessment of evidence of&#xD;
      biological activity of the tumor PET scan may be performed at Baseline and four weeks from&#xD;
      the administration of the first dose of ARQ 736 (approximately Cycle 2 Day1).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess safety and tolerability of study drug in subjects with advanced solid tumors who have BRAF and/or NRAS mutations</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to treatment discontinuation + 30 days with an estimated treatment duration of 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess pharmacokinetic profile</measure>
    <time_frame>During first cycle of treatment (28 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess pharmacodynamic activity</measure>
    <time_frame>During first cycle of treatment (28 days) plus Day 1 of each consecutive cycle with an estimated treatment duration of 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine preliminary evidence of activity</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to treatment discontinuation with an estimated treatment duration of 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine recommended Phase 2 dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to treatment discontinuation with an estimated treatment duration of 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Solid Tumor</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ARQ 736</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ARQ 736</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects in this study will receive ARQ 736 orally at dose levels specified for their respective dose cohorts. Dosing will begin at 900 mg/day (first cohort) and escalate until the recommended Phase 2 dose or maximum tolerated dose is determined. Cycles will be repeated in four-week (28-day) intervals until progression of disease, unacceptable toxicity, or another discontinuation criterion is met. In the case of toxicity, dose adjustment will be permitted.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ARQ 736</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed written informed consent granted prior to initiation of any study-specific&#xD;
             procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female subjects of ≥ 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All subjects must be positive for a BRAF and/or NRAS mutation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically or cytologically confirmed locally advanced, inoperable or metastatic&#xD;
             solid tumors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure to respond to at least one prior systemic therapy (including previous&#xD;
             treatment with BRAF inhibitors) or to whom standard or curative therapy does not exist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of greater than three months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) ≤2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease as defined by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin (Hgb) ≥10 g/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1.5 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count ≥100 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin ≤1.5 × upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate transaminase (AST) and alanine transaminase (ALT) ≤2.5 × ULN (≤5 x ULN for&#xD;
             subjects with liver metastases)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine ≤1.5 × ULN or creatinine clearance &gt;60 mL/min/1.73 m^2 for subjects&#xD;
             with creatinine levels above institutional normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left Ventricular Ejection Fraction (LVEF) ≥ the institutional lower limit normal&#xD;
             (ILLN)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female subjects of child-producing potential must agree to use double-barrier&#xD;
             contraceptive measures, oral contraception or avoidance of intercourse during the&#xD;
             study and for 30 days after the last dose of ARQ 736&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test within&#xD;
             seven days prior to the first dose of ARQ 736&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must agree to have tumor and/or skin (nevi) biopsy at baseline and on Day 15 or Day 22&#xD;
             of Cycle 1. Tumor biopsy will be done if the subject has a lesion for which in the&#xD;
             Investigator's opinion a non- or minimally invasive tumor biopsy may be performed. If&#xD;
             tumor biopsy is not available, skin (nevi) biopsy should be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anti-cancer chemotherapy, immunotherapy, or investigational agents within four weeks&#xD;
             of the first dose of ARQ 736&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery or radiotherapy within two weeks of the first dose of ARQ 736&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Brain metastases that are progressing or have been documented to be stable for less&#xD;
             than six weeks, or for which systemic corticosteroids are required&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition as ARQ 736&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable or unwilling to swallow the complete daily dose of ARQ 736&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant gastrointestinal disorder(s), in the opinion of the Investigator, (e.g.,&#xD;
             Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis, extensive gastric resection)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of myocardial infarction (MI) within 6 months of the administration of the&#xD;
             first dose of ARQ 736 (MI occurring &gt; 6 months of the first dose of ARQ 736 will be&#xD;
             permitted)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of congestive heart failure defined as Class II to IV per New York Heart&#xD;
             Association (NYHA) classification within 6 months of the administration of the first&#xD;
             dose of ARQ 736&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous malignancy within 2 years of the first dose of ARQ 736, except carcinoma&#xD;
             in-situ of the cervix&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent uncontrolled illness, including but not limited to:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing or active infection, including human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection or&#xD;
             bleeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric illness/substance abuse/social situation that would limit compliance with&#xD;
             study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood transfusion within five days prior to blood draw being used to confirm&#xD;
             eligibility&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90025</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06520</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>New Brunswick</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>08903</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Rozzano</city>
        <zip>20089</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 20, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 20, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 21, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 2, 2013</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 2, 2013</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 3, 2013</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>BRAF mutations</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

