<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01661010</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>120181</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>12-HG-0181</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01661010</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Clinical Study of Sex Chromosome Variants</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Clinical Study of Patients With Sex Chromosome Variants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Purpose/Lay Summary: Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Chromosomes are the structures inside of each cell that carry our genetic material (genes).&#xD;
      Certain differences in the sex chromosomes are known to cause various diseases, such as&#xD;
      infertility, Turner syndrome, or Klinefelter syndrome. However, it is not fully understood&#xD;
      why these differences are seen and what clinical findings may be caused with different sex&#xD;
      chromosome variants. This study is seeking to learn more about the genetic and clinical&#xD;
      characteristics of disorders related to the X and Y chromosomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To study related medical conditions in people with sex chromosome variants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with known sex chromosome differences may be eligible to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Healthy volunteers age 18 - 55&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be screened with a physical exam and medical history. Blood and urine&#xD;
           samples will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This study will last about 5 days. Participants will have a variety of endocrine and&#xD;
           other tests. They will provide blood, urine, and semen samples for these tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Imaging studies of the heart and abdomen will be performed. These tests may include&#xD;
           ultrasounds and magnetic resonance imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will also have their vision and hearing checked.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Healthy volunteers with have a single day visit for a medical history, physical exam,&#xD;
           and blood and skin samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Treatment will not be provided as part of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Compensation is offered.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Infertility is a disease that affects approximately 10% of couples world-wide. Causes of&#xD;
      infertility are varied and include age-related decline in fecundity, other causes of&#xD;
      ovulatory dysfunction, tubal and pelvic pathology, male causes, idiopathic, and&#xD;
      multifactorial. The underlying genetic causes of infertility are incompletely understood. The&#xD;
      purpose of this study is to increase our understanding of the genetic and clinical&#xD;
      manifestations of infertility related to sex-chromosome variants through detailed physical,&#xD;
      radiologic, and laboratory studies. We will concentrate on a group of patients (both male and&#xD;
      female) with known sex-chromosome variationsfully characterized through genetic sequencing&#xD;
      and karyotyping. Other patients with&#xD;
&#xD;
      sex chromosome variants will be invited depending on the variant described. Patients&#xD;
      recruited and consenting to this study will be evaluated at the NIH Clinical Center&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 30, 2012</start_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phenotype</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>To characterize the physical, reproductive, endocrinologic and radiologic phenotype of a group of patients who have known sex-chromosome structural and copy-number variants.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Spectrum</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>To examine the spectrum of clinical characteristics of infertility and other conditions related to sex-chromosome variants and facilitate early clinical recognition, diagnostic confirmation, anticipatory management, prognostication, and proper genetic counseling.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">112</enrollment>
  <condition>Male Factor Infertility</condition>
  <condition>Female Factor Infertility</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <description>Family members can serve as control group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sex-linked genes</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients previously identified through outside research or diagnostic labs as having sex- chromosome variants causing deletion/duplication of sex-linked genes or entire sex chromosomes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients previously identified through outside research or diagnostic labs as having&#xD;
        sex-chromosome variants causing deletion/duplication of sex-linked genes or entire sex&#xD;
        chromosomes.@@@&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients previously identified through outside research or diagnostic labs as&#xD;
                  having sex-chromosome variants causing deletion/duplication of sex-linked genes&#xD;
                  or entire sex chromosomes, male and female.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. In the event that a patient with a sex-chromosome variant self-refers to the&#xD;
                  protocol, medical records will be reviewed by a committee to include Dr. David&#xD;
                  Page, Dr. Maximilian Muenke, and others to decide whether the patient is&#xD;
                  appropriate for enrollment in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Willing family members of subjects enrolled may be enrolled as control subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Anyone unwilling to provide informed consent or assent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. We reserve the right to exclude patients with medical conditions that would place a&#xD;
             potential participant at high risk of complications if managed at the NIH clinical&#xD;
             center (ex. dialysis dependency, unstable cardiac conditions, unstable severe&#xD;
             depression/suicidality).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. We reserve the right to exclude cases that are clearly not related to Ychromosome&#xD;
             variants, infertility or our direct research interests (e.g. infertility with clearly&#xD;
             non-genetic etiology). This almost never happens, and we would attempt to make&#xD;
             referrals to a more appropriate investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        It is our intention to try to remove as many economic, cultural, geographic, racial, and&#xD;
        gender barriers as we reasonably can to promote a diverse participation of infertility&#xD;
        cases for research purposes.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ashley J Buscetta, C.R.N.P.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?B_2012-HG-0181.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brandell RA, Mielnik A, Liotta D, Ye Z, Veeck LL, Palermo GD, Schlegel PN. AZFb deletions predict the absence of spermatozoa with testicular sperm extraction: preliminary report of a prognostic genetic test. Hum Reprod. 1998 Oct;13(1O):2812-5.</citation>
    <PMID>9804236</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bondy CA; Turner Syndrome Study Group. Care of girls and women with Turner syndrome: a guideline of the Turner Syndrome Study Group. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2007 Jan;92(1):10-25. Epub 2006 Oct 17.</citation>
    <PMID>17047017</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Berta P, Hawkins JR, Sinclair AH, Taylor A, Griffiths BL, Goodfellow PN, Fellous M. Genetic evidence equating SRY and the testis-determining factor. Nature. 1990 Nov 29;348(6300):448-50.</citation>
    <PMID>2247149</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 23, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 7, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 7, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 9, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Infertility</keyword>
  <keyword>Turner's Syndrome</keyword>
  <keyword>X-Chromosome</keyword>
  <keyword>Y-Chromosome</keyword>
  <keyword>Aneuploidy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

