<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01661543</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>QFH-11-044</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01661543</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>U of A/ U of M Beans and Peas Health Claim Project</brief_title>
  <official_title>Substantiating a Health Claim for Pulses (Beans and Peas) and Cholesterol Lowering Abilities</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alberta</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Alberta Innovates Health Solutions</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Pulse Canada</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Manitoba</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alberta</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to compare how regularly eating (dried) beans or peas or rice&#xD;
      (control) lowers blood lipids, particularly Low Density Lipoprotein cholesterol and total&#xD;
      cholesterol, in mildly hypercholesterolemic men and women. The investigators hypothesize that&#xD;
      regularly eating beans or peas will significantly improve blood lipid profiles in these&#xD;
      people.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in this study will consume 1 study food item 5 out of 7 days a week containing&#xD;
      beans or peas or rice for a total of 6 weeks. This study will benefit Canadian pulse growers&#xD;
      by enhancing development of food products for human consumption and supporting marketing&#xD;
      strategies to increase awareness that a diet rich in pulses can improve human health.&#xD;
      Measuring changes in blood and urinary polyphenol levels will help to verify whether these&#xD;
      compounds play a role in the beneficial actions of beans and peas and subsequently assist&#xD;
      with the identification of the beneficial bean/pea components. This in turn, will enable crop&#xD;
      breeders to select for plants that are rich in these compounds.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      OBJECTIVES: The aim of this study is to conduct a multi-centre randomized, controlled trial&#xD;
      to specifically compare the biological effectiveness of bean versus peas vs rice (control) on&#xD;
      LDL-cholesterol in mildly hypercholesterolemic men and women. In addition, the effects of&#xD;
      beans and peas on other key factors associated with cardiovascular disease, including&#xD;
      triglycerides, High Density Lipoprotein-cholesterol, body weight/fatness, glucose, insulin,&#xD;
      glycated hemoglobin and biomarkers of vascular function. Inflammation and metabolism will be&#xD;
      investigated, as well as the participants' assessment of study food acceptability, satiety&#xD;
      and gastrointestinal responses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      BACKGROUND: Pulses (beans, peas, lentils and chickpeas) are healthy foods that contain twice&#xD;
      the amount of protein as cereals, are very high in fibre, key vitamins and minerals like&#xD;
      folate and iron and are low in fat. Canada is the world's largest producer and exporter of&#xD;
      lentils and peas, and Alberta produced 34% of the pea crop and 12% of beans in 2010. Current&#xD;
      consumption of pulses in Canada is low, due to a lack of pulse-based convenient food&#xD;
      products. An approved health claim can drive interest in development of food products with&#xD;
      particular ingredients as seen with oat beta-glucan. Experts agree that existing evidence for&#xD;
      the cholesterol-lowering effects of pulses is particularly strong for beans, but more studies&#xD;
      are needed to show the effects of peas, lentils and chickpeas are comparable to beans.&#xD;
      Results from this study will be used to substantiate a health claim for beans and other pulse&#xD;
      crops in the future, similar to the health claims that exist for beta-glucan and plant&#xD;
      sterols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS AND PROCEDURES: This multi-center study will compare the effects of beans (pinto,&#xD;
      black, Great Northern, small red) versus peas (yellow, green) to control (rice-based) foods&#xD;
      on total and Low Density Lipoprotein-Cholesterol in mildly hypercholesterolemic (&gt;3 mmol/L&#xD;
      and &lt; 5mmol/L; not on medications) adults. There will be 3 study arms: i) beans, ii) peas,&#xD;
      and iii) rice (control). The study groups will be asked to consume food items containing 120&#xD;
      grams of cooked beans or cooked peas daily for 6 weeks. The control group will be asked to&#xD;
      consume one 1/2 cup serving per day of rice-based foods in matrices similar to those&#xD;
      containing beans or peas for 6 weeks. The study or control foods will be incorporated into&#xD;
      the participants normal dietary pattern. All food items will be provided to participants free&#xD;
      of charge. Food items, generally in the form of soups or stews, will be developed by a&#xD;
      collaborator in Food Science at the University of Manitoba in the initial phase of this&#xD;
      project .&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators plan to recruit approximately 180 participants (n= 75 participants at the&#xD;
      University of Manitoba and n= 105 at University of Alberta). Interested individuals&#xD;
      (potential participants) will be first asked to attend a screening visit. The screening visit&#xD;
      procedures will be discussed prior to the screening visit, including the need to fast (i.e.,&#xD;
      no food or beverage intake except water for 12 hours) for blood sampling to determine if&#xD;
      Low-density-lipoprotein-cholesterol and triglyceride levels are within acceptable range. Once&#xD;
      at this visit, individuals will be provided with a description of the study by the&#xD;
      investigating team's study coordinator. The eligibility criteria will be reviewed with&#xD;
      candidates by the investigating team's study coordinator to assess their suitability for the&#xD;
      study. Individuals meeting all inclusion/exclusion criteria will be contacted by the study&#xD;
      coordinator with this information. All individuals who are screened will be contacted by the&#xD;
      study coordinator once eligibility has been confirmed. An appointment for a baseline&#xD;
      assessment meeting will be scheduled for those who are eligible and who confirm interest in&#xD;
      the study; those who are not eligible or who are eligible and no longer wish to participate&#xD;
      will be thanked for their time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the baseline assessment visit individuals will be reminded of the study description and&#xD;
      will be asked to provide written informed consent at this time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once enrolled, participants will undergo a complete medical history including age, sex,&#xD;
      alcohol use, exercise habits, current medical problems, medication and family history of&#xD;
      previous events such as stroke and diabetes. A fasting blood sample will be obtained to&#xD;
      assess plasma lipid profile.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked to attend 4 in-person clinic visits over the duration of the study&#xD;
      for screening, baseline assessment, and at 3 and 6 weeks (at the end of the study).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once identified and after giving informed consent, participants will be randomized to one of&#xD;
      the 3 study arms. The randomization will be either computer generated, or done manually by a&#xD;
      study coordinator for both sites. Each participant will be given a randomized number, and&#xD;
      will be used for all study documentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will fill out questionnaire relating to demographics, lifestyle, food intake,&#xD;
      gastrointestinal responses etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The baseline visit will include a height and weight measurement, waist circumference and body&#xD;
      composition using the Bod Pod machine (air displacement) Blood pressure will be recorded.&#xD;
      Participants will be assessed for changes in their medication profile and discuss current&#xD;
      medical conditions. The three day food record (completed at home) will be collected. Urine&#xD;
      sample and fasting blood sample will be drawn for lipid assessment profile, insulin, glucose,&#xD;
      glycated hemoglobin, polyphenols and biomarkers of vascular function, inflammation and&#xD;
      metabolism. Blood required will not exceed 60mL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization will be done at the baseline visit. Prior to leaving, participants will be&#xD;
      provided with the first 3-week supply of assigned foods and instruction about how to prepare&#xD;
      and consume them, and will be reminded to fast before their next visit. This visit will take&#xD;
      approximately 2.5 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Week 3 visit will include height and weight measurements, waist circumference and body&#xD;
      composition using Bod Pod (via air displacement). Blood pressure will be recorded.&#xD;
      Participants will be assessed for changes in their medication profile and current medical&#xD;
      conditions. The 3 day food record (completed at home) will be collected. Urine sample will be&#xD;
      collected. Fasting blood sample will be drawn for assessment of lipid profile, insulin,&#xD;
      glucose, glycated hemoglobin, polyphenols and biomarkers of vascular function, inflammation&#xD;
      and metabolism. The total blood required will not exceed 60mL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will complete a questionnaire to assess compliance, acceptability of the study&#xD;
      foods, satiety, GI responses and any adverse events. Questions will be addressed. Before&#xD;
      leaving, participants will be provided with the second 3-week supply of assigned foods, and&#xD;
      instructions about how to prepare and consume them. Participants will be reminded to fast&#xD;
      prior to next visit. Visit will take approximately 2 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Week 6 visit: Measurements taken for height and weight, waist circumference, body composition&#xD;
      using Bod Pod (air displacement) and blood pressure will be repeated. Participants will be&#xD;
      assessed for changes in their medication profile and current medical conditions. Urine sample&#xD;
      will be collected for polyphenols. A fasting blood sample will be drawn for assessment of&#xD;
      lipid profile, insulin, glucose, glycated hemoglobin, polyphenols, and biomarkers of vascular&#xD;
      function (University of Manitoba only), inflammation and metabolism. Total blood will not&#xD;
      exceed 60 mL. Participants will complete a questionnaire to assess compliance, acceptability&#xD;
      of the foods, satiety, Gastrointestinal responses and any adverse events. Total time&#xD;
      required, approximately 2.5 hours. Completion of this visit marks the end of the study.&#xD;
      Participants will be paid, and thanked for their time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Lowering of Cholesterol</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Cholesterol will be tested at Baseline, 3 and 6 week interval</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">180</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypercholesterolemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Bean consumption to lower cholesterol</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will consume 90 grams of beans per day for 5 out of 7 days for 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control (rice) consumed to show results</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group will consume 90 grams of rice per day for 5 out of 7 days for 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Peas consumed to lower cholesterol</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will consume 90g of peas per day for 5 days out of each week for 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Beans</intervention_name>
    <description>90g of beans per day for 5 out of 7 days per week will be given to participants for 6 weeks to determine the cholesterol lowering effects of various pulses.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Bean consumption to lower cholesterol</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control (rice)</intervention_name>
    <description>90g of rice per day will be given to the control group to demonstrate the cholesterol lowering effects of the experimental group.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control (rice) consumed to show results</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Peas</intervention_name>
    <description>90 grams of peas will be consumed 5 out of 7 days per week</description>
    <arm_group_label>Peas consumed to lower cholesterol</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male, or non-pregnant, non-lactating females, aged 20 to 75 years; This age range&#xD;
             allows for a large variety of participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  LDL-cholesterol &gt;3.00 mmol/L and &lt;5.00 mmol/L; Cholesterol is high enough that a&#xD;
             lowering can be seen, but low enough that the participant is not taking medications or&#xD;
             alternative measures to lower cholesterol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting triglycerides &lt;4.00 mmol/L; Low enough that it is not dangerous to&#xD;
             participant, but high enough to see a lowering effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stable body weight (±5%) for the past 3 months and BMI of 20-40; Participants with&#xD;
             high BMI are more likely to have high lipid levels, it is important to have a stable&#xD;
             body weight so energy requirements are not drastically changing during the study&#xD;
             period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be on a stable regime for the past 3 months if taking medications or if taking&#xD;
             vitamin and mineral/dietary/herbal supplements; Stable regime reduces risk of any&#xD;
             changes during study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to read, write and communicate orally in English; All questionnaires and&#xD;
             communication will be completed in English.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Willing to comply with the protocol requirements, including a stable level of physical&#xD;
        activity during the study and no other pulse-containing foods consumed during the study;&#xD;
        this will ensure the most valid results.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Willing to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Regular high pulse consumption (&gt;2 servings per week); Any additional pulse&#xD;
             consumption will affect the outcome of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of medications to lower blood lipids or to lower blood glucose; the aim of the&#xD;
             study is to prove the cholesterol lowering capabilities of beans and peas, any other&#xD;
             methods of blood lipid lowering will skew data.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of non-prescription products designed to lower blood lipids (e.g. margarine or&#xD;
             yogurt with added plant sterols) within the past 3 months; see above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical history of liver disease, renal insufficiency, inflammatory bowel disease or&#xD;
             other gastrointestinal disorders influencing gastrointestinal motility or nutrient&#xD;
             absorption; this will decrease effectiveness of bean/ consumption.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any active medical or surgical condition(s) within the past 3 months precluding study&#xD;
             participation; participants must be in a stable condition with no recovery or pending&#xD;
             surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Conditions or medications which are likely to increase the risk to the participants or&#xD;
             study personnel, or to reduce the ability of the participant to comply with the&#xD;
             protocol, or affect the results;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of gastrointestinal reactions or allergies to beans, peas or rice-based foods,&#xD;
             or to one or more ingredients in the study foods which significantly limits the number&#xD;
             of study foods that can be consumed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently participating in or having participated in a food intervention study within&#xD;
             the last 3 months.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rhonda C Bell, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alberta</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Linda McCargar, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alberta</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Cathy Chan, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>university</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Spencer Proctor, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alberta</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jocelyn Ozga, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alberta</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David Wishart, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alberta</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carla Taylor, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Manitoba</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Peter Zahradka, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Manitoba</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michel Aliani, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Manitoba</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alberta</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edmonton</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T6G 2E1</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Manitoba</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winnipeg</city>
        <state>Manitoba</state>
        <zip>R2H 2A6</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 7, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 7, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 9, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 22, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 22, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 24, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypercholesterolemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

