<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00388921</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2005033</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00388921</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>High/Low Dose Vit A in Diarrhea/ALRI in Severe PEM</brief_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangladesh</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangladesh</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Vitamin A deficiency is an important health problem globally including Bangladesh. The&#xD;
      problem is greater among under-five children, particularly in malnourished. Vitamin A&#xD;
      supplementation reduces morbidity from diarrhoeal diseases and also prevents future diarrhoea&#xD;
      episodes. However, there are conflicting reports on the role of vitamin A supplementation on&#xD;
      morbidity from acute lower respiratory infections (ALRI) including pneumonia. In&#xD;
      non-malnourished children supplementation has been reported to be associated with increased&#xD;
      incidence and morbidity of ALRI. The WHO committee[1] has reviewed both the risk and benefit&#xD;
      of mega dose (200,000 IU) vitamin A supplementation during acute illness particularly&#xD;
      diarrhoea, irrespective of the nutritional status of under-5 children and recommended vitamin&#xD;
      A supplementation in areas where vitamin A status is low. In Bangladesh mega dose (200,000&#xD;
      IU) of vitamin A is routinely supplemented to under-5 children every 6 months. Absorption of&#xD;
      vitamin A precursors from the GI tract is reduced in severely malnourished children, who are&#xD;
      also lacking in retinol binding protein (RBP), required for transportation of retinol to&#xD;
      target tissues. Thus it is established that a significant portion of the supplemented vitamin&#xD;
      A is excreted in feces and urine of malnourished children. The excretion of vitamin A&#xD;
      increases substantially during acute infections including diarrhoeal diseases. On the other&#xD;
      hand, due to reduced RBP, concentration of free vitamin A increases in the body resulting in&#xD;
      the possibility of adverse events including &quot;pseudotumor cerebri&quot;. It has recently been&#xD;
      observed that low-dose daily supplementation of vitamin A to malnourished children produces a&#xD;
      better effect on recovery from acute illness and also in preventing infectious diseases among&#xD;
      under-five children. However, the limitations of those studies included a small sample size,&#xD;
      delayed assessment of retinol after supplementation among the others. Thus WHO felt that the&#xD;
      issue needs to be addressed in a well-designed clinical trial. We hope that our proposed&#xD;
      study will enable us to compare the efficacy of low-dose daily administration of vitamin A&#xD;
      with that of initial mega dose followed by daily low dose of vitamin A in malnourished&#xD;
      children presenting with acute diarrhoeal diseases with or without ALRI. If the results of&#xD;
      this study indicate that the daily low-dose has similar efficacy to that of the currently&#xD;
      recommended mega dose followed by daily low-dose of vitamin A, would have important&#xD;
      programmatic implications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Globally An estimated 140-250 million under-five children are deficient in vitamin A, which&#xD;
      is associated with increased mortality and morbidity among this population. A relationship&#xD;
      between the severity of vitamin A deficiency and childhood mortality has also been reported.&#xD;
      In 2002, the United Nations held a special session to examine ways to eliminate this problem&#xD;
      through various approaches including breast-feeding, food fortification, improved diet and&#xD;
      supplementation. Periodic supplementation of a mega dose of vitamin A has been recommended to&#xD;
      be a suitable intervention at the community level which is likely to improve the over all&#xD;
      vitamin A status. This is also cost effective and patient compliant. This approach has&#xD;
      resulted in reduction in all-causes of deaths among under-five children by 23% in areas where&#xD;
      vitamin A deficiency is a major public health problem [3]&#xD;
      (http://www.who.int/vaccines/en/vitamina.shtml accessed on 26 May, 2005 at 1300 hrs). In view&#xD;
      of the public health importance of vitamin A nutriture, the Government of Bangladesh&#xD;
      recommends the administration of 200,000 IU of vitamin A every six months to all children&#xD;
      aged 12-59 months irrespective of their nutritional and vitamin A status (Institute of Public&#xD;
      Health Nutrition. Field guide for National Vitamin A Plus Campaign, 2005).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vitamin A is required for maintenance of integrity of epithelial cells and its growth and&#xD;
      differentiation, visual function, and the immune system [4]. Vitamin A deficiency leads to&#xD;
      patchy keratinization of epithelial lining of the respiratory, genitourinary and&#xD;
      gastrointestinal tracts [5], which acts as protective barriers against infections. The loss&#xD;
      of intestinal epithelial integrity increases the likelihood of bacterial colonization and&#xD;
      incidence of infections and septicemia, and it has also been shown that vitamin A&#xD;
      supplementation in smaller or higher doses help repair the damaged mucosa during the&#xD;
      convalescence stage [6-10]. Vitamin A deficiency state is worsened during acute infections&#xD;
      that reduces the dietary intake and absorption, and increases excretion of vitamin A in urine&#xD;
      [11]. The mortality in vitamin A deficiency is also related to reduced immune function [12],&#xD;
      [13]. Vitamin A improves wound healing by mediating early inflammatory responses associated&#xD;
      with influx of macrophages, enhanced fibroblast differentiation, and collagen accumulation&#xD;
      [14].&#xD;
&#xD;
      About half of the absorbed vitamin A ingested is oxidized and excreted in the feces and&#xD;
      urine, and the remainder is stored in the liver as retinol ester. It is released into the&#xD;
      plasma for transportation to peripheral tissues after binding with specific protein known as&#xD;
      retinol binding protein (RBP). Protein deficiency in severe malnutrition reduces the hepatic&#xD;
      synthesis of RBP [15], [16] which is the likely to be the reason for low serum retinol level&#xD;
      observed in such children [17-19]. Infectious diseases such as diarrhoea and acute lower&#xD;
      respiratory infections including pneumonia are common in malnourished children, which worsen&#xD;
      the vitamin A level [20]. Acute infections are also associated with acute phase response and&#xD;
      a transient decrease in serum retinol level [21]. This is due to reduced transcription of&#xD;
      messenger RNA for RBP, resulting in decreased release of RBP from the liver into the blood&#xD;
      [22], [23]. It is likely that liver utilizes all of its available resources for rapid&#xD;
      synthesis of proteins that are required for the host defense in acute infection, thereby&#xD;
      limiting the synthesis of relatively lesser important ones such as RBP. In severe infection,&#xD;
      the increased urinary loss of retinol contributes to the lower serum retinol concentration&#xD;
      [24]. Thus the utilization of vitamin A in the peripheral tissue is adversely affected in&#xD;
      systemic infections and in protein- energy malnutrition leading to development of features of&#xD;
      vitamin A deficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Acute lower respiratory infections (ALRI) including pneumonia, and diarrhoeal diseases are&#xD;
      the two most common illnesses that affect the under-five children. Earlier studies have&#xD;
      observed beneficial role of high dose vitamin A as an adjunct therapy in the treatment of&#xD;
      both watery and invasive diarrhoeas [25, 26]. It was observed that an increase of 1&#xD;
      mmol/liter of retinol reduces proportion of patients with diarrhoea and respiratory disease&#xD;
      by 50% and 80% respectively [9]. A more recent study had observed supplementation of vitamin&#xD;
      A to under-five children to be associated with reduced frequency of diarrhoea and ALRI, and&#xD;
      subsequent malnutrition [27]. In another study 85% of the infants attending a diarrhoea&#xD;
      treatment centre in Bangladesh were found to have depleted vitamin A stores, as measured by&#xD;
      relative dose response test, and 61% of them remained deficient despite receiving high dose&#xD;
      of vitamin A [24, 28]. Healthy children receiving high dose of vitamin A may experience&#xD;
      higher incidences of adverse manifestations such as nausea, vomiting and higher incidence of&#xD;
      diarrhoeal episode [29], while low dose vitamin A is associated with reduced incidence of&#xD;
      severe diarrhoea in malnourished children [15]. In India studies examined the effect of an&#xD;
      intermediate dose (8.7 mmol; 2500 mgm), administered weekly, and did not observe any&#xD;
      difference in the incidence, severity and or duration of diarrhea in vitamin A deficient&#xD;
      children [30]. In another community based study, infants aged 2-15 months receiving 16700 IU&#xD;
      vitamin A or placebo weekly for 8 weeks experienced enhanced gut repair as indicated by&#xD;
      improved lactulose-mannitol (L:M) ratio, as compared to the hospitalized infants who received&#xD;
      high dose. The results suggest impaired gut permeability during convalescent period. There is&#xD;
      every possibility that the low vitamin A level during the infectious state and the low&#xD;
      retinol concentration in malnourished children aggravates the already existing compromised&#xD;
      gut mucosa thus necessitating the vitamin A supplementation among the hospitalized&#xD;
      malnourished children [10].&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are conflicting reports on the role of high dose of vitamin A supplementation in the&#xD;
      management of ALRI and pneumonia in malnourished children [31], [15]. Even sub-clinical&#xD;
      vitamin A deficiency in non-malnourished children is associated with increased risk of ARI&#xD;
      [32], [33]. Meta-analysis of community-based studies of high dose vitamin A supplementation&#xD;
      to children aged 6 months to 5 years did not observe any protective or detrimental effects of&#xD;
      vitamin A supplementation on pneumonia-specific mortality according to the vitamin A and&#xD;
      pneumonia working group [34]. In fact, some studies have reported an increase in the&#xD;
      incidence of ALRI in children with adequate nutritional status receiving vitamin A&#xD;
      supplementation [35]. In a placebo-controlled study, high dose vitamin A supplementation did&#xD;
      neither influence recovery nor the duration of hospitalization in Guatemalan children with&#xD;
      ALRI [31]. A higher dose of vitamin A was evaluated in studies in Brazil [36], Vietnam [37],&#xD;
      Chile [38] and Tanzania [39], and none of them had observed any beneficial effect, and in&#xD;
      fact had observed a negative effect in adequately nourished children [40]. Another clinical&#xD;
      trial conducted in Peru not only observed high dose vitamin A supplements to be ineffective&#xD;
      in improving recovery from pneumonia in hospitalized children, but actually observed&#xD;
      prolonged duration of the clinical signs, higher requirements of oxygen support, and higher&#xD;
      nursing time and patient care cost in high-dose supplemented group [41]. On the other hand,&#xD;
      in a population based, controlled clinical trial in Ecuadorian urban slum children, weekly&#xD;
      supplementation of low dose vitamin A (10,000 IU) for 40 weeks was associated with a strong&#xD;
      protective effect on ALRI in malnourished under-five children [42].&#xD;
&#xD;
      The reports on mortality and morbidity from diarrhoea and pneumonia in severely malnourished&#xD;
      children in association with vitamin A supplementation are conflicting. In the 21st IVACG&#xD;
      meeting three papers were reviewed. They observed no significant difference in mortality (8%&#xD;
      vs. 8.4% and 8.8%) in high and low dose of vitamin A and placebo group [15]. Yet another&#xD;
      study also failed to show any significant reduction (16.8 vs. 12.4%) in the mortality in&#xD;
      patients receiving high or low dose of vitamin A [43]. However, in sub-group analysis deaths&#xD;
      were significantly lower among oedematous children who received low dose vitamin A on&#xD;
      admission [44]. A meta-analysis observed substantial reduction in mortality in association&#xD;
      with vitamin A supplementation in population where at least low-level deficiency state was&#xD;
      prevalent, and the effect was independent of dose, sex and age, and the effect was more&#xD;
      pronounced for incidence of diarrhoea than for respiratory diseases [45]. However, no&#xD;
      difference in morbidity (frequency, duration, or prevalence) from diarrhoeal or respiratory&#xD;
      diseases was noted (Ghana VAST Study Team) [46] among stunted children in Ghana.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Malnourished children are deficient in RBP, facilitating excretion of the resultant free,&#xD;
      unbound form of vitamin A either through urine or faces, a situation that is aggravated&#xD;
      during acute infections. Vitamin A, when administered in a single high dose, presumably&#xD;
      circulates in free form in the extra cellular fluids before being taken up by the liver. This&#xD;
      free form of vitamin A perhaps affects sodium and water metabolism causing 'pseudotumor&#xD;
      cerebri', an adverse event of hypervitaminosis A [47]. Thus a mega dose supplementation may&#xD;
      not be yielding any better effect in the severely malnourished children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rationale&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vitamin A supplementation is beneficial in the management of clinical and sub-clinical&#xD;
      deficiencies of this important micronutrient, and has been observed to improve outcomes from&#xD;
      certain illnesses, particularly diarrhoeal diseases and in preventing infectious diseases.&#xD;
      The beneficial effect of vitamin A supplementation in ALRI including pneumonia is not that&#xD;
      clear. WHO currently recommends single high dose of vitamin A supplementation to malnourished&#xD;
      children with diarrhoea because of low cost with high participation rate for improving health&#xD;
      status of children. The WHO recommendation is based on studies in communities that showed&#xD;
      benefit of the cheapest intervention, which is quicker to implement into health programmes.&#xD;
      The programmes for vitamin A capsule distribution reduced risk of vitamin A deficiency among&#xD;
      participating children. Interpretation of the three studies done in the Democratic Republic&#xD;
      of Congo and Senegal, as mentioned earlier, in relation to the existing guidelines on vitamin&#xD;
      A supplementation was considered difficult and their validity was doubted in a meeting&#xD;
      convened by WHO in September 2004. It was, however, recognized that the question of vitamin A&#xD;
      dosage remains an important one and there is scope for further research. The meeting proposed&#xD;
      that the high dose only be given if the interval is at least 6 months from the last previous&#xD;
      high dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Bangladesh, high potency (200,000 IU) vitamin A is routinely supplemented to under-five&#xD;
      children every 6 months. There are at least three large studies that failed to observe any&#xD;
      effect of mega dose of vitamin A on the incidences and duration of diarrhoea and respiratory&#xD;
      tract infections. In recent studies it has been shown that daily low-dose supplementation of&#xD;
      vitamin A to malnourished under-five children produces similar or better effect, compared to&#xD;
      high dose, during acute illness and also in preventing infectious diseases. Studies have&#xD;
      observed higher mortality in high dose vitamin A supplemented group compared to the low dose&#xD;
      group. However, they were done in smaller number of children [15, 44]. In serum, vitamin A&#xD;
      remains saturated with RBP in a 1:1 ratio. Therefore, the amount of vitamin A in excess of&#xD;
      this ratio, as would be expected in mega-dose supplementation of vitamin A to severely&#xD;
      malnourished children with low serum RBP, would be non-functional at best, at least&#xD;
      theoretically [19]. Two trials in Asia that used high dose vitamin A observed conflicting&#xD;
      results. One study reported that, capsule distribution was not universal and probably vitamin&#xD;
      A deficient children would be missed, and the response of the high dose was unlikely to be&#xD;
      due to non-specific changes. In the other study, vitamin A supplementation alone failed to&#xD;
      show any expected improvement of child survival in demographic data but they did not deny the&#xD;
      importance of vitamin A supplementation in improving nutritional status [48, 49]. On the&#xD;
      other hand, weekly supplement of 8,333 IU of vitamin A was reported to reduce mortality by&#xD;
      54% [50]. There thus is a need for a carefully designed study with adequate sample size to&#xD;
      address the effect of low dose vitamin A on morbidity and mortality among severely&#xD;
      malnourished children with diarrhoea and pneumonia- the basis of our proposed study. We hope&#xD;
      that the results of this study will enable us to compare the cure rates of low-dose daily&#xD;
      administration of vitamin A with that of the initial mega dose followed by daily low dose of&#xD;
      vitamin A. Daily basal requirements (estimated amount which is needed to prevent signs of&#xD;
      deficiency) for 0-1 and 2-6 years old children are 600 and 650 IU respectively, and the&#xD;
      normal requirement (which is sufficient to maintain desirable levels of tissue store) for the&#xD;
      same age group are 1200 and 1300 IU respectively [51]. It is estimated that malnourished&#xD;
      children will lose 0.1µmol of retinol /day (97 IU) through urine during acute illness [24].&#xD;
&#xD;
      The national coverage rate (percentage of target age children who received vitamin A capsules&#xD;
      during the past six months, according to information provided by the mothers) of vitamin A in&#xD;
      rural areas was 45% in 1982-83[52]. The rate gradually decreased to 37% in 1987-88 and 35% in&#xD;
      1989 respectively [53], [54]. However, the Nutritional Surveillance Project reported in&#xD;
      December 1995, that the coverage of vitamin A capsule distribution increased substantially-&#xD;
      83.6% in rural and 73.7% in the urban areas [54]. It is noteworthy that night blindness is&#xD;
      considered as the marker of vitamin A deficiency, and when that exceeds 1%, is considered as&#xD;
      a significant public health problem [55]. In Bangladesh, the proportion of children aged&#xD;
      18-59 months having night blindness in rural areas and urban slums were 0.23% and 0.12%&#xD;
      respectively [52]. These figures are well below the cut-off for public health significance of&#xD;
      vitamin A deficiency. Anecdotal observations of doctors working at the ICDDR, B Hospital,&#xD;
      Dhaka, indicate a significant decrease in the number of children with clinical vitamin A&#xD;
      deficiency seeking treatment in the hospital. Further more, according to a report of the&#xD;
      surveillance system of Dhaka Hospital of ICDDR, B 84 children presented with conjunctival&#xD;
      xerosis and only three had keratomalacia/corneal ulcer out of the total of 11,605 under-5&#xD;
      children who attended the hospital during the period 1996-2004. Children to be enrolled in&#xD;
      our proposed study will receive 5000 IU of vitamin A. That amounts to be an additional 1000&#xD;
      IU during the acute phase and 800 IU during the nutritional rehabilitation phase of severe&#xD;
      malnutrition from various diets provided to them during their hospital stay. We thus estimate&#xD;
      that the total amount of vitamin A received from these sources, even after adjusting for&#xD;
      urinary excretion and the retinol level, will not fall below the basal and normal&#xD;
      requirements. We feel that once we are able to maintain the daily optimal level of vitamin A&#xD;
      stores in the body the sudden development of keratomalacia can be averted. However, we will&#xD;
      remain vigilant, through performing careful clinical examination (of eye and skin), to&#xD;
      exclude children with any form of clinical vitamin A deficiency from enrollment. Children&#xD;
      with clinical vitamin A deficiency disease (conjunctival xerosis, Bitot's spots,&#xD;
      keratomalacia, or dermatosis suggestive of vitamin A deficiency) will not be eligible for&#xD;
      enrollment and will be provided with the currently recommended treatment with vitamin A&#xD;
      supplementation as is routinely followed in this hospital. It may also be noted that a couple&#xD;
      of studies did not observe development of an overt sign of vitamin A deficiency in children&#xD;
      not receiving vitamin A (placebo group) [15, 41]. Additionally, serum retinol concentrations&#xD;
      were not significantly changed after 7 days of hospitalization both among children receiving&#xD;
      the high dose and children receiving the low dose or placebo [15].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical failure rates in the first 48 hours for the Dhaka hospital for shigellosis, cholera&#xD;
      and pneumonia were 31%, 35% and 40% respectively. Thus we postulate that the clinical failure&#xD;
      from diarrhoea and pneumonia will be reduced at least by 15% from the current rate, if&#xD;
      vitamin A can be supplemented at lower daily dose to malnourished children attending the&#xD;
      Dhaka Hospital of ICDDR, B&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2007</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2007</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Resolution of diarrhoea</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Resolution of ALRI</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of acute phase of illness</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to nutritional rehabilitation (achieving of 80% of W/H)</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rates of weight gain</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Morbidity developed during hospitalization such as nosocomial infections</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measurement of Serum retinol and RBP on admission, on day 3 and on day 15</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Case fatality rates</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment>260</enrollment>
  <condition>Respiratory Infections</condition>
  <condition>Diarrhea</condition>
  <condition>Malnutrition</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vitamin A</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 6-59 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Either sex&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Severe malnutrition as defined by the presence of any of the followings:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bipedal oedema&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Weight (measured after correction of dehydration) for height Z score &lt;-3 of the&#xD;
                  National Center for Health Statistics (NCHS) reference&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Written informed consent of respective parents/ guardians for participation of&#xD;
                  the children in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Children having diarrhoea (watery or invasive) or cough and cold or both for the last&#xD;
             48 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Failure to obtain consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Received a dose of vitamin A within the last three months&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of night blindness or eye signs of vitamin A deficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Measles or history of measles within last 8 weeks [56]&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Clinical suspicion of TB (evening rise of temperature, loss of appetite, gradual loss&#xD;
             of weight, cough, night sweating) after applying modified Kenneth Jones criteria [57],&#xD;
             shock other than due to hypovolaemia or hypoglycaemia, congestive cardiac failure,&#xD;
             severe sepsis (hypothermia, tachycardia, tachypnea, hypotension) [58], and seizure&#xD;
             disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Trisomy-21&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Cerebral palsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any other known chronic disease (e.g. hepatic, renal or congenital disorder) or&#xD;
             malignant condition.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>59 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Samima Sattart, MBBS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangladesh</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dhaka Hospital, ICDDR,B</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dhaka</city>
        <zip>1212</zip>
        <country>Bangladesh</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Bangladesh</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2005</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 15, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 16, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 17, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 25, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 25, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 28, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Vitamin A</keyword>
  <keyword>Children</keyword>
  <keyword>Severe malnutrition</keyword>
  <keyword>Retinol</keyword>
  <keyword>Retinol binding protein</keyword>
  <keyword>Diarrhoea</keyword>
  <keyword>ALRI</keyword>
  <keyword>Age 6-59 months</keyword>
  <keyword>Either sex</keyword>
  <keyword>Severe malnutrition as defined by the presence of any of the followings:</keyword>
  <keyword>Bipedal oedema</keyword>
  <keyword>Weight (measured after correction of dehydration) for height Z score &lt;-3 of the National Center for Health Statistics (NCHS) reference</keyword>
  <keyword>Written informed consent of respective parents/ guardians for participation of the children in the study.</keyword>
  <keyword>Children having diarrhoea (watery or invasive) or cough and cold or both for the last 48 hours.</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diarrhea</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vitamin A</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

