<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00129051</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NA-15-0005</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00129051</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Helical Tomotherapy as a Radiotherapy Technique for Treating Pelvic and Abdominal Metastases</brief_title>
  <official_title>Helical Tomotherapy as a Radiotherapy Technique for Treating Pelvic and Abdominal Metastases</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Alberta Health Services</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>AHS Cancer Control Alberta</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Radiation treatment is often used to treat cancer that has spread to the abdomen. It can be&#xD;
      very effective at relieving symptoms such as pain, but the radiotherapy itself can cause&#xD;
      side-effects such as cramping and diarrhea. This study will investigate whether it is&#xD;
      possible to reduce the unwanted side-effects of radiotherapy with a new technology called&#xD;
      &quot;helical tomotherapy&quot;. Tomotherapy is a new way to deliver radiation in a much more accurate&#xD;
      fashion than is currently done, and with less radiation being delivered to normal tissues&#xD;
      around the tumor. This study will involve the treatment of 20 patients, who have a spread of&#xD;
      their cancer within the abdomen and pelvis, using helical tomotherapy. The dose and energy of&#xD;
      radiation will be the same as is currently used - only the delivery system is different. The&#xD;
      purpose is to assure that tomotherapy is a safe way to deliver radiation treatment and to&#xD;
      investigate whether it will reduce the toxicity of radiation treatment in these patients.&#xD;
      Patients will be treated in groups of three until all 20 have been treated. The toxicity of&#xD;
      treatment will be measured with a questionnaire for each one. If any unexpected severe&#xD;
      treatment complications occur, further accrual will stop.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Radiotherapy is an effective treatment for treating metastatic disease. When used to treat&#xD;
      disease in the lower abdomen or pelvis, however, it is frequently associated with&#xD;
      gastrointestinal toxicity. The most common symptoms of radiation enteritis are diarrhea,&#xD;
      bloating, and abdominal cramping. They are caused by irritation and inflammation of the bowel&#xD;
      mucosa, and although the pathophysiology is poorly understood, it is thought to be due in&#xD;
      part to malabsorption of bile salts and lactose, imbalances in bacterial flora, disturbances&#xD;
      in motility. The true incidence of clinically significant enteritis is not well known and&#xD;
      probably underestimated, because the majority of patients with symptoms do not seek medical&#xD;
      advice, but is approximately 80% in patients receiving pelvic radiotherapy for gynecologic&#xD;
      and rectal tumors. Different approaches have been taken to try to minimize acute small and&#xD;
      large bowel toxicity from radiotherapy. Medical management with opioid derivatives, such as&#xD;
      loperamide, is often effective for mild cases. Other medications, which try to inhibit the&#xD;
      biochemical pathways leading to symptomatic gastroenteritis, have undergone clinical testing&#xD;
      with some success. The other approach to minimizing toxicity is to minimize the volume and/or&#xD;
      dose of radiation delivered to the small bowel. Simple mechanical devices, such as the &quot;belly&#xD;
      board&quot; or a mesh sling, have had some success. With new techniques in intensity-modulated&#xD;
      radiotherapy, it may be possible to avoid much of the bowel, or significantly reduce the dose&#xD;
      delivered to the bowel, without mechanical intervention or compromising tumour doses. The aim&#xD;
      of this trial is to test whether a new and highly sophisticated form of intensity modulated&#xD;
      radiotherapy called helical tomotherapy can safely be used to deliver radiotherapy to the&#xD;
      abdomen and pelvis. It will also establish whether this treatment modality will allow a&#xD;
      reduction in the radiation dose to normal structures and the incidence of radiation-induced&#xD;
      bowel injury. Helical tomotherapy is a new form of radiation treatment delivery which will be&#xD;
      introduced at the Cross Cancer Institute in late 2001 or early 2002. Unlike standard&#xD;
      radiotherapy, in which treatment is delivered through one or a few separate beams, helical&#xD;
      tomotherapy delivers treatment with a rotating, intensity-modulated fan beam. The patient is&#xD;
      translated through the ring of the gantry while the beam is rotated around, so that the&#xD;
      treatment beam forms a helical shape in a similar manner to that of computed tomography (CT)&#xD;
      scans. The ring gantry provides a stable platform to perform tomographic verification of both&#xD;
      setup and delivered dose. Helical tomotherapy is similar to the NOMOS PeacockTM system&#xD;
      currently in clinical use. The PeacockTM system also uses an intensity-modulated fan beam,&#xD;
      but because it is an attachment to a standard C-arm linear accelerator, it delivers treatment&#xD;
      by a &quot;translate then rotate&quot; method rather than a continuous spiral delivery. Because of the&#xD;
      complete freedom of helical tomotherapy to deliver treatment from all angles around the&#xD;
      patient and with intensity modulation and inverse treatment planning, it is possible to treat&#xD;
      highly complex and irregular target volumes while giving a low radiation dose to surrounding&#xD;
      normal structures. This study, along with a parallel study involving the treatment of bone&#xD;
      metastases, will involve the first patients to be treated with helical tomotherapy at the&#xD;
      Cross Cancer Institute. It will be an important first step in understanding the processes and&#xD;
      capabilities of helical tomotherapy in delivering accurate image-guided therapy. It is&#xD;
      designed to provide the framework for the next generation of clinical trials using helical&#xD;
      tomotherapy in the adjuvant and radical setting. The objectives of the study are as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess whether is is feasible to deliver daily fractionated radiotherapy with helical&#xD;
           tomotherapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the acute toxicity associated with the treatment of pelvic and abdominal&#xD;
           metastases with helical tomotherapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To test the accuracy of the daily setup verification process inherent in the helical&#xD;
           tomotherapy system;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To perform in vivo dosimetry, where possible;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To analyze the dose distributions possible with helical tomotherapy planning, and&#xD;
           compare to plans obtained using conventional linear accelerator systems.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To accomplish these objectives, the investigators will recruit 20 patients for treatment with&#xD;
      helical tomotherapy. Patients with solid malignancy of any primary site with proven or&#xD;
      suspected metastatic disease involving the abdomen, pelvis, or bones of the lumbar spine or&#xD;
      pelvis will be eligible, provided they are over 18 years of age; signed informed consent is&#xD;
      obtained; and there are no contraindications for radiotherapy. The investigators will select&#xD;
      patients for enrollment who have a high likelihood (&gt;50%) of suffering from grade 2 or higher&#xD;
      acute GI toxicity if standard radiotherapy techniques were used. Treatment will be delivered&#xD;
      with the helical tomotherapy system, with the dose plan designed to treat the target volume&#xD;
      to a homogeneous dose, while minimizing dose to normal structures including the small bowel.&#xD;
      The first 10 patients will be treated with a dose of 2500 cGy in 10 fractions, and the second&#xD;
      cohort of 10 patients to 3000 cGy in 10 fractions. The slightly lower than normal dose used&#xD;
      for the first cohort is designed to provide an extra margin of safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Considerations: With the doses of radiation used in the current study, the risk&#xD;
      of grade 4-5 toxicity using standard treatment techniques is very low. The investigators&#xD;
      will, therefore, use observed grade 4-5 acute toxicity as an early stopping rule to monitor&#xD;
      the safety of helical tomotherapy. Patients will be accrued onto treatment sequentially, with&#xD;
      no more than 3 patients on treatment or within 1 week of completing treatment at any time. If&#xD;
      a patient develops a grade 4 toxicity during or shortly after treatment, further accrual will&#xD;
      be suspended until such time as the cause of the severe treatment toxicity can be&#xD;
      established, and it is determined that treatment to subsequent patients can proceed safely.&#xD;
      If a second severe toxicity is observed the trial will close to accrual. For the purposes of&#xD;
      the study the risk of grade 4-5 radiation enteritis (using standard radiotherapy techniques)&#xD;
      is assumed to be 2% or less. Thus the probability of stopping accrual before trial completion&#xD;
      is 0.16 if there is no reduction in toxicity rate with helical tomotherapy (according to&#xD;
      binomial probabilities). If the true rate is 1% then the probability of rejecting treatment&#xD;
      is 0.01. The acute side effects of treatment will be monitored with the use of a patient&#xD;
      symptom questionnaire and physician assessment with history and physical examination. These&#xD;
      will be performed pre-treatment, weekly during treatment, and at 1 and 4 weeks post&#xD;
      treatment. A secondary endpoint of the study is to test the setup verification process of the&#xD;
      helical tomotherapy system. It is designed to automatically detect whether patients are set&#xD;
      up accurately for treatment, and to adjust the treatment for day-to-day changes in patient&#xD;
      position. For the first 10 patients, the investigators will compare the tomotherapy-derived&#xD;
      setup error to the error manually computed by studying the CT image sets. If the computer&#xD;
      derived setup error is accurate when compared to the manual evaluation (within 5 mm for at&#xD;
      least 80% of measurements), then the automated setup verification process will be utilized&#xD;
      for the second cohort of 10 patients. It is estimated that this study will take 3-6 months to&#xD;
      complete.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2001</start_date>
  <completion_date>November 2005</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>feasibility and tolerance</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>efficacy</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment>20</enrollment>
  <condition>Neoplasm Metastasis</condition>
  <condition>Carcinoma</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tomotherapy</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intra-abdominal metastatic cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior abdominal radiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient refusal&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Robert Pearcey, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>AHS Cancer Control Alberta</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cross Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edmonton</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T6G 1Z2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2005</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 9, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 9, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 11, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 8, 2010</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 8, 2010</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 9, 2010</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>tomotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>metastatic carcinoma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

