<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00273247</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>INT-98-016</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00273247</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment With IFN After Curative Resection of HCC in HCV-Related Cirrhosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Adjuvant α-Interferon Treatment After Resection of Hepatocellular Carcinoma in HCV-Related Cirrhosis: a Randomized Trial on Prevention of Cancer Recurrence</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute, Milan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Associazione Italiana per la Ricerca sul Cancro</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Institute, Milan</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      We conducted a randomized controlled trial of adjuvant interferon (IFN) therapy in patients&#xD;
      with hepatitis-C virus (HCV)-related cirrhosis who underwent curative resection of&#xD;
      hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) to investigate whether IFN could reduce or delay the incidence&#xD;
      of recurrent tumor (secondary/tertiary prevention of HCC). Patients were randomly assigned to&#xD;
      treatment with IFN (3MU thrice/wk /48 weeks) vs. no treatment after curative resection of&#xD;
      HCC(control group)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary liver cancer (hepatocellular carcinoma, HCC) remains a major cancer-related cause of&#xD;
      death with an estimated incidence of 1 million cases per year worldwide and particular&#xD;
      endemic distribution related to chronic hepatitis carriers. Post-necrotic cirrhosis due to&#xD;
      chronic infection by HBV and HCV is the leading background for HCC development with a yearly&#xD;
      rate of 3% and a 5-year probability of survival of 20%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Liver surgery, resection or transplantation, appears the only chance of curative treatment of&#xD;
      the tumor, but feasibility is still ranging from 15 to 30% in Western countries at time of&#xD;
      diagnosis. Several alternative treatments are available but their potential curative effects&#xD;
      are lacking, due to the absence of controlled trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Liver resection is claimed to be feasible in order 15-30% of patients with HCC with mortality&#xD;
      reported in major centers extremely low (5%). Technical and biological devices developed in&#xD;
      the setting of OLT can now support the limited reserve of cirrhotic livers after resection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Regulated segmentectomy is advisable with removal of the whole portal territory belonging to&#xD;
      the tumor. Single nodule tumors (&lt; 5 cm) and compensated cirrhosis (Child class A) are&#xD;
      accepted as the best candidates for liver resection that now can be performed with minimal&#xD;
      blood loss, and minimal ischemia damage. Intraoperative ultra sound examination is now&#xD;
      routinely used as the golden standard for staging and detection of previously undiscovered&#xD;
      neoplastic nodules. Hepatic decompensation with ascites development, cholestasis and variceal&#xD;
      bleeding within three months from surgery are the main negative prognostic factors for&#xD;
      patient survival. Five years survival exceed 50% but tumor recurrences due to cirrhosis&#xD;
      persistence could exceed 30% after three years of follow-up. Several attempts to reduce&#xD;
      recurrence through antiangiogenetic and antiproliferative agents have been proposed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the present project a prospective randomized trial of Interferon (as antiproliferative&#xD;
      drug) versus control in anti-HCV positive patients will investigate in homogeneous categories&#xD;
      of resected tumor possible variation in the natural history and namely a reduction of&#xD;
      recurrence rate after curative resection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Purpose and Study Design&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial was intentionally designed in 1997 as an unresticted collection of patients with&#xD;
      histologically proved HCC and a HCV-related cirrhosis selected for surgical resection of the&#xD;
      tumor in 4 experienced surgical Liver Units in Italy. Eligible patients were stratified on&#xD;
      the basis of concomitant anti-core antibodies against HBV (anti-HBc) into two populations:&#xD;
      &quot;pure HCV&quot; (HCV-RNA:positive, anti-HBc:negative) and &quot;mixed HCV+HBV&quot; (HCV-RNA:positive,&#xD;
      anti-HBc:positive). Within each strata patients were then randomized in a 1:1 ratio to&#xD;
      treatment with α-interferon (IFN) vs. no treatment (control). No restriction criteria were&#xD;
      applied to tumor stage, as far as the resection of HCC was judged as potentially curative at&#xD;
      pre-operative staging, intra-operative ultrasound and post-operative pathology (clearance of&#xD;
      surgical margins).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study was originally designed for lymphoblastoid α-interferon; then soon after trial&#xD;
      approval by the NCI-Milan Scientific and Ethic Committee (#98-016) the protocol was amended&#xD;
      for allowing also the use of recombinant α-2a (Roferon-A, Hoffmann-La Roche, Nutley NJ) or α&#xD;
      -2b interferon (Intron-A, Schering-Plough, Kenilworth, NJ). The latter was eventually the&#xD;
      preferred form. Patients allocated to treatment received IFN 3 MU/thrice weekly for 48 weeks&#xD;
      starting within 6 weeks from the operation. The severity of adverse events during treatment&#xD;
      were monitored and rated. Therapy was discontinued in case of life-threatening adverse event&#xD;
      or in case of HCC recurrence during treatment. For severe events other than anemia the IFN&#xD;
      dose was reduced by 50%; full dose could be resumed after the event was resolved or&#xD;
      discontinued if the effect persisted. The percentage of the total predicted dose of IFN&#xD;
      actually assumed by each patients was recorded. Patients assuming at least 80% of the total&#xD;
      dose of IFN and treated for at least 80% of the expected duration of therapy were a priori&#xD;
      defined as adherent to therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recurrences were a priori defined as &quot;early&quot; or &quot;late&quot; whether or not they occurred within 2&#xD;
      years from the surgical removal of the HCC. In fact early recurrence were related to&#xD;
      intra-hepatic metastases of the primary tumor possibly missed at the time of therapy, while&#xD;
      late recurrence might be due to new cancer foci related to the persistence of HCV-related&#xD;
      carcinogenetic factors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary endpoint of this randomized clinical trial (RCT) was recurrence-free survival (RFS)&#xD;
      while the secondary endpoint were disease-specific survival (DSS) and overall survival (OS).&#xD;
      Further secondary endpoints were the assessment of IFN tolerability in post-surgical patients&#xD;
      and the observation of prognostic factors related to early or late recurrence. Adherent&#xD;
      patients were considered for a subgroup analysis focused on patients who effectively received&#xD;
      the treatment designed to prevent HCC recurrence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrolment for the trial started on June 1998. By December 2002 the predicted sample size of&#xD;
      150 randomized patients was completed (&quot;pure HCV&quot;: 80 and &quot;mixed HCV+HBV&quot;: 70). The baseline&#xD;
      clinical, laboratory and tumor characteristics of the two arms and viral strata were&#xD;
      comparable. After 45 months of median follow-up the three- and five- years survival rates&#xD;
      were 69% and 52.4% respectively for the control group and 77.3% and 63.6% respectively for&#xD;
      the IFN group (P= 0.471) . At the univariate analysis tumor multiplicity (&gt;1 nodule) and&#xD;
      vascular invasion were significantly related to recurrence. After adjustment of the relative&#xD;
      weight of prognostic factors in a series of Cox models and cumulative incidence curves&#xD;
      calculated on pattern of recurrence, a benefit of IFN was observed on late recurrence&#xD;
      occurring in the pure-HCV patients adherent to treatment (hazard rate: 0.3; 95% Confidence&#xD;
      interval:0.09-0.9, P=0.04).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In conclusion, although adjuvant IFN failed to show a generalized effect on prevention of HCC&#xD;
      recurrence after curative resection, it effectively reduced late recurrence due to new tumor&#xD;
      foci in pure-HCV patient adherent to therapy (i.e.: receiving at least 80% of IFN dose for at&#xD;
      least 80% of time).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 1998</start_date>
  <completion_date>September 2005</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrence Free Survival</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Specific Survival</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Patient Survival</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment>150</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Hepatitis C Virus Infection</condition>
  <condition>Liver Cirrhosis</condition>
  <condition>Interferon Treatment</condition>
  <condition>Hepatic Resection</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Interferon alpha-2b</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HCV-RNA positive / HBsAg-negative patients with HCC undergoing potentially curative&#xD;
             resection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Curative surgery (i.e. no residual tumor intraoperative US and tumor-free margins at&#xD;
             pathology)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No recurrence 1 month after surgery (CT, NMR, US)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-resection treatments allowed (TACE, RFA, PEI)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HCV-RNA positive (lower limit of detection: 100 copies/ml) regardless of blood titers&#xD;
             or genotype&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HBsAg-positivity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of any active neoplastic site&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous IFN or chemotherapy or treatment of other tumors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe surgical complication and/or causes of cirrhosis not related to HCV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient comorbidity (Hb &lt;12 g/dl, HIV infection, autoimmune disease, psychiatric&#xD;
             disorder, seizure, severe cardiovascular disease, poorly controlled diabetes, BMI &gt;35)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active alcohol intake (&gt;80 g/day)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Vincenzo Mazzaferro, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute, Milan, Italy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milan</city>
        <zip>20133</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2005</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 5, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 5, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 9, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 5, 2006</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 5, 2006</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 9, 2006</last_update_posted>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferon alpha-2</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

