<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01356459</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2010.261</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01356459</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pressure Ulcer Prevention in Intensive Care Unit (ICU)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective Randomised Controlled Trial of the Effectiveness of Absorbent Silicone Self Adherent Dressings in the Prevention of Sacral and Heel Pressure Ulcers in Trauma and Critically Ill ED/ICU Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Melbourne Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Melbourne Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study is designed as a randomised controlled trial of trauma patients admitted to the&#xD;
      Royal Melbourne Hospital (RMH) Emergency Department (ED) and subsequently transferred to the&#xD;
      Intensive Care Unit (ICU). Patients meeting the study inclusion criteria will be randomly&#xD;
      allocated to either the control group that will receive usual pressure ulcer prevention&#xD;
      strategies or the trial group that will receive usual care plus have a Mepilex Border Sacrum&#xD;
      dressing applied to their sacrum and Mepilex Boarder Heel dressing applied to each heel in&#xD;
      the ED.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis:Patients treated with Mepilex Border dressings will have a lower incidence rate of&#xD;
      sacral and heel pressure ulcer development than patients receiving standard care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aims&#xD;
&#xD;
      To determine the effectiveness of Mepilex Border dressings in preventing sacral and heel&#xD;
      pressure ulcer development&#xD;
&#xD;
      To determine the cost effectiveness of Mepilex Border dressings in preventing sacral and heel&#xD;
      pressure ulcers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary endpoint&#xD;
&#xD;
      Incidence rates of pressure ulcers in ICU expressed as the total number of pressure ulcers&#xD;
      developed per week in both groups&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoint&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cost of trial dressings to prevent pressure ulcers Cost of the management of developed&#xD;
      pressure ulcers&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients treated with Mepilex Border dressings will have a lower incidence rate of sacral and&#xD;
      heel pressure ulcer development than patients receiving standard care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects and Sampling&#xD;
&#xD;
      All trauma and critically ill patients admitted to ED and defined by the ED as being trauma&#xD;
      and/or critically ill. These patients will subsequently be transferred to ICU over a six (6)&#xD;
      month period commencing January 2010&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators calculate that to detect a decrease in the ICU pressure ulcer incidence&#xD;
      rate of 3.5% (from 4% to 0.5%) in the intervention group with power set at 80% and alpha of&#xD;
      0.05 will require a total of 220 patients per group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomisation&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be randomised to either the intervention group or to the control group by&#xD;
      allocating each subject a study number and then using a computer generated set of random&#xD;
      numbers to determine group allocation. The randomisation of participants will be undertaken&#xD;
      by an ED research nurse when the patient is admitted to ED and following screening to&#xD;
      determine if they meet the inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant selection:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following procedure will be used by the ED Research Nurse to determine if the person is&#xD;
      included in the study and to which group the individual will be allocated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential participant Meets inclusion criteria and does not meet exclusion criteria Conducts&#xD;
      standard MH pressure ulcer risk screening (Braden Scale) Assigns participant a study number&#xD;
      Records ED data at admission (see below) Determines group allocation by comparing participant&#xD;
      study number to randomisation sequence&#xD;
&#xD;
      If randomised to trial group:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Applies Mepilex Border dressings to sacrum and heels Records time of dressing application&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
      Trial group patients who meet the inclusion criteria will have a Mepilex Border dressing&#xD;
      applied to their sacrum and heels on admission to ED by the ED research nursing staff. It is&#xD;
      necessary to apply the dressing at this point because the investigators wish to investigate&#xD;
      the potential protective effects of the dressing if the patient needs to have a surgical&#xD;
      procedure which may involve a long period in the OR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mepilex Border Dressing Mepilex Border is an absorbent, atraumatic self-adhesive island&#xD;
      dressing with a perforated soft silicone wound contact layer. The absorbent core of the&#xD;
      dressing consists of three components, a thin sheet of polyurethane foam, a piece of nonwoven&#xD;
      fabric and a layer of superabsorbent polyacrylate fibres. The core is located centrally upon&#xD;
      a larger piece of polyurethane film and is held in place by the perforated silicone adhesive&#xD;
      layer that extends to the outer margins of the dressing. This gentle adhesion also tends to&#xD;
      prevent maceration by inhibiting the lateral movement of exudate from the wound on to the&#xD;
      surrounding skin. The silicone layer does not adhere to the surface of a wound and therefore&#xD;
      the dressing may be removed without causing pain or trauma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method of use The wound contact surface of the dressing is protected with a divided plastic&#xD;
      film, which must be removed before use. If clinically indicated, the wound should be cleaned&#xD;
      and the surrounding skin thoroughly dried before application of the dressings. If additional&#xD;
      fixation is required this should only be applied around the margins of the dressing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Frequency of Change The interval between changes will normally be determined by the amount of&#xD;
      exudate produced by the wound, but the dressing may be left in place for several days on&#xD;
      clean non-infected wounds.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The manufacturers note that there are no absolute contra-indications to the use Mepilex&#xD;
      Border dressings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As patients in this study will not have a wound in the areas where the dressing will be&#xD;
      applied the investigators propose to change each dressing every three days or as required if&#xD;
      they become soiled or dislodged. This decision will be made by members of the research team&#xD;
      whao are involved with the daily assessment of each patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The skin under the dressings will be observed daily by members of the research team to&#xD;
      determine if any pressure related injuries have developed. Pressure related injuries are&#xD;
      defined as per the Australian Wound management Association clinical guideline for the&#xD;
      prediction, prevention and management of pressure ulcers. All members of the research team&#xD;
      have undergone inter-rater reliability testing in September 2010 for their ability to&#xD;
      recognise and stage a pressure ulcer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Measurement&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient demographics Age Wt Gender Race Pre-existing disease Charlson Comorbidity Index score&#xD;
      Reason for admission Management pre admission Eg. Time on spinal board Time in Ambulance Time&#xD;
      in ED ED management - ventilation ED physiological observations Number of OR procedures Time&#xD;
      in OR Time in ICU Nutritional status Immobility Urinary incontinence Faecal incontinence&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pressure ulcers:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pressure ulcer incidence per week&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pressure ulcers will be staged according to the Australian Wound Management Association&#xD;
      (AWMA) staging system&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cost of trial dressings used for total duration of trial Cost of management of developed&#xD;
      pressure ulcers Staff time Consumables&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physiological data All physiological data collected in ICU Shock/SIRS Cardiac arrest Drive&#xD;
      lines Spinal cord injury Mechanical ventilation Traction/external fixators&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pharmaceutical data All drugs Sedation/Paralytics Vasopressor drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      A survival analysis will be used to determine the difference in pressure ulcer incidence&#xD;
      rates per group and logistic regression will be used to investigate potential interactions&#xD;
      between demographic and physiological variables between groups and incidence rates. Analysis&#xD;
      will be conducted separately for sacral and heel wounds as the main analysis. The&#xD;
      investigators may pool the results if there appears to be no difference between the incidence&#xD;
      rates for sacral and heel wounds. All analytical procedures will be carried out by the&#xD;
      Statistical Consulting Centre, University of Melbourne.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cost analysis will involve calculating the total treatment and prevention costs associated&#xD;
      with pressure ulcers including staff time and consumables. The costing analysis will be&#xD;
      carried out by a research nurse in ICU who will observe and record the total staff time by&#xD;
      grade of RN spent on pressure ulcer prevention in all patients. Costs such as support&#xD;
      surfaces (dynamic mattresses and overlays) will also be added to prevention costs.&#xD;
      Intervention group patients will also have the costs of the Mepilex Border dressings added to&#xD;
      their pressure ulcer prevention costs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Should a patient in either group develop a pressure ulcer the cost of managing the wound will&#xD;
      be calculated based on staff time by grade, consumables such as dressings, investigations&#xD;
      such as microbiological specimen collection and analysis. These costs will be determined for&#xD;
      the total time that the patient remains in ICU.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pressure ulcer incidence</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly</time_frame>
    <description>Number of pressure ulcers developed in the ICU per week</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cost</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly</time_frame>
    <description>The cost of treating developed pressure versus the cost of preventing the development of pressure ulcers</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">440</enrollment>
  <condition>Pressure Ulcers</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in this arm will have Mepilex dressings applied to their sacrum and heels</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in this arm will have standard care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mepilex Border Dressing</intervention_name>
    <description>Soft silicone self adherent dressing</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Mepilex Border Sacrum</other_name>
    <other_name>Mepilex Heel</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ED and ICU admission for critical illness and/or major trauma Over 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than 18 years old Suspected or actual spinal injury Pre-existing sacral or heel&#xD;
             pressure ulcer Trauma to sacral and/or heel area&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Melbourne Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Melbourne</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <zip>3050</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 17, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 18, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 19, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 8, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 8, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 12, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pressure ulcers</keyword>
  <keyword>ICU</keyword>
  <keyword>Prevention</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pressure Ulcer</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

