<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04210752</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EG-HZ-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04210752</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Assess the Safety, Tolerability and Explore the Immunogenicity of EG-HZ in Healthy Adult Volunteers</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1, Randomised, Activator-Controlled, Double-Blind, Parallel Study to Assess the Safety, Tolerability and Explore the Immunogenicity of EG-HZ in Healthy Adult Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>EyeGene Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Novotech (Australia) Pty Limited</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>EyeGene Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 1, first in human (FIH), randomised, active-controlled, double-blind study&#xD;
      designed to assess the safety and tolerability and explore preliminary efficacy of the EG-HZ&#xD;
      vaccine. Oversight will be provided by a Safety Review Committee (SRC).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Subjects will undergo a Screening period beginning up to 28 days prior to randomisation, the&#xD;
      first of two vaccinations administered 2 months apart, pre- and post-dose assessment,&#xD;
      follow-up visits, and an end of study (EOS) or early termination (ET) visit (as applicable).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be randomised prior to vaccination on Day 1, to one (1) of five (5) treatment&#xD;
      groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 24, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 3, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 3, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events as assessed by CTCAE v4.0</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, estimated 9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Safety and tolerability determined by abnormal clinical laboratory tests, vitals signs, physical exam, ECG parameters. It is an composite Outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To explore the immunogenicity of EG-HZ at various excipient combinations</measure>
    <time_frame>Blood samples for analysis of immunogenicity will be collected pre-dose and at multiple time points post-dose following administration of each vaccination. Through study completion, estimated 9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Immunogenicity is determined by Anti-Glycoprotein E total immunoglobulin G (IgG) antibody concentration at 1 month (Day 90) and 6 months (Day 240) post last vaccination.&#xD;
Humoral immunity: anti-Varicella zoster virus total IgG antibody; anti-Glycoprotein E total IgG antibody.&#xD;
Cell-mediated immunity: CD4+ T cell; CD8+ T cell</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Prevention of Herpes Zoster (HZ)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 1 (EG-HZ-001)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive two single IM vaccinations, 2 months apart, the first on Day 1 and the second on Day 60 (±5 days). Subjects will be randomised to treatment at a ratio of 1:1:1:1:1 (n=8 per treatment)&#xD;
Route of administration: Intramuscular injection</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 2 (EG-HZ-002)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive two single IM vaccinations, 2 months apart, the first on Day 1 and the second on Day 60 (±5 days). Subjects will be randomised to treatment at a ratio of 1:1:1:1:1 (n=8 per treatment)&#xD;
Route of administration: Intramuscular injection</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 3 (EG-HZ-003)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive two single IM vaccinations, 2 months apart, the first on Day 1 and the second on Day 60 (±5 days). Subjects will be randomised to treatment at a ratio of 1:1:1:1:1 (n=8 per treatment)&#xD;
Route of administration: Intramuscular injection</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 4 (EG-HZ-004)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive two single IM vaccinations, 2 months apart, the first on Day 1 and the second on Day 60 (±5 days). Subjects will be randomised to treatment at a ratio of 1:1:1:1:1 (n=8 per treatment)&#xD;
Route of administration: Intramuscular injection</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 5 (Shingrix)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Shingrix&#xD;
Suspension for injection supplied as a single dose vial of lyophilised VZVgE antigen component to be reconstituted with the accompanying vial of AS01B adjuvant suspension component. After reconstitution, a single dose of ShingrixTM is 0.5 mL.&#xD;
Route of Administration: Intramuscular injection</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Treatment 1 (EG-HZ-001)</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will receive two single IM vaccinations, 2 months apart, the first on Day 1 and the second on Day 60 (±5 days). Subjects will be randomised to treatment at a ratio of 1:1:1:1:1 (n=8 per treatment)&#xD;
Route of Administration: IM injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 1 (EG-HZ-001)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>EG-HZ</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Treatment 2 (EG-HZ-002)</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will receive two single IM vaccinations, 2 months apart, the first on Day 1 and the second on Day 60 (±5 days). Subjects will be randomised to treatment at a ratio of 1:1:1:1:1 (n=8 per treatment)&#xD;
Route of Administration: IM injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 2 (EG-HZ-002)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>EG-HZ</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Treatment 3 (EG-HZ-003)</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will receive two single IM vaccinations, 2 months apart, the first on Day 1 and the second on Day 60 (±5 days). Subjects will be randomised to treatment at a ratio of 1:1:1:1:1 (n=8 per treatment)&#xD;
Route of Administration: IM injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 3 (EG-HZ-003)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>EG-HZ</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Treatment 4 (EG-HZ-004)</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will receive two single IM vaccinations, 2 months apart, the first on Day 1 and the second on Day 60 (±5 days). Subjects will be randomised to treatment at a ratio of 1:1:1:1:1 (n=8 per treatment)&#xD;
Route of Administration: IM injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 4 (EG-HZ-004)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>EG-HZ</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Treatment 5</intervention_name>
    <description>Shingrix&#xD;
Suspension for injection supplied as a single dose vial of lyophilised VZVgE antigen component to be reconstituted with the accompanying vial of AS01B adjuvant suspension component. After reconstitution, a single dose of ShingrixTM is 0.5 mL.&#xD;
Route of Administration: IM injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 5 (Shingrix)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Comparator</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Able to understand and comply with the study procedures, understand the risks involved&#xD;
             in the study, and provide written informed consent before the first study-specific&#xD;
             procedure;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Healthy male and female volunteers aged 50 to 70 years at time of Screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects must have a BMI between ≥18.0 and ≤35.0 kg/m2 at Screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Availability to volunteer for the entire study duration and willing to adhere to all&#xD;
             protocol requirements;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Must have a negative urine pregnancy test on the day of dosing prior to each&#xD;
             vaccination;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects must have clinical laboratory values within normal ranges as specified by the&#xD;
             testing laboratory, unless deemed NCS by the PI;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Normal physical findings, vital signs, 12-lead ECG, and no significant medical&#xD;
             condition at the time of Screening, as judged by the PI;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Must agree to abstain from alcohol intake from 48 hours before each vaccination;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Must be non-smokers or, if light or occasional smokers (&lt;10 cigarettes per day), must&#xD;
             agree to abstain from smoking from 48 hours before each vaccination;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Must have a negative urine drug screen/alcohol breath test on the day of dosing prior&#xD;
             to each vaccination. Repeat urine drug screens will be permitted for suspected false&#xD;
             positive results;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Must agree to use highly effective, medically accepted double-barrier contraception&#xD;
             (both male and female partners) from Screening until study completion as specified&#xD;
             below in this criterion. Highly effective double-barrier contraception is defined as&#xD;
             use of a condom&#xD;
&#xD;
        AND one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Birth control pills (The Pill)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Depot or injectable birth control&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. IUD&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Birth Control Patch (e.g., Ortho Evra)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. NuvaRing®&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Implantable contraception (e.g., Implanon)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Documented evidence of surgical sterilisation at least 6 months prior to Screening,&#xD;
             i.e., tubal ligation or hysterectomy for women or vasectomy for men&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnant or lactating at Screening or planning to become pregnant (self or partner) at&#xD;
             any time during the study, including the follow-up period;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of severe allergic reaction (e.g., anaphylaxis) to any component of the&#xD;
             vaccine;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of herpes zoster (Shingles);&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Previous vaccination against HZ (either a registered product or an investigational&#xD;
             product through participation in a HZ vaccine study);&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Previous vaccination against VZV;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Chronic administration (defined as more than 14 consecutive days) of&#xD;
             immunosuppressants or other immune-modifying drugs within 3 months prior to the first&#xD;
             vaccine dose (intra-articular, intra-bursal, or topical [skin or eyes] corticosteroids&#xD;
             are permitted at the discretion of the PI);&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of autoimmune disease/s which required therapeutic intervention/s, or any&#xD;
             active autoimmune disease requiring therapeutic intervention/s including but not&#xD;
             limited to: systemic or cutaneous lupus erythematosus, autoimmune arthritis/rheumatoid&#xD;
             arthritis, Guillain-Barré syndrome, multiple sclerosis, Sjögren's syndrome, idiopathic&#xD;
             thrombocytopenic purpura, glomerulonephritis, autoimmune thyroiditis, giant cell&#xD;
             arteritis (temporal arteritis), psoriasis, and insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus&#xD;
             (i.e. type 1 diabetes);&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Bleeding diathesis or condition associated with prolonged bleeding that would, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the Investigator, contraindicate intramuscular injection;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Vaccines administered or scheduled in the period from 4 weeks prior to Dose 1 through&#xD;
             to 28 days post-vaccination dose 2, excluding licensed non-replicating vaccines (i.e.,&#xD;
             inactivated and subunit vaccines, including inactivated and subunit influenza vaccines&#xD;
             for seasonal or pandemic flu, with or without adjuvant) administered up to 8 days&#xD;
             prior to each dose and/or at least 14 days after any dose of study vaccine (to be&#xD;
             determined at the discretion of the PI);&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Receipt of any immunoglobulins or blood/plasma products within 60 days prior to&#xD;
             vaccination on Day 1 and until the EOS/ET visit;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Positive test for HCV, HBsAg, or HIV antibody at Screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. History or presence of any clinically unstable medical, surgical or psychiatric&#xD;
             condition, at the discretion of the Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Active malignancy and/or history of malignancy in the past 5 years, except for&#xD;
             completely excised basal cell carcinoma or low grade cervical intraepithelial&#xD;
             neoplasia;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. History of significant hypersensitivity or anaphylaxis involving any drug, food or&#xD;
             other precipitating agent (e.g., bee sting);&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Abnormal laboratory values or investigations (including ECG) that, in the opinion of&#xD;
             the Investigator, are deemed clinically significant and would preclude participation&#xD;
             in the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Renal insufficiency defined by eGFR &lt;90 mL/min (CKD-EPI);&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Hepatic synthetic insufficiency as defined as a serum albumin of &lt;35 g/L; or serum&#xD;
             bilirubin &gt;20 μmol/L;&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Acute disease or acute stage of chronic disease and/or fever at the time of enrolment.&#xD;
             Fever is defined as temperature ≥ 37.5°C (99.5°F), regardless of the route. Subjects&#xD;
             with a minor illness (such as mild diarrhoea, mild upper respiratory infection)&#xD;
             without fever may, be enrolled at the discretion of the Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Regular use of any prescribed or non-prescribed medications, including herbal&#xD;
             remedies, which, in the opinion of the Investigator, might adversely affect the safety&#xD;
             of the subject or the interpretability of study results. Participants who are taking a&#xD;
             stable dose of medication for a controlled medications include, for example, stable&#xD;
             doses of antidepressants, cholesterol lowering agents, high blood pressure medication,&#xD;
             reflux medication, hormone replacement therapy, NSAIDs, paracetamol, occasional&#xD;
             Ventolin, etc.);&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. History of or present alcohol abuse, or excessive intake of alcohol, as judged by the&#xD;
             Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Blood donation or significant blood loss within 30 days prior to the first study drug&#xD;
             administration and until the EOS/ET visit;&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Plasma donation within 7 days prior to the first study drug administration and until&#xD;
             the EOS/ET visit;&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Administration of another IP (defined as a compound that has not been approved for&#xD;
             marketing) or has participated in any other clinical study that included IP treatment&#xD;
             within 3 months prior to administration of IP in this study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Any person who is initially excluded from study participation based on one or more of&#xD;
             the time-limited exclusion criteria (e.g., acute illness) may be considered for&#xD;
             enrollment once the condition has resolved as long as the subject continues to meet&#xD;
             all other entry criteria;&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Subject taking any non-topical antiviral therapy with activity against herpes viruses,&#xD;
             including but not limited to acyclovir, famciclovir, ganciclovir, and valacyclovir 3&#xD;
             days prior to vaccination or 14 days after;&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Any other reason that, in the opinion of the Investigator, might interfere with the&#xD;
             evaluation required by the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. The subject is, in the opinion of the Investigator, unlikely to comply with the&#xD;
             clinical study protocol or is unsuitable for any other reason.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Q-Pharm Pty Ltd (Nucleus Network)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Herston</city>
        <state>Queensland</state>
        <zip>4006,</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 17, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 22, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 26, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Herpes Zoster</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

