<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04216342</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>200029</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>20-H-0029</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04216342</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of Fx-5A in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Intravenous, Open-Label, Dose Escalation Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of Fx-5A in Healthy Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Heart disease is the leading cause of death, disability, and healthcare expense in the United&#xD;
      States. Researchers think a new drug called Fx-5A may be useful to treat different&#xD;
      cardiovascular diseases and inflammation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To understand the safety, tolerability, and effects of Fx-5A.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy people ages 18 and older who are not pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical exam&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pregnancy test for female participants&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will stay in the hospital for 36-48 hours. This will include:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      EKGs: Electrodes will be placed on the participant s chest. The patches are connected to&#xD;
      cables that will send information from their heart to a machine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Single infusion of Fx-5A. A needle will be used to insert a plastic tube into a vein in the&#xD;
      participant s arm. This tube will remain in the arm for the duration of the hospital stay for&#xD;
      blood tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have follow-up visits day 7 and day 28 after their infusion. At these&#xD;
      visits, they will have blood tests and an EKG.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation will last 5-10 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cardiovascular disease (CVD) is one of the leading causes of death worldwide and elevated&#xD;
      levels of cholesterol and triglycerides on plasma lipoproteins are major contributing risk&#xD;
      factors. Therapeutic agents that increase High Density Lipoproteins (HDL) may be useful&#xD;
      additions to our current treatment approaches for preventing Coronary Heart Disease (CHD),&#xD;
      because while existing drugs lower Low&#xD;
&#xD;
      Density Lipoproteins (LDL), they do not fully prevent CHD. A potential new CHD treatment&#xD;
      strategy has recently been described called Acute HDL Therapy, which involves weekly&#xD;
      intravenous infusions of HDL, or HDL components (i.e. ApoA-I), or HDL mimetics into patients&#xD;
      suffering from acute coronary syndrome. In early stage clinical trials, a 5-week course of&#xD;
      this therapy has been shown to&#xD;
&#xD;
      rapidly reduce atherosclerotic plaques, as assessed by intravascular ultrasound. The goal of&#xD;
      Acute HDL Therapy is to rapidly stabilize patients at significant risk for developing a&#xD;
      myocardial infarction, while concurrently starting them on conventional lipid lowering drugs&#xD;
      and other agents already known to reduce the risk of myocardial infarction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This clinical research project is designed to investigate the safety and pharmacological&#xD;
      properties of a short synthetic peptide mimic of Apolipoprotein A-I (apoA-I), referred to as&#xD;
      the 5A peptide (or peptide 5A). This 5A peptide can potentially be used instead of&#xD;
      recombinant apoA-I in Acute HDL Therapy, and has several potential advantages over the use of&#xD;
      recombinant apoA-I. When the 5A peptide is combined with sphingomyelin, the complex is&#xD;
      referred to as the Fx-5A peptide-lipid complex. Fx-5A was specifically designed to remove&#xD;
      excess cellular cholesterol via the ABCA1 transporter, which is thought to be one of the main&#xD;
      anti-atherogenic functions of HDL. Furthermore, the peptide-lipid complex has been shown to&#xD;
      mobilize macrophage cholesterol in animal models. Fx-5A markedly decreases the development of&#xD;
      atherosclerotic plaque in preclinical models, such as in apoE-deficient mice, while also&#xD;
      decreasing macrophage recruitment and foam cell formation in the rabbit collar model.&#xD;
      Separately, animal models have shown that Fx-5A can also minimize inflammation associated&#xD;
      with diseases like asthma, colitis and chronic kidney disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current research project is designed as a Phase 1A, open-label, dose-escalation study to&#xD;
      evaluate the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, and pharmacodynamics of a single&#xD;
      intravenous infusion of the Fx-5A peptide-lipid complex at 4 different doses in healthy&#xD;
      subjects. Each of the 4 dosing cohorts (2.5, 5.0, 10.0 and 20.0 mg/kg) will enroll 4&#xD;
      subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For each dosing cohort, there are three distinct phases of this study; Screening,&#xD;
      Intervention, and Follow-Up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 29, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the safety and tolerability of the Fx-5A peptide complex.</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>A complete study is defined by the procedures described up to day 7 after Fx-5A infusion, the intervention phase of the study. A 28 days follow up is designed to study the immunogenicity of the drug. Once a subject completes the day 28 follow up the study is ended for the subject ( end of the study ).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the PK and PD of the Fx-5A peptide-lipid complex</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>A complete study is defined by the procedures described up to day 7 after Fx-5A infusion, the intervention phase of the study. A 28 days follow up is designed to study the immunogenicity of the drug. Once a subject completes the day 28 follow up the study is ended for the subject ( end of the study ).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">64</enrollment>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>subjects entered into the trial may go thru a 0-4 weeks screening (Screening Phase). On the Intervention phase, subjects will be followed for 7 days which includes: entry criteria assessments and settling at the inpatient unit on Day 0, a single-dose I.V. infusion with data collection on Day 1 followed by 24 hours monitoring (Day 2), a 7-day and 28-day outpatient follow-up visit (Follow-Up Phase).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fx-5A peptide complex</intervention_name>
    <description>subject will receive a slow I.V. infusion of the Fx-5A peptide complex as described in Table 1. Five to 10 mL of blood will be collected at 30min (+/- 5min*), 1h (+/- 10min*), 2h (+/- 10min*), 4h (+/- 15min*), 8h (+/- 30min*), 12h (+/- 30min*), and 24h (+/- 30min*) for laboratory tests and to be stored for research tests. The patient will be dismissed, as inpatient, 24-36 hours after the beginning of the treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years of age or above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential must be willing to use an appropriate form of birth&#xD;
             control during the course of the study and two forms of birth control during the&#xD;
             interventional portion of the study and up to day 7 after infusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject willing to return for all study visits, complete all study-related tasks, and&#xD;
             agree not to participate in other research studies from screening visit to study&#xD;
             completion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness and capacity to provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, planned pregnancy (within the study period), or current breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject taking any supplements or medications for at least 8 weeks prior to enrollment&#xD;
             (with the exception of oral contraceptives).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergies or intolerances to any components of the Fx-5A peptide-lipid complex&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergies or intolerances to eggs or egg components&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of febrile illness within 5 days prior to dosing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypertension (not treated or uncontrolled&amp;)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI equal to or above 30 kg/m^2, and weight above 247 lb (112.3 kg).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood donation equal to or above 500 mL within 2 months prior to dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with an investigational drug within a month or 5 half-lives of the&#xD;
             investigational drug, whichever is longer, prior to dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Laboratory changes (with CTCAE grade 2 or above): Abnormal levels of ALT, AST, CK,&#xD;
             CRP, Alkaline Phosphatase, HbA1c, Urea, Creatinine, TSH, hemoglobin and hematocrit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with renal (eGFR&lt;90 mL/min /1.73m^2) or liver impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects may also be excluded for any reason that may compromise their safety or the&#xD;
             accuracy of research data collection.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marcelo J Amar, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Joy Lynne V Freeman</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 480-7632</phone>
    <email>joylynne.freeman@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2020-H-0029.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/H7XXWJX</url>
    <description>https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/H7XXWJX</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 13, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 31, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 31, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pharmacology</keyword>
  <keyword>PEPTIDE</keyword>
  <keyword>ApoA-I</keyword>
  <keyword>Fx-5A</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

