<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03172624</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>17-219</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03172624</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Nivolumab Plus Ipilimumab in Patients With Salivary Gland Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Study of Nivolumab Plus Ipilimumab in Patients With Recurrent/Metastatic Salivary Cancers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bristol-Myers Squibb</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to find out what effects, good and/or bad, treatment with two&#xD;
      drugs called nivolumab and ipilimumab have on the participant and salivary cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 26, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a phase II study evaluating the efficacy of nivolumab in combination with ipilimumab in patients with recurrent and/or metastatic (R/M) salivary gland cancers (SGCs). Patients will be enrolled to two cohorts: Cohort 1, patients with R/M adenoid cystic carcinoma (&quot;ACC group&quot;), and Cohort 2: patients with R/M SGC of any histology, except ACC (&quot;non-ACC group&quot;).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>best overall response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>using the new international criteria proposed by the revised Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) guideline (version 1.1)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">64</enrollment>
  <condition>Salivary Gland Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>R/M adenoid cystic carcinoma (ACC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Enrolled patients will be treated with nivolumab 3 mg/kg every 2 weeks plus ipilimumab 1 mg/kg every 6 weeks (1 cycle= 6 weeks).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>R/M SGC of any histology, except ACC (Non ACC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Enrolled patients will be treated with nivolumab 3 mg/kg every 2 weeks plus ipilimumab 1 mg/kg every 6 weeks (1 cycle= 6 weeks).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nivolumab</intervention_name>
    <description>nivolumab 3 mg/kg every 2 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>R/M SGC of any histology, except ACC (Non ACC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>R/M adenoid cystic carcinoma (ACC)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ipilimumab</intervention_name>
    <description>ipilimumab 1 mg/kg every 6 weeks (1 cycle= 6 weeks)</description>
    <arm_group_label>R/M SGC of any histology, except ACC (Non ACC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>R/M adenoid cystic carcinoma (ACC)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort 1 only: Patients must have pathologically or cytologically confirmed adenoid&#xD;
             cystic carcinoma. Cancers arising from non-salivary gland primary sites are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have pathologically or cytologically confirmed salivary gland cancer of&#xD;
             any histology except for adenoid cystic carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have recurrent and/or metastatic disease not amenable to potentially&#xD;
             curative surgery or radiotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 2 weeks must have elapsed since the end of prior systemic treatment and/or 4&#xD;
             weeks since completion of radiotherapy with resolution of all treatment-related&#xD;
             toxicity to NCI CTCAE Version 4.0 grade ≤1 (or tolerable grade 2) or back to baseline&#xD;
             (except for alopecia, lymphopenia, or hypothyroidism) prior to starting study drug&#xD;
             treatment. Any number of prior therapies for recurrent/metastatic salivary gland&#xD;
             cancer are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: Patients previously treated with hormonal therapies (e.g., drugs targeting the&#xD;
        androgen receptor) may continue these drugs prior to trials enrollment and concomitantly&#xD;
        with study therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have RECIST v1.1 measurable disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort 1 and acinic cell carcinoma patients in Cohort 2 only: Patients must have&#xD;
             documentation of a new or progressive lesion on a radiologic imaging study performed&#xD;
             within 6 months prior to study enrollment (progression of disease over any interval is&#xD;
             allowed) and/or new/worsening disease related symptoms within 6 months prior to study&#xD;
             enrollment. Note: This assessment will be performed by the treating investigator.&#xD;
             Evidence of progression by RECIST criteria is not required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG performance status 0 or 1 (or Karnofsky ≥ 70%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have tissue from the primary tumor or metastases available for&#xD;
             correlative studies. Either a paraffin block or at least 20 unstained slides are&#xD;
             acceptable (30 unstained slides would be ideal). (If less than twenty unstained slides&#xD;
             are available and a paraffin bloc is not available, the patient may be able to&#xD;
             participate at the discretion of the investigator.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must agree to undergo two research biopsies of malignant lesions. Tumor&#xD;
             tissue obtained prior to study consent or treatment as part of standard of care can&#xD;
             also be submitted in lieu of performance of the first pre-treatment biopsy, if the&#xD;
             Principal Investigator deems it to be of sufficient quantity/quality/timeliness.&#xD;
             Patients may be exempt from biopsy if 1) the investigator or person performing the&#xD;
             biopsy judges that no tumor is accessible for biopsy, 2) the investigator or person&#xD;
             performing the biopsy feels that the biopsy poses too great of a risk to the patient,&#xD;
             or 3) the patient's platelet count is &lt;100,000/mcl or he/she cannot be safely removed&#xD;
             from anti-coagulation therapy (if the anti-coagulation therapy needs to be temporarily&#xD;
             held for the biopsy procedure). If the only tumor accessible for biopsy is also the&#xD;
             only lesion that can be used for RECIST v1.1 response evaluation, then the patient may&#xD;
             be exempt from biopsy. If the investigator deems a second research biopsy to be high&#xD;
             risk after a patient has completed the first research biopsy, the patient may be&#xD;
             exempt from the second biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Screening laboratory values must meet the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  WBC ≥ 2000/μL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Neutrophils ≥ 1500/μL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥ 100 x10^3/μL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin &gt; 9.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST/ALT ≤ 3 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN (except subjects with Gilbert Syndrome, who can have&#xD;
                  total bilirubin &lt; 3.0 mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN or creatinine clearance (CrCl) ≥ 40 mL/min (if using&#xD;
                  the Cockcroft-Gault formula below):&#xD;
&#xD;
        Female CrCl = (140 - age in years) x weight in kg x 0.85 72 x serum creatinine in mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
        Male CrCl = (140 - age in years) x weight in kg x 1.00 72 x serum creatinine in mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP)* must use appropriate method(s) of&#xD;
             contraception. WOCBP should use an adequate method to avoid pregnancy for 23 weeks (30&#xD;
             days plus the time required for nivolumab to undergo five half-lives) after the last&#xD;
             dose of investigational drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  WOCBP is defined as any female who has experienced menarche and who has not&#xD;
                  undergone surgical sterilization (hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy) or who&#xD;
                  is not postmenopausal. Menopause is defined clinically as 12 months of amenorrhea&#xD;
                  in a woman over 45 in the absence of other biological or physiological causes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Women who are not of childbearing potential are not required to use contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test&#xD;
             upon study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men who are sexually active with women of child bearing potential must use adequate&#xD;
             contraception upon study entry until 31 weeks after the last dose of study treatment.&#xD;
             Men who are surgically sterile or azoospermic do not require contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptomatic metastatic brain or leptomeningeal tumors (asymptomatic or treated&#xD;
             metastatic brain or leptomeningeal tumors are allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or prior use of immunosuppressive doses of systemic corticosteroids (&gt;10&#xD;
             mg/day prednisone equivalents) or other immunosuppressive medications within 2 weeks&#xD;
             of study drug administration. NOTE: Subjects are permitted to use topical, ocular,&#xD;
             intra-articular, intranasal, and inhalational corticosteroids (with minimal systemic&#xD;
             absorption). Physiologic replacement doses of systemic corticosteroids are permitted,&#xD;
             even if &gt;10 mg/day prednisone equivalents. A brief course of corticosteroids for&#xD;
             prophylaxis (e.g., contrast dye allergy) or for treatment of non-autoimmune conditions&#xD;
             (eg, delayed-type hypersensitivity reaction caused by contact allergen) is permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active, known, or suspected autoimmune disease within the past 2 years. NOTE: Subjects&#xD;
             are permitted to enroll if they have vitiligo, type I diabetes mellitus, residual&#xD;
             hypothyroidism due to autoimmune condition only requiring hormone replacement,&#xD;
             psoriasis not requiring systemic treatment, or conditions not expected to recur in the&#xD;
             absence of an external trigger&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should be excluded if they have had prior systemic treatment with an&#xD;
             anti-PD-1, anti-PD-L1, anti-PD-L2, anti-CTLA-4 antibody, or any other antibody or drug&#xD;
             specifically targeting T-cell costimulation or immune checkpoint pathways.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should be excluded if they have a known history of testing positive for&#xD;
             hepatitis B virus surface antigen (HBV sAg) or hepatitis C virus antibody (HCV&#xD;
             antibody) indicating acute or chronic infection (those with treated hepatitis B or C&#xD;
             infection and a negative viral load prior to study entry would be eligible)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should be excluded if they have a known history of testing positive for human&#xD;
             immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or known acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergy to study drug components.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe hypersensitivity reaction to any monoclonal antibody.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant or breast-feeding.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alan Ho, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memoral Sloan Kettering Basking Ridge</name>
      <address>
        <city>Basking Ridge</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07920</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memoral Sloan Kettering Monmouth</name>
      <address>
        <city>Middletown</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07748</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Bergen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montvale</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07645</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Commack</name>
      <address>
        <city>Commack</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11725</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Westchester</name>
      <address>
        <city>Harrison</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10604</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Rockville Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rockville Centre</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11570</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Nassau</name>
      <address>
        <city>Uniondale</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11553</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mskcc.org/mskcc/html/44.cfm</url>
    <description>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 30, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 30, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 1, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Nivolumab</keyword>
  <keyword>Ipilimumab</keyword>
  <keyword>17-219</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Salivary Gland Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ipilimumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

