<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04543630</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>N-20200009</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04543630</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Maxillary Sinus Floor Augmentation in Diabetic Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Maxillary Sinus Floor Augmentation in Diabetic Patients With Particulated Autogenous Bone Graft Compared With Advanced Platelet-rich Fibrin. A Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Copenhagen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Copenhagen University Hospital at Herlev</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Aalborg University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Copenhagen</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Placement of implants in diabetic patients is associated with higher risk of implant failure&#xD;
      and peri-implant marginal bone loss due to an increased susceptibility to infections,&#xD;
      impaired wound healing and associated microvascular complications. However, diabetic patients&#xD;
      do not encounter a higher implant failure rate compared with non-diabetic patients, if the&#xD;
      plasma glucose levels are normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prosthetic rehabilitation of the posterior maxilla with implants is frequently compromised&#xD;
      due to atrophy of the alveolar process and pneumatisation of the maxillary sinus. Maxillary&#xD;
      sinus floor augmentation (MSFA) with autogenous bone graft is generally considered the&#xD;
      preferred grafting material due to its osteoinductive, osteogenic, and osteoconductive&#xD;
      properties. However, harvesting of autogenous bone graft is associated with risk of donor&#xD;
      site morbidity and unpredictable resorption of the graft. Thus, bone substitutes, blood&#xD;
      coagulum and platelet rich fibrin are used increasingly to simplify the surgical procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fabrication of advanced platelet rich fibrin (APRF) from blood samples possess significant&#xD;
      potential for bone regeneration without the use of additional autogenous bone grafts or bone&#xD;
      substitutes. Consequently, use of APRF in conjunction with MSFA will avoid bone harvesting&#xD;
      and simplify the surgical procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective is to test the H0-hypothesis of no difference in implant treatment outcome&#xD;
      after MSFA with particulated autogenous bone graft compared with APRF. Forty consecutively&#xD;
      insulin-dependent diabetes patients with missing posterior maxillary tooth/teeth will be&#xD;
      allocated to implant placement and MSFA with particulated autogenous bone graft from the&#xD;
      zygomatic buttress or APRF. Blood samples will be obtained preoperatively and&#xD;
      postoperatively. Clinical and radiographical evaluation using periapical radiographs and CBCT&#xD;
      will be performed preoperatively, immediate postoperatively, before abutment connection,&#xD;
      after prosthetic rehabilitation, one year, three years and five years after loading to assess&#xD;
      the implant treatment outcome and the volumetric changes of the augmented area. Outcome&#xD;
      measures will include survival of suprastructures and implants, volumetric stability of the&#xD;
      augmented area, peri-implant marginal bone level, immunological analyses of blood samples,&#xD;
      oral health related quality of life, and complications related to the two treatment&#xD;
      modalities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Purpose The aim of the present study is to test the H0-hypotheisis of no difference in&#xD;
      implant treatment outcome after MSFA in partial edentulous diabetic patients with&#xD;
      particulated autogenous bone graft compared with APRF after five years of functional implant&#xD;
      loading.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective is to test the H0 hypothesis of no differences in:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Survival of suprastructures and implants.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Volumetrical stability of the graft material.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Peri-implant marginal bone level.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Implantat stability quotient.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Effect of implant placement and graft material on hematological and inflammatory&#xD;
           parameters.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient-reported outcome measures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Biologic and technical complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome measures&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Survival of suprastructures. Loss of suprastructures is defined as a total loss because&#xD;
           of a non-treatable mechanical/or biological complication.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Survival of implants. Loss of implants is defined as removal of a non-integrated&#xD;
           implant, mobility of previously clinical osseointegrated implant, and removal of&#xD;
           non-mobile implants due to progressive peri-implant marginal bone loss and inflammation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Volumetric changes of the graft material.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Peri-implant marginal bone level.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Levels of hematological and inflammatory parameters.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient-reported outcome measures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Biologic and technical complications e.g. loosening of crown and fractures of veneer&#xD;
           ceramic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials and methods Study population Forty consecutive insulin-dependent diabetes patients&#xD;
      with missing posterior maxillary tooth/teeth will be included and randomly allocated to MSFA&#xD;
      with particulated autogenous bone graft (control group) or APRF (test group). The study will&#xD;
      be conducted at the Department of Odontology, Sections of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery and&#xD;
      Periodontology, University of Copenhagen and Department of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery,&#xD;
      Copenhagen University Hospital (Rigshospitalet) and Aalborg University Hospital, Aalborg,&#xD;
      Denmark.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethical considerations, perspectives and informed consent The study has been approved by The&#xD;
      North Denmark Region Committee on Health Research Ethics and will be performed according to&#xD;
      the Declaration of Helsinki on clinical research. All patients will receive verbal and&#xD;
      written information about the study by the investigators at a clinical visit prior to&#xD;
      surgery. Written informed consent is mandatory for inclusion in the study and will be&#xD;
      obtained by the investigators prior to surgery from each patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Initial examination&#xD;
&#xD;
      The initial examination of the patient will include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Clinical examination and assessment of the periodontal health status:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Missing one posterior maxillary tooth (&gt;4 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Need of one implant in the posterior part of the maxilla.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adjacent tooth in opposite jaw in contact with planned crown.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Plaque and gingival index, probing pocket depth, and probing attachment level of the&#xD;
           adjacent tooth/teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Radiographical examination of the residual alveolar bone height based on CBCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Orthopantomography to document the pre-treatment status.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient will fill out the OHIP-14 questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgical procedure The surgical procedure will be performed in local anesthesia with or&#xD;
      without oral sedation or in general anesthesia. Implant installation and fabrication of the&#xD;
      subsequently prosthetic solution will be performed according to manufacturer's&#xD;
      recommendations. Prior to surgery, patients are pre-medicated as outlined in Table I.&#xD;
      Patients will rinse with 0.12% chlorhexidine solution for one minute immediately before&#xD;
      surgery. A sealed randomization envelope is opened in order to allocate patients to&#xD;
      particulated autogenous bone graft from the zygomatic buttress (control) or APRF (test).&#xD;
      Venous blood is collected from all the included patients via venipuncture of the forearm. The&#xD;
      first 30 ml venous blood is discarded to prevent infection. A venous blood sample (80 ml,&#xD;
      distributed in eight 10-ml glass-coated plastic tubes) via puncture of a vein in the cubital&#xD;
      fossa is collected and centrifuged (A-PRF 12, Process, Nice, France) according to a&#xD;
      previously described method. The blood samples are centrifuged at 200 g for 14 min. The tubes&#xD;
      containing the centrifuged blood are placed to rest for approximately 25 min to give the&#xD;
      fibrin clot a firmer consistency before collecting it for the final membrane preparation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The maxillary sinus wall is exposed by an intraoral marginal incision from tuber maxillae to&#xD;
      the first premolar with a vertical releasing incision. A 1 x 1 cm bony window to the&#xD;
      maxillary sinus is created maintaining an intact Schneiderian membrane. The Schneiderian&#xD;
      membrane is elevated from the sinus floor as well as the lateral sinus wall and displaced&#xD;
      dorsocranially with blunt dissector. An implant bed is successively prepared on the top of&#xD;
      the alveolar crest following manufactory's recommendations. An implant (AstraTech, 13 mm) is&#xD;
      inserted with a cover screw. The implant stability quotient is measured for all inserted&#xD;
      implants (Penguin, Integration Diagnostics Sweden AB, Göteborg, Sweden). Autogenous bone&#xD;
      graft is harvested with curved SafeScraper from the zygomatic buttress. Specially prepared&#xD;
      stainless steel cup are used to estimate 2 cm3 of particulated autogenous bone graft, which&#xD;
      is packed around the inserted implant. In the test group, the sinus is filled with APRF&#xD;
      membrane around the inserted implant. The bony window to the maxillary sinus is covered with&#xD;
      a barrier membrane to seal the opening to the maxillary sinus. Periosteum and mucosa are&#xD;
      sutured with a monofilament 4-0 suture. Minor perforations of sinus membrane will be covered&#xD;
      with a membrane. If the sinus membrane is largely perforated, the procedure will be&#xD;
      cancelled, and the patient will be withdrawn from the study. No provisional restoration is&#xD;
      inserted during the healing period. Patients will be instructed to rinse with 0.12%&#xD;
      chlorhexidine solution twice a day until suture removal has taken place after 7-10 days.&#xD;
      Postoperative medication is outlined in Table I. Patient questionnaire will be filled out&#xD;
      after one week and one month&#xD;
&#xD;
      Abutment surgery After six months of healing, abutment surgery is performed. The implant&#xD;
      stability quotient is measured for all inserted implants. The implant is rinsed with saline&#xD;
      and a prefabricated healing abutment is placed. The implants are manually tested for mobility&#xD;
      and osseointegration by percussion. Mucosa is adapted and sutured with a monofilament 4-0&#xD;
      suture. The prosthetic restoration will be initiated three weeks after the healing abutment&#xD;
      has been placed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prosthetic restoration Prosthetic restoration will include an individualized abutment and a&#xD;
      fixed restoration performed by experienced prosthodontists with extensive clinical experience&#xD;
      with implant-based prosthetics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be scheduled for a postoperative clinical examination at baseline, one year,&#xD;
      three year and five years after loading. The following parameters will be recorded at each&#xD;
      visit:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Plaque and gingival index, probing pocket depth, and probing attachment level.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Oral health related quality of life - OHIP-14.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient satisfaction (VAS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Oral health related quality of life - OHIP-14 and patient satisfaction Oral Health Impact&#xD;
      Profile (OHIP) is a questionnaire designed to measure impairment of oral health related&#xD;
      quality of life and focuses on the frequency of complaints regarding the general dentition&#xD;
      over a course of time. OHIP has been translated to and validated in several languages,&#xD;
      including Danish. However, OHIP states the patient's overall oral impairment, and does not&#xD;
      take a specific treatment site into account. Therefore, additional questionnaire including&#xD;
      VAS may be used to evaluate the area of a missing tooth and/or a tooth replacement. The total&#xD;
      implant treatment, peri-implant soft tissues, implant crown, and implant function at the&#xD;
      follow-up examination will be assessed using a systematic questionnaire. Each question will&#xD;
      be scored on a 100-mm VAS with 0 indicating extreme dissatisfaction and 100 indicating&#xD;
      complete satisfaction. The VAS scores will be measured to the nearest mm by a ruler.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hematological and inflammatory parameters The inflammatory assessment will include six blood&#xD;
      samples obtained at inclusion, intraoperatively, one month postoperatively, at baseline, one&#xD;
      year and five years after functional implant loading. Serum level of high sensitivity CRP&#xD;
      (hsCRP9 (reference value 0-5 mg/L), fibrinogen (reference value 200-400 mg/dL), serum level&#xD;
      of total cholesterol (standard ≤ 190 mg/dL), low-density lipoprotein (LDL-C) (standard ≤ 115&#xD;
      mg/dL), high-density lipoprotein (HDL-C) (standard for men &gt; 40 mg/dL, for women &gt; 46 mg/dL),&#xD;
      leukotriene B4, prostaglandin E2, penetraxin-3, surfactant protein-D and serum levels of&#xD;
      complement components C1, C3 and C9. White blood cell count (WBC) will be determined in blood&#xD;
      from the heparin tube (standard 4.0-11.0 × 103 μL) following fractionation. Moreover, plasma&#xD;
      levels of interleukin (IL)-1beta, IL-6, IL-10, tumor necrosis factor-alfa (TNF-alfa),&#xD;
      transforming growth factor beta-1 (TGF-beta1), receptor activator of nuclear factor kappa-B&#xD;
      ligand (RANKL) and osteoprotegrin (OPG), will be determined from plasma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Radiographical assessment Radiographical evaluation will include seven sets of periapical&#xD;
      radiographs and CBCT (I-Cat, Cone Beam 3-D Imaging System, Imaging Sciences, International&#xD;
      Inc. Hatfield, USA) obtained preoperatively, immediately postoperatively, after abutment&#xD;
      connection, at baseline, one year, three years and five years after loading. To provide&#xD;
      blinding of the radiographical evaluation, the CBCT-scans are coded. Volumetrical changes of&#xD;
      the grafts are estimated by point counting and the method described originally by Cavalieri.&#xD;
      The original outline of the maxillary sinus before implant installation is recorded and&#xD;
      superimposed on the corresponding images. A point grid test system is superimposed at random&#xD;
      on all images, allowing 100-200 points to hit the graft of each maxillary sinus. The numbers&#xD;
      of intersections over the graft are counted on each selected image. Cavalieri volume&#xD;
      estimation principle is used to estimate the total volume of the graft.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Peri-implant marginal bone changes are evaluated by linear measurements on digital periapical&#xD;
      radiographs and will be done on radiographs obtained at implant placement, baseline, 3-years&#xD;
      and 5-years after loading. The distance from the implant-abutment connection to the marginal&#xD;
      bone level will be measured mesially and distally parallel with the long-axis of the implant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data management and analysis, including calculation of sample size Data management and&#xD;
      analysis including calculation of descriptive statistics are done using STATA (Data analysis&#xD;
      and statistical software, version 13, StataCorp P, Texas, USA). A power calculation are based&#xD;
      on differences in marginal bone level changes preformed in a previous study involving&#xD;
      replacement of a single tooth with 2 different protocols of implant treatment.38 The&#xD;
      calculation is based on the observed changes in marginal bone level from insertion of the&#xD;
      implant to abutment connection (a change of 0.65 mm and a standard deviation of 0.65), 17&#xD;
      patients in each group reaches a power of 97% at the 5%-level. With 15% to cover drop-outs,&#xD;
      each treatment group should include 20 patients. The statistical evaluation is performed by&#xD;
      analysis of variance. Scheffe´s multiple comparison test is used post hoc to determine the&#xD;
      relative effect of the various graft types. Level of significance is 0.05.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Well-controlled diabetic patients with indication of sinus floor augmentation to allow placement of a dental implant in the posterior maxilla will be randomized to one of two sinus augmentation protocols: particulated autogenous bone or advanced platelet-rich fibrin</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The outcome assessor will be blinded to which arm the individual participant was treated under</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Implant survival</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Presence of implant at follow-up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Implant survival</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Presence of implant at follow-up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Implant survival</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Presence of implant at follow-up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Volumetrical stability of the graft material</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 3 and 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Augmented volume measeured on CBCT</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peri-implant marginal bone level</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 3 and 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Marginal bone level measured on periapical radiographs</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of implant placement and graft material on hematological and inflammatory parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-surgery, immediately after surgery, Baseline, 1, 3 and 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammatory markers measuered through blood samples</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Jaw, Edentulous, Partially</condition>
  <condition>Diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Particulated autogenous bone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Particulated autogenous bone is considered the gold standard for sinus floor augmentation. The bone will be harvested locally</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Advanced platelet-rich fibrin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Advanced platelet-rich fibrin will be be obtained through a blood sample from the participant</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sinus floor augmentation</intervention_name>
    <description>Sinus floor augmentaion using the lateral window technique</description>
    <arm_group_label>Advanced platelet-rich fibrin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Particulated autogenous bone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥20 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insulin-dependent diabetes with missing posterior maxillary tooth/teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residual bone height of the maxillary alveolar process between 4 and 7 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Width of the alveolar process ≥6.5 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of mandibular occluding teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Plasma glucose levels below 7.8 mmol/l or 140 mg/dl.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindications to implant therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Full mouth plaque score &gt;25%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progressive periodontitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute infection in the area intended for implant placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parafunction, bruxism, or clenching.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric problems or unrealistic expectations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smoking. Previous smoker will not be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Simon S Jensen, Professor</last_name>
    <phone>+4535333052</phone>
    <email>simon.storgaard.jensen@sund.ku.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Thomas Starch-Jensen, Professor</last_name>
    <phone>+4523266370</phone>
    <email>thomas.jensen@rn.dk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aalborg University Hospital, Dept. of Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Surgery</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aalborg</city>
        <zip>9800</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Copenhagen University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen</city>
        <zip>2100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Simon S Jensen, Professor</last_name>
      <phone>04535451700</phone>
      <email>simon.storgaard.jensen@regionh.dk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Copenhagen, School of Dental Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen</city>
        <zip>2100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 13, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Copenhagen</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Simon Storgård Jensen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Implant Dentistry</keyword>
  <keyword>Sinus floor augmentation</keyword>
  <keyword>Autogenous bone</keyword>
  <keyword>Platelet-rich fibrin</keyword>
  <keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Jaw, Edentulous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Jaw, Edentulous, Partially</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

