<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04543383</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CR108769</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-000180-24</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>70033093EDI1001</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04543383</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Assess the Reversal of the Anticoagulant Effects of JNJ-70033093 by 4-Factor Prothrombin Complex Concentrate (4F-PCC) (Part 1) and Recombinant Human Factor VIIa (rFVIIa) (Part 2) in Healthy Participants</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Two-Part, Open-Label, Randomized, Placebo-Controlled, 3-Period Crossover Study to Assess the Reversal of the Anticoagulant Effects of JNJ-70033093 by 4-Factor Prothrombin Complex Concentrate (Part 1) and Recombinant Human Factor VIIa (Part 2) in Healthy Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary purpose of this study is to evaluate the reversal of the anticoagulant effects of&#xD;
      JNJ-70033093 by 4-Factor Prothrombin Complex Concentrate (4F-PCC) and Recombinant Human&#xD;
      Factor VIIa (rFVIIa) in healthy participants as measured by changes from baseline of the&#xD;
      coagulation testing parameters (activated partial thromboplastin time [aPTT] and thrombin&#xD;
      generation assay [TGA]).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Suspended</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Pending further data collection and analysis&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 27, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 28, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 28, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1: Ratio of Postbaseline to Baseline in Activated Partial Thromboplastin Time (aPTT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 56 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Ratio of postbaseline to baseline in activated partial thromboplastin time will be assessed. aPTT measures the time it takes plasma to clot when exposed to substances that activate the contact factors, which assesses the intrinsic and common pathways of coagulation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Ratio of Postbaseline to Baseline in Activated Partial Thromboplastin Time</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 17 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Ratio of postbaseline to baseline in activated partial thromboplastin time will be assessed. aPTT measures the time it takes plasma to clot when exposed to substances that activate the contact factors, which assesses the intrinsic and common pathways of coagulation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1: Ratio of Postbaseline to Baseline in Endogenous Thrombin Potential (ETP) (Thrombin Generation Assay [TGA]) Parameter</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 56 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Ratio of postbaseline to baseline in endogenous thrombin Potential TGA parameter will be assessed. The TGA measures the thrombin generation that is indicative of an overall coagulating capacity. A calibrated automated thrombography is used to monitor the concentration of thrombin in clotting plasma with a fluorogenic substrate. The data derived from the thrombography can be used to determine the ETP (TGA parameter).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Ratio of Postbaseline to Baseline in ETP (TGA Parameter)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 17 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Ratio of postbaseline to baseline in ETP (TGA Parameter) will be assessed. The TGA measures the thrombin generation that is indicative of an overall coagulating capacity. A calibrated automated thrombography is used to monitor the concentration of thrombin in clotting plasma with a fluorogenic substrate. The data derived from the thrombography can be used to determine the ETP (TGA parameter).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1: Ratio of Postbaseline to Baseline in Lag time (TGA Parameter)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 56 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Ratio of postbaseline to baseline in Lag time (TGA Parameter) will be assessed. The TGA measures the thrombin generation that is indicative of an overall coagulating capacity. A calibrated automated thrombography is used to monitor the concentration of thrombin in clotting plasma with a fluorogenic substrate. The data derived from the thrombography can be used to determine the lag time (TGA parameter).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Ratio of Postbaseline to Baseline in Lag time (TGA Parameter)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 17 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Ratio of postbaseline to baseline in lag time (TGA Parameter) will be assessed. The TGA measures the thrombin generation that is indicative of an overall coagulating capacity. A calibrated automated thrombography is used to monitor the concentration of thrombin in clotting plasma with a fluorogenic substrate. The data derived from the thrombography can be used to determine the lag time (TGA parameter).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1: Ratio of Postbaseline to Baseline in Time to Peak Thrombin (TGA Parameter)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 56 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Ratio of postbaseline to baseline in time to peak thrombin (TGA Parameter) will be assessed. The TGA measures the thrombin generation that is indicative of an overall coagulating capacity. A calibrated automated thrombography is used to monitor the concentration of thrombin in clotting plasma with a fluorogenic substrate. The data derived from the thrombography can be used to determine the peak time (TGA parameter).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Ratio of Postbaseline to Baseline in Time to peak Thrombin (TGA Parameter)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 17 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Ratio of postbaseline to baseline in time to peak thrombin (TGA Parameter) will be assessed. The TGA measures the thrombin generation that is indicative of an overall coagulating capacity. A calibrated automated thrombography is used to monitor the concentration of thrombin in clotting plasma with a fluorogenic substrate. The data derived from the thrombography can be used to determine the peak time (TGA parameter).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1: Ratio of Postbaseline to Baseline in Peak Thrombin (TGA parameter)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 56 days</time_frame>
    <description>Ratio of postbaseline to baseline in peak thrombin (TGA parameter) will be assessed. The TGA measures the thrombin generation that is indicative of an overall coagulating capacity. A calibrated automated thrombography is used to monitor the concentration of thrombin in clotting plasma with a fluorogenic substrate. The data derived from the thrombography can be used to determine the peak thrombin (TGA parameter).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Ratio of Postbaseline to Baseline in Peak Thrombin (TGA parameter)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 17 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Ratio of postbaseline to baseline in peak thrombin (TGA parameter) will be assessed. The TGA measures the thrombin generation that is indicative of an overall coagulating capacity. A calibrated automated thrombography is used to monitor the concentration of thrombin in clotting plasma with a fluorogenic substrate. The data derived from the thrombography can be used to determine the peak thrombin (TGA parameter).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Number of Participants with Treatment-Emergent Adverse Events (TEAE) as a Measure of Safety and Tolerability</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 56 Days; Part 2: Up to 17 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with TEAE as a measure of safety and tolerability will be assessed. Any AE occurring at or after the initial administration of study intervention through the day of last dose to be treatment-emergent. An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical study participant administered a medicinal (investigational or non-investigational) product does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the treatment. Therefore, it can be any unfavorable and unintended sign (including an abnormal finding), symptom, or disease temporally associated with the use of a medicinal product, whether or not related to that medicinal product.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Number of Participants with TEAEs of interest</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 56 Days; Part 2: Up to 17 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with TEAEs of interest (liver injury, bleeding and thromboembolic events) will be assessed. Any AE occurring at or after the initial administration of study intervention through the day of last dose to be treatment-emergent. AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical study participant administered a medicinal (investigational or non-investigational) product does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the treatment. Therefore, it can be any unfavorable and unintended sign (including an abnormal finding), symptom, or disease temporally associated with the use of a medicinal product, whether or not related to that medicinal product.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Pulse rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Changes from baseline in pulse rate will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Systolic Blood Pressure (SBP) and Diastolic Blood Pressure (DBP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Changes from baseline in SBP and DBP will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in QTc Interval</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in QT interval corrected for heart rate (QTc interval) using Fridericia method will be measured by ECG.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change from Baseline in Heart Rate (HR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in HR will be measured by ECG.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change from Baseline in QRS Interval</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in QRS interval will be measured by ECG.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change from Baseline in PR Interval</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in PR interval will be measured by ECG.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in QT Interval</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in QT interval will be measured by ECG.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Hematology Parameter: Platelet count</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in hematology parameter (Platelet count) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Hematology Parameter: Red Blood Cell (RBC) count</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in hematology parameter (RBC count [Unit: Cells per liter]) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Hematology Parameter: Hemoglobin (Hb)</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in hematology parameter (Hb [Grams per deciliter]) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Hematology Parameter: Hematocrit</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in hematology parameter (Hematocrit) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Hematology Parameter: Mean Corpuscular Volume (MCV)</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in hematology parameter (MCV [Femtoliter]) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Hematology Parameter: Mean Corpuscular Hemoglobin (MCH)</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in hematology parameter (MCH [Picogram]) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Hematology Parameter: Percentage of Reticulocytes</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in hematology parameter (Percentage of reticulocytes) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Hematology Parameters: Neutrophils, Lymphocytes, Monocytes, Eosinophils and Basophils</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in hematology parameters (Neutrophils, Lymphocytes, Monocytes, Eosinophils and Basophils [Unit: Giga cells per liter]) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline Coagulation Parameter: Activated Partial Thromboplastin Time (aPTT) and Prothrombin Time (PT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in coagulation parameter (aPTT and PT [Unit: Seconds]) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change from Baseline in Serum Chemistry Parameters: Bicarbonate, Calcium, Glucose, Chloride, Magnesium, Phosphate, Sodium, BUN, Cholesterol, HDL, LDL, Triglycerides</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in serum chemistry parameters (Bicarbonate, Calcium, Glucose, Chloride, Magnesium, Phosphate, Sodium, Blood urea nitrogen [BUN], Cholesterol, High density Lipoprotein [HDL], Low density lipoprotein [LDL], Triglycerides [Unit: Millimole per Liter]) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change from Baseline in Serum Chemistry Parameters: ALT, AST, GGT, LDH, Alkaline phosphatase, CPK</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in serum chemistry parameters (Alanine Aminotransferase (ALT), Aspartate Aminotransferase (AST), Gamma-glutamyl transferase (GGT), Lactic acid dehydrogenase (LDH), Alkaline phosphatase, Creatine phosphokinase (CPK) [Unit: International units per Liter]) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change from Baseline in Serum Chemistry Parameters: Amylase</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in serum chemistry parameters (Amylase [Unit: Units per liter]) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change from Baseline in Serum Chemistry Parameters: Lipase</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in serum chemistry parameters (Lipase [Unit: Units per liter]) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change from Baseline in Serum Chemistry Parameters: Total bilirubin, Creatinine and Uric acid</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in serum chemistry parameters (Total bilirubin, Creatinine and Uric acid [Unit: Micromoles per Liter]) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change from Baseline in Serum Chemistry Parameters: Total protein and Albumin</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in serum chemistry parameters (Total protein and Albumin [Unit: Gram per Liter]) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Urinalysis Parameter: Specific gravity</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in urinalysis parameter (Specific gravity) tests will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Urinalysis Parameters: Bilirubin</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in urinalysis parameters (Bilirubin) tests will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Urinalysis Parameters: Nitrite</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in urinalysis parameters (Nitrite) tests will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Urinalysis Parameter: Ketones</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in urinalysis parameter (Ketones) tests will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Urinalysis Parameter: Blood</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in urinalysis parameter (Blood) tests will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Urinalysis Parameter: Protein</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in urinalysis parameter (Protein) tests will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Urinalysis Parameter: Glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in urinalysis parameter (Glucose) tests will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Urinalysis Parameter: pH</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in urinalysis parameter (pH) tests will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Urinalysis Parameter: Urobilinogen</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in urinalysis parameter (Urobilinogen) tests will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Change From Baseline in Urinalysis Parameter: Leukocyte esterase</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Up to 98 Days; Part 2: Up to 59 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in urinalysis parameter (Leukocyte esterase) tests will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Maximum Observed Analyte Concentration (Cmax) of JNJ-70033093</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Predose, 2, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, 24, 48, and 72 hours Postdose; Part 2: Predose, 2, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, and 24 hours Postdose</time_frame>
    <description>Cmax is the maximum observed analyte concentration.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Maximum Observed Analyte Concentration (Cmax) of rFVIIa</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, and 24 hours Postdose</time_frame>
    <description>Cmax is the maximum observed analyte concentration.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Time to Reach Maximum Plasma Concentration (Tmax) of JNJ-70033093</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Predose, 2, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, 24, 48, and 72 hours Postdose; Part 2: Predose, 2, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, and 24 hours Postdose</time_frame>
    <description>Tmax is defined as actual sampling time to reach the maximum observed analyte concentration.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Time to Reach Maximum Plasma Concentration (Tmax) of rFVIIa</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, and 24 hours Postdose</time_frame>
    <description>Tmax is defined as actual sampling time to reach the maximum observed analyte concentration.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Elimination Half-Life (t1/2) of JNJ-70033093</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Predose, 2, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, 24, 48, and 72 hours Postdose; Part 2: Predose, 2, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, and 24 hours Postdose</time_frame>
    <description>t1/2 is elimination half-life is that time measured for the plasma concentration to decrease by 1 half to its original concentration of JNJ-70033093.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Elimination Half-Life (t1/2) of rFVIIa</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, and 24 hours Postdose</time_frame>
    <description>t1/2 is elimination half-life is that time measured for the plasma concentration to decrease by 1 half to its original concentration of rFVIIa.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Area Under the Plasma Concentration-Time Curve From Time Zero to Infinite Time (AUC [0-infinity]) of JNJ-70033093</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Predose, 2, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, 24, 48, and 72 hours Postdose; Part 2: Predose, 2, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, and 24 hours Postdose</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve from time zero to infinity with extrapolation of the terminal phase of JNJ-70033093.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Area Under the Plasma Concentration-Time Curve From Time Zero to Infinite Time (AUC [0-infinity]) of rFVIIa</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, and 24 hours Postdose</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve from time zero to infinity with extrapolation of the terminal phase of rFVIIa.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts 1 and 2: Area Under Plasma Concentration From Time Zero to the Last Quantifiable Concentration (AUC [0-last]) of JNJ-70033093</measure>
    <time_frame>Part 1: Predose, 2, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, 24, 48, and 72 hours Postdose; Part 2: Predose, 2, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, and 24 hours Postdose</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve from time zero to the time corresponding to the last quantifiable concentration of JNJ-70033093 will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Area Under Plasma Concentration From Time Zero to the Last Quantifiable Concentration (AUC [0-last]) of rFVIIa</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, and 24 hours Postdose</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve from time zero to the time corresponding to the last quantifiable concentration of rFVIIa will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Systemic Clearance (CL) of rFVIIa</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, and 24 hours Postdose</time_frame>
    <description>Systemic Clearance (CL) is a quantitative measure of the rate at which a drug substance is removed from the body. The total systemic clearance after intravenous dose will be estimated by dividing the total administered dose by the plasma Area Under the Plasma Concentration-Time Curve From Time Zero to Infinite Time (AUC [0-infinity]).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Volume of distribution (Vz) of rFVIIa</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 4, 4.45, 4.75, 5, 6, 8, 12, and 24 hours Postdose</time_frame>
    <description>The Vz is defined as the theoretical volume in which the total amount of drug would need to be uniformly distributed to produce the desired blood concentration of a drug.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1: Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive a single oral dose of JNJ-70033093 after high fat meal and intravenous (IV) infusion of 4-Factor Prothrombin Complex Concentrate (4F-PCC) or placebo 4 hours after administration of JNJ-70033093 on Day 1 in following treatment sequence: ABC1, BC1A, C1AB, BAC1, C1BA and AC1B in period 1, period 2 and period 3 respectively where, Treatment A= Dose 1 of JNJ-70033093 +Dose 3 of 4F-PCC; Treatment B=Dose 2 of JNJ-70033093+Dose 3 of 4F-PCC; Treatment C1=Dose 2 of JNJ-70033093+Placebo with a washout period of 14 days to 21 days between Day 1 of each study period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1: Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive a single oral dose of JNJ-70033093 after high fat meal and intravenous (IV) infusion of 4-Factor Prothrombin Complex Concentrate (4F-PCC) or placebo 4 hours after administration of JNJ-70033093 on Day 1 in following treatment sequence: ABC2, BC2A, C2AB, BAC2, C2BA and AC2B in period 1, period 2 and period 3 respectively where, Treatment A= Dose 1 of JNJ-70033093 +Dose 3 of 4F-PCC; Treatment B=Dose 2 of JNJ-70033093+Dose 3 of 4F-PCC; Treatment C2=Dose 1 of JNJ-70033093+Placebo with a washout period of 14 days to 21 days between Day 1 of each study period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2: Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive a single oral dose of JNJ-70033093 after high fat meal and IV injection of Recombinant Human Factor VIIa (rFVIIa) or placebo 4 hours after administration of JNJ-70033093 on Day 1 in following treatment sequence: DEF1, EF1D, F1DE, EDF1, F1ED and DF1E in period 1, period 2 and period 3 respectively where, Treatment D=Dose 1 of JNJ-70033093 +Dose 4 of rFVIIa; Treatment E=Dose 2 of JNJ-3093+Dose 4 of rFVIIa; Treatment F1=Dose 2 of JNJ-70033093+Placebo with a washout period of 4 days between Day 1 of each study period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2: Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive a single oral dose of JNJ-70033093 after high fat meal and IV injection of the reversal agent Recombinant Human Factor VIIa (rFVIIa) or placebo 4 hours after administration of JNJ-70033093 on Day 1 in following treatment sequence: DEF2, EF2D, F2DE, EDF2, F2ED and DF2E in period 1, period 2 and period 3 respectively where, Treatment D=Dose 1 of JNJ-70033093 +Dose 4 of rFVIIa; Treatment E=Dose 2 of JNJ-70033093 +Dose 4 of rFVIIa; Treatment F2=Dose 1 of JNJ-70033093 +Placebo with a washout period of 4 days between Day 1 of each study period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>JNJ-70033093</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive a single oral dose of JNJ-70033093 on Day 1 in two of the 3 periods.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1: Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1: Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2: Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2: Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BMS-986177</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>4-Factor Prothrombin Complex Concentrate (4F-PCC)</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive IV infusion of 4-Factor Prothrombin Complex Concentrate (4F-PCC) on Day 1 in two of the 3 periods.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1: Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1: Group 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Recombinant Human Factor VIIa (rFVIIa)</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive IV injection of rFVIIa on Day 1 in two of the 3 periods.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2: Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2: Group 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo matching to 4F-PCC</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive placebo matching to 4F-PCC on Day 1 of one of the 3 study periods.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1: Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1: Group 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo matching to rFVIIa</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive placebo matching to rFVIIa on Day 1 of one of the 3 study periods.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2: Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2: Group 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must be healthy on the basis of medical history, physical examination,&#xD;
             vital signs, electrocardiogram (ECG), and laboratory test results, including serum&#xD;
             chemistry, lipid profiles (LDL, high-density lipoprotein [HDL], apolipoprotein B and&#xD;
             lipoprotein a), levels of protein C, protein S and antithrombin, fibrinogen, factors&#xD;
             VIIIc, IXc, Xc, XIc and blood coagulation (activated partial thromboplastin time&#xD;
             [aPTT], prothrombin time [PT]) measured at local laboratory, hematology and urinalysis&#xD;
             performed at screening. If abnormalities or deviations from normal are observed, they&#xD;
             must be of no clinical significance in the opinion of the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Before randomization, a woman must either be: Not of childbearing potential defined&#xD;
             as: Postmenopausal-A postmenopausal state is defined as no menses for 12 months&#xD;
             without an alternative medical cause. A high follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) level&#xD;
             greater than (&gt;) 40 International Units Per Liter (IU/L) or milli-international units&#xD;
             per milliliter (mIU/mL) in the postmenopausal range) may be used to confirm a&#xD;
             postmenopausal state in women, however, in the absence of 12 months of amenorrhea, a&#xD;
             single FSH measurement is insufficient; Permanently sterile- Permanent sterilization&#xD;
             methods include hysterectomy, bilateral salpingectomy, bilateral tubal&#xD;
             occlusion/ligation procedures, and bilateral oophorectomy. Of childbearing potential,&#xD;
             a woman must have an intrauterine device without estrogen- and or&#xD;
             progestogen-containing system, or have vasectomized partner or practice sexual&#xD;
             abstinence, agrees to remain on the above highly effective contraceptive method&#xD;
             throughout the study and for at least 90 days after the last dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A male participant must wear a condom when engaging in any activity with a woman of&#xD;
             childbearing potential during the study and for the duration of treatment with&#xD;
             JNJ-70033093 plus 5 half-lives of the study drug for a total of 94 days after the&#xD;
             completion of treatment. Male participants should also be advised of the benefit for a&#xD;
             female partner to use a highly effective method of contraception because condom may&#xD;
             break or leak&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If a woman, must have a negative highly sensitive serum (Beta-human chorionic&#xD;
             gonadotropin [Beta-hCG]) pregnancy test at screening and urine (Beta-hCG) pregnancy&#xD;
             test on Day -1 of each study period (Part 1) or on Day -1 of Period 1 (Part 2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women must have no history of excessive menstrual bleeding or hemorrhage following&#xD;
             pregnancy delivery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A male participant must agree not to donate sperm for the purpose of reproduction&#xD;
             during the study and for 94 days after receiving the last dose of study intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI; weight (kilogram [kg]/height^2 [meter {m}]^2) body weight not&#xD;
             less than 50 kg and not more than 100 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or family history of any known illness that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator, might confound the results of the study or pose an additional risk in&#xD;
             administering study drug to the participant or that could prevent, limit or confound&#xD;
             the protocol specified assessments. This may include but is not limited to any known&#xD;
             bleeding or clotting disorder, cardiolipin antibody and anti-beta2-glycoprotein I,&#xD;
             abnormal levels of fibrinogen, factors VIIIc, IXc, Xc, XIc, inherited or acquired&#xD;
             thrombophilia, bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy, excessive bruising, bleeding from&#xD;
             nose or gums or known disorders with increased bleeding risk, serious bleeding&#xD;
             including gastrointestinal bleeding requiring hospitalization, intracranial bleeding&#xD;
             of any type, or uncontrollable postoperative bleeding, a history of arterial or venous&#xD;
             thrombosis, phlebitis, inherited or acquired thrombophilia, known family history of&#xD;
             unexplained thrombotic disorders, known intracranial or intraabdominal tumor,&#xD;
             hemorrhage, or aneurysm, liver or renal dysfunction, clinically significant cardiac,&#xD;
             vascular disorders, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, endocrine, neurologic, hematologic,&#xD;
             rheumatologic, psychiatric, neoplastic abnormalities, or metabolic disturbances, or&#xD;
             poor venous access&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of drug or alcohol abuse according to Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of&#xD;
             Mental Disorders criteria within 1 year before screening or positive test result(s)&#xD;
             for alcohol and/or drugs of abuse (such as hallucinogens [lysergic acid diethylamide&#xD;
             [LSD]), barbiturates, opiates, opioids, cocaine, cannabinoids, amphetamines, and&#xD;
             benzodiazepines) at screening and/or on Day -1 of Period 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have laboratory values at screening or Day -1 of Period 1 above or below limits of&#xD;
             normal that in the investigator's judgment may affect the safety of the participants&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following laboratory results outside of the ranges specified below at&#xD;
             screening or on Day -1 of Period 1, confirmed by repeat: Hemoglobin or hematocrit &lt;&#xD;
             lower limit of normal, Platelet count &lt; lower limit of normal, aPTT, or PT &gt; ULN,&#xD;
             Low-density lipoprotein (LDL), High-density lipoprotein (HDL), apolipoprotein B, or&#xD;
             lipoprotein a, outside the normal reference ranges, Factor II gene mutation or Factor&#xD;
             V Leiden mutation assessed by polymerase chain reaction (PCR) tests, positive for&#xD;
             Lupus Anticoagulants (LA screen, confirm and Silica Clotting Time [SCT]), cardiolipin&#xD;
             antibody and anti-beta2-glycoprotein I, abnormal levels of protein C, protein S,&#xD;
             antithrombin, fibrinogen, factors VIIIc, IXc, Xc, XIc&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following on 12-lead ECG based on an average of triplicate measurements at&#xD;
             screening or Day -1 of Period 1: PR greater than or equal to (&gt;=) 210 msec, QRS &gt;=120&#xD;
             msec, QTcF&gt;=450 msec for male and &gt;=470 msec for female, Heart Rate (HR) &gt;= 100 bpm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of any significant drug allergy (such as anaphylaxis or hepatotoxicity) and&#xD;
             known allergy to the study drugs or any of the excipients of the formulations. History&#xD;
             of allergy to or unwillingness to consume any component of high-fat breakfast menu to&#xD;
             be provided in this study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>54 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC Clinical Trial</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>PRA Health Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Groningen</city>
        <zip>NZ 9728</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 3, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Thrombin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data sharing policy of the Janssen Pharmaceutical Companies of Johnson &amp; Johnson is available at www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency. As noted on this site, requests for access to the study data can be submitted through Yale Open Data Access (YODA) Project site at yoda.yale.edu</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

