<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04545853</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MEP_PC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04545853</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Associations Between Pain Perceptions and Movement-evoked Pain.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Associations Between Pain Perceptions and Movement-evoked Pain: a Cross-sectional Study.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vrije Universiteit Brussel</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vrije Universiteit Brussel</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to investigate the associations between pain cognitions and&#xD;
      movement-evoked pain in people with musculoskeletal pain complaints.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will investigate the associations between pain cognitions and movement-evoked pain&#xD;
      in people with musculoskeletal pain complaints. This study will be carried out as a&#xD;
      cross-sectional study. Participants will be recruited by means of flyers and social media.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pain cognitions will be assessed using questionnaires (The Pain Catastrophizing Scale (PCS),&#xD;
      The llness perception questionnaire-revised (IPQ-R), The Pain Vigilance and Awareness&#xD;
      Questionnaire (PVAQ), The Tampa Scale for Kinesiophobia (TSK), The 36-item short form health&#xD;
      survey (SF-36)), whilst movement-evoked pain will be assessed using a lifting task.&#xD;
      Participants will need to rate the experienced pain immediately after completing the task. To&#xD;
      estimate the extent to which pain cognitions explain movement-evoked pain, correlational&#xD;
      analyses will first be conducted between all variables to determine what variables will be&#xD;
      included in the hierarchical regression analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Movement-evoked pain</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed only once at baseline.</time_frame>
    <description>Pain that is experienced in response to a physical task. Participants will perform a lifting task. Participants will be asked to lift a series of 19-canisters that will be arranged in a standardized pattern on a waist-high table. Participants will provide a pain rating on a 11 points Numeric Rating Scale (NRS) with the endpoints no pain&quot; (0) and &quot;excruciating pain&quot; (10)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Illness perceptions</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed only once at baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The illness perception questionnaire-revised (IPQ-R) will be used to measure patients' illness perceptions. In the first domain, called illness identity, the perceived symptoms and their possible relation to the illness are evaluated. In this study, participants will indicate whether or not they believe that a specific symptom is related to pain (&quot;yes&quot; or &quot;no&quot;). The second domain, the beliefs domain, covers 7 dimensions: the acute/chronic timeline, the cyclical character of the illness, the consequences, controllability, curability, emotional representations and illness coherence. The third domain lists 18 possible causes to which individuals attribute their condition, the degree to which individuals perceive themselves as responsible for the illness, as well as the responsibility individuals take for curing themselves. For each item in the second and third domain, patients rate their level of agreement on a 5-point Likert scale, ranging from &quot;strongly disagree&quot; to &quot;strongly agree&quot;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain catastrophizing</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed only once at baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The Pain Catastrophizing Scale (PCS) is a questionnaire to objectify catastrophic thinking about pain. It consists of 13 items describing different thoughts and feelings that individuals may have when experiencing pain. Items are scored on a 5-point scale. A general score and scores on 3 subscales (i.e., helplessness (6 items), magnification (3 items), and rumination (4items)) will be obtained; higher scores indicate more severe catastrophic thoughts about pain</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Attention to pain</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed only once at baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The Pain Vigilance and Awareness Questionnaire (PVAQ) will be used to investigate patients' attention to pain. It is a 16-item measure of attention to pain that assesses awareness, consciousness, vigilance, and observation of pain. Scores range from 0 to 80 and high scores correspond to hypervigilance for pain.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fear of injury due to movement</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed only once at baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The Tampa Scale for Kinesiophobia (TSK) is a 17-item questionnaire that will be used to measure the fear of (re) injury due to movement. Scores range from 17 to 68, with scores ≤ 37 suggesting low fear of movement and scores &gt; 37 indicating high fear of movement.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed only once at baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The 36-item short form health survey (SF-36) is a multidimensional generic questionnaire assessing quality of life, which consists of 8 dimensions: physical functioning (10 items), role constraint caused by physical health problems (4 items), bodily pain (2 items), general health (5 items), vitality (4 items), social functioning (2 items), role constraint caused by emotional problems (3 items) and mental health (5 items). Higher scores reflecting a better health condition</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Musculoskeletal Pain</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants will be recruited by flyers at the University Hospital Brussels, social media.&#xD;
        Prior to inviting the eligible participants, the presence of musculoskeletal pain will be&#xD;
        confirmed by phone in order to proceed to the informed consent process. Musculoskeletal&#xD;
        pain is defined as pain, that potential participants report, feeling in the muscles, joints&#xD;
        or bones. This pain can be localized, regional, or widespread.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years or older,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  presence of musculoskeletal pain for more than three months,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  medically stable (no serious health conditions, no pending surgery or invasive medical&#xD;
             procedure, no contraindication to physical activity).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of co-existing pain conditions of other origins with chronic musculoskeletal&#xD;
             pain not being the primary condition (i.e. predominant subject of symptom complaints)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe underlying comorbidity (like diagnosed diabetes, cardiovascular problems, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnant or given birth in the preceding year.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 4, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 28, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 28, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Vrije Universiteit Brussel</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lynn Leemans</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

