<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04541030</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999920136</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>20-C-N136</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04541030</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Integrated Genomic Prostate Score With MRI Targeted Prostate Biopsies</brief_title>
  <official_title>UAB-NCI Collaborative Study on Integrating Genomic Prostate Score With MRI Targeted Prostate Biopsies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prostate cancer is one of the most common cancers in men. For some men, their cancer is&#xD;
      monitored. Others have surgery to remove the prostate. Focal therapy is another treatment&#xD;
      option. It treats the areas of cancer selectively, which leaves the rest of the prostate&#xD;
      intact. This can help lessen side effects. Men who get focal therapy must be chosen&#xD;
      carefully. The Oncotype DX Genomic Prostate Score (GPS) assay tests biopsy samples for&#xD;
      certain cancer-related genes. It then then gives a score from 1 to 100 to predict the&#xD;
      likelihood of poor outcomes. The GPS is used to choose men for focal therapy. Researchers&#xD;
      want to test the GPS further.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess how GPS may be useful when used with MRI to improve how men are chosen for focal&#xD;
      therapy of prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Men age 18 and older who had NCCN low or intermediate risk prostate cancer and had MRI and&#xD;
      radical prostatectomy at the Urologic Oncology Branch, National Cancer Institute and&#xD;
      collaborating centers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a multisite study. It will review data and samples that were collected in the past.&#xD;
      Samples and images from up to 277 participants will be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tumor tissue will be tested with the GPS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data such as age at diagnosis, race, biopsy results, and pathology results will be merged&#xD;
      with the GPS results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be entered into an in-house electronic system. It will be password protected. All&#xD;
      data will be kept in secure sites that comply with NIH security standards.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Prostate cancer is one of the most common malignancies occurring in men. While many men&#xD;
           will qualify for active surveillance (AS), those with intermediate risk disease are&#xD;
           often recommended definitive therapy despite the morbidity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Focal therapy for prostate cancer has been promoted as an alternative to the standard&#xD;
           paradigm of immediate radical prostatectomy (RP) versus AS for prostate cancer&#xD;
           management. Focal therapy treats the areas of cancer selectively, leaving the remainder&#xD;
           of the prostate intact.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  While focal therapy offers great promise in terms of minimizing side effects and helping&#xD;
           prostate cancer patients avoid radical therapies, careful patient selection is required.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The Oncotype DX Genomic Prostate Score (GPS) assay was developed using the ability to&#xD;
           extract and amplify RNA of sufficient quantity and quality from the very small amounts&#xD;
           of prostate tumor tissue from biopsy samples. Using these samples, a discovery study&#xD;
           identified 12 cancerrelated genes associated with multiple clinically relevant endpoints&#xD;
           including adverse pathology, biochemical recurrence, clinical recurrence, and prostate&#xD;
           cancer associated death.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The GPS assay uses these 12 genes and 5 reference genes to construct an algorithm giving&#xD;
           a score from 0-100 to predict the likelihood of adverse pathology.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The goal of this study is to evaluate how GPS may be useful in conjunction with MRI to&#xD;
           improve patient selection for focal therapy of prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      -To determine if there is a positive association between continuous GPS score and occult high&#xD;
      risk and/or non-organ confined disease on whole mount prostatectomy specimens where an MRI&#xD;
      was performed less than 6 months before diagnostic biopsy, and the biopsy was less than 6&#xD;
      months before RP and the lesion was not identified on multiparameter MRI (mpMRI)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Samples and images from men, over 18 years old, who were diagnosed with NCCN low or&#xD;
           intermediate risk prostate cancer and were managed with radical prostatectomy at the&#xD;
           Urologic Oncology Branch, National Cancer Institute and collaborating centers&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Biopsy Gleason Score &lt;= 7&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Multiparametric MRI, with images available for review, within 6 months prior to the&#xD;
           prostatectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Availability of adequate diagnostic biopsy tissue specimen for GPS analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This multisite study will be a prospective analysis of retrospective data.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Samples and images will be obtained from will consist of approximately 277 evaluable&#xD;
           patients who were diagnosed with NCCN low or intermediate risk prostate cancer and were&#xD;
           managed with RP at the Urologic Oncology Branch, National Cancer Institute and&#xD;
           collaborating centers.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In the interest of a demographically diverse cohort, samples and images from patients&#xD;
           from UAB will be identified, working in reverse chronological order until the cohort is&#xD;
           complete or eligible specimens are exhausted; remaining cases will then be selected from&#xD;
           the NCI patient population, also working in reverse chronological order.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Tumor tissue from the highest-grade lesion will be tested with the Oncotype DX Genomic&#xD;
           Prostate Scor for generation of the GPS.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Clinical characteristics including but not limited to age at diagnosis, race, PSA,&#xD;
           biopsy results, Prostate MRI PIRADS score, and surgical pathology results will be&#xD;
           collected and merged with GPS results.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 2, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>relationship between continuous GPS score and occult high-risk disease</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 years</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if there is a positive relationship between continuous GPS score and occult high-risk disease on whole mount prostatectomy specimens where an MRI was performed less than 6 months before diagnostic biopsy, and the biopsy was less than 6 months before RP and the lesion was not identified on mpMRI</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>distributions of clinical, pathological and demographic variables</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 years</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the distributions of clinical, pathological and demographic variables for the Genomic Health, Inc. (GHI) study cohort with all the eligible samples from patients in the participating institutions databases</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">286</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>GPS Cohort 1</arm_group_label>
    <description>Samples and images from up to 277 evaluable patients diagnosed with NCCN low or intermediate risk prostate cancer, Gleason &lt;= 7, managed with RP, and mpMRI within 6 months prior to prostatectomy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Samples from male patients with NCCN low or intermediate risk disease managed with radical&#xD;
        prostatectomy (multiparametric MRI (mpMRI) performed within 6 months prior to the&#xD;
        prostatectomy indicating localized, organ confined disease and adequate diagnostic biopsy&#xD;
        tissue specimen).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Samples and images from men &gt; =18 with NCCN very low, low, or intermediate risk&#xD;
             prostate cancer with tumor tissue that meet the pathologic tissue requirements of the&#xD;
             Oncotype DX Genomic Prostate Score assay&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biopsy Gleason Score 7 or lower within 6 months preceding radical prostatectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  3Tesla MRI with/without coil performed within 6 months preceding diagnostic biopsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Availability of diagnostic biopsy&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any active therapy received for prostate cancer (e.g., hormonal treatment, radiation,&#xD;
             chemotherapy, biologic agents, surgery) prior to radical prostatectomy. 5 alpha&#xD;
             reductase inhibitor treatment will not be considered to be hormonal treatment for this&#xD;
             definition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men with NCCN high risk or very high-risk prostate cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biopsy Gleason 8&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No biopsy tissue available&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Missing surgical pathology whole mount, or unwilling to send surgical pathology whole&#xD;
             mount to NCI for review&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Missing diagnostic PSA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Missing clinical T stage&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known lymph node positive or metastatic disease at time of diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Missing MRI 6 months before diagnostic biopsy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Peter A Pinto, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama at Birmingham</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35294</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 12, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 5, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Gleason Score</keyword>
  <keyword>Multiparameter MRI</keyword>
  <keyword>Focal Therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

