<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04543201</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UBRT21040</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04543201</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Telehealth Visits to Discuss Advanced Directives for Patients Newly Diagnosed With High Grade Glioma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Early Telehealth Visits for Discussion of Advanced Directives for Patients Newly Diagnosed With High Grade Glioma: Impact on Patient Care and Satisfaction</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Rochester</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Rochester</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      High grade gliomas (HGGs) are rapidly progressive brain tumors resulting in death for most&#xD;
      patients between 6 months and 2 years after diagnosis. It is important for patients with HGG&#xD;
      to discuss and document their wishes at the end of life. However, many of these patients&#xD;
      experience early changes in cognition which impede their decision-making. For this reason,&#xD;
      these patients should have early discussions with their providers. However, implementation of&#xD;
      this remains challenging in clinical practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, we will create an Early STructured Advanced care Referrals by Telehealth&#xD;
      (Early START) visit for patients soon after their initial oncology visit. A checklist and&#xD;
      pre-visit guide were developed to help guide the visit for both the provider and patient.&#xD;
      Providers will receive special training in running these visits. Caregivers and/or family&#xD;
      members will be encouraged to participate. Visits will be done using video or telephone and&#xD;
      recorded. For patients who do not have access to technology for these visits, it will be&#xD;
      provided. After the visit, patients, caregivers and/or family who participated, and providers&#xD;
      will fill out surveys to address feasibility of having these extra visits and improve the&#xD;
      visits for future. Patients will be followed until death. Caregivers and/or family who&#xD;
      participated will be asked about whether end of life was in line with the patient's wishes.&#xD;
      We will also use the patient's medical record to assess other aspects of end of life. We will&#xD;
      compare end of life outcomes with other similar patients treated at our center.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      High grade gliomas (HGGs) are rapidly progressive brain tumors resulting in death for most&#xD;
      patients between 6 months and 2 years after diagnosis. Discussion and documentation of an&#xD;
      advance care plan are needed to achieve end of life goals that are concordant with a&#xD;
      patient's wishes. Early cognitive dysfunction in brain tumor patients can impede patients&#xD;
      from making decisions about their own care. Patients with HGG, therefore require discussion&#xD;
      and documentation of end of life goals early in their disease course, but implementation of&#xD;
      this has been elusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, we will integrate an Early STructured Advanced care Referrals by Telehealth&#xD;
      (Early START) visit into standard neuro-oncologic care prior to initiation of adjuvant&#xD;
      chemotherapy in patients with HGG. Multi-disciplinary providers including physicians,&#xD;
      advanced practice providers, and nurses will undergo an in-service by palliative care experts&#xD;
      to perform Early START with a standardized checklist followed by periodic training sessions.&#xD;
      Fifty patients with HGG will be enrolled over a 12-month period. They will receive a&#xD;
      pre-visit educational guide to increase literacy regarding advance directives (AD) followed&#xD;
      by a provider-led Early START visit that will be recorded. Post-visit assessments will&#xD;
      address patient and caregiver perspectives on the intervention, patient and caregiver&#xD;
      knowledge, patient satisfaction and patient-reported anxiety measures. A provider&#xD;
      questionnaire will assess length of visit, adherence to the checklist and AD outcomes of the&#xD;
      visit. Patients will be followed until death. End of life quality measures and concordance of&#xD;
      death with goals of care will be assessed using a combination of caregiver surveys and the&#xD;
      electronic medical record. These outcomes will be compared to historical controls treated at&#xD;
      our center from 2010-2015.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1a. To determine the effectiveness of Early START as measured by AD documentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1b. To determine the utility of Early START as measured by timing of hospice enrollment&#xD;
      at the end of life and place of death concordant with the patient's goals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: As our primary aim, we hypothesize that Early START will increase the percentage&#xD;
      of AD documentation by the 3rd oncology visit from 51% to 80%. As secondary outcomes, we&#xD;
      hypothesize that it will decrease the percentage of AD that are completed by proxy from 45%&#xD;
      to 25%, will improve end of life quality measures as compared to our published historical&#xD;
      controls and that the majority of patients who undergo Early START will die in a setting of&#xD;
      their choosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2a. To demonstrate the feasibility of Early START as measured by the percent of visits&#xD;
      completed prior to the third oncology visit, adherence to a pre-specified checklist, and&#xD;
      length of time to complete the visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2b. To optimize the Early START intervention by incorporating patient/caregiver and&#xD;
      provider feedback.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: We hypothesize that 80% of visits will be completed using telehealth by the 3rd&#xD;
      oncology visit, 80% of providers will utilize the pre-specified checklist and that average&#xD;
      visit duration will be less than one hour.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 26, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 19, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 26, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Advanced Directive Completion Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of diagnosis to 3rd oncology visit at an average of 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of patients who complete an advanced directive by the third oncology visit</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Early START visit completion</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of diagnosis to 3rd oncology visit at an average of 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of Early START (Early STructured Advanced care Referrals by Telehealth) visits completed by the third oncology visit</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Checklist use</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of Early START visit [on average between 3-4 months after diagnosis]</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of providers who use the checklist</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of visit</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of visit [average 60 min]</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of time in minutes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Advanced Care Directive Completion by patient vs proxy</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of diagnosis to death up to 5 years after registration</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of completed Advanced Care Directives completed by proxy (rather than by the patient)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Chemotherapy use at end of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of diagnosis to death up to 5 years after registration</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of patients that were treated with chemotherapy within 14 days of death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospice enrollment</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of diagnosis to death up to 5 years after registration</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of patients who were enrolled in hospice &gt;7 days prior to death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Palliative care and/or hospice involvement at end of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of diagnosis to death up to 5 years after registration</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of patients who received a palliative care or hospice consult prior to death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Setting of end of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of diagnosis to death up to 5 years after registration</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of patients for whom setting of death was consistent with their wishes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Glioma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Early STructured Advanced care Referrals by Telehealth</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Early START visit using checklist over telephone or zoom:&#xD;
A telehealth visit conducted within 4 months of patient diagnosis, with the goal of encouraging patients to discuss and document their end-of-life wishes prior to the onset of cognitive impediments common among patients with late-stage high grade glioma.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Early START visit using checklist over telephone or zoom</intervention_name>
    <description>Prior to visit subject receives pre-visit educational guide and copy of advance directive form&#xD;
Follow up surveys:&#xD;
Immediate: provider feedback survey&#xD;
2-4 weeks after visit: subject feedback survey and caregiver/family feedback survey&#xD;
After subject death: caregiver/family survey</description>
    <arm_group_label>Early STructured Advanced care Referrals by Telehealth</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New pathologic diagnosis of WHO grade III or IV glioma within four months of consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe cognitive dysfunction or aphasia precluding discussion of advanced care&#xD;
             planning issues&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sara Hardy, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Rochester</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sara Hardy, MD</last_name>
    <phone>585-273-4096</phone>
    <email>Sara_Hardy@URMC.rochester.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jennifer Serventi, NP</last_name>
    <email>Jennifer_Serventi@URMC.rochester.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Rochester</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>14642</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jessica Ellis</last_name>
      <phone>585-275-2224</phone>
      <email>Sara_Hardy@URMC.Rochester.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Rochester</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sara J Hardy</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

