<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04540744</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CR108794</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-000566-42</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>67896062PAH1001</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04540744</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Macitentan/Tadalafil Combination Administered a Fixed-dose Combination Formulation Compared to the Reference Free Combination of Macitentan and Tadalafil</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Single-center, Open-label, Single-dose, Randomized, 2-way Crossover Phase 1 Study in Healthy Adult Participants to Assess the Relative Oral Bioavailability of the Combination of Macitentan/Tadalafil (10 mg/20 mg) Administered a Fixed-dose Combination Formulation Compared to the Reference Free Combination of 10 mg Macitentan (Opsumit®) and 20 mg Tadalafil (Adcirca®)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to assess the rate and extent of absorption of macitentan and&#xD;
      tadalafil following administration of a single oral dose of a fixed-dose combination (FDC) of&#xD;
      10 milligram (mg)/20 mg macitentan/tadalafil (test), compared to the coadministration as a&#xD;
      free combination (reference) of 10 mg macitentan and 20 mg tadalafil under fasted conditions&#xD;
      in healthy adult participants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 8, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Observed Plasma Analyte Concentration (Cmax) of Macitentan, its Metabolite ACT-132577, and Tadalafil</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose and up to 216 hours post dose (Up to Day 10)</time_frame>
    <description>Cmax is defined as maximum observed plasma analyte concentration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Concentration-time Curve from Time Zero to the Last Quantifiable Concentration (AUC [0-last]) of Macitentan, its Metabolite ACT-132577, and Tadalafil</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose and up to 216 hours post dose (Up to Day 10)</time_frame>
    <description>AUC(0-last) is the area under the plasma analyte concentration-time curve from time zero to time of the last quantifiable (non-below quantification limit [non-BQL]) concentration, calculated by linear-linear trapezoidal summation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Concentration-time Curve from Time Zero to Infinity (AUC [0-infinity]) of Macitentan, its Metabolite ACT-132577, and Tadalafil</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose and up to 216 hours post dose (Up to Day 10)</time_frame>
    <description>AUC (0-infinity) is the area under the analyte concentration-time curve (AUC) from time zero to infinite time, calculated as the sum of AUC (0-last) and C(last)/lambda(z); wherein AUC (0-last) is area under the plasma concentration-time curve from time zero to last measurable concentration, C(last) is the last observed measurable (non-BQL) analyte concentration; and lambda(z) is apparent terminal elimination rate constant.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Adverse Events as a Measure of Safety and Tolerability</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical event that occurs in a participant administered an investigational product, and it does not necessarily indicate only events with clear causal relationship with the relevant investigational product.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">18</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Sequence AB</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive a single oral dose of fixed dose combination (FDC) of macitentan/tadalafil (10 milligram [mg]/20 mg) in fasted conditions (test) (Treatment A) in treatment period 1 followed by a single oral dose of a free combination of 10 mg macitentan and 20 mg tadalafil in fasted conditions (reference) (Treatment B) in treatment period 2 on Day 1. Study drug intake in subsequent treatment periods in an individual participant will be separated by a washout period of at least 10 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Sequence BA</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive Treatment B in treatment period 1 followed by Treatment A in treatment period 2 on Day 1. Study drug intake in subsequent treatment periods in an individual participant will be separated by a washout period of at least 10 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>FDC of macitentan/tadalafil (10 mg/20 mg)</intervention_name>
    <description>FDC of macitentan/tadalafil (10 mg/20 mg) tablet will be administered orally as per assigned treatment sequence.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Sequence AB</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Sequence BA</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Opsumit</other_name>
    <other_name>Adcirca</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Macitentan 10 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>Macitentan 10 mg tablet will be administered orally as a free combination as per assigned treatment sequence.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Sequence AB</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Sequence BA</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Opsumit</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tadalafil 20 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>Tadalafil 20 mg tablet will be administered orally as a free combination as per assigned treatment sequence.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Sequence AB</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Sequence BA</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Adcirca</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must sign an informed consent form (ICF) indicating they understand the purpose of,&#xD;
             and procedures required for, the study and are willing to participate in the study,&#xD;
             before starting any screening activities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI; weight [kg]/height^2 [m]^2) between 18.5 and 30.0 kilogram per&#xD;
             meter square (kg/m^2) inclusive, and body weight not less than 50.0 kg at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy on the basis of physical examination, medical and surgical history, performed&#xD;
             at screening. If there are abnormalities, the participant may be included only if the&#xD;
             investigator judges the abnormalities to be not clinically significant. This&#xD;
             determination must be recorded in the participant's source documents and initialed by&#xD;
             the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systolic blood pressure (SBP) between 100 and 145 millimeter of Mercury (mmHg)&#xD;
             (inclusive) and diastolic blood pressure (DBP) between 50 and 90 mmHg (inclusive) at&#xD;
             screening, preferably measured on the right arm, supine after 5 minutes of rest and&#xD;
             standing after 3 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Twelve-lead electrocardiogram (ECG) with heart rate between 45 and 90 beats per minute&#xD;
             (bpm) and without clinically relevant abnormalities, at the discretion of the&#xD;
             investigator, measured after the participant is supine for at least 5 minutes, at&#xD;
             screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  During the study (from the day of first study drug intake onwards) and for a minimum&#xD;
             of 1 spermatogenesis cycle (defined as approximately 90 days) after the last study&#xD;
             drug intake, a male participant must agree: (a) to wear a condom when engaging in any&#xD;
             activity that allows for passage of ejaculate to another person (male participant&#xD;
             should also be advised of the benefit for a female partner to use a highly effective&#xD;
             method of contraception as condom may break or leak); (b) not to donate sperm for the&#xD;
             purpose of reproduction.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Contraceptive use by men or women should be consistent with local regulations regarding the&#xD;
        use of contraceptive methods for participants participating in clinical studies&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participant who is breastfeeding at screening and/or plans to breastfeed&#xD;
             throughout the study until 30 days after last study drug intake&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergies, hypersensitivity, or intolerance to any active substance or drugs of&#xD;
             the same class, or any excipient of the drug formulation(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Values of hepatic aminotransferase (alanine aminotransferase and/or aspartate&#xD;
             aminotransferase) greater than (&gt;)1.5 * upper limit of normal at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any loss of vision (permanent or transient blindness in 1 or both eyes, including&#xD;
             ophthalmic migraine, transient ischemic attack, retinal artery/vein thrombosis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hereditary degenerative retinal disorders, including retinitis pigmentosa&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC Clinical Trial</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Pharmacology Unit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Merksem</city>
        <zip>2170</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://pam.sylogent.com/cr/CR108794</url>
    <description>To learn how to participate in this trial please click here.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 7, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tadalafil</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Macitentan</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data sharing policy of the Janssen Pharmaceutical Companies of Johnson &amp; Johnson is available at www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency. As noted on this site, requests for access to the study data can be submitted through Yale open Data Access (YODA) Project site at yoda.yale.edu</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

