<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04542473</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>OxTREC 43-20</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04542473</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pancreatic Enzymes and Bile Acids in Acutely Ill Severely Malnourished Children</brief_title>
  <acronym>PB-SAM</acronym>
  <official_title>Pancreatic Enzymes and Bile Acids: A Non-Antibiotic Approach to Treat Intestinal Dysbiosis in Acutely Ill Severely Malnourished Children</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Oxford</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Amsterdam</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Toronto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Washington</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Oregon Health and Science University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Kenya Medical Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Queen Elizabeth Central Hospital, Blantyre, Malawi</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Makerere University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>KEMRI-Wellcome Trust Collaborative Research Program</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangladesh</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Oxford</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Children with severe malnutrition who are sick and admitted to hospitals have high mortality,&#xD;
      usually because of infection. Malnourished children have more potentially harmful bacteria in&#xD;
      their upper intestines than well-nourished children and this may contribute to inflammation&#xD;
      in the gut and whole body. These bacteria may cross from the intestines to the bloodstream&#xD;
      causing life-threatening infections. A related abnormality among malnourished children is&#xD;
      reduction in the digestive enzymes made by the pancreas and the liver. Apart from helping&#xD;
      with digestion of food, these enzymes are important in helping the body control bacteria in&#xD;
      the upper intestines. It is therefore possible that treatment with digestive enzymes could&#xD;
      help reduce the burden of harmful bacteria and thus lower inflammation and the risk of&#xD;
      serious infection. One study conducted in Malawi has shown that children with severe&#xD;
      malnutrition who were supplemented with pancreatic enzymes had a lower risk of dying.&#xD;
      However, this was a small study and although promising, requires validation. No studies of&#xD;
      supplementation with bile acids have been done among severely malnourished children. However,&#xD;
      bile acids are commonly used to manage patients with liver function abnormalities, something&#xD;
      that malnourished children suffer from as well. The investigators want to find out if&#xD;
      supplementing these pancreatic enzymes and bile acids among ill children with severe acute&#xD;
      malnutrition is safe and reduces the risk of death, deterioration or readmission to hospital.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Severely malnourished children who present with an acute illness have a high risk of&#xD;
      mortality. Severe malnutrition is associated with intestinal inflammation and changes in the&#xD;
      fecal microbiome ('dysbiosis'). Apart from in the large intestine, dysbiosis is also present&#xD;
      in the small (upper) intestine, where increased bacterial density and altered microbial&#xD;
      composition can contribute to intestinal inflammation and intestinal dysfunction which may&#xD;
      ultimately contribute to the development of sepsis and death. The bacterial density and&#xD;
      composition in the small intestine can be altered using antibiotics. However, apart from side&#xD;
      effects, antibiotic use contributes to the development of antibiotic resistance, which is&#xD;
      very common in hospitalized malnourished patients and can pose a threat to both individual&#xD;
      and public health. In addition to intestinal dysbiosis and intestinal inflammation, children&#xD;
      with severe malnutrition suffer from impaired exocrine pancreatic and hepatobiliary function,&#xD;
      which are important for nutrient digestion and absorption to aid their recovery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One previous pilot trial showed that treating children with severe malnutrition with&#xD;
      pancreatic enzymes led to a reduction in mortality. The investigators hypothesize that&#xD;
      supplementing these enzymes exogenously to severely malnourished children will improve their&#xD;
      clinical outcome by reducing dysbiosis, intestinal inflammation and sepsis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this study is to determine whether treating ill severely malnourished&#xD;
      children with pancreatic enzymes or bile acids is safe and improves mortality. The&#xD;
      investigators will conduct a double blind, randomized clinical trial in a 2x2 factorial&#xD;
      design in hospitalized severely malnourished children. Participants will be treated with&#xD;
      pediatric formulations of pancreatic enzymes, bile acids, both or placebo for 21 days.&#xD;
      Participants will be followed up daily during their hospital stay and on day 21 and 60 after&#xD;
      enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This trial will be conducted in three stages to allow for careful interim evaluations to&#xD;
      assess safety and study progress. After the first and second stage, interim analyses assess&#xD;
      safety and likelihood of benefit before enrolling the full sample size to assess mortality as&#xD;
      the primary outcome. Secondary outcomes include adverse events, length of hospital stay and&#xD;
      growth. Exploratory outcomes will examine intestinal and systemic inflammation and metabolic&#xD;
      changes to examine mechanisms affected by the interventions, and costs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two sub-studies will be conducted. In Kenya and Bangladesh, daily blood gases, lactate and&#xD;
      biochemistry for the first 5 days to assess early clinical progress. In Malawi and Uganda,&#xD;
      hydrogen breath testing will be used to evaluate impact on upper small intestinal bacterial&#xD;
      overgrowth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Overall, this trial will determine whether a non-antibiotic, bactericidal intervention given&#xD;
      in additional to standard of care management reduces mortality in acutely ill severely&#xD;
      malnourished children.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Double-blind, randomized clinical trial 2x2 factorial design in 3 stages:&#xD;
In stage 1, (200 participants). Then the Data &amp; Safety Monitoring Committee (DSMC) will review data for likelihood major safety signals/harm (non-inferior to placebo) based on a composite endpoint of toxicity, serious adverse events (SAEs) and deaths.&#xD;
In stage 2, (200 more participants, total 400 participants). Then the DSMC will review data on a composite endpoint of SAEs and deaths and results of modeled simulations for the likelihood of superiority over placebo for mortality. Interventions with less than 80% probability of efficacy will be discontinued. Sample size for stage 3 may be adjusted.&#xD;
In stage 3, (800 more participants, total target sample size 1,200) across all sites, based on a hazard ratio of 0.66 (a 33% reduction in mortality) from a baseline mortality of 24% to 16% with 90% power, 20% inflation for the factorial design and 5% loss to follow up.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Sequential study numbers will be computer generated according to a blocked randomization list of random block sizes allocated to each site before the study begins.&#xD;
Identical study investigation medical product (IMP) packs will be labelled with sequential study numbers according to a prepared blocked randomization list before the trial begins. An independent off-site trial-pharmacist will implement labeling of the IMP with unique study numbers according to the randomization list.&#xD;
Study numbers will be issued in consecutive order at each site.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
    <description>Death</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of SAEs</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
    <description>All serious adverse events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of toxicity events</measure>
    <time_frame>21 days</time_frame>
    <description>Grade 3 or 4 toxicity events whilst receiving investigational products</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intestinal function</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
    <description>number of days with diarrhoea during index hospital admission</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antimicrobials</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
    <description>Days on second and third-line antibiotics during index admission and readmission</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalisation duration</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days from enrolment to discharge during index admission</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Growth - arm circumference cm</measure>
    <time_frame>60 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Change in MUAC in cm between enrolment and 60 days later</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Growth - weight for age z score</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
    <description>Change in weight for age z score between enrolment and 60 days later</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Growth - weight for length z score</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
    <description>Change in weight for length z score between enrolment and 60 days later</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Growth - length for age z score</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
    <description>Change in length for age z score between enrolment and 60 days later</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1200</enrollment>
  <condition>SEPSIS</condition>
  <condition>MALNUTRITION, CHILD</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pancreatic Enzymes (PE)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pancreatic enzymes formulated as 5000 IE lipase, 3600 IE amylase and 200 IE protease per 100 mg of granules, packaged as sachets. The target dose is 3000 IU lipase/kg, twice daily (1440 IU/kg amylase/80 IU/kg protease), which is the dose used for children with cystic fibrosis and exocrine pancreas insufficiency. For oedematous malnutrition, weight for dosing is reduced by 10%. To be prescribed following enrolment and given just prior to or during a feed. Prescription will follow weight bands to allow a lower range of 2000 IU/kg/day and upper range of 4000 IU/kg/day:&#xD;
Weight from Weight to Dose Dose Upper range Lower range (Kg) (Kg) (sachets) (IU Lipase) (IU/kg/dose) (IU Lipase)&#xD;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 2.50 4.99 2 10000 4000 2000 5.00 7.49 4 20000 4000 2670 7.50 9.99 6 30000 4000 3000 10.0 15.0 8 40000 4000 2667</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo-PE</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral/enteral placebo matching active Pancreatic Enzymes (PE). Dose presentation in whole sachets of 100mg of granules. For oedematous malnutrition, weight for dosing is reduced by a pragmatic 10%. To be prescribed following enrolment and given just prior to or during a feed. Prescription will follow weight bands:&#xD;
Weight from Weight to Dose Dose Upper range Lower range (Kg) (Kg) (sachets) (IU Lipase) (IU/kg/dose) (IU Lipase)&#xD;
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 2.50 4.99 2 Nil Nil Nil 5.00 7.49 4 Nil Nil Nil 7.50 9.99 6 Nil Nil Nil 10.0 15.0 8 Nil Nil Nil</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ursodeoxycholic acid (UA)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The dose of ursodeoxycholic acid will be given at 10 mg/kg twice per day just prior to or during a feed, using a suspension of 50 mg/ml = 0.2 ml/kg. For oedematous malnutrition participants, weight is pragmatically reduced by 10%. To be prescribed and given following enrolment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo-UA</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The dose of placebo will be given twice per day just prior to or during a feed at 0.2 ml/kg. To be prescribed and given following enrolment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pancreatic Enzyme</intervention_name>
    <description>CREON micro 5000</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pancreatic Enzymes (PE)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo-PE</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CREON</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ursodeoxycholic acid</intervention_name>
    <description>Ursodiol C24H40O4 suspension</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo-UA</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Ursodeoxycholic acid (UA)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 2 to &lt;59 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Admitted to hospital with an acute, non-traumatic illness and within 72 hours of&#xD;
             admission at the time of enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe malnutrition (weight-for-height &lt;-3 z scores of the median WHO growth standards&#xD;
             and/or mid upper arm circumference &lt;115mm (&lt;110mm age below 6 months), or symmetrical&#xD;
             oedema of at least the feet related to malnutrition (not related to a primary cardiac&#xD;
             or renal disorder)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to feed orally in usual state of health.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Accompanied by care provider who provides written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary caregiver plans to stay in the study area during the duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of two or more features of severity as specified below. If a child meets two&#xD;
             criteria, they may be enrolled before further criteria are assessed (e.g. a child may&#xD;
             be eligible on clinical signs before the complete blood count results are known):&#xD;
&#xD;
        Respiratory distress &quot;Subcostal indrawing&quot; or &quot;nasal flaring&quot; or &quot;head-nodding&quot; Oxygenation&#xD;
        &quot;Central cyanosis&quot; or SaO2 &lt;90% Circulation Limb temperature gradient or capillary refill&#xD;
        &gt;3 seconds Conscious level AVPU &lt; &quot;A&quot; Pulse &gt; 180 per min Haemoglobin &lt; 7g/dl Blood glucose&#xD;
        &lt; 3mmol/L White blood cells &lt; 4 or &gt; 17.5 x 109/L Temperature &lt;36 or &gt;38.5oC Very low MUAC&#xD;
        MUAC &lt;11cm&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>59 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>James A Berkley, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Oxford</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Robert Bandsma, MD</last_name>
    <phone>416-813-7654</phone>
    <phone_ext>309057</phone_ext>
    <email>robert.bandsma@sickkids.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Wieger Voskiujl, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+31 621297632</phone>
    <email>w.p.voskuijl@amsterdamumc.nl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>ICDDR,B Dhaka Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dhaka</city>
        <country>Bangladesh</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jobayer Chisti, MBBS</last_name>
      <email>chisti@icddrb.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Abu Sadat Md. Sayeem, MBBS</last_name>
      <email>sayeem@icddrb.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>KEMRI WT Clinical Trials Facility</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kilifi</city>
        <zip>80800</zip>
        <country>Kenya</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Johnstone Thitiri, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>+254709983338</phone>
      <email>Jthitiri@kemri-wellcome.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Caroline Ogwang, MBBS</last_name>
      <phone>+254709983115</phone>
      <email>COgwang@kemri-wellcome.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Queen Elizabeth Central Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Blantyre</city>
        <country>Malawi</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Isabel Potani</last_name>
      <email>isabelpotani@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mulago Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kampala</city>
        <country>Uganda</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ezekiel Mupere, MBBS</last_name>
      <email>mupez@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christina Lancioni, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Bangladesh</country>
    <country>Kenya</country>
    <country>Malawi</country>
    <country>Uganda</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.chainnetwork.org</url>
    <description>The CHAIN Network</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhang L, Voskuijl W, Mouzaki M, Groen AK, Alexander J, Bourdon C, Wang A, Versloot CJ, Di Giovanni V, Wanders RJ, Bandsma R. Impaired Bile Acid Homeostasis in Children with Severe Acute Malnutrition. PLoS One. 2016 May 10;11(5):e0155143. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0155143. eCollection 2016.</citation>
    <PMID>27163928</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bartels RH, Bourdon C, Potani I, Mhango B, van den Brink DA, Mponda JS, Muller Kobold AC, Bandsma RH, Boele van Hensbroek M, Voskuijl WP. Pancreatic Enzyme Replacement Therapy in Children with Severe Acute Malnutrition: A Randomized Controlled Trial. J Pediatr. 2017 Nov;190:85-92.e2. doi: 10.1016/j.jpeds.2017.07.013. Epub 2017 Sep 11.</citation>
    <PMID>28912050</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Njunge JM, Gwela A, Kibinge NK, Ngari M, Nyamako L, Nyatichi E, Thitiri J, Gonzales GB, Bandsma RHJ, Walson JL, Gitau EN, Berkley JA. Biomarkers of post-discharge mortality among children with complicated severe acute malnutrition. Sci Rep. 2019 Apr 12;9(1):5981. doi: 10.1038/s41598-019-42436-y.</citation>
    <PMID>30979939</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Attia S, Versloot CJ, Voskuijl W, van Vliet SJ, Di Giovanni V, Zhang L, Richardson S, Bourdon C, Netea MG, Berkley JA, van Rheenen PF, Bandsma RH. Mortality in children with complicated severe acute malnutrition is related to intestinal and systemic inflammation: an observational cohort study. Am J Clin Nutr. 2016 Nov;104(5):1441-1449. Epub 2016 Sep 21.</citation>
    <PMID>27655441</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 6, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 1, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 1, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 1, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>&quot;small intestinal bacterial overgrowth&quot;</keyword>
  <keyword>&quot;severe malnutrition&quot;</keyword>
  <keyword>&quot;factorial&quot;</keyword>
  <keyword>&quot;pancreatic enzymes&quot;</keyword>
  <keyword>&quot;bile acids&quot;</keyword>
  <keyword>&quot;bacterial&quot;</keyword>
  <keyword>&quot;translocation&quot;</keyword>
  <keyword>&quot;dysbiosis&quot;</keyword>
  <keyword>&quot;inflammation&quot;</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Child Nutrition Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ursodeoxycholic Acid</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Anonymised data may be shared through application to DGC@kemri-wellcome.org. Datasets will be uploaded on the HARVARD DATAVERSE for managed access</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

