<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04546542</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1ASSJ</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04546542</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Hydroxychloroquine Blood Levels in Primary Sjögren Syndrome Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>1ASSJHCQ</acronym>
  <official_title>Analysis of Hydroxychloroquine Blood Levels in Patients With Primary Sjögren Syndrome and Possible Correlation With the Disease Activity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Sao Paulo General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Sao Paulo General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Introduction. Primary Sjögren's syndrome (pSS) is an autoimmune disease characterized by&#xD;
      chronic inflammatory infiltration of the salivary and lacrimal glands causing dry eye and&#xD;
      mouth. Multiple systemic manifestations can also occur. Hydroxychloroquine (HCQ), an&#xD;
      antimalarial immunomodulator, has been used for the treatment of arthralgias, myalgia and&#xD;
      constitutional symptoms resulting from pSS. However, there are no studies that evaluated&#xD;
      whether blood levels of HCQ could influence in the therapeutic response, as has been reported&#xD;
      in systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives. Analyze in patients with pSS receiving HCQ as part of their treatment: blood&#xD;
      levels of HCQ; adherence using a questionnaire versus blood levels and the possible&#xD;
      correlation of blood levels with the disease activity score in a cross-sectional evaluation&#xD;
      followed by a longitudinal six-month assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients and methods. Observational cross-sectional evaluation followed by a six-month&#xD;
      longitudinal assessment, including patients with pSS receiving HCQ for at least 3 months at&#xD;
      study admission. Patients will be evaluated clinically and the HCQ blood level measured at&#xD;
      the beginning of the study (T0), at 3 months (T3), and at 6 months (T6). As there are no&#xD;
      previous studies on blood levels of HCQ in patients with pSS, the sample of 75 patients was&#xD;
      calculated based on the percentage of these patients currently using HCQ in our service&#xD;
      (nearly 50%) and in the number of patients in current follow-up (about 150). We will evaluate&#xD;
      75 adult patients with pSS according to the classification criteria of the American-European&#xD;
      Consensus Group 2002 and/or the American College of rheumatology (ACR) and the European&#xD;
      League Against Rheumatism (EULAR) 2016, of both sexes and followed up regularly at the&#xD;
      Sjögren Syndrome outpatient Clinic of the Rheumatology Service of &quot;Hospital das Clínicas da&#xD;
      Faculdade de Medicina da Universidade de São Paulo (HCFMUSP)&quot;. The following will be used in&#xD;
      the clinical evaluation: the xerostomia Inventory; the xerophthalmia questionnaire - Ocular&#xD;
      Surface Disease Index (OSDI); the EULAR Sjögren Syndrome Reported Index (ESSPRI); the EULAR&#xD;
      Sjögren Syndrome Disease Activity Index (ESSDAI); the Sjögren's Syndrome Disease Damage Index&#xD;
      (SSDDI); the non-stimulated and stimulated salivary flow and the 8-item Morisky Medication&#xD;
      Adherence Scale. Blood levels of HCQ will be measured by high performance liquid&#xD;
      chromatography and tandem mass spectrometry.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 22, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline of HCQ blood levels at 3 and 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Hydroxychloroquine blood levels will be measure using liquid chromatography tandem Mass Spectrometry (LC-MS/MS), as previously described (PEDROSA et al., 2020).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HCQ adherence in pSS patients</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Will be analysed the possible correlation between MTA (measure for treatment adhernce - a quesionnaire of adherence) score and HCQ blood levels em ng/mL (using liquid chromatography tandem Mass Spectrometry (LC-MS/MS), as previously described (PEDROSA et al., 2020). For SLE patients, adherence by HCQ blood levels is defined when HCQ blood levels are &gt;500 ng/mL, this value in pSS patients will be estimated using this 2 assessements</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease activity in pSS patients</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will evaluate the disease activity in pSS patients and correlate if HCQ blood levels can predict risk of disease acrivity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">75</enrollment>
  <condition>Sjogren's Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>pSS patients under Hydroxychloroquine (HCQ) 2016-AAO dose</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients under Hydroxychloroquine (HCQ) 2016-American Academy of ophtalmology (AAO) dose will have HCQ blood levels, disease activity and adherence evaltuated at study entry and before 3 and 6-months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Parallel Assignment</intervention_name>
    <description>We will evaluate 75 patients with pSS (Consenso Americano-europeu de 2002 / EULAR/ACR Classification Criteria, 2016) of both sexes at baseline and 6-months</description>
    <arm_group_label>pSS patients under Hydroxychloroquine (HCQ) 2016-AAO dose</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>pSS</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        pSS patients according to the classification criterias regularly followed at outpatient&#xD;
        clinic, Rheumathology division of Hospital das Clinicas da Universidade de Sao Paulo&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pSS according to the classification criterias&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who have been receiving HCQ for at least 3 months before study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who agree to participate in the study, according to the signing of the Free&#xD;
             and Informed Consent Term (ICF).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Present other associated systemic autoimmune diseases, such as rheumatoid arthritis,&#xD;
             systemic lupus erythematosus, systemic sclerosis, demato/polymyositis, mixed&#xD;
             connective tissue disease, spondyloarthritis, primary biliary cholangitis and&#xD;
             autoimmune hepatitis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Present a previous history of radiotherapy of the head and neck, positive serologies&#xD;
             for HIV, hepatitis B and C, sarcoidosis, graft versus host disease and IgG4-related&#xD;
             disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of drugs that can interact with HCQ or interfere in HCQ blood levels (tamoxifen,&#xD;
             antacids and digoxin), alcoholism, current infections, liver and heart failure,&#xD;
             dialysis, severe chronic renal failure (serum creatinine ≥3 mg/dL) and pregnancy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rheumatology Division of Hospital das Clínicas da Faculdade de Medicina da Universidade de Sao Paulo</name>
      <address>
        <city>São Paulo</city>
        <state>Sao Paulo</state>
        <zip>05403-000</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital das Clinicas da Faculdade de Medicina da USP</name>
      <address>
        <city>São Paulo</city>
        <zip>05403-000</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Pedrosa TN, Pasoto SG, Aikawa NE, Yuki EF, Borba EF, Filho JCF, Carricondo PC, Zanetti CB, Conde PG, Duarte NJ, Fontoura N, Romano P, Carvalho VM, Silva CA, Bonfa E. Understanding the dynamics of hydroxychloroquine blood levels in lupus nephritis. Lupus. 2020 May;29(6):560-568. doi: 10.1177/0961203320912832. Epub 2020 Mar 19.</citation>
    <PMID>32192398</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Cankaya H, Alpöz E, Karabulut G, Güneri P, Boyacioglu H, Kabasakal Y. Effects of hydroxychloroquine on salivary flow rates and oral complaints of Sjögren patients: a prospective sample study. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endod. 2010 Jul;110(1):62-7. doi: 10.1016/j.tripleo.2010.02.032.</citation>
    <PMID>20610299</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Yavuz S, Asfuroğlu E, Bicakcigil M, Toker E. Hydroxychloroquine improves dry eye symptoms of patients with primary Sjogren's syndrome. Rheumatol Int. 2011 Aug;31(8):1045-9. doi: 10.1007/s00296-010-1415-4. Epub 2010 Mar 23.</citation>
    <PMID>20309693</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 4, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sjogren's Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

