<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04544709</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB 117455</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04544709</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intradiscal Platelet Rich Plasma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Intradiscal Platelet-Rich Plasma Injection for Chronic Discogenic Low Back Pain</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Utah</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Utah</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To assess changes in pain and function in patients with discogenic low back pain after a&#xD;
      standard of care intradiscal injection of Platelet-Rich Plasma (PRP).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Low back pain is one of a few conditions which affects all individuals through the lifespan.&#xD;
      The etiology of low back pain is multifactorial and in many cases self-limiting, however it&#xD;
      also is the leading cause for working age adults to be disabled with more than $87 billion&#xD;
      spent on low back pain disorders in 2013 Lumbar disc herniation and internal disc disruption&#xD;
      are two causes more common in these younger age groups reaching 39-42% with a predicted&#xD;
      probability above 60% until age 50y. While the natural history of disc herniation suggests&#xD;
      most individuals will return to a prior level of function in 3-6 months, there is a high rate&#xD;
      of recurrent episodes which can cause short-term disability. Continued pain from a discogenic&#xD;
      source can lead to decreased activity levels and accelerate degenerative changes in the disc&#xD;
      and facet joints as described by Kirkaldy-Willis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Current guidelines for treatment of axial low back pain from discogenic sources including&#xD;
      those with radiculopathy include a 6-12-week course of conservative care including&#xD;
      medications, therapy, acupuncture, chiropractic and exercise before an interventional&#xD;
      paradigm of injections and/or surgical treatment. For those individuals who do not improve&#xD;
      with conservative care and have predominately axial pain, options are limited as success&#xD;
      rates from epidural steroid injections and surgery are 50% or less. Other treatments include&#xD;
      chymopapain injection, intradiscal electrothermal annuloplasty (IDET), nucleoplasty,&#xD;
      methylene blue injection, ozone injection , fibrin sealant injections. All of which have 50%&#xD;
      or less likelihood of reducing pain more than 50%, although much of this data is from&#xD;
      uncontrolled or prospective case-control studies only.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Platelet- rich plasma (PRP) injections stand apart from those listed above in that they are&#xD;
      purported to be &quot;regenerative&quot; interventions for the diseased lumbar disc. PRP is a&#xD;
      concentrated injectant of growth factors and anabolic factors which have in vitro and animal&#xD;
      studies that have demonstrated upregulated proteoglycan synthesis and nucleus pulposus&#xD;
      proliferation, restoration of disc height, healing of annular puncture wounds and&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory effect with down regulation of TNF-alpha and IL-1. There has been limited&#xD;
      clinical trials in humans on the effect of intradiscal PRP, including 3 trials of which 1 is&#xD;
      a RCT and 2 are prospective series. Efficacy of intra-discal injection has shown&#xD;
      statistically significant benefits in reduction in pain, improvement in physical function at&#xD;
      follow-up points from 3-24 months. Each of these trials have limited sample sizes, short&#xD;
      duration follow-up and lack of a standardized PRP preparation, making the generalizability&#xD;
      difficult.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 14, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 14, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Numeric Rating Scale for Pain at 2 month Follow-up</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants with &gt;80% and &gt;50% decrease in back pain on the Numeric Rating Scale pain score at the 2-month follow-up assessment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Numeric Rating Scale Median</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Change in median Numeric Rating Scale pain score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Discogenic Pain</condition>
  <condition>Low Back Pain</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Discogenic Low Back Pain</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient with Refractory Discogenic Low back pain who will be scheduled for platelet rich plasma injection as standard of care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Low back intradiscal injection of platelet rich plasma (PRP)</intervention_name>
    <description>SOC Intradiscal Lumbar PRP Procedure : A small amount of blood is drawn from you, then it is spun in a centrifuge to obtain only the platelets and few other cells. After being spun the small amount of platelets will be injected into the specific disc that is believed to be causing pain in an attempt to help reduce inflammation and pain at the site. The injection will be done under fluoroscopic guidance (x-ray) that allows very careful and precise placement of the needle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Discogenic Low Back Pain</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age greater than 18 years of age at day of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Clinical diagnosis of refractory discogenic low back pain for &gt;3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Magnetic resonance imaging pathology consistent with clinical symptoms/signs or&#xD;
             positive lumbar provocative discography according to SIS/IASP standards at one or two&#xD;
             levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Back pain greater than leg pain with an intensity of at least 4/10 or higher using the&#xD;
             Numerical Rating Scale (NRS).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Pain duration of more than 12 weeks despite trial of conservative therapy&#xD;
             (medications, physical therapy, or chiropractic care) for 2 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Refusal to participate, provide consent, or provide follow-up information for the&#xD;
             24-month duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Contraindications to intradiscal injection of PRP (active infection, bleeding&#xD;
             disorders, current anticoagulant or antiplatelet medication use, allergy to iodinated&#xD;
             contrast, penicillin or clindamycin and pregnancy or breastfeeding).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. More than 2 levels of clinical or discogram proven pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Non-discogenic source of low back pain as identified by separate diagnostic blocks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Negative lumbar provocation discography.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Active moderate to severe lumbar radiculopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Intradural disc herniation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Spinal fracture within the past 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Steroid injection in the spine within the last 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Any intradiscal injection other than contrast dye or anesthetic in the last 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Prior fusion at level considered to be the source of the pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Prior lumbar spine surgery within the last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. AP diameter of spinal canal less than or equal to 9mm at level to be treated.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Severe uncontrolled medical condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Moderate to severe hepatic dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Severe psychological illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. History of Inflammatory arthritis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Malignancy within past 5 years except basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Current use of equal to greater than 30mg morphine-equivalent per day of opioid use.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. A history of alcohol or drug abuse within past 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Use of any investigational drug within past 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. A known allergy or sensitivity to citrate (used for processing PRP).&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Severe anaphylactic/anaphylactoid reaction to any medications used.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Pending litigation involving subject's back pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. No insurance coverage for any subsequent tests or procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Disc protrusion greater than 5mm from base of vertebral body.&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. Greater than 50% disc height loss at involved level(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
         28. Inability or unwillingness to continue rehabilitation protocols.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Shellie Cunningham, BS</last_name>
    <phone>801-587-5488</phone>
    <email>shellie.cunningham@hsc.utah.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Maddie Littell</last_name>
    <phone>801-587-1436</phone>
    <email>madelaine.littell@hsc.utah.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Utah Orthopaedic Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84108</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Shellie S Cunningham, BS</last_name>
      <phone>801-587-5488</phone>
      <email>shellie.cunningham@hsc.utah.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 3, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Utah</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Zack McCormick</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Zachary McCormick, MD FAAPMR, Associate Professor, Director of Clinical Spine Research, Director of Interventional Spine and Musculoskeletal Medicine Fellowship</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Platelet Rich Plasma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

