<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02401308</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB # 14BN147</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02401308</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Trial Comparing Functional Outcomes of Awake vs. Asleep Deep Brain Stimulation (DBS) for Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial Comparing Functional Outcomes of Awake vs. Asleep Deep Brain Stimulation (DBS) for Parkinson's Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>St. Joseph's Hospital and Medical Center, Phoenix</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>St. Joseph's Hospital and Medical Center, Phoenix</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of the proposed study is to demonstrate that the functional outcomes of DBS&#xD;
      surgery utilizing the &quot;asleep&quot; technique are not inferior to those reported for traditional&#xD;
      &quot;awake&quot; DBS technique.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Traditional DBS is performed without general anesthesia with the patient awake. Local&#xD;
      anesthetic is used to numb the skin and tissue where the incision is made, and the patients&#xD;
      are given mild sedatives to alleviate anxiety and discomfort. Parkinson's patients need to be&#xD;
      off their medications during awake DBS in order to obtain single-unit cellular recordings to&#xD;
      locate and map the desired target. The process of electrophysiological mapping can result in&#xD;
      multiple brain penetrations during lead placement, and the entire procedure may last anywhere&#xD;
      from 4-6 hours on average. The concept of being awake during brain surgery and being off&#xD;
      medications are significant concerns for some patients. In addition, it is widely recognized&#xD;
      that microelectrode recording increases the risk of hemorrhage during DBS surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, there has been increasing interest in performing DBS under general anesthesia,&#xD;
      where the stimulated targets are located anatomically (i.e. on MRI) rather than&#xD;
      physiologically via microelectrode recordings. This technology has been termed &quot;asleep&quot; DBS&#xD;
      and is performed with the patient under general anesthesia. Intraoperative imaging is&#xD;
      utilized to verify the stereotactic accuracy of DBS electrodes placement at the time of&#xD;
      surgery. Because stereotactic accuracy (and surgical safety) is the surgical endpoint, there&#xD;
      is no need for the patient to be off medication and awake during the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Traditional DBS is performed without general anesthesia with the patient awake. Local&#xD;
      anesthetic is used to numb the skin and tissue where the incision is made, and the patients&#xD;
      are given mild sedatives to alleviate anxiety and discomfort. Parkinson's patients need to be&#xD;
      off their medications during awake DBS in order to obtain single-unit cellular recordings to&#xD;
      locate and map the desired target. The process of electrophysiological mapping can result in&#xD;
      multiple brain penetrations during lead placement, and the entire procedure may last anywhere&#xD;
      from 4-6 hours on average. The concept of being awake during brain surgery and being off&#xD;
      medications are significant concerns for some patients. In addition, it is widely recognized&#xD;
      that microelectrode recording increases the risk of hemorrhage during DBS surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The safety and efficacy of the two approaches to DBS surgery have been equivalent, and we are&#xD;
      at a position of equipoise with regard to what to offer to patients. To date, there have been&#xD;
      no randomized, controlled clinical trials comparing the efficacy and functional outcomes of&#xD;
      the two DBS methods. After informed consent is obtained, the patients will undergo routine&#xD;
      DBS pre-operative evaluation and diagnostic testing. This includes a pre-operative 3T-MRI&#xD;
      with and without gadolinium as well as pre-operative medical clearance by the patient's PCP&#xD;
      or general practitioner and/or other medical specialist if necessary. They will also receive&#xD;
      a baseline clinical evaluation including both motor function (Unified Parkinson's Disease&#xD;
      Rating Scale on and off antiparkinsonian medication) and quality of life (Parkinson's disease&#xD;
      Questionnaire-39) if not already completed as part of the routine DBS candidacy evaluation&#xD;
      within 2 months of surgery. Patients who elect to participate in this trial will undergo a&#xD;
      routine pre-operative neurocognitive evaluation consisting of the following routine&#xD;
      evaluative tests: Wechsler Test of Adult Reading, Mattis Dementia Rating Scale 2nd Edition,&#xD;
      Wechsler Abbreviate Scale of Intelligence 2nd Edition; Wechsler Memory Scale 3rd edition,&#xD;
      Digit Span, Stroop Neuropsychological Screening Test, Trail Making Test, Wisconsin Card&#xD;
      Sorting Test, Controlled Oral Word Association Test, Animal Naming, Boston Naming Test,&#xD;
      Wechsler Memory Scale 4th Edition, Logical Memory, Hopkins Verbal Learning Test - Revised,&#xD;
      Brief Visuospatial Memory Test - Revised, Hooper visual Organization Test, Judgment of Line&#xD;
      Orientation, Beck Depression Inventory, Beck Anxiety Inventory, Questionnaire for&#xD;
      Impulsive-Compulsive Disorders in Parkinson's Disease, Apathy Evaluation Scale; Epworth&#xD;
      Sleepiness Scale, The subjects will then be randomized to 2 groups by using random numbers in&#xD;
      an envelope system. We anticipate that 120 total patients will need to be enrolled in this&#xD;
      pilot study (60 awake, 60 asleep), and thus the numbers 1-120 will be placed in envelopes. An&#xD;
      odd number will correspond to the awake DBS procedure, and an even number will indicate an&#xD;
      asleep DBS procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of the proposed study is to demonstrate that the functional outcomes of the&#xD;
      &quot;asleep&quot; technique are not inferior to those reported for traditional &quot;awake&quot; DBS technique.&#xD;
      The primary data points for this study will include six month functional outcomes using&#xD;
      accepted metrics for Parkinson's disease, including both motor function (Unified Parkinson's&#xD;
      Disease Rating Scale [UPDRS] obtained in the medication &quot;on&quot; and medication &quot;off&quot; states) and&#xD;
      quality of life (Parkinson's Disease Questionnaire-39). The null hypothesis is that asleep&#xD;
      DBS results in inferior UPDRS-III scores at 6-months after surgery. Our secondary aim will be&#xD;
      to evaluate any cognitive changes associated with DBS surgery selection (awake vs. asleep) in&#xD;
      PD patients. Current standard of care for patient selection in DBS focuses primarily on the&#xD;
      evaluation of motor symptoms and currently there is no guidance for how a patients' DBS&#xD;
      surgery selection (awake vs. asleep) would impact on subsequent neurocognitive function.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Lack of subject enrollment.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 15, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 5, 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 5, 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months post-operatively</time_frame>
    <description>Motor function outcomes using accepted metrics for Parkinson's disease - the Unified Parkinson's Disease Rating Scale [UPDRS] obtained in 3 states:&#xD;
medication &quot;off&quot; / device &quot;on&quot;.&#xD;
Medication &quot;off&quot; / device &quot;off&quot;&#xD;
medication &quot;on&quot; / device &quot;on&quot;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neurocognitive Function</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months post-operatively</time_frame>
    <description>Neurocognitive evaluation consisting of the following routine evaluative tests: Wechsler Test of Adult Reading, Mattis Dementia Rating Scale 2nd Edition, Wechsler Abbreviate Scale of Intelligence 2nd Edition; Wechsler Memory Scale 3rd edition, Digit Span, Stroop Neuropsychological Screening Test, Trail Making Test, Wisconsin Card Sorting Test, Controlled Oral Word Association Test, Animal Naming, Boston Naming Test, Wechsler Memory Scale 4th Edition, Logical Memory, Hopkins Verbal Learning Test - Revised, Brief Visuospatial Memory Test - Revised, Hooper visual Organization Test, Judgment of Line Orientation, Beck Depression Inventory, Beck Anxiety Inventory, Questionnaire for Impulsive-Compulsive Disorders in Parkinson's Disease, Apathy Evaluation Scale; Epworth Sleepiness Scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months post-operatively</time_frame>
    <description>Parkinson's Disease Questionnaire-39 to evaluate the patient's assessment of their quality of life following DBS surgery</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1</enrollment>
  <condition>Parkinson's Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Awake DBS Surgery</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery: Parkinson's patients undergoing traditional &quot;awake&quot; DBS surgery utilizing microelectrode recordings and intra-operative stimulation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Asleep DBS Surgery</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery:Parkinson's patients undergoing DBS surgery under general anesthesia utilizing intraoperative imaging to verify the stereotactic accuracy of DBS electrodes placement at the time of surgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Deep Brain Stimulation surgery</intervention_name>
    <description>Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: awake vs. asleep</description>
    <arm_group_label>Asleep DBS Surgery</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Awake DBS Surgery</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>DBS</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parkinson's disease per Queens Square criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Appropriate DBS candidate for multi-disciplinary team consensus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 - 85 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Motor skills allowing for capability to complete evaluations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medically cleared for undergoing anesthesia and DBS surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dementia per DSM-V criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical or other condition precluding MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of supraspinal CNS disease other than PD&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alcohol use of more than 4 drinks per day&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of suicide attempt&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently uncontrolled clinically significant depression (BDI&gt;20)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of schizophrenia, delusions, or currently uncontrolled visual hallucinations&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Francisco A Ponce, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Barrow Neurological Institute / St. Joseph's Hosptial and Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Barrow Neurological Institute / St. Joseph's Hospital &amp; Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Phoenix</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85013</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ostrem JL, Galifianakis NB, Markun LC, Grace JK, Martin AJ, Starr PA, Larson PS. Clinical outcomes of PD patients having bilateral STN DBS using high-field interventional MR-imaging for lead placement. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2013 Jun;115(6):708-12. doi: 10.1016/j.clineuro.2012.08.019. Epub 2012 Sep 1.</citation>
    <PMID>22944465</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nakajima T, Zrinzo L, Foltynie T, Olmos IA, Taylor C, Hariz MI, Limousin P. MRI-guided subthalamic nucleus deep brain stimulation without microelectrode recording: can we dispense with surgery under local anaesthesia? Stereotact Funct Neurosurg. 2011;89(5):318-25. doi: 10.1159/000330379. Epub 2011 Sep 15.</citation>
    <PMID>21921673</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Harries AM, Kausar J, Roberts SA, Mocroft AP, Hodson JA, Pall HS, Mitchell RD. Deep brain stimulation of the subthalamic nucleus for advanced Parkinson disease using general anesthesia: long-term results. J Neurosurg. 2012 Jan;116(1):107-13. doi: 10.3171/2011.7.JNS11319. Epub 2011 Oct 14.</citation>
    <PMID>21999316</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weaver FM, Follett K, Stern M, Hur K, Harris C, Marks WJ Jr, Rothlind J, Sagher O, Reda D, Moy CS, Pahwa R, Burchiel K, Hogarth P, Lai EC, Duda JE, Holloway K, Samii A, Horn S, Bronstein J, Stoner G, Heemskerk J, Huang GD; CSP 468 Study Group. Bilateral deep brain stimulation vs best medical therapy for patients with advanced Parkinson disease: a randomized controlled trial. JAMA. 2009 Jan 7;301(1):63-73. doi: 10.1001/jama.2008.929.</citation>
    <PMID>19126811</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pezeshkian P, DeSalles AA, Gorgulho A, Behnke E, McArthur D, Bari A. Accuracy of frame-based stereotactic magnetic resonance imaging vs frame-based stereotactic head computed tomography fused with recent magnetic resonance imaging for postimplantation deep brain stimulator lead localization. Neurosurgery. 2011 Dec;69(6):1299-306. doi: 10.1227/NEU.0b013e31822b7069.</citation>
    <PMID>21725253</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Papanastassiou V, Rowe J, Scott R, Silburn P, Davies L, Aziz T. Use of the Radionics Image Fusiontrade mark and Stereoplantrade mark programs for target localization in functional neurosurgery. J Clin Neurosci. 1998 Jan;5(1):28-32.</citation>
    <PMID>18644283</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alexander E 3rd, Kooy HM, van Herk M, Schwartz M, Barnes PD, Tarbell N, Mulkern RV, Holupka EJ, Loeffler JS. Magnetic resonance image-directed stereotactic neurosurgery: use of image fusion with computerized tomography to enhance spatial accuracy. J Neurosurg. 1995 Aug;83(2):271-6.</citation>
    <PMID>7616273</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kooy HM, van Herk M, Barnes PD, Alexander E 3rd, Dunbar SF, Tarbell NJ, Mulkern RV, Holupka EJ, Loeffler JS. Image fusion for stereotactic radiotherapy and radiosurgery treatment planning. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 1994 Mar 30;28(5):1229-34.</citation>
    <PMID>8175410</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 24, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 26, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 27, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>September 27, 2021</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>September 27, 2021</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Awake DBS Surgery</title>
          <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery: Parkinson's patients undergoing traditional &quot;awake&quot; DBS surgery utilizing microelectrode recordings and intra-operative stimulation&#xD;
Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: awake vs. asleep</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P2">
          <title>Asleep DBS Surgery</title>
          <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery:Parkinson's patients undergoing DBS surgery under general anesthesia utilizing intraoperative imaging to verify the stereotactic accuracy of DBS electrodes placement at the time of surgery.&#xD;
Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: awake vs. asleep</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="1"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="1"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
          <drop_withdraw_reason_list>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Study was terminated by the PI due to lack of enrollment.</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="1"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
          </drop_withdraw_reason_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <population>Study was terminated due to lack of enrollment. Only 1 subject was enrolled. No analysis was completed.</population>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Awake DBS Surgery</title>
          <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery: Parkinson's patients undergoing traditional &quot;awake&quot; DBS surgery utilizing microelectrode recordings and intra-operative stimulation&#xD;
Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: awake vs. asleep</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B2">
          <title>Asleep DBS Surgery</title>
          <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery:Parkinson's patients undergoing DBS surgery under general anesthesia utilizing intraoperative imaging to verify the stereotactic accuracy of DBS electrodes placement at the time of surgery.&#xD;
Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: awake vs. asleep</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B3">
          <title>Total</title>
          <description>Total of all reporting groups</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="0"/>
            <count group_id="B2" value="1"/>
            <count group_id="B3" value="1"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>&lt;=18 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Between 18 and 65 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>&gt;=65 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Region of Enrollment</title>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>United States</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Functional Outcomes</title>
        <description>Motor function outcomes using accepted metrics for Parkinson's disease - the Unified Parkinson's Disease Rating Scale [UPDRS] obtained in 3 states:&#xD;
medication &quot;off&quot; / device &quot;on&quot;.&#xD;
Medication &quot;off&quot; / device &quot;off&quot;&#xD;
medication &quot;on&quot; / device &quot;on&quot;</description>
        <time_frame>6 months post-operatively</time_frame>
        <population>Study was terminated due to lack of enrollment. No analysis was completed.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Awake DBS Surgery</title>
            <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery: Parkinson's patients undergoing traditional &quot;awake&quot; DBS surgery utilizing microelectrode recordings and intra-operative stimulation&#xD;
Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: awake vs. asleep</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Asleep DBS Surgery</title>
            <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery:Parkinson's patients undergoing DBS surgery under general anesthesia utilizing intraoperative imaging to verify the stereotactic accuracy of DBS electrodes placement at the time of surgery.&#xD;
Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: awake vs. asleep</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Functional Outcomes</title>
          <description>Motor function outcomes using accepted metrics for Parkinson's disease - the Unified Parkinson's Disease Rating Scale [UPDRS] obtained in 3 states:&#xD;
medication &quot;off&quot; / device &quot;on&quot;.&#xD;
Medication &quot;off&quot; / device &quot;off&quot;&#xD;
medication &quot;on&quot; / device &quot;on&quot;</description>
          <population>Study was terminated due to lack of enrollment. No analysis was completed.</population>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="0"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="0"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Neurocognitive Function</title>
        <description>Neurocognitive evaluation consisting of the following routine evaluative tests: Wechsler Test of Adult Reading, Mattis Dementia Rating Scale 2nd Edition, Wechsler Abbreviate Scale of Intelligence 2nd Edition; Wechsler Memory Scale 3rd edition, Digit Span, Stroop Neuropsychological Screening Test, Trail Making Test, Wisconsin Card Sorting Test, Controlled Oral Word Association Test, Animal Naming, Boston Naming Test, Wechsler Memory Scale 4th Edition, Logical Memory, Hopkins Verbal Learning Test - Revised, Brief Visuospatial Memory Test - Revised, Hooper visual Organization Test, Judgment of Line Orientation, Beck Depression Inventory, Beck Anxiety Inventory, Questionnaire for Impulsive-Compulsive Disorders in Parkinson's Disease, Apathy Evaluation Scale; Epworth Sleepiness Scale.</description>
        <time_frame>6 months post-operatively</time_frame>
        <population>Study was terminated due to lack of enrollment. No analysis was completed.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Awake DBS Surgery</title>
            <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery: Parkinson's patients undergoing traditional &quot;awake&quot; DBS surgery utilizing microelectrode recordings and intra-operative stimulation&#xD;
Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: awake vs. asleep</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Asleep DBS Surgery</title>
            <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery:Parkinson's patients undergoing DBS surgery under general anesthesia utilizing intraoperative imaging to verify the stereotactic accuracy of DBS electrodes placement at the time of surgery.&#xD;
Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: awake vs. asleep</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Neurocognitive Function</title>
          <description>Neurocognitive evaluation consisting of the following routine evaluative tests: Wechsler Test of Adult Reading, Mattis Dementia Rating Scale 2nd Edition, Wechsler Abbreviate Scale of Intelligence 2nd Edition; Wechsler Memory Scale 3rd edition, Digit Span, Stroop Neuropsychological Screening Test, Trail Making Test, Wisconsin Card Sorting Test, Controlled Oral Word Association Test, Animal Naming, Boston Naming Test, Wechsler Memory Scale 4th Edition, Logical Memory, Hopkins Verbal Learning Test - Revised, Brief Visuospatial Memory Test - Revised, Hooper visual Organization Test, Judgment of Line Orientation, Beck Depression Inventory, Beck Anxiety Inventory, Questionnaire for Impulsive-Compulsive Disorders in Parkinson's Disease, Apathy Evaluation Scale; Epworth Sleepiness Scale.</description>
          <population>Study was terminated due to lack of enrollment. No analysis was completed.</population>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="0"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="0"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Quality of Life</title>
        <description>Parkinson's Disease Questionnaire-39 to evaluate the patient's assessment of their quality of life following DBS surgery</description>
        <time_frame>6 months post-operatively</time_frame>
        <population>Study was terminated due to lack of enrollment. No analysis was completed.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Awake DBS Surgery</title>
            <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery: Parkinson's patients undergoing traditional &quot;awake&quot; DBS surgery utilizing microelectrode recordings and intra-operative stimulation&#xD;
Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: awake vs. asleep</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Asleep DBS Surgery</title>
            <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery:Parkinson's patients undergoing DBS surgery under general anesthesia utilizing intraoperative imaging to verify the stereotactic accuracy of DBS electrodes placement at the time of surgery.&#xD;
Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: awake vs. asleep</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Quality of Life</title>
          <description>Parkinson's Disease Questionnaire-39 to evaluate the patient's assessment of their quality of life following DBS surgery</description>
          <population>Study was terminated due to lack of enrollment. No analysis was completed.</population>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="0"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="0"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>Per protocol, participants were to be followed for 6 months post surgery.</time_frame>
      <desc>Only 1 subject was enrolled and he was randomized to the asleep arm. Therefore, there were no subjects at risks for AEs in the Awake Arm.</desc>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Awake DBS Surgery</title>
          <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery: Parkinson's patients undergoing traditional &quot;awake&quot; DBS surgery utilizing microelectrode recordings and intra-operative stimulation&#xD;
Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: awake vs. asleep</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E2">
          <title>Asleep DBS Surgery</title>
          <description>Deep brain stimulation surgery:Parkinson's patients undergoing DBS surgery under general anesthesia utilizing intraoperative imaging to verify the stereotactic accuracy of DBS electrodes placement at the time of surgery.&#xD;
Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: Deep Brain Stimulation surgery: awake vs. asleep</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="0"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="1"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="0"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="1"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>5</frequency_threshold>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="0"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="1"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>All Principal Investigators ARE employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <limitations_and_caveats>This trial was terminated without meeting the objectives. One out of the planned 120 participants was enrolled. There was no analysis completed.</limitations_and_caveats>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Lisa Arnold - Operations Manager Neurosurgery Clinical Research</name_or_title>
      <organization>St. Joseph's Hospital and Medical Center</organization>
      <phone>602-406-9593</phone>
      <email>lisa.arnold@dignityhealth.org</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

