<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02405806</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>140917-281</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02405806</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Effects of Nutrition on Metabolic Risk Factors and Mechanisms</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Effects of Nutrition on Metabolic Risk Factors and Mechanisms</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Region Skane</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Lund University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Region Skane</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The overall aim for this study is to evaluate the clinical effects of a modified diet on&#xD;
      metabolic risk factors such as diabetes mellitus and obesity, and the mechanisms this&#xD;
      nutrition composition exerts on gastrointestinal physiology, inflammatory responses, and&#xD;
      quality of life, where the subjects are their own controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Within this study, the investigators will be able to relate the nutritional composition to&#xD;
      metabolic disorders, the gut microbiota, secreted intestinal neuropeptides, and bio- and&#xD;
      inflammatory markers in serum, plasma and urine.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Material and Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects are recruited consequently from the primary care, and from the Department of&#xD;
      Endocrinology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator will include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. patients with type 2 diabetes to study the effect of a modified diet for 3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. healthy volunteers for intake of two different breakfasts with some days in between the&#xD;
           meals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All categories will be exposed to exactly the same study design.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Protocols:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Various protocols will be used in the study, to collect information about the status at&#xD;
      inclusion, and to be able to measure changes in anthropometry, health status and symptoms&#xD;
      during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study-questionnaire:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This questionnaire is similar to the questionnaires used in the great population cohorts&#xD;
      Malmö Diet and Cancer Study (MDCS, general population from Malmö, N = 28 000), and Malmö&#xD;
      Offspring Study (MOS) (general population from Malmö, children and grandchildren to&#xD;
      participants in MDCS, calculated to include 5000 participants, started 2013, supported by&#xD;
      grants from VR). It is also used in a newly started endoscopy study where all consecutive&#xD;
      patients performing a colonoscopy at the Department of Gastroenterology in Malmö will be&#xD;
      included (calculated to include 2000 participants). The questionnaire contains questions&#xD;
      about socioeconomic factors, life style factors (including diet, smoking, stuff use, alcohol&#xD;
      habits, physical activity), medical health, drug consumption, heredity factors and&#xD;
      gastrointestinal symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nutrition questionnaire:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This questionnaire is used to get information about ordinary diet, energy intake, and so on.&#xD;
      This basic information is used to plan the diet from Life Science Lab, so similar energy&#xD;
      supply and breakfast are provided.&#xD;
&#xD;
      36-item Short-Form questionnaire (SF-36): This is a world-wide used instrument to evaluate&#xD;
      quality of life. It has been used to measure quality of life in many various diseases, and&#xD;
      norm value references are available. The instrument measures physical functioning, role&#xD;
      functional-physical, bodily pain, general health, vitality, social functioning, role&#xD;
      functioning-emotional, and mental health. These parameters are valuable to evaluate, to&#xD;
      estimate the effects evoked in daily life, by a change in life style factors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anthropometric protocol:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This questionnaire is used to screen the study participants before inclusion, and to be able&#xD;
      to exclude patients with already ongoing weight-reducing diet. In addition, it contains&#xD;
      questions about BMI, body composition, and a basal physical examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Satiety scoring:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This protocol has been used in previous studies by the group, to estimate the degree of&#xD;
      hunger/satiety before and after a standardized meal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nutrition:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All subjects will get the diet delivered free from charge from Life Science Lab (Lund&#xD;
      University). Life Science Lab was founded 1998 as a leading medical and technical research&#xD;
      for advanced cardiovascular and thoracic surgery sciences. Due to the importance of life&#xD;
      style effects on the cardiovascular diseases and well-being, Life Science Lab also conducts&#xD;
      life style-related science to reduce known risk factors for cardiovascular diseases. The main&#xD;
      focus is to develop healthy nutrition in normal food formula by reforming the food-meal&#xD;
      composition for everyone. The meal-diet consists of ordinary raws, but with minimal&#xD;
      industrial processing. The food is based on traditional Nordic raws, e.g. whole grains,&#xD;
      vegetables, leguminous, root crops, fat fish, birds, fruits, berries and nuts. At the same&#xD;
      time, the amount of sugar, read meat, processed meat, and dairy products is limited. The diet&#xD;
      has a good nutritional supply, but contains less calories than what is usually recommended&#xD;
      (2000 kcal/day compared with 2400 kcal/day).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The meal is planned together with the kitchen of Life science Lab. Food composition, recipes,&#xD;
      and instructions how to cook the food is delivered regularly from Life Science Lab for lunch&#xD;
      and dinner. The breakfasts for the subjects are planned together with the PI and the&#xD;
      nutritionist at Life Science Lab, but the subjects have to buy the food themselves. Three&#xD;
      alternatives are suggested, depending on their ordinary breakfast ingested, described in the&#xD;
      nutrition questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neuropeptides/inflammatory markers:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The neuropeptides, or their precursors, that will be studied in serum/plasma are peptides&#xD;
      involved in regulation of satiety and digestion, e.g. cholecystokinin (CCK), gastrin,&#xD;
      ghrelin, glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1), and glucagon-like peptide-2 (GLP-2), leptin,&#xD;
      motilin, neurotensin, oxytocin, and peptide YY (PYY). To evaluate permeability defects in the&#xD;
      intestinal mucosa, levels of zonulin and bacterial endotoxins, i.e. lipopolysaccharides, will&#xD;
      be measured in plasma. Low-graded inflammation is reflected by high-sensitive C-reactive&#xD;
      protein (CRP), plasminogen activator inhibitor type 1 (PAI-1), and factors involved in AGE&#xD;
      will be analyzed. In addition, different cytokines, tracers, and routine analyses will be&#xD;
      performed. Cooperation with laboratories in Denmark and Great Britain will be established.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Gut microbiota:&#xD;
&#xD;
      DNA extractions and Terminal Restriction Fragment Length Polymorphism (T-RFLP) and&#xD;
      quantification of specific bacterial groups will be done by quantitative polymerase chain&#xD;
      reaction (PCR) in accordance with the protocols the investigator has used and described&#xD;
      earlier by the research group. As reference, a restricted number of samples will be analyzed&#xD;
      with massively-parallel pyrosequencing of partial ribosomal ribonucleic acid (rRNA) ribosomal&#xD;
      genes. The gut microbiota bacterial constitution (bacterial species) will be correlated to&#xD;
      gastrointestinal symptoms and diseases, and changes in bio- and inflammatory markers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design&#xD;
&#xD;
      When a group of patients are recruited, the investigator will have an information meeting for&#xD;
      the whole group. At that meeting, held by the PI, the subjects will receive medical&#xD;
      information about metabolic diseases, and about nutrition and its effects on health and&#xD;
      disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After this initial meeting, the subjects are handled individually. For overview, se&#xD;
      flow-chart, last page. At inclusion, all subjects have to complete questionnaires and some&#xD;
      examinations:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Study-questionnaire containing questions about ordinary lifestyle factors, socioeconomic&#xD;
           factors, health- and drug information, heredity, and gastrointestinal symptoms;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Nutrition questionnaire containing information about ordinary food habits&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Quality of life questionnaire SF-36;&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Anthropometric protocol, including nutritional screening, completed by the investigator;&#xD;
           and&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Eight tubes (SST- phenolsulfotransferase platelet survival time (PST)- and&#xD;
           ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid (EDTA) tubes), à 6 ml, to collect serum, plasma and&#xD;
           blood cells. Feces sampling for microbiota analyses. Urine sampling during the night.&#xD;
           All biological material will be stored at -20 ◦C or -80◦ C for later analyses, or&#xD;
           analyzed at once (Hb, leukocytes, thrombocytes, CRP, electrolytes, liver enzymes,&#xD;
           lipids, bleeding status, glomerular filtration rate (GFR), insulin, fp-glucose, HbA1c&#xD;
           and thyroid-stimulating hormone (TSH), cobalamin, folate and routine urine analyses incl&#xD;
           microalbuminuria).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The questionnaires 1, 3, 4, and 5, and experimental procedures will be repeated after 3&#xD;
      months of the diet and at termination after 6 months, with standard food the last 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two weeks after introduction of the new diet, insulin, glucose and proinsulin are measured in&#xD;
      plasma/serum, along with anthropometric protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the evaluation of the diet, the subjects have to continue with the same degree of&#xD;
      physical activity as previously. No dietary supplements such as fish oil, probiotics or&#xD;
      multivitamin drugs are allowed to take. As most one visit to a restaurant or to another diet&#xD;
      per week is allowed. Journeys or a stay during a longer time period at another place must be&#xD;
      discussed with the leader of the research. Maximal intake of alcoholic beverages is 30 g&#xD;
      ethanol/week. 12 g ethanol corresponds to the following: 1 bottle (50cl) ordinary beer, 1&#xD;
      bottle (33cl) strong beer, 1 glass (15cl) wine, 1 glass (8cl) strong wine, or 1 glass (4cl)&#xD;
      spirits. formula: volume% x ml volume/100 x 0.8.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Test meal in a substudy of healthy volunteers&#xD;
&#xD;
      The subjects come fasting (12 h) in the morning, bringing the breakfast to consume. Before&#xD;
      starting the meal, two blood samples are taken with 10 min in between. After the start of the&#xD;
      meal, a new blood sample is collected at 10, 20, 30, 45, 60, 90, 120, and 180 min afterwards.&#xD;
      Each blood sample consists of 6 ml plasma. At the same time intervals, the satiety score is&#xD;
      completed. With a few days in between, the same procedure is performed where their previous&#xD;
      ordinary, daily breakfast is replaced by the new diet, so that 2 test meals are performed&#xD;
      during run-in; one with ordinary breakfast and one with new diet breakfast.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the whole study, PI has a close contact (email and phone) with the patient to be able&#xD;
      to support the patient and enhance compliance as much as possible.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 15, 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in metabolic effects, intestinal permeability and microbiota composition after food intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>In the larger study, the investigator will give the patients a moderate, low carbohydrate food for 3 months and then evaluate the effects in plasma concentration of insulin, fp-glucose, C-peptide, proinsulin, HbA1c, lipids, and zonulin. Feces wil be analyzed for microbiota composition as quantified by PCR.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life as assessed by the SF-36</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>In the larger study, the investigator will give the patients a moderate, low carbohydrate food for 3 months and assess the quality of life before and after intervention by SF-36</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in hormonal effects of food intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours</time_frame>
    <description>The investigator will test one single meal of each food type, standard food or a moderate, low carbohydrate food and then evaluate the plasma concentration over 3 hours of cholecystokinin (CCK), gastrin, ghrelin, glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1), glucagon-like peptide-2 (GLP-2), leptin, motilin, neurotensin, oxytocin, and peptide YY (PYY).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <condition>Diet Modification</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>low carbohydrate food</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The subjects will be given a diet with moderate, low carbohydrate content for 3 months, or as a single test meal, and this will be evaluated in metabolic parameters, microbiota and biomarkers in serum as described previously.&#xD;
Intervention: Food: Low carbohydrate food</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>standard food</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The subjects will be given a diet with standard food as a single test meal, and this will be evaluated in metabolic parameters, microbiota and biomarkers in serum, as described Intervention: Food: Standard food</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>low carbohydrate food</intervention_name>
    <description>low carbohydrate food</description>
    <arm_group_label>low carbohydrate food</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>standard food</intervention_name>
    <description>standard food</description>
    <arm_group_label>standard food</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy subjects should be healthy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prediabetes should have fasting plasma glucose levels o 5.6-6.9 mmol/l or plasma&#xD;
             glucose level 2 h after an oral glucose test of 7.8-11.1 mmol/l, without any diabetes&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with diabetes should have type-2 diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Obesity should have BMI 30-3 and glucose levels within reference values&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with diabetes or obesity should not have severe cardiac, kidney, liver or&#xD;
             psychiatric diseases&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bodil Ohlsson, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Lund University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ohlsson B, Björgell O, Ekberg O, Darwiche G. The oxytocin/vasopressin receptor antagonist atosiban delays the gastric emptying of a semisolid meal compared to saline in human. BMC Gastroenterol. 2006 Mar 16;6:11.</citation>
    <PMID>16542457</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sullivan M, Karlsson J, Taft C. SF-36: Swedish manual and interpretation guide, 2nd Edition. Gothenburg: Sahlgrenska University Hospital. 2002.</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 27, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 1, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 9, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 9, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 10, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Region Skane</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Bodil Ohlsson</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor, senior consultant</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

