<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02401906</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ALR_2015-8</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02401906</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>MRI and Orbital Tumours (MEDORT)</brief_title>
  <acronym>MEDORT</acronym>
  <official_title>MRI for the Etiological Diagnosis of Orbital Tumours</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fondation Ophtalmologique Adolphe de Rothschild</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fondation Ophtalmologique Adolphe de Rothschild</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Orbital masses develop at the expense of the orbital structures lacrimal glands, oculomotor&#xD;
      muscles, optic nerve, meningeal spaces, peripheral nerves, bone wall, orbital fat, lymphoid&#xD;
      structures or vascular structures. These masses can be tumors, benign or malignant, or&#xD;
      pseudotumor, mainly represented by specific or non-specific orbital inflammation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pathology is of considerable importance for the diagnosis and the treatment of those masses.&#xD;
      However, biopsy or surgical resection of the orbital masses is sometimes difficult and&#xD;
      dangerous outside expert centers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The identification of a non-invasive technique for distinguishing tumors from pseudotumors,&#xD;
      thus avoid in some cases a biopsy, would be a major contribution for the patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The MRI assessment performed routinely in a patient with an orbital mass includes&#xD;
      morphological sequences T1, T2 fat suppression, T1 injected fat suppression, diffusion. This&#xD;
      exploration requires, regardless of the performed research, a contrast agent injection (0.1&#xD;
      mg / kg weight of Gadobutrol®).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this research protocol, during the injection of the contrast agent performed during the&#xD;
      MRI assessment performed routinely, a DCE perfusion sequence, which consists of a repeated&#xD;
      acquisition at short intervals of a volume gradient echo T1, will be added. This acquisition&#xD;
      will be preceded by two short series for calibration. The post treatment will include&#xD;
      parametric permeability cards (Ktrans) and plasmatic volume (Vp), evaluating one or more&#xD;
      regions of interest in the tumor, normal lacrimal glands, jaw muscles and nasal mucosa being&#xD;
      the reference. It will also be added a magnetic susceptibility EPI sequence type. All the&#xD;
      qualitative parameters (T1, T2, T1 injected, distribution, low signal intensity in&#xD;
      susceptibility) and quantitative (Ktrans, Vp, relative intensity enhancement, apparent&#xD;
      diffusion coefficient) parameters will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The result of the pathological exam of the biopsy or of the surgical specimen, which is the&#xD;
      gold-standard, will be collected.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 27, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 25, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 25, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity and specificity based on the patterns of the intra voxel incoherent motion, the dynamic susceptibility contrast and enhancement, for distinguishing orbital tumors from orbital pseudotumor, the gold standard being the pathological exam.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Orbital Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Orbital Pseudotumor</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MRI</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patient aged over 18 years, with an orbital mass for which a biopsy or a resection is&#xD;
        planned, coming for an MRI, before any surgical treatment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient aged over 18 years, with an orbital mass for which a biopsy or a resection is&#xD;
             planned, coming for an MRI, before any surgical treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute or relative contra-indication to MRI or to a contrast agent gadolinium&#xD;
             injection (including pregnant or likely to be, breastfeeding women)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient under guardianship&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient not willing to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of affiliation to social security or medical state aid (AME) or universal health&#xD;
             coverage (CMU)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Motion artifact on the sequences, not corrected by the repeat sequences&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metal artifact prohibiting the analysis of the region of interest&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biopsy or resection not performed, particularly if the orbital mass is due to an&#xD;
             infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  MRI findings allowing a diagnosis without the need for pathology&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fondation ophtalmique Adolphe de Rothschild</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75019</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 17, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 24, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 30, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Orbital Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Orbital Pseudotumor</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

