<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02405585</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NLG0605</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1409-1350</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02405585</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Immunotherapy and SBRT Study in Borderline Resectable Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Exploratory Phase 2 Study of Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy Followed by Stereotactic Body Radiation Therapy (SBRT) With Algenpantucel-L (HyperAcute®-Pancreas) Immunotherapy in Subjects With Borderline Resectable Pancreatic Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>NewLink Genetics Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Lumos Pharma</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Unfortunately, despite the best clinical efforts and breakthroughs in biotechnology, most&#xD;
      patients diagnosed with pancreatic cancer continue to die from the rapid progression of their&#xD;
      disease. One primary reason for this is that the disease is typically without symptoms until&#xD;
      significant local and/or distant spread has occurred and is often beyond the chance for cure&#xD;
      at the time of the diagnosis. The lack of any treatment to substantially increase long term&#xD;
      survival rates is reflected by the poor outcomes associated with this disease, specifically&#xD;
      time to disease progression and overall survival.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, another important part of the body is now being looked at as a target for therapy&#xD;
      against this disease - the immune system. Scientists have clearly shown that pancreatic tumor&#xD;
      cells produce a number of defective proteins, or express normal proteins in highly&#xD;
      uncharacteristic ways, as part of this cancer. In some cancers, these abnormalities can cause&#xD;
      an immune response to the cancer cells much in the way one responds to infected tissue. In&#xD;
      progressive cancers however, the immune system fails to effectively identify or respond to&#xD;
      these abnormalities and the cancer cells are not attacked or destroyed for reasons not yet&#xD;
      fully understood. This clinical trial proposes a new way to stimulate the immune system to&#xD;
      recognize pancreatic cancer cells and to stimulate an immune response that destroys or blocks&#xD;
      the growth of the cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This new method of treatment helps the immune system of pancreatic cancer patients to&#xD;
      &quot;identify&quot; the cancerous tissue so that it can be eliminated from the body. As an example,&#xD;
      patients with certain diseases may require an organ transplant to replace a damaged kidney or&#xD;
      heart. After receiving their transplant, these patients receive special drugs because they&#xD;
      are at great danger of having an immune response that destroys or &quot;rejects&quot; the transplanted&#xD;
      organ. This &quot;rejection&quot; occurs when their immune system responds to differences between the&#xD;
      cells of the transplanted organ and their own immune system by attacking the foreign tissue&#xD;
      in the same way as it would attack infected tissue. When the differences between foreign&#xD;
      tissues and the patient's body are even larger, as with the differences between organs from&#xD;
      different species, the rejection is very rapid, highly destructive, and the immunity it&#xD;
      generates is longlasting. This is called hyperacute rejection and the medicine used to&#xD;
      immunize patients in this protocol tries to harness this response to teach a patient's immune&#xD;
      system to fight their pancreatic cancer just as the body would learn to reject a transplanted&#xD;
      organ from an animal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To do this, Algenpantucel-L immunotherapy contains human pancreatic cancer cells that contain&#xD;
      a mouse gene that marks the cancer cells as foreign to patient's immune systems. The immune&#xD;
      system therefore attacks these cancer cells just as they would attack any truly foreign&#xD;
      tissue, destroying as much as it can. Additionally, the immune system is stimulated to&#xD;
      identify differences (aside from the mouse gene) between these cancer cells and normal human&#xD;
      tissue as foreign. This &quot;education&quot; of the immune system helps treat the patient because&#xD;
      pancreatic cancer cells already present in a treated patient are believed to show some of the&#xD;
      same differences from normal tissue as the modified pancreatic cancer cells in the product.&#xD;
      Due to these similarities, the immune system, once &quot;educated&quot; by the Algenpantucel-L&#xD;
      immunotherapy, identifies the patient's cancer as foreign and attacks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Historically, external beam radiation has been part of the treatment of pancreatic cancer,&#xD;
      both before and after surgical resection. Recent breakthroughs in technology now allow for&#xD;
      more intensive doses of radiation to be delivered to the body with greater precision. These&#xD;
      newer, more precise radiation treatments, called stereotactic body radiation, deliver more&#xD;
      intensive radiation to a locally advanced tumor and are now being employed in the treatment&#xD;
      of pancreatic cancer. Stereotactic body radiation may increase the chances that surgery will&#xD;
      successfully remove a pancreatic cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this experimental study, all patients will be given a strong combination of antitumor&#xD;
      chemotherapy while receiving injections of an immunotherapy drug consisting of two types of&#xD;
      pancreatic cancer cells that have been modified to make them more easily recognized and&#xD;
      attacked by the immune system. The investigators propose to test this new treatment paradigm&#xD;
      along with stereotactic body radiation in patients with borderline resectable pancreatic&#xD;
      cancer to demonstrate that treatment with this combination of therapies increases the time&#xD;
      until the tumor progresses as well as overall survival.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This protocol attempts to treat pancreatic cancer using a naturally occurring barrier to&#xD;
      xenotransplantation in humans to increase the efficacy of immunizing subjects against their&#xD;
      pancreatic cancer. In this protocol, the transfer of the murine&#xD;
      alpha(1,3)galactosyltransferase [alpha(1,3)GT] gene to immunotherapy component cells results&#xD;
      in the cell surface expression of alpha(1,3)galactosyl-epitopes (alpha gal) epitopes on&#xD;
      membrane glycoproteins and glycolipids. These epitopes are the major target of the hyperacute&#xD;
      rejection response. This response occurs when organs are transplanted from lower animal donor&#xD;
      species into primates and results in rapid destruction of transplanted tissue and an&#xD;
      augmented response against transplant antigens, including antigens not related to the alpha&#xD;
      gal epitopes. Human hosts have pre-existing anti-alpha-gal antibodies that are thought to&#xD;
      result from chronic immunological stimulation due to exposure to alpha-gal epitopes that are&#xD;
      naturally expressed on normal gut flora and these antibodies may comprise up to 1% of serum&#xD;
      IgG. Opsonization and lysis of the immunotherapy component cells mediated by this antibody is&#xD;
      believed to increase the efficiency of antigen processing by targeting vaccine components to&#xD;
      antigen presenting cells via the Fc gamma receptor.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 30, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months (assuming enrollment period of 1 year)</time_frame>
    <description>The primary objective of this study is to assess progression free survival after treatment with a regimen of mFOLFIRINOX with algenpantucel-L immunotherapy followed by SBRT in subjects who have borderline resectable pancreatic cancer.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>30 months (assuming enrollment period of 1 year)</time_frame>
    <description>A secondary objective of this study is to assess overall survival (OS) in pancreatic cancer patients with borderline resectable pancreatic cancer who will receive a regimen of mFOLFIRINOX with algenpantucel-L Immunotherapy followed by SBRT.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency and grade of adverse events of FOLFIRINOX in combination with algenpantucel-L Immunotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months (assuming enrollment period of 1 year)</time_frame>
    <description>A secondary objective of this study is to assess the safety (frequency and grade of adverse events) of administration of algenpantucel-L Immunotherapy given in combination with a standard of care regimen of chemotherapy mFOLFIRINOX followed by SBRT</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immune Response</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months (assuming enrollment period of 1 year)</time_frame>
    <description>A secondary objective of this study is to assess the immunologic responses of subjects with pancreatic cancer undergoing antitumor immunization with algenpantucel-L Immunotherapy as measured by anti-alpha Gal antibodies, and-tumor antibodies, and total IgE.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tumor Response</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months (assuming enrollment period of 1 year)</time_frame>
    <description>A secondary objective of this study is to assess the tumor response rate as measured by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1 and Immune Response Criteria (irRC).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resection Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months (assuming enrollment period of 1 year)</time_frame>
    <description>A secondary objective of this study is to assess the R0 resection rate following neoadjuvant chemotherapy, immunotherapy and SBRT.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Pancreatic Carcinoma Non-resectable</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>mFOLFIRINOX + Algenpantucel-L (HAPa) Immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>SOC mFOLFIRINOX + Algenpantucel-L (HAPa) Immunotherapy&#xD;
Day 93-100 Disease evaluated: Progressive disease = salvage therapy off study. Day 93-100 Disease evaluated: Stable disease or better = SBRT + HAPa on days 1 and 15 of radiotherapy Post SBRT: surgery + adjuvant SOC Gemcitabine + HAPa given 1 and 15 for 6 cycles.&#xD;
Post adjuvant therapy: 6 monthly immunizations with HAPa</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>mFOLFIRINOX</intervention_name>
    <description>mFOLFIRINOX consisting of Oxaliplatin 85 mg/m^2 IV over 2 hours; Irinotecan 180 mg/m^2 IV over 90 minutes; Leucovorin 400 mg/m^2 IV over 2 hours; Fluorouracil 2.4 g/m^2 IV over 46 hours - given on days 15, 29, 43, 57, 71 and 85</description>
    <arm_group_label>mFOLFIRINOX + Algenpantucel-L (HAPa) Immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Oxaliplatin</other_name>
    <other_name>Eloxatin®</other_name>
    <other_name>Irinotecan</other_name>
    <other_name>Camptosar®</other_name>
    <other_name>Leucovorin</other_name>
    <other_name>Citrovorum factor</other_name>
    <other_name>folinic acid</other_name>
    <other_name>Fluorouracil</other_name>
    <other_name>5-Fluorouracil</other_name>
    <other_name>5-FU</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Algenpantucel-L Immunotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>HAPa1 and HAPa2 immunotherapy components Algenpantucel-L Immunotherapy (HAPa) consisting of 300 Million HAPa cells given by intradermal injection for up to 28 doses total.</description>
    <arm_group_label>mFOLFIRINOX + Algenpantucel-L (HAPa) Immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>HyperAcute®-Pancreas</other_name>
    <other_name>HAPa</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SBRT</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects that have at least stable disease at evaluation (day 93-100) are eligible to receive SBRT radiation given at 1.8 Gy per fraction for 28 fractions for a total dose of 50.4 Gy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>mFOLFIRINOX + Algenpantucel-L (HAPa) Immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Gemcitabine</intervention_name>
    <description>Gemcitabine 1000 mg/m^2 given intravenously over 30 minutes for 3 weeks (days 1, 8 and 15) with 1 week rest.&#xD;
Given as adjuvant treatment (days 1, 8 and 15) with 1 week rest for 6 cycles after surgical resection.</description>
    <arm_group_label>mFOLFIRINOX + Algenpantucel-L (HAPa) Immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Gemzar</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A histological diagnosis of adenocarcinoma of the pancreas confirmed by pathology.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have borderline resectable pancreatic cancer with no metastatic spread&#xD;
             as determined by a baseline diagnostic CT scan with intravenous contrast (or MRI). CT&#xD;
             should be performed according to a defined pancreas protocol such as triphasic&#xD;
             cross-sectional imaging with thin slices. Optimal multi-phase technique including a&#xD;
             non-contrast phase plus arterial, pancreatic parenchymal and portal venous phase of&#xD;
             contrast enhancement with thin cuts (3mm) throughout the abdomen is preferred. Studies&#xD;
             must be evaluated by a radiologist and/or surgeon and deemed borderline resectable as&#xD;
             defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Borderline resectable- Tumors considered borderline resectable are defined as&#xD;
                  follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Venous involvement of the SMV/portal vein demonstrating tumor abutment with&#xD;
                  impingement and narrowing of the lumen, encasement of the SMV/portal vein but&#xD;
                  without encasement of the nearby arteries, or short-segment venous occlusion&#xD;
                  resulting from either tumor thrombus or encasement but with suitable vessel&#xD;
                  proximal and distal to the area of vessel involvement, allowing for safe&#xD;
                  resection and reconstruction&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Gastroduodenal artery encasement up to the hepatic artery with either short&#xD;
                  segment encasement or direct abutment of the hepatic artery without extension to&#xD;
                  the celiac axis.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Tumor abutment of the SMA not to exceed greater than 180 degrees of the&#xD;
                  circumference of the vessel wall.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tumors considered to be unresectable due to local advancement include an absence of&#xD;
             distant metastases as well as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Head: Greater than 180 degrees SMA encasement or any celiac abutment or&#xD;
                  unreconstructible SMV/portal occlusion or aortic invasion or encasement.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Body: Greater than 180 degrees SMA or celiac encasement or unreconstructible&#xD;
                  SMV/portal occlusion or aortic invasion.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Tail: SMA or celiac encasement greater than 180 degrees.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Nodal status: Involvement of lymph nodes beyond the field of resection should be&#xD;
                  considered unresectable due to distant spread and therefore not eligible for this&#xD;
                  protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status ≤ 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum albumin ≥ 2.0 gm/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected survival ≥ 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate organ function including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Marrow: WBC ≥3000/mm^3 and platelets ≥100,000/mm^3.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Hepatic: serum total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 mg/dL, ALT (SGPT) and AST (SGOT) ≤3 x upper&#xD;
                  limit of normal (ULN) at time of enrollment. If a patient has elevated liver&#xD;
                  function tests at the time of initial presentation or develops them during&#xD;
                  work-up and they are the result of a mechanical obstruction of biliary drainage&#xD;
                  by tumor compression or invasion, a biliary drain may be placed as described in&#xD;
                  NCCN Practice Guidelines in Oncology V2.2012. If drainage allows for the liver&#xD;
                  function tests to come within inclusion criteria, the patient may be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Renal: serum creatinine (sCr) ≤2.0 x ULN, or creatinine clearance (Ccr) ≥30&#xD;
                  mL/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have the ability to understand the study, its inherent risks, side&#xD;
             effects and potential benefits and be able to give written informed consent to&#xD;
             participate. Patients may not be consented by a durable power of attorney (DPA).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All subjects of child producing potential must agree to use contraception or avoidance&#xD;
             of pregnancy measures while enrolled on study and receiving the experimental product,&#xD;
             and for one month after the last immunization.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt;18-years-old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other malignancy within five years, unless the probability of recurrence of the prior&#xD;
             malignancy is &lt;5% as determined by the Principal Investigator based on available&#xD;
             information. Patient's curatively treated for squamous and basal cell carcinoma of the&#xD;
             skin or patients with a history of malignant tumor in the past that have been disease&#xD;
             free for at least five years are also eligible for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of organ transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current, active immunosuppressive therapy such as cyclosporine, tacrolimus, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects taking chronic systemic corticosteroid therapy for any reason are not&#xD;
             eligible. Subjects may receive steroids as prophylactic anti-emetics per the&#xD;
             mFOLFIRINOX regimen. Subjects receiving inhaled or topical corticosteroids are&#xD;
             eligible. Subjects who require chronic systemic corticosteroids after beginning&#xD;
             treatment, will be removed from study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant or uncontrolled congestive heart failure (CHF), myocardial infarction or&#xD;
             significant ventricular arrhythmias within the last six months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has active, uncontrolled bacterial, viral, or fungal infection(s) requiring&#xD;
             systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Autoimmune disease (e.g., systemic lupus erythematosis (SLE), rheumatoid arthritis&#xD;
             (RA), etc.). Patients with a remote history of asthma or mild active asthma are&#xD;
             eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other serious medical conditions that may be expected to limit life expectancy to less&#xD;
             than 2 years (e.g., active liver cirrhosis) or a serious illness in medical opinion of&#xD;
             the clinical investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition, psychiatric or otherwise, that would preclude informed consent,&#xD;
             consistent follow-up or compliance with any aspect of the study (e.g., untreated&#xD;
             schizophrenia or other significant cognitive impairment, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A known history of allergy or hypersensitivity to any of the study drugs or any of&#xD;
             their excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or nursing women due to the unknown effects of immunization on the developing&#xD;
             fetus or newborn infant. (For patients with child bearing potential, a βHCG must be&#xD;
             completed within 14 days of first treatment).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known HIV positive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with chemotherapy or radiation for pancreatic cancer or prior&#xD;
             treatment with radiation for other diagnoses to expected pancreatic cancer treatment&#xD;
             fields.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current grade II or higher peripheral neuropathy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Louisville</name>
      <address>
        <city>Louisville</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40292</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lahey Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Burlington</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>New Mexico Cancer Care Alliance</name>
      <address>
        <city>Albuquerque</city>
        <state>New Mexico</state>
        <zip>87106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seattle Cancer Care Alliance</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.newlinkgenetics.com</url>
    <description>Click here for more information regarding NewLink Genetics.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>May 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 25, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 27, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 1, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <disposition_first_submitted>February 22, 2019</disposition_first_submitted>
  <disposition_first_submitted_qc>February 22, 2019</disposition_first_submitted_qc>
  <disposition_first_posted type="Actual">February 26, 2019</disposition_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 26, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 26, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pancreatic Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Immunotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Vaccine Therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leucovorin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted, but a results disposition has been submitted           -->
</clinical_study>

