<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02408770</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UHSM0315</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2016BS001</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02408770</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Breast Cancer - Anti-Progestin Prevention Study 1</brief_title>
  <acronym>BC-APPS1</acronym>
  <official_title>A Pilot Prevention Study of the Effects of the Anti-progestin Ulipristal Acetate (UA) on Surrogate Markers of Breast Cancer Risk</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Manchester</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this study is to determine the effects of the antiprogestin&#xD;
      ulipristal acetate (UA) on the epithelial and stromal compartments of the normal breast in&#xD;
      women at increased risk of breast cancer (BC) and to relate these effects to quantitative&#xD;
      changes on multiparametric magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). The goal is to define predictive&#xD;
      imaging biomarkers for subsequent testing in randomised prevention trials of antiprogestins.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Breast cancer (BC) is the commonest cancer, affecting 1.4 million women per year of whom a&#xD;
      third die from the disease. There is an urgent need for new approaches to BC prevention.&#xD;
      Progesterone is a hormone that is produced naturally from a woman's ovaries during each&#xD;
      menstrual cycle and is often used in hormone replacement therapy (HRT) after the menopause.&#xD;
      When used in HRT progesterone increases the risk of BC and BC death. In experiments in mice&#xD;
      and rats progesterone has been shown to increase the growth of the normal mammary gland (the&#xD;
      rodent breast). When human breast tissue is grown in the laboratory it also grows in response&#xD;
      to progesterone. In particular progesterone has been shown to increase the growth of&#xD;
      particular cells called stem cells which survive for a long time in the breast. It is thought&#xD;
      that the exposure of these stem cells to progesterone over many years is the reason that&#xD;
      women whose periods start early and finish late or those who do not have a pregnancy to&#xD;
      interrupt their menstrual cycles and those that take HRT all have an increased risk of BC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this project the investigators will use a drug that blocks the effects of progesterone&#xD;
      called ulipristal acetate (UA, EsmyaTM) that is currently licenced in the treatment of&#xD;
      fibroids of the uterus. When used to treat fibroids UA is very well tolerated with no&#xD;
      increase in side effects compared to a placebo tablet. 30 women at increased risk of BC will&#xD;
      be recruited and have magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scan and mammogram followed by a&#xD;
      biopsy of one breast. After 3 months of UA treatment the MRI will be repeated along with a&#xD;
      biopsy from the other breast. The effects of UA on many different cell types in the biopsies,&#xD;
      including the stem cells and also the tissues like collagen that support them will be&#xD;
      examined in detail. The effects of UA treatment on gene and protein expression in the breast&#xD;
      tissue will also be examined. The goal is to identify which women will be sensitive or&#xD;
      resistant to UA as a BC prevention treatment. In addition changes in the MRI scans with UA&#xD;
      treatment will be examined using several different analysis techniques to try and identify&#xD;
      who will likely benefit from UA treatment in the future without the need for biopsies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 29, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change in the proliferation of normal breast epithelium, assessed by Ki67</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>percentage of luminal basal and mixed colonies by adherent and FACS analyses</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in MRI background parenchymal enhancement assessed by BiRADs scoring</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>proportion of participants with specific side effects from ulipristal acetate</measure>
    <time_frame>monthly to 4 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>ulipristal acetate 5mg daily for 3 months</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ulipristal acetate</intervention_name>
    <description>selective progesterone receptor modulator</description>
    <arm_group_label>treatment</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Esmya</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Premenopausal females aged between 25 and 45 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Regular menses&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known BRCA1 or BRCA2 mutation or moderate to high risk of developing BC defined as&#xD;
             &gt;17% lifetime risk from age 20 or &gt;3% risk between 40-50 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ovulatory menstrual cycles&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  eGFR ≥ 40mls/min/1.73m2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Personal history of breast, uterine, cervical or ovarian cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breast feeding within the last 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or planning for pregnancy in the next 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to radiological contrast media or to ulipristal acetate or its&#xD;
             excipients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current treatment with:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Anti-estrogens, GnRH analogues or hormonal contraceptives, corticosteroids or&#xD;
        antiplatelet/anticoagulant therapy or moderate or potent inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  APTT and PT outside the normal institutional ranges. Hb &lt;100g/l and platelet count&#xD;
             &lt;150x109/l. Serum creatinine, bilirubin, ALT, ALP or LDH &gt;1,5xULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindications to MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior breast enhancement/augmentation surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Genital bleeding of unknown aetiology&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sacha J Howell, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Manchester</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospitals of South Manchester</name>
      <address>
        <city>Manchester</city>
        <zip>M204BX</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 31, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 3, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ulipristal acetate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

