<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02339012</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>150063</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>15-AG-0063</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02339012</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Genetic and Epigenetic Signatures of Translational Aging Laboratory Testing (GESTALT)</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Genetic and Epigenetic Signatures of Translational Aging Laboratory Testing (GESTALT)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute on Aging (NIA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Biomarkers are substances in people s blood and tissues. They help researchers understand&#xD;
      diseases and signs of aging. Scientists want to do more research on biomarkers to find ways&#xD;
      to improve quality of life in old age.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To learn more about biomarkers and their relationship to aging.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Adults at least 20 years old who weigh at least 110 pounds and have a body mass index below&#xD;
      30. They must agree that their genetic samples can be collected, studied, and stored.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be screened with medical history, physical exam, and blood and urine&#xD;
           tests. They will have heart tests and nurse will assess their veins. They will fill out&#xD;
           a questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will have a 2-day baseline visit. Then they will return every 2 years for&#xD;
           up to 10 years. These follow-up visits will repeat the baseline visit:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Repeat of screening procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Physical performance tests like balance and walking tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Leg and grip strength tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Health and mental state questions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Memory and problem solving tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cytapheresis. Blood will be removed through a needle in the vein of one arm and run&#xD;
           through a machine. The blood will be returned through a needle in a vein of the other&#xD;
           arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Visits may also include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Magnetic resonance imaging scans. Participants will lie on a table that slides in and&#xD;
           out of a machine that takes pictures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Diabetes test. After fasting, participants will drink a sweet drink and give blood.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Breathing and walking tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Wearing a device that record physical activity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Scan of the abdomen and the right leg.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A small amount of muscle tissue and/or skin removed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Under the assumption that aging is caused by dysfunction of specific biological mechanisms,&#xD;
      it is reasonable to hypothesize that slowing aging should delay the onset of chronic diseases&#xD;
      that typically affect older persons and improve their longevity and quality of life. Indeed,&#xD;
      there is emerging evidence that factors associated with premature mortality are also involved&#xD;
      in multiple pathologic conditions typical of aging. Scientists have suggested that these&#xD;
      factors are genetic in nature and involve variations in the genetic code sequence. Contrary&#xD;
      to this view, genetic approaches to study of aging have had limited success and it has been&#xD;
      argued that the study of aging and longevity requires a more comprehensive analysis that&#xD;
      includes non-genetic biomarkers such as epigenetic, gene expression and protein biomarkers.&#xD;
      This is because these non-genetic biomarkers reflect the interaction between genetic&#xD;
      variation and environmental/behavioral factors. A major limitation in this approach to date&#xD;
      is that most studies of epigenetic, gene expression and protein biomarkers rely on blood&#xD;
      specimens, which may not recapitulate the biology of other tissues. In addition, although all&#xD;
      cell types from the same person have exactly the same genetic code; information on epigenetic&#xD;
      modifications, RNAm, and protein expression likely differ across cell types and at different&#xD;
      points in time. Thus, global measures of these biomarkers in specific cell types can be&#xD;
      affected by percentages of these cell types in the blood, and it is well known that such&#xD;
      percentages change with aging and chronic diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To overcome the limitations described above, we plan to use cytapheresis to collect large&#xD;
      number of PBMCs in a group of healthy individuals dispersed over a wide age-range. The&#xD;
      collection of large number of PBMCs is essential to obtain enough cells for each cell type to&#xD;
      support measurements of the biomarkers of interest. The information collected will be used to&#xD;
      identify biomarkers that change with aging in individuals who are initially healthy,&#xD;
      independent of changes in specific PBMCs cell types. We will also develop a statistical model&#xD;
      that can be used by other studies of biomarkers to adjust their analysis for PBMCs cell type&#xD;
      composition without having to perform complex and expensive measures, such as flow cytometry.&#xD;
      The data collected in PBMCs will be compared to similar biomarker data obtained from&#xD;
      muscle/fat and skin biopsies to understand to what extent biomarkers measured in the blood&#xD;
      recapitulate similar changes that occur in different human tissues. Finally, once&#xD;
      methodological limitations of measuring biomarkers in the blood have been addressed, we plan&#xD;
      to assess the relationship of biomarkers assessed in specific circulating cell types, in the&#xD;
      whole blood, bone marrow aspirate and in muscle/fat and skin biopsies to physiological&#xD;
      measures that typically change with aging, including measures of body composition&#xD;
      (anthropometrics, CT scan and MRI), energetics (spirometry at rest and during different&#xD;
      degrees of exercise intensity), homeostatic equilibrium (hormones and inflammatory markers),&#xD;
      neurological function (neurocognitive testing, brain MRI, nerve conduction studies). At the&#xD;
      first follow-up, Year 2 (and every four years after it) we will focus on in depth&#xD;
      characterization of phenotypes that are relevant for aging. This strategy reduces the burden&#xD;
      to participants but still allows delineating trajectories of essential variables and relate&#xD;
      them longitudinally. The final goal is to develop new hypotheses about the biological nature&#xD;
      of the aging process and how aging is associated with decline of physical and cognitive&#xD;
      function.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 15, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2099</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2099</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Development of state-of-theart expression/methylation /protein PBMC atlas in aging</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>measurement of epigenetic, gene expression, and protein biomarkers</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>5</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Volunteers</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>20-34</arm_group_label>
    <description>healthy individuals ages 20-34 years</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>35-49</arm_group_label>
    <description>healthy individuals ages 35-49 years</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>50-64</arm_group_label>
    <description>healthy individuals ages 50-64 years</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>65-79</arm_group_label>
    <description>healthy individuals ages 65-79 years</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>80+</arm_group_label>
    <description>healthy individuals ages 80 years and older</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Healthy Volunteers&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  Since the study of gene expression and epigenetic regulation are essential aims of&#xD;
             GESTALT, all participants are required to consent to DNA/RNA testing and storage at&#xD;
             the Screening Visit and all subsequent Follow-up Visits. Participants that refuse&#xD;
             genetic testing and storage will not be eligible to participate or to continue to&#xD;
             participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The criteria below pertain only to the Screening and Baseline Visits, except where&#xD;
        otherwise noted. If any of the conditions develop while the participant is in the study,&#xD;
        the participant remains in the study. In particular, participants who develop neurological&#xD;
        or motor problems from medical conditions such as stroke or Parkinson s disease may be&#xD;
        retained in the study, although they are excluded from specific testing in which their&#xD;
        underlying health condition is an exclusion criterion. Participants that develop severe&#xD;
        cognitive problems and are diagnosed by the cognition group with dementia, will no longer&#xD;
        be able to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age greater than or equal to 20 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are willing to return every 2 years for study visit procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agree to genetic (DNA/RNA) sample collection, analysis and storage.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have good venous access for cytapheresis and are in good health as&#xD;
&#xD;
        determined by the Apheresis Health History Questionnaire and are found eligible for&#xD;
        apheresis (Apheresis Eligibility form).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weigh greater than or equal to 110lbs and a body mass index (BMI) &lt; 30.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have established genetic diseases such as sickle cell, hemochromatosis (iron&#xD;
             overload), cystic fibrosis or Ehlers-Danlos syndrome (connective tissue disorder).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have autoimmune diseases such as Hashimoto s thyroiditis, Myasthenia Gravis or&#xD;
             Rheumatoid arthritis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Report that they are able to perform daily self- care without assistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Report that they able to walk independently for at least 400 meters without assistance&#xD;
             and without developing severe symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Report they are able to perform normal activities of daily living without shortness of&#xD;
             breath (walking or climbing stairs) or other severe symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have cognitive impairment based on mental status screening tests and&#xD;
             evaluations) .&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have a history of cardiovascular disease or cerebrovascular disease including&#xD;
             angina (requiring treatment), myocardial infarction, congestive heart failure,&#xD;
             uncontrolled hypertension, pacemaker, stroke or transient ischemic attacks (TIA).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have a history of diabetes (requiring any medical treatment other than diet and&#xD;
             exercise) and their fasting Glucose is &lt;126 mg/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have active (any activity in the last 10 years) cancer, except for locally&#xD;
             limited basal cell cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have clinically significant hormonal dysfunction (Self-reported or laboratory&#xD;
             values out of range. Mild hypothyroidism in participants over 60 is not considered&#xD;
             exclusion).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have a history of neurological diseases or birth defects (other than minor&#xD;
             anatomical abnormalities, which do not affect physical and/or cognitive function).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have a history of kidney or liver disease (associated with reduced kidney or&#xD;
             liver function).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have a history of severe gastrointestinal (G.I.) diseases, with symptoms or&#xD;
             requiring chronic treatment such as gastroesphageal reflux disease (GERD), Crohn s&#xD;
             disease or ulcerative colitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have a history of severe pulmonary disease such as chronic obstructive&#xD;
             pulmonary disease (COPD) or asthma requiring continuous medication use.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have muscle-skeletal conditions due to diseases or traumas (that cause&#xD;
             pathological weakness and/or chronic pain).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have a history of severe psychiatric conditions associated with behavioral&#xD;
             problems or requiring absolute and continuous need for medical treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have any medical condition that requires absolute and continuous need for long&#xD;
             term treatment with antibiotics, corticosteroids, immunosuppressors, H2 blockers&#xD;
             and/or proton pump inhibitors, or pain medications.-Do not have a medical condition&#xD;
             that requires the use of chronic anticoagulant medication such as Coumadin, heparin or&#xD;
             antiplatelet agents other than low dose aspirin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have important sensory deficits (legally blind and/or any condition that&#xD;
             precludes the participant from being tested with standard neuropsychological tests or&#xD;
             providing informed consent).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are able to read and speak English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are able to understand the study risks and procedures, and consent to participate in&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not currently pregnant or a nursing mother.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not currently smoke and have not smoked in the past 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Veins are adequate for cytapheresis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No current illness that as judged by the study physician substantially increases the&#xD;
             risks associated with cytapheresis (active infections, allergies, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No history of allergy to acid- citrate- dextrose (ACD) anticoagulant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No history of an active bleeding disorder such as hemophilia or Von Willebrand&#xD;
             disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No history of seizures within the last 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No history of Lyme disease, unless six weeks post treatment and no new symptoms, of&#xD;
             Chagas disease, Babesiosis, or Leishmanias.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are not claustrophobic and are eligible to perform MRI as per the MRI eligibility form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have hip or knee replacements or other medical conditions that prevent MRI&#xD;
             research scans from being performed&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participant Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        These criteria pertain to the Screening and Baseline Visits. If conditions considered as&#xD;
        exclusion criteria for study entry develop any time after the baseline evaluation, the&#xD;
        participant remains in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV virus infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatitis B or C.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active syphilis, gonorrhea or TB requiring treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  WBC &lt;3,000 or &gt; 12,000/mcrL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &lt; 100,000 or &gt;600,000 /mcrL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &lt; 11.0 g/dL in women and &lt; 12.0 in men.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine &gt;1.6 mg/dl or calculated creatinine clearance &lt; 50 cc/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bilirubin &gt; 1.5 mg/dl (unless higher levels can be ascribed to Gilbert s disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ALT, AST or alkaline phosphatase twice the normal serum concentration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Corrected calcium &lt; 8.5 or &gt; 10.7 mg/dl.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Albumin &lt; 3.1 g/dl.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive Urine Drug Screen (unless taking prescribed medication and at the discretion&#xD;
             of the PI).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently pregnant or a nursing mother.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Furthermore, if the participant is found eligible at screening and baseline but fails a&#xD;
        urine drug screen (unless taking a prescribed medication and at the discretion of the PI)&#xD;
        at any of the subsequent (follow-up) visits, the participant will be asked to return to&#xD;
        repeat the test and if positive, will no longer be eligible to participate in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Luigi Ferrucci, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute on Aging (NIA)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Linda M Zukley, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(410) 350-3983</phone>
    <email>zukleylm@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Luigi Ferrucci, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(410) 558-8110</phone>
    <email>ferruccilu@grc.nia.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institute of Aging, Clinical Research Unit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21224</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>NIA Studies Recruitment</last_name>
      <phone>410-350-3941</phone>
      <email>niastudiesrecruitment@mail.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2015-AG-0063.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 4, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 14, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 14, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 15, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Genome Wide Association</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
  <keyword>Methylation</keyword>
  <keyword>Phenotype</keyword>
  <keyword>Cytometry</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

