<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03526471</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LAAC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03526471</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Omega™ Left Atrial Appendage (LAA) Occluder in Patients With Non-Valvular Atrial Fibrillation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prospective, Single-arm Study to Assess the Safety and Performance of the Omega™ Left Atrial Appendage (LAA) Occluder in Patients With Non-Valvular Atrial Fibrillation and High Bleeding Risk</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vascular Innovations Co. Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>MedPass International</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vascular Innovations Co. Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Atrial fibrillation is associated with increased risk of stroke mostly because of clot&#xD;
      formation in the left atrial appendage, a small alcove in the left atrium heart chamber.&#xD;
      Plugging this appendage with an implantable plug type device, which is placed via a catheter&#xD;
      painlessly in the femoral vein, has been proven to be a reliable alternative to the standard&#xD;
      anti-clotting medication in a number of recent international trials. The Omega device is a&#xD;
      new design of such a plug, made from biocompatible and compressible nitinol and fabric.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up to 195 patients will be enrolled in Europe, assuming that enrolment will stop once the&#xD;
      Omega™ device has been successfully implanted in 150 evaluable patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary performance endpoint of the study is LAA closure (defined as complete seal or&#xD;
      efficient seal with a peri-device leak ≤ 5 mm) at 60 days (+/- 15 days) visit documented by&#xD;
      transoesophageal echocardiogram (TEE/TOE) with colour flow Doppler.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a single arm study to assess the safety and performance of the Omega™ Left Atrial&#xD;
      Appendage (LAA) Occluder in patients with Non-valvular atrial fibrillation (NVAF) and high&#xD;
      bleeding risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be conducted in accordance with the ISO standard ISO 14155 (Clinical&#xD;
      investigation of medical devices for human subjects - Good clinical practice) and other legal&#xD;
      requirements as applicable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary performance endpoint of the study is LAA closure (defined as complete seal or&#xD;
      efficient seal with a peri-device leak ≤ 5 mm) at 60 days (+/- 15 days) visit documented by&#xD;
      transoesophageal echocardiogram (TEE/TOE) with colour flow Doppler.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary safety endpoint of the study is device-related complications (serious adverse&#xD;
      events [SAEs]) through 60 days (+/- 15 days) post-procedural.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following consent a number of assessments will be undertaken prior to the procedure to ensure&#xD;
      the study eligibility criteria are met. These assessments include; medical history, physical&#xD;
      exams, ECG, blood tests, transthoracic echocardiogram, transesophageal echocardiogram and&#xD;
      cardiac CT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The implant procedure will usually be performed under general anaesthetic. A thin catheter is&#xD;
      inserted in the femoral vein in the right groin area and advanced under X-Ray guidance to the&#xD;
      right atrium, then a very small needle is used to cross through to the left atrium to allow&#xD;
      the delivery catheter to place the Omega in the Appendage, guided by both X-Ray and&#xD;
      transesophageal echo. A medication regimen for endocarditis prophylaxis anticoagulation is&#xD;
      recommended post procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following discharge, patients will be seen again at 60 days, 6 months and 12 months to&#xD;
      collect data for the primary performance endpoint (by TTE or TEE) and safety endpoints (mRS,&#xD;
      stroke/TIA assessments, and ECG).&#xD;
&#xD;
      An interim analysis is planned following the collection of 60 day data for the first 10&#xD;
      patients implanted with the device. An additional interim analysis will be performed&#xD;
      following the collection of 60 days (+/- 15 days) data for the first 50 patients implanted&#xD;
      with the device.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Final analysis will be performed once all 150 subjects have been implanted with the device&#xD;
      and completed the study to further document and confirm the safety and effectiveness of the&#xD;
      device.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>LAA closure</measure>
    <time_frame>at 60 days (+/- 15 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Complete seal or efficient seal with a peri-device leak ≤ 5 mm documented by transoesophageal echocardiogram (TEE/TOE) with colour flow Doppler.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Device-related complications</measure>
    <time_frame>through 60 days post-procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Serious adverse event criteria set out in the protocol and being assessed as related to the study device.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Procedure-related complications</measure>
    <time_frame>1 to 6 days post-procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Meeting the serious adverse event criteria set out in the protocol and being assessed as related to the study procedure.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Major bleeding</measure>
    <time_frame>From procedure to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as ≥ BARC 3 bleed</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ischemic stroke</measure>
    <time_frame>From procedure to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Confirmed by Neurologic assessment and appropriate CT/MR imaging</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Systemic embolism</measure>
    <time_frame>From procedure to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Confirmed by appropriate imaging.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pericardial effusion/tamponade</measure>
    <time_frame>From procedure to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Per protocol</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Technical success</measure>
    <time_frame>At implant</time_frame>
    <description>Composite of: Occlusion of the LAA, No device-related complications, No leak &gt;5mm on colour Doppler Transesophageal Echocardiography (TEE),</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Procedural success</measure>
    <time_frame>At procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Composite of: Technical success, No procedure-related complications except uncomplicated (minor) device embolization resolved by percutaneous retrieval during the procedure without surgical intervention or damage to surrounding cardiovascular structures.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Atrial Fibrillation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Left Atrial Appendage (LAA) Occluder</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Left Atrial Appendage (LAA) Occluder</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Omega™ Left Atrial Appendage (LAA) Occluder</intervention_name>
    <description>catheter delivery of Omega device in the left atrial appendage</description>
    <arm_group_label>Left Atrial Appendage (LAA) Occluder</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 60 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Documented paroxysmal, persistent, or permanent non-valvular atrial fibrillation (AF)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. At increased risk of stroke or systemic embolism defined as CHADS2 score &gt; 2 or a&#xD;
             CHA2DS2-VASc score &gt; 3&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Deemed, by investigator, to be unsuitable or contraindicated for long term oral&#xD;
             anticoagulation therapy due to high bleeding risk&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. To have suitable anatomy for percutaneous LAA occlusion procedure with a single Omega™&#xD;
             device based on CT scan evaluation&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Able and willing to comply with the required medication regimen post-device implant&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Able to understand and willing to provide written informed consent to participate in&#xD;
             the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Able to and willing to return for required follow-up visits and examinations.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Requires long-term oral anticoagulation therapy for any indication other than atrial&#xD;
             fibrillation&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Contraindicated for or allergic to aspirin, clopidogrel, warfarin or novel oral&#xD;
             anticoagulant (NOAC) use&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Has undergone surgical atrial septal defect (ASD) repair or has an ASD closure device&#xD;
             implanted&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Has undergone surgical patent foramen ovale (PFO) repair or has a PFO closure device&#xD;
             implanted&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Implanted with a mechanical heart valve prosthesis thus requiring long term oral&#xD;
             anticoagulation&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Has any contraindications for a percutaneous catheterization procedure (e.g. subject&#xD;
             is too small to accommodate the transoesophageal echocardiogram (TEE/TOE) probe or&#xD;
             required catheters, or subject has active infection or bleeding disorder)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Stroke or transient ischemic attack (TIA) within 90 days prior to implant procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Underwent any cardiac or non-cardiac intervention or surgery within 30 days prior to&#xD;
             implant, or intervention or surgery is planned within 60 days after implant procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Myocardial infarction (MI) within 90 days prior to implant&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. New York Heart Association Class IV Congestive Heart Failure&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Left ventricular ejection Fraction (LVEF) &lt;30%&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Symptomatic carotid artery disease (defined as &gt;50% reduced diameter with symptoms of&#xD;
             ipsilateral transient or visual TIA evidenced by amaurosis fugax, ipsilateral&#xD;
             hemispheric TIAs or ipsilateral stroke); if subject has a history of carotid stent or&#xD;
             endarterectomy the subject is eligible if there is &gt;50% reduced diameter&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Reversible cause of AF (i.e. secondary thyroid disorders, acute alcohol intoxication,&#xD;
             trauma, recent major surgical procedures)&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. History of idiopathic or recurrent venous thromboembolism requiring long term oral&#xD;
             anticoagulation&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Left atrial appendage is obliterated or surgically ligated&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Resting heart rate &gt;110 bpm&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Thrombocytopenia (defined as &lt; 70,000 platelets/mm3) or anaemia with haemoglobin&#xD;
             concentration of &lt; 10 g/dl (i.e. anaemia as determined by the investigator which would&#xD;
             require transfusion)&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Actively enrolled or plans to enrol in a concurrent clinical study in which the active&#xD;
             treatment arm may confound the results of this trial&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Active endocarditis or other infection producing bacteraemia&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Subject has a known malignancy or other illness where life expectancy is less than 2&#xD;
             years&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Impaired renal function with eGFR &lt;40 ml/min/1.73 m2&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. More than mild hepatic failure, i.e. ALT, AST, or Alkalic Phosphatase &gt;2× upper limit&#xD;
             of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
        Echocardiographic Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Intracardiac thrombus - including LAA - visualized by echocardiographic imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Existing circumferential pericardial effusion &gt;2mm&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Significant mitral valve stenosis (i.e. mitral valve area &lt;1.5 cm2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. High risk patent foramen ovale (PFO), defined as an atrial septal aneurysm (atrial&#xD;
             septal excursion &gt;15mm; excursion defined as maximal protrusion of the ASA beyond the&#xD;
             plane of the atrial septum during cardiac cycle) or large shunt (substantial passage&#xD;
             of bubbles, i.e. &gt;25, within 3 cardiac cycles from appearing in the right atrium)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Complex atheroma with mobile plaque of the descending aorta and/or aortic arch&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Cardiac tumour&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. LAA anatomy cannot accommodate an Omega™ device (as per IFU)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Placement of the device would interfere with any intracardiac or intravascular&#xD;
             structure.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aidan Mulloy</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Eclipse Medical Ltd.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rigshospitalet</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen</city>
        <zip>2100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chulalongkorn University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pathum Wan</city>
        <state>Bangkok</state>
        <zip>12000</zip>
        <country>Thailand</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
    <country>Thailand</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 3, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 3, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 16, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 25, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 25, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Left Atrial Appendage</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-valvular atrial fibrillation</keyword>
  <keyword>High Bleeding Risk</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

