<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03522454</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>378469</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03522454</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The PERFORM-TAVR Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>PERFORM-TAVR</acronym>
  <official_title>Protein and Exercise to Reverse Frailty in OlderR Men and Women Undergoing TAVR: The PERFORM-TAVR Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jewish General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of British Columbia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>McGill University Health Centre/Research Institute of the McGill University Health Centre</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>St. Boniface Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Montreal Heart Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hamilton Health Sciences Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ottawa Heart Institute Research Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Unity Health Toronto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sunnybrook Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hopital du Sacre-Coeur de Montreal</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centre hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal (CHUM)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Jewish General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The PERFORM-TAVR trial (Protein and Exercise to Reverse Frailty in OldeR Men and women&#xD;
      undergoing Transcatheter Aortic Valve Replacement) is a multicenter randomized clinical trial&#xD;
      with a parallel-group design. The investigators will screen consecutive patients ≥70 years of&#xD;
      age before TAVR and enrol those that have evidence of physical frailty defined by an SPPB&#xD;
      score ≤8 or an SF36-PF score ≤55. The investigators will randomly allocate 200 patients to&#xD;
      receive a multi-faceted intervention consisting of a home-based exercise program and a&#xD;
      protein-rich oral nutritional supplement or usual lifestyle counselling. The primary endpoint&#xD;
      will be the change in SF36-PF score at 12 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      STUDY DESIGN:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The PERFORM-TAVR trial (Protein and Exercise to Reverse Frailty in OldeR men and woMen&#xD;
      undergoing Transcatheter Aortic Valve Replacement) is a multicenter randomized clinical trial&#xD;
      with a parallel-group design. We will screen consecutive patients ≥70 years of age before&#xD;
      TAVR and enroll those that have evidence of physical frailty defined as an SPPB score ≤8 or&#xD;
      an SF36-PF score ≤55. The SPPB and SF36-PF were chosen as the main inclusion criteria and&#xD;
      also as key endpoints based on their ease-of-use, reproducibility, responsiveness to change,&#xD;
      and superior predictive value for mortality and patient-centered outcomes in the Frailty-AVR&#xD;
      Study. We will randomly allocate 200 patients to receive a multi-faceted intervention&#xD;
      consisting of home-based exercise and protein supplementation or standard-of-care lifestyle&#xD;
      counselling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      INTERVENTION GROUP:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The multi-faceted intervention consists of two synergistic components performed by&#xD;
      participants at their homes. The first component is a home-based supervised exercise program&#xD;
      that combines walking and weight-bearing exercises to build strength and balance performed&#xD;
      for 12 weeks after the patient is discharged home post-TAVR. The exercises are based on the&#xD;
      WEBB program that was developed at the University of Sydney and validated to help therapists&#xD;
      individually prescribe progressive exercise that is challenging but safe for older adults&#xD;
      (http://www.webb.org.au/attachments/File/WEBB_draft_19.pdf). Starting as soon as the patient&#xD;
      returns home post-TAVR, a trained therapist (TT; physiotherapist or certified exercise&#xD;
      physiologist, depending on local expertise) will visit their home for 1 hour twice weekly&#xD;
      over a 12-week period to supervise and tailor the exercises according to each individual's&#xD;
      capability and progress, and to reinforce the goal of moderate-intensity aerobic activity&#xD;
      such as brisk walking at least 30 minutes 5 days per week. If the patient is transferred to a&#xD;
      convalescence or inpatient rehabilitation facility or another hospital, the TT will defer&#xD;
      home visits until they are discharged to their home. If the patient is referred to an&#xD;
      outpatient rehabilitation program, the TT will continue to perform home visits concurrently.&#xD;
      The low use of center-based rehabilitation reflects well-known accessibility barriers in our&#xD;
      Canadian healthcare environment and reaffirms the high relevance of our home-based&#xD;
      intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To monitor compliance, the TT will ask patients to note their daily exercises in their log&#xD;
      book and wear a wrist-worn accelerometer (Garmin Vivofit 4) to record daily step counts. The&#xD;
      accelerometer provides motivational cues such as individualized daily step count goals and&#xD;
      gentle beeps to remind patients to move when they have been sedentary for a prolonged period&#xD;
      during the day. We previously used the Garmin Vivofit in an elderly cardiac population as&#xD;
      part of the Get Going Trial and found it to be &quot;geriatric-friendly&quot; owing to its minimalist&#xD;
      interface, large font size, lightweight waterproof design, and year-long battery that does&#xD;
      not necessitate charging or computer syncing. The majority of patients (including those ≥80&#xD;
      years) reported a high level of comprehension and satisfaction with this device. The TT will&#xD;
      sync the patient's accelerometer devices at every home visit using a smartphone or tablet,&#xD;
      review their step counts, and provide personalized coaching to increase daily walking.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The second component is a protein-rich oral nutritional supplement (Ensure Enlive) with 20g&#xD;
      protein and 1.5g HMB per serving, delivered as a ready-to-drink beverage in 235 mL bottles,&#xD;
      consumed twice daily for 4 weeks pre-TAVR and 12 weeks after the patient is discharged home&#xD;
      post-TAVR. This beverage contains 350 calories, and is provided in chocolate and vanilla&#xD;
      flavors. It should be consumed with breakfast (first serving of the day) and with exercise&#xD;
      (second serving of the day), not before meals, so as to supplement rather than replace food&#xD;
      intake. The HMB ingredient stimulates muscle protein synthesis, particularly when combined&#xD;
      with exercise due to the muscle priming effect. To monitor and promote compliance, the TT&#xD;
      will ask patients to note their beverage consumption in their log book, instruct them to&#xD;
      consume a beverage during home exercise sessions, periodically replenish their supply of&#xD;
      beverages during home visits, and perform bottle counts. The log book provided to the&#xD;
      participants also contains information on healthy eating and maintaining an active lifestyle&#xD;
      (same as control group).&#xD;
&#xD;
      LIFESTYLE COUNSELLING GROUP:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lifestyle counselling consists of formalized usual care - instructing patients to perform&#xD;
      moderate-intensity aerobic activity at least 30 minutes 5 days per week as tolerated and eat&#xD;
      a balanced diet based on the AHA/ACC Guideline on Lifestyle Management. In order to&#xD;
      standardize this counselling and ensure that it is safely carried out in both groups, the TT&#xD;
      will provide and explain information on healthy eating and maintaining an active lifestyle&#xD;
      based on the &quot;Easy Tips for Heart Healthy Eating&quot; and &quot;Walking for a Healthy Heart&quot; brochures&#xD;
      designed by the American Heart Association. The latter outlines practical tips to safely&#xD;
      begin a walking program and gradually increase walking time over a 12-week period to meet the&#xD;
      goal of 150 minutes per week. All of this information will be easily legible in a log book&#xD;
      provided to participants. We will not instruct lifestyle counselling group patients to&#xD;
      consume protein-rich nutritional supplements during the trial unless prescribed by their&#xD;
      treating physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTCOME MEASURES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint is the SF36-PF score at 12 weeks. Secondary endpoints are physical&#xD;
      functioning measured by the Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB), health-related QOL&#xD;
      measured by the 36-Item Short Form Health Survey (SF-36), cognitive function measured by the&#xD;
      Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA), habitual physical activity level measured by the&#xD;
      modified Paffenbarger questionnaire, handgrip strength measured by a Jamar dynamometer, body&#xD;
      composition and phase angle measured by a portable bioimpedance device, frailty measured by&#xD;
      the Essential Frailty Toolset, sarcopenia measured by the SARC-F questionnaire and EWGSOP&#xD;
      criteria, and a composite safety endpoint of all-cause mortality, injurious fall, acute&#xD;
      kidney injury, or readmission for worsening angina, heart failure, or arrhythmia. The&#xD;
      aforementioned primary and secondary endpoints will be re-assessed at 24 weeks to detect&#xD;
      latent effects and sustained adherence, and vital status and questionnaires will be assessed&#xD;
      by telephone at 52 weeks. Clinical events will be defined according to the Valve Academic&#xD;
      Research Consortium-2 data dictionary. A 3-member independent Data Safety and Monitoring&#xD;
      Board will review all adverse events.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 15, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The outcome assessor who will perform the 3 and 6 month visits will be blinded to the participant's assigned intervention.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SF36-PF</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Short-Form 36 Physical Functioning (SF36-PF) scale; range 0-100 (higher is better)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SPPB</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB) scale; range 0-12 (higher is better)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health-related quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Short Form Health Survey (SF-36) scale; population-standardized to mean score of 50 with standard deviation of 10 (higher is better) for the 8 section scores and 2 summary scores</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Habitual physical activity (in kcal per week)</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Modified Paffenbarger activity scale; range 0-upwards (higher is better)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frailty</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Essential Frailty Toolset (EFT) scale; range 0-5 (lower is better)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sarcopenia</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>SARC-F scale; range 0-10 (lower is better)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fat free mass (in kg)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Portable bioimpedance device; biological range (higher is better)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase angle (in degrees)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Portable bioimpedance device; biological range (higher is better)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Handgrip strength (in kg)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Jamar dynamometer; range 0-upwards (higher is better)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cognitive function</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA) scale; range 0-30 (higher is better)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants suffering composite safety endpoint</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>All-cause mortality, injurious fall, acute kidney injury, or readmission for worsening angina, heart failure, or arrhythmia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants suffering death from any cause</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>All-cause mortality assessed by medical records and telephone contact</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Frail Elderly</condition>
  <condition>Exercise</condition>
  <condition>Dietary Supplements</condition>
  <condition>Postoperative Care</condition>
  <condition>Rehabilitation</condition>
  <condition>Transcatheter Aortic Valve Replacement</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intervention group: Combination of a protein-rich oral nutritional supplement consumed twice daily for 4 weeks pre-TAVR and 12 weeks after the patient is discharged home post-TAVR, and a home-based supervised exercise program that combines walking and weight-bearing exercises to build strength and balance performed for 12 weeks after the patient is discharged home post-TAVR.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lifestyle counselling group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Lifestyle counselling group: Recommendation to perform moderate-intensity aerobic activity at least 30 minutes 5 days per week as tolerated and eat a balanced diet based on the AHA/ACC Guideline on Lifestyle Management.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Protein-rich oral nutritional supplement</intervention_name>
    <description>Ready-to-drink beverage containing 20 g protein and 1.5 g hydroxymethylbutyrate (HMB) per serving, consumed twice daily.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Home-based supervised exercise program</intervention_name>
    <description>WEBB (Weight-bearing Exercise for Better Balance) program combining walking and weight-bearing exercises to build strength and balance, administered by a trained therapist at the participant's home.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥70 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing TAVR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physically frail: SPPB score ≤8 or SF36-PF score ≤ 55 pre-TAVR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed written or verbal consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Decompensated or non-ambulatory class IV symptoms of angina, dyspnea, claudication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled diabetes with HbA1C &gt;8.5% (or mean glucose ≥11.0 in the absence of a&#xD;
             HbA1C test)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &lt;30 mL/min/1.73 m2 by the MDRD equation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cirrhosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to ingredient in beverage&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to safely ingest beverage by mouth&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to walk without human assistance or high-risk of falls&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate-to-severe cognitive impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant language barrier&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID positive or suspected at screening&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>70 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jonathan Afilalo, MD, MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Jewish General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sarah Lantagne</last_name>
    <phone>514-340-8222</phone>
    <phone_ext>28692</phone_ext>
    <email>sarah.lantagne@ladydavis.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jewish General Hospital / McGill University Health Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montreal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H3T 1E2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jonathan Afilalo, MD MSc</last_name>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Sarah Lantagne</last_name>
      <phone>514-340-8222</phone>
      <phone_ext>28692</phone_ext>
      <email>sarah.lantagne@ladydavis.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 17, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 30, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 11, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 7, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 7, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Jewish General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jonathan Afilalo</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Frailty</keyword>
  <keyword>TAVR</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

