<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02807961</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EL-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02807961</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics of ELX-02 in Healthy Adult Volunteers</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 1a, Randomized, Double-blinded, Placebo-controlled, Single-dose Escalation Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability and Pharmacokinetics of ELX-02 in Healthy Adult Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Eloxx Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Eloxx Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is the first study in humans of ELX-02, an advanced synthetic aminoglycoside optimized&#xD;
      as a translational read-through drug (TRID) for the treatment of genetic conditions caused by&#xD;
      nonsense. mutations. This is a classical Phase 1a study designed as a randomized,&#xD;
      double-blinded, placebo-controlled, single dose escalation to evaluate the safety,&#xD;
      tolerability and pharmacokinetics of ELX-02 in healthy adult volunteers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Transferred study to Antwerp, Belgium&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>0-10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence and characteristics of adverse events occurring following single doses of ELX-02</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics</measure>
    <time_frame>0-10 days</time_frame>
    <description>The following PK parameters will be calculated based on ELX-02 plasma concentrations: Cmax, Tmax, AUC24h, AUCinf, AUC144h, t½, mean residence time (MRT), volume of distribution (Vd), clearance (CL), absolute bioavailability (F) and an estimation of ELX-02 dose linearity of PK parameters. The following parameters will be calculated based on ELX-02 urine concentrations: urinary mass excretion of ELX-02 (in mass and %dose) and cumulated urinary excretion (in % dose) for each collection interval and total renal clearance. The following parameters will be calculated from the individual urine drug concentrations: Ae, Ae0-12h, Ae12-24h, Ae24-48h, Ae0-48h, fe.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">42</enrollment>
  <condition>Genetic Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Nonsense Mutations</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo comparator arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>ELX-02, active comparator</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ELX-02</intervention_name>
    <description>Synthetic aminoglycoside</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo comparator</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects must meet all of the following inclusion criteria to be eligible for enrollment in&#xD;
        the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Be able and willing to provide written Informed Consent indicating that the subject&#xD;
             has been informed of all pertinent aspects of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Be willing and able to comply with all scheduled visits, treatment plan, laboratory&#xD;
             tests, and other study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Healthy female subjects and/or male subjects who, at the time of Screening, are&#xD;
             between the ages of 18 and 45 years, inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Healthy is defined as no clinically relevant abnormalities identified by a detailed&#xD;
             medical history, full physical examination, including blood pressure and pulse rate&#xD;
             measurements, 12-lead ECG and clinical laboratory tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Female subjects of non childbearing potential must meet at least one of the following&#xD;
             criteria: Postmenopausal status, defined as: cessation of regular menses for at least&#xD;
             12 consecutive months with no alternative pathological or physiological cause;&#xD;
             post-menopausal status will be confirmed by a serum FSH level, Have undergone a&#xD;
             documented hysterectomy and/or bilateral oophorectomy, Have medically confirmed&#xD;
             ovarian failure Female subjects of non-childbearing potential must agree to undergo&#xD;
             pregnancy test at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
             All other female subjects (including females with tubal ligations) will be considered&#xD;
             to be of childbearing potential and may be enrolled if they have negative pregnancy&#xD;
             tests on Screening and admission days and agree to use a reliable method of&#xD;
             contraception for two weeks (14 days) before and four weeks (28 days) after dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Female subjects of childbearing potential must agree to undergo repeated pregnancy&#xD;
             tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Reliable methods of contraception include: Abstention from sexual intercourse,&#xD;
             Established use of oral, inserted, injected, implanted or transdermal hormonal methods&#xD;
             of contraception (provided the subject plans to remain on the same treatment&#xD;
             throughout the entire study and has been using that hormonal contraceptive for an&#xD;
             adequate period of time to ensure effectiveness), Copper-containing intrauterine&#xD;
             device&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Male subjects must be willing to use an effective method of contraception during the&#xD;
             course of the study until 28 days after drug administration. These include condom,&#xD;
             having undergone a vasectomy or abstain from sexual intercourse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Be on no medications with potential to impair renal function, e.g., NSAIDs, or with&#xD;
             ototoxic potential, e.g., quinine or salicylates.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Non-smoking and no use of any tobacco or nicotine products (by declaration) for a&#xD;
             period of at least 6 months prior to Screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Normal renal function (MDRD GFR &gt; 60 mL/min) based on serum creatinine concentration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Negative HIV, HBsAg or HCV Ab serology tests at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. No personal history of hearing loss, tinnitus, vertigo, imbalance and unsteadiness.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Normal Screening auditory and vestibular assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Body Mass Index (BMI) of 19.0 to 30.0 Kg/m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects with any of the following characteristics/conditions will not be included in the&#xD;
        study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects who are investigational site staff members directly involved in the conduct&#xD;
             of the study and their family members, site staff members otherwise supervised by the&#xD;
             Investigator, or subjects who are the Sponsor employees directly involved in the&#xD;
             conduct of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participation in another clinical trial within 6 months prior to dosing (calculated&#xD;
             from the previous study's last doing day). If the previous trial involved agents with&#xD;
             delayed effects or prolonged metabolism, a 12 months interval is required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Evidence or history of clinically relevant hematological, renal, endocrine, pulmonary,&#xD;
             gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, hepatic, psychiatric, neurologic, or allergic&#xD;
             disease (including drug allergies,). This includes any acute or chronic medical or&#xD;
             psychiatric condition or laboratory abnormality that may increase the risk associated&#xD;
             with study participation or ELX-02 administration or may interfere with the&#xD;
             interpretation of study results and, in the judgment of the Investigator, would make&#xD;
             the subject inappropriate for entry into this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. A positive urine drug screen (cannabinoids, amphetamines, benzodiazepines, and&#xD;
             opiates), at Screening and on admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of regular alcohol consumption (by declaration) exceeding 7 drinks/week for&#xD;
             females or 14 drinks/week for males (1 drink = 150 mL of wine or 360 mL of beer or 45&#xD;
             mL of hard liquor) within 6 months of Screening. A positive alcohol breath test on&#xD;
             admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Screening supine blood pressure (BP) ≥ 140 mm Hg (systolic) or ≥ 90 mm Hg (diastolic),&#xD;
             following at least 5 minutes of supine rest. If BP exceeds protocol-required limits,&#xD;
             BP measurement should be repeated for up to two more times and the last BP value&#xD;
             should be used to determine the subject's eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Screening supine 12-lead ECG demonstrating QTc &gt;450 msec for men or &gt;470 msec for&#xD;
             women, or a QRS interval &gt;120 msec.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects with ANY abnormalities in clinical laboratory tests at Screening, considered&#xD;
             by the Investigator as clinically relevant. In particular, subjects with ALT, AST and&#xD;
             total bilirubin ≥ 1.5 upper limit of normal will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Pregnant or breastfeeding female subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Use of prescription or nonprescription drugs, vitamins, herbal and/or dietary&#xD;
             supplements within 7 days or 5 half-lives (whichever is longer) prior to&#xD;
             administration of ELX-02. As an exception, acetaminophen/paracetamol may be used at&#xD;
             doses of ≤ 2 g/day. Aspirin and NSAIDS should not be administered within 1 week of&#xD;
             study dose. Limited use of non-prescription medications that are not believed to&#xD;
             affect subject safety or the overall results of the study may be permitted on a&#xD;
             case-by-case basis following approval by the Sponsor.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects who donated blood or received blood or plasma derivatives in the 3 months&#xD;
             preceding study drug administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Known allergy or hypersensitivity to any drug and/or to any of the excipients of&#xD;
             ELX-02.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subjects with an inability to communicate well with the Investigators and CRC staff&#xD;
             (e.g., language problem, poor mental development).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subjects with any acute medical situation (e.g. acute infection) within 48 hours prior&#xD;
             to Day 1, which is considered of significance by the Principal Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Subjects with any history of ear disease or surgeries, dizziness or ongoing tinnitus.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Subjects with any abnormality on physical examination by an ENT specialist at&#xD;
             screening that indicates the presence of a vestibular pathology, conductive hearing&#xD;
             loss or balance problem.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Subjects with audiometry results as follows: any pure-tone threshold &gt;25dB, inter-ear&#xD;
             difference in any frequency of ≥ 20dB, word recognition score (discrimination) &lt;92%.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Abnormal ENG/VNG [as indicated by a cumulative response of &lt;12 degrees to caloric&#xD;
             testing (response to warm and cold stimulation united) in either ear] or abnormal c/v&#xD;
             HIT.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. DHI-H score &gt;16&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. THI-H score &gt;14&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>August 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 10, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 20, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 21, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 19, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 19, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Translational read through</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Genetic Diseases, Inborn</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

