<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02802891</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SFRH/BD/108605/2015</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02802891</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The JOIN Project: The Air in Diagnosis and Prevention of Asthma and Allergy</brief_title>
  <acronym>JOIN</acronym>
  <official_title>Projeto JOIN - o ar Como Meio de prevenção e a diagnóstico da Asma e Alergia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universidade do Porto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universidade do Porto</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The JOIN project combines the health and indoor environment research areas to contribute in&#xD;
      the development and validation of a new asthma diagnosis method through exhaled VOC analysis.&#xD;
      This method is more sensitive, more specific, and completely non-invasive. Moreover, the JOIN&#xD;
      project will assess the impact of exposure to the indoor environment, namely endocrine&#xD;
      disruptors, on asthma and allergy development in children.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The JOIN project combines the health and indoor environment research areas to contribute in&#xD;
      the development and validation of a new asthma diagnosis method through exhaled VOC analysis.&#xD;
      This method is more sensitive, more specific, and completely non-invasive. Moreover, the JOIN&#xD;
      project will assess the impact of exposure to the indoor environment, namely endocrine&#xD;
      disruptors, on asthma and allergy development in children. The specific objectives of the&#xD;
      project are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Classify children with asthma and healthy controls using exhaled VOC profiles;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Classify asthma phenotypes using exhaled VOCprofiles;&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Evaluate the influence of prolonged exposure to exogenous VOCs on the exhaled breath&#xD;
           samples;&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Characterize indoor exposure by measuring the concentrations of a set of chemicals&#xD;
           identified as EDCs in indoor air and dust at homes;&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Evaluate the association between exposure to EDCs indoors and children's health outcomes&#xD;
           focused on asthma/allergies and also with the exacerbation of allergies and respiratory&#xD;
           symptoms in those who are already sensitized;&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Investigate which building materials and consumer products might be contributing most to&#xD;
           children's exposure;&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Assess the association between EDCs indoor exposure and lung function, airway&#xD;
           inflammation and responsiveness, and exhaled and urine biomarkers of disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The completion of this project may contribute to the validation of a new asthma diagnostic&#xD;
      method on its way to be introduced in a real clinical context.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The indoor air quality auditing will permit a better understanding of the exposure process to&#xD;
      endocrine disruptors and health effects, mainly in children. The project will also evaluate&#xD;
      and compare EDCs in indoor air and in children, as a result from exposure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Workplan:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Selection and recruitment of the study population&#xD;
&#xD;
           In this project, 75 children aged 6 to 18 years old are expected to be recruited (with&#xD;
           their legal guardian's consent) during clinical visits at the immunoallergology&#xD;
           department of Hospital S. João. All participants will be informed about the aims and&#xD;
           procedures of the project and will be asked to sign an informed consent form. Data&#xD;
           collected will be confidential and participants will have the right to have their data&#xD;
           removed from the study at any time.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Upon agreement with the legal guardians, the visits to participants' homes will be&#xD;
           scheduled. During the visits, EBC and urine samples will be collected, as well as&#xD;
           exhaled breath (non-condensed).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Questionnaire survey A self-administered standardized questionnaire, based on&#xD;
           International study of Asthma and Allergies in Childhood (ISAAC), completed by&#xD;
           parents/legal guardians at home, will be carried out. Socio-demographic and economic&#xD;
           information, smoking and drinking habits, use of personal care products, family history&#xD;
           of diseases and dietary habits will be collected. A set of questions about&#xD;
           respiratory/allergic health of the child, current symptoms/diagnosis (during the past 3&#xD;
           months) will also be included. Simultaneously, features of indoor environment factors,&#xD;
           such as type of dwelling, age of the building, type of flooring, ventilation, will be&#xD;
           identified.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Clinical assessment and biological samples collection Children attending S. João&#xD;
           Hospital Centre for an immunoallergology clinical evaluation will be invited to&#xD;
           participate in this study. Upon acceptance, data from spirometry, fractional exhaled&#xD;
           nitric oxide (FeNO) and skin-prick-tests will be retrieved from the participants'&#xD;
           clinical file. Immediately after the clinical assessment, exhaled breath condensate&#xD;
           (EBC) will be collected from the children by breathing 10 to 15 minutes to an exhaled&#xD;
           air condensing system (portable TurboDECCS). The EBC samples will be stored at -80ºC&#xD;
           until laboratory analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
           During the indoor air quality auditing in children homes, additional EBC samples will be&#xD;
           collected (to understand if there were significant differences when compared to the&#xD;
           samples obtained at the hospital), as well as exhaled air (non-condensed). The exhaled&#xD;
           air will be collected using 1 L Tedlar® bags (SKC Inc. USA) previously cleansed with 3&#xD;
           nitrogen flushes according to manufacturer instructions. The breathing bags serve solely&#xD;
           to store and transport the air and are an already developed and approved product. The&#xD;
           participants will be asked not to ingest food or flavoured beverages in the 2h prior to&#xD;
           breath collection. Children will be instructed to cleanse their mouths with water,&#xD;
           inhale, hold their breath for 5 seconds and subsequently exhale deeply into the Tedlar&#xD;
           bag.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Samples of urine will be collected from children in two moments. The 1st moment will be&#xD;
           on the day next to clinical evaluation in S. João Hospital Centre and the 2nd moment&#xD;
           will be on the day of indoor air quality audit.It will be previously given to each&#xD;
           participant a commercial polypropylene specimen collection containers to obtain 6-10 mL&#xD;
           of urine. Urine samples will be collected at home in early morning after a fasting&#xD;
           period of at least 8 hoursto measure urinary EDCs' metabolites, such as MBzP, MEP, MEHP.&#xD;
           After collection urine samples should be stored a -20°C and delivered on the day of&#xD;
           indoor air quality audit. Subsequently, the samples will be frozen at -20ºC until&#xD;
           analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Clinical diagnosis of asthma (reference standard) will be conducted by 7 different&#xD;
           allergologists attributed randomly to each patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Building inspection and characterization A checklist will be used to get information&#xD;
           regarding possible indoor sources (consumer and cleaning products, furniture, type of&#xD;
           flooring), other building characteristics (e.g. age, ventilation, etc.), recent&#xD;
           refurbishing and outdoor sources, occupant's behaviours and information on the presence&#xD;
           of specific materials and consumers use will also be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Indoor air audit EDCs will be measured in indoor air and dust because indoor air has&#xD;
           been identified as an important source of chemical exposure, while house dust has been&#xD;
           demonstrated to be an important exposure pathway. Dust also provides a record of&#xD;
           chemicals that have been used in the home historically since degradation processes&#xD;
           indoors are typically slow. The chemicals targeted for analysis included phthalates,&#xD;
           bisphenol A, ethanolamines and glycol ethers. These compounds were selected based on&#xD;
           evidence of endocrine disruption, asthma exacerbation, expected presence indoors and in&#xD;
           consumer products, and compatibility with analytical methods developed in household&#xD;
           exposure studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
           EDCs indoor air samples will be collected using a URG personal pesticide sampling&#xD;
           cartridges (University Research Glassware; chapel HilL, Nc), which will be placed in the&#xD;
           children bedroom at approximately breathing height. At the end of the sampling period,&#xD;
           the URG samplers will be stored at -4°c prior to shipping to the laboratory. To measure&#xD;
           EDCs in dust, household vacuum cleaner bags will be used. Dust samples will be collected&#xD;
           from all surfaces of the bedroom floor and also from the surface of objects, such as&#xD;
           shelves, cupboards, doorframes, window frames, TV and audio sets, and personal&#xD;
           computers. Dust from each bag will be sieved with a 100µm metal screen and stored in&#xD;
           glass jars (pre-cleaned with hexane) at -20°C until chemical analysis be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Indoor air VOCs in the children bedrooms will be collected by active sampling, according&#xD;
           to standardized procedures, at the same time as the clinical assessment in order to&#xD;
           evaluate the influence of the pertinent ambient VOCs in the clinical test. The sampling&#xD;
           will be performed using a 5 L flow control pump (SKC Inc. USA) connected to a stainless&#xD;
           steel sorption tube filled with 200 mg of Tenax TA 60/80 (Supelco). The sampling will&#xD;
           start at the same time as the clinical assessment and will be programmed to end after&#xD;
           one hour, giving a representative sample of the indoor air VOCs at the time of the&#xD;
           exhaled breath collection. At the end of the sampling, the tubes will be sealed with&#xD;
           air-tight caps and transported to the laboratory, where they will be stored at room&#xD;
           temperature until analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Laboratory analysis Volatile organic compounds and EDCs will be analysed by electronic&#xD;
           nose (Cyranose 320). Multivariate analysis will be performed to observe if VOC profiles&#xD;
           of participants with asthma is different from those without asthma. Classification&#xD;
           rates, area under the ROC curve, sensitivity and specificity will be estimated for the&#xD;
           different models.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 13, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 13, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Volatile organic compounds in the exhaled breath condensate</measure>
    <time_frame>4 to 8 months after recruitment</time_frame>
    <description>Volatile organic compounds, released from EBC through heating, will be measured by an electronic nose system</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Endocrine disruptors in the urine</measure>
    <time_frame>4 to 8 months after recruitment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ISAAC-based questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>4 to 8 months after recruitment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>24h food questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>4 to 8 months after recruitment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Endocrine disruptors in the house dust</measure>
    <time_frame>4 to 8 months after recruitment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Skin prick tests</measure>
    <time_frame>During recruitment</time_frame>
    <description>Performed during the regular examination in the outpatient clinic. Requested by the physician.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Spirometry with bronchodilation</measure>
    <time_frame>During recruitment</time_frame>
    <description>Performed during the regular examination in the outpatient clinic. Requested by the physician.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">64</enrollment>
  <condition>Asthma</condition>
  <condition>Atopy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Recruitment group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Group of individuals (aged 6 to 18 years old) recruited for the JOIN project. Consent was obtained from legal guardians for individuals under 18.&#xD;
Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
Individuals who refused to partake in the clinical assessment, despite the legal guardians consent.&#xD;
Individuals who provided an insufficient amount of sample (ex: low volume of EBC)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Exhaled breath condensate (no DNA)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Urine (DNA)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Children performing skin prick tests and spirometry with bronchodilation while attending&#xD;
        immunoallergology consultations in the outpatients clinic of S. João Hospital Centre.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals (6 to 18 years old) with skin prick tests and spirometry with&#xD;
             bronchodilation results.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with chronic diseases (other than asthma and atopy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planning to change home address in the next 4 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Low volume of EBC&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refused to participate despite signing written consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>André Moreira, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Universidade do Porto</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centro Hospitalar S. João</name>
      <address>
        <city>Porto</city>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Portugal</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 3, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 13, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 16, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 4, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 4, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 8, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Asthma</keyword>
  <keyword>Allergy</keyword>
  <keyword>Diagnosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Endocrine disruptors</keyword>
  <keyword>Children</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

