<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01905592</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>213551</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1307-BCG, BIG5-13</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>PR-30-5010-C</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01905592</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase III Trial of Niraparib Versus Physician's Choice in HER2 Negative, Germline BRCA Mutation-positive Breast Cancer Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>BRAVO</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase III, Randomized, Open Label, Multicenter, Controlled Trial of Niraparib Versus Physician's Choice in Previously-treated, HER2 Negative, Germline BRCA Mutation-positive Breast Cancer Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tesaro, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>European Organisation for Research and Treatment of Cancer - EORTC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Breast International Group</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Myriad Genetic Laboratories, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>US Oncology Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sarah Cannon</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Facing Our Risk of Cancer Empowered</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tesaro, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to compare progression-free survival (PFS) in patients with&#xD;
      advanced/metastatic breast cancer who have a BRCA mutation when treated with niraparib as&#xD;
      compared to those treated with physician's choice&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase III, randomized, open label, multicenter, controlled trial of niraparib&#xD;
      versus physician's choice in previously-treated, HER2 negative, germline BRCA&#xD;
      mutation-positive breast cancer patients. Niraparib is an orally active PARP inhibitor.&#xD;
      Niraparib (in a 2:1 ratio) will be administered once daily continuously during a 21-day&#xD;
      cycle. Physician's choice will be administered on a 21-day cycle. Health-related quality of&#xD;
      life will be measured. The safety and tolerability will be assessed by clinical review of&#xD;
      adverse events (AEs), physical examinations, electrocardiograms (ECGs), and safety laboratory&#xD;
      values.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 25, 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 26, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 23, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomization will be 2:1 (treatment:control) in at least 215 patients with germline BRCA mutations.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival (PFS) - Central Review Assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of randomization to the date of disease progression or death due to any cause, whichever occurs earlier, up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>The primary objective of this study is to compare progression-free survival (PFS), as assessed by blinded central review, of patients with advanced/metastatic human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 (HER2)-negative gBRCAmut breast cancer when treated with niraparib as compared to those treated with physician's choice single agent chemotherapy standards (eribulin, vinorelbine, gemcitabine or capecitabine). PFS is defined as the date of randomization to the date of disease progression or death due to any cause, whichever occurs earlier as per Response evaluation criteria in solid tumors (RECIST) version 1.1 as determined by central review assessment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>From treatment randomization to date of death of any cause, up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>To compare overall survival of patients with advanced/metastatic HER2-negative gBRCAmut breast cancer who have a gBRCAmut when treated with niraparib as compared to those treated with physician's choice. Overall Survival (OS) is defined as the time from randomization to the date of death of any causes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine Concordance Between gBRCAmut Tests for the Purpose of Developing a Commercial Companion Diagnostic Test</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study</time_frame>
    <description>To establish germline BRCA (gBRCA) mutation status of screened patients using a centrally provided, validated test as well as future tests, and determine concordance between tests for the purpose of developing a commercial companion diagnostic test. The concordance of the candidate companion diagnostic test with the centralized gBRCA mutation test with respect to identifying gBRCA mutated patients will be evaluated using a separate blood sample. The sensitivity and specificity of the companion diagnostic test to the centralized validated test with respect to gBRCA status will be determined along with the corresponding 95% confidence intervals.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and Tolerability</measure>
    <time_frame>End of Study</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate safety and tolerability as measured by all adverse events (AEs). Safety and tolerability will be described using frequency of AEs and AEs of Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) grade &gt;=3. Safety analyses will include all patients who have received at least one dose of study drug and will be evaluated descriptively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival (PFS) - Investigator Assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>PFS is defined as the date of randomization to the date of disease progression or death due to any cause, whichever occurs earlier as per RECIST version 1.1 as determined by Investigator assessment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Treatment Failure</measure>
    <time_frame>Date of randomization to discontinuation of treatment for any reason, up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate time to treatment failure (discontinuation of treatment for any reason). Time to treatment failure is defined from the date of randomization to progression or discontinuation of treatment for any reason, including but not restricted to disease progression, treatment toxicity, and death. If progressive disease occurred earlier than treatment discontinuation, the date of progressive disease was considered the date of treatment failure. At the time of analysis, patients who were continuing to receive treatment were censored on the date of last contact.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response Rate and Duration of Response</measure>
    <time_frame>End of Study</time_frame>
    <description>To compare response rate and duration of response. The best response (complete response [CR], partial response [PR], stable disease [SD] or disease progression [PD]) for each patient will be summarized by treatment arm. The overall response rate (ORR) (ORR = CR+PR) will be summarized by treatment arm along with the corresponding exact 2-sided 95% confidence interval. A chi-square test will be used to compare ORR between the treatment arms. Duration of response will be summarized for the subgroup of patients that obtained objective response (CR or PR) using the Kaplan-Meier method and be displayed graphically where appropriate. The median duration and 2-sided 95% confidence interval for the median will be provided for each treatment arm.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To Compare Time to Deterioration of Health-related Quality of Life: QLQ-C30 and EQ-5D-5L</measure>
    <time_frame>13 months</time_frame>
    <description>To compare time to deterioration of health-related quality of life (HRQoL): European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer Quality of Life Questionnaire (EORTC QLQ-C30) and EuroQol 5 Dimension 5 Level (EQ-5D-5L). Patient reported outcomes were collected via questionnaires (EORTC QLQ-C30 and EQ-5D-5L). These had to be completed within 4 weeks prior to randomization and subsequent questionnaires were filled in every 2 cycles (ie. 6 weeks) while on-treatment and every 3 months while in follow- up. Collection of HRQoL data was limited to the first 12 months after randomization. The primary HRQoL endpoint considered relevant for this study is time to HRQoL deterioration (TTQ). TTQ is defined as the time from randomization to death, progression or clinical relevant deterioration in pre-specified QLQ-C30 scales. Patients who had not experienced an event at the time of analysis were censored at the time of the last completed HRQoL assessment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subsequent Therapies and Potential Relationships With Outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>End of Study</time_frame>
    <description>To describe subsequent therapies and potential relationships with outcomes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess Genetic and Non-genetic Biomarkers</measure>
    <time_frame>End of Study</time_frame>
    <description>To assess genetic and non-genetic biomarkers relating to treatment efficacy. Germline and tumor mutations may be explored including somatic BRCA1 and 2 mutations, reversion mutations, loss of heterozygosity as well as genome landscape and transcriptional or functional measures of homologous recombination (HR) deficiency.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess Outcomes by Germline Mutation BRCA1 vs BRCA2</measure>
    <time_frame>End of Study</time_frame>
    <description>To assess outcomes by germline mutation BRCA1 vs BRCA2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-treatment Data</measure>
    <time_frame>End of Study</time_frame>
    <description>Descriptive summary statistics will be used to summarize post- treatment data (.i.e subsequent anticancer therapies and any new malignancy)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">215</enrollment>
  <condition>Neoplasms, Breast</condition>
  <condition>Carcinoma of Breast</condition>
  <condition>Human Epidermal Growth Factor 2 Negative Carcinoma of Breast</condition>
  <condition>BRCA1 Gene Mutation</condition>
  <condition>BRCA2 Gene Mutation</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Neoplasms</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Physician's choice</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Physician may select from 4 active comparators</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>niraparib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be randomized 2:1 to receive niraparib 300 mg (3x100 mg capsules) once daily for 21 continuous days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>niraparib</intervention_name>
    <description>300 mg (3x100 mg capsules) once daily until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops</description>
    <arm_group_label>niraparib</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>formerly MK-4827</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Physician's choice</intervention_name>
    <description>Choice of 4 standard of care metastatic breast cancer chemotherapies, until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops</description>
    <arm_group_label>Physician's choice</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Germline BRCA1 or BRCA2 mutation; patients with unknown BRCA status who meet NCCN BRCA&#xD;
             screening criteria will be screened for BRCA mutation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Histologically or cytologically confirmed HER2-negative metastatic or locally advanced&#xD;
             disease that is not amenable to resection or radiation with curative intent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Up to 2 prior cytotoxic regimens for advanced or metastatic breast cancer; patients&#xD;
             with no prior cytotoxic regimens for advanced or metastatic disease will only be&#xD;
             allowed if they relapsed during or within 12 months of (neo-) adjuvant cytotoxic&#xD;
             therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prior therapy should have included a taxane and/or anthracycline (unless&#xD;
             contraindication to those) in the neoadjuvant, adjuvant, or advanced/metastatic&#xD;
             setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Hormone receptor positive patients must also have hormone resistant disease; either&#xD;
             relapsed while on adjuvant endocrine treatment, or within one year of completing&#xD;
             adjuvant endocrine treatment, or progression on at least one line of endocrine&#xD;
             treatment for advanced cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. ECOG performance status 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Adequate bone marrow, kidney and liver function&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with platinum resistant cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Symptomatic uncontrolled brain metastases&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Prior diagnosis of Stage IV ovarian cancer; Stage III ovarian cancer must have a&#xD;
             5-year disease-free interval; Stage II ovarian cancer must have a 2-year disease-free&#xD;
             interval&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Known hypersensitivity to the components of niraparib&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Invasive cancer other than breast cancer within 2 years (except basal or squamous cell&#xD;
             carcinoma of the skin that has been definitely treated)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnant or breast feeding patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Immunocompromised patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Known active Hepatitis B or C&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Prior treatment with a PARP inhibitor&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Known history of myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. known and persistent (&gt;4 weeks) &gt;/= grade 3 toxicity or fatigue from prior cancer&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>GSK Clinical Trials</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>GlaxoSmithKline</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tucson</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90033</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90048</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Myers</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33901</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33176</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02111</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Omaha</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Henderson</city>
        <state>Nevada</state>
        <zip>89074</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Clifton Park</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>12065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lake Success</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11042</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Eugene</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97401</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97225</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19111</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37203-1625</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75237</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Worth</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>76104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78217</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Webster</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77598</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Weslaco</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78596</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Low Moor</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>24457</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Everett</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98111</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Green Bay</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>54311</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aalst</city>
        <zip>9300</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brussels</city>
        <zip>1200</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bruxelles</city>
        <zip>1000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edegem</city>
        <zip>2650</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Liège</city>
        <zip>4000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Namur</city>
        <zip>5000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Calgary</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T2N 4N2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kelowna</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V1Y 5L3</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5G 2M9</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montreal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H2L 4M1</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bordeaux</city>
        <zip>33076</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dijon Cedex</city>
        <zip>21079</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lille Cedex</city>
        <zip>59020</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lyon Cedex 08</city>
        <zip>69373</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montpellier</city>
        <zip>34298</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nantes cedex</city>
        <zip>44202</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris Cedex 5</city>
        <zip>75248</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint-Cloud</city>
        <zip>92210</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Heraklion,Crete</city>
        <zip>71110</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Maroussi</city>
        <zip>15123</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nea Kifissia</city>
        <zip>14564</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Neo Faliro</city>
        <zip>18547</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Thessaloniki</city>
        <zip>57001</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Budapest</city>
        <zip>1122</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Debrecen</city>
        <zip>4032</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miskolc</city>
        <zip>3501</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nyiregyhaza</city>
        <zip>4400</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pécs</city>
        <zip>7624</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Szeged</city>
        <zip>6720</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Reykjavik</city>
        <zip>IS-101</zip>
        <country>Iceland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Haifa</city>
        <zip>3109601</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Holon</city>
        <zip>58100</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kfar-Saba</city>
        <zip>44281</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rehovot</city>
        <zip>76100</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tel Aviv</city>
        <zip>6423906</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tel Hashomer</city>
        <zip>52621</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Meldola (FC)</city>
        <state>Emilia-Romagna</state>
        <zip>47014</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Parma</city>
        <state>Emilia-Romagna</state>
        <zip>43100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rimini</city>
        <state>Emilia-Romagna</state>
        <zip>47900</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Viterbo</city>
        <state>Lazio</state>
        <zip>01100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Genova</city>
        <state>Liguria</state>
        <zip>16132</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cremona</city>
        <state>Lombardia</state>
        <zip>26100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milano</city>
        <state>Lombardia</state>
        <zip>20141</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ancona</city>
        <state>Marche</state>
        <zip>60020</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lecce</city>
        <state>Puglia</state>
        <zip>73100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Prato</city>
        <state>Toscana</state>
        <zip>59100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Legnago (VR)</city>
        <state>Veneto</state>
        <zip>37045</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leiden, RC</city>
        <zip>2333 ZA</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Limburg</city>
        <zip>6229HX</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Zwolle</city>
        <zip>8025 AB</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lodz</city>
        <zip>93-513</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Raciborz</city>
        <zip>47-400</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Coimbra</city>
        <zip>3000-075</zip>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lisbon</city>
        <zip>1400-038</zip>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Porto</city>
        <zip>4200-072</zip>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>8035</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Burgos</city>
        <zip>09005</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cáceres</city>
        <zip>10003</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>L'Hospitalet de Llobregat</city>
        <zip>8907</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lerida</city>
        <zip>25198</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lugo</city>
        <zip>27003</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28041</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pamplona</city>
        <zip>31008</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <zip>46009</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <zip>46015</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vigo</city>
        <zip>36312</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Southampton</city>
        <state>Hampshire</state>
        <zip>SO16 6YD</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Northwood</city>
        <state>Middlesex</state>
        <zip>HA6 2RN</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Headington, Oxford</city>
        <state>Oxfordshire</state>
        <zip>OX3 7LJ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sutton</city>
        <state>Surrey</state>
        <zip>SM2 5PT</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bebington, Wirral</city>
        <zip>CH63 4JY</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Belfast</city>
        <zip>BT9 7AB</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edinburgh</city>
        <zip>EH4 2XU</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Glasgow</city>
        <zip>G11 6NT</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>NW1 2PG</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SE1 9RT</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SW3 6JJ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nottingham</city>
        <zip>NG5 1PB</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Whitchurch, Cardiff</city>
        <zip>CF14 2TL</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Greece</country>
    <country>Hungary</country>
    <country>Iceland</country>
    <country>Israel</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
    <country>Poland</country>
    <country>Portugal</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.facingourrisk.org</url>
    <description>Facing our risk of cancer empowered website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 18, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 18, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 23, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>January 29, 2020</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>August 10, 2020</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2020</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Human Epidermal Growth Factor 2 Negative Carcinoma of Breast</keyword>
  <keyword>BRCA1 Gene Mutation</keyword>
  <keyword>BRCA2 Gene Mutation</keyword>
  <keyword>PARP Inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>BRCA</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Niraparib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 13, 2017</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/92/NCT01905592/Prot_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 24, 2017</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/92/NCT01905592/SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <recruitment_details>Previously treated, HER2 negative, germline BRCA mutation positive breast cancer patients were enrolled. The study was designed to randomize 306 patients, however enrollment was ended prematurely due to futility. Results are presented based on the primary analysis (data assessed from enrollment to end of follow-up, up to a maximum of 4 years).</recruitment_details>
      <pre_assignment_details>Of the 215 patients enrolled, 9 patients enrolled based on a local Breast Cancer gene (BRCA) test results were later determined to be BRCA wild type by central testing. Therefore, only 206 of the 215 patients enrolled were included in the analysis, and were considered in centrally confirmed intent-to-treat (ITT) population.</pre_assignment_details>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Physician's Choice</title>
          <description>Physician selection from 4 standard of care metastatic breast cancer chemotherapies (eribulin or vinorelbine or gemcitabine or capecitabine), until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P2">
          <title>Niraparib</title>
          <description>Niraparib 300 milligram (mg) (3x100 mg capsules) once daily until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="71"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="135"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="71"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="135"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
          <drop_withdraw_reason_list>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Disease Progression</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="51"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="104"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Toxicity</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="1"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="16"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Physician Decision</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="2"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>New anti-cancer</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="1"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Protocol Violation</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="1"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Sponsor's decision</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="1"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Not treated</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="7"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="3"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Ongoing in Study</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="7"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Withdrawal by Subject</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="10"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="2"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
          </drop_withdraw_reason_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <population>The centrally-confirmed intent-to-treat population is defined as all randomized patients with a central confirmation of germline BRCA mutation.</population>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Physician's Choice</title>
          <description>Physician selection from 4 standard of care metastatic breast cancer chemotherapies (eribulin or vinorelbine or gemcitabine or capecitabine), until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B2">
          <title>Niraparib</title>
          <description>Niraparib 300 mg (3x100 mg capsules) once daily until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B3">
          <title>Total</title>
          <description>Total of all reporting groups</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="71"/>
            <count group_id="B2" value="135"/>
            <count group_id="B3" value="206"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age, Customized</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>18-64</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="67"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="127"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="194"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>65-74</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="8"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>&gt;=75</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="68"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="135"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="203"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="3"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Ethnicity (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="12"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Not Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="50"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="110"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="160"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="15"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="19"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="34"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Race/Ethnicity, Customized</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Race</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Ashkenazi Jewish descendant</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="11"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>White or Caucasian</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="59"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="108"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="167"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Black</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Asian</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="2"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Other</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Missing</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="7"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Progression Free Survival (PFS) - Central Review Assessment</title>
        <description>The primary objective of this study is to compare progression-free survival (PFS), as assessed by blinded central review, of patients with advanced/metastatic human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 (HER2)-negative gBRCAmut breast cancer when treated with niraparib as compared to those treated with physician's choice single agent chemotherapy standards (eribulin, vinorelbine, gemcitabine or capecitabine). PFS is defined as the date of randomization to the date of disease progression or death due to any cause, whichever occurs earlier as per Response evaluation criteria in solid tumors (RECIST) version 1.1 as determined by central review assessment.</description>
        <time_frame>From the date of randomization to the date of disease progression or death due to any cause, whichever occurs earlier, up to 4 years</time_frame>
        <population>The intent-to-treat population is defined as all randomized patients with a central confirmation of germline BRCA mutation.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Physician's Choice</title>
            <description>Physician selection from 4 standard of care metastatic breast cancer chemotherapies (eribulin or vinorelbine or gemcitabine or capecitabine), until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Niraparib</title>
            <description>Niraparib 300 mg (3x100 mg capsules) once daily until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Progression Free Survival (PFS) - Central Review Assessment</title>
          <description>The primary objective of this study is to compare progression-free survival (PFS), as assessed by blinded central review, of patients with advanced/metastatic human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 (HER2)-negative gBRCAmut breast cancer when treated with niraparib as compared to those treated with physician's choice single agent chemotherapy standards (eribulin, vinorelbine, gemcitabine or capecitabine). PFS is defined as the date of randomization to the date of disease progression or death due to any cause, whichever occurs earlier as per Response evaluation criteria in solid tumors (RECIST) version 1.1 as determined by central review assessment.</description>
          <population>The intent-to-treat population is defined as all randomized patients with a central confirmation of germline BRCA mutation.</population>
          <units>months</units>
          <param>Median</param>
          <dispersion>95% Confidence Interval</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="71"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="135"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="3.1" lower_limit="1.6" upper_limit="7.2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="4.1" lower_limit="2.9" upper_limit="4.5"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Overall Survival</title>
        <description>To compare overall survival of patients with advanced/metastatic HER2-negative gBRCAmut breast cancer who have a gBRCAmut when treated with niraparib as compared to those treated with physician's choice. Overall Survival (OS) is defined as the time from randomization to the date of death of any causes.</description>
        <time_frame>From treatment randomization to date of death of any cause, up to 4 years</time_frame>
        <population>Intent-to-treat Population.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Physician's Choice</title>
            <description>Physician selection from 4 standard of care metastatic breast cancer chemotherapies (eribulin or vinorelbine or gemcitabine or capecitabine), until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Niraparib</title>
            <description>Niraparib 300 mg (3x100 mg capsules) once daily until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Overall Survival</title>
          <description>To compare overall survival of patients with advanced/metastatic HER2-negative gBRCAmut breast cancer who have a gBRCAmut when treated with niraparib as compared to those treated with physician's choice. Overall Survival (OS) is defined as the time from randomization to the date of death of any causes.</description>
          <population>Intent-to-treat Population.</population>
          <units>months</units>
          <param>Median</param>
          <dispersion>95% Confidence Interval</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="71"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="135"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="15.8" lower_limit="12.1" upper_limit="18.4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="14.5" lower_limit="11.7" upper_limit="17.2"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Determine Concordance Between gBRCAmut Tests for the Purpose of Developing a Commercial Companion Diagnostic Test</title>
        <description>To establish germline BRCA (gBRCA) mutation status of screened patients using a centrally provided, validated test as well as future tests, and determine concordance between tests for the purpose of developing a commercial companion diagnostic test. The concordance of the candidate companion diagnostic test with the centralized gBRCA mutation test with respect to identifying gBRCA mutated patients will be evaluated using a separate blood sample. The sensitivity and specificity of the companion diagnostic test to the centralized validated test with respect to gBRCA status will be determined along with the corresponding 95% confidence intervals.</description>
        <time_frame>End of study</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Safety and Tolerability</title>
        <description>To evaluate safety and tolerability as measured by all adverse events (AEs). Safety and tolerability will be described using frequency of AEs and AEs of Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) grade &gt;=3. Safety analyses will include all patients who have received at least one dose of study drug and will be evaluated descriptively.</description>
        <time_frame>End of Study</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Progression Free Survival (PFS) - Investigator Assessment</title>
        <description>PFS is defined as the date of randomization to the date of disease progression or death due to any cause, whichever occurs earlier as per RECIST version 1.1 as determined by Investigator assessment.</description>
        <time_frame>Assessed up to 4 years</time_frame>
        <population>Intent-to-treat Population.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Physician's Choice</title>
            <description>Physician selection from 4 standard of care metastatic breast cancer chemotherapies (eribulin or vinorelbine or gemcitabine or capecitabine), until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Niraparib</title>
            <description>Niraparib 300 mg (3x100 mg capsules) once daily until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Progression Free Survival (PFS) - Investigator Assessment</title>
          <description>PFS is defined as the date of randomization to the date of disease progression or death due to any cause, whichever occurs earlier as per RECIST version 1.1 as determined by Investigator assessment.</description>
          <population>Intent-to-treat Population.</population>
          <units>months</units>
          <param>Median</param>
          <dispersion>95% Confidence Interval</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="71"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="135"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="3.1" lower_limit="2.7" upper_limit="5.1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="5.0" lower_limit="4.2" upper_limit="5.5"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Time to Treatment Failure</title>
        <description>To evaluate time to treatment failure (discontinuation of treatment for any reason). Time to treatment failure is defined from the date of randomization to progression or discontinuation of treatment for any reason, including but not restricted to disease progression, treatment toxicity, and death. If progressive disease occurred earlier than treatment discontinuation, the date of progressive disease was considered the date of treatment failure. At the time of analysis, patients who were continuing to receive treatment were censored on the date of last contact.</description>
        <time_frame>Date of randomization to discontinuation of treatment for any reason, up to 4 years</time_frame>
        <population>Intent-to-treat Population.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Physician's Choice</title>
            <description>Physician selection from 4 standard of care metastatic breast cancer chemotherapies (eribulin or vinorelbine or gemcitabine or capecitabine), until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Niraparib</title>
            <description>Niraparib 300 mg (3x100 mg capsules) once daily until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Time to Treatment Failure</title>
          <description>To evaluate time to treatment failure (discontinuation of treatment for any reason). Time to treatment failure is defined from the date of randomization to progression or discontinuation of treatment for any reason, including but not restricted to disease progression, treatment toxicity, and death. If progressive disease occurred earlier than treatment discontinuation, the date of progressive disease was considered the date of treatment failure. At the time of analysis, patients who were continuing to receive treatment were censored on the date of last contact.</description>
          <population>Intent-to-treat Population.</population>
          <units>months</units>
          <param>Median</param>
          <dispersion>95% Confidence Interval</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="71"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="135"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="2.6" lower_limit="1.6" upper_limit="3.2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="4.3" lower_limit="4.0" upper_limit="5.5"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Response Rate and Duration of Response</title>
        <description>To compare response rate and duration of response. The best response (complete response [CR], partial response [PR], stable disease [SD] or disease progression [PD]) for each patient will be summarized by treatment arm. The overall response rate (ORR) (ORR = CR+PR) will be summarized by treatment arm along with the corresponding exact 2-sided 95% confidence interval. A chi-square test will be used to compare ORR between the treatment arms. Duration of response will be summarized for the subgroup of patients that obtained objective response (CR or PR) using the Kaplan-Meier method and be displayed graphically where appropriate. The median duration and 2-sided 95% confidence interval for the median will be provided for each treatment arm.</description>
        <time_frame>End of Study</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>To Compare Time to Deterioration of Health-related Quality of Life: QLQ-C30 and EQ-5D-5L</title>
        <description>To compare time to deterioration of health-related quality of life (HRQoL): European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer Quality of Life Questionnaire (EORTC QLQ-C30) and EuroQol 5 Dimension 5 Level (EQ-5D-5L). Patient reported outcomes were collected via questionnaires (EORTC QLQ-C30 and EQ-5D-5L). These had to be completed within 4 weeks prior to randomization and subsequent questionnaires were filled in every 2 cycles (ie. 6 weeks) while on-treatment and every 3 months while in follow- up. Collection of HRQoL data was limited to the first 12 months after randomization. The primary HRQoL endpoint considered relevant for this study is time to HRQoL deterioration (TTQ). TTQ is defined as the time from randomization to death, progression or clinical relevant deterioration in pre-specified QLQ-C30 scales. Patients who had not experienced an event at the time of analysis were censored at the time of the last completed HRQoL assessment.</description>
        <time_frame>13 months</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Subsequent Therapies and Potential Relationships With Outcomes</title>
        <description>To describe subsequent therapies and potential relationships with outcomes</description>
        <time_frame>End of Study</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Assess Genetic and Non-genetic Biomarkers</title>
        <description>To assess genetic and non-genetic biomarkers relating to treatment efficacy. Germline and tumor mutations may be explored including somatic BRCA1 and 2 mutations, reversion mutations, loss of heterozygosity as well as genome landscape and transcriptional or functional measures of homologous recombination (HR) deficiency.</description>
        <time_frame>End of Study</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Assess Outcomes by Germline Mutation BRCA1 vs BRCA2</title>
        <description>To assess outcomes by germline mutation BRCA1 vs BRCA2</description>
        <time_frame>End of Study</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Post-treatment Data</title>
        <description>Descriptive summary statistics will be used to summarize post- treatment data (.i.e subsequent anticancer therapies and any new malignancy)</description>
        <time_frame>End of Study</time_frame>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>Up to 4 years</time_frame>
      <desc>Safety analyses included all patients who have received at least one dose of study drug.</desc>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Physician's Choice</title>
          <description>Physician selection from 4 standard of care metastatic breast cancer chemotherapies (eribulin or vinorelbine or gemcitabine or capecitabine), until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E2">
          <title>Niraparib</title>
          <description>Niraparib 300 mg (3x100 mg capsules) once daily until progression or unacceptable toxicity develops</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <default_vocab>MedDRA 20.0</default_vocab>
        <default_assessment>Non-systematic Assessment</default_assessment>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="39" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="79" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="33" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Blood and lymphatic system disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title vocab="MedDRA (Unspecified)">Thrombocytopenia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="10" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Anaemia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="9" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Febrile neutropenia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Leukopenia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Neutropenia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Cardiac disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Pericardial effusion</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Tachycardia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Gastrointestinal disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title vocab="MedDRA (Unspecified)">Nausea</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Vomiting</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Constipation</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Abdominal pain</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Diarrhoea</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Proctalgia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>General disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Pain</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Pyrexia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Asthenia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Fatique</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Malaise</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Infections and infestations</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Pneumonia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Sepsis</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Cellulitis</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Lower respiratory tract infection</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Lung infection</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Pyelonephritis</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Upper respiratory tract infection</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Urinary tract infection</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Injury, poisoning and procedural complications</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Accidental overdose</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Investigations</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Platelet count decreased</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Electrocardiogram ST segment depression</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Metabolism and nutrition disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Hypercalcaemia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Musculoskeletal and connective tissue disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Back pain</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Joint range of motion decreased</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Nervous system disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Headache</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Dizziness</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Hypoaesthesia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Language disorder</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Syncope</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Renal and urinary disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Acute kidney injury</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title vocab="MedDRA (Unspecified)">Micturition disorder</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Respiratory, thoracic and mediastinal disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Epistaxis</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Pleurisy</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Pleuritic pain</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Respiratory failure</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Vascular disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Deep vein thrombosis</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Hypotension</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>5</frequency_threshold>
        <default_vocab>MedDRA 20.0</default_vocab>
        <default_assessment>Non-systematic Assessment</default_assessment>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="63" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="134" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Blood and lymphatic system disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title vocab="MedDRA (Unspecified)">Anaemia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="23" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="90" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Nausea</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="24" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="81" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Thrombocytopenia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="48" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Neutropenia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="19" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="26" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title vocab="MedDRA (Unspecified)">Leukopenia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="9" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="11" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Cardiac disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Tachycardia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="11" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Gastrointestinal disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Vomiting</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="11" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="49" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Constipation</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="11" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="48" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Diarrhoea</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="22" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="19" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Abdominal pain</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="10" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="15" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Abdominal pain upper</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="17" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Stomatitis</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="15" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Dry mouth</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="6" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Dyspepsia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="9" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>General disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Fatigue</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="29" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="66" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Asthenia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="9" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="23" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Dizziness</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="6" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="27" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Insomnia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="24" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Pyrexia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="15" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Oedema peripheral</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="6" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="9" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Palmar-plantar erythrodysaesthesia syndrome</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="12" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Infections and infestations</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Viral upper respiratory tract infection</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="11" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Upper respiratory tract infection</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="9" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Urinary tract infection</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="7" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Influenza like illness</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="8" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Investigations</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Weight decreased</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="10" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="53" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Platelet count decreased</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="43" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Neutrophil count decreased</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="10" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="26" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>White blood cell count decreased</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="31" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Alanine aminotransferase increased</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="7" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="18" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Gamma-glutamyltransferase increased</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="7" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="17" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Blood alkaline phosphatase increased</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="15" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Aspartate aminotransferase increased</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="13" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Lymphocyte count decreased</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="9" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Weight increased</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="7" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Metabolism and nutrition disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Decreased appetite</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="7" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="41" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Musculoskeletal and connective tissue disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Back pain</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="7" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="30" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Pain in extremity</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="19" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Arthralgia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="8" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="9" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Bone pain</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="9" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Musculoskeletal pain</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="9" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title vocab="MedDRA (Unspecified)">Neck pain</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="10" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Musculoskeletal chest pain</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="7" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Myalgia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="6" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Nervous system disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Headache</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="10" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="45" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Dysgeusia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="10" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Paraesthesia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="6" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Psychiatric disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Anxiety</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="8" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="18" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Respiratory, thoracic and mediastinal disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Dyspnoea</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="8" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="25" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Cough</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="15" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Epistaxis</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="10" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Skin and subcutaneous tissue disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Alopecia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="7" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Vascular disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Hypertension</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="65"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="17" subjects_at_risk="134"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>Principal Investigators are NOT employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>Neither Institution nor Investigator will submit for publication or public disclosure any publication or disclosure based on the results of the Study until after the first to occur of (a) publication of the Multi-Center Clinical Trial results; (b) notification by Sponsor that the Multi-Center Clinical Trial submission is no longer planned; or (c) the eighteen (18) month anniversary of the completion or early termination of the Multi-Center Clinical Trial.</restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <limitations_and_caveats>IDMC interim analysis concluded that concerns with the quantity and quality of data in the control arm precluded meaningful comparative analyses and generation of a clinically useful endpoint, therefore enrollment was ended prematurely.</limitations_and_caveats>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>GSK Response Center</name_or_title>
      <organization>GlaxoSmithKline</organization>
      <phone>866-435-7343</phone>
      <email>GSKClinicalSupportHD@gsk.com</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

