<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01989533</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>140011</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>14-I-0011</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01989533</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Safety and Immunogenicity of HIV Vaccines in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I Study of Safety and Immunogenicity of Ad4-HIV Vaccine Vectors in Healthy Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Emergent BioSolutions</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Vaccines create resistance to disease. This study tests experimental human immunodeficiency&#xD;
      virus (HIV) vaccines that use an adenovirus as a transporter. Transporters may help vaccines&#xD;
      stimulate an immune response against HIV. This means the body works to fight infection.&#xD;
      Researchers want to see if different ways of giving the vaccines cause different immune&#xD;
      responses. They also want to see if the vaccines adenovirus is contagious. Adenoviruses cause&#xD;
      cold symptoms or mild eye infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants cannot get HIV from these vaccines. But they can get the adenovirus, so their&#xD;
      entire household and intimate contacts must participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To test the safety of experimental HIV vaccines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Healthy adults 18-49 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be screened with medical history, physical exam, and blood and urine&#xD;
           tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will receive the vaccine 3 times over 6 months. Each time, they will have a&#xD;
           physical exam and blood and urine tests. Samples will be taken from their nose, rectum,&#xD;
           and cervix.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Some participants will receive the vaccine by swallowing 11 capsules with water. Clinic&#xD;
           staff will observe them for 1 hour.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Some participants will receive the vaccine swabbed in their throat. They will get dose 1&#xD;
           at the hospital and stay there for 1 week. They will have medical tests and nose swabs.&#xD;
           Doses 2 and 3 will not require a hospital stay.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will have 7 follow-up visits over 6 months, with a physical exam and blood&#xD;
           tests. Samples will be taken from their nose, throat, and rectum.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Household and intimate contacts will have 4 clinic visits over 8 months, with a physical&#xD;
           exam and blood tests.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 1, single center, randomized, double-blind study designed to evaluate the&#xD;
      safety and immunogenicity of live, replication-competent recombinant Adenovirus type 4-HIV&#xD;
      vaccine regimens. The oral route will also contain a placebo control. The vaccine candidates&#xD;
      Ad4-mgag and Ad4-EnvC150 will be formulated as enteric-coated capsules to be delivered&#xD;
      orally, and as an aqueous formulation for intranasal administration. Determining the optimal&#xD;
      regimen and route will greatly accelerate investigations of these vectors as HIV vaccine&#xD;
      platforms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants volunteering to receive the vaccine orally will be randomized to 1 of 4&#xD;
      treatment arms, and those volunteering to receive the vaccine via the intranasal route will&#xD;
      be randomized to 1 of 3 treatment arms. Participants will receive either 1 or both vaccines&#xD;
      or placebo, depending on group assignment. The study vaccines will be administered to&#xD;
      participants in 3 rounds of vaccination at 0, 2, and 6 months. All participants will receive&#xD;
      a booster vaccination with a bivalent HIV gp120 glycoprotein at 8 months. Intranasal vaccine&#xD;
      recipients with household contact(s) will receive the first vaccine in the NIH Special&#xD;
      Clinical Studies Unit or other appropriate unit and be followed on an inpatient basis to&#xD;
      allow for respiratory isolation. Intranasal vaccinees without household contact(s) may also&#xD;
      receive the vaccination as inpatients or may opt to receive the vaccine on an outpatient&#xD;
      basis if they agree to follow precautions for preventing the spread of adenovirus. Beginning&#xD;
      4 days after vaccination, inpatient participants will be tested daily for respiratory&#xD;
      shedding of Ad4 by nasopharyngeal wash. They will be discharged to home with close monitoring&#xD;
      on Day 7 or after 2 consecutive negative washes, whichever comes first; they may remain on&#xD;
      the unit longer if medically necessary. Prior to receiving the second dose of vaccine on an&#xD;
      outpatient basis, seroconversion to Ad4 will be confirmed in the intranasal vaccine&#xD;
      recipients. Those who have household contact(s) and have not seroconverted will continue to&#xD;
      receive subsequent doses as inpatients until they show seroconversion. Those who do not have&#xD;
      household contact(s) and those who have seroconverted may receive the remaining vaccinations&#xD;
      as inpatients or may opt to receive the doses on an outpatient basis if they agree to follow&#xD;
      precautions for preventing the spread of adenovirus. If they decline these options, they may&#xD;
      withdraw from the study and will be replaced. Oral capsule recipients will be vaccinated and&#xD;
      discharged to home.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to clinical and laboratory monitoring of safety, the principal assessments will&#xD;
      be shedding of this viruses in rectal, cervicovaginal, throat, and nasal swabs, and&#xD;
      assessment of the antibody (mucosal and systemic) response to the HIV and to the Ad4 virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The candidate vaccines will also be administered to 2 groups of participants who have&#xD;
      previously received an unrelated HIV vaccine in another clinical study and/or are Ad4&#xD;
      seropositive. The aim for these groups is to explore the boost potential of the enteric&#xD;
      coated capsule and aqueous formulations of the Ad4-mgag and Ad4- EnvC150 vaccines when given&#xD;
      to subjects who have previously received another HIV vaccine and/or are Ad4 seropositive.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The adenovirus vaccines will not be retested for stability in 2018, and therefore will be out&#xD;
      of specifications on May 9th 2018. In an effort to capture as much information on&#xD;
      immunogenicity and adenoviral replication as possible, we will implemement the following&#xD;
      change beginning in 2018. The study will continue with enrollment into the remaining&#xD;
      treatment groups in a nonrandomized manner such that remaining participants receive both the&#xD;
      Ad4-mgag and Ad4-EnvC150 intranasally. These participants will receive 2 rounds of the&#xD;
      intranasal vaccine at Months 0 and 2 followed by a single dose of the booster vaccination at&#xD;
      Month 4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will be followed for a total of 6 months following the final dose of study&#xD;
      vaccine. Household and intimate contacts will also be enrolled and monitored for Adenovirus&#xD;
      and HIV antibodies for up to 8 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 19, 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 8, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 8, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the safety of the Ad4-mgag and Ad4-EnvC150 vaccines in humans when administered via the oral or intranasal route.</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>Safety</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the immunogenicity of the Ad4- mgag and Ad4-EnvC150 vaccines in humans when administered via the oral or intranasal routes in humans</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>Immunogenicity response</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">62</enrollment>
  <condition>Vaccine Response</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo controlled (blinded)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intranasal Randomized</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral Open label</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>D</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intranasal Open Label</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ad4-mgag</intervention_name>
    <description>Ad4 live virus vaccine with an HIV insert</description>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>D</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ad4-EnvC150</intervention_name>
    <description>Ad4 live virus vaccine with an HIV insert</description>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>D</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>gp 120 Protein Boost</intervention_name>
    <description>HIV protein boost</description>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>D</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All participants (vaccinees, household contacts, and intimate contacts) must meet all of&#xD;
        the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 18 to 49 years for vaccinees. Age 18 to 65 years for household and intimate&#xD;
             contacts.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Negative FDA-approved HIV test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Able to provide proof of identity to the acceptance of the Principal Investigator or&#xD;
             designee during enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Available and willing to participate in follow-up visits and tests for the duration of&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willing to have samples stored for future research.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The following inclusion criteria apply to vaccinees and intimate contacts, but not to&#xD;
        household contacts:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. In good general health without clinically significant medical history.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Willing to discuss HIV infection risks with the study clinicians, assessed as low risk&#xD;
             for HIV infection, amenable to HIV risk reduction counseling, and committed to&#xD;
             maintaining behavior consistent with&#xD;
&#xD;
             low risk of HIV exposure through the last required clinic visit in the protocol&#xD;
             schedule.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Negative Beta-HCG pregnancy test for females presumed to be of reproductive potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. A female must meet one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. No reproductive potential because of menopause (one year without menses) or&#xD;
                  because of a hysterectomy, bilateral oophorectomy, or tubal ligation.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Participant agrees to be heterosexually inactive or consistently practice&#xD;
                  contraception at least 21 days prior to and 28 days following each vaccination.&#xD;
                  Acceptable methods of contraception include the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  condoms, male or female, with a spermicide.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  diaphragm or cervical cap with spermicide.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  contraceptive pills, Norplant, or Depo-Provera.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  male partner has previously undergone a vasectomy for which there is&#xD;
                       documentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  intrauterine device.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Male participants must agree to practice abstinence or effective birth control for at&#xD;
             least 21 days prior to and 28 days following each vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The following inclusion criteria apply only to vaccinees and not to household or intimate&#xD;
        contacts:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Willing to receive HIV test results and abide by NIH guidelines for partner&#xD;
             notification of positive HIV results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Physical examination and laboratory results without clinically significant findings&#xD;
             within the 8 weeks prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Willing to avoid vaccination other than the study agent for 30 days prior to and 30&#xD;
             days after administration of the Ad4-HIV vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Safety Laboratory Criteria within 8 weeks prior to enrollment:&#xD;
&#xD;
             Hematopoietic: -White blood cell count and Lymphocyte count +/- 25% of normal limits&#xD;
             for the NIH Clinical Center&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count of least 100,000/mm(3)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin &gt;11.2 g/dL for females and &gt;13.0 g/dL for males.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Renal: BUN &lt;23 mg/dL; creatinine within normal limits for the NIH Clinical Center&#xD;
&#xD;
             Hepatic: Serum total bilirubin less than or equal to 2 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
             Metabolic: ALT &lt;2 times upper limit of normal range&#xD;
&#xD;
             Endocrine: Serum glucose within normal range&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Additional Laboratory Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Immunologic: No history of hypogammaglobulinemia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Serologic: Ad4 neutralizing antibody 80% inhibitory dilution &lt;1:100 (This criterion does&#xD;
        not apply to participants in Arms C and D.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        The following inclusion criterion applies only to intranasal vaccinees and not to capsule&#xD;
        vaccine recipients or household or intimate contacts:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Willing to either:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. be hospitalized at the Clinical Center under respiratory precautions for up to 7 days&#xD;
             or longer if medically indicated (required for those with household contact(s) until&#xD;
             they show seroconversion); or&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. follow precautions for preventing the spread of adenovirus in the community.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A participant (vaccinees, household contacts, and intimate contacts) will be excluded if&#xD;
        they have the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Any condition that, in the investigator s judgement, places the subject at undue risk by&#xD;
        participating in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The following exclusion criterion applies to vaccinees and intimate contacts, but not to&#xD;
        household contacts:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of any prior disease or therapy which would affect immune or pulmonary&#xD;
             function.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Prior malignancy, except curatively-treated basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of&#xD;
             the skin or carcinoma in situ of the cervix.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of radiation therapy or cytotoxic/cancer chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of diabetes mellitus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Immunodeficiency or autoimmune disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Acute infection or a recent (within 6 months) history of chronic infection suggestive&#xD;
             of immunodeficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Taking any medication which may affect immune function, except participants may be&#xD;
             taking low doses of nonprescription strength NSAIDS (including e.g. ibuprofen or&#xD;
             aspirin) or acetaminophen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Chronic respiratory disorders including asthma, emphysema, interstitial lung disease,&#xD;
             pulmonary hypertension, recurrent pneumonia, or recent or ongoing respiratory tract&#xD;
             infection. If a respiratory disorder is transient, defer immunization but do not&#xD;
             exclude the participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Active Hepatitis B or C infection (i.e. Hepatitis B or C positive serology with the&#xD;
             presence of virus antigen or DNA. Ongoing viral replication will be confirmed by a&#xD;
             Hepatitis B antigen or Hepatitis C viral load).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Female of child-bearing potential who is breast-feeding or planning pregnancy during&#xD;
             the 28 days following vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The following exclusion criteria apply only to vaccinees and not to household or intimate&#xD;
        contacts:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any medical, psychiatric, or social condition, or occupational or other responsibility&#xD;
             that, in the judgment of the investigator, would interfere with or serve as a&#xD;
             contraindication to receipt of live virus vaccine, protocol adherence, or a&#xD;
             participant s ability to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Psychiatric condition that precludes compliance with the protocol; past or present&#xD;
             psychoses; past or present bipolar disorder requiring therapy that has not been well&#xD;
             controlled on medication for the past two years; disorder requiring lithium; or&#xD;
             suicidal ideation occurring within five years prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participants that live in the same house or apartment with any of the following will&#xD;
             be excluded:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. An individual under 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. An elderly individual (&gt;65 years of age).&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. An immunocompromised or immunosuppressed individual.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. An individual with chronic respiratory disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. A woman who is currently pregnant or planning a pregnancy during the period of&#xD;
                  immunization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Healthcare worker who has direct contact with immunodeficient, unstable patients, or&#xD;
             pediatric patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participants caring for children &lt;18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Receipt of any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Antiviral medications within 30 days prior to vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Blood products within 120 days prior to HIV screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Immunoglobulin within 60 days prior to HIV screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Investigational research drugs or any other investigational agent that in the&#xD;
                  judgement of the Principal Investigator might interact with the study vaccine&#xD;
                  within 30 days prior to initial study vaccine administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Allergy treatment with antigen injections within 30 days of study vaccine&#xD;
                  administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of Guillain-Barr(SqrRoot)(Copyright) syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Indeterminate HIV Western Blot test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Prior receipt of an Ad5-based vaccine.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark Connors, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Boyaka PN, Tafaro A, Fischer R, Leppla SH, Fujihashi K, McGhee JR. Effective mucosal immunity to anthrax: neutralizing antibodies and Th cell responses following nasal immunization with protective antigen. J Immunol. 2003 Jun 1;170(11):5636-43.</citation>
    <PMID>12759444</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brandt CD, Kim HW, Vargosko AJ, Jeffries BC, Arrobio JO, Rindge B, Parrott RH, Chanock RM. Infections in 18,000 infants and children in a controlled study of respiratory tract disease. I. Adenovirus pathogenicity in relation to serologic type and illness syndrome. Am J Epidemiol. 1969 Dec;90(6):484-500.</citation>
    <PMID>4312064</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Braucher DR, Henningson JN, Loving CL, Vincent AL, Kim E, Steitz J, Gambotto AA, Kehrli ME Jr. Intranasal vaccination with replication-defective adenovirus type 5 encoding influenza virus hemagglutinin elicits protective immunity to homologous challenge and partial protection to heterologous challenge in pigs. Clin Vaccine Immunol. 2012 Nov;19(11):1722-9. doi: 10.1128/CVI.00315-12. Epub 2012 Aug 29.</citation>
    <PMID>22933397</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 24, 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 19, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 19, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 21, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 14, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 14, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HIV Vaccine</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteer</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

