<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01982110</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>17004</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01982110</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Mindfulness Based Application for Smoking Cessation</brief_title>
  <acronym>MBSC</acronym>
  <official_title>A Mindfulness Based Application for Smoking Cessation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Virginia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Virginia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cigarette smoking is the leading cause of preventable death and disability in the world.&#xD;
      Although over 70% of smokers want to quit, fewer than 5% achieve this goal annually.&#xD;
      Additional effective, safe, and accessible treatments for nicotine dependence are needed due&#xD;
      to the low abstinence rates (20-30%) achieved in behavioral therapies, the unappealing side&#xD;
      effects of pharmacotherapy, and the frequent lack of accessibility to treatment. Recent&#xD;
      evidence supports the central role of craving in maintaining nicotine dependence, and neither&#xD;
      behavioral nor replacement therapies directly target the relationship between cravings and&#xD;
      smoking. Mindfulness therapy has been found to be effective in teaching strategies to&#xD;
      decouple the association between craving and smoking. Mindfulness based smoking therapy (MT)&#xD;
      has preliminary support for reducing consumption in smokers, and Dr. Judson Brewer has&#xD;
      recently translated this program into a mobile device application (app) for smoking&#xD;
      cessation. With Dr. Brewer's consultation, we propose to assess the feasibility of&#xD;
      implementation of a MT mobile application in local hospital and community clinics and the&#xD;
      effectiveness of the MT mobile application compared to a National Cancer Institute (NCI)&#xD;
      QuitPal behavioral change group. We will examine smoking results at end of treatment and 2&#xD;
      and 6 month follow-up as well as the role of craving. If MT smoking cessation is determined&#xD;
      to be effective in a mobile phone application, this finding will be a significant step in&#xD;
      providing an additional effective and safe treatment for smokers wishing to quit or cut down&#xD;
      on their intake, and will be especially important in providing treatment options for&#xD;
      marginalized or hard-to-access individuals wishing to reduce cigarette intake.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cigarette smoking is the leading cause of preventable death and disability in the world,&#xD;
      accounting for 10% of all deaths. In the US, smoking costs more than $193 billion in health&#xD;
      care costs and lost productivity per year. Although over 70% of smokers want to quit, fewer&#xD;
      than 5% achieve this goal annually. Mainstay behavioral treatments for smoking have focused&#xD;
      on teaching individuals to avoid cues, foster positive affective states, develop lifestyle&#xD;
      changes that reduce stress, divert attention from cravings, substitute other activities for&#xD;
      smoking, learn cognitive strategies that reduce negative mood and develop social support&#xD;
      mechanisms. These have shown modest success, with abstinence rates between only 20-30% over&#xD;
      the past thirty years. This is presumably due to the complex nature of the acquisition and&#xD;
      maintenance of nicotine addiction, including associative learning mechanisms as well as&#xD;
      positive and negative reinforcement. Over time, cues that are judged to be positive or&#xD;
      negative can induce affective states, which can then trigger a craving to smoke. Though the&#xD;
      centrality of craving remains controversial, evidence suggests that craving is strongly&#xD;
      associated with smoking, which, mainly through the physiological properties of nicotine,&#xD;
      results in the maintenance or improvement of positive or reduction of negative affective&#xD;
      states. This sets up reinforcement loops by reinforcing memories between affect and smoking.&#xD;
      Thus, attention has been focused on additional strategies to help people tolerate negative&#xD;
      affect and cravings rather than avoiding cues or substituting activities, and recent research&#xD;
      suggest that MT may decouple the association between craving and smoking, thus facilitating&#xD;
      smoking cessation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mindfulness training (MT) targets affective or craving states by teaching individuals to&#xD;
      observe aversive body and mind states instead of reacting to them with habitual reactions,&#xD;
      thus allowing more adaptive, healthier responses. Mindfulness training (MT) has shown promise&#xD;
      in reducing anxiety and depression and has recently been explored in the treatment of&#xD;
      addictions. In a 2011 randomized controlled trial by Brewer, et al., individuals who received&#xD;
      an 8- session MT vs. the American Lung Association's 8 session freedom from smoking (FFS)&#xD;
      treatment, showed significantly greater rate of reduction in cigarette use and greater point&#xD;
      prevalence abstinence rates during treatment and maintained these gains during follow up. FFS&#xD;
      is a behavior modification program and includes stress reduction and relapse prevention.&#xD;
      Although both treatment groups were assigned home practice as part of their treatment, only&#xD;
      those who received mindfulness training demonstrated a significant association between home&#xD;
      practice and smoking outcomes, suggesting that there was a specific benefit to mindfulness&#xD;
      practice and that positive treatment outcomes for those in this group are not merely a result&#xD;
      of greater enthusiasm or interest in quitting. The ability of MT to attenuate the&#xD;
      relationship between craving and substance use has been observed in other studies as well.&#xD;
      Elwafi, et al. (2012) demonstrated that people who practiced mindfulness more smoked less,&#xD;
      regardless of their level of craving. Practicing mindfulness appears critical to MT treatment&#xD;
      outcomes. These results suggest that MT may help individuals develop a tolerance to craving&#xD;
      itself, thus over time acting to dismantle the addictive loop. To date, research in this area&#xD;
      has been conducted in randomized clinical trials in structured laboratory settings only.&#xD;
      Important next steps are to examine the effectiveness of MT treatments for smoking cessation&#xD;
      in naturalistic environments and to utilize methods of delivering treatment in real world&#xD;
      settings that will facilitate compliance with mindfulness practice and thus improve treatment&#xD;
      outcomes - for example, via a mobile device application. Additionally, trials comparing MT to&#xD;
      alternative treatment approaches typically offered in outpatient clinics such as support&#xD;
      groups, acupuncture, individual counseling, or nicotine replacement therapies are lacking.&#xD;
      Mindfulness based (MT) smoking cessation has been adapted to a mobile device application&#xD;
      called &quot;Craving to Quit&quot; based on the work done by Brewer and will be the mindfulness&#xD;
      intervention used in this study. Standardization and implementation via a mobile application&#xD;
      is a logical and necessary next step in the dissemination of treatment and will potentially&#xD;
      provide access to an effective smoking cessation program for persons who may not otherwise be&#xD;
      able to access treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Smoking behavior</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will assess number of cigarettes smoked and CO levels</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Craving</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will assess levels of craving to smoke.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">5</enrollment>
  <condition>Nicotine Dependence</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness Based Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Craving to Quit mobile application is provided for participants</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Behavioral Smoking Cessation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>NCI Quit Pal via a mobile phone application is provided for participants</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mindfulness based smoking cessation</intervention_name>
    <description>Mindfulness based interventions are provided via a mobile phone application.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness Based Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Craving to Quit</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Behavioral Smoking Cessation intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Behavioral Smoking Cessation intervention is a behaviorally based intervention is provided via a mobile phone application.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Behavioral Smoking Cessation</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Behavioral therapy</other_name>
    <other_name>Cognitive Behavioral therapy</other_name>
    <other_name>NCI QuitPal</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males and females who have given written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smoke an average of a minimum of five cigarettes per day&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Literate in English and able to read, understand, and complete the rating scales and&#xD;
             questionnaires accurately, follow instructions, and make use of mindfulness techniques&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Express a wish to quit smoking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A score at least in the &quot;contemplation&quot; range, as assessed via the Readiness to Change&#xD;
             questionnaire (Heather &amp; McCambridge, 2013)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to participate in mindfulness techniques&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to attend all clinic visits without interruption&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any current Axis I DSM-IV-TR psychiatric disorder other than alcohol abuse, marijuana&#xD;
             abuse, or nicotine dependence that, in the clinician's opinion, warrants treatment or&#xD;
             would preclude safe participation in the protocol, including, but not limited to:&#xD;
             psychosis, schizophrenia, dementia, schizotypal personality disorder, borderline&#xD;
             personality disorder, bipolar disorder, primary diagnosis of eating disorder, or&#xD;
             chronic suicidality or homicidality&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious medical comorbidity requiring medical intervention or close supervision,&#xD;
             including seizures, pacemakers, heart transplant, severe arrhythmias, or active atrial&#xD;
             fibrillation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suicide attempt in the last thirty days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gross neurological disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mental retardation, which will be assessed by the PI, postdoctoral fellows, and&#xD;
             doctoral students in clinical psychology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minors below the legal smoking age&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jennifer K Penberthy, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Virginia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Virginia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlottesville</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>22908</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 29, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 5, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 13, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 15, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 15, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 17, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Virginia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jennifer Kim Penberthy</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Department of Psychiatry and Neurobehavioral Sciences</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>smoking cessation</keyword>
  <keyword>mindfulness</keyword>
  <keyword>behavioral intervention</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tobacco Use Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

