<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05083871</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>798-2021-OSS-AUSLBO</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05083871</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cognitive Appraisals and Team Performance Under Stress in Simulated Trauma Care</brief_title>
  <official_title>Cognitive Appraisals and Team Performance Under Stress in Simulated Trauma Care</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Azienda Usl di Bologna</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Manchester Metropolitan University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Humanitas Clinical and Research Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Azienda Sanitaria Universitaria Friuli Centrale</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Azienda Usl di Bologna</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Medical teams work in demanding situations that are often uncertain, changeable and require&#xD;
      accurate decision-making, skilled movement and coordinated action. How teams perform matters&#xD;
      for patient outcomes. In addition to medical expertise, how individuals and the team&#xD;
      collectively respond and manage the psychological stress of the situation has a significant&#xD;
      impact on performance. One approach, which attempts to explain the facilitating and&#xD;
      debilitating effects of stress on performance is the biopsychosocial model of challenge and&#xD;
      threat. A challenge state occurs when perceived personal resources meet or exceed the&#xD;
      situation's demands, whereas threat occurs when demands exceed resources. Challenge states&#xD;
      have been consistently associated with improved performance in a range of environments and&#xD;
      activities, including medical settings. In a recent study conducted during a national&#xD;
      simulation-based training event for residents (the SIMCUP Italia 2018) it was found that a&#xD;
      high level of resources is associated with better performance until demands become very high.&#xD;
      The present study builds on previous work to explore how challenge and threat states are&#xD;
      linked to performance. It includes a more recently developed and robust measure of demands&#xD;
      and resource appraisals. In addition, secondary aims include the exploration of how&#xD;
      psychological variables, specifically cognitive anxiety, somatic anxiety, self-confidence and&#xD;
      social identity (connection with other members of the medical team) are linked to challenge&#xD;
      and threat and performance. Understanding the psychological determinants of performance in&#xD;
      critical care can provide the basis for individual and team-based interventions to improve&#xD;
      critical care team performance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 20, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Performance in simulated emergency trauma care</measure>
    <time_frame>3 days</time_frame>
    <description>Composite outcome measure taking into account both technical and non technical skills evaluation from the course instructors</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>participants' perceptions of task demands vs. personal resources</measure>
    <time_frame>3 days</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the evolution of the participants' perceptions of task demands vs. personal resources throughout the course</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>mental readiness</measure>
    <time_frame>3 days</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the evolution of the participants' mental readiness throughout the course</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Social identity</measure>
    <time_frame>3 days</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the evolution of the participants' social identity throughout the course</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">130</enrollment>
  <condition>Trauma</condition>
  <condition>Stress, Emotional</condition>
  <condition>Cognitive Change</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Learners of the European Trauma Course</arm_group_label>
    <description>Learners attending the European Trauma Course</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>European Trauma Course</intervention_name>
    <description>Structured learning program specifically focused on Trauma management. The course provides frontal lessons, workshops for the technical skills and simulated scenarios.&#xD;
Please see https://www.erc.edu/courses/european-trauma-course for additional details</description>
    <arm_group_label>Learners of the European Trauma Course</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study population will include all the learners attending the European Trauma Course in&#xD;
        Italy, independently from their previous work experience and educational background&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Learners of the European Trauma Course in Italy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt; 18 years&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lorenzo Gamberini, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+393403550540</phone>
    <email>l.gamberini@118er.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Marco Tartaglione, MD</last_name>
    <email>m.tartaglione@118er.it</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.erc.edu/courses/european-trauma-course</url>
    <description>European Trauma Course official site</description>
  </link>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mendes WB, Major B, McCoy S, Blascovich J. How attributional ambiguity shapes physiological and emotional responses to social rejection and acceptance. J Pers Soc Psychol. 2008 Feb;94(2):278-91. doi: 10.1037/0022-3514.94.2.278.</citation>
    <PMID>18211177</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tomaka J, Blascovich J, Kibler J, Ernst JM. Cognitive and physiological antecedents of threat and challenge appraisal. J Pers Soc Psychol. 1997 Jul;73(1):63-72.</citation>
    <PMID>9216079</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Blascovich J, Mendes WB, Hunter SB, Salomon K. Social &quot;facilitation&quot; as challenge and threat. J Pers Soc Psychol. 1999 Jul;77(1):68-77.</citation>
    <PMID>10434409</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Turner MJ, Jones MV, Sheffield D, Slater MJ, Barker JB, Bell JJ. Who thrives under pressure? Predicting the performance of elite academy cricketers using the cardiovascular indicators of challenge and threat states. J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2013 Aug;35(4):387-97.</citation>
    <PMID>23966448</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vine SJ, Freeman P, Moore LJ, Chandra-Ramanan R, Wilson MR. Evaluating stress as a challenge is associated with superior attentional control and motor skill performance: testing the predictions of the biopsychosocial model of challenge and threat. J Exp Psychol Appl. 2013 Sep;19(3):185-94. doi: 10.1037/a0034106.</citation>
    <PMID>24059821</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Carenzo L, Braithwaite EC, Carfagna F, Franc J, Ingrassia PL, Turner MJ, Slater MJ, Jones MV. Cognitive appraisals and team performance under stress: A simulation study. Med Educ. 2020 Mar;54(3):254-263. doi: 10.1111/medu.14050. Epub 2020 Feb 7.</citation>
    <PMID>32034800</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mendes WB, Gray HM, Mendoza-Denton R, Major B, Epel ES. Why egalitarianism might be good for your health: physiological thriving during stressful intergroup encounters. Psychol Sci. 2007 Nov;18(11):991-8.</citation>
    <PMID>17958714</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Franc JM, Verde M, Gallardo AR, Carenzo L, Ingrassia PL. An Italian version of the Ottawa Crisis Resource Management Global Rating Scale: a reliable and valid tool for assessment of simulation performance. Intern Emerg Med. 2017 Aug;12(5):651-656. doi: 10.1007/s11739-016-1486-7. Epub 2016 Jun 16.</citation>
    <PMID>27312510</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Medical simulation, Cognitive appraisal, Stress psychology</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

