<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05080582</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1614032021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05080582</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mother Scented Simulated Hand for Mechanically Ventilated Preterm Neonates During Invasive Procedures?</brief_title>
  <acronym>Zaky-Hand</acronym>
  <official_title>Does Mother Scented Simulated Hand Promote Comfort, Reduce Pain and Distress Among Mechanically Ventilated Preterm Neonates During Invasive Procedures</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Alexandria University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Alexandria University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aimed to determine the effect of Mother-Scented Simulated Hand (MSSH) on promoting&#xD;
      comfort among mechanically ventilated preterm neonates during invasive procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Hypotheses&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Preterm neonates who receive MSSHH exhibit higher levels of comfort during invasive&#xD;
           procedures than those who receive standard care.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Preterm neonates who receive MSSHH exhibit lower levels of pain and stress during&#xD;
           invasive procedures than those who receive standard care&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A quasi-experimental, pre-posttest, two group, study was carried out in NICU of in Smouha,&#xD;
      Alexandria. A sample of 62 mechanically ventilated neonates were randomly assigned to two&#xD;
      equal groups; the study group wrapped with a warm MSSH during the invasive procedures while&#xD;
      the control group received standard care of NICU. Two observers independently rated the&#xD;
      neonates' level of comfort, distress, and pain during Endotracheal Suctioning (ETS) and heel&#xD;
      prick using COMFORTneo Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On day one of mechanical ventilation, the neonates received the same standard care of the&#xD;
      NICU, while they wrapped with a warm Mother-Scented Simulated Hand as follow; simulated hand&#xD;
      was scented with mothers' body odor by placing it on the mothers' bare chest or behind the&#xD;
      neck for one hour. Then, the MSSH was placed under a radiant warmer for a couple of minutes&#xD;
      to reach the mothers' unique warm touch. Inside the incubator, the mechanically ventilated&#xD;
      neonates were placed in a side-lying flexed fetal position, where they encircled with the two&#xD;
      warm simulated human hand to contain them. Where the palm of one MSSH cupped the neonates'&#xD;
      head, and the palm of the other hand cupped the lower part of body and extremities. The&#xD;
      neonates were kept in such a position throughout the mentioned invasive procedures. Neonates'&#xD;
      physiological response, comfort, distress, and pain levels were assessed the same way as the&#xD;
      first day.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 22, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of comfort, pain and distress</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>COMFORTneo Scale:&#xD;
This scale was developed by Dijk et al. (2009). It is a numerical rating scale to assess neonates' comfort, distress and pain levels. It consists of 6 items, including alertness, calmness/agitation, respiratory response, body movement, facial tension, and muscle tone. The neonates' behavioral response was rated on 5 points numerical rating scale (1-5), and the total score ranged from 6 to 30. The lower score indicates a higher level of comfort and vice versa.&#xD;
The COMFORTneo scale has additional two Numerical Rating Scales (NRSs) for pain and distress. These scales are scored after the COMFORTneo score. Both of them range from zero to ten; the Zero score represents no pain or distress, while the ten score represents the worst imaginable pain or distress.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">62</enrollment>
  <condition>Pain</condition>
  <condition>Distress, Emotional</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mother-Scented Simulated Hand</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The neonates received the same standard care of the NICU, while they wrapped with a warm Mother-Scented Simulated Hand as follow; simulated hand was scented with mothers' body odor by placing it on the mothers' bare chest or behind the neck for one hour. Then, the MSSH was placed under a radiant warmer for a couple of minutes to reach the mothers' unique warm touch. Inside the incubator, the mechanically ventilated neonates were placed in a side-lying flexed fetal position, where they encircled with the two warm simulated human hand to contain them. Where the palm of one MSSH cupped the neonates' head, and the palm of the other hand cupped the lower part of body and extremities. The neonates were kept in such a position throughout the mentioned invasive procedures, as shown in Figure 2. Neonates' physiological response, comfort, distress, and pain levels were assessed the same way as the first day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NICU Standard Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The neonates were provided with standard care, which entailed maintaining a quiet environment with minimal stimulation, uninterrupted periods of sleep, containment. Neonates were placed in a side-lying position, while their extremities were flexed close to the body and wrapped with rolled sheets or towels to simulate the intrauterine posture. This position was maintained during the performance of the invasive procedures.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mother-Scented Simulated Hand</intervention_name>
    <description>Preterm neonates wrapped with a warm Mother-Scented Simulated Hand during the invasive procedures</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mother-Scented Simulated Hand</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>NICU Standard Care</intervention_name>
    <description>Neonates were placed in a side-lying position, while their extremities were flexed close to the body and wrapped with rolled sheets or towels to simulate the intrauterine posture.</description>
    <arm_group_label>NICU Standard Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preterm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Newly admitted&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemodynamic stability&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving sedatives&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Low APGAR score lower than three at five minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypothermia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypoglycemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hyperglycemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intraventricular hemorrhage grade III&amp; IV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neonatal seizures&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>28 Days</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eman m Taha, professor</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Alexandria University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Faculty of Nursing</name>
      <address>
        <city>Alexandria</city>
        <zip>56321</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu TW, Azhibekov T, Seri I. Transitional Hemodynamics in Preterm Neonates: Clinical Relevance. Pediatr Neonatol. 2016 Feb;57(1):7-18. doi: 10.1016/j.pedneo.2015.07.002. Epub 2015 Aug 29. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26482579</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Holsti L, Grunau RE, Shany E. Assessing pain in preterm infants in the neonatal intensive care unit: moving to a 'brain-oriented' approach. Pain Manag. 2011 Mar 1;1(2):171-179.</citation>
    <PMID>21874145</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Loos HM, Reger D, Schaal B. The odour of human milk: Its chemical variability and detection by newborns. Physiol Behav. 2019 Feb 1;199:88-99. doi: 10.1016/j.physbeh.2018.11.008. Epub 2018 Nov 8. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30414885</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pineda R, Bender J, Hall B, Shabosky L, Annecca A, Smith J. Parent participation in the neonatal intensive care unit: Predictors and relationships to neurobehavior and developmental outcomes. Early Hum Dev. 2018 Feb;117:32-38. doi: 10.1016/j.earlhumdev.2017.12.008. Epub 2017 Dec 21.</citation>
    <PMID>29275070</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zeraati H, Nasimi F, Rezaeian A, Shahinfar J, Ghorban Zade M. Effect of Multi-sensory Stimulation on Neuromuscular Development of Premature Infants: A Randomized Clinical Trial. Iran J Child Neurol. 2018 Summer;12(3):32-39.</citation>
    <PMID>30026767</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vittner D, Butler S, Smith K, Makris N, Brownell E, Samra H, McGrath J. Parent Engagement Correlates With Parent and Preterm Infant Oxytocin Release During Skin-to-Skin Contact. Adv Neonatal Care. 2019 Feb;19(1):73-79. doi: 10.1097/ANC.0000000000000558.</citation>
    <PMID>30335622</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>van Dijk M, Roofthooft DW, Anand KJ, Guldemond F, de Graaf J, Simons S, de Jager Y, van Goudoever JB, Tibboel D. Taking up the challenge of measuring prolonged pain in (premature) neonates: the COMFORTneo scale seems promising. Clin J Pain. 2009 Sep;25(7):607-16. doi: 10.1097/AJP.0b013e3181a5b52a.</citation>
    <PMID>19692803</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 18, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Alexandria University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Zohour Ibrahim Mahmoud Rashwan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Pediatric nurse specialist, Faculty of Nursing, principal Investigator, lecturer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Simulated Hand</keyword>
  <keyword>Comfort</keyword>
  <keyword>Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Distress</keyword>
  <keyword>Invasive procedures</keyword>
  <keyword>Preterm Neonates</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

