<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05088278</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Long term ACLR</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05088278</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Long Term Clinical and Radiographical Outcomes of Different Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction Techniques</brief_title>
  <official_title>Long Term Clinical and Radiographical Outcomes of Different Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction Techniques</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istituto Ortopedico Rizzoli</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istituto Ortopedico Rizzoli</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the long-term results of various anterior cruciate&#xD;
      ligament reconstruction techniques. This assessment is necessary for the current context of&#xD;
      anterior cruciate ligament research as several techniques and grafts are used in clinical&#xD;
      practice, however, the various studies existing in the literature focus mainly only on the&#xD;
      direct comparison of two techniques and usually with short-to-medium term follow-up. Since&#xD;
      gonarthrosis is one of the most debated consequences of cruciate ligament reconstruction, a&#xD;
      comparison of different long-term procedures would be desirable to have a clearer picture of&#xD;
      the risks and benefits associated with different types of intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In the beginning, the Database of our Institute is consulted, all the patients that underwent&#xD;
      ACL reconstruction at least 15 years ago are selected. The original group will be divided&#xD;
      into subgroups based on the surgical technique adopted, of the different techniques we took&#xD;
      into consideration only these three: anatomical ACL reconstruction with patellar tendon,&#xD;
      anatomical ACL reconstruction with hamstrings, non-anatomical ACL reconstruction&#xD;
      &quot;Over-the-top plus lateral plasty&quot;. The patients will be contacted to ask if they are&#xD;
      interested to take part in the study; at least 25 patients for each group will be recruited.&#xD;
      All the patients recruited will sign an informed consent about the study and the personal&#xD;
      data treatment. After consent acquisition, patients will undergo a clinical examination and a&#xD;
      questionnaire about pain and knee status will be administered; moreover, a radiographical&#xD;
      examination of the operated knee will be performed to assess the osteoarthritis progression.&#xD;
      Patients that reported graft rupture will be registered as failures.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective and objective IKDC</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical scores widely used to assess knee function and symptoms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>VAS pain</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Numerical score to quantitatively assess the intensity of pain (0-10)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Kellgreen-Lawrence</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Radiographical score that graded knee ostheoarthritis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Knee Laxity</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of knee anterior posterior laxity and quantification of Pivot shift using measurement devices (KT-1000; Kira)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Failure and complications</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Failures and complication rate for each arm of the study</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Short Form-36 Health Survey</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>SF-36 is a set of generic, coherent, and easily administered quality-of-life measures. These measures rely upon patient self-reporting and are now widely utilized by managed care organizations and by Medicare for routine monitoring and assessment of care outcomes in adult patients.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anterior knee pain</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>The patients will report in dicotomic way (yes/no) the presence/absence of pain referred to patello-femural joint.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Global satisfaction about the surgical procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>The patients will report in dicotomic way (yes/no) if they are satisfied with the surgical procedure results</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tight circumference</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Tight circumference measured 5 cm and 15 cm above the patella; it is a direct measurement of quadriceps trophism and indirectly explore the muscular status of affected limb.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lysholm</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical score used to assess knee function in context of ligamentary and meniscal lesions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tegner</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Score that graded activity based on work and sports referred to knee status</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Anterior Cruciate Ligament Tear</condition>
  <condition>Osteoarthritis, Knee</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients who underwent anatomical single-bundle ACL reconstruction with hamstrings</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BPT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients who underwent anatomical single-bundle ACL reconstruction with patellar tendon</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Over-the-top plus lateral plasty</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients who underwent ACL reconstruction with Over-the-top plus lateral plasty technique</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Anatomical single bundle ACL reconstruction with hamstrings</intervention_name>
    <description>Anatomical ACL reconstruction with quadruple-bundle hamstrings graft</description>
    <arm_group_label>HS</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Anatomical single bundle ACL reconstruction with patellar tendon</intervention_name>
    <description>Anatomical single bundle ACL reconstruction with patellar tendon</description>
    <arm_group_label>BPT</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ACL reconstruction with over the top plus lateral plasty technique</intervention_name>
    <description>Non-anatomical ACL reconstruction, the hamstrings' tibial insertion is preserved; a double-bundle hamstring graft is passed intra-articularly, fixed in over the top position on the lateral femoral condyle, and then passed extra-articularly deeply to ileo-tibial band up to the tibia, where it is fixed at the level of Gerdy's tubercle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Over-the-top plus lateral plasty</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who underwent ACL reconstruction with single-bundle anatomical technique&#xD;
             (patellar tendon, semitendinous and gracile tendons) or &quot;Over-The-Top plus lateral&#xD;
             plastic&quot; technique and any associated procedures with at least 15 years of follow up;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients aged between 15 and 50 at the time of surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with isolated ACL tear;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with healthy contralateral knee at the time of surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with grade III-IV chondral lesions according to Outerbridge scale at surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients no longer available;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Women of childbearing age who cannot exclude pregnancy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients unable to give informed consent or patients unwilling to sign informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Stefano Zaffagnini, MD Prof</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Istituto Ortopedico Rizzoli</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Piero Agostinone, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+39 3890260196</phone>
    <email>piero.agostinone@ior.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istituto Ortopedico Rizzoli</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bologna</city>
        <zip>40136</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Piero Agostinone, MD</last_name>
      <phone>3890260196</phone>
      <email>piero.agostinone@ior.it</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Stefano Zaffagnini, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alberto Grassi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gian Andrea Lucidi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Giacomo Dal Fabbro, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Margherita Serra, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Samuelsen BT, Webster KE, Johnson NR, Hewett TE, Krych AJ. Hamstring Autograft versus Patellar Tendon Autograft for ACL Reconstruction: Is There a Difference in Graft Failure Rate? A Meta-analysis of 47,613 Patients. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2017 Oct;475(10):2459-2468. doi: 10.1007/s11999-017-5278-9.</citation>
    <PMID>28205075</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Getgood A, Hewison C, Bryant D, Litchfield R, Heard M, Buchko G, Hiemstra LA, Willits KR, Firth A, MacDonald P; Stability Study Group. No Difference in Functional Outcomes When Lateral Extra-Articular Tenodesis Is Added to Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction in Young Active Patients: The Stability Study. Arthroscopy. 2020 Jun;36(6):1690-1701. doi: 10.1016/j.arthro.2020.02.015. Epub 2020 Mar 6.</citation>
    <PMID>32147485</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zaffagnini S, Marcheggiani Muccioli GM, Grassi A, Roberti di Sarsina T, Raggi F, Signorelli C, Urrizola F, Spinnato P, Rimondi E, Marcacci M. Over-the-top ACL Reconstruction Plus Extra-articular Lateral Tenodesis With Hamstring Tendon Grafts: Prospective Evaluation With 20-Year Minimum Follow-up. Am J Sports Med. 2017 Dec;45(14):3233-3242. doi: 10.1177/0363546517723013. Epub 2017 Sep 18.</citation>
    <PMID>28922015</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Xie X, Xiao Z, Li Q, Zhu B, Chen J, Chen H, Yang F, Chen Y, Lai Q, Liu X. Increased incidence of osteoarthritis of knee joint after ACL reconstruction with bone-patellar tendon-bone autografts than hamstring autografts: a meta-analysis of 1,443 patients at a minimum of 5 years. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol. 2015 Jan;25(1):149-59. doi: 10.1007/s00590-014-1459-3. Epub 2014 Apr 21.</citation>
    <PMID>24748500</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mouarbes D, Menetrey J, Marot V, Courtot L, Berard E, Cavaignac E. Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Outcomes for Quadriceps Tendon Autograft Versus Bone-Patellar Tendon-Bone and Hamstring-Tendon Autografts. Am J Sports Med. 2019 Dec;47(14):3531-3540. doi: 10.1177/0363546518825340. Epub 2019 Feb 21.</citation>
    <PMID>30790526</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chen H, Liu H, Chen L. Patellar Tendon Versus 4-Strand Semitendinosus and Gracilis Autografts for Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: A Meta-analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials With Mid- to Long-Term Follow-Up. Arthroscopy. 2020 Aug;36(8):2279-2291.e8. doi: 10.1016/j.arthro.2020.04.024. Epub 2020 May 7.</citation>
    <PMID>32387652</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Curado J, Hulet C, Hardy P, Jenny JY, Rousseau R, Lucet A, Steltzlen C, Morin V, Grimaud O, Bouguennec N, Pujol N, Sonnery-Cottet B, Graveleau N; French Society for Orthopaedic, Trauma Surgery (Société française de chirurgie orthopédique et traumatologique, SoFCOT). Very long-term osteoarthritis rate after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: 182 cases with 22-year' follow-up. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2020 May;106(3):459-463. doi: 10.1016/j.otsr.2019.09.034. Epub 2020 Feb 1.</citation>
    <PMID>32019734</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Zaffagnini S, Marcacci M, Lo Presti M, Giordano G, Iacono F, Neri MP. Prospective and randomized evaluation of ACL reconstruction with three techniques: a clinical and radiographic evaluation at 5 years follow-up. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2006 Nov;14(11):1060-9. Epub 2006 Aug 15.</citation>
    <PMID>16909301</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>anterior cruciate ligament</keyword>
  <keyword>knee osteoarthritis</keyword>
  <keyword>hamstrings</keyword>
  <keyword>patellar tendon</keyword>
  <keyword>lateral extra articular tenodesis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

