<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05084820</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>REC/Lhr/20/0213 Hira Rehman</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05084820</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Action Observation Treatment on Motor Function in Upper Limb of Patients With Chronic Stroke</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Action Observation Treatment on Motor Function in Upper Limb of Patients With Chronic Stroke</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Riphah International University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Riphah International University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To determine the effects of action observation treatment on motor functions in upper limb of&#xD;
      patients with chronic stroke&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Stroke is one of the major cause of death in Pakistan and also a prime source of disability&#xD;
      in older adults.Mirror neuron system depends on motor regions, and its dominant aspect is&#xD;
      that,it is activated for implementation of motor activity and also for its observation. This&#xD;
      &quot;dual activation&quot; characteristic of mirror neuron helps in improving the observation and&#xD;
      execution of different actions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      aim of this study is to determine the effects of action observation treatment on motor&#xD;
      function in upper limb of patients with chronic stroke.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An RCT will be conducted on 14 chronic stroke patients from Omar Hospital and Riphah&#xD;
      Rehabilitation Centre Lahore. Patients will be randomly allocated into control group (n=7)&#xD;
      and Experimental group (n=7) by lottery method. Control group will be given only conventional&#xD;
      treatment that included stretching, strengthening, pinching, gripping, reaching and grasping&#xD;
      exercises, while Experimental group received conventional treatment and action observation&#xD;
      treatment 3 days/ week for 4 weeks. Treatment outcomes will be assessed on Modified Barthel&#xD;
      Index and Fugl-Meyer Assessment for upper extremity (FMA-UE)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>each participant will be requested to draw either number one or two from a box.number one refers to group A and number two refers to group B. Group A patients will receive conventional treatment of 40 minutes in total. group B is experimental group , patients will watch videos of 5 common motor tasks that implicit the usage of items to be used for action observation treatment.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>modified barthal index</measure>
    <time_frame>40 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The Modified Barthel Index score was used for practical evaluation in activities of daily living. The MBI comprises of 10 items, 6 out of 10 items scored from 0-2 points, 2 items scored from 0-3 points and other 2 items scored from 0-3 points, giving a highest total score of 20 points.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fugl-Meyer Assessment test</measure>
    <time_frame>40 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Fugl-Meyer Assessment test for Upper extermity.to assess level of motor impairment and its recovery after treatment. The FMA-UE comprises of 7 times.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">14</enrollment>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Action observation treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Action observation treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>conventional treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>conventional treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Action observation treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will watch 5 videos of motor tasks; each video is of 30 sec and watch for 4 times (i.e. for 2 minutes). Then patient will execute the motor act, soon after the observation with an affected limb for 2 minutes, with total rest time of 5 minutes for this treatment. Conventional treatment of muscle stretching, strengthening and ROM exercises will be given for 15 minutes including rest. Total treatment time is 40 minutes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Action observation treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>conventional treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>conventional treatment of 40 minutes in total will be performed including Stretching (for 8-10 sec with set of 5 repetitions/ session on each side for 3 minutes total with rest), strengthening (weighted bicep curls, side arm raise and open arm movement exercises with set of 5 repetitions/ session for 9 minutes total with rest), Range of motion exercises active and passive with set of 5 repetitions/ session for 3 minutes total with rest and gripping,reaching, grasping exercises (on each side for total 25 minutes including rest) with assistance of physiotherapist</description>
    <arm_group_label>conventional treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic Stroke patients (with more than 6 months- 4 years) illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that were able to communicate and comprehend oral instructions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with Mini Mental State Examination (MMSE) score more than 24&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients having psychiatric histories.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Visual and hearing impaired patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with speech impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with arthritic deformities in upper limb (with or without using assistive&#xD;
             device)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with diagnosed mental illness.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>zeest hashmi, MS NMPT</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Riphah International University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Riphah international university</name>
      <address>
        <city>Islamabad</city>
        <state>Fedral</state>
        <zip>44000</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mao H, Li Y, Tang L, Chen Y, Ni J, Liu L, Shan C. Effects of mirror neuron system-based training on rehabilitation of stroke patients. Brain Behav. 2020 Aug;10(8):e01729. doi: 10.1002/brb3.1729. Epub 2020 Jul 1.</citation>
    <PMID>32608554</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Keller J, Štětkářová I, Macri V, Kühn S, Pětioký J, Gualeni S, Simmons СD, Arthanat S, Zilber P. Virtual reality-based treatment for regaining upper extremity function induces cortex grey matter changes in persons with acquired brain injury. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2020 Sep 12;17(1):127. doi: 10.1186/s12984-020-00754-7.</citation>
    <PMID>32919473</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Keci A, Tani K, Xhema J. Role of Rehabilitation in Neural Plasticity. Open Access Maced J Med Sci. 2019 May 14;7(9):1540-1547. doi: 10.3889/oamjms.2019.295. eCollection 2019 May 15. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31198470</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Habibi-Koolaee M, Shahmoradi L, Niakan Kalhori SR, Ghannadan H, Younesi E. Prevalence of Stroke Risk Factors and Their Distribution Based on Stroke Subtypes in Gorgan: A Retrospective Hospital-Based Study-2015-2016. Neurol Res Int. 2018 Jul 26;2018:2709654. doi: 10.1155/2018/2709654. eCollection 2018.</citation>
    <PMID>30147952</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>stroke</keyword>
  <keyword>action observation treatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

