<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05087810</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>211147</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05087810</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Stress and Anxiety Effects on Overactive Bladder</brief_title>
  <official_title>Stress and Anxiety Effects on Overactive Bladder</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to assess how psychological stress and anxiety relate to bladder&#xD;
      sensitivity and to psychological burdens in people with overactive bladder and how this can&#xD;
      be measured effectively.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Overactive bladder (OAB) (i.e. urinary urgency, with or without urgency urinary incontinence,&#xD;
      frequency, and nocturia) affects 1 in 7 U.S. men and women and results in substantial&#xD;
      impairment to quality of life (QOL). To help self-manage and cope with OAB, many people adopt&#xD;
      compensatory bladder behaviors, such as restricting fluids, using containment products,&#xD;
      strategic planning and mapping restroom access, and even curtailing activities or travel&#xD;
      altogether, which further adversely impact QOL. These behaviors may be driven by anxiety and&#xD;
      stress related to urinary urgency and incontinence episodes as well as ensuing distress and&#xD;
      embarrassment. Prior research has linked anxiety and OAB: up to 40% of women and 30% of men&#xD;
      with OAB also have generalized anxiety disorder. The link between stress and OAB is less&#xD;
      studied. In animals, experimental stress can cause OAB-like symptoms and behaviors as well as&#xD;
      bladder and somatic hypersensitivity. In limited human studies, women with OAB may have&#xD;
      greater physiologic and psychologic stress reactivity, and acute stress may exacerbate&#xD;
      urinary urgency. However, how stress impacts on the bladder in the context of OAB or what&#xD;
      psychological factors drive compensatory behaviors that impair QOL in OAB remain unknown, as&#xD;
      there are no highly-controlled studies of anxiety-OAB links. Understanding these&#xD;
      relationships would be a critical advance to individualizing care of patients with OAB. The&#xD;
      proposed project will comprehensively investigate for the first time how stress, anxiety and&#xD;
      OAB interact, including the impacts on bladder sensitivity, urinary symptoms, and&#xD;
      compensatory bladder behaviors. The investigators propose a feedforward loop, whereby&#xD;
      increased OAB symptoms increase anxiety (via response to coping with stressful situations),&#xD;
      which in turn increases OAB symptoms (via increased bladder sensitivity). The study further&#xD;
      proposes that compensatory behaviors are driven by anxiety-related learning processes that&#xD;
      help perpetuate this relationship. The team will test the hypotheses in a sample of men and&#xD;
      women with OAB and healthy controls. Aim 1 will test the hypothesis that acute,&#xD;
      experimentally induced psychological stress will be more strongly associated with increased&#xD;
      bladder sensitivity in OAB patients than in controls, using a novel bladder sensation meter&#xD;
      with oral hydration and stress induction procedures. Aim will test the hypothesis that&#xD;
      psychological stress and anxiety will have concurrent and lagged effects on day-to-day&#xD;
      urinary symptoms that are stronger in individuals with OAB than in controls, using an&#xD;
      ecological momentary assessment approach (7-day electronic diary) to examine prospective&#xD;
      associations between everyday perceived stress, anxiety and urinary symptoms. Aim 3 will test&#xD;
      the hypothesis that compensatory behaviors (i.e. coping) used at the time of voiding will be&#xD;
      associated with subsequent reductions in anxiety levels, using a 3-day sensation-related&#xD;
      bladder diary that captures concurrent bladder behaviors and anxiety symptoms as well as&#xD;
      lagged symptoms 30 minutes post-void. Delineating these relationships and patterns will allow&#xD;
      for identification of potentially modifiable factors or areas for intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a case-control study in which all participants undergo the same procedures</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Bladder stress reactivity</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Changes to bladder sensation prompted by acute psychological stress tasks as measured by degree of perception of bladder fullness (100 point scale)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Systolic blood pressure responses</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Changes to non-invasive systolic blood pressure prompted by psychological stress tasks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Diastolic blood pressure response</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Changes to non-invasive diastolic blood pressure prompted by psychological stress tasks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Heart rate response</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Changes to non-invasive heart rate prompted by psychological stress tasks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">216</enrollment>
  <condition>Overactive Bladder</condition>
  <condition>Stress, Psychological</condition>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Subjects</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All subjects will undergo accelerated oral hydration to induce diuresis and then acute psychological stress tasks to induce acute stress. Outcomes will measure changes to perceived bladder sensation in response to acute stress provocation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Psychological stress induction</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will undergo acute psychological stress induction by performing mental arithmetic tasks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Subjects</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Accelerated oral hydration</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will drink 2L of fluid in a short period of time to force diuresis and urine production.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Subjects</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or Female, at least 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive status and English language skills sufficient to complete all study related&#xD;
             assessment materials&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of OAB (score of ≥4 on the OAB-V3 awareness tool)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Urgency predominant urinary incontinence, if incontinence present&#xD;
&#xD;
        Specific entry criteria for control subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject to the same inclusion/exclusion criteria, plus:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of OAB (score of ≤3 on the OAB-V3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No urgency-related urinary incontinence&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Post void residual urine &gt;150ml&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Need for catheterization, indwelling or intermittent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men: uroflow &lt; 10 ml per sec&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current symptomatic urinary tract infection that has not resolved&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Comorbid neurological conditions, including spinal cord injury, systemic neurologic&#xD;
             illnesses (i.e. multiple sclerosis, Parkinson's disease) or central nervous system&#xD;
             disease (i.e. brain tumor, stroke) thought to impact bladder function&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Iatrogenic (i.e. post-surgical) or non-iatrogenic obstructive conditions (i.e. pelvic&#xD;
             organ prolapse greater than stage 2, urethral stricture, benign prostatic enlargement)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior pelvic irradiation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or prior bladder malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed diagnosis of Interstitial Cystitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hematuria without a clinically appropriate evaluation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>William S Reynolds, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>William S Reynolds, MD</last_name>
    <phone>6153431317</phone>
    <email>w.stuart.reynolds@vumc.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>William S Reynolds, MD</last_name>
      <phone>615-343-1317</phone>
      <email>w.stuart.reynolds@vumc.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>William S. Reynolds</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Urinary Bladder, Overactive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stress, Psychological</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

