<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05087732</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>VIV-STYL-LIDO-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05087732</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness and Safety of STYLAGE® M LIDOCAINE Versus STYLAGE® M in Filling Nasolabial Folds</brief_title>
  <acronym>MLIDOM</acronym>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Triple Blinded, Randomized, Controlled Clinical Study of the Effectiveness and Safety of STYLAGE® M LIDOCAINE Versus STYLAGE® M in Filling Nasolabial Folds</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Laboratoires Vivacy</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Laboratoires Vivacy</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This clinical investigation is designed to compare the STYLAGE® M Lidocaïne to STYLAGE® M in&#xD;
      terms of correction of nasolabial folds severity and pain felt by the subject, and to assess&#xD;
      and compare the safety and effectiveness of both products.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects with moderate to severe nasolabial folds will receive both treatments in a&#xD;
      split-face design at D0, and a touch-up will be done 14 days after if necessary. The subjects&#xD;
      will be followed-up over a 12-month period after initial injection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study will be prospective, triple-blinded (Subject, Treating Investigator, and Blinded&#xD;
      Live Evaluator),randomized,within-subjects (split-face),active-controlled, monocenter with&#xD;
      blinded subjects and evaluators assessing the efficacy , safety and pain of STYLAGE® M&#xD;
      Lidocaïne and STYLAGE® M in the treatment of nasolabial folds.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sixty five healthy subjects between the age of 30 and 65, with symetrical moderate to severe&#xD;
      nasolabial folds with grade 3 or 4 on both sides on the Wrinkle Severity Rating Scale (WSRS)&#xD;
      for nasolabial folds as assessed in live, who have given their informed consent and met all&#xD;
      eligibility criteria, will be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STYLAGE® M Lidocaïne will be injected in one nasolabial fold (right or left according to the&#xD;
      randomization list). STYLAGE® M will be injected in the contralateral nasolabial fold.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A touch-up is possible if required 14 days after. Subjects will be followed up at 14 days, 3,&#xD;
      6 and 12 months timepoints. All the effectiveness and safety evaluations will be done by a&#xD;
      Blinded Live Evaluator (BLE) who will be different from the Treating Investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Variation in severity score of nasolabial folds will be assessed in live by the BLE and&#xD;
      retrospectively assessed on photographs (2D) by an Independent Photographic Reviewer using&#xD;
      the validated 5-point Wrinkles Severity Rating Scale (WSRS) at each time point The subjects&#xD;
      and the independent blinded evaluator will assess the overall aesthetic improvement level of&#xD;
      the face, for each side independently, at each time point after treatment initiation The&#xD;
      subjects will be asked to score the pain felt during injection, and 5, 15 and 30 minutes&#xD;
      after injection on a Visual Analog Scale .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 19, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 29, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 29, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Within-subject study with treatment of one nasolabial fold with STYLAGE® M and STYLAGE® M Lidocaïne of the other nasolabial fold</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Treating investigators (Injectors) , subjects, blinded live evaluator and Independant Photographic reviewer are blinded.&#xD;
The product name will not be printed on the labels of investigational device (outside boxes, blisters and syringes )</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference of aesthetic improvement on the Wrinkle Severity Rating Scale (WSRS),</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>First co-primary endpoint will be the difference of aesthetic improvement on the Wrinkle Severity Rating Scale (WSRS), as evaluated by the BLE, at the side of the face treated with Stylage® M lidocaïne compared to the side of the face treated with Stylage® M, in a double non-inferiority statistical model.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Within-subject difference in injection site pain</measure>
    <time_frame>immediatly after injection of each side</time_frame>
    <description>Second co-primary endpoint will be the (STYLAGE® M Side - STYLAGE® M lidocaine Side), self-assessed by the subjects on a 100 mm Visual Analogue Scale (VAS), in a superiority statistical model.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>WSRS change from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>4 days, 3, and 12 months after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>WSRS change from baseline as assessed by the Blinded Live Evaluator (BLE)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>WSRS change from baseline on photographs</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days, 3, 6, and 12 months after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>WSRS change from baseline as assessed by an Independent Photographic Reviewer (IPR), on photographs.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Responder rate for WSRS in live</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days, 3, 6, and 12 months after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Responder rate for WSRS , as assessed by the BLE. A responder is defined as a subject with at least 1-point improvement from baseline on the WSRS.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Responder rate for WSRS on photograph</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days, 3, 6 and 12 months after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Responder rate for WSRS , as assessed by an Independent Photographic Reviewer (IPR), on photographs.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Global Aesthetic Improvement assessed by the BLE</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days, 3, 6, and 12 months after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Global Aesthetic Improvement assessed by the BLE on the Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale (GAIS).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Global Aesthetic Improvement assessed by the Subject</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days, 3, 6, and 12 months after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Global Aesthetic Improvement assessed by the Subject on the Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale (GAIS).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportions of GAIS responders assessed by the BLE</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days, 3, 6, and 12 months after baseline.</time_frame>
    <description>Proportions of GAIS responders defined as subjects with a GAIS score &quot; Improved &quot;, &quot; Much Improved &quot;, or &quot; Very Much Improved &quot;, as assessed by the BLE</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportions of GAIS responders assessed by the subjects</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days, 3, 6, and 12 months after baseline.</time_frame>
    <description>Proportions of GAIS responders defined as subjects with a Global Aesthetic &quot; Improved &quot;, &quot; Much Improved &quot;, or &quot; Very Much Improved &quot;, as assessed by the subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subject Satisfaction questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days, 3, 6, and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of subjects either &quot; Somehow satisfied &quot;, &quot; Satisfied &quot;, or &quot; Very Satisfied &quot;, as assessed by the subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Injection Site Pain self-assessed by the subjects (touch-up)</measure>
    <time_frame>immediatly after touch-up injection</time_frame>
    <description>Injection Site Pain during injection self-assessed by the subjects of each side during optional touch-up treatment (VAS 100mm).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Injection Site Pain self-assessed by the subjects (initial and touch-up)</measure>
    <time_frame>5, 15, and 30 minutes post-injection</time_frame>
    <description>Injection Site Pain self-assessed by the subjects at during initial and optional touch-up treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects who reported at least 10 mm, 20 mm, and 30 mm less VAS pain (initial and touch-up).</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after injection, and at 5, 15, and 30 minutes after each injection</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of subjects who reported at least 10 mm, 20 mm, and 30 mm less VAS pain associated with injections of Stylage® M Lidocaïne compared to Stylage® M, immediately after injection (initial and touch-up).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects that reported at least half less VAS pain (initial and touch-up)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after injection, and at 5, 15, and 30 minutes after each injection</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of subjects that reported at least half less VAS pain associated with injections of Stylage® M Lidocaïne compared to Stylage® M (initial and touch-up).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Injection site reaction and adverse events reporting</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Product tolerance will be assessed by collection of Injection Site Reactions (ISRs) after each injection session, and Adverse Events throughout the study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">65</enrollment>
  <condition>Aging</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Stylage® M Lidocaïne</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>STYLAGE® M Lidocaine is a hyalorunic acid injectable gel with Lidocaine hydrochloride whose intended purpose is the filling of skin depressions on the face by dermal injection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Stylage® M</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>STYLAGE® M Lidocaine is a hyalorunic acid injectable gel whose intended purpose is the filling of skin depressions on the face by dermal injection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>STYLAGE® M Lidocaïne</intervention_name>
    <description>Up to 2 mL will be injected at Day 0 on a nasolabial fold and, if required, up to 1 mL could be injected 14 days after on the same nasolabial fold (touch-up).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Stylage® M</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Stylage® M Lidocaïne</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>STYLAGE® M</intervention_name>
    <description>Up to 2 mL will be injected at Day 0 on a nasolabial fold and, if required, up to 1 mL could be injected 14 days after on the same nasolabial fold (touch-up).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Stylage® M</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Stylage® M Lidocaïne</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age: between 30 and 65 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject with right and left NLF rating grade 3 or 4 (Moderate or Severe) on the&#xD;
             Wrinkle Severity Rating Scale (WSRS), as assessed by a Blinded Live Evaluator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject having the same WSRS grade on both NLFs (i.e., symmetrical NLFs).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject with marionette's lines that do not require to be treated in addition to&#xD;
             nasolabial folds, according to the Blinded Live Evaluator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects willing to abstain from any other facial plastic surgical or cosmetic&#xD;
             procedures (i.e., dermal fillers, toxin treatments, facial ablative or fractional&#xD;
             laser, microdermal abrasion, chemical peels, non-invasive skin-tightening) below the&#xD;
             level of the lower orbital rim, for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects agreeing not to take Anti-histamines within 2 weeks prior to touch-up visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject able to comply with protocol requirements and to complete all required visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subject, psychologically able to understand the study related information and to give&#xD;
             a written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subject having given freely and expressly his/her informed consent to participate in&#xD;
             the study, and use of data privacy, prior to any study-related procedure being&#xD;
             performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subject agreeing to have photographs taken.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Female of childbearing potential must have a negative urinary pregnancy test (UPT) at&#xD;
             Visit 1 and practice a reliable method of contraception throughout the study, and for&#xD;
             at least 12 weeks prior to study enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subject affiliated to a health social security.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject presenting any symptom which can be related to a medical condition that is&#xD;
             likely to make the subject not being compliant with the study schedule, at the&#xD;
             discretion of the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pregnant or breastfeeding woman or planning a pregnancy during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Had prior surgery in the mid- and/or lower-face area, including the nasolabial&#xD;
             fold(s), or has a permanent implant or graft in the mid- and/or lower-face area, or a&#xD;
             tattoo, a scar, moles, or anything that could interfere with effectiveness&#xD;
             assessments. (NOTE: Rhinoplasty is permitted if the procedure was ≥ 12 months prior to&#xD;
             study enrolment).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject in a social or sanitary establishment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject who had been deprived of their freedom by administrative or legal decision or&#xD;
             who is under guardianship.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject participating to another research on human beings or who is in an exclusion&#xD;
             period of one.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject having received 4500 euros indemnities for participation in researches&#xD;
             involving human beings in France in the 12 previous months, including participation in&#xD;
             the present study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject suffering from a severe or progressive disease or any other pathology that may&#xD;
             interfere with the evaluation of the study results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subject with known history of or suffering from autoimmune disease and/or immune&#xD;
             deficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subject with a past history of streptococcal disease, such as acute rheumatic fever or&#xD;
             recurrent sore throats with cardiac localisation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects suffering from porphyria.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subject suffering from inflammatory and/or infectious cutaneous disorders in or near&#xD;
             the studied zones (herpes, acne, mycosis, papilloma…). Subject with recurrent herpes&#xD;
             is not eligible even if asymptomatic at time of inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subject having history of severe allergy or anaphylactic shock including&#xD;
             hypersensitivity to hyaluronic acid, to gram positive bacterial proteins, to lidocaine&#xD;
             or antiseptic solution or amide type local anaesthetics.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subject predisposed to develop keloids or hypertrophic scarring.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Subject prone to develop inflammatory skin conditions or having tendency to bleeding&#xD;
             disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Subject having received treatment with a laser, a dermabrasion, a surgery, a peeling&#xD;
             or other ablative procedure below the inferior orbital rim within the past 6 months&#xD;
             prior to study start.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Subject having received injection with a resorbable filling product (eg, hyaluronic&#xD;
             acid, collagen) below the inferior orbital rim within the past 12 months prior to&#xD;
             study start.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Subject having received at any time injection with a slowly resorbable filling product&#xD;
             (polylactic acid, calcium hydroxyapatite, combinations of hyaluronic acid (HA) and&#xD;
             hypromellose, HA and dextran microbeads or HA and TriCalcium Phosphate (TCP), etc.) or&#xD;
             with a non-resorbable filling product (polyacrylamide, silicone, combination of&#xD;
             methacrylic polymers and collagen, polymer particles, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Subject having received at any time a treatment with tensor threads below the inferior&#xD;
             orbital rim.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Subject who received oral surgery (tooth extraction, orthodontia or implantation)&#xD;
             within 6 weeks prior to study start or who plans to undergo any of these procedures&#xD;
             during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Subject having started or changed her oral contraceptive or any other hormonal&#xD;
             treatment during 12 weeks prior to study start or planning to change it during the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Subject using medication such as aspirin, nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAID)&#xD;
             (ibuprofen, naproxen, etc.), antiplatelet agents, anticoagulants, vitamin C or other&#xD;
             substances known to increase coagulation time within one week prior to treatment&#xD;
             dates.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Subject using medication that reduce or inhibit hepatic metabolism (cimetidine,&#xD;
             beta-blockers, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Subject undergoing a topical treatment on the test area or a systemic treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Anti-histamines during the 2 weeks prior to study start;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Immunosuppressors and/or corticoids during the 4 weeks prior to study start;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Retinoids during the 6 months prior to study start.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Siham RHARBAOUI</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dermscan Pharmascan</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>marie-Helene Peirone</last_name>
    <phone>00 33 6 52 39 19 20</phone>
    <email>mh.peirone@vivacy.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Audrey NATALIZIO</last_name>
    <phone>Tel: + 33(0) 472 82 36 56</phone>
    <email>ana@dermscan.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Eurofins Dermscan Pharmascan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Villeurbanne</city>
        <zip>69100</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Audrey NATALAZIO</last_name>
      <phone>+ 33 4 72 82 36 56</phone>
      <email>ANA@dermscan.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Siham RHARBAOUI, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>hyaluronic acid</keyword>
  <keyword>Nasolabial Folds</keyword>
  <keyword>Injection</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy subjects</keyword>
  <keyword>Prospective</keyword>
  <keyword>Randomized</keyword>
  <keyword>Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Within-subjects</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

