<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05088629</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>universitysanko</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05088629</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>3-meter Walk Back Test, Proprioception, Trunk Control and Muscle Strength in Children With Cerebral Palsy</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Relationship of the 3-meter Back Walk Test With Proprioception, Trunk Control and Muscle Strength in Children With Cerebral Palsy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sanko University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sanko University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The gait problems of the child with CP should be examined in detail. At this point, by&#xD;
      assigning a different task to the child with the backward walking assessment, body&#xD;
      perception, trunk stability provided by anterior-posterior cocontraction, balance, correction&#xD;
      and protective reactions are observed. This observation ensures the exact determination of&#xD;
      the problem that will guide the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Back walking is a more difficult activity as it involves neuromuscular control and depends on&#xD;
      proprioceptive sense and protective reflexes. In activities of daily living, backward walking&#xD;
      is needed to perform tasks such as leaning on a chair and opening the door.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The only test that can be applied to evaluate the ability to walk backwards is the 3 meter&#xD;
      back walk test. This test was found to be valid and reliable both in the elderly population&#xD;
      and in patients with total knee arthroplasty. In the literature, no study has been found on&#xD;
      the factors affecting the three-meter backward walking skills in children with CP. The aim of&#xD;
      this study is to examine the relationship between 3 meter back walk test and proprioception,&#xD;
      trunk control and muscle strength.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cerebral palsy is a non-progressive neurodevelopmental disorder that occurs in the immature&#xD;
      brain during pregnancy, birth or postpartum. It is the picture of childhood that most&#xD;
      frequently causes functional disability. Motor development retardation, balance and posture&#xD;
      problems are among the most important problems that cause disability in CP. This picture is&#xD;
      often accompanied by cognitive, sensory, perceptual deficiencies, orthopedic disorders and&#xD;
      other medical problems. In children with spastic CP, selective movement deficiencies, lack of&#xD;
      muscle strength, lack of postural control, lack of proprioception sense, loss of balance and&#xD;
      coordination, muscle tone disorders, and motor development delays are seen. Disorders due to&#xD;
      muscle tone problems, secondary joint deformations and alignment problems, especially in&#xD;
      walking function, are common problems in activities performed against gravity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Deficiencies in trunk strength and control, lack of strength in antigravity muscles, severity&#xD;
      of spasticity, loss of balance and coordination, combined with time-distance problems of&#xD;
      walking, cause excessive energy consumption, insufficient for daily living activities and&#xD;
      social participation, negatively affecting quality of life, causing muscle and joint problems&#xD;
      over time. gait pattern.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main purpose of the study is to examine the relationship of the 3-meter back walk test&#xD;
      with proprioception, trunk control and muscle strength in children with cerebral palsy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 15, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 15, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>3 meter back walk test</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>A distance of three meters will be measured and marked. When the signal is given, they will be asked to walk backwards safely and stop when they reach the marked point.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proprioception</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of proprioception with a goniometer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Trunk Control Measurement Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>It consists of two main parts, static sitting balance and dynamic sitting balance. An increase in the score indicates increased trunk control.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Muscle Strength</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Muscle strength will be evaluated with a digital manual muscle dynamometer.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gillette Functional Walking Assessment Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>It is an observational assessment scale that evaluates the functional effectiveness of walking.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Cerebral Palsy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>One group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>3-meter Walk Back Test, Proprioception, Trunk Control and Muscle Strength test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Clinical Tests</intervention_name>
    <description>Clinical Tests</description>
    <arm_group_label>One group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The age of onset of maturation of walking, in terms of covering the maturation ages&#xD;
             and between 6-15 years old,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children with CP with a Communication Function Classification System (CFCS) ≤ 3,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children with upper extremity muscles ≤ 2 according to the Modified Ashworth Scale&#xD;
             (MASH)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children in Level-I-II, which are groups with independent walking ability according to&#xD;
             Gross Motor Function Classification System,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not having any known vision problems in terms of not affecting the postural control&#xD;
             responses,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not using any pharmacological agent that may affect muscle tone,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to follow verbal commands without mental retardation at a level that interferes&#xD;
             with communication,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who have not had any Boutilinum Toxin injection and/or orthopedic surgery in the&#xD;
             lower extremity in the last six months,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children without epileptic seizures will be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having contractures in any joint of the hip, knee and ankle in the lower extremity,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children with hearing and vision problems with any diagnosis will not be included in&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nevin ERGUN, Prof.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Sanko University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Enver KATIRCI, pt</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rehabilitation Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hatice ADIGÜZEL, asst. prof.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Kahramanmaraş Sütçü İmam University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Zekiye İpek KATIRCI KIRMACI, asst. prof.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Kahramanmaraş Sütçü İmam University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Enver Katırcı, pt</last_name>
    <phone>+905432414146</phone>
    <email>enverkatirci@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sanko University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>zekiye ipek katırcı kırmacı</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Asst. Prof.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>cerebral palsy</keyword>
  <keyword>back walk</keyword>
  <keyword>proprioception</keyword>
  <keyword>trunk control</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Paralysis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cerebral Palsy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

