<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05080543</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Microcirculation septic shock</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05080543</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Microcirculation Recruitment Using Albumin 20% and Terlipressin in Septic Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Recruitment of Microcirculation Using Albumin 20% and Terlipressin in Patients With Septic Shock: a Randomized Controlled Double-blinded Study.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Amany Mousa Salama Muhammed</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to evaluate the effect of combining HSA 20% and terlipressin on the&#xD;
      microcirculation in patients with septic shock using the following;-&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Microcirculation recruitment by Cytocam-IDF.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cardiac output by LiDCOrapid.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Measuring serum lactate level.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Sepsis is one of the major medical problems and is responsible for high morbidity and&#xD;
      mortality. Surviving Sepsis Campaign Guideline 2016 introduced 3-hours and 6-hours bundles in&#xD;
      management of septic shock. The 2018 update of the Surviving Sepsis Campaign guidelines&#xD;
      introduced the 'Hour-1 Bundle' which recommends treatment with intravenous fluids,&#xD;
      measurement of serum lactate concentration as a marker of illness severity, administration of&#xD;
      vasopressors, obtaining blood cultures and administering broad-spectrum antibiotics, all&#xD;
      within the first hour.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The usual targets for resuscitation of patients with septic shock are the macro-circulatory&#xD;
      parameters such as mean arterial blood pressure and heart rate; however, it is believed that&#xD;
      restoration of microcirculatory parameters is not sufficient to avoid organ failure unless it&#xD;
      was associated with improved microcirculatory perfusion. The loss of coherence between macro-&#xD;
      and micro-circulatory parameters increases the need to evaluate the microcirculatory blood&#xD;
      flow. So impaired microvascular perfusion is increasingly recognized as a major determinant&#xD;
      of tissue hypoxia during sepsis and is a key factor in the pathogenesis of sepsis-induced&#xD;
      organ failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fluid resuscitation is recommended to be initiated immediately and completed within the first&#xD;
      hour. Guidelines recommend at least a 30-mL/kg bolus of crystalloid fluid as the initial&#xD;
      resuscitation. Crystalloid is the fluid of choice for initial resuscitation and subsequent&#xD;
      intra-vascular volume replacement in patients with sepsis and septic shock.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Albumin in addition to crystalloids is suggested when patients require a substantial amount&#xD;
      of crystalloids. Although the guidelines make no recommendation regarding which concentration&#xD;
      of albumin should be used, 5% albumin is most commonly used in patients with hypovolemia to&#xD;
      administer as much volume as possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In 2016, a study showed that in a rat model of normotensive endotoxemia, the infusion of 4%&#xD;
      or 20% Human Serum Albumin &quot;HSA&quot; restored microvascular perfusion in otherwise unresuscitated&#xD;
      animals. A more stable microvascular improvement noticed with 20% HSA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sepsis is also characterized by an enhanced activation of inflammatory and oxidative stress&#xD;
      pathways, which leads to endothelial dysfunction and vascular hyporeactivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For its ability to counteract oxidative and nitrosative stress, albumin may represent not&#xD;
      only a plasma expander but also an endothelium-modulating agent. In an experimental rodent&#xD;
      model of endotoxemia, (HSA) prevented endothelial dysfunction and vascular hyporeactivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In patients with septic shock requiring vasopressors, a targeted mean arterial pressure &quot;MAP&quot;&#xD;
      of 65 mm Hg within the first hour is recommended. Norepinephrine is the recommended&#xD;
      first-line vasopressor in septic shock. If MAP is not maintained at 65 mm Hg or greater with&#xD;
      norepinephrine alone or if the norepinephrine dose needs to be decreased, either vasopressin&#xD;
      (up to 0.03 unit/minute) or epinephrine can be added to norepinephrine. Although&#xD;
      norepinephrine is widely regarded as the first-line vasoactive medication in sepsis,&#xD;
      literature continues to debate whether the early addition of vasopressin should be common&#xD;
      practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Terlipressin is a synthetic analogue of vasopressin which has greater selectivity for the V1&#xD;
      receptor that cause vascular smooth muscle vasoconstriction in response to vasopressin and&#xD;
      thus could be associated with fewer side effects than vasopressin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In 2016 a study showed that terlipressin therapy was associated with good improvement in&#xD;
      hemodynamic variables and kidney functions more than adrenaline in patients with refractory&#xD;
      septic shock despite adequate fluid resuscitation and the use of norepinephrine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      No data was found on effect of combination of albumin and terlipressin on microcirculation in&#xD;
      septic patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study aims to investigate the effect of this combination on microcirculation using&#xD;
      Cytocam-IDF (incident dark-field illumination), Braedius.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>a randomized controlled and double-blinded</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Flow Index 6hs</measure>
    <time_frame>6 hrs</time_frame>
    <description>Determination the degree the mean flow index (MFI) 6 hrs after administration albumin and terlipressin in patient with septic shock</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Flow Index 24hs</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hs</time_frame>
    <description>Determination the degree the mean flow index (MFI) 24 hrs after administration albumin and terlipressin in patient with septic shock.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Septic Shock</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group AT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>will receive a bolus of albumin (1gm/kg) and terlipressin loading dose of 1 mg over 20 minutes followed by infusion at rate (2 μ g/kg/h)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Controlled</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>will receive the routine management of septic shock patients as culture-based IV antibiotics, IV fluids and intropic support plus a placebo (as lactated ringer solution in the same infusion rates for blinding).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Albumin 20% and terlipressin</intervention_name>
    <description>Evaluation the effect of adding 20% HSA and terlipressin on microvascular ﬂow index (MFI), flow heterogeneity index, total vessel density (TVD), and perfused vessel density (PVD) in comparison to the standard care in patient with septic shock.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Controlled</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group AT</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Microcirculation</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of septic shock meeting all of the following criteria less than 24&#xD;
             hours:-&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Clinically possible or probable or microbiologically confirmed infection taking&#xD;
                  into account the definitions of the &quot;International Sepsis Forum (ISF)&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Despite adequate volume therapy, vasopressors are required to maintain mean&#xD;
                  arterial pressure (MAP) ≥ 65 mm Hg.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Serum lactate level &gt; 2 mmol/l (18 mg/dl) despite adequate volume therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who failed to achieve target MAP despite adequate resuscitation with fluids&#xD;
             and maximum dose of noreadrenaline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute coronary artery disease or underlying cardiac dysfunction [cardiac index (CI)&#xD;
             &lt;2.2 l/min/m 2 ].&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe liver disease (Child-Pugh grade C)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic renal failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to Norepinephrine, terlipressin and human albumin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those having Raynaud's phenomenon, or a vasospastic diathesis and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other causes of shock e.g.; hemorrhagic hypovolaemia, cardiogenic shock, anaphylactic&#xD;
             shock, neurogenic shock.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant patients and lactation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amany Mousa Salama, Assistant lecturer</last_name>
    <phone>+201004820018</phone>
    <email>dr.amany.mousa@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Mohamed Sayed Arafa, Lecturer</last_name>
    <phone>+201003752053</phone>
    <email>dr.3arafa1@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Amany Mousa Salama Muhammed</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>CairoU</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Microcirculation</keyword>
  <keyword>Terlipressin</keyword>
  <keyword>Human Albumin 20%</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Shock, Septic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Terlipressin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

