<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05083611</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PTGraMI01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05083611</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Graded Motor Imagery in Phantom Limb Pain (GraMI Protocol)</brief_title>
  <acronym>GraMI</acronym>
  <official_title>The Effectiveness of Graded Motor Imagery in Phantom Limb Pain in Amputee Patients (GraMI Protocol)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Vic - Central University of Catalonia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Vic - Central University of Catalonia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The International Association for the Study of Pain defines phantom limb pain (PLP) as that&#xD;
      pain referred to a part of the body that has been previously removed as if it were still&#xD;
      present. It affects between 55-80% of the population who has suffered an amputation, but not&#xD;
      in the same frequency and intensity. Graded motor imagery (GMI) is a progressive,&#xD;
      physiotherapeutic treatment modality developed to train and reorganize the brain based on&#xD;
      three consecutive techniques: laterality recognition, motor imagery, and mirror therapy. The&#xD;
      scientific evidence on the implementation of GMI in PLP is scarce, noting that there is no&#xD;
      standardized way to use it in this patient profile. Therefore, the need is generated to&#xD;
      develop and validate a GMI protocol to address the PLP and test its effectiveness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study hypothesis is that graded motor imagery is a conservative treatment method based on&#xD;
      motor learning, neuroplasticity, and mirror neuron stimulation that may have positive effects&#xD;
      in decreasing phantom limb pain in the amputated patient, and as a consequence, decrease the&#xD;
      associated psychological factors and improve the quality of life and functionality of the&#xD;
      person.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A randomized clinical trial will be performed with simple blinding, following the CONSORT&#xD;
      guide for this type of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It will be carried out at the community level with supervision and follow-up by the principal&#xD;
      investigator.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The International Association for the Study of Pain defines phantom limb pain (PLP) as that&#xD;
      pain referred to a part of the body that has been previously removed as if it were still&#xD;
      present. It affects between 55-80% of the population who has suffered an amputation, but not&#xD;
      in the same frequency and intensity. The persistence of this pain over time may decrease the&#xD;
      person's quality of life. The main hypothesis is that after an amputation, maladaptive&#xD;
      plasticity occurs at the level of the primary motor and sensory cortex, causing an&#xD;
      incongruity of visual, motor and sensory information.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Graded motor imagery (GMI) is a progressive, physiotherapeutic treatment modality developed&#xD;
      to train and reorganize the brain based on three consecutive techniques: laterality&#xD;
      recognition, motor imagery, and mirror therapy. The scientific evidence on the implementation&#xD;
      of GMI in PLP is scarce, noting that there is no standardized way to use it in this patient&#xD;
      profile. Therefore, the need is generated to develop and validate a GMI protocol to address&#xD;
      the PLP and test its effectiveness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, at the beginning of this project, a systematic review was performed to know the&#xD;
      effectiveness of the GMI, and the techniques that make it up, on the PLP of the amputated&#xD;
      patient, and thus be able to design an GMI protocol based on scientific evidence.&#xD;
      Subsequently, this protocol was validated through a group of international experts through a&#xD;
      study with Delphi methodology, resulting in the GMI protocol called GraMI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The GraMI protocol is easy to implement, allowing the patient to perform it autonomously at&#xD;
      home with the follow-up of a professional. It is necessary to have a mirror box and a mobile&#xD;
      application to be able to carry out the intervention. During the COVID-19 pandemic, many&#xD;
      patients remained in their homes confined without being able to access their rehabilitation,&#xD;
      which caused alterations in the quality of life, in the prescribed treatment and in the&#xD;
      evolution of the symptoms. The promotion of the patient's self-care at home, enhances their&#xD;
      active participation and the intensity of the intervention, so that greater benefits can be&#xD;
      obtained and consequently improvement in the quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Study the effects of the GraMI protocol on DMF in the amputee patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Design a mobile application to be able to carry out the intervention and determine its&#xD;
           usability.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Analyse the effects of the GraMI protocol on the quality of life, functionality and&#xD;
           psychological aspects of amputee patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Understand the perception and satisfaction obtained through the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A randomized clinical trial will be performed with simple blinding, following the CONSORT&#xD;
      guide for this type of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It will be carried out at the community level with supervision and follow-up by the principal&#xD;
      investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During recruitment, a person outside the intervention will randomize the participants through&#xD;
      sealed envelopes where they will be assigned to the control group or intervention group. A&#xD;
      non-probabilistic sampling type for quotas will be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intervention of the two groups will last 6 weeks plus 8 weeks of follow-up. During the&#xD;
      study, three assessments will be performed, one at the beginning, one after the intervention&#xD;
      (6 weeks) and one follow-up (8 weeks post-intervention).&#xD;
&#xD;
      These assessments will collect quantitative variables and also conduct semi-structured&#xD;
      individual interviews with participants who are part of the intervention group in order to&#xD;
      know and understand the influence of phantom limb pain in their lives and the degree of&#xD;
      satisfaction obtained through the intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 10, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline phantom limb pain at 6 weeks post-intervention and 8 weeks follow-up</measure>
    <time_frame>Post intervention (6 weeks) and 8 weeks follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by Short Form McGill Pain Questionnaire. Assesses pain qualitatively and quantitatively, it is a self-testifying scale</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from quality of life at 6 weeks post-intervention and 8 weeks follow-up</measure>
    <time_frame>Post intervention (6 weeks) and 8 weeks follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by EuroQol scale. It is a self-challenging scale made up of 5 dimensions: mobility, self-care, regular activities, pain / discomfort and anxiety / depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline functionality at 6 weeks post-intervention and 8 weeks follow-up</measure>
    <time_frame>Post intervention (6 weeks) and 8 weeks follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by Functional Independence Scale (FIM). It is a scale built from 18 items within 6 areas of operation: personal care, sphincter control, mobility, walking, communication and social knowledge.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline physcological aspects at 6 weeks post-intervention and 8 weeks follow-up</measure>
    <time_frame>Post intervention (6 weeks) and 8 weeks follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by Beck depression inventory. It is a self-answering scale of 21 questions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Phantom Limb Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group will receive an information session on phantom limb pain (1 hour) and will continue with the usual treatment received.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The experimental group will receive an educational session on phantom limb pain and the previously designed GraMI protocol through a systematic review and validation through a study with Delphi methodology. This protocol contains the three techniques with their defined intensity, frequency, duration and progression.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>GraMI</intervention_name>
    <description>The intervention will last 6 weeks. Each technique lasts for 2 weeks. The first two techniques will be performed through the previously designed mobile application and the last technique will be performed through a mirror box. The patient can do it autonomously with the supervision of the principal investigator.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People over the age 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Amputation of a limb.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minimum score of 3 on the VAS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pharmacologically stable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be discharged from hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Visual disturbances (hemianopia).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant neurological or cognitive disturbances (attention deficit, sensory&#xD;
             aphasia).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receive two of the three techniques that make up the GMI as treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sandra Rierola Fochs</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Universitat de Vic- Universitat Central de Catalunya (UVic-UCC)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sandra Rierola Fochs</last_name>
    <phone>630841957</phone>
    <email>sandra.rierola@uvic.cat</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <reference>
    <citation>Anaforoğlu Külünkoğlu B, Erbahçeci F, Alkan A. A comparison of the effects of mirror therapy and phantom exercises on phantom limb pain. Turk J Med Sci. 2019 Feb 11;49(1):101-109. doi: 10.3906/sag-1712-166.</citation>
    <PMID>30762318</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Limakatso K, Corten L, Parker R. The effects of graded motor imagery and its components on phantom limb pain and disability in upper and lower limb amputees: a systematic review protocol. Syst Rev. 2016 Sep 1;5(1):145. doi: 10.1186/s13643-016-0322-5.</citation>
    <PMID>27582042</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Moseley GL. Graded motor imagery for pathologic pain: a randomized controlled trial. Neurology. 2006 Dec 26;67(12):2129-34. Epub 2006 Nov 2.</citation>
    <PMID>17082465</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Limakatso K, Madden VJ, Manie S, Parker R. The effectiveness of graded motor imagery for reducing phantom limb pain in amputees: a randomised controlled trial. Physiotherapy. 2020 Dec;109:65-74. doi: 10.1016/j.physio.2019.06.009. Epub 2019 Jun 28.</citation>
    <PMID>31992445</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 15, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Vic - Central University of Catalonia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Rierola</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Physiotherapist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Phantom limb pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Graded motor imagery</keyword>
  <keyword>Treatment</keyword>
  <keyword>Amputee</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Phantom Limb</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

