<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05086783</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>3629</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05086783</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Video-based Coaching (VBC) in Gynecologic Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicentre, Randomized Controlled Trial to Assess Video-based Feedback for Surgical Coaching in Gynecology and Gynecologic Oncology</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mount Sinai Hospital, Canada</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Health Network, Toronto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mount Sinai Hospital, Canada</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This multi-centre, randomized controlled trial aims to assess the role of video-based&#xD;
      coaching (VBC) in residency education in gynecologic and gynecologic oncology surgery. It&#xD;
      involves a trainee and a surgical coach, who together review a recording of the trainee&#xD;
      performing a surgical skill or procedure and coaching is provided for skill improvement.&#xD;
      Resident performance will be evaluated using a standardized scoring scale by two experienced&#xD;
      surgeons before and after the intervention and compared to the control group receiving the&#xD;
      standard surgical teaching curriculum.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Achieving technical excellence is a core component of surgical training. Historically, a&#xD;
      combination of didactic teaching, surgical simulation and the master-apprentice model (MAM)&#xD;
      were the cornerstone of surgical education. With restrictions on resident duty hours and&#xD;
      operating time with the COVID-19 pandemic and a shift to competency-based medical education,&#xD;
      there is an opportunity to transform surgical education and improve educational efficiency.&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to assess the effect of video-based coaching (VBC) on resident&#xD;
      skill acquisition in laparoscopic suturing of the vaginal vault at the time of laparoscopic&#xD;
      hysterectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will include year 3 to 5 Obstetrics and Gynecology residents completing&#xD;
      gynecology and gynecologic oncology rotations at the study sites. Participants will be&#xD;
      randomized to the control (standard surgical curriculum) and intervention (standard&#xD;
      curriculum and VBC) arms on the day of the first attempt. The effectiveness of VBC will be&#xD;
      measured by the difference in baseline and post-intervention standardized blinded score&#xD;
      between the intervention and control group during laparoscopic closure of the vaginal cuff.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All residents will be video recorded performing laparoscopic closure of the vaginal cuff at&#xD;
      the time of hysterectomy using video recording built into the laparoscopic equipment in the&#xD;
      operating rooms. Residents in the control group will receive standard surgical teaching&#xD;
      (MAM), then they will be video-recorded performing the skill at their second attempt.&#xD;
      Residents in the intervention group will receive the standard surgical teaching plus the&#xD;
      intervention of reviewing the recorded video with the surgical coach at the end of the&#xD;
      procedure (MAM plus VBC). The surgical coach will provide specific personalized feedback on&#xD;
      performance and suggestions for improvement following the Wisconsin Coaching Framework during&#xD;
      their coaching session. Participants will then be recorded on their subsequent attempt.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All raw video footage will be edited to include only the relevant portion of the film. This&#xD;
      will facilitate the assessment process (i.e., the assessors will view only the relevant&#xD;
      footage). The edited video segments for both groups on both attempts will be scored&#xD;
      independently using the validated surgical assessment tool by two blinded, experienced&#xD;
      gynecologic laparoscopists to evaluate surgical performance (blinded to attempt number and&#xD;
      randomization group). The average score between both assessors will be used for statistical&#xD;
      analysis. The effectiveness of VBC will be evaluated by comparing the difference in&#xD;
      assessment scores between the baseline and post-intervention scores between the control and&#xD;
      intervention groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 6, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants will be randomized to the intervention (video-based coaching plus standard surgical teaching following the master-apprentice model) or the control (standard surgical teaching following the master-apprentice model)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Due to the nature of the intervention, the participants and the surgical coach will not be blinded. The participants will be informed of their assignment after completing the first attempt. The staff surgeon in the operating room for each attempt will be blinded. The experienced laparoscopists who will be scoring the videos will be blinded to the group allocation and the attempt number.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean change from baseline in modified-OSATS (Objective Structured Assessment of Technical Skill) score after video-based coaching intervention compared to control of standard surgical teaching</measure>
    <time_frame>The first and second attempt will occur within a 1 month timeframe. The blinded assessors will complete the evaluation of the surgical videos for performance within 6 months of study completion.</time_frame>
    <description>The modified OSATS score is a standardized rubric for assessing technical skills</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Participant assessment of desirability of video-based surgical coaching</measure>
    <time_frame>Desirability will be calculated at the end of study enrolment within 1 year,</time_frame>
    <description>Desirability of the intervention will be evaluated based on the proportion of eligible residents who enrol in the study (number enrolled/number eligible).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Participant assessment of usefulness of video-based surgical coaching</measure>
    <time_frame>Questionnaire to be completed by participant within 1 month of second attempt.</time_frame>
    <description>Participants in the intervention arm will complete a surgical coachee questionnaire to determine if the participants in the intervention arm found the coaching experience to be useful for developing their surgical skills.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Surgical coach assessment of feasibility of video-based surgical coaching</measure>
    <time_frame>Questionnaire to be completed by surgical coach on day of coaching session and all questionnaires will be completed within 1 year.</time_frame>
    <description>Surgical coach will complete a questionnaire immediately after the coaching activity, which will collect time for video-editing, time for coaching session and receptivity of the participant to coaching</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Inter-rater reliability of the video evaluations by the blinded, experienced laparoscopists</measure>
    <time_frame>The blinded assessors will complete the evaluation of the surgical videos for performance within 6 months of study completion.</time_frame>
    <description>The intraclass correlation coefficient (ICC) between the two score for each video will be calculated</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Education</condition>
  <condition>Surgery</condition>
  <condition>Gynecologic Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Video-based coaching</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the intervention arm will receive the standard surgical teaching while in the operating room (master-apprentice model (MAM)), plus the intervention of reviewing the recorded video with the surgical coach after performing their first attempt at laparoscopic closure of the vaginal vault.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard surgical teaching</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the control arm will receive the standard surgical teaching while in the operating room (master-apprentice model-(MAM)).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Video-based coaching</intervention_name>
    <description>The coaching session will follow the Wisconsin Coaching Framework (Greenberg 2015). The surgical coaching session will last at maximum 30 minutes and will occur within 1-2 week following the procedure. The surgical coaching session will occur over Zoom. The second attempt will occur within 1 week following the coaching session.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Video-based coaching</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard surgical teaching (master-apprentice model - (MAM))</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard surgical teaching that conventionally occurs in the operating room follows a master-apprentice model (MAM).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard surgical teaching</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Video-based coaching</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Postgraduate year (PGY) 3 to 5 residents in the Obstetrics and Gynaecology program at&#xD;
             the University of Toronto&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Completing chief gynecology rotation at Mount Sinai Hospital (MSH) and Sunnybrook&#xD;
             Health Sciences Centre (SHSC), and gynecologic oncology rotation at University Health&#xD;
             Network (UHN) and SHSC form Sept 2021 until June 2022&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous participation in study on another rotation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Evan Tannenbaum, MD, MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>MOUNT SINAI HOSPITAL</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Brenna Swift</last_name>
    <phone>647-520-8468</phone>
    <email>brenna.swift@mail.utoronto.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M4N 3M5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Danielle Vicus, MD</last_name>
      <phone>(416) 480-4378</phone>
      <email>danielle.vicus@sunnybrook.ca</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mount Sinai Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5G 1Z5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Evan Tannenbaum, MD, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>416-586-4800</phone>
      <phone_ext>3758</phone_ext>
      <email>Evan.Tannenbaum@sinaihealth.ca</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Health Network</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5G 1Z5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Stephane Laframboise, MD</last_name>
      <phone>(416) 946-2254</phone>
      <email>stephane.laframboise@uhn.ca</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Mount Sinai Hospital, Canada</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Evan Tannenbaum</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor, Obstetrician/Gynecologist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Surgical education</keyword>
  <keyword>Coach</keyword>
  <keyword>Laparoscopy</keyword>
  <keyword>Gynecologic surgery</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

