<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05086588</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BTOPL-BBG-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05086588</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Evaluation of Two Different Brilliant Blue G Dyes as Staining Agent in Vitreo Retinal Surgery.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Open-label, Comparative Clinical Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of BIO-BLUE 90 PLUS With ILM-Blue® as Staining Agent in Vitreo Retinal Surgery.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dr. Lutfi Kirdar Kartal Training and Research Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dr. Lutfi Kirdar Kartal Training and Research Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, Open-label, comparative clinical study to asses two brilliant blue G&#xD;
      dyes as staining agent in Vitro Retinal Surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study was designed as prospective, open label, comparative observational study. The&#xD;
      patients over 18 years old and undergone Macular Surgery, Internal Limiting membrane removal&#xD;
      surgery or vitreomacular traction using the two brilliant blue G dyes as staining agent in&#xD;
      Vitro Retinal Surgery were planned to enroll the study. Two blue G dyes (Bio Blue 90 plus and&#xD;
      ILM Blue) was randomly assigned at the subject's initial intraoperative visit, according to a&#xD;
      computer-generated randomization schedule. During the pars plana vitrectomy, Bio Blue 90 Plus&#xD;
      or ILM Blue dyes were injected into eye to stain ILM. Injected Dye was removed from the eye&#xD;
      at the end of study before injecting long term tamponade. A total of 5 visits were conducted&#xD;
      during the study. Out of them pre-operative visit was done on 1 visit, Surgery/Intraoperative&#xD;
      visit and thereafter there were three follow-up visits. The follow- up visits were performed&#xD;
      at 1 month, 3 months and 6 Months after the completion of Surgery. Clinical evaluation will&#xD;
      be done recording and using staining Ability of ILM (Intra-Operatively), Visualization of&#xD;
      Stained Membrane (Intra-Operatively),OCT parameters: (Pre-Op &amp; Post-Op Follow-Up), FFA&#xD;
      parameters: (Pre-Op &amp; Post-Op Follow-Up),Fundus auto fluorescence (FAF), Multifocal ERG&#xD;
      (Pre-Op &amp; Post-Op Follow-Up) and Visual Field analyses (Pre-Op &amp; Post-Op Follow-Up).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 4, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 12, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 12, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Staining Ability of ILM</measure>
    <time_frame>Intra-Operatively</time_frame>
    <description>Staining of ILM is assed after dye injection with choosing Excellent/Good/ Needs to Improve by surgeon</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline to 1 Month, 3 Months and 6 Months in CMT (Central Macular Thickness)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-Op, 1 Month, 3 Month and 6 Month</time_frame>
    <description>CMT (Central Macular Thickness) in micron meters is accessed with ocular coherence tomography</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline to 1 Month, 3 Months and 6 Months in TMV ( Total Macular Volume)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-Op, 1 Month, 3 Month and 6 Month</time_frame>
    <description>TMV ( Total Macular Volume) in cubic millimeter is accessed with ocular coherence tomography</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline to 1 Month, 3 Months and 6 Months in SFCT (sub foveal choroidal thickness)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-Op, 1 Month, 3 Month and 6 Month</time_frame>
    <description>SFCT (sub foveal choroidal thickness) in cubic meter is accessed with ocular coherence tomography</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline to 1 Month, 3 Months and 6 Months in Intra-retinal cuff pathology segmentation</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-Op, 1 Month, 3 Month and 6 Month</time_frame>
    <description>Intra-retinal cuff pathology segmentation in micron meter is accessed with ocular coherence tomography</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline to 1 Month, 3 Months and 6 Months in RNFL Thickness (Retinal Nerve Fiber Layer)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-Op, 1 Month, 3 Month and 6 Month</time_frame>
    <description>RNFL Thickness (Retinal Nerve Fiber Layer) in micron meter is accessed with ocular coherence tomography</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline to 1 Month, 3 Months and 6 Months in Hole diameter</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-Op, 1 Month, 3 Month and 6 Month</time_frame>
    <description>Hole diameter in micron meter is accessed with ocular coherence tomography</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline to 1 Month, 3 Months and 6 Months in Optic Disc situation</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-Op, 1 Month, 3 Month and 6 Month</time_frame>
    <description>Optic Disc situation is accessed with ocular coherence tomography</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline to 6 Month in Foveal perfusion characteristics</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-Op, 6 Month</time_frame>
    <description>Foveal perfusion characteristics are assed with FFA(Fundus Fluorescein Angiography)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline to 6 Month in Vascular evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-Op, 6 Month</time_frame>
    <description>Vascular evaluation is assed with FFA(Fundus Fluorescein Angiography)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline to 6 Month in Fundus auto fluorescence (FAF)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-Op, 6 Month</time_frame>
    <description>Fundus auto fluorescence (FAF) are assed with FFA(Fundus Fluorescein Angiography)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Multifocal ERG</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-op, 1 Month, 3 Month and 6 Month</time_frame>
    <description>During multifocal ERG testing, the patient views a rapidly changing sequence on the monitor. The resulting electrical activity is recorded by an electrode, then amplified and analyzed. During stimulation the hexagons on the screen independently change every 13 milliseconds. They all follow the same pseudorandom sequence, with each hexagon starting at a slightly different position in this sequence. Using a cross-correlation technique, the software determines the retinal response from each of the 103 segments of the retina.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overview of Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 Months</time_frame>
    <description>An AE could be any unfavorable and unintended symptom, sign, disease or condition, or test abnormality whether or not considered related to the investigational product. A serious adverse event (SAE was an AE resulting in any of the following outcomes or deemed significant for any other reason: death; initial or prolonged hospitalization; life-threatening experience (immediate risk of dying); persistent or significant disability/incapacity; congenital anomaly. Treatment-emergent AEs (TEAE): AEs that developed/worsened during the 'on treatment period' (from first dose of study device until the end of study period). Category &quot;AE&quot; included participant with both serious and non-serious AE.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visualization of Stained Membrane</measure>
    <time_frame>Intra-Operatively</time_frame>
    <description>Visualization of Membrane is assed before and after dye injection with choosing poor/good options by surgeon</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Field Analyses</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-op, 1 Month, 3 Month and 6 Month</time_frame>
    <description>A test that measures the extent and distribution of the field of vision. A visual field test is done via automated perimetry.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Best Corrected Visual Acuity</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-op, 1 Month, 3 Month and 6 Month</time_frame>
    <description>Monocular visual acuity for each eye is be assessed using ETDRS charts held at 4 M.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">86</enrollment>
  <condition>Macular Holes</condition>
  <condition>Epiretinal Membrane</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Bio Blue 90 Plus</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients who were underwent Macular Surgery using Bio Blue 90 Plus (Brilliant Blue G Dye; 0.25 g /l concentration in 0.5 ml BD Glass Syringe; Biotech Vision Care Pvt. Ltd., Ahmedabad, India.)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ILM Blue</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients who were underwent Macular Surgery using ILM Blue (Brilliant Blue G Dye; 0.25 g /l concentration in 0.5 ml BD Glass Syringe; D.O.R.C. Dutch Ophthalmic Research Center (International) B.V., Zuidland, The Netherlands)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients who were underwent Macular Surgery using study devices were included in the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Over 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient undergone Macular Surgery, Epiretinal membrane removal surgery or&#xD;
             vitreomacular traction using the study device&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who can attend all the regular follow-up examinations as per the routine&#xD;
             schedule.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to adhere to the protocol requirements as evidenced by the informed&#xD;
             consent form (ICF) duly read signed and dated by the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Standard exclusion criteria for Macular Surgery like trauma history, previous macular&#xD;
             surgery, rhegmatogenous retinal detachment together with macular hole, myopia higher&#xD;
             than 10 diopter (D), macular hole for more than 2 years and previous retinal vessel&#xD;
             disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participated in any study during the use of the study device.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aysu Karatay Arsan, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>KARTAL DR. LÜTFİ KIRDAR ŞEHİR HASTANESİ</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kartal Dr. Lütfi Kirdar Şehir Hastanesi</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <zip>34865</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Dr. Lutfi Kirdar Kartal Training and Research Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Aysu Karatay Arsan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assoc. Prof. MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Brilliant Blue G Dye</keyword>
  <keyword>ILM Pealing</keyword>
  <keyword>Macular Hole</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Retinal Perforations</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Epiretinal Membrane</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

