<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05080361</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BRAFREC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05080361</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Rechallenge of BRAF +/- MEK Inhibitors Following an Adverse Event in Patients With Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>BRAFREC</acronym>
  <official_title>Rechallenge of Rapidly Accelerated Fibrosarcoma B-type (BRAF) +/- Mitogen-activated Extracellular Signal-regulated Kinase (MEK) Inhibitors Following an Adverse Event in Patients With Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Caen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Caen</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Very little data are published on the safety of a rechallenge with a BRAF inhibitor or&#xD;
      combination of BRAF and MEK inhibitor (BRAFi and MEKi) after an adverse event (AE). This&#xD;
      study aimed at identifying the recurrence rate of the same AE after a BRAFi +/- MEKi&#xD;
      rechallenge in patients with cancer and the factors associated to the recurrence.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an observational, cross-sectional, pharmacovigilance cohort study. AEs were extracted&#xD;
      from safety reports from the World Health Organization database VigiBase®, to evaluate the&#xD;
      safety of a rechallenge with a BRAF inhibitor or combination of BRAF and MEK inhibitor (BRAFi&#xD;
      and MEKi) after an adverse event (AE) in patients with cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrence rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to the date of the individual case safety report notification in VigiBase(r), assessed up to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome is the rate of recurrence of the same AE after a BRAFi+/- MEKi rechallenge among informative rechallenges The recurrence rate will be obtained by dividing the number of cases with an AE recurrence by the number of informative rechallenges and will be expressed as a percentage</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of rechallenge and non-rechallenge cases</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline characteristics (initial adverse event, cancer indication, age, sex) Measurements are the Medical Dictionary for Regulatory Activities preferred terms for adverse events and cancer indications, the Anatomical and Therapeutical Class for drugs. Age is categorized (18-45, 45-64, 65-74, &gt; 75y.o.), sex (male, female).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Factors associated with the recurrence after a rechallenge among informative rechallenges (i.e. variables associated with a higher recurrence rate, in a regression model)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Across baseline characteristics (initial adverse event, cancer indication, age, sex). Measurements are the Medical Dictionary for Regulatory Activities preferred terms for adverse events and cancer indications, the Anatomical and Therapeutical Class for drugs. Age is categorized (18-45, 45-64, 65-74, &gt; 75y.o.), sex (male, female).&#xD;
The recurrence is defined as a second occurrence of an initial adverse event after the treatment was reintroduced. It is a dichotomous outcome.&#xD;
Data will be analyzed through a regression model, so as to determinate which of these covariates are associated with a higher recurrence rate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of occurrence of a different AE after a monotherapy or combination therapy rechallenge (among informative rechallenges)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to the date of the individual case safety report notification in VigiBase(r), assessed up to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>The occurrence rate will be obtained by dividing the number of cases with another AE that occurred following a treatment rechallenge by the number of informative rechallenges and will be expressed as a percentage</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">16000</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Reports of adverse events associated with the use of BRAF +/- MEK inhibitors</arm_group_label>
    <description>Reports of adverse event (individual case safety reports) from Vigibase, the World Health Organization pharmacovigilance database related to the use of BRAF +/- MEK inhibitors from inception (1986) until March, 1, 2021 will be extracted.&#xD;
Cases concurrently reporting on immune checkpoint inhibitor therapies will be excluded.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BRAF inhibitor</intervention_name>
    <description>Reports of adverse events occurring in patients treated with at least one BRAFi or MEKi as reported in the individual case safety reports.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Reports of adverse events associated with the use of BRAF +/- MEK inhibitors</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MEK inhibitor</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study population is made of individual case safety reports from the World Health&#xD;
        Organization pharmacovigilance database VigiBase, where patients had an adverse event&#xD;
        following BRAF+/-MEKi therapy intakes.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All consecutive AE cases associated with BRAFi and MEKi therapy. Combination therapy&#xD;
             cases, where BRAFi were concurrently reported with MEKi will be identified, as well as&#xD;
             the combination therapy regimen (V+C, D+T, E+B). We will not study MEKi monotherapy&#xD;
             cases&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  MEKi monotherapy cases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases concurrently reporting on immune checkpoint inhibitor therapies&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Charles Dolladille</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Caen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data for this study are available at http://www.vigiacess.org/. Dissemination to study participants / researchers is not possible outside of the dedicated website.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

