<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05086679</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1400-2-101-54781</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05086679</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Compression Stockings for Treating Vasovagal Syncope (COMFORTS II) Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>COMFORTS II</acronym>
  <official_title>Compression Stockings for Treating Vasovagal Syncope (COMFORTS II) Trial; a Double Blind, Multi-center Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tehran Heart Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Tehran Arrhythmia Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Rajaie Cardiovascular Medical and Research Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Imam Khomeini Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Isfahan University of Medical Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Guilan University of Medical Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tehran Heart Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Syncope, a sudden, transient loss of consciousness (TLOC), is a common inconvenience of daily&#xD;
      function and quality of life (QoL). The vasovagal syncope (VVS) is the most common type of&#xD;
      syncope, which central and peripheral stimuli may trigger syncope by decreasing peripheral&#xD;
      vascular resistance, bradycardia, or both. The venous return to the heart is one of these&#xD;
      triggers which its reduction may occur due to prolonged standing, hot environment,&#xD;
      hypovolemia, or redistribution of blood volume. The compression stockings may reduce syncopal&#xD;
      episodes by increasing venous return. Although the use of compression stockings was never&#xD;
      assessed in clinical trials, it could be a possible treatment for decreasing VVS recurrences.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The COMFORTS II study is designed as a multicenter, longitudinal, double blind, parallel&#xD;
      design RCT to assess the beneficial effect of compression stockings for preventing&#xD;
      recurrences of VVS. The participants will be treated by the standard treatment of VVS, and&#xD;
      then they will be randomized into two groups (1:1 ratio) to use compression stockings, one&#xD;
      group with 25-30 mm Hg pressure and the other one with up to 10 mmHg pressure, Randomization&#xD;
      and allocation concealment will be done by the primary investigators (www.comfortstrial.com).&#xD;
      To balance participant enrolment, participating centers will stratify the randomization&#xD;
      block. The enrolling physicians will be blinded to the randomization to minimize the&#xD;
      selection bias. Hence, the randomization code will not be revealed till the patient has been&#xD;
      enrolled, and the baseline features and consent form have been uploaded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The syncope Unit of Tehran Heart Center (SUTHC), Tehran University of Medical Sciences is the&#xD;
      primary investigation site (same as COMFORTS I trial). Seven study centers across Iran&#xD;
      declared their commitment to participate in this study (see trial organization). After&#xD;
      randomization, participants will be allocated their treatment as one group will have&#xD;
      compression stockings with 25-30 mm Hg pressure and in the control group pressure will be&#xD;
      limited up to 10 mmHg. Participants will be asked to use compression stockings as long as&#xD;
      they could (ideal would be the majority of the time they are upright). Adherence of patients&#xD;
      to the use of compression stockings will be daily with predefined forms given to patients&#xD;
      after randomization. In addition, a CD included some videos and booklets about instructions&#xD;
      on how to wear CS and how to keep them will be provided for the participants with their&#xD;
      compression stockings. All patients will receive standard treatment of VVS despite their&#xD;
      randomization. According to syncope guidelines, patients will learn to drink 2-3 liters of&#xD;
      fluids, consume 10 grams 120 mmol/day of sodium chloride, and practice counter-pressure&#xD;
      maneuvers (squatting, leg crossing, handgrip, and arm-tensing&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 10, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 10, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of participants with no recurrence</measure>
    <time_frame>The follow-up continues for 12 months after randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of participants with no recurrence to all participants in their arm of treatment during the follow-up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The time to the first recurrence of syncope</measure>
    <time_frame>The follow-up continues for 12 months after randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Time from randomization to occurrence of the first episode of vasovagal syncope during the follow-up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The frequency of spells in the follow-up period</measure>
    <time_frame>The follow-up continues for 12 months after randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The frequency of spells in the follow-up period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The time between first and second recurrence of syncope</measure>
    <time_frame>The follow-up continues for 12 months after randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The time between first and second recurrence of syncope</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">244</enrollment>
  <condition>Syncope, Vasovagal</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Compression stockings with 25-30 mm Hg pressure</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Compression stockings with 25-30 mm Hg pressure, as long as they could (ideal would be the majority of the time they are upright)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Compression stockings with up to 10 mm Hg pressure</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Compression stockings with up to 10 mm Hg pressure, as long as they could (ideal would be the majority of the time they are upright)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Compression Stockings with 25-30 mm Hg pressure</intervention_name>
    <description>The group will have compression stockings with 25-30 mm Hg pressure. All the participants' size for compression stocking will be measured at the first visit. Three points will be measured: below and above their knees and above their ankle. Subsequently, Right Arian Farmed Co (Tehran, Iran) will provide compression stockings for patients based on their sizes. Participants will be asked to use compression stockings as long as they could (ideal would be the majority of the time they are upright). In addition, a CD included some videos and booklets about instructions on how to wear CS and how to keep them will be provided for the participants with their compression stockings.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Compression stockings with 25-30 mm Hg pressure</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Compression stockings with up to 10 mm Hg pressure</intervention_name>
    <description>The group will have compression stockings with up to 10 mm Hg pressure. All the participants' size for compression stocking will be measured at the first visit. Three points will be measured: below and above their knees and above their ankle. Subsequently, Right Arian Farmed Co (Tehran, Iran) will provide compression stockings for patients based on their sizes. Participants will be asked to use compression stockings as long as they could (ideal would be the majority of the time they are upright). In addition, a CD included some videos and booklets about instructions on how to wear CS and how to keep them will be provided for the participants with their compression stockings.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Compression stockings with up to 10 mm Hg pressure</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lifestyle modification</intervention_name>
    <description>All patients will receive standard treatment of VVS despite their randomization(drink 2-3 liters of fluids, consume 10 grams 120 mmol/day of sodium chloride, and practice counter-pressure maneuvers (squatting, leg crossing, handgrip, and arm-tensing))</description>
    <arm_group_label>Compression stockings with 25-30 mm Hg pressure</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Compression stockings with up to 10 mm Hg pressure</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female patients with 18≤age≤65&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  VVS as the cause of TLOC&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥2 episodes of VVS during the last year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The capability of giving informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other causes of TLOC including orthostatic hypotension, postural tachycardia, carotid&#xD;
             sinus hypersensitivity, or seizure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiac rhythm disorders including ventricular tachycardia, long QT syndrome, Brugada&#xD;
             syndrome, ARVC, CHB, and any conduction abnormality on ECG&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe valvular heart disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiac systolic dysfunction (ejection fraction≤40%)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Obstructive coronary artery disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal failure stage≥3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other non-cardiovascular chronic illnesses&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Urinary retention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pheochromocytoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thyrotoxicosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Glaucoma&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hamed Tavolinejad, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Tehran Heart Center, Tehran University of Medical Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Amirhossein Poopak, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Tehran Heart Center, Tehran University of Medical Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Masih Tajdini, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+982188029640</phone>
    <email>mtajdini@sina.tums.ac.ir</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <link>
    <url>http://comfortstrial.com/</url>
    <description>Description The COMFORTS Trial website</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sadeghian S, Aminorroaya A, Tajdini M. The Syncope Unit of Tehran Heart Center. Eur Heart J. 2021 Jan 7;42(2):148-150. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa532.</citation>
    <PMID>33346809</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Aminorroaya A, Tavolinejad H, Sadeghian S, Jalali A, Alaeddini F, Emkanjoo Z, Mollazadeh R, Bozorgi A, Oraii S, Kiarsi M, Shahabi J, Akbarzadeh MA, Rahimi B, Joharimoghadam A, Mohsenizade A, Mohammadi R, Oraii A, Ariannejad H, Apakuppakul S, Ngarmukos T, Tajdini M. Comparison of Outcomes with Midodrine and Fludrocortisone for Objective Recurrence in Treating Syncope (COMFORTS trial): Rationale and design for a multi-center randomized controlled trial. Am Heart J. 2021 Jul;237:5-12. doi: 10.1016/j.ahj.2021.03.002. Epub 2021 Mar 6.</citation>
    <PMID>33689731</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Tehran Heart Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Masih Tajdini, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Cardiology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Syncope, Vasovagal</keyword>
  <keyword>Syncope</keyword>
  <keyword>Compression stocking</keyword>
  <keyword>Randomized Clinical Trial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Syncope</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syncope, Vasovagal</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data is not publicly available due to privacy/ethical restrictions. The data can be shared upon reasonable request to the trial committee.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

