<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04756362</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>001/20</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04756362</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>IN-HOspital Program to systematizE Chest Pain Protocol (IN-HOPE)</brief_title>
  <acronym>In-Hope</acronym>
  <official_title>Potential Impact in Clinical Practice of Early Exclusion Protocols for Acute Myocardial Infarction With High Sensitivity Troponin T in Different Scenarios (IN-HOspital Program to SystematizE Chest Pain Protocol-IN HOPE)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital Samaritano Paulista</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Roche Diagnostics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital Samaritano Paulista</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Multicenter Nationwide Study for Analysis of the Potential Impact in Clinical Practice of&#xD;
      Early Exclusion Protocols for Acute Myocardial Infarction with High Sensitivity Troponin T&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Chest pain is the main clinical complaint in emergency room visits and represents the most&#xD;
      common symptom of Acute Myocardial Infarction, which is the main cause of death in Brazil and&#xD;
      worldwide. Although most patients with chest pain do not have a final diagnosis of AMI, they&#xD;
      remain under observation until the diagnosis of AMI is excluded. The most current strategy&#xD;
      recommended for rapid AMI exclusion uses high-sensitivity cardiac troponin T at time zero and&#xD;
      one hour later. However, some points that have not yet been properly evaluated in previous&#xD;
      studies can be evaluated in the current study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Evaluation of the early exclusion protocol (0 -1 hour) in a Brazilian population&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Evaluation of the early exclusion protocol (0 -1 hour) in isolation and associated with&#xD;
           traditional risk scores (TIMI, GRACE, HEART and EDACS)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Systematic evaluation of the early exclusion protocol (0 -1 hour) in patients without&#xD;
           chest pain but with a pre-defined condition of suspected AMI.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 23, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of early rule out for myocardial infarction diagnosis</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Accuracy of the 0 and 1 hour algorithm using troponin for diagnosis of myocardial infarction compared to the gold standard with measurements every 3 hours</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of early rule out for myocardial infarction according to type of symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Accuracy of the 0 and 1 hour algorithm using troponin for diagnosis of myocardial infarction compared to the gold standard with measurements every 3 hours with or without chest pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of early rule out for myocardial infarction according to chest pain score (TIMI)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Accuracy of the 0 and 1 hour algorithm using troponin for diagnosis of myocardial infarction compared to the gold standard with measurements every 3 hours according to chest pain score (TIMI). TIMI score minimum 0 and maximum 7 points (higher scores mean a worse outcome).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of early rule out for myocardial infarction according to chest pain score (EDACS)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Accuracy of the 0 and 1 hour algorithm using troponin for diagnosis of myocardial infarction compared to the gold standard with measurements every 3 hours according to chest pain score (EDACS). EDACS score minimum -6 and maximum +20 points (higher scores mean a worse outcome).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of early rule out for myocardial infarction according to chest pain score (GRACE)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Accuracy of the 0 and 1 hour algorithm using troponin for diagnosis of myocardial infarction compared to the gold standard with measurements every 3 hours according to chest pain score (GRACE). GRACE score minimum 1 and maximum 372 points (higher scores mean a worse outcome).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of early rule out for myocardial infarction according to chest pain score (HEART)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Accuracy of the 0 and 1 hour algorithm using troponin for diagnosis of myocardial infarction compared to the gold standard with measurements every 3 hours according to chest pain score (HEART). HEART score minimum 0 and maximum 10 points (higher scores mean a worse outcome).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1300</enrollment>
  <condition>Chest Pain</condition>
  <condition>Acute Coronary Syndrome</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Consecutive patients with suspected acute coronary syndrome&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient agrees and signs an informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  One of the following 2 criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Acute chest pain (last episode of pain beginning &lt;6 hours after inclusion) or&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Syncope, dyspnea or epigastric pain without an obvious cause at the initial&#xD;
                  assessment (last episode of one of these symptoms beginning &lt;6 hours after&#xD;
                  inclusion) associated with at least one of the following factors: Age ≥ 65 years,&#xD;
                  history of arterial disease, history of diabetes mellitus.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiac arrest or hypoxemia or hemodynamic instability or cardioversion during the&#xD;
             first hour of assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thrombolytic therapy, primary angioplasty or other medical condition that requires&#xD;
             hospitalization identified within one hour after the evaluation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dialysis patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with trauma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Myocardial revascularization or acute myocardial infarction in the last month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant and breastfeeding women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient unable to be followed for 30 days&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Pedro E de Barros e Silva, MD, MHS, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>551121772533</phone>
    <email>pedro.barros@bcri.org.br</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Samaritano Paulista</name>
      <address>
        <city>São Paulo</city>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pedro de Barros e Silva, MD, MHS, PHD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hospital Samaritano Paulista</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Pedro Gabriel Melo de Barros e Silva</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Chest pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Acute coronary syndrome</keyword>
  <keyword>Troponin</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Chest Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

