<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04756336</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>C20-109-07</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04756336</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>LTX-109 as Treatment for Hidradenitis Suppurativa</brief_title>
  <official_title>Proof of Concept Study on LTX-109 as Treatment for Hidradenitis Suppurativa</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pharma Holdings AS</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital of North Norway</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pharma Holdings AS</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      An Open label Phase II//proof of concept-study to demonstrate if percutaneous application of&#xD;
      LTX-109 in a gel vehicle is a safe treatment of Hidradenitis suppurativa and to identify&#xD;
      clinical response to intervention, as well to identify if covariates such as age, disease&#xD;
      duration, smoking state and BMI influence patient reported measures.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      It is unclear whether bacterial colonization in hidradenitis suppurativa/acne inversa (HS)&#xD;
      comprises a primary cause, triggering factor or secondary phenomenon of the disease&#xD;
      pathogenesis. Studies imply that aberrant immune responses play a role involving both the&#xD;
      innate and adaptive immune system, however the clinical picture of HS lesions appears&#xD;
      reminiscent of bacterial infection, e.g. due to intense inflammation and malodorous&#xD;
      discharge. Recent microbiological studies indicate certain bacterial species are associated&#xD;
      with mature HS lesions. It is demonstrated a significant high occurrence of large bacterial&#xD;
      biofilms (aggregates &gt; 50 μm in diameter) in tunnels. In total, an array of studies point to&#xD;
      a potential involvement of a specific microbiota in the pathogenesis of HS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The antimicrobial effect of LTX-109 can reduce or eradicate bacterial growth and thus also&#xD;
      the inflammatory stimulus of hidradenitis. The antiinflammatory effects of LTX-109 through&#xD;
      inhibition of bacterial colonization or infection can prevent rupture and proliferation of&#xD;
      follicular material in the dermis. Hidradenitis in more advanced stages can be targeted with&#xD;
      this investigational drug. However, it is not reasonable to expect that chronic, longstanding&#xD;
      inflammation and sinus formation will heal in six week of intervention. Therefore, patients&#xD;
      with most severe activity (Hurley stadium III) or with widespread disease (&gt;5 palm units)&#xD;
      will not be included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator wishes to document whether LTX-109 is an effective compound on hidradenitis.&#xD;
      Evidence-based medical treatment of mild disease consists of topical antibiotics&#xD;
      (Clindamycin). Systemic antibiotics (Tetracycline) is used for disease that is more&#xD;
      widespread. In other parts of Europe, but not recommended in Norway due to the fear of&#xD;
      over-usage of Rifampicin, patients who fail to exhibit response to treatment or have a&#xD;
      moderate-to-severe disease, systemic Clindamycin 300 in combination with Rifampicin can be&#xD;
      given.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients failing to exhibit response to treatment options mentioned above or for&#xD;
      moderate-to-severe disease, biologic therapy (Adalimumab) can be administered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interestingly, Bacterial growth in HS patients has shown a high level of resistance to&#xD;
      antibiotics, including rifampicin, clindamycin and tetracyclines, cited as an empiric choice&#xD;
      in HS therapeutic guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, other treatment options targeting bacteria in HS is warranted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It would be important to demonstrate whether the lytic peptidomimetic LTX-109 may be&#xD;
      effective in the condition as the treatment has apparent benefits, such as a good safety&#xD;
      profile, easy self-administered application and no known risk of development of resistance to&#xD;
      the Investigational Medicinal Product.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be open label on 16 patients. Treatment will be twice daily application on&#xD;
      affected lesions for 6 weeks. Followup after end of treatment will be 3 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 5, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Consecutive case series</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Investigator assessed signs for local reactions to the Investigational Medicinal Product</measure>
    <time_frame>End point analysis at 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Investigator assessment of signs of local reactions</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient reported symptoms for local reactions to the Investigational Medicinal Product</measure>
    <time_frame>End point analysis at 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported symptoms for local reactions</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Investigator assessment of condition from Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>End point analysis after 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Investigator assessed change in condition assessed by Hidradenitis suppurativa score (Sartorius) from Baseline to week 6</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Investigator assessment disease activity from Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>End point analysis after 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Investigator assessed change in disease activity assessed by Hurley's stage division from Baseline to week 6</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Investigator assessed number of lesions from Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>End point analysis after 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Investigator assessed change in number of inflammatory lesions from Baseline to week 6 assessed by International Hidradenitis Suppurativa Severity Score System</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Patient recorded Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI) from Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Endpoint analysis at week 6</time_frame>
    <description>Change in patient recorded Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI) from Baseline to week 6</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Patient recorded Visual Analog Score for pain (VAS) from Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Endpoint analysis at week 6</time_frame>
    <description>Change in patient recorded Visual Analog Score for pain (VAS) from Baseline to week 6</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">11</enrollment>
  <condition>Hidradenitis Suppurativa</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LTX-109 treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients are treated with LTX-109 gel, 3% w/w twice daily (morning- evening) by application on active hidradenitis lesions during the intervention period of 6 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>LTX-109 gel, 3% w/w</intervention_name>
    <description>The drug is applied to affected lesions according to treatment regimen</description>
    <arm_group_label>LTX-109 treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with active hidradenitis in the stage I-II according to Hurley's&#xD;
             classification.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients are referred to a dermatology out-patient clinic or patients already in an&#xD;
             established treatment program, where there is indication for new or different&#xD;
             treatment, or surgical intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients must have typical affection of the disease of either axillae, groins, and/or&#xD;
             perigenital/perianal area&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Signed informed consent and expected cooperation of the patients for the treatment and&#xD;
             follow up must be obtained and documented according to international guidelines, and&#xD;
             national/local regulations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. For women in fertile age: Concents to use highly effective contraception until the end&#xD;
             of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients in need of emergency medical or surgical treatment of hidradenitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects must not have used the following HS treatments within the specified timeframe&#xD;
             prior to Baseline Visit:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Systemic therapy for HS, including but not limited to corticosteroids,&#xD;
                  antibiotics, dapsone or retinoids within 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Targeted biologic treatments (refer to within 5 half-lives [if known]) or within&#xD;
                  12 weeks, whichever is longer.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Topical treatments with antibiotics, including but not limited to clindamycin&#xD;
                  within 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with hidradenitis affecting larger areas (&gt;5 palm units)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient does not agree to be registered in the national quality register for HS&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Pregnant or lactating women&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any reason why, in the opinion of the investigator, the patient should not participate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Øystein Grimstad, Phd., MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital of North Norway</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of North Norway</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tromsø</city>
        <zip>9038</zip>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Norway</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 21, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hidradenitis Suppurativa</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hidradenitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

