<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04750941</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AAAS4953</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04750941</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Copanlisib and Ketogenic Diet</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pilot Phase II Study of the PI3K Inhibitor Copanlisib in Combination With a Ketogenic Diet in the Treatment of Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Follicular Lymphoma or Endometrial Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Columbia University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bayer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Columbia University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter, open label, pilot phase II study of the PI3K inhibitor copanlisib in&#xD;
      combination with a ketogenic diet in the treatment of patients with one of the following&#xD;
      malignancies: (a) relapsed or refractory (R/R) follicular lymphoma (FL), (b) R/R endometrial&#xD;
      cancer (EC) with a documented activating mutation in PIK3CA or loss of phosphatase and tensin&#xD;
      homolog (PTEN).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      As the investigators recently reported ketogenic diet can suppress hyperinsulinemia&#xD;
      associated with PI3K inhibitors, leading to potentiation of the anti-tumor effects of PI3K&#xD;
      inhibitors. Copanlisib potently inhibits PI3Kα and PI3Kδ. It has been approved for the&#xD;
      treatment of relapsed follicular lymphoma, based on ORR of 59% (84 of 142 patients). The CR&#xD;
      rate in FL was 14%, and the median progression-free survival was 11.2 months. Copanlisib&#xD;
      demonstrated encouraging clinical activity in marginal zone lymphoma (ORR 70% including 9%&#xD;
      CR). While these results are clinically meaningful, FL and MZL inevitably develop resistance&#xD;
      to copanlisib with time, even in those patients who initially respond to the therapy. Novel&#xD;
      strategies to improve the efficacy of copanlisib in FL and MZL, by improving CR and PFS, may&#xD;
      transform how to manage these incurable malignancies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 58 weeks or 4 weeks after the last dose</time_frame>
    <description>ORR will be determined from the number of individuals with a complete response (CR) and number of individuals with a partial response (PR)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete Response (CR) Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 58 weeks or 4 weeks after the last dose</time_frame>
    <description>Total number of participants with a CR.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Partial Response (PR) Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 58 weeks or 4 weeks after the last dose</time_frame>
    <description>Total number of participants with a PR.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ORR at the Simon stage I analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 58 weeks or 4 weeks after the last dose</time_frame>
    <description>ORR will be determined from the number of individuals with a complete response (CR) and number of individuals with a partial response (PR).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient compliance with the ketogenic diet</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 58 weeks or 4 weeks after the last dose</time_frame>
    <description>Total # of patients who are compliant with the ketogenic diet.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">42</enrollment>
  <condition>Follicular Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Endometrial Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Follicular Lymphoma (FL)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The lymphoma study group will enroll 23 patients with FL.&#xD;
In cycle 1, patients will first start ketogenic diet for 7 days (Day -6 to Day 0). Only patients who demonstrate compliance and tolerance with the ketogenic diet for all 7 days, as confirmed by pertinent blood and urine tests, will be allowed to continue the study and treatment using copanlisib and the ketogenic diet starting on Day 1. In cycle 2 and beyond, patients will start the ketogenic diet and copanlisib on day 1.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Endometrial Cancer (EC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The solid tumor group will enroll 19 patients with EC.&#xD;
In cycle 1, patients will first start ketogenic diet for 7 days (Day -6 to Day 0). Only patients who demonstrate compliance and tolerance with the ketogenic diet for all 7 days, as confirmed by pertinent blood and urine tests, will be allowed to continue the study and treatment using copanlisib and the ketogenic diet starting on Day 1. In cycle 2 and beyond, patients will start the ketogenic diet and copanlisib on day 1.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Copanlisib</intervention_name>
    <description>Copanlisib will be infused intravenously on days 1, 8, 15 of each cycle, over 1 hour, of 28-day cycles.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Endometrial Cancer (EC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Follicular Lymphoma (FL)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ketogenic Diet</intervention_name>
    <description>In cycle 1, patients will first start the ketogenic diet for 7 days (Day -6 to Day 0).&#xD;
Only the patients who demonstrate compliance and tolerance with the ketogenic diet, as confirmed by pertinent blood and urine tests and a diary of diet, will be allowed to continue the study and start copanlisib on Day 1. The ketogenic diet will continue daily throughout the treatment days.&#xD;
In cycle 2 and beyond, patients will start the ketogenic diet and copanlisib on day 1.&#xD;
The ketogenic diet will then continue daily throughout the treatment days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Endometrial Cancer (EC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Follicular Lymphoma (FL)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be willing and able to provide written informed consent for the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be 18 years of age or older on day of signing informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For lymphoma, patients should have measurable disease based on the Lugano Criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For FL patients must have received at least two lines of prior therapy. There is no&#xD;
             upper limit for the number of prior therapies. Tumor tissues of all patients are&#xD;
             encouraged to be submitted (optional) prospectively for whole or targeted exome&#xD;
             sequencing of key cancer related genes, using the Columbia Combined Cancer Panel&#xD;
             (CCCP) or a comparable sequencing platform, such as the MSK-IMPACT 468-gene oncopanel.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For EC the patients must have recurrent/advanced tumor for which surgical or the&#xD;
             systemic curative treatments, or standard therapeutic approaches are not available.&#xD;
             The following histologic subtypes are eligible: endometrioid, serous, clear cell,&#xD;
             undifferentiated /dedifferentiated, mucinous, squamous, transitional, not-otherwise&#xD;
             specified, and mixed celltype.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fresh and or archived tumor tissues must be available to (a) establish the diagnosis&#xD;
             of the respective malignancies as described in Inclusion Criteria, and (b) be&#xD;
             investigated for biomarkers. Patients without historical material or fresh tissue&#xD;
             biopsy that is adequate for both diagnosis and correlative studies will not be&#xD;
             eligible for the clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left Ventricular Ejection Fraction (LVEF) &gt; 50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A performance status of 0-2 on the Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG)&#xD;
             Performance Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Demonstrate adequate organ function. All screening labs should be performed within 14&#xD;
             days of treatment initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV positive patients will be eligible as long as the viral load by polymerase chain&#xD;
             reaction (PCR) testing is undetectable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test within 7&#xD;
             days prior to treatment start.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The following treatments are prohibited: (a) Chemotherapy (including PI3K inhibitors&#xD;
             and other approved or investigational drugs) and monoclonal antibody within 3 weeks;&#xD;
             (b) radiotherapy within 2 weeks prior to entering the study; (c) systemic steroids&#xD;
             that have not been stabilized (≥ 5 days) to the equivalent of ≤10 mg/day prednisone&#xD;
             prior to the start of the study drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that have not recovered from adverse events due to chemotherapy agents&#xD;
             administered more than 3 weeks earlier.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypersensitivity to copanlisib or any of its excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Type I diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled Type II diabetes mellitus (HbA1c&gt; 7.5%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Type II diabetes requiring treatment with a sulfonylurea, meglitinide, or insulin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that received major surgery and have not recovered adequately from the&#xD;
             toxicity and/or complications from the intervention prior to starting therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active, clinically serious infections &gt; CTCAE version 5 Grade 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known active concurrent malignancy with the following exception:&#xD;
             nonmelanoma skin cancer, prostatic intraepithelial neoplasia, or carcinoma in situ of&#xD;
             the cervix, prostate cancer that responds to androgen deprivation therapy and has no&#xD;
             progression of disease for at least 12 months. If there is a history of prior&#xD;
             malignancy, the patient must be disease-free for ≥ 3 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled hypertension, i.e., blood pressure (BP) of ≥ 150/90; patients who have a&#xD;
             history of hypertension controlled by medication must be on a stable dose (for at&#xD;
             least one month) and meet all other inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant use of strong CYP3A4 inhibitors (defined in the protocol).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled moderate to severe hypertriglyceridemia (TG&gt;300 mg/dL).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Myocardial infarction within 6 months of cycle 1, day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptomatic coronary artery disease (CAD), e.g., angina Canadian Class II-IV (see&#xD;
             Appendix 5).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An ECG recorded at screening showing evidence of cardiac ischemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Congestive heart failure (CHF) that meets New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class II&#xD;
             to IV definitions and/or ejection fraction &lt; 40% by multigated acquisition (MUGA) scan&#xD;
             or &lt; 50% by echocardiogram and/or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arterial or venous thrombotic or embolic events such as cerebrovascular accident&#xD;
             (including transient ischemic attacks) within 6 months before the start of study&#xD;
             medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding, or expecting to conceive or father&#xD;
             children within the projected duration of the trial, starting with the pre-screening&#xD;
             or screening visit through at least 30 days after the last dose of trial treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of nephrolithiasis or nephrolithiasis incidentally discovered during CT&#xD;
             screening. *Known selenium deficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI) less than 20.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An allergy or intolerance to egg, gluten or milk protein.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of serious or uncontrolled gout or hyperuricemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, lactation, or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other disease, metabolic dysfunction, physical examination finding, or clinical&#xD;
             laboratory finding that, in the investigators' opinion, gives reasonable suspicion of&#xD;
             a disease or condition that contraindicates the use of an investigational drug or that&#xD;
             may affect the interpretation of the results or render the patient at high risk from&#xD;
             treatment complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgical procedure or significant traumatic injury within 28 days prior to Day 1&#xD;
             or anticipation of the need for major surgery during the course of study treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jennifer E. Amengual, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Columbia University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jennifer E. Amengual, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(212) 326 - 5720</phone>
    <email>jea2149@cumc.columbia.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University Irving Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jennifer E. Amengual, MD</last_name>
      <phone>212-326-5720</phone>
      <email>jea2149@cumc.columbia.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jennifer E. Amengual, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Weill Cornell Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Peter Martin, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Peter Martin, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10604</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Vicky Makker, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Vicky Makker, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Columbia University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jennifer Amengual</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Herbert Irving Assistant Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Keto diet</keyword>
  <keyword>Copanlisib</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Follicular</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

