<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04751058</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HU Virgen Rocio</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04751058</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Genetic Profile in Patients With Aortic Syndrome</brief_title>
  <acronym>GEN-AOR</acronym>
  <official_title>Genetic Profile in Patients With Aortic Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospitales Universitarios Virgen del Rocío</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospitales Universitarios Virgen del Rocío</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The overall prevalence has increased significantly in the general population, which may be&#xD;
      due in part to advances in diagnostic techniques, such as improved imaging techniques. Aortic&#xD;
      dissection (AD) can cause sudden cardiac death (SCD). Approximately 95% of thoracic AAS are&#xD;
      clinically &quot;silent&quot; until a life-threatening complication arises in an unpredictable manner&#xD;
      and presents as sudden cardiac death. The peak incidence of death caused by aortic dissection&#xD;
      occurs within 48 hours, therefore, timely diagnosis is essential and saves lives.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We have traditionally associated as risk factors in patients with ASA long-term arterial&#xD;
      hypertension, present in 66-75% of cases, smoking, dyslipidemia or atherosclerotic disease.&#xD;
      Likewise, any condition that alters the structure of the aorta such as: collagen diseases,&#xD;
      aneurysms, bicuspid aorta, and manipulation of the thoracic aorta (cardiac surgery, 18%, or&#xD;
      percutaneous intervention that can injure the intima) is involved in ASA. In addition to the&#xD;
      well-known hereditary syndromes that affect collagen (Marfan, Elher-Danlos ...) there is a&#xD;
      clear familial aggregation: 13-19% of patients without identifiable syndrome have&#xD;
      first-degree relatives with thoracic aortic aneurysms or ICD, something that has been called&#xD;
      &quot;thoracic aortic dissection and familial aneurysm syndrome.&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
      Notable achievements have been made in the discovery of genetic mutations associated with SAA&#xD;
      and key regulatory molecules involved, including the extracellular matrix (ECM), cytoskeletal&#xD;
      proteins, and the TGF-β signaling pathway. Identification of the causative gene is&#xD;
      advantageous for both patients and their families, especially those who do not show symptoms.&#xD;
      The specific underlying genotype could benefit the process of diagnosis, surveillance and&#xD;
      surgery, with the aim of reducing morbidity and mortality&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      HYPOTHESIS.:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A proportion of patients admitted to the Hospital with a diagnosis of Aortic Syndrome without&#xD;
      phenotypic characteristics are carriers of mutations. The presence of these mutations can&#xD;
      condition both the indication for treatment, post-surgical aortic remodeling, and family&#xD;
      traceability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OBJECTIVE.:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this study is to analyze the prevalence of mutations in non-phenotypic&#xD;
      patients admitted urgently due to Aortic Syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material and method:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients admitted to the Intensive Care Unit of the Virgen del Rocio University Hospital in&#xD;
      Seville (third level Hospital) with the diagnosis of Aortic Syndrome will be included. The&#xD;
      clinical and angiographic variables were analyzed. All patients will undergo, with prior&#xD;
      informed consent, a peripheral blood extraction, from which a DNA sample will be obtained&#xD;
      using the ChemagicTM 360 equipment. This DNA will be processed for massive sequencing on&#xD;
      Illumina's NextSeq500 platform using the technology Capture SeqCap EZ Choice Library&#xD;
      NimbleGen. The data generated will be analyzed bioinformatically and the identified variants&#xD;
      prioritized based on their population frequency (&lt;0.01), location (exonic and close to&#xD;
      splicing sites), their presence in databases of clinical significance ClinVar, HGMD and LOVD&#xD;
      and the phenotypic association of the mutated gene OMIM and Orphanet.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>% of patients with presence of Missense mutations</measure>
    <time_frame>post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>massive sequencing</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>% of patients with presence of splicing mutations</measure>
    <time_frame>post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>massive sequencing</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>% of patients with presence of frameshift mutations</measure>
    <time_frame>post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>massive sequencing</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>% of patients with presence of nonframeshift mutations</measure>
    <time_frame>post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>massive sequencing</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">73</enrollment>
  <condition>Gene Abnormality</condition>
  <condition>Acute Aortic Syndrome</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Genetic</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>genetic analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Intervention details: sampling in peripheral blood for the Methodology:&#xD;
Automatic DNA extraction (ChemagicTM 360)&#xD;
Mass sequencing using SeqCap EZ Choice Library capture technology (NimbleGen) and NextSeq sequencer (Illumina).&#xD;
Bioinformatic analysis:.&#xD;
Identification of point mutations and small deletions or insertions&#xD;
Analysis of CNVs using the BEDtools program package&#xD;
Search of the identified variants in the following public databases: 1000G, dbSNP, ExAC, EVS, GenomADm CSVS and DGV. Those with a MAF&gt; 1% have been considered benign, in public or private databases of our population.&#xD;
The analysis process has focused exclusively on the genes described to date as associated with the pathology under study and included in the panel used. The reference sequences used for these genes are: determination of possible mutations, nucleotics, etc.</description>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      peripheral blood samples&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study includes all patients who are admitted with the diagnosis of Acute Aortic&#xD;
        Syndrome verified by imaging techniques (CT Angiography) in the Intensive Care Unit of a&#xD;
        tertiary Hospital with a 24-hour Cardiac and Vascular Surgery Service&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient older than 16 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients admitted alive with a diagnosis of acute aortic syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written consent to be DNA analysis and conservation in the DNA bank&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refusal to participate in the study and , or analysis of their DNA.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Without life expectancy and , or Income without life.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Antonio M Puppo Moreno, MD;PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Andaluz Health Service</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Antonio M Puppo Moreno, 1980</last_name>
    <phone>+34669410840</phone>
    <email>apuppo@telefonica.net</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Alejandro Adsuar Gomez, 2002</last_name>
    <phone>+34669410840</phone>
    <email>apuppo@telefonica.net</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Virgen del Rocio</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sevilla</city>
        <state>Andalucia</state>
        <zip>41012</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Antonio M Puppo Moreno, 1980</last_name>
      <phone>+34669410840</phone>
      <phone_ext>M</phone_ext>
      <email>apuppo@telefonica.net</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Virgen del Rocio</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sevilla</city>
        <zip>41012</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Antonio M Puppo Moreno, 1980</last_name>
      <phone>+34669410840</phone>
      <email>apuppo@telefonica.net</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Alejandro Adsuar Gomez, 2002</last_name>
      <phone>+34620283679</phone>
      <email>alejandro.adsuar@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bravo-Gil N, González-Del Pozo M, Martín-Sánchez M, Méndez-Vidal C, Rodríguez-de la Rúa E, Borrego S, Antiñolo G. Unravelling the genetic basis of simplex Retinitis Pigmentosa cases. Sci Rep. 2017 Feb 3;7:41937. doi: 10.1038/srep41937.</citation>
    <PMID>28157192</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>López-Domingo FJ, Florido JP, Rueda A, Dopazo J, Santoyo-Lopez J. ngsCAT: a tool to assess the efficiency of targeted enrichment sequencing. Bioinformatics. 2014 Jun 15;30(12):1767-8. doi: 10.1093/bioinformatics/btu108. Epub 2014 Feb 26.</citation>
    <PMID>24578402</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Biddinger A, Rocklin M, Coselli J, Milewicz DM. Familial thoracic aortic dilatations and dissections: a case control study. J Vasc Surg. 1997 Mar;25(3):506-11.</citation>
    <PMID>9081132</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Albornoz G, Coady MA, Roberts M, Davies RR, Tranquilli M, Rizzo JA, Elefteriades JA. Familial thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections--incidence, modes of inheritance, and phenotypic patterns. Ann Thorac Surg. 2006 Oct;82(4):1400-5.</citation>
    <PMID>16996941</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Coady MA, Davies RR, Roberts M, Goldstein LJ, Rogalski MJ, Rizzo JA, Hammond GL, Kopf GS, Elefteriades JA. Familial patterns of thoracic aortic aneurysms. Arch Surg. 1999 Apr;134(4):361-7.</citation>
    <PMID>10199307</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Milewicz D, Hostetler E, Wallace S, Mellor-Crummey L, Gong L, Pannu H, Guo DC, Regalado E. Precision medical and surgical management for thoracic aortic aneurysms and acute aortic dissections based on the causative mutant gene. J Cardiovasc Surg (Torino). 2016 Apr;57(2):172-7. Epub 2016 Feb 2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26837258</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Elefteriades JA, Farkas EA. Thoracic aortic aneurysm clinically pertinent controversies and uncertainties. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2010 Mar 2;55(9):841-57. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2009.08.084. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20185035</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Milewicz DM, Chen H, Park ES, Petty EM, Zaghi H, Shashidhar G, Willing M, Patel V. Reduced penetrance and variable expressivity of familial thoracic aortic aneurysms/dissections. Am J Cardiol. 1998 Aug 15;82(4):474-9.</citation>
    <PMID>9723636</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Robertson EN, van der Linde D, Sherrah AG, Vallely MP, Wilson M, Bannon PG, Jeremy RW. Familial non-syndromal thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections - Incidence and family screening outcomes. Int J Cardiol. 2016 Oct 1;220:43-51. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2016.06.086. Epub 2016 Jun 23.</citation>
    <PMID>27372041</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Renner S, Schüler H, Alawi M, Kolbe V, Rybczynski M, Woitschach R, Sheikhzadeh S, Stark VC, Olfe J, Roser E, Seggewies FS, Mahlmann A, Hempel M, Hartmann MJ, Hillebrand M, Wieczorek D, Volk AE, Kloth K, Koch-Hogrebe M, Abou Jamra R, Mitter D, Altmüller J, Wey-Fabrizius A, Petersen C, Rau I, Borck G, Kubisch C, Mir TS, von Kodolitsch Y, Kutsche K, Rosenberger G. Next-generation sequencing of 32 genes associated with hereditary aortopathies and related disorders of connective tissue in a cohort of 199 patients. Genet Med. 2019 Aug;21(8):1832-1841. doi: 10.1038/s41436-019-0435-z. Epub 2019 Jan 24.</citation>
    <PMID>30675029</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Poninska JK, Bilinska ZT, Franaszczyk M, Michalak E, Rydzanicz M, Szpakowski E, Pollak A, Milanowska B, Truszkowska G, Chmielewski P, Sioma A, Janaszek-Sitkowska H, Klisiewicz A, Michalowska I, Makowiecka-Ciesla M, Kolsut P, Stawinski P, Foss-Nieradko B, Szperl M, Grzybowski J, Hoffman P, Januszewicz A, Kusmierczyk M, Ploski R. Next-generation sequencing for diagnosis of thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections: diagnostic yield, novel mutations and genotype phenotype correlations. J Transl Med. 2016 May 4;14(1):115. doi: 10.1186/s12967-016-0870-4.</citation>
    <PMID>27146836</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Proost D, Vandeweyer G, Meester JA, Salemink S, Kempers M, Ingram C, Peeters N, Saenen J, Vrints C, Lacro RV, Roden D, Wuyts W, Dietz HC, Mortier G, Loeys BL, Van Laer L. Performant Mutation Identification Using Targeted Next-Generation Sequencing of 14 Thoracic Aortic Aneurysm Genes. Hum Mutat. 2015 Aug;36(8):808-14. doi: 10.1002/humu.22802. Epub 2015 Jun 13.</citation>
    <PMID>25907466</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Arslan-Kirchner M, Arbustini E, Boileau C, Charron P, Child AH, Collod-Beroud G, De Backer J, De Paepe A, Dierking A, Faivre L, Hoffjan S, Jondeau G, Keyser B, Loeys B, Mayer K, Robinson PN, Schmidtke J. Clinical utility gene card for: Hereditary thoracic aortic aneurysm and dissection including next-generation sequencing-based approaches. Eur J Hum Genet. 2016 Jan;24(1):e1-5. doi: 10.1038/ejhg.2015.225. Epub 2015 Oct 28.</citation>
    <PMID>26508578</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Renard M, Francis C, Ghosh R, Scott AF, Witmer PD, Adès LC, Andelfinger GU, Arnaud P, Boileau C, Callewaert BL, Guo D, Hanna N, Lindsay ME, Morisaki H, Morisaki T, Pachter N, Robert L, Van Laer L, Dietz HC, Loeys BL, Milewicz DM, De Backer J. Clinical Validity of Genes for Heritable Thoracic Aortic Aneurysm and Dissection. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018 Aug 7;72(6):605-615. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2018.04.089.</citation>
    <PMID>30071989</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zheng J, Guo J, Huang L, Wu Q, Yin K, Wang L, Zhang T, Quan L, Zhao Q, Cheng J. Genetic diagnosis of acute aortic dissection in South China Han population using next-generation sequencing. Int J Legal Med. 2018 Sep;132(5):1273-1280. doi: 10.1007/s00414-018-1890-9. Epub 2018 Jul 28.</citation>
    <PMID>30056620</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Arnaud P, Hanna N, Benarroch L, Aubart M, Bal L, Bouvagnet P, Busa T, Dulac Y, Dupuis-Girod S, Edouard T, Faivre L, Gouya L, Lacombe D, Langeois M, Leheup B, Milleron O, Naudion S, Odent S, Tchitchinadze M, Ropers J, Jondeau G, Boileau C. Genetic diversity and pathogenic variants as possible predictors of severity in a French sample of nonsyndromic heritable thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections (nshTAAD). Genet Med. 2019 Sep;21(9):2015-2024. doi: 10.1038/s41436-019-0444-y. Epub 2019 Feb 11.</citation>
    <PMID>30739908</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Clouse WD, Hallett JW Jr, Schaff HV, Spittell PC, Rowland CM, Ilstrup DM, Melton LJ 3rd. Acute aortic dissection: population-based incidence compared with degenerative aortic aneurysm rupture. Mayo Clin Proc. 2004 Feb;79(2):176-80.</citation>
    <PMID>14959911</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mészáros I, Mórocz J, Szlávi J, Schmidt J, Tornóci L, Nagy L, Szép L. Epidemiology and clinicopathology of aortic dissection. Chest. 2000 May;117(5):1271-8.</citation>
    <PMID>10807810</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kuzmik GA, Sang AX, Elefteriades JA. Natural history of thoracic aortic aneurysms. J Vasc Surg. 2012 Aug;56(2):565-71. doi: 10.1016/j.jvs.2012.04.053.</citation>
    <PMID>22840907</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gago-Díaz M, Ramos-Luis E, Zoppis S, Zorio E, Molina P, Braza-Boïls A, Giner J, Sobrino B, Amigo J, Blanco-Verea A, Carracedo Á, Brion M. Postmortem genetic testing should be recommended in sudden cardiac death cases due to thoracic aortic dissection. Int J Legal Med. 2017 Sep;131(5):1211-1219. doi: 10.1007/s00414-017-1583-9. Epub 2017 Apr 8.</citation>
    <PMID>28391405</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Erbel R, Aboyans V, Boileau C, Bossone E, Bartolomeo RD, Eggebrecht H, Evangelista A, Falk V, Frank H, Gaemperli O, Grabenwöger M, Haverich A, Iung B, Manolis AJ, Meijboom F, Nienaber CA, Roffi M, Rousseau H, Sechtem U, Sirnes PA, Allmen RS, Vrints CJ; ESC Committee for Practice Guidelines. 2014 ESC Guidelines on the diagnosis and treatment of aortic diseases: Document covering acute and chronic aortic diseases of the thoracic and abdominal aorta of the adult. The Task Force for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Aortic Diseases of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). Eur Heart J. 2014 Nov 1;35(41):2873-926. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehu281. Epub 2014 Aug 29. Erratum in: Eur Heart J. 2015 Nov 1;36(41):2779.</citation>
    <PMID>25173340</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hospitales Universitarios Virgen del Rocío</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Antonio M. Puppo Moreno</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

