<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04750928</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>210011</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>21-C-0011</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04750928</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cyclin-Dependent Kinase (CDK)4/6 Inhibitor Abemaciclib for Neurofibromatosis Type I (NF1) Related Atypical Neurofibromas</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I/II Study of the Cyclin-Dependent Kinase(CDK)4/6 Inhibitor Abemaciclib for Neurofibromatosis Type 1 (NF1) Related Atypical Neurofibromas</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      NF1 is a genetic disease that causes tumors called atypical neurofibromas. These tumors,&#xD;
      which arise from nerves, can cause serious medical problems. The only treatment is surgery.&#xD;
      Researchers want to see if a drug called abemaciclib can help.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To find a safe, tolerable dose of abemaciclib for treating atypical neurofibromas.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People ages 12 and older who have NF1 and have one or more atypical neurofibromas that cannot&#xD;
      or will not be removed with surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical history and physical exam&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood, urine, and heart tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      MRI: Participants will lie in a machine that takes pictures of the body. A padding or coil&#xD;
      will be placed around their head. They may have a contrast agent injected into a vein.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biopsy sample: A small piece of tumor will be removed using a large needle.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have frequent visits during the study. These will include repeats of the&#xD;
      screening tests as well as the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
      PET scan: Participants will lie in a machine that takes pictures of the body. They will have&#xD;
      a contrast agent injected into their arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Questionnaires about the effects of abemaciclib on pain and quality of life&#xD;
&#xD;
      Possible photographs of tumors&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will take abemaciclib capsules orally twice daily in 28-day cycles. They will&#xD;
      take the drug for up to 2 years. Some may be able to take it for longer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have a follow-up visit about 30 days after their last dose of the study&#xD;
      drug. Then they will have visits every 3 months for 1 year.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1) is a genetic tumor predisposition syndrome (incidence of&#xD;
      1:3000), which results in the development of progressive tumor and non-tumor manifestations,&#xD;
      the majority of which have no effective medical therapies. 25-50% of individuals with&#xD;
      neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1) develop histologically benign plexiform neurofibromas (PN),&#xD;
      which can cause substantial morbidity. Recently, the POB identified that MEK inhibitors cause&#xD;
      shrinkage of the majority of PN and that PN shrinkage is associated with clinical benefit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A natural history study of NF1 at the NCI has gathered comprehensive imaging information&#xD;
      using longitudinal whole-body MRI with volumetric measurements. By this approach, distinct&#xD;
      nodular lesions (DNL) were identified, many of which are atypical neurofibromas (ANF) based&#xD;
      on pathology review.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The NCI POB and others have described ANF as precursor lesions for aggressive soft tissue&#xD;
      sarcomas called malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors (MPNST), which show poor response to&#xD;
      chemotherapy and have poor survival. Of note, ANF appear to be less responsive to treatment&#xD;
      with MEK inhibitors indicating a different biology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exome sequencing of 16 ANF resected at the National Cancer Institute, Pediatric Oncology&#xD;
      Branch (NCI POB) and Belgium revealed that 90% of the cases had heterozygous loss of CDKN2A/B&#xD;
      as the only new somatic change in addition to biallelic NF1 deletion, consistent with prior&#xD;
      reports. These results demonstrate that transformation of NF1 nerve tumors may genetically&#xD;
      proceed through the premalignant ANF by a common mechanism that might be a point of&#xD;
      intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CDKN2A is the primary inhibitory brake on CDK4/6 driven signaling and is commonly deleted in&#xD;
      glioblastoma, pancreas, bladder, breast and prostate cancer. The specific CDK4/6 inhibitor,&#xD;
      abemaciclib, has FDA approval for the treatment of metastatic breast cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ANF is a prototypic premalignant lesion for testing experimental intervention, as these&#xD;
      lesions are at risk for transformation, and share a common potentially druggable genomic&#xD;
      alteration (CDKN2A/B deletion). We propose a clinical trial of abemaciclib in children and&#xD;
      adults with NF1 and unresectable ANF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase I: To determine the recommended Phase II dose (RP2D) of abemaciclib in patients with&#xD;
      NF1 and a measurable ANF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase II: To determine the objective response rate (ORR) in the target ANF; complete and&#xD;
      partial response (CR + PR), response determined by volumetric MRI analysis (^3 20% volume&#xD;
      reduction) compared to baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients must be at least 12 years of age with a diagnosis of NF1 with associated age-related&#xD;
      requirements as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Willingness of patients &gt;= 12 years old and &lt;18 years old to undergo pre-treatment&#xD;
      percutaneous biopsy of ANF if deemed feasible with minimal morbidity&#xD;
&#xD;
      Willingness of patients &gt;=18 years old to undergo pre-treatment and on-treatment percutaneous&#xD;
      biopsy of ANF if deemed feasible with minimal morbidity&#xD;
&#xD;
      Presence of &gt;= 1 measurable ANF (biopsy confirmed) for which surgical removal could cause&#xD;
      significant morbidity OR for which patient is unwilling to undergo surgical resection OR the&#xD;
      presence of more than one distinct nodular lesion (DNL) including at least 1 biopsy proven&#xD;
      ANF&#xD;
&#xD;
      For patients of all ages with ANF who cannot be safely biopsied with minimal morbidity,&#xD;
      biopsy requirement to be performed at NIH Clinical Center will be waived from eligibility&#xD;
      criteria. In this case, review of available archival tissue by NIH Pathology will be&#xD;
      necessary to confirm diagnosis of ANF, which is mandatory for eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a Phase I/II non-randomized, open label, single institution study of the CDK4/6&#xD;
      inhibitor, abemaciclib, in children and adults with NF1 and a measurable ANF or with multiple&#xD;
      ANF/DNL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primarily because the tolerability of investigational agents may differ between the NF1&#xD;
      population and non-NF1 population and secondarily because abemaciclib has not been evaluated&#xD;
      in children to date, there will be a limited dose finding phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the Phase 1 portion of the trial, the first 6 subjects enrolled will be treated at 75%&#xD;
      of the adult recommended Phase II dose (ARP2D; 150mg PO BID) of abemaciclib used in patients&#xD;
      with malignancies, in a 28-day cycle. For patients &lt; 18 years of age, dosing will be based on&#xD;
      body surface area (BSA).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cohorts of up to 6 subjects will be enrolled, with dose adjustment depending on dose-limiting&#xD;
      toxicities (DLT) until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD)/ recommended Phase II dose (RP2D) is&#xD;
      established.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Phase II trial is a Simon minimax two-stage trial design. A response rate of&#xD;
      approximately 30% or greater would be considered desirable. The first stage of the Phase II&#xD;
      portion of the trial will enroll 15 evaluable subjects; if 0 to 2 of the 15 have a PR or CR,&#xD;
      then no further subjects will be accrued. If 3 or more of the 15 subjects have a PR or CR,&#xD;
      then accrual would continue until a total of 21 evaluable subjects have been enrolled in&#xD;
      phase II.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The accrual ceiling will be set at 50 eligible subjects (to include patients who are screened&#xD;
      but found to not be eligible to undergo treatment).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will undergo careful toxicity monitoring. Restaging MRI for response will be&#xD;
      performed pre-cycles 3 and 5, and then every 4 cycles for remainder of the first year.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>safety of abemaciclib in patients with NF1 and a measurable ANF</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>List of adverse event frequency</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tolerability of abemaciclib on a prolonged dosing schedule</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 years of treatment or until disease progression or unacceptable treatment-related toxicity</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of treatment and adverse event types and frequency</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stable disease rate of target ANF</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline through 30 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients that have progressive disease</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response rate of non-target ANF/DNL</measure>
    <time_frame>at progression</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in non-target ANF/DNL determined by volumetric MRI analysis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of abemaciclib on CDK4/6 target inhibition</measure>
    <time_frame>after Day 7 of Cycle 1</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of phosphorylated Retinoblastoma (pRB) in tumor biopsy samples</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of abemaciclib on ANF related pain and quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline through 30 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Patient-Reported Outcome response</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Abemaciclib pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamic</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Drug level in blood</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Neurofibromatosis 1</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1/ Phase I Dose Escalation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Abemaciclib orally twice daily at escalating doses to determine the MTD/RP2D</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2/ Phase II Objective Response Rate</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Abemaciclib orally twice daily at the RP2D</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Abemaciclib</intervention_name>
    <description>Abemaciclib is to be administered orally on Days 1 through 28 of each 28-day cycle</description>
    <arm_group_label>1/ Phase I Dose Escalation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>2/ Phase II Objective Response Rate</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a clinical diagnosis of NF1, i.e., patients must have at least two&#xD;
             of the diagnostic criteria for NF1 listed below (NIH Consensus conference) or a&#xD;
             confirmed&#xD;
&#xD;
        NF1 mutation from a CLIA-certified laboratory:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -- Six or more cafe-au-lait macules (&gt;= 0.5cm in prepubertal subjects or &gt;= 1.5 cm&#xD;
&#xD;
        in post pubertal subjects)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Freckling in axilla or groin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A neurofibroma or plexiform neurofibroma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Optic glioma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Two or more Lisch nodules&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A distinctive bony lesion (dysplasia of the sphenoid bone or dysplasia or thinning of&#xD;
             long bone cortex)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A first-degree relative with NF1&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of &gt;= 1 ANF (biopsy confirmed) for whom surgical removal could cause&#xD;
                  significant clinical morbidity OR for which patient is unwilling to undergo&#xD;
                  surgical resection OR the presence of more than one distinct nodular lesion (DNL)&#xD;
                  including at least 1 biopsy proven ANF&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTES: Definition of DNL. In addition, there will not be a requirement for confirmed&#xD;
        CDKN2A/B deletion for study eligibility due to known biopsy sampling error and tumor&#xD;
        heterogeneity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;= 12 years old (no maximum age) with associated age-related requirements as&#xD;
             follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;= 12 years old with BSA &gt;= 0.71 M^2 and able to swallow whole tablets&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness of patients &gt;= 12 years old and &lt;18 years old to undergo pre-treatment&#xD;
             percutaneous biopsy of ANF if deemed feasible with minimal morbidity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness of patients &gt;=18 years old to undergo pre-treatment and on-treatment&#xD;
             percutaneous biopsy of ANF if deemed feasible with minimal morbidity&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: For patients of all ages with ANF that cannot be safely biopsied with minimal&#xD;
        morbidity, biopsy requirement to be performed at NIH Clinical Center will be waived from&#xD;
        eligibility criteria. In this case, review of available archival tissue by NIH Pathology&#xD;
        will be necessary to confirm diagnosis of ANF, which is mandatory for eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease: Patients must have at least one measurable ANF defined as a lesion&#xD;
             of at least 3 centimeters (cm) measured in one dimension. Measurability and&#xD;
             suitability for volumetric MRI analysis of the target ANF must be confirmed with the&#xD;
             NCI POB prior to enrolling a patient. The target ANF will be defined as the clinically&#xD;
             most relevant ANF, which has to be amenable to volumetric MRI analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
             - Prior Therapies:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Since there is no standard effective chemotherapy for patients with NF1 and ANF,&#xD;
             patients may be treated on this trial without having received prior medical therapy&#xD;
             directed at their ANF.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Investigational agents/biologic therapies (not chemotherapy): Patients who have&#xD;
             received previous investigational agents or biologic therapies are eligible for&#xD;
             enrollment. At least 28 days must have elapsed since receiving medical therapy&#xD;
             directed at any NF1 related tumor. Patients who received prior medical therapy for a&#xD;
             NF1 related tumor manifestation must have recovered from the acute toxic effects of&#xD;
             all prior therapy to &lt;= grade 1 CTCAEv5 except for residual alopecia or Grade 2&#xD;
&#xD;
        peripheral neuropathy prior to enrollment before entering this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chemotherapy agents: Patients who received chemotherapy must have recovered (CTCAE&#xD;
             Grade &lt;=1) from the acute effects of chemotherapy except for residual alopecia or&#xD;
             Grade 2 peripheral neuropathy prior to enrollment. A washout period of at least 28&#xD;
             days is required between last chemotherapy dose and enrollment (provided the patient&#xD;
             did not receive radiotherapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who received adjuvant radiotherapy must have completed and fully recovered&#xD;
             from the acute effects of radiotherapy. Patients who have received previous radiation&#xD;
             therapy are eligible for enrollment. At least 6 weeks must have elapsed since the last&#xD;
             radiation therapy and start of treatment. The only target ANF cannot have received&#xD;
             radiation previously.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 4 weeks must have elapsed since any major surgeries, with evidence of good&#xD;
             wound healing. Minimally invasive biopsies and central line placements are not&#xD;
             considered major surgeries.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received prior treatment with abemaciclib or another specific CDK4/6&#xD;
             inhibitor are not eligible for enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adequate performance scale (Lansky/Karnofsky &gt;=70%).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adequate organ function as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hematologic Function: Patients must have an absolute neutrophil count =1500/ micro&#xD;
             lliter, hemoglobin &gt;=9 g/dL (transfusion independent, defined as not receiving blood&#xD;
             transfusion unless related to trauma or surgeries), and platelets &gt;=100,000/ micro&#xD;
             liter (transfusion independent, defined as not receiving platelet transfusions unless&#xD;
             related to trauma or surgeries)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatic Function: Patients must have bilirubin within 1.5 x the upper limit of normal&#xD;
             for age, with the exception of those with Gilbert syndrome, and AST/ALT within &lt;= 3 x&#xD;
             upper limit of normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal Function: Patients must have a creatinine clearance or radioisotope GFR&#xD;
             &gt;=60ml/min/1.73 m^2 or a normal serum creatinine based on age, described below.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age (years) is &gt;12 and &lt;=15 then Maximum Serum Creatinine (mg/dL) = 1.2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age (years) is &gt;15 then Maximum Serum Creatinine (mg/dL) = 1.5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiac Function: Normal ejection fraction (ECHO or cardiac MRI) &gt;= 53% (or the&#xD;
             institutional normal; if a range is given then the upper value of the range will be&#xD;
             used); QTC or QTcF &lt;=450 msec.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Willingness to avoid grapefruit or grapefruit juice during abemaciclib&#xD;
                  administration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Informed Consent: Ability of subject or Legally Authorized Representative (LAR)&#xD;
                  to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
                  All patients or their legal guardians (if the patient is &lt; 18 years old) must&#xD;
                  sign an IRB-approved document of informed consent to demonstrate their&#xD;
                  understanding of the investigational nature and the risks of this study before&#xD;
                  any protocol-related studies are performed. When appropriate, pediatric subjects&#xD;
                  will be included in all discussions.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Based on animal studies, the effects of abemaciclib can cause fetal harm. For&#xD;
                  these reasons, women of child-bearing potential and men must agree to use a&#xD;
                  highly effective contraceptive method during treatment and for at least 3 months&#xD;
                  after the last dose of abemaciclib. Should a woman become pregnant or suspect she&#xD;
                  is pregnant while she or her partner is participating in this study, she should&#xD;
                  inform her treating physician immediately. Men treated or enrolled on this&#xD;
                  protocol must also agree to use adequate contraception prior to the study, for&#xD;
                  the duration of study participation, and 4 months after completion of abemaciclib&#xD;
                  administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Woman subjects of childbearing potential (WOCBP) must have a negative serum pregnancy&#xD;
             test with a sensitivity of at least 25 mIU/mL within 7 days of the first dose of&#xD;
             abemaciclib.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A woman is considered to be of childbearing potential if she is postmenarcheal, has&#xD;
             not reached a postmenopausal state (&gt;= 12 continuous months of amenorrhea with no&#xD;
             identified cause other than menopause), and has not undergone surgical sterilization&#xD;
             (removal of ovaries and/or uterus).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraceptive methods may include intrauterine devices (IUD), or barrier method, a&#xD;
             spermicidal agent should be added as a double barrier protection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases of pregnancy that occur during maternal exposures to abemaciclib should be&#xD;
             reported. If a patient or spouse/partner is determined to be pregnant following&#xD;
             abemaciclib initiation she must discontinue treatment immediately. Data on fetal&#xD;
             outcomes and breastfeeding are to be collected for regulatory reporting and drug&#xD;
             safety evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women, or women who intent to become pregnant during the study, are excluded&#xD;
             from this study because of the teratogenic effects of abemaciclib. Because there is an&#xD;
             unknown but potential risk for adverse events in nursing infants secondary to&#xD;
             treatment of the mother with these agents, breastfeeding should be discontinued if the&#xD;
             mother is treated on study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  May not have a NF1-related tumor such as optic pathway glioma or malignant peripheral&#xD;
             nerve sheath tumor, which requires treatment with chemotherapy or surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious preexisting medical condition(s) that would preclude participation in this&#xD;
             study (for example, interstitial lung disease, severe dyspnea at rest requiring oxygen&#xD;
             therapy, history of major surgical resection involving the stomach or small bowel that&#xD;
             would preclude adequate absorption, or preexisting Crohn s disease or ulcerative&#xD;
             colitis or a preexisting chronic condition resulting in baseline Grade 2 or higher&#xD;
             diarrhea).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, symptomatic&#xD;
             congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, active&#xD;
             bleeding diatheses or renal transplant, or psychiatric illness/social situations that&#xD;
             would limit compliance with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Personal history of any of the following conditions: syncope of cardiovascular&#xD;
             etiology, ventricular arrhythmia of pathological origin (including, but not limited&#xD;
             to, ventricular tachycardia and ventricular fibrillation), or sudden cardiac arrest.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active bacterial infection (requiring intravenous [IV] antibiotics at time of&#xD;
             initiating study treatment), fungal infection, or detectable viral infection (such as&#xD;
             known human immunodeficiency virus positivity or with known active hepatitis B or C&#xD;
             [for example, hepatitis B surface antigen positive]. Patients with HIV who have&#xD;
             adequate CD4 counts and who have no requirement for antiviral therapy will be&#xD;
             eligible. NOTE: Screening is not required for enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with interstitial lung disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Requires treatment with strong CYP3A inhibitors or inducers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to swallow tablets, since tablets cannot be crushed or broken.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to undergo MRI and/or contraindication for MRI examinations following the&#xD;
             MRI protocol (see Study Procedure Manual). Prosthesis or orthopedic or dental braces&#xD;
             that would interfere with volumetric analysis of target ANF on MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refractory nausea and vomiting that would limit drug administration in the opinion of&#xD;
             the Principal Investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known severe hypersensitivity to abemaciclib or any excipient of abemaciclib or&#xD;
             history of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to abemaciclib&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical judgment by the investigator that the patient should not participate in the&#xD;
             study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andrea M Gross, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Anne Goodwin, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(240) 760-6195</phone>
    <email>goodwina@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact National Cancer Institute Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>888-624-1937</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2021-C-0011.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 5, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Kinase Inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>distinct nodular lesion</keyword>
  <keyword>genomic alteration</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neurofibromatoses</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neurofibromatosis 1</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neurofibroma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

