<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04759144</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FAST-Kids</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04759144</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>FASter Insulin in Closed-loop Technology in Children</brief_title>
  <acronym>FAST-Kids</acronym>
  <official_title>A Randomised Crossover Study Comparing Hybrid Closed-loop Insulin Delivery Using Ultra-rapid Acting Insulin to Hybrid Closed-loop Insulin Delivery Using Standard Rapid-acting Insulin in Children With Type 1 Diabetes in the Home Setting (FAST-Kids)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Cambridge</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Alder Hey Children's NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Cambridge</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main objective of this study is to compare 24/7 hybrid closed-loop insulin delivery under&#xD;
      free living conditions applying faster insulin aspart (FiAsp) to 24/7 hybrid closed-loop&#xD;
      insulin delivery applying standard insulin aspart in very young children with type 1&#xD;
      diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The closed-loop system consists of three components: the continuous glucose monitor (CGM),&#xD;
      the insulin pump and a smartphone Application, or App, that translates, in real-time, sensor&#xD;
      glucose levels received from the glucose monitoring device and calculates the amount of&#xD;
      insulin to be delivered by the coupled insulin pump.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a double-blind, multi-centre, randomised, crossover design study, involving a run-in&#xD;
      period followed by two 8-week study periods during which glucose levels will be controlled by&#xD;
      a hybrid closed-loop system using either standard insulin aspart or faster insulin aspart in&#xD;
      random order.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants aged 2-6 years with type 1 diabetes on insulin pump therapy will be recruited&#xD;
      through paediatric diabetes outpatient clinics at participating clinical centres. Enrolment&#xD;
      will target up to 30 children (aiming for 6-14 participants per centre) to allow for dropouts&#xD;
      during run-in.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to the use of study devices, participants and parents/guardians will receive&#xD;
      appropriate training by the research team on the safe use of the study pump and CGM device,&#xD;
      and the hybrid closed-loop insulin delivery system. Parents/guardians at nursey/school may&#xD;
      also receive training by the study team if required. Participants will have regular contact&#xD;
      with the study team during the study including 24/7 telephone support. Parents/guardians will&#xD;
      be asked to complete validated questionnaires at the start and end of the study to assess&#xD;
      quality of life measures including sleep.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome is the between group difference in time spent in target range between 3.9&#xD;
      and 10.0 mmol/l as recorded by CGM during the study. Secondary outcomes are time spent with&#xD;
      glucose levels above and below target, as recorded by CGM, and other CGM-based metrics.&#xD;
      Safety evaluation comprises assessment of the frequency and severity of hypoglycaemic&#xD;
      episodes and diabetic ketoacidosis (DKA).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Purpose of clinical trial:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To compare hybrid closed-loop applying faster insulin aspart to hybrid closed-loop applying&#xD;
      standard insulin aspart over 8 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study objective is to compare hybrid closed-loop glucose control using faster insulin&#xD;
      aspart with hybrid closed-loop control using standard insulin aspart in very young children&#xD;
      with type 1 diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. EFFICACY: The objective is to assess the ability of a hybrid closed-loop system applying&#xD;
           faster insulin aspart to maintain CGM glucose levels within the target range from 3.9 to&#xD;
           10.0 mmol/l, in comparison to a hybrid closed-loop system applying standard insulin&#xD;
           aspart in very young children with type 1 diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. SAFETY: The objective is to evaluate the safety of closed-loop glucose control using&#xD;
           faster insulin aspart compared to standard insulin aspart in terms of episodes and&#xD;
           severity of hypoglycaemia, frequency of diabetic ketoacidosis (DKA) and nature and&#xD;
           severity of other adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. UTILITY: The objective is to determine the acceptability and duration of use of the&#xD;
           closed-loop system.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. HUMAN FACTORS: The objective is to assess emotional and behavioural characteristics of&#xD;
           parents/guardians and their response to the closed-loop system and clinical trial using&#xD;
           validated surveys.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participating clinical centres:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Addenbrooke's Hospital, Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Cambridge&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. John Radcliffe Hospital, Oxford University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Oxford&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Nottingham Children's Hospital, Nottingham&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Alder Hey Children's Hospital, Liverpool&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample Size:&#xD;
&#xD;
      24 children randomised (6-14 participants per centre).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Maximum duration of study for a subject:&#xD;
&#xD;
      6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be recruited through the paediatric diabetes outpatient clinics at&#xD;
      participating clinical centres (see above). Enrolment will target up to 30 participants&#xD;
      (aiming for 6-14 participants per centre), to allow for dropouts during run-in.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consent:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Written informed consent will be obtained from all parents/guardians.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Screening and baseline Assessment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible participants will undergo a baseline assessment including a blood sample for the&#xD;
      measurement of HbA1c. Height and weight will be recorded. Validated questionnaires will be&#xD;
      completed by parents/guardians.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pre-Study Training and Run-in:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Training sessions on the use of the study CGM, insulin pump and hybrid closed-loop insulin&#xD;
      delivery will be provided by the research team. During the closed-loop training session,&#xD;
      parents/guardians will operate the system under the supervision of the clinical research&#xD;
      team. Participants and parents/guardians will use the study CGM, insulin pump, and hybrid&#xD;
      closed-loop insulin delivery during a 2-4 week run-in period. For compliance and to assess&#xD;
      the ability of the participant to use the study devices safely, at least 8 days of CGM data&#xD;
      need to be recorded and safe use of study insulin pump and hybrid closed-loop insulin&#xD;
      delivery demonstrated during the last 14 days of the run-in period. The CGM data will also be&#xD;
      used to assess baseline glucose control and may be used for treatment optimisation as&#xD;
      necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Competency Assessment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Competency on the use of study pump,study CGM and hybrid closed-loop insulin delivery will be&#xD;
      evaluated by the research team. Training may be repeated if required.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomisation:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible participants will be randomised using randomisation software to the initial use of&#xD;
      faster insulin aspart with the hybrid closed-loop system or to standard insulin aspart with&#xD;
      the hybrid closed-loop system for 8 weeks before crossing over to the other treatment arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Faster insulin aspart with hybrid closed-loop:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Participants and their parents/guardians will use the hybrid closed-loop system with&#xD;
           faster insulin aspart for 8 weeks at home. The participant, parents/guardians and the&#xD;
           research team will be blinded to the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Crossover assessment:&#xD;
&#xD;
           At the end of the first study arm, validated questionnaires will be completed by the&#xD;
           parents/guardians.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Standard insulin aspart with hybrid closed-loop:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants and their parents/guardians will use the hybrid closed-loop system with standard&#xD;
      insulin aspart for 8 weeks at home. The participant, parents/guardians and the research team&#xD;
      will be blinded to the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study contacts:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants and parents/guardians will be contacted 24 hours after starting each study arm&#xD;
      to ensure there are no concerns regarding the study devices. Participants will be contacted&#xD;
      by the study team (email/phone) 2 and 4 weeks after the start of each study arm in order to&#xD;
      record any adverse events, device deficiencies, and changes in insulin settings, other&#xD;
      medical conditions and/or medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In case of any problems related to the technical devices or diabetes management, participants&#xD;
      and parents/guardians will be able to contact a 24-hour telephone helpline to the local&#xD;
      research team. The local research team will have access to central 24 hour advice on&#xD;
      technical issues.&#xD;
&#xD;
      End of study assessments:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Height and weight will be recorded. Validated questionnaires will be completed by&#xD;
      parents/guardians. Participants will resume usual care using their pre-study insulin pump.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures for safety monitoring during trial:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Standard operating procedures for monitoring and reporting of all adverse events will be in&#xD;
      place, including serious adverse events (SAE), serious adverse device effects (SADE) and&#xD;
      specific adverse events (AE) such as severe hypoglycaemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A data safety and monitoring board (DSMB) will be informed of all serious adverse events and&#xD;
      any unanticipated serious adverse device effects that occur during the study and will review&#xD;
      compiled adverse event data at periodic intervals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Criteria for withdrawal of subjects on safety grounds:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A participant and parent/guardian may terminate participation in the study at any time&#xD;
      without necessarily giving a reason and without any personal disadvantage. An investigator&#xD;
      can stop the participation of a participant after consideration of the benefit/risk ratio.&#xD;
      Possible reasons are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Serious adverse events&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Serious protocol violation&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Non-compliance&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Failure to satisfy competency assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Decision by the investigator, or the Sponsor, that termination is in the participant's&#xD;
           best medical interest&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Allergic reaction to insulin&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 12, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Device: CamAPS FX&#xD;
The automated closed loop system (CamAPS FX) will consist of:&#xD;
Dana insulin pump (Diabecare, Sooil, Seoul, South Korea)&#xD;
Dexcom G6 real-time CGM sensor (Dexcom, Northridge, CA, USA)&#xD;
An Android smartphone hosting CamAPS FX app with the Cambridge model predictive control algorithm and communicating wirelessly with the insulin pump and glucose sensor&#xD;
Cloud upload system to monitor CGM/insulin data.&#xD;
Treatment: Two insulins will be used&#xD;
Faster insulin aspart (Fiasp)&#xD;
Standard insulin aspart (Novorapid)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>An unmasked member of staff will undertake randomisation. The participants and the clinical staff will be blind to allocated treatment sequence.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time in target (3.9 to 10.0mmol/L) (70 to 180 mg/dL)</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>The between group difference in time spent with sensor glucose levels between 3.9 to 10.0 mmol/l during the 8 week intervention period.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent above target glucose (10.0 mmol/L) (180 mg/dL)</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of time spent with sensor glucose readings above target glucose (10.0mmol/L) (180mg/dL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Average of sensor glucose levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent below target glucose (3.9 mmol/L) (70 mg/dL)</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of time spent with sensor glucose readings below target glucose (3.9mmol/L)(70mg/dL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Standard deviation of glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Standard deviation Standard deviation of sensor glucose levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Coefficient of variation of glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Coefficient of variation of sensor glucose levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent below target glucose (3.0 mmol/L) (54 mg/dL)</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of time spent with sensor glucose readings below target glucose (3.0mmol/L)(54mg/dL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time with glucose levels in significant hyperglycaemia (glucose levels &gt; 16.7 mmol/L) (300 mg/dL)</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of time spent with glucose levels in significant hyperglycaemia (glucose levels &gt; 16.7mmol/L) (300mg/dL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>BMI SDS</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total, basal, and bolus insulin dose</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of episodes of severe hypoglycaemia</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Safety evaluation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of diabetic ketoacidosis</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Safety evaluation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency and nature of other adverse events or serious adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Safety evaluation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Closed-loop use</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of time of closed-loop is operational (Utility evaluation)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CGM use</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of time CGM is available (Utility evaluation)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Human factors assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of emotional and behavioural characteristics of parents/guardians, their response to the closed-loop system and information about parent/guardian sleep will be assessed through validated surveys.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Faster insulin aspart with hybrid closed-loop insulin delivery</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Unsupervised home use of hybrid closed-loop insulin delivery with faster insulin aspart for 8 weeks.&#xD;
Intervention: Use of faster insulin aspart with hybrid closed-loop insulin delivery</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard insulin aspart with hybrid closed-loop insulin delivery</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Unsupervised home use of hybrid closed-loop insulin delivery with standard insulin aspart for 8 weeks.&#xD;
Intervention: Use of standard insulin aspart with hybrid closed-loop insulin delivery</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CamAPS FX using faster insulin aspart</intervention_name>
    <description>CamAPS FX closed loop system comprises:&#xD;
Dana insulin pump (Diabecare, Sooil, Seoul, South Korea)&#xD;
Dexcom G6 real-time CGM sensor (Dexcom, Northridge, CA, USA)&#xD;
An Android smartphone hosting CamAPS FX app with the Cambridge model predictive control algorithm and communicating wirelessly with the insulin pump and glucose sensor&#xD;
Cloud upload system to monitor CGM/insulin data</description>
    <arm_group_label>Faster insulin aspart with hybrid closed-loop insulin delivery</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CamAPS FX using standard insulin aspart</intervention_name>
    <description>CamAPS FX closed loop system comprises:&#xD;
Dana insulin pump (Diabecare, Sooil, Seoul, South Korea)&#xD;
Dexcom G6 real-time CGM sensor (Dexcom, Northridge, CA, USA)&#xD;
An Android smartphone hosting CamAPS FX app with the Cambridge model predictive control algorithm and communicating wirelessly with the insulin pump and glucose sensor&#xD;
Cloud upload system to monitor CGM/insulin data</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard insulin aspart with hybrid closed-loop insulin delivery</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age between 2 and 6 years (inclusive)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Type 1 diabetes as defined by WHO for at least 6 months [WHO definition: 'The&#xD;
             aetiological type named type 1 encompasses the majority of cases which are primarily&#xD;
             due to beta-cell destruction, and are prone to ketoacidosis. Type 1 includes those&#xD;
             cases attributable to an autoimmune process, as well as those with beta-cell&#xD;
             destruction for which neither an aetiology nor a pathogenesis is known (idiopathic).&#xD;
             It does not include those forms of beta-cell destruction or failure to which specific&#xD;
             causes can be assigned (e.g. cystic fibrosis, mitochondrial defects, etc.).']&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Insulin pump user (with or without continuous glucose monitoring or flash glucose&#xD;
             monitoring system) for at least 3 months, with parent/guardian good knowledge of&#xD;
             insulin self-adjustment as judged by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Treated with U-100 rapid or ultra-rapid acting insulin analogue&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Screening HbA1c ≤ 11% (97mmol/mol) on analysis from local laboratory&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Able to wear glucose sensor&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Able to wear closed-loop system 24/7&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. The parent/guardian is willing to follow study specific instructions&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The parent/guardian is proficient in English&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Physical or psychological disease likely to interfere with the normal conduct of the&#xD;
             study and interpretation of the study results as judged by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Untreated coeliac disease or thyroid disease based on local investigations prior to&#xD;
             study enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current treatment with drugs known to interfere with glucose metabolism, e.g. systemic&#xD;
             corticosteroids&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Known or suspected allergy to insulin&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Parent/guardian's lack of reliable telephone facility for contact&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Parent/guardian's severe visual impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Parent/guardian's severe hearing impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Medically documented allergy towards the adhesive (glue) of plasters or subject is&#xD;
             unable to tolerate tape adhesive in the area of sensor placement&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Serious skin diseases (e.g. psoriasis vulgaris, bacterial skin diseases) located in&#xD;
             parts of the body which could potentially be used for localisation of the glucose&#xD;
             sensor)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>6 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Roman Hovorka, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Wellcome Trust-MRC Institute of Metabolic Science University of Cambridge</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Roman Hovorka, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+44 1223 762 862</phone>
    <email>rh347@cam.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Alina Cezar</last_name>
    <phone>+44 1223 769 068</phone>
    <email>ac2367@medschl.cam.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Department of Paediatrics</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cambridge</city>
        <state>Cambridgeshire</state>
        <zip>CB2 0QQ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Julia Fuchs, MBChB</last_name>
      <email>jf674@cam.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ajay Thankamony</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wellcome Trust-MRC Institute of Metabolic Science University of Cambridge</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cambridge</city>
        <state>Cambridgeshire</state>
        <zip>CB2 0QQ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Roman Hovorka</last_name>
      <phone>+44 1223 762 862</phone>
      <email>rh347@cam.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Roman Hovorka</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tauschmann M, Thabit H, Bally L, Allen JM, Hartnell S, Wilinska ME, Ruan Y, Sibayan J, Kollman C, Cheng P, Beck RW, Acerini CL, Evans ML, Dunger DB, Elleri D, Campbell F, Bergenstal RM, Criego A, Shah VN, Leelarathna L, Hovorka R; APCam11 Consortium. Closed-loop insulin delivery in suboptimally controlled type 1 diabetes: a multicentre, 12-week randomised trial. Lancet. 2018 Oct 13;392(10155):1321-1329. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31947-0. Epub 2018 Oct 3. Erratum in: Lancet. 2018 Oct 13;392(10155):1310.</citation>
    <PMID>30292578</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tauschmann M, Allen JM, Nagl K, Fritsch M, Yong J, Metcalfe E, Schaeffer D, Fichelle M, Schierloh U, Thiele AG, Abt D, Kojzar H, Mader JK, Slegtenhorst S, Barber N, Wilinska ME, Boughton C, Musolino G, Sibayan J, Cohen N, Kollman C, Hofer SE, Fröhlich-Reiterer E, Kapellen TM, Acerini CL, de Beaufort C, Campbell F, Rami-Merhar B, Hovorka R; KidsAP Consortium. Home Use of Day-and-Night Hybrid Closed-Loop Insulin Delivery in Very Young Children: A Multicenter, 3-Week, Randomized Trial. Diabetes Care. 2019 Apr;42(4):594-600. doi: 10.2337/dc18-1881. Epub 2019 Jan 28.</citation>
    <PMID>30692242</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tauschmann M, Allen JM, Wilinska ME, Thabit H, Acerini CL, Dunger DB, Hovorka R. Home Use of Day-and-Night Hybrid Closed-Loop Insulin Delivery in Suboptimally Controlled Adolescents With Type 1 Diabetes: A 3-Week, Free-Living, Randomized Crossover Trial. Diabetes Care. 2016 Nov;39(11):2019-2025. Epub 2016 Sep 9.</citation>
    <PMID>27612500</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dovc K, Boughton C, Tauschmann M, Thabit H, Bally L, Allen JM, Acerini CL, Arnolds S, de Beaufort C, Bergenstal RM, Campbell F, Criego A, Dunger DB, Elleri D, Evans ML, Fröhlich-Reiterer E, Hofer S, Kapellen T, Leelarathna L, Pieber TR, Rami-Merhar B, Shah VN, Sibayan J, Wilinska ME, Hovorka R; APCam11, AP@Home, and KidsAP Consortia. Young Children Have Higher Variability of Insulin Requirements: Observations During Hybrid Closed-Loop Insulin Delivery. Diabetes Care. 2019 Jul;42(7):1344-1347. doi: 10.2337/dc18-2625. Epub 2019 May 21.</citation>
    <PMID>31221700</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Musolino G, Dovc K, Boughton CK, Tauschmann M, Allen JM, Nagl K, Fritsch M, Yong J, Metcalfe E, Schaeffer D, Fichelle M, Schierloh U, Thiele AG, Abt D, Kojzar H, Mader JK, Slegtenhorst S, Ashcroft N, Wilinska ME, Sibayan J, Cohen N, Kollman C, Hofer SE, Fröhlich-Reiterer E, Kapellen TM, Acerini CL, de Beaufort C, Campbell F, Rami-Merhar B, Hovorka R; Kidsap Consortium. Reduced burden of diabetes and improved quality of life: Experiences from unrestricted day-and-night hybrid closed-loop use in very young children with type 1 diabetes. Pediatr Diabetes. 2019 Sep;20(6):794-799. doi: 10.1111/pedi.12872. Epub 2019 Jun 13.</citation>
    <PMID>31140654</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 18, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Cambridge</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr Roman Hovorka</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Study Director</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Faster insulin aspart</keyword>
  <keyword>Closed loop insulin delivery</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Insulin Aspart</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Insulin, Long-Acting</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Insulin degludec, insulin aspart drug combination</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Study protocol, statistical analysis plan and fully anonymised individual participant data that underlie the results reported in the manuscript will be available 6 months following publication and ending 36 months following manuscript publication to investigators whose proposed use of the data has been approved by an independent review committee identified for this purpose, to achieve aims in the approved proposal. Proposals should be directed to rh347@cam.ac.uk and may be submitted up to 36 months following article publication. To gain access, data requestors will need to sign a data access agreement.&#xD;
Fully anonymised data may be shared with third parties (EU or non-EU based) for the purposes of advancing management and treatment of diabetes.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Study protocol, statistical analysis plan and fully anonymised individual participant data that underlie the results reported in the manuscript will be available 6 months following publication and ending 36 months following manuscript publication to investigators whose proposed use of the data has been approved by an independent review committee identified for this purpose, to achieve aims in the approved proposal. Proposals should be directed to rh347@cam.ac.uk and may be submitted up to 36 months following article publication.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Study protocol, statistical analysis plan and fully anonymised individual participant data that underlie the results reported in the manuscript will be available 6 months following publication and ending 36 months following manuscript publication to investigators whose proposed use of the data has been approved by an independent review committee identified for this purpose, to achieve aims in the approved proposal. Proposals should be directed to rh347@cam.ac.uk and may be submitted up to 36 months following article publication.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

