<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04755205</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>210009</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>21-C-0009</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04755205</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Natural History Study of Children and Adults With Olfactory Neuroblastoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Natural History Study of Children and Adults With Olfactory Neuroblastoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Olfactory neuroblastoma (ONB) is a rare cancer. It grows from tissue in the upper part of the&#xD;
      nose cavity, related to the sense of smell and can affect a person s sense of smell.&#xD;
      Researchers want to better understand the health problems of people with ONB. This may help&#xD;
      them design better treatment and supportive care studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To better understand ONB-the course of the disease, tumor characteristics, response to&#xD;
      treatments, and management of the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People ages 3 years and older who have ONB. They must enroll in NIH studies #19-C-0016 and&#xD;
      #18-DC-0051.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with a medical history and medical record review.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants do not have to visit NIH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will give a blood sample. They will complete surveys to assess their emotional&#xD;
      and physical wellbeing and needs. Leftover tissue from biopsies and surgeries will be&#xD;
      collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will take smell tests. They will smell items and answer questions about them.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may take taste tests. They will get plastic taste strips that they will move&#xD;
      around their mouth to determine the taste.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may have a physical exam. Their performance status may be assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may give blood, saliva, urine, and nasal secretion samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may have computed tomography and/or magnetic resonance imaging scans.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may have one or more tumor biopsies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will talk to the research team about the results of their medical record/tests&#xD;
      evaluation. The team will recommend how to best manage and treat their disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may give samples and complete surveys every 12 months. Their medical records&#xD;
      will be reviewed every year. They will be monitored for the rest of their life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Olfactory neuroblastoma (ONB), also known as esthesioneuroblastoma, is a malignant tumor of&#xD;
      the nasal cavity believed to arise from the olfactory epithelium. ONB is rare, with a&#xD;
      reported incidence of 0.4 per million (approximately 300 cases per year in the United&#xD;
      States).&#xD;
&#xD;
      ONB most frequently arises in adults aged 20-60 years. Pediatric ONB is particularly rare,&#xD;
      with only small case series or multi-institutional studies reported. However, a Surveillance&#xD;
      Epidemiology and End Results (SEER) study of 47 pediatric patients with intranasal malignancy&#xD;
      reported ONB as the most frequent pediatric intranasal malignancy (28%).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to the location of ONB in the sinonasal tract and anterior skull base, the presenting&#xD;
      symptoms are often non-specific, including nasal obstruction and epistaxis, thus patients&#xD;
      often present at advanced stages. Furthermore, ONB has a propensity for local invasion and&#xD;
      relatively high rates of distant spread most commonly to the neck, lungs, and bones.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical management is adults is generally surgical with adjuvant radiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The natural history of pediatric and adult ONB is incompletely understood, and treatment&#xD;
      options for recurrent or metastatic ONB are limited. The planned natural history study as&#xD;
      part of the NCI POB Rare Tumor Patient Engagement Network (RTPEN) will allow for&#xD;
      comprehensive evaluation and recommendations to these patients while longitudinally&#xD;
      collecting clinical, epidemiologic, and biological data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To characterize the natural history of ONB including clinical presentation, family history,&#xD;
      patterns of disease progression, response to current treatment methods, disease recurrence,&#xD;
      and overall survival&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients of age &gt;= 3 years old with histologically documented ONB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects must be enrolled on NCI protocol 19-C-0016.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects must also enroll on NIDCD Protocol 18-DC-0051.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This protocol is a subprotocol to protocol 19-C-0016: &quot;Natural History and Biospecimen&#xD;
      Acquisition Study for Children and Adults with Rare Solid Tumors&quot;. After enrollment on the&#xD;
      master protocol and having evaluations detailed, patient will be enrolled on this subprotocol&#xD;
      specific for olfactory neuroblastoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will undergo a comprehensive study entry evaluation including acquisition of&#xD;
      imaging of tumor sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical histories will be documented, and patients followed throughout the course of their&#xD;
      disease, with particular attention to patterns of disease recurrence and progression,&#xD;
      response to therapies, duration of responses, and patient reported outcomes. Specimens will&#xD;
      be obtained longitudinally, when feasible, and tumor growth rates will also be assessed&#xD;
      throughout the course of the disease, when feasible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood and tumor samples may be obtained at study entry and while on study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2028</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterize the natural history of ONB</measure>
    <time_frame>duration of study</time_frame>
    <description>To characterize the natural history of ONB including clinical presentation, family history, patterns of disease progression, response to current treatment methods, disease recurrence, and overall survival.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Olfactory Neuroblastoma</condition>
  <condition>Esthesioneuroblastoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1</arm_group_label>
    <description>Subjects with confirmed olfactory neuroblastoma.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with olfactory neuroblastoma.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must be enrolled on NCI protocol 19-C-0016: &quot;Natural History and Biospecimen&#xD;
             Acquisition Study for Children and Adults with Rare Solid Tumors&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must also enroll on NCI Protocol 18-DC-0051: &quot;Biospecimen Procurement for&#xD;
             NIDCD Clinical Protocols&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with histologically documented olfactory neuroblastoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;= 3 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability of subject to understand and the willingness to sign a written consent&#xD;
             document&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pregnant women are excluded from this study because of more than minimal risk activities&#xD;
        (imaging studies with contrast, biopsies) pertaining to enrollment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Charalampos Floudas, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Marissa B Mallek, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(240) 760-7498</phone>
    <email>marissa.mallek@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact National Cancer Institute Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>888-624-1937</phone>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Nyall London, MD</last_name>
      <phone>(301) 827-6933</phone>
      <email>nyall.london@nih.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?B_2021-C-0009.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 16, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>esthesioneuroblastoma</keyword>
  <keyword>nasal cavity tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>pediatric onb</keyword>
  <keyword>adult onb</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neuroblastoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Esthesioneuroblastoma, Olfactory</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

