<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04754724</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00107782</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04754724</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of GIMate Handheld Hydrogen Breath Monitor for Diagnosis of Lactose Malabsorption</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of GIMate Handheld Hydrogen Breath Monitor for Diagnosis of Lactose Malabsorption</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vivante Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Duke University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vivante Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this study is to assess the performance of the Vivante Health GIMate Breathalyzer&#xD;
      device in diagnosing lactose malabsorption.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Lactose malabsorption is a common condition due to lactase deficiency which results in&#xD;
      gastrointestinal symptoms for many which is termed lactose intolerance. Lactase is an enzyme&#xD;
      occurring in the intestinal mucosa that hydrolyzes lactose into its constituent parts,&#xD;
      galactose and glucose. The enzyme is normally present in neonates, however, for a majority of&#xD;
      individuals in the world there is an inherited and irreversible reduction in enzyme activity&#xD;
      as individuals age. Secondary lactose malabsorption can also occur when there is injury to&#xD;
      the intestinal mucosa from a reversible condition such as infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The mechanism of hydrogen detection is based on undigested lactose in the colon being&#xD;
      fermented by bacteria resulting in the production of hydrogen which is then partially&#xD;
      absorbed into the bloodstream and ultimately exhaled by the lungs via the pulmonary&#xD;
      circulation and gas exchange. Direct lactase activity can also be measured on tissue obtained&#xD;
      through jejunal biopsy via endoscopy. This approach, however, is more invasive, costly, and&#xD;
      potentially less reliable given issues relating to sampling bias&#xD;
&#xD;
      Current clinical hydrogen breath tests for diagnosis of lactose malabsorption are bulky and&#xD;
      expensive for clinical providers to use and obtain. As a result, Vivante Health is testing&#xD;
      how effective the GIMate device is in diagnosing lactose malabsorption as an alternative&#xD;
      option.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Positive percent agreement</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Negative percent agreement</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">31</enrollment>
  <condition>Lactose Intolerance</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>GIMate</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Individuals with suspected lactose intolerance who start with GIMate use first</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>H2 Check</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Individuals with suspected lactose intolerance who start with H2 Check use first</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>GIMate</intervention_name>
    <description>Use of GIMate to detect lactose malabsorption</description>
    <arm_group_label>GIMate</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>H2 Check</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>H2 Check</intervention_name>
    <description>Use of H2 Check to detect lactose malabsorption</description>
    <arm_group_label>GIMate</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>H2 Check</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy male or non-pregnant female between 18 and 55 years of age (inclusive)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able and willing to provide written consent and follow instructions to complete&#xD;
             required study procedures (including dietary restriction) and questionnaires.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Self-reported or suspected history of lactose malabsorption or lactose intolerance&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of prior gastrointestinal surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Self-reported history of any chronic gastrointestinal disease (examples include&#xD;
             gastroesophageal reflux disease, celiac disease, Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis,&#xD;
             pancreatitis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Self-reported history of endocrine or metabolic disease that may impact&#xD;
             gastrointestinal or colonic function (examples include hyper/hypothyroidism, diabetes,&#xD;
             etc)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Clinically significant cardiovascular, respiratory, renal, hepatic, hematologic,&#xD;
             neurologic or psychiatric disease for which chronic therapy (prescription or non-&#xD;
             prescription is required)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Self-reported history of allergic reaction to any drug or drug component&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Antibiotic use within 28 days of lactose malabsorption test&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Use of non-antibiotic prescription or OTC products (dietary or digestive supplements&#xD;
             and laxatives) within 14 days of testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Self-reported use of nicotine-containing products or chronic secondhand smoke exposure&#xD;
             within 14 days of testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Any other condition which in the Investigator's opinion may adversely affect the&#xD;
             participant's ability to complete the study or its measures or which may pose&#xD;
             significant risk to the participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Consumption of food after midnight on day of testing (within 12 hours) of testing or&#xD;
             consumption of non-water beverage after midnight (or less than 8 hours) prior to&#xD;
             testing.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27517</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Montalto M, Curigliano V, Santoro L, Vastola M, Cammarota G, Manna R, Gasbarrini A, Gasbarrini G. Management and treatment of lactose malabsorption. World J Gastroenterol. 2006 Jan 14;12(2):187-91. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16482616</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gilat T, Russo S, Gelman-Malachi E, Aldor TA. Lactase in man: a nonadaptable enzyme. Gastroenterology. 1972 Jun;62(6):1125-7.</citation>
    <PMID>5068338</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wang Y, Harvey CB, Hollox EJ, Phillips AD, Poulter M, Clay P, Walker-Smith JA, Swallow DM. The genetically programmed down-regulation of lactase in children. Gastroenterology. 1998 Jun;114(6):1230-6.</citation>
    <PMID>9609760</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Labayen I, Forga L, González A, Lenoir-Wijnkoop I, Nutr R, Martínez JA. Relationship between lactose digestion, gastrointestinal transit time and symptoms in lactose malabsorbers after dairy consumption. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2001 Apr;15(4):543-9.</citation>
    <PMID>11284784</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shaw AD, Davies GJ. Lactose intolerance: problems in diagnosis and treatment. J Clin Gastroenterol. 1999 Apr;28(3):208-16. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>10192605</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rezaie A, Buresi M, Lembo A, Lin H, McCallum R, Rao S, Schmulson M, Valdovinos M, Zakko S, Pimentel M. Hydrogen and Methane-Based Breath Testing in Gastrointestinal Disorders: The North American Consensus. Am J Gastroenterol. 2017 May;112(5):775-784. doi: 10.1038/ajg.2017.46. Epub 2017 Mar 21.</citation>
    <PMID>28323273</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Peuhkuri K, Poussa T, Korpela R. Comparison of a portable breath hydrogen analyser (Micro H2) with a Quintron MicroLyzer in measuring lactose maldigestion, and the evaluation of a Micro H2 for diagnosing hypolactasia. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 1998 May;58(3):217-24.</citation>
    <PMID>9670345</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malabsorption Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lactose Intolerance</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

