<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04755465</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-16/10</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04755465</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of NMES Training in Patients With Hematological Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of NMES Training on Muscle Strength in Hematological Cancer Patients With Steroid Induced Myopathy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Acibadem University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Medipol University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Acibadem University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Physical activity levels of adult hematologic cancer patients are very low. The resulting&#xD;
      physical inactivity causes fatigue, muscle loss and deterioration in physical performance&#xD;
      values. However, physical exercise programs still play a minor role in the treatment concepts&#xD;
      of hematological malignancies. In addition, there are no reliable data in the literature&#xD;
      regarding risk factors, feasibility and exercise results in individuals with hematological&#xD;
      malignancies. Although it is known that the use of corticosteroids, which are among the drugs&#xD;
      given during chemotherapy, causes steroid myopathy, there are no physical exercise programs&#xD;
      performed with this patient group in the literature. In our study, we aimed to evaluate the&#xD;
      effect of NMES training on muscle strength in hematological cancer patients who developed&#xD;
      steroid myopathy during chemotherapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Although people with hematological malignancies have to endure long stages of treatment and&#xD;
      inactivity that are known to reduce their physical performance levels, it is still common&#xD;
      practice to rest and avoid intense exercise. Although physical activity and exercise are&#xD;
      important approaches in many diseases, their effects on cancer have been studied recently.&#xD;
      There are still not enough studies in this area and it is not widely used. In recent studies,&#xD;
      it is thought that exercise may benefit the symptoms that develop due to treatment in cancer&#xD;
      patients. Even in the presence of severe myopathy and fatigue, skeletal muscle provides great&#xD;
      adaptation when there is an appropriate exercise stimulus. In addition, exercise can increase&#xD;
      immune functions, so it is thought that exercise practices in hematological cancer patients&#xD;
      can specifically improve cellular functions such as microbial phagocytosis, T-cell&#xD;
      proliferation, vaccine response, and killing tumor cells. There are various studies and&#xD;
      approaches that try to create a different strategy and include physical exercise in the&#xD;
      treatment strategy of hematological malignancies. These exercise programs generally include&#xD;
      aerobics, flexibility and resistance training methods. The necessity of developing&#xD;
      alternative methods to exercise is emphasized in the literature due to the development of&#xD;
      complications that affect participation in basic exercise such as walking. Neuromuscular&#xD;
      electrical stimulation (NMES) has proven efficacy in improving muscle strength in a variety&#xD;
      of populations. NMES training also has applicability for the cancer population to prevent&#xD;
      treatment-related complications and improve health-related quality of life. However, there is&#xD;
      still no high-level evidence to support the administration of NMES in cancer patients. It is&#xD;
      known that the use of corticosteroids, which are among the drugs given during chemotherapy&#xD;
      applications, causes steroid myopathy. In our study, we aimed to evaluate the effect of NMES&#xD;
      applications on muscle strength in hematological cancer patients who developed steroid&#xD;
      myopathy during chemotherapy. In addition, we aimed to evaluate the effect of NMES training&#xD;
      on fatigue, mobility and quality of life in hematological cancer patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 8, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 8, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Muscle Strength Evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline Muscle Strength at 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Participants' muscle strength measurements will be made using a digital hand dynamometer (J Tech Commander Muscle Tester). The patients will be seated in the appropriate position and the dynamometer will be placed in the dominant leg to give resistance to the muscle to be evaluated. While patients press the dynamometer as hard as possible for three seconds, the evaluator will give resistance to prevent any movement to provide an isometric contraction. Following the familiarization test, patients will perform three trials with standardized verbal encouragement and the highest strength (kilogram, kg) sustained for over half a second will be recorded.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Muscle Strength Evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline Functional Muscle Strength at 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Lower extremity functional strength will be evaluated using the &quot;Sit and Stand for 30 sec&quot; test. The patient will be instructed to stand up and sit back and forth from a standardized chair as quickly as possible in 30 seconds without using his arms. Participants will be able to use their hands to help them stand as needed, and standardized verbal encouragement will be provided to continue sitting and standing throughout the test.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anthropometric Assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Immediately after completion of 4 weeks training programme</time_frame>
    <description>Thigh circumference measurement will be made from the middle of the thigh over the Quadriceps muscle. By marking the inguinal region and the proximal part of the patella, the midpoint between the two points will be found. All measurements will be made on the right side and by the same physiotherapist.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mobility Assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Immediately after completion of 4 weeks training programme</time_frame>
    <description>&quot;Timed Up-Go Test&quot; will be applied before and after treatment to evaluate the patient's mobility and functional exercise capacity. The time taken to complete the task is strongly correlated with the level of functional mobility. In other words, the longer the person completes the task, the more dependent he is on daily life activities.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Brief Fatigue Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Immediately after completion of 4 weeks training programme</time_frame>
    <description>The Brief Fatigue Scale will be used to assess cancer-related fatigue in our study. This scale is one of the standard tests used to evaluate fatigue in cancer patients. Evaluates the level of fatigue in the last 24 hours and the effect of fatigue on daily activities (general activity, mood, walking ability, work life, relationships with other people, joy of life)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>European Cancer Research and Treatment Organization Quality of Life Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Immediately after completion of 4 weeks training programme</time_frame>
    <description>The assessment of quality of life will be carried out using the European Cancer Research and Treatment Organization Quality of Life Questionnaire Version 3.0. The scale consists of three subsections: general health status scale, functional scale, and symptom scale, and includes a total of 30 questions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Immediately after completion of 4 weeks training programme</time_frame>
    <description>The severity of myopathy will be determined according to the Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status Scale based on the degree of muscle weakness found in the Cancer Therapy Assessment Program Common Toxicity Criteria, and patients with an ECOG performance status of 1-3 will be treated.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Hematologic Malignancy</condition>
  <condition>Steroid Myopathy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Conventional Exercise Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The treatment program was designed by reviewing the exercise principles and the literature on physical activity and hematologic cancer patients recommended by the American College of Sports Medicine. Patients will be treated for 3 days / week for 4 weeks. Each session was planned to last 40 minutes. The exercise program will be applied in the patient's own room under the supervision of a physiotherapist. Depending on the health condition of the patient, the exercise will be postponed or canceled for the next day. Conventional exercise program includes active movements of upper and lower extremities, stretching exercises and resistance exercises for lower extremities.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NMES Training Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In addition to conventional exercises, NMES will be applied to the quadriceps muscles in both legs of the patients in this group. The application will be made with a portable device using disposable electrodes. One of the electrodes will be placed proximally, that is, at the midpoint of the quadriceps muscle, while the second electrode will be placed on the distal part. Stimulation intensity will be adjusted individually for each limb to achieve the maximum tolerated intensity. In order to ensure that the patients get used to the device, low-intensity current with a frequency range of 2-15 Hz will be used initially. Afterwards, the treatment program will continue with a high frequency current with a frequency range of 20-60 Hz. The duration of treatment will likewise be increased as adaptation is made to the patient.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Neuromuscular Electrical Stimulation</intervention_name>
    <description>Neuromuscular Electrical Stimulation (NMES) is based on the principle of creating a contraction by stimulating the nerve fibers innervating the related muscle in the healthy muscle and the muscle fibers in the denervated muscle with electrical current. The electric currents used in stimulation of muscles and nerves perform this function by changing the electrical potential of cell membranes.&#xD;
It is contraindicated in pregnancy, presence of pacemaker, severe heart disease, epilepsy, fracture, dementia and impaired consciousness. We prevent contraindicated situations by excluding volunteer participants with these characteristics.</description>
    <arm_group_label>NMES Training Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Structured Exercise</intervention_name>
    <description>Warm-up exercise, main training program and cool down exercise. Main training consists of resistance exercises to be applied with resistance bands of different resistance or with the patient's own body weight. Our prescribed training protocol includes 4-6 different exercises for each limb (bench press with resistance band, upper extremity proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation exercises, biceps/triceps curl, leg press, knee extension, 4-way hip motion, mini squat). Intensity, sets and number of repetitions will be adapted to a target score between 12 and 14 using the Borg scale. It will be applied as low intensity, long-term passive stretching exercises to the pectoral, hamstring and gastrocsoleus muscle groups. Patients will perform 1-2 sets of 8-10 repetitions of each resistance exercise determined by their level of fatigue. Resistance will be increased every three visits. If the patient complains of excessive fatigue, the resistance will be reduced to the previous level.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Conventional Exercise Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>NMES Training Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed with hematological cancer,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥ 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG Performance Status to be between 1-3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin; 8-10gr / dl and over&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving platelet support related to thrombocytopenia and/or having a platelet value&#xD;
             of 20.000 mm3 or more&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Leukocyte (WBC) count being 3000 μL and above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Giving written consent to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Comorbidities that cause fatigue (eg multiple sclerosis, Parkinson's disease, heart&#xD;
             failure)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of previously diagnosed heart disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Using a pacemaker&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having blood values that prevent him from exercising (Hemoglobin; being 8 g / dl and&#xD;
             below; thrombocyte value being 20,000 mm3 and below-not receiving thrombocytopenia&#xD;
             treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Rapid deterioration of the general condition (sudden uncontrolled weight loss,&#xD;
             confused consciousness, high C reactive protein (CRP) values)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Brain metastasis or femoral bone metastasis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having a dementia or psychotic condition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being depressed and /or taking medication to treat depression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of epilepsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of neuropathy accompanying myopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having sensory defects in NMES application area&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Denying NMES application&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy status in female patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to understand written and spoken Turkish&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ant Uzay, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Acibadem Healthcare Group</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Fatma Mutluay, Prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Medipol University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elif Es Safran, MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Acibadem University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Elif Es Safran, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>+905312758849</phone>
    <email>elif.bayraktar@acibadem.edu.tr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Acibadem University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <zip>34752</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Elif Es Safran, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>+905312758849</phone>
      <email>elif.bayraktar@acibadem.edu.tr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Elif Es Safran, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Fatma Mutluay, Prof</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ant Uzay, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 15, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Acibadem University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Elif Esma Safran</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Lecturer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hematology</keyword>
  <keyword>Therapeutic Electrical Stimulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Exercise Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Steroid Myopathy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hematologic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Muscular Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>After completion of study</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

