<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04759274</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STU 2020-1124</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04759274</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Diuretic Tuner Clinical Decision Support</brief_title>
  <official_title>Diuretic Tuner Clinical Decision Support Mobile Device Application for Diuretic Titration in Hypervolemic States</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This purpose of this study is to determine the effectiveness of a mobile phone application in&#xD;
      helping to control body swelling in patients with kidney problems. The application will help&#xD;
      in the day to day adjustments in diuretic medication dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in this study will have an application loaded on to their mobile phone by the&#xD;
      study team and be taught how to use it over a 2 hour visit. Participants will need to check&#xD;
      their blood pressure and weight daily and enter this information into the mobile phone&#xD;
      application every day. Participants will need to follow daily instructions in their&#xD;
      medication dosing provided by the application. There will be periodic blood testing. This&#xD;
      will happen at 2 weeks, 90 days, and up to 4 other times if necessary. At the end of the&#xD;
      study there is a 2 hour study visit during which participants will answer a survey. The total&#xD;
      length of the study is 90 days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Population: 30 subjects with signs of hypervolemia and either nephrotic syndrome or&#xD;
      chronic kidney disease 4 to 5.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Intervention: This is a nonrandomized, uncontrolled trial. The Diuretic Tuner mobile&#xD;
      device application will be deployed in the care of hypervolemic subjects as defined in the&#xD;
      study population. The Diuretic Tuner will integrate each subject's estimated dry weight and&#xD;
      starting diuretic dose (both defined by healthcare provider) with daily weights and blood&#xD;
      pressures to provide individualized guidance to the subject in day-to-day adjustments to his&#xD;
      or her diuretic regimen. In addition, the application will generate a diary of daily weights,&#xD;
      blood pressures, fluid intake, and medication compliance. There will be no control arm as&#xD;
      this first phase is to test feasibility/safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Outcome Measures: The primary outcomes of interest will focus on the achievement of the&#xD;
      provider-defined estimated dry weight (both the time to achieving this target as well as the&#xD;
      subsequent stability in weights around this target). Secondary outcomes of interest include&#xD;
      safety metrics (3-month hospitalization rates, rates of hypokalemia, and rates of acute&#xD;
      kidney injury) and tool usability (assessed through surveys evaluating ease of comprehension&#xD;
      and satisfaction).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean time to the attainment of dry weight</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Mean time in days to the attainment of the provider-specified estimated dry weight</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>90 day weight variability</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>90 day weight variability around the target dry weight, as assessed by standard deviation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Composite rate of hospitalization, hypokalemia, or acute renal insufficiency</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>90 day adverse event rate for the composite outcome including hospitalization for volume-related complications (hypervolemia, hypovolemia, or electrolyte disturbance), hypokalemia (serum potassium &lt; 3.5 mmol/L), or acute renal insufficiency (serum creatinine ≥ 2 times baseline or &gt; 6 mg/dL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Diuretic Tuner usability assessed by user survey</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Diuretic tuner usability (measured by Likert scale survey administered to each subject at the end of 90 days)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Edema</condition>
  <condition>Hypervolemia</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Kidney Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Nephrotic Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Diuretic Tuner users</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The Diuretic Tuner is a mobile device application that integrates a patient's estimated dry weight and starting diuretic dose (both defined by a healthcare provider) with daily weights and blood pressures to provide individualized guidance to the patient in day-to-day adjustments to his or her diuretic regimen. In addition, the application generates a diary of daily weights, blood pressures, fluid intake, and medication compliance.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Diuretic Tuner</intervention_name>
    <description>Mobile device application for diuretic dose titration</description>
    <arm_group_label>Diuretic Tuner users</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of nephrotic range proteinuria (&gt; 3 g/d proteinuria by 24hr urine&#xD;
             protein, 24hr urine albumin, spot urine protein/creatinine ratio, or spot urine&#xD;
             albumin/creatinine ratio) or stage 4 or 5 chronic kidney disease (estimated glomerular&#xD;
             filtration rate &lt; 30 mL/min/1.73 m2 by Modification of Diet in Renal Disease equation)&#xD;
             PLUS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical signs of hypervolemia present (lower extremity edema, ascites, or pleural&#xD;
             effusions) with an estimated dry weight (defined as edema-free weight without&#xD;
             orthostatic hypotension) 5 lbs less than enrollment body weight&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight &lt; 100 lbs or &gt; 300 lbs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Autonomic insufficiency resulting in orthostatic hypotension at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypokalemia at enrollment (defined as serum potassium &lt; 3.5 mmol/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate to severe hyponatremia at enrollment (defined as serum sodium &lt; 130 mmol/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine &gt; 6 mg/dL or &gt; 1.5 times baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are unable or unwilling to measure their home blood pressures and weights&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients without a working phone number and smart phone device&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expectation that the patient will require dialysis initiation within &lt; 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected lifespan of &lt; 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of a medical condition that would interfere with effectively using the&#xD;
             Diuretic Tuner (dementia, illiteracy, or blindness)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prisoners&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kamalanathan K Sambandam, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>214-645-6190</phone>
    <email>ksambandam@utsouthwestern.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas Southwestern</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75390</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kamalanathan K Sambandam</last_name>
      <phone>469-441-7181</phone>
      <email>ksambandam@utsouthwestern.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 18, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kamalanathan Sambandam</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nephrotic Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nephrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diuretics</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

