<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04750057</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D3461R00027</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04750057</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Anifrolumab Early Access Program</brief_title>
  <acronym>AMANA</acronym>
  <official_title>An Early Access Program for Anifrolumab Treatment in Adult Patients With Active Systemic Lupus Erythematosus - AMANA</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Clinigen, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>AstraZeneca</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To provide early access (ie, before marketing authorisation) to anifrolumab 300 mg IV Q4W&#xD;
      while receiving standard therapy in adult patients with moderate-to-severe active SLE&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a multi-centre, open-label, early access program (EAP) designed to provide treatment&#xD;
      access to intravenous (IV) treatment regimen of 300 mg anifrolumab (MEDI-546) every 4 weeks&#xD;
      (Q4W) for eligible patients with moderate-to-severe active SLE while receiving standard&#xD;
      therapy. Anifrolumab will be provided free of charge to the patients entering this&#xD;
      program.This global EAP will be opened in a sequential fashion, country by country, based on&#xD;
      the requesting Treating Physician(s) and local regulations&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>No longer available</overall_status>
  <study_type>Expanded Access</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <expanded_access_info>
    <expanded_access_type_treatment>Yes</expanded_access_type_treatment>
  </expanded_access_info>
  <condition>Systemic Lupus Erythematosus</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Anifrolumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Multi-centre, open-label, early access program (EAP) designed to provide access to intravenous (IV) treatment regimen of 300 mg anifrolumab (MEDI-546) every 4 weeks (Q4W) for eligible patients with moderate-to-severe active SLE while receiving standard therapy.</description>
    <other_name>MEDI-546, D3461</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Population A:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Received anifrolumab or placebo in the long-term extension study, D3461C00009, and are&#xD;
             within 12 weeks of Week 164 (follow-up visit 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Provided written informed consent before any program-related procedures are performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Adequate peripheral venous access.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Females of childbearing potential must use two effective methods of avoiding&#xD;
             pregnancy, only one of which is a barrier method, from screening until 12 weeks after&#xD;
             final dose of anifrolumab, unless the patient is surgically sterile (eg, bilateral&#xD;
             oophorectomy or complete hysterectomy), has a sterile male partner, is at least 1 year&#xD;
             ostmenopausal, or practises sustained abstinence consistent with the patient's&#xD;
             customary lifestyle. Postmenopausal is defined as at least 1 year since last menses&#xD;
             and the patient has an elevated follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) level greater than&#xD;
             the local laboratory value of post-menopausal at screening - as detailed in Section&#xD;
             5.4.3.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. All males (sterilised or non-sterilised) who are sexually active must use a condom&#xD;
             (with spermicide where commercially available) from Day 1 (first dose of anifrolumab)&#xD;
             until at least 12 weeks after receiving the final dose of anifrolumab. It is strongly&#xD;
             recommended that the female partner of a male patient also uses an effective method of&#xD;
             contraception (other than a barrier method) throughout this period. Male patients must&#xD;
             not donate sperm while taking part in the EAP and for 12 weeks after their last dose&#xD;
             of anifrolumab - see Section 5.4.3 for further details.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Females with an intact cervix must have a documented normal Pap smear without&#xD;
             documented malignancy (eg, no signs of cervical intraepithelial neoplasia [CIN] grade&#xD;
             III, carcinoma in situ [CIS] or adenocarcinoma in situ [AIS]) within 2 years of&#xD;
             entering this EAP and receiving anifrolumab. Any abnormal Pap smear result documented&#xD;
             within 2 years before receiving anifrolumab must be repeated to confirm patient&#xD;
             eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. COVID-19: Any negative polymerase chain reaction (PCR) test result (central&#xD;
             laboratory) at screening and no known or suspected COVID-19 exposure within 2 weeks&#xD;
             prior to screening. If there is a known or suspected exposure, a patient must be&#xD;
             negative upon retest obtained after 2 weeks and must remain asymptomatic for inclusion&#xD;
             in the study. Note: Patients positive at screening may be re-screened after 3 months&#xD;
             provided there has been no development of severe COVID-19 disease or sequalae.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Discontinued anifrolumab or placebo, for any reason including an AE, before completing&#xD;
             Year 3 of the treatment period for study 09 or study 1145.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Major medical event, such as cerebrovascular accident (CVA), myocardial infarction&#xD;
             (MI), malignancy, opportunistic infection, suicide attempt, or that, in the opinion of&#xD;
             the Treating Physician, would interfere with patient safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any other condition that, in the opinion of the Treating Physician, would interfere&#xD;
             with patient safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Active severe or unstable neuropsychiatric SLE where, in the opinion of the Treating&#xD;
             Physician, protocol-specified standard therapy is insufficient and utilisation of a&#xD;
             more aggressive therapeutic approach, such as adding IV cyclophosphamide and/or high&#xD;
             dose IV pulse corticosteroid therapy or other treatments not permitted in the&#xD;
             protocol, is indicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Active severe SLE-driven renal disease where, in the opinion of the Treating.&#xD;
             Physician or delegate, protocol-specified standard therapy is insufficient and&#xD;
             utilisation of a more aggressive therapeutic approach, such as adding IV&#xD;
             cyclophosphamide and/or high dose IV pulse corticosteroid therapy or other treatments&#xD;
             not permitted in the protocol, is indicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Is receiving any of the following medications:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Azathioprine &gt; 200 mg/day&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Mycophenolate mofetil &gt; 2 g/day or mycophenolic acid &gt; 1.44 g/day&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Oral, subcutaneous (SC), or intramuscular (IM) methotrexate &gt; 25 mg/week&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Oral prednisone &gt; 40 mg/day (or prednisone equivalent - see Appendix E1)&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Mizoribine &gt; 150 mg/day&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Biologics eg, belimumab, rituximab&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Received any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Live or attenuated vaccine within 8 weeks before signing the ICF. Note:&#xD;
                  administration of inactivated vaccines is acceptable - the Sponsor recommends&#xD;
                  that Treating Physicians ensure all patients are up to date on required&#xD;
                  vaccinations, including influenza (inactivated/recombinant) before EAP entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Restricted medications listed in Appendix D if the washout period is not met.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Received any investigational product (small molecule or biologic agent) within 4 weeks&#xD;
             or 5 half-lives (whichever is greater) before signing the ICF (see Appendix D).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Received any commercially available biologic agent within 5 half-lives before signing&#xD;
             ICF (see Appendix D).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Received B-cell-depleting therapy (including, but not limited to: ocrelizumab,&#xD;
             ofatumumab, atacicept, obinutuzumab, rituximab) within 26 weeks before signing the&#xD;
             ICF; within 40 weeks for atacicept (see Appendix D) or if therapy was administered 26&#xD;
             weeks or more ago (40 weeks for atacicept), absolute B-cell count should not be less&#xD;
             than the lower limit of normal (LLN) or baseline (whichever is lower) before receipt&#xD;
             of B-cell-depleting therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Positive hepatitis B, hepatitis C or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Known history of allergy or reaction to any component of anifrolumab or history of&#xD;
             anaphylaxis to any human gamma globulin therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. COVID-19: Any history of severe COVID-19 infection (e.g. requiring hospitalisation,&#xD;
             intensive care unit (ICU) care or assisted ventilation) or any prior COVID-19&#xD;
             infection with unresolved sequelae. Any acute COVID-19 infection (laboratory confirmed&#xD;
             or suspected based on clinical symptoms) within the last 3 months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Population B:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who have:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Completed study D3461C0009 safety follow-up period (Week 164), and more than 12&#xD;
                  weeks since Week 164 (safety follow-up visit 2); OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Completed safety follow-up period in phase 2 study CD1145; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Not previously taken part in any anifrolumab clinical study and have attempted&#xD;
                  the standard therapeutic options at the maximum tolerated dose (see inclusion&#xD;
                  criterion 2); AND&#xD;
&#xD;
             i. Are not eligible for enrollment in an anifrolumab clinical study, AND ii. Have&#xD;
             moderate to severe SLE (no lupus nephritis or severe CNS lupus)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Attempted standard therapies, such as an antimalarial, therapeutic doses of oral&#xD;
             corticosteroids, minimum of 2 immunosuppressants and biologics (belimumab or&#xD;
             rituximab, if available in their country) from the following therapeutic options at&#xD;
             the maximum tolerated dose:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Azathioprine ≤ 200 mg/day&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Antimalarial (eg, chloroquine, hydroxychloroquine, quinacrine)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Mycophenolate mofetil ≤ 2 g/day or mycophenolic acid ≤ 1.44 g/day&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Oral, SC, or IM methotrexate ≤ 25 mg/week&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Mizoribine ≤ 150 mg/day (Japan only)&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Oral prednisone or equivalent (see Appendix E1) ≤ 40 mg/day&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Biologics (eg, belimumab, rituximab).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Provided written informed consent before any program-related procedures are performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Adequate peripheral venous access.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Females of childbearing potential must use two effective methods of avoiding&#xD;
             pregnancy, only one of which is a barrier method, from screening until 12 weeks after&#xD;
             final dose of anifrolumab, unless the patient is surgically sterile (eg, bilateral&#xD;
             oophorectomy or complete hysterectomy), has a sterile male partner, is at least 1-year&#xD;
             postmenopausal, or practises sustained abstinence consistent with the patient's&#xD;
             customary lifestyle. Postmenopausal is defined as at least 1 year since last menses&#xD;
             and the patient has an elevated FSH level greater than the local laboratory value of&#xD;
             postmenopausal at screening - as detailed in Section 5.4.3.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. All males (sterilised or non-sterilised) who are sexually active must use a condom&#xD;
             (with spermicide where commercially available) from Day 1 (first dose of anifrolumab)&#xD;
             until at least 12 weeks after receiving the final dose of anifrolumab. It is strongly&#xD;
             recommended that the female partner of a male patient also uses an effective method of&#xD;
             contraception (see Section 5.4.3) (other than a barrier method) throughout this&#xD;
             period. Male patients must not donate sperm while taking part in the EAP and for 12&#xD;
             weeks after their last dose of anifrolumab - see Section 5.4.3 for further details.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Females with an intact cervix must have a documented normal Pap smear without&#xD;
             documented malignancy (eg, no signs of CIN grade III, CIS or AIS) within 2 years of&#xD;
             entering this EAP and receiving anifrolumab. Any abnormal Pap smear result documented&#xD;
             within 2 years before receiving anifrolumb must be repeated to confirm patient&#xD;
             eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. COVID-19: Any negative PCR test result (central laboratory) at screening and no known&#xD;
             or suspected COVID-19 exposure within 2 weeks prior to screening. If there is a known&#xD;
             or suspected exposure, a patient must be negative upon retest obtained after 2 weeks&#xD;
             and must remain asymptomatic for inclusion in the program. Note: Patients positive at&#xD;
             screening may be re-screened after 3 months provided there has been no development of&#xD;
             severe COVID-19 disease or sequalae.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Discontinued anifrolumab or placebo before completing Year 3 of the treatment period&#xD;
             for study D3461C0009 or study CD1145.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Major medical event, such as CVA, MI, malignancy, opportunistic infection, suicide&#xD;
             attempt, or that, in the opinion of the Treating Physician, would interfere with&#xD;
             patient safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any condition that, in the opinion of the Treating Physician, would interfere with&#xD;
             patient safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Active severe or unstable neuropsychiatric SLE where, in the opinion of the Treating&#xD;
             Physician, protocol-specified standard therapy is insufficient and utilisation of a&#xD;
             more aggressive therapeutic approach, such as adding IV cyclophosphamide and/or&#xD;
             high-dose IV pulse corticosteroid therapy or other treatments not permitted in the&#xD;
             protocol, is indicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Active severe SLE-driven renal disease where, in the opinion of the Treating Physician&#xD;
             or delegate, protocol-specified standard therapy is insufficient and utilisation of a&#xD;
             more aggressive therapeutic approach, such as adding IV cyclophosphamide and/or&#xD;
             high-dose IV pulse corticosteroid therapy or other treatments not permitted in the&#xD;
             protocol, is indicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Is receiving any of the following medications:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Azathioprine &gt; 200 mg/day&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Mycophenolate mofetil &gt; 2 g/day or mycophenolic acid &gt; 1.44 g/day&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Oral, SC, or IM methotrexate &gt; 25 mg/week&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Oral prednisone &gt; 40 mg/day (or prednisone equivalent - see Appendix E1)&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Mizoribine &gt; 150 mg/day&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Biologics eg, belimumab, rituximab&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Received any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Live or attenuated vaccine within 8 weeks before signing the ICF. Note:&#xD;
                  administration of inactivated vaccines is acceptable - the Sponsor recommends&#xD;
                  that Treating Physicians ensure all patients are up to date on required&#xD;
                  vaccinations, including influenza (inactivated/recombinant) before EAP entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Restricted medications listed in Appendix D if the washout period is not met.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Received any investigational product (small molecule or biologic agent) within 4 weeks&#xD;
             or 5 half-lives (whichever is greater) before signing the ICF (see Appendix D).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Received any commercially available biologic agent within 5 half-lives before signing&#xD;
             ICF (see Appendix D).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Received B-cell-depleting therapy (including, but not limited to: ocrelizumab,&#xD;
             ofatumumab, atacicept, obinutuzumab, rituximab) within 26 weeks before signing the&#xD;
             ICF; within 40 weeks for atacicept (see Appendix D) or if therapy was administered 26&#xD;
             weeks or more ago (40 weeks for atacicept), absolute B-cell count should not be less&#xD;
             than the LLN or baseline (whichever is lower) before receipt of B-cell-depleting&#xD;
             therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Positive hepatitis B, hepatitis C or HIV.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Known history of allergy or reaction to any component of anifrolumab or history of&#xD;
             anaphylaxis to any human gamma globulin therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. COVID-19: Any history of severe COVID-19 infection (e.g. requiring hospitalisation,&#xD;
             ICU care or assisted ventilation) or any prior COVID-19 infection with unresolved&#xD;
             sequelae. Any acute COVID-19 infection (laboratory confirmed or suspected based on&#xD;
             clinical symptoms) within the last 3 months prior to screening.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

