<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01483170</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DNDiFEX003</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01483170</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Multiple Dose Study to Evaluate Security, Tolerance and Pharmacokinetic of Fexinidazole (Drug Candidate for Human African Trypanosomiasis) Administered With a Loading Dose and With Food</brief_title>
  <official_title>Double-blind, Placebo Controlled, Randomized Multiple Ascending Dose Study in Fed Conditions for Ten Days Dosing Regimen With a Loading Dose to Evaluate the Safety, the Tolerability and the Pharmacokinetics of Oral Fexinidazole in 36 Healthy Male Sub-Saharan Volunteers.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Drugs for Neglected Diseases</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Drugs for Neglected Diseases</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This trial will study the tolerability and pharmacokinetic of fexinidazole using two&#xD;
      different dosage regimen of repeated administrations. The drug is administered to human&#xD;
      healthy volunteers of sub-saharan origin together with food, once a day during 10 days, with&#xD;
      a loading dose during 4 days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objectives: To assess safety and tolerability of two different fexinidazole dosing&#xD;
      regimen, for 10 days repeated administration under fed conditions in healthy male sub-Saharan&#xD;
      volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives: To validate the exposure to fexinidazole, M1 and M2 after different&#xD;
      dosing regimens in fed conditions for 10 days in order to evaluate the more appropriate&#xD;
      administration regimen for the pivotal phase II/III study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology/Study Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two dose regimens consisting of repeated oral ascending dose (OAD) dosing in fed condition&#xD;
      with two different ascending loading doses for 4 days followed by the same dose for 6 days&#xD;
      will be evaluated. The study will be conducted in double-blind conditions for both the&#xD;
      clinical and bioanalytical parts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For each dosing regimen, subjects will reside at the clinical unit from the evening of Day -2&#xD;
      to the afternoon of Day 17 including an 8 days safety follow up (168 h post last dose).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    poor tolerability at highest dose&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>September 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Trypanosomiasis, African</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fexinidazole</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo fexinidazole</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tablets Fexinidazole</intervention_name>
    <description>Administration of 3 or 4 tablets of 600mg per day during 4 days (loading dose) then administration of 2 tablets of 600mg for 6 days Dosing in fed condition.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Fexinidazole</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo fexinidazole</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo fexinidazole</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male healthy volunteers 18 to 45 years of age,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All subjects to be of sub-Saharan African origins with both parents of sub-Saharan&#xD;
             African origins too,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male subjects with a body mass index (BMI) calculated as weight in kg/(height in m)2&#xD;
             from 18 to 28 kg/m2 inclusive at screening,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to communicate well with the Investigator and research staff and to comply with&#xD;
             the requirements of the entire study,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provision of written informed consent to participate as shown by a signature on the&#xD;
             volunteer consent form,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Light smokers (less than 10 cigarettes per day) or subjects who are non-smokers. No&#xD;
             smoking (or use of smoking substitute e.g. nicotine patch) is permitted from screening&#xD;
             throughout the study,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal arterial blood pressure (BP) and pulse rate or, if abnormal, considered not&#xD;
             clinically significant by the principal Investigator. These will be measured after&#xD;
             resting for 5 min,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Registered with the French Social Security in agreement with the French law on&#xD;
             biomedical experimentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who on direct questioning and physical examination have evidence of any clinically&#xD;
             significant acute or chronic disease, including known or suspected HIV, HBV or HCV&#xD;
             infection,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With any clinically significant abnormality following review of pre-study laboratory&#xD;
             tests(ASAT, ALAT and alkaline phosphatase (ALP) must be within normal ranges), vital&#xD;
             signs, full physical examination and ECG,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who are within the exclusion period defined in the National Register for Healthy&#xD;
             Volunteers of the French Ministry of Health,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who forfeit their freedom by administrative or legal award or who were under&#xD;
             guardianship,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to give their informed consent,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who have a positive laboratory test for Hepatitis B surface antigen (HbsAg), or&#xD;
             anti-HIV 1/2 or anti-HCV antibodies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who have a history of allergy, intolerance or photosensitivity to any drug,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who have a history of serious allergy, asthma, allergic skin rash or sensitivity to&#xD;
             any drug,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who are known or suspected alcohol or drug abusers (more than 14 units of alcohol per&#xD;
             week, one unit = 8 g or about 10 mL of pure alcohol),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who drink more than 8 cups daily of beverage containing caffeine,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who have a positive laboratory test for urine drug screening (opiates,&#xD;
             cocaine,amphetamine, cannabis, benzodiazepines),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who have undergone surgery or have donated blood within 12 weeks prior to the start of&#xD;
             the study,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who have taken any prescribed or over the counter drug (including antacid drug), with&#xD;
             the exception of paracetamol (up to 3 g per day) within 2 weeks prior to the first&#xD;
             dose administration,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who have any clinical condition or prior therapy which, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             Investigator, made the subject unsuitable for the study,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who participated to any clinical trial with an investigational drug in the past 3&#xD;
             months preceding study entry.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lionel Hovsepian, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>SGS Aster</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>SGS Life Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75015</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.dndi.org</url>
    <description>Sponsor website</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.dndi.org/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/ClinicalPK_Tarral_FexinidazoleHAT_2014.pdf</url>
    <description>Publication combining results of NCT00982904 + NCT01340157</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 29, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 30, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 1, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 29, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 29, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Trypanosomiasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Trypanosomiasis, African</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

