<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00463879</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0508000458</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00463879</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Galantamine for Cognitive Deficits in Schizophrenia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Galantamine for Cognitive Deficits in Schizophrenia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Alliance for Research on Schizophrenia and Depression</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the acute effects of the nicotinic receptor&#xD;
      allosteric modulator galantamine (0, 4 and 8 mg) on neurocognitive function in schizophrenic&#xD;
      smokers (n=20) versus schizophrenic nonsmokers (n=10) in an outpatient human laboratory&#xD;
      setting.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The proposed study will entail a comprehensive evaluation of the effects of acute doses of&#xD;
      the nAChR allosteric modulator galantamine hydrochloride (0, 4 and 8 mg) on neurocognitive&#xD;
      measures in schizophrenic smokers (n=20) and schizophrenic non-smokers (n=10) in a human&#xD;
      laboratory paradigm. After training on a battery of neurocognitive assessments, all subjects&#xD;
      will be studied during three separate test weeks where they will complete the neurocognitive&#xD;
      batter at baseline, and then again after acute administration of the three doses of&#xD;
      galantamine in a counterbalanced order across subjects in each experimental group.&#xD;
      Specifically, smokers would be randomized into one of two groups: 1) those who undergo&#xD;
      overnight smoking abstinence prior to the study cognitive sessions in order to determine&#xD;
      galantamine's effects on abstinence-induced cognitive impairment, and 2) those who may smoke&#xD;
      as usual prior to the study cognitive sessions. The inclusion of nonsmokers will allow for&#xD;
      the assessment of galantamine's effects on cognitive deficits in schizophrenia independent of&#xD;
      cigarette smoking. Finally, genetic variations in key metabolic genes involved in&#xD;
      catecholamine metabolism (COMT and DBH) would be evaluated as determinants of&#xD;
      galantamine-related improvements in cognitive performance in schizophrenic smokers and&#xD;
      nonsmokers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We predict that galantamine will dose-dependently improve selected cognitive deficits&#xD;
      associated with schizophrenia (e.g., spatial working memory, sustained attention and prepulse&#xD;
      inhibition) which we have previously shown are selectively improved by cigarette smoking in&#xD;
      smokers with schizophrenia [18], and that this effect would be more pronounced in nonsmokers&#xD;
      with schizophrenia. If our results are positive, they would support the rationale for&#xD;
      controlled clinical trials using nAChR agonists like galantamine to treat selected domains of&#xD;
      cognitive dysfunction in this disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following experimental groups will be studied:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Schizophrenic Smokers under abstinence conditions (n=10)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Schizophrenic Smokers in the smoking condition. (n=10)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Schizophrenic Nonsmokers (n=10)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three acute doses of galantamine (GAL) will be tested (0, 4 and 8 mg) in all subjects during&#xD;
      three separate test sessions separated by at least 3 days, with study medication doses across&#xD;
      sequential subjects given in a randomized, counterbalanced manner.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Smokers (n=20) and nonsmokers (n=10) with schizophrenia will be recruited from the outpatient&#xD;
      division of The Connecticut Mental Health Center (CMHC) in New Haven, CT, and it's affiliated&#xD;
      satellite centers (Hispanic Clinic, West Haven Mental Health Center, and Yale Behavioral&#xD;
      Mental Health Center).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Screening Procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All potential subjects would meet with study staff over 2-3 intake and evaluation sessions to&#xD;
      determine study eligibility, which would typically take place within 4 weeks of study&#xD;
      enrollment. A description of the evaluation measures is given below:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The screening evaluation will include completion of informed consent forms, a urine&#xD;
      toxicology screen to screen for recent use of illegal substances, a urine pregnancy test for&#xD;
      female subjects, a psychiatric evaluation using the SCID for DSM-IV disorders, PANSS, AIMS,&#xD;
      Webster, Barnes, BDI, Tiffany Questionnaire for Smoking Urges (T-QSU), Minnesota Nicotine&#xD;
      Withdrawal Scale (M-NWS), Shipley Full Scale Intelligence Quotient (IQ), a blood draw for&#xD;
      plasma nicotine, plasma cotinine, as well as CBC and LFT's, and a physical examination&#xD;
      conducted by Dr. George. Subjects will be separately consented for the genetics portion of&#xD;
      the study and blood will be taken for genotyping purposes. Finally, a pre-study&#xD;
      neuropsychological testing session would be performed in order to orient and train&#xD;
      participants on the laboratory procedures. Subjects who are pregnant or planning on becoming&#xD;
      pregnant will not be eligible to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will compensate all subjects who complete the screening and evaluation process ($25.00)&#xD;
      and the neurocognitive training session ($25.00) for a total of $50.00. In addition, subjects&#xD;
      would be paid $25.00 for donating a blood sample for genotyping.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood for genotyping will be obtained for COMT and DBH polymorphisms in smokers and&#xD;
      nonsmokers in schizophrenia participating in this study. The genotyping for these studies&#xD;
      will be done in collaboration with the Psychiatric Genetics laboratory of Joseph F. Cubells,&#xD;
      M.D., Ph.D. at Emory University.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Experimental Procedures: Smokers will be tested on the cognitive battery at baseline (Day 1,&#xD;
      with periodic smoking breaks to minimize nicotine withdrawal), and then again 24 hours later&#xD;
      after overnight smoking abstinence (Day 2). Non-smokers will be tested at baseline (Day 1)&#xD;
      and again 24 hours later (Day 2). Study medications will be given as a single dose before the&#xD;
      Day 2 session which will produce ascending plasma drug levels (t= ½ 5/7 h) during the two&#xD;
      hour testing session, in a counterbalanced dosing schedule of galantamine hydrobromide (0, 4,&#xD;
      and 8 mg) within each test group. If systolic blood pressure is below 90 mm Hg, the&#xD;
      galantamine study medication will be held. Before and after each session (Day 1 and Day 2),&#xD;
      clinical ratings using the PANSS, HDRS, extrapyramidal ratings, and adverse event ratings&#xD;
      would be completed. For smokers, pre-session tobacco craving and withdrawal ratings, expired&#xD;
      breath carbon monoxide, and plasma cotinine and nicotine levels would be obtained. Smokers&#xD;
      randomized to the abstinence condition would receive $150.00 for successful completion of&#xD;
      each of the subsequent three test session procedures requiring overnight abstinence ($50.00&#xD;
      for successful abstinence, and $100.00 for subsequent testing session completion). Smokers&#xD;
      randomized to the non-abstinence condition would be also receiving $150.00 for successful&#xD;
      completion of each of the three test session procedures in order to maintain consistency.&#xD;
      Nonsmokers would receive $100.00 for completion of each of the three test sessions beyond the&#xD;
      training session. In addition, a completion bonus of $50.00 will be paid to all subjects who&#xD;
      complete all study procedures. Thus, smokers with schizophrenia could earn $575.00, and&#xD;
      nonsmokers $425.00 for their completion of the entire study. The proposed single subject&#xD;
      timeline is given below:&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2007</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>1. Change on selected cognitive deficits associated with schizophrenia (e.g., spatial working memory, sustained attention and prepulse inhibition.)</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">21</enrollment>
  <condition>Schizophrenia</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Galantamine</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
&#xD;
        Schizophrenic smokers (n=20) and schizophrenic nonsmokers (n=10) in these studies (total&#xD;
        n=20 subjects) will be:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Between 18 and 60 years of age,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have a Full Scale IQ score &gt;80.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Smokers will meet DSM-IV criteria for nicotine dependence, and smoke at least 15&#xD;
             cigarettes per day, with an FTND score at baseline &gt;5, breath CO &gt;10, and plasma&#xD;
             cotinine &gt;150 ng/ml.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Nonsmokers will report a history of never smoking (&lt;100 cigarettes lifetime) or be&#xD;
             abstinent from smoking for at least 6 months prior to randomization, with abstinence&#xD;
             biochemically confirmed by CO level &lt;10 ppm and plasma cotinine &lt;15 ng/ml.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Schizophrenic subjects will meet DSM-IV criteria for schizophrenia or schizoaffective&#xD;
             disorder, and be on a stable dose of antipsychotic medication for at least three&#xD;
             months, with positive symptoms stability as judged by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects must be non-treatment seeking smokers with respect to their nicotine&#xD;
             dependence.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Meet criteria for current abuse or dependence for any other alcohol or substance of&#xD;
             abuse within the past 6 months, with the exception of nicotine dependence (smokers) or&#xD;
             caffeine (all groups).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. An inability to learn the neuropsychological tasks during the training session.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of dementia, other neurological illness (e.g. idiopathic Parkinson's Disease,&#xD;
             Epilepsy), or any other acute or chronic medical condition known to significantly&#xD;
             influence neurocognitive function, at the discretion of the P.I. and Project Director.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. A history of severe renal or hepatic insufficiency, or a known hypersensitivity to&#xD;
             galantamine hydrochloride (Razadyne®).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. For smokers, current use of any tobacco products (chewing tobacco, cigars, nicotine&#xD;
             replacement therapies like lozenges, gum, nasal spray, inhaler or patch) besides&#xD;
             cigarettes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. A history of hypotension, or currently taking anti-hypertensive medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Interested in quitting smoking (in which case they will be referred to our smoking&#xD;
             cessation treatment study).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Not capable of giving informed consent for participation in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Positive urine toxicology screen for any substance of abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients who are pregnant or planning on becoming pregnant.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tony P George, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Toronto</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Connecticut Mental Health Center, Yale School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06519</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2007</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 18, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 19, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 20, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 11, 2007</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 11, 2007</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 12, 2007</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Schizophrenia</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognition</keyword>
  <keyword>Smoking</keyword>
  <keyword>Galantamine</keyword>
  <keyword>Nicotine</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognitive Deficits</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cognitive Dysfunction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Galantamine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

