<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00468780</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>724180022</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00468780</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Standardized Comparison of Triage in EMS</brief_title>
  <official_title>Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of Redirecting Ambulance Patients to Destinations Based on Acuity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Unity Health Toronto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Unity Health Toronto</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this study is to evaluate the reliability and validity of acuity estimates&#xD;
      by paramedics employing the Canadian Triage Acuity Scale (CTAS) in the out of hospital&#xD;
      setting. The study has the potential to help guide policy decisions pertaining to the safe&#xD;
      transfer of ambulance patients to alternative destinations reducing ED overcrowding and&#xD;
      ambulance off load time. Emergency Department triage nurses employ the same acuity scale and&#xD;
      if this study is successful the emergency departments and the EMS services could communicate&#xD;
      about capacity to handle patients based on acuity, volumes and waiting times.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      CTAS stands for the Canadian Triage Acuity Scale. CTAS defines 5 levels of triage according&#xD;
      to the perceived need for physician assessment. CTAS was developed to measure ED case mix and&#xD;
      evaluate the potential effect of changes in the delivery of health care on patients seeking&#xD;
      emergency care. Although the Canadian Institute of Health Information (CIHI) collects data on&#xD;
      total visits, admissions, and ambulatory care visits, there are few standards for reporting&#xD;
      data from Emergency Departments. The Canadian Association of Emergency Physicians endorsed&#xD;
      CTAS as a standardized data element to assess and compare case mix and acuity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At present there are no consistently utilized measures of patient acuity performed by&#xD;
      paramedics in Ontario. Information on the interface between Prehospital Care and Emergency&#xD;
      Departments would inform decision-making on the Emergency Health Care system. The&#xD;
      introduction of CTAS provides a superb opportunity to evaluate its utility in providing this&#xD;
      information on an accurate and consistent basis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The use of an acuity scale common to the in-hospital and prehospital setting seems ideal.&#xD;
      However, there are several questions to be answered regarding the feasibility, reliability,&#xD;
      safety and validity of CTAS before widespread implementation. The Society for Academic&#xD;
      Emergency Medicine's position clearly states, &quot;Patients may be referred to other locations&#xD;
      where they will receive care appropriate to the acuity of their problem only if the triage&#xD;
      criteria, if any, are based on research that shows them to be safe and effective&quot;. In their&#xD;
      prospective trial, Brillman et al. noted that 26-38% of emergency department patients who&#xD;
      were admitted to hospital would not have been identified at triage even when the treating&#xD;
      physician assessed them. If physicians are not capable of accurate triage decisions, one must&#xD;
      consider the reliability of a paramedic under the challenges of the prehospital setting.&#xD;
      Moreover, recent high-profile coroner cases suggest that liability is a significant concern.&#xD;
      Paramedics are accustomed to point-of-care assessment and triage, and do not have access to&#xD;
      some of the resources utilized by ED nurses. Because the environment, context, discriminating&#xD;
      tools, resources and skill set differ between triage nurses and paramedics, it is essential&#xD;
      to evaluate the use of paramedic assessment tools in the determination of an accurate and&#xD;
      consistent CTAS score. Moreover there has not as yet been an emphasis on paramedic assessment&#xD;
      interfacing with decision-making and time to care. It is important to ensure, therefore, that&#xD;
      the prehospital application of CTAS is appropriate and safe.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objectives of this study are to evaluate the criterion validity of CTAS assignment by&#xD;
      paramedics at departure from scene and arrival at hospital compared to a CTAS expert (gold&#xD;
      standard), to evaluate the inter-rater reliability of CTAS assignment by paramedics at&#xD;
      arrival at hospital compared to triage nurses, to evaluate the predictive validity of CTAS&#xD;
      level assignment with respect to patient outcomes and health care resource utilization and to&#xD;
      describe the relationship and the use of the return priority code and the CTAS category.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A random sample of Advanced Care Paramedic crews and an equal number of randomly selected&#xD;
      Basic Care Paramedic crews from five EMS systems (rural and urban) will be invited to&#xD;
      participate. A paramedic observer (advanced and basic) with advanced CTAS skills will observe&#xD;
      each crew, record the critical elements of each prehospital encounter on a data collection&#xD;
      sheet and assign a CTAS level to the patient on departure from scene and arrival at hospital.&#xD;
      The observer will also record the CTAS level and return priority code conveyed by the&#xD;
      paramedic to the dispatch centre, and evaluate whether the use of both the return priority&#xD;
      code (in which an urgent return is assigned a value of 4) and the CTAS score (in which an&#xD;
      urgent call is assigned a value of 1 or 2) generates any difficulties in paramedic&#xD;
      communication with dispatch on departure from the scene.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the hospital, the observer will ensure that the triage nurse assigns the CTAS level&#xD;
      without prior knowledge of the paramedic assignment. The observer will record the CTAS level&#xD;
      assigned by the triage nurse as well as the CTAS level at departure from the scene and on&#xD;
      arrival at the receiving hospital, return priority code and status change code recorded by&#xD;
      the treating paramedic on the ambulance call report. The patient's health insurance number&#xD;
      (HIN) will be collected for the purposes of linkage to outcome data. The observer will record&#xD;
      the times of departure from scene and arrival at hospital to estimate the transport interval.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Validity will be measured by calculating a kappa statistic comparing the observer's (gold&#xD;
      standard) CTAS score with the paramedic CTAS score at departure from scene and arrival at&#xD;
      hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inter-rater reliability of CTAS between medics (as assigned at arrival at hospital) and&#xD;
      triage nurses will be estimated using a kappa statistic. The same measure of agreement will&#xD;
      be estimated between the triage nurse and the observer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Agreement between the return priority code initially conveyed by the paramedic to dispatch&#xD;
      and the code recorded on the ACR will be evaluated using the kappa statistic. The&#xD;
      relationship between CTAS score and return priority code will be measured using descriptive&#xD;
      statistics and non-parametric correlation. The frequency of calls in which problems in&#xD;
      paramedic communication with dispatch arose with respect to the use of both CTAS and return&#xD;
      priority will be calculated and the types of problems encountered described.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2003</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CTAS level assignment</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of departue from scene and arrival at hospital</time_frame>
    <description>Reliability and validity of CTAS level assignment by paramedics and EMS service implementation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">928</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This study is taking place in 7 EMS systems in Ontario: Peterborough, Thunder Bay,&#xD;
        Hamilton, Simcoe/Muskoka, Durham, Peel, and Toronto.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The participants(Both Primary care paramedics and Advance Care Parmaeidcs)are riding as&#xD;
        civilian observers under contract to the Sunnybrook and Women's College Health Sciences&#xD;
        Centre Research Institute and have signed liability release forms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The main focus of the SCORE study is to determine how well paramedics in the field can&#xD;
        correctly assign CTAS scores. By showing that it can be done reliably, decisions can be&#xD;
        made on suitable destinations, especially for the low acuity patient.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Laurie Morrison, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Sunnybrook Health Sciences Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hamilton Health Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamilton</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>L8V 1C3</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sunnybrook-Osler Centre for Prehospital Care</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M9W 7K6</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://sunnybrook.ca/research/?page=sri_prog_tecc_focus_3</url>
    <description>Prehospital and Transport Medicine Research Program Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 1, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 2, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 3, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 23, 2014</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 23, 2014</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 26, 2014</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Canadian Triage Acuity Scale</keyword>
  <keyword>paramedics</keyword>
  <keyword>triage nurse</keyword>
  <keyword>triage levels</keyword>
  <keyword>inter-rater reliability</keyword>
  <keyword>health services outcomes</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

