<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00441077</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999907102</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>07-HG-N102</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00441077</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Interventions to Educate An Underserved Population About Inherited Disease Risks</brief_title>
  <official_title>Using a Communication Intervention to Provide Information About Inherited Risk to Underserved Latino Communities</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will examine how to communicate with an underserved population about inherited&#xD;
      disease risks. It will present information about inherited risk to a Latino population&#xD;
      through either a lay health advisor (LHA) or through printed information. The LHA is a member&#xD;
      of the Latino community who has received training in public speaking, group facilitation, and&#xD;
      managing group dynamics and in family health history and genetics. Previous studies have&#xD;
      shown that an LHA can effectively communicate health information to diverse audiences, but&#xD;
      such interventions have not been studied in the context of inherited risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Spanish-speaking Latino men and women over the age of 18 in the Oakland, CA, and Washington,&#xD;
      DC, areas who have basic Spanish reading and writing skills may be eligible for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants are recruited to one of two groups. One group participates in group educational&#xD;
      sessions with an LHA about inherited disease risks and family health history, and the other&#xD;
      receives this information from a brochure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Educational Sessions&#xD;
&#xD;
      Groups of 5 to 8 individuals complete a questionnaire and then participate in a 45-minute&#xD;
      educational session on concepts related to genetics, family health history, lifestyle and&#xD;
      environment. Participants engage in role-playing to practice discussing family health history&#xD;
      with family members. The LHA teaches participants the skills needed to fill in family health&#xD;
      history tool called My Family Health Portrait and answers questions. After the question and&#xD;
      answer session, participants complete a second questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Brochure-Only&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants complete a questionnaire and then read a Spanish-language brochure produced by&#xD;
      the U.S. Surgeon General's Office about the importance of knowing one's family history. They&#xD;
      then complete a second questionnaire.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      How to effectively educate the public about inherited risk is an important communication&#xD;
      issue now and will likely become even more important over the next decade. Little research&#xD;
      has been conducted, however, to examine how to communicate about this topic with individuals&#xD;
      from underserved populations. The planned study provides a unique and innovative opportunity&#xD;
      to examine how to reach an underserved community and present information about inherited risk&#xD;
      in an understandable and usable form by building upon an existing relationship between NHGRI&#xD;
      and the National Council of La Raza (NCLR). NCLR has previously designed a culturally&#xD;
      tailored lay health advisor (LHA) intervention designed to increase knowledge and awareness&#xD;
      about inherited risk among Latinos and to motivate them to seek information about their&#xD;
      family history. The primary objective of this study will be to examine the pathways by which&#xD;
      the LHA communication intervention impacts information seeking outcome variables. We will&#xD;
      examine the roles of possible mediating variables (i.e., perceived information need,&#xD;
      conceptual knowledge, self-efficacy) and assess the effects of contextual variables (i.e.,&#xD;
      family and personal history of disease, genetic beliefs, acculturation, health care access,&#xD;
      sociodemographic variables) on the outcomes. The second objective is to provide quantitative&#xD;
      data on the effects of the intervention on information seeking outcome measures (i.e.,&#xD;
      discussing family history with family members and health care providers) by comparing the&#xD;
      intervention to a brochure-only condition; these data can inform the planning of a&#xD;
      large-scale randomized controlled intervention trial. A third objective is to examine&#xD;
      predictors of intention to seek information about family history at baseline. A&#xD;
      quasi-experimental design will be used; we will recruit 350 individuals to participate in the&#xD;
      LHA intervention and 200 to a brochure-only comparison group. All participants will be&#xD;
      Spanish-speaking healthy volunteers who are at least 18 years of age and have basic Spanish&#xD;
      reading and writing skills. Participants will be recruited through community-based clinics in&#xD;
      Oakland, CA and Washington, DC and will either participate in a LHA or be asked to read&#xD;
      information about family history. They will complete brief, self-administered questionnaires&#xD;
      in Spanish before and after participating in the intervention or reading the brochure.&#xD;
      Because of the quasi-experimental design, multiple logistic regression models will be used in&#xD;
      the analysis in order to control for covariates. Understanding how to effectively inform&#xD;
      underserved communities about inherited risk is a research area of critical importance if&#xD;
      genomics is to be used to benefit the public health.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 19, 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 12, 2007</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 12, 2007</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intentions to seek information about family history.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment>550</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Volunteers</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Education</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All participants in this study will be healthy volunteers. Eligibility criteria for&#xD;
        participation in the study are the following: (1) being at least 18 years of age; and (2)&#xD;
        being able to speak Spanish and having basic Spanish reading and writing skills.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>La Raza</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oakland</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>La Clinica del Pueblo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington, D.C.</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20009</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Balcázar H, Alvarado M, Hollen ML, Gonzalez-Cruz Y, Pedregón V. Evaluation of Salud Para Su Corazón (Health for your Heart) -- National Council of La Raza Promotora Outreach Program. Prev Chronic Dis. 2005 Jul;2(3):A09. Epub 2005 Jun 15.</citation>
    <PMID>15963311</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Catz DS, Green NS, Tobin JN, Lloyd-Puryear MA, Kyler P, Umemoto A, Cernoch J, Brown R, Wolman F. Attitudes about genetics in underserved, culturally diverse populations. Community Genet. 2005;8(3):161-72.</citation>
    <PMID>16113533</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Derose KP, Baker DW. Limited English proficiency and Latinos' use of physician services. Med Care Res Rev. 2000 Mar;57(1):76-91.</citation>
    <PMID>10705703</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 25, 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 27, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 27, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 28, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Genetics</keyword>
  <keyword>Family History</keyword>
  <keyword>Latino</keyword>
  <keyword>Information Seeking</keyword>
  <keyword>Lay Health Advisors</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Heart Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Information</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

