<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00049556</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CDR0000258117</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-02-C-0303</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-5561</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00049556</nct_id>
    <nct_alias>NCT00046007</nct_alias>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Gefitinib in Treating Patients With Cervical Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Pilot Study of Clinical Activity and Proteomic Pathway Profiling of the EGFR Inhibitor, ZD1839 (Iressa; Gefitinib), in Patients With Epithelial Ovarian Cancer or Cervical Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      RATIONALE: Biological therapies such as gefitinib may interfere with the growth of the tumor&#xD;
      cells and slow the growth of cervical cancer. Comparing results of diagnostic procedures&#xD;
      performed before, during, and after treatment with gefitinib may help doctors predict a&#xD;
      patient's response to treatment and help plan the most effective treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well gefitinib works in treating patients with&#xD;
      cervical cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine the reduction in phosphorylation of epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR),&#xD;
           AKT, and ERK by proteomics in tumor and normal skin of patients with ovarian epithelial&#xD;
           cancer or cervical cancer receiving gefitinib. (Open to accrual for cervical cancer&#xD;
           patients only as of 4/5/2005)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine the clinical activity of this drug in these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine the toxicity of this drug in these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Correlate the biologic modulation of EGFR, ERK, and AKT by this drug with outcome and&#xD;
           toxic effects in these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Correlate EGFR modulation in skin with outcome and toxic effects in patients treated&#xD;
           with this drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Correlate expression of EGFR and phosphorylated-EGFR in tissue biopsies from these&#xD;
           patients with biochemical modulation and outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine the application of surface-enhanced laser desorption and ionization with&#xD;
           time-of-flight detection (SELDI-TOF) and artificial intelligence bioinformatics to&#xD;
           serially obtained serum samples for predicting response and toxic effects in these&#xD;
           patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: Patients are stratified according to disease (cervical cancer vs ovarian epithelial,&#xD;
      fallopian tube, and primary peritoneal cancer). (Open to accrual for cervical cancer patients&#xD;
      only as of 4/5/2005)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive oral gefitinib daily. Treatment continues every 28 days in the absence of&#xD;
      disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biopsies of a sentinel lesion (with CT guidance or laparoscopy) are obtained at baseline and&#xD;
      at 4 weeks. Skin biopsies of unaffected areas are also obtained at these time points. Tissue&#xD;
      is examined using immunohistochemical methods. Proteomic profiling using surface-enhanced&#xD;
      laser desorption/ionization with time-of-flight (SELDI-TOF) mass spectrometry is conducted on&#xD;
      serum at baseline and then every 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients are followed monthly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 30-40 patients (15-20 per stratum) will be accrued for this&#xD;
      study within 10-12 months. (Open to accrual for cervical cancer patients only as of 4/5/2005)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2006</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Biochem. modulation of EGFR signal transduction pathways in tumor by tissue lysate array reduction in phosphorylation of EGFR , AKT, and ERK in tumor biopsies at baseline and at 4 weeks during therapy</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Biochem. modulation of EGFR signal transduction pathways in skin biopsy tissue by tissue lysate array reduction in phosphorylation of EGFR , AKT, and ERK in skin biopsies at baseline and at 4 weeks during therapy</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical activity of gefitinib as measured by CT scan of chest/abdomen/pelvis every 8 weeks</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Toxicity as measured by laboratory testing, history, physical exam, and patient diary every 4 weeks</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Skin as a surrogate site for study of EGFR modulation and correlation with outcome and toxicity as measured by tissue lysate arrays at baseline and 4 weeks after the start of study therapy</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Potential collateral activation of other signal pathways in tumor and skin as measured by tissue lysate arrays at baseline and 4 weeks after the start of study therapy</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Expression of EGFR and phosphorylated-EGFR (pY-EGFR) as measured by tissue lysate arrays at baseline and 4 weeks after the start of study therapy</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prediction of response and/or toxicity by serially obtained serum samples using surface-enhanced laser desorption and ionization with time-of-flight detection (SELDI-TOF) and artificial intelligence bioinformatics at baseline and then monthly</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <condition>Cervical Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Fallopian Tube Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Primary Peritoneal Cavity Cancer</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>gefitinib</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>immunohistochemistry staining method</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>surface-enhanced laser desorption/ionization-time of flight mass spectrometry</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>biopsy</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>sentinel lymph node biopsy</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed ovarian epithelial cancer or cervical cancer (open to accrual&#xD;
             for cervical cancer patients only as of 4/5/2005)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Relapsed or refractory&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The following are also eligible: (open to accrual for cervical cancer patients only as&#xD;
             of 4/5/2005)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cancer of the fallopian tube&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Primary peritoneal cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cancer with low malignant potential and an invasive recurrence&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Block or recuts of primary tumor or recent resection specimen of a metastatic site&#xD;
             required&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease with a sentinel lesion adequate for core biopsy by percutaneous&#xD;
             biopsy or laparoscopy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No CNS involvement&#xD;
&#xD;
        PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 and over&#xD;
&#xD;
        Performance status&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Life expectancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not specified&#xD;
&#xD;
        Hematopoietic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  WBC greater than 3,000/mm^3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count greater than 100,000/mm^3&#xD;
&#xD;
        Hepatic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bilirubin less than 1.5 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  AST and ALT no greater than 2.5 times upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
        Renal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine less than 1.5 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
        Cardiovascular&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No myocardial infarction within the past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No unstable dysrhythmia within the past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        Other&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No other invasive malignancy within the past 5 years except noninvasive nonmelanoma&#xD;
             skin cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No active ocular inflammation or infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No active infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not pregnant or nursing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 2 months after study&#xD;
&#xD;
        PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Biologic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No prior cetuximab or monoclonal antibody ABX-EGF&#xD;
&#xD;
        Chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy (6 weeks for nitrosoureas or mitomycin) and&#xD;
             recovered&#xD;
&#xD;
        Endocrine therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 4 weeks since prior hormonal therapy and recovered&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No concurrent tamoxifen&#xD;
&#xD;
        Radiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy and recovered&#xD;
&#xD;
        Surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recovered from prior oncologic or other major surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
        Other&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No prior epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitory agents (e.g., OSI-774)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No concurrent antiretroviral therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No concurrent itraconozole, ketoconazole, erythromycin, verapamil, chlorpromazine,&#xD;
             amiodarone, or chloroquine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No concurrent drugs known to induce CYP3A4 enzymes (e.g., phenytoin, carbamazepine,&#xD;
             rifampicin, barbiturates, oxacarbazepine, rifapentine, or Hypericum perforatum)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Virginia Kwitkowski, MS, RN, CS, CRNP</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Warren Grant Magnuson Clinical Center - NCI Clinical Studies Support</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892-1182</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NCI - Center for Cancer Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Posadas EM, Liel MS, Kwitkowski V, Minasian L, Godwin AK, Hussain MM, Espina V, Wood BJ, Steinberg SM, Kohn EC. A phase II and pharmacodynamic study of gefitinib in patients with refractory or recurrent epithelial ovarian cancer. Cancer. 2007 Apr 1;109(7):1323-30.</citation>
    <PMID>17330838</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Liel MS, Espina V, Pazzagli C, et al.: Phase II study of gefitinib in epithelial ovarian cancer: Proteomic pathway profiling in tumor biopsies. [Abstract] American Association for Cancer Research: 96th Annual Meeting, April 16-20, 2005, Anaheim/Orange County, CA. A-5745, 2005. .</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2006</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 12, 2002</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 26, 2003</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 27, 2003</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 18, 2013</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 18, 2013</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">June 20, 2013</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>fallopian tube cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>borderline ovarian surface epithelial-stromal tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>primary peritoneal cavity cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>recurrent cervical cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>recurrent ovarian epithelial cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Ovarian Epithelial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gefitinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

