<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00043940</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TMC-98-10</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00043940</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Anticoagulant Therapy With Bivalirudin in the Performance of Percutaneous Coronary Intervention in Patients With Heparin-Induced Thrombocytopenia (AT BAT, First Inning)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Anticoagulant Therapy With Bivalirudin in the Performance of PCI in Patients With Heparin-Induced Thrombocytopenia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The Medicines Company</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The Medicines Company</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Primary Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess the safety of bivalirudin as an alternative anticoagulant therapy for patients with&#xD;
      new or previous heparin-induced thrombocytopenia (HIT) / heparin-induced thrombocytopenia and&#xD;
      thrombosis syndrome (HITTS) undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI). This will be&#xD;
      measured by the composite incidence of major bleeding events during administration or within&#xD;
      48 hours after stopping bivalirudin (or at hospital discharge, whichever occurs first). The&#xD;
      components of the composite endpoint are: a) intracranial bleeding; b) retroperitoneal&#xD;
      bleeding; c) bleeding that results in hemodynamic compromise; d) bleeding that requires&#xD;
      transfusion of three or more units of whole blood or packed red cells; and e) a decrease in&#xD;
      hemoglobin of greater than or equal to g/dL or in hematocrit of greater than or equal to 9%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each component of the primary composite endpoint.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate the level of anticoagulation achieved with bivalirudin. The goal is to achieve an&#xD;
      activated clotting time (ACT) between 300 and 350 sec during PCI and 4-hour bivalirudin&#xD;
      infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate bivalirudin's effects on platelet counts.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 1999</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 2003</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Major bleeding events</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours</time_frame>
    <description>composite incidence of major bleeding events during administration or within 48 hours after stopping bivalirudin</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Heparin-Induced Thrombocytopenia</condition>
  <condition>Thrombosis</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>bivalirudin</intervention_name>
    <description>Bivalirudin therapy will be given as a 0.75-mg/kg intravenous bolus and 1.75-mg/kg/h intravenous infusion during procedure and up to 4 hours.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males and females at least 18 years of age,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be able to provide written informed consent,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Need anticoagulation for percutaneous coronary intervention (angioplasty, rotational&#xD;
             atherectomy, directional coronary atherectomy, transluminal extraction catheter, or&#xD;
             coronary stent),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New diagnosis or history of clinically suspected or objectively documented HIT/HITTS,&#xD;
             defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
        (A) Positive heparin-induced platelet aggregation (HIPA) or other functional assay, defined&#xD;
        as: (B) HIT: Thrombocytopenia associated with heparin therapy, where the platelet count:&#xD;
        (i) has decreased to &lt;100x10(9)/L (minimum of 30% drop from the platelet count before&#xD;
        heparin treatment), OR (ii) has decreased to &lt;150x10(9)/L (minimum of 40% drop from the&#xD;
        platelet count before heparin treatment, OR, (C) HITTS: Thrombocytopenia (as defined above)&#xD;
        PLUS arterial or venous thrombosis (deep-vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, mesenteric&#xD;
        venous or arterial thrombosis, acute myocardial infarction, left ventricular thrombus,&#xD;
        ischemic stroke, or occlusion or limb arteries), diagnosed by physical exam/lab evidence&#xD;
        and/or appropriate imaging studies (duplex ultrasound, venography, ventilation-perfusion&#xD;
        scan, venous or arterial angiography, MRI/MRA, catheterization).&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Overt or known active significant bleeding,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Definitive evidence of an alternative explanation for the thrombocytopenia (e.g.m DIC,&#xD;
             sepsis, other consumptive coagulopathy, ITP, TTP, HUS, or bone-marrow failure),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Coagulation disorder or bleeding diathesis unrelated to HIT/HITTS,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with renal impairment, defined as calculated creatinine clearance &lt;30 mL/min,&#xD;
             or any other medical conditions (including hepatic, pulmonary, gastrointestinal,&#xD;
             endocrine, or psychiatric) that, in the investigator's opinion, would endanger the&#xD;
             patient if she/he receives anticoagulant therapy,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nonhemorrhagic stroke within the past 6 months or any previous hemorrhagic stroke,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intracranial neoplasm, or cerebral/spinal arteriovenous malformation or aneurysm,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lumbar puncture, or spinal/epidural catheter placement within the past 7 days,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known prior hemorrhage (gastrointestinal, genitourinary, pericardia, pleural,&#xD;
             retroperitoneal spaces), major surgery, or serious trauma within the past 6 weeks,&#xD;
             unless attending physician believes the need for anticoagulation with PCI outweighs&#xD;
             the potential bleeding risk,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Puncture of a non-compressible vessel within 24 hours before the planned PCI,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed uncontrolled hypertension (systolic blood pressure &gt; or = 100 mmHg) at study&#xD;
             entry,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing anticoagulant therapy at study entry. However, patients may be entered if the&#xD;
             therapy can be safely stopped periprocedurally, or, in the case of oral warfarin, if&#xD;
             the prothrombin time INR can safely be brought to &lt; or = 1.5 just before study drug&#xD;
             infusion,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected pregnancy, or breast-feed. Women of childbearing potential must&#xD;
             have a negative pregnancy test (urine or blood) and must be made explicitly aware that&#xD;
             bivalirudin may cause excessive menstrual bleeding. Known or suspected pregnancy, or&#xD;
             breast-feeding,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to bivalirudin or leech proteins,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If the patient has participated in a drug trial within the past 48 hour, call the DCRI&#xD;
             hotline.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke Clinical Research Institute, Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2011</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 14, 2002</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 15, 2002</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 16, 2002</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 15, 2011</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 15, 2011</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">September 16, 2011</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>thrombosis</keyword>
  <keyword>bivalirudin</keyword>
  <keyword>direct thrombin inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>HIT</keyword>
  <keyword>HITTS</keyword>
  <keyword>HIT/HITTS</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thrombocytopenia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bivalirudin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

