<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04659395</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>533039</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04659395</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>How to Develop a Training Program for Nurses in Ultrasound Guided Femoral Nerve Block</brief_title>
  <official_title>How to Develop a Training Program for Nurses in Ultrasound Guided Femoral - a Methodology Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sykehuset i Vestfold HF</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of South-Eastern Norway</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sykehuset i Vestfold HF</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this study the intervention consists of a one-day-training program for nurses and three&#xD;
      supervised ultrasound guided femoral nerve block (UGFNB) per registered nurse.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The training consists of an instruction movie, one-day on-site-simulation and practical&#xD;
      examination. The nurses are watching an instruction video and review current local guidelines&#xD;
      for UGFNB in advance. The one-day training is situated in a simulation center and consists of&#xD;
      theoretical and practical training divided into; infection prevention, anatomy, use of&#xD;
      ultrasound and prevention and treatment of complications. A ultrasound model (Gen II Femoral&#xD;
      Vascular Access and Regional Anesthesia Ultrasound Training Model) and a living human model&#xD;
      is used to examine the femoral nerve and the neighboring structures using ultrasound. At the&#xD;
      end of the one-day course, the nurses attends a practical examination with the researchers&#xD;
      and anesthesiologists observing, to assure that they could perform the UGFNB procedure&#xD;
      correctly. To pass the exam and be able to move on to the supervised blocks in real patients,&#xD;
      there has to be a consensus between the researchers and anesthesiologist that they had&#xD;
      sufficient knowledge and practical skills. 1) Sterile procedure 2) Management of the&#xD;
      ultrasound machine and oral description of the anatomic surroundings in the groin area 3)&#xD;
      Preparation of the local anesthetics and performance of an UGFNB. They also have to do an&#xD;
      oral presentation in how they would perform a cardiopulmonary resuscitation procedure and how&#xD;
      to manage complications / toxic reactions. Approved exam required at least seven points. This&#xD;
      study will explore if a one-day course as described above is adequate, sufficient and&#xD;
      maintains the safety framework of performing UGFNB in nurses&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Acute pain is a common reason for patients admitted to Emergency Departments (ED) . Globally&#xD;
      over 1 million hip fractures occur yearly , a trauma that is close related with acute&#xD;
      distinct pain in the proximal part of the affected extremity. Experiencing severe pain is&#xD;
      associated with increased length of stay, higher risk of delirium, movement restriction,&#xD;
      difficulties with mobilization and reduced health related quality of life. There is&#xD;
      considerable research regarding patients' satisfaction with their ED experiences. These&#xD;
      studies indicate that patient dissatisfaction with the stay at ED has been an international&#xD;
      challenge over several years . Disapproval such as; pain management , but also limited&#xD;
      information on potential latency before further treatment and poor explanation about the&#xD;
      causes and treatment of the condition is prominent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pain control can be difficult , and often requires advanced nursing and physician care due to&#xD;
      co-morbidity . Inadequate analgesia appear to be risk factors for delirium in frail older&#xD;
      adults, and research indicates that total avoiding opioids or using very low or high doses of&#xD;
      opioids may increase the risk of delirium. Therefore, optimizing acute pain management is&#xD;
      important. Ultrasound Guided Femoral Nerve block (UGFNB) performed in hip fracture patients&#xD;
      is a valuable alternative to systemic analgesic, as it provides analgesia to the fractured&#xD;
      area, thereby facilitating reduction in opioid administration. Traditionally, an UGFNB is&#xD;
      performed by an anesthesiologist. Recently, several examples of task shifting from physicians&#xD;
      to nurses are described with no significant difference in successful treatment results with&#xD;
      equal patients satisfaction and safety as physician performed procedures. Task shifting&#xD;
      approach is endorsed by the World Health Organization (WHO) in order to make more efficient&#xD;
      use of the available human resource of health. A recent report from the European Union (EU)&#xD;
      states that implementation of task shifting has been rarely evaluated and limited documented.&#xD;
      Therefore, we need studies to examine the methodology in how we can train nurses in the ED to&#xD;
      take more responsibility for assessing and treating patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the study we aime to;&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. describe a methodology for a training course for nurse led UGFNB.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. evaluate if the training process resulted in a safe and successful UGFNB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data which will be collected are&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. ASA classification (ASA Physical Status Classification System )&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Length of stay&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Morbidity&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Hospital acquired pneumonia&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Acute myocardial infarction (AMI)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Acute renal failure&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Respiratory failure&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Complication rate, number of;&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  intravasal injection - visually + circulatory and neurological symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  hematoma - defined as a new tumor &gt; 2 cm in the groin / injection site measured by&#xD;
                ultrasound&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Neurologic systemic outcomes / symptoms / paresthesia that have occurred after&#xD;
                admission and which persist until discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Allergic reaction&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Number of total morphine equivalents, mg (iv/po) administered prehospital and during&#xD;
           Emergency Department stay&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Patients physical characteristic (physical examination; gender, age, height, weight, ,&#xD;
           blood pressure, heart rate, SpO2 (oxygen saturation) and use of oxygen will be noted&#xD;
           together with current disease&#xD;
&#xD;
      A short, but personal interview with the patients having received an UGFNB by a study nurse&#xD;
      can describe both the service received and the patient's experience with it. The interviews&#xD;
      will be performed after the patient has been relieved of pain. The PhD (Philosophiae&#xD;
      Doctor)-candidate, not the study nurse having performed the nerve block, will conduct the&#xD;
      interviews. The patients will be asked whether the nerve block relieved them of pain, how&#xD;
      they experienced the procedure and the fact that it was performed by a nurse had any&#xD;
      relevance. Also, the PhD-candidate will interview the patient at a later point during the&#xD;
      hospital stay for a second time to compare the answers&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study nurses and the anesthesiologists that has supervised the nurses will be presented&#xD;
      with a questionnaire after each UGFNB conducted. The PhD-candidate will hand out the&#xD;
      questionnaire immediately after the FNB is conducted by a study nurse. The items in the&#xD;
      questionnaire include feasibility and success of the procedure and are identical for nurses&#xD;
      and anesthesiologists.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Finally, each study nurse will do three UGFNB with supervision by an anesthesiologist before&#xD;
      we start inclusion in a later randomized controlled trial. Five study nurses will be included&#xD;
      and fifteen patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The inclusion criteria for patients will be:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients arriving at the ED diagnosed with a hip fracture (radiological confirmed)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ASA- classification 1-4&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Written and verbal informed consent by patient&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria for patients will be:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with; dementia, without ability to give informed consent and other cognitively&#xD;
           challenges needed to participate in this study (at the discretion of the study nurse)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Known allergies to local anesthetic (Ropivacaine) used in UGFNB&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Use of anticoagulants or platelet inhibitors. Acetylsalicylic acid and dipyridamole is&#xD;
           allowed. If a recent (last 2 hours) INR( international normalized ratio) is below &lt;1.5&#xD;
           the patient can be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Age &lt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Severe head injury which leads to significant loss of consciousness (GCS &lt;12)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  &gt;10 mg or more morphine administrated pre-hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Skin lesions/infection at presumed block site&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients admitted with other suspected or verified fractures, except small fractures in&#xD;
           hands and foots.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Verbal and written informed consent The study nurses will inform the patients by oral and&#xD;
      written information and inclusion and intervention of the patient will start after written&#xD;
      consent.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 19, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 11, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A methodology study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) - during passive movement at 120 minutes after start of procedure, measured by 5 timepoints</measure>
    <time_frame>120 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Cumulative Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) - during passive movement (30 degree flexion in the fractured hip) in patients with hip fracture during stay in the ED at 120 minutes after admission, measured by five time Points; At the end of procedure, 30 min.-, 60 min.-, 90 min.- and 120 min after start of procedure. NRS score: 0 is no pain and 10 is the worst pain.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) - during passive movement at baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline (timepoint 0)</time_frame>
    <description>Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) - during passive movement (30 degree flexion in the fractured hip) in patients with hip fracture during stay in the ED at baseline (inclution of patient) NRS score: 0 is no pain and 10 is the worst pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) - during passive movement after 30 minutes</measure>
    <time_frame>After 30 minutes from baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) - during passive movement (30 degree flexion in the fractured hip) in patients with hip fracture during stay in the ED after 30 minutes from baseline NRS score: 0 is no pain and 10 is the worst pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) - during passive movement after 60 minutes</measure>
    <time_frame>After 60 minutes from baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) - during passive movement (30 degree flexion in the fractured hip) in patients with hip fracture during stay in the ED after 60 minutes from baseline NRS score: 0 is no pain and 10 is the worst pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) - during passive movement after 90 minutes</measure>
    <time_frame>After 90 minutes from baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) - during passive movement (30 degree flexion in the fractured hip) in patients with hip fracture during stay in the ED after 90 minutes from baseline NRS score: 0 is no pain and 10 is the worst pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) - during passive movement after 120 minutes</measure>
    <time_frame>After 120 minutes from baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) - during passive movement (30 degree flexion in the fractured hip) in patients with hip fracture during stay in the ED after 120 minutes from baseline NRS score: 0 is no pain and 10 is the worst pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hematoma</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Hematoma - defined as a new tumor &gt; 2 centimeter in the groin / injection site measured by ultrasound, Yes or no</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intravasal injection</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Intravasal injection - visually + circulatory and neurological symptoms, yes or no</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient experience- description of pain</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Patient experience of pain- During rest and motion measured by a 1-5 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction- waiting time to pain relief</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Patiens experiences on waiting time to pain relief measured in a scale form 1-5</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction- information</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Patient experiences on information measured in a scale form 1-5</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction- description of pain before the procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Patient experience on pre-procedure pain measured by 1-5 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction- description of pain after the procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Patient satisfaction- description of pain after the procedure measured by 1-5 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction- safety</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Patient satisfaction- description of patient reported feeling of safety during nurse led procedure measured by a 1-5 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction-effect of procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Patient satisfaction regarding reduction of pain after the procedure measured by a 1-5 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction-hearing status</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Patient satisfaction hearing status measured by a 1-4 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self reported-registered nurse- complexity</measure>
    <time_frame>approximately 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Complexity of procedure measured by scale 1-5</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self reported-registered nurse-success</measure>
    <time_frame>approximately 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Success of procedure measured by 1-5 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self reported-registered nurse-Recognition of anatomic structures</measure>
    <time_frame>approximately 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Recognition of anatomic structures at ultrasound, measured by a 1-4</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self reported-registred nurse-spread of anesthesia</measure>
    <time_frame>approximately 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Spread of anesthesia, measured by a 1-4 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self reported-registered nurse- patient benefit from procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>approximately 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Patient benefit of procedure measured by a 1-5 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self reported-Anesthesiologist-complexity</measure>
    <time_frame>approximately 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Complexity of procedure measured by scale 1-5</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self reported-Anesthesiologist-success</measure>
    <time_frame>approximately 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Success of procedure measured by a 1-5 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self reported-Anesthesiologist-Recognition of anatomic structures</measure>
    <time_frame>approximately 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Recognition of anatomic structures at ultrasound measured by a 1-4 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self reported-Anesthesiologist-spread of anesthesia</measure>
    <time_frame>approximately 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Spread of anesthesia, measured by a 1-4 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self reported-Anesthesiologist-Patient benefit of procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>approxemitely 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Patient benefit of procedure measured by a 1-5 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">5</enrollment>
  <condition>Hip Fractures</condition>
  <condition>Ultrasound Therapy; Complications</condition>
  <condition>Pain, Acute</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Emergency nurses</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Emergency nurses who are trained in an one-day course</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Emergency nurses</intervention_name>
    <description>Emergency nurses who are trained for one-day in ultrasound-guided femoral nerve block</description>
    <arm_group_label>Emergency nurses</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Registered nurses or registered nurses with continuing education in acute nursing or&#xD;
             geriatrics&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The nurses need to be aware that it will increase the workload in beginning of the&#xD;
             project.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Registered nurse has to be senior staff experienced i.e. worked in the ED&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Motivated to take on a new task in the ED&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Certificated in advanced CPR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Familiar with routines in the ED and the relevant patient group&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  They must be willing to be a part of this project for approximately 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Working at least 75%.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refuse to participate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elin saga, Nurse</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The Hospital of Vestfold</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vestfold Hospital Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tønsberg</city>
        <zip>3103</zip>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Norway</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dochez E, van Geffen GJ, Bruhn J, Hoogerwerf N, van de Pas H, Scheffer G. Prehospital administered fascia iliaca compartment block by emergency medical service nurses, a feasibility study. Scand J Trauma Resusc Emerg Med. 2014 Jun 23;22:38. doi: 10.1186/1757-7241-22-38.</citation>
    <PMID>24957807</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mandy, L. . Nurse-led femoral nerve service for patients with fractured neck of femur. Advanced Nursing Practice in Pain Management. C. E. e. al., John wiley and sons: (2009)16.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ketelaars R, Stollman JT, van Eeten E, Eikendal T, Bruhn J, van Geffen GJ. Emergency physician-performed ultrasound-guided nerve blocks in proximal femoral fractures provide safe and effective pain relief: a prospective observational study in The Netherlands. Int J Emerg Med. 2018 Mar 2;11(1):12. doi: 10.1186/s12245-018-0173-z.</citation>
    <PMID>29500558</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Layzell M. Nurse-led femoral nerve block service for patients with fractured neck of femur. 2010 05.02.18. In: Advancing nursing practice in pain management [Internet]. Chichester, West Sussex; Ames, Iowa: Blackwell Pub.; [16]</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>WHO (2008). Task Shifting - Global Recommendations and Guidelines. WHO. Geneva, Switzerland., WHO Document Production Services: 96.</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 2, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 2, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sykehuset i Vestfold HF</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Espen Lindholm</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Consultant</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Task shifting</keyword>
  <keyword>Ultrasound guided</keyword>
  <keyword>Training</keyword>
  <keyword>Education</keyword>
  <keyword>Emergency department</keyword>
  <keyword>Registered nurse</keyword>
  <keyword>Nerve block</keyword>
  <keyword>Hip fracture</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acute Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hip Fractures</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>No plan for sharing IPD</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

