<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04655573</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00107118</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04655573</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Pilot Study of a Micro-Organosphere Drug Screen Platform to Lead Care in Advanced Breast Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pilot Study of a Micro-Organosphere Drug Screen Platform to Lead Care in Advanced Breast Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Duke University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Duke University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to assess the feasibility of generating patient derived&#xD;
      micro-organospheres (PDMO) from patients with advanced breast cancer to determine sensitivity&#xD;
      to the most common forms of chemotherapy used in advanced breast cancer care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the feasibility of generating sufficient patient&#xD;
      derived micro-organospheres (PDMO) from a biopsy of a patient's advanced breast cancer to&#xD;
      determine sensitivity to the most common forms of chemotherapy used in advanced breast cancer&#xD;
      care. While subjects are on study, they will first receive a standard of care clinical biopsy&#xD;
      from which extra tissue is taken for research purposes. Following the biopsy, a PDMO will be&#xD;
      generated and they will receive a chemotherapy regimen as determined by their treating&#xD;
      physician. This study aims to enroll 15 patients. Of this 15 patient cohort we aim to enroll&#xD;
      5 patients with estrogen receptor positive (ER+)/human epidermal growth factor receptor 2&#xD;
      negative (HER2-) disease, 5 patients with ER+/HER2+ or ER-/HER2+ disease, and 5 patients with&#xD;
      ER-/HER2- (TNBC) disease. There are risks to having biopsies and blood draws that may include&#xD;
      moderate bleeding and pain at the biopsy site.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Year</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of patients with successful generation of PDMO from the patient's biopsy</measure>
    <time_frame>10 days of biopsy</time_frame>
    <description>The PDMO establishment will be monitored and success will be defined as the formation of 3D organoid structures in at least 80% of droplets in each well, in 20 randomly sampled wells per PDMO model, within 7 days. With an anticipated generation of 90% we anticipate being able to generate 13 PDMO from the first 15 patients to perform a drug screen within 10 days of biopsy. The exact 90% lower confidence bound (LCB) will be computed for the proportion of patients with successful generation of PDMO and completed drug screen within 10 days. For the first 6 patients, if at least 5 PDMO can be generated and screened on 6 patients' samples the procedure will be deemed feasible. With 6 patients studied the exact 90% LCB assuming 5 successful cases is 0.71. We would thus be 90% confident that the success rate of this strategy is at least 71%.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Association between specific chemotherapy sensitivity in PDMO to clinical outcome of patient</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study (up to 2 years)</time_frame>
    <description>For the 15 evaluable patients, the MODEL ABC platform will be used to assess sensitivity to chemotherapy and generate a prediction model for correlation with patient data. For each sample, two primary outcomes will be collected: i) PDMO drug sensitivity data, and ii) the patient's clinical outcome (PFS). Treating PDMO with 10 chemotherapy single agents at 10 drug concentrations each will generate drug sensitivity data. For all 15 samples, PDMO sensitivity to each concentration of each drug will be used alongside the 15 clinical responses (PFS) to develop a predictor of PFS by correlating drug response data to clinical data.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patient Derived Micro-Organospheres (PDMO)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Subjects will undergo image-guided biopsy as a standard of care clinical biopsy from which extra tissue is taken for research purposes. Following the biopsy, a PDMO will be generated and they will receive a chemotherapy regimen as determined by their treating physician. PDMO are successfully generated, and the patient begins treatment with a hemotherapy backbone. A patient will be considered evaluable if pathology results are available from the biopsy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Breast Cancer Tumor Resection</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients with ABC will be receiving a biopsy, and a PDMO from the patient's biopsies will be generated from it. It is a model correlating clinical response with PDMO sensitivity to the most common forms of chemotherapy used in advanced breast cancer care.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patient Derived Micro-Organospheres (PDMO)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Patient derived tumor specimens that are cultured into patient-derived micro-organospheres&#xD;
      (PDMO) for patients with ABC.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Subjects with advanced breast cancer&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Female ages 18 or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Evidence of advanced cancer of the breast that is surgically unresectable with&#xD;
             pathology confirming ER, PR, and HER2 status. NOTE: patients may enroll prior to&#xD;
             receiving clinical biopsy results. If they are not confirmed to have advanced&#xD;
             adenocarcinoma of the breast or ER, PR, HER2 are not confirmed, they will not be&#xD;
             evaluable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient is eligible for chemotherapy as monotherapy or in combination other agent(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ER+/HER2- ABC, must have progressed on endocrine therapy and CDK 4/6 inhibitor&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ER+/HER2+ or ER-/HER2+ ABC, must have progressed on ≥ 2 lines of anti-HER2&#xD;
                  therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ER-/HER2-, PD-L1+ ABC, must have progressed on checkpoint blockade unless&#xD;
                  checkpoint blockade is not able to be provided per the clinicians discretion&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Treating physician is planning to treat the breast cancer in the advanced setting with&#xD;
             a chemotherapy backbone.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. ECOG performance status of 0, 1, or 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any metastatic site that is amenable to core needle biopsy. Patients with brain&#xD;
             metastases and/or leptomeningeal disease are allowed and PDMO may be generated from a&#xD;
             resected breast cancer brain metastasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Chronic or current active infectious disease requiring systemic antibiotics,&#xD;
             antifungal, or antiviral treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Clinically significant cardiac disease, including unstable angina, acute myocardial&#xD;
             infarction within 6 months from Day 1 of study drug administration, New York Heart&#xD;
             Association Class II, III, or IV congestive heart failure, and arrhythmia requiring&#xD;
             therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Presence of significant concurrent, uncontrolled medical condition including, but not&#xD;
             limited to renal, hepatic, hematological, gastrointestinal, endocrine, pulmonary,&#xD;
             cardiac, neurological, cerebral, active infection, non-healing wound or psychiatric&#xD;
             disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pregnant or actively breastfeeding women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Not willing to use an effective method of birth control.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jeremy Force, DO</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Duke University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Michelle Parks</last_name>
    <phone>919-668-1861</phone>
    <email>michelle.parks@duke.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jeremy Force, DO</last_name>
      <phone>919-668-1861</phone>
      <email>jeremy.force@duke.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 30, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 7, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Patient derived micro-organospheres (PDMO)</keyword>
  <keyword>Chemotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Advanced Breast Cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

