<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04655937</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRAS ID: 287785</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04655937</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Wellbeing After Stroke (WAterS)</brief_title>
  <acronym>WAterS</acronym>
  <official_title>Wellbeing After Stroke (WAterS) Pilot Study Exploring Acceptance and Commitment Therapy (ACT) Psychological Support Delivered to Groups of Community-based Stroke Survivors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Manchester</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Stroke Association</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Manchester</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Stroke survivors face a range of mental health challenges adjusting post-stroke. There is a&#xD;
      lack of treatment options and clinical psychologist workforce to deliver support. Acceptance&#xD;
      and Commitment Therapy (ACT) has been used successfully in clinical services to improve&#xD;
      wellbeing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators worked with stroke survivors, health care professionals and researchers to&#xD;
      develop group ACT therapy, specifically for stroke survivors, to be delivered using video&#xD;
      calling (Zoom). Staff training and supervision programmes were also developed to equip Stroke&#xD;
      Association workforce (paraprofessionals) to deliver ACT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current study will recruit and train up to 10 paraprofessionals with some experience of&#xD;
      supporting stroke survivors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study aims to recruit up to 60 stroke survivors in the community who are at least 4&#xD;
      months post-stroke and experiencing distress adjusting to their stroke. The investigators&#xD;
      aimed to make everything accessible for people with mild/moderate difficulties with thinking&#xD;
      and communicating. Recruitment takes place across England, over a 12 month period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will test how feasible and acceptable it is to deliver our remote ACT intervention&#xD;
      to stroke survivors, using a 'modified randomised consent' design that involves two levels of&#xD;
      consent for stroke survivors:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The first level is agreement to complete online measures of well-being every 3 months&#xD;
           for up to 12 months (taking around 20 minutes), with the option to participate in&#xD;
           groups. Those who don't opt for groups will not be treated but will be followed up about&#xD;
           their wellbeing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Those who opt to attend groups will be randomly allocated to attend either the ACT&#xD;
           intervention or an active control group, involving social support. Both groups involve 8&#xD;
           weekly sessions and homework.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be collected on how successfully the groups are delivered and how acceptable they&#xD;
      are / how to improve them, through online surveys, feedback questionnaires and interviews.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background: Stroke survivors face a range of mental health challenges during the adjustment&#xD;
      process post-stroke. It is not always easy for stroke survivors to access treatment to help&#xD;
      them face these challenges, due to the lack of interventions and access to clinical&#xD;
      psychologists. Acceptance and Commitment Therapy (ACT) has good theoretical underpinning to&#xD;
      support adjustment post stroke. The potential benefits of ACT may be further increased by&#xD;
      group delivery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators have worked with stroke survivors, expert clinicians and researchers to&#xD;
      develop an ACT intervention to be delivered remotely to groups, to support their adjustment&#xD;
      and wellbeing post-stroke. The investigators have also developed a remote staff training and&#xD;
      clinical supervision programme to equip paraprofessionals (Stroke Association coordinators)&#xD;
      to deliver the course.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims: The study aims to explore feasibility and acceptability of paraprofessionals delivering&#xD;
      the adapted ACT intervention to stroke survivors in community settings in the context of a&#xD;
      modified pilot randomised consent trial, with a non-randomised no-treatment group and a&#xD;
      randomised active comparator arm (attention control) that is also delivered by&#xD;
      paraprofessionals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: There are three work packages described that, whilst distinct, do overlap in terms&#xD;
      of participants and timelines. All methods and study materials have been informed through&#xD;
      collaboration with stroke survivors and carers through the WAterS Research User Group (RUG):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Work package 1 (staff training): remotely training paraprofessionals to deliver either&#xD;
           the remote ACT intervention or attention control. Through qualitative research and&#xD;
           competency exercises, explore whether this equips staff with confidence and skills to&#xD;
           deliver the study components.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Work package 2 (pilot trial): a modified randomised consent design allows for&#xD;
           exploration of the acceptability of outcomes data collection separate to the&#xD;
           acceptability of delivering remote group interventions and other study components.&#xD;
           Eligible stroke survivors are recruited with baseline clinical and demographic&#xD;
           information collected. They are invited to contribute self-report outcomes data about&#xD;
           their psychological wellbeing, every three months for up to 12 months. Participants&#xD;
           groups will include a no-treatment group, and a group that is randomised and&#xD;
           subsequently invited to participate in either the ACT intervention (8 short weekly&#xD;
           sessions delivered by zoom) or an attention control group (involving social attention;&#xD;
           time-matched sessions). Stroke survivors randomised and attending groups (intervention&#xD;
           or attention control) will be asked to complete additional self-report outcomes data in&#xD;
           weeks 1 and weeks 8 of the groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Work package 3 (process evaluation; runs in parallel with pilot trial): observation and&#xD;
           filming of groups (intervention and attention control) will facilitate monitoring of&#xD;
           fidelity, as well as provide opportunities for paraprofessional facilitators to reflect&#xD;
           on delivery and competency during ongoing clinical supervision. In addition, the&#xD;
           acceptability of course content to stroke survivor attendees will be explored through&#xD;
           postal or online feedback questionnaires and qualitative interviews.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants. Up to 10 paraprofessionals (Stroke Association Coordinators) with some&#xD;
      experience of supporting stroke survivors and facilitating existing social support groups&#xD;
      will be recruited for training in Work Package 1 and subsequent facilitation of groups.&#xD;
      Paraprofessionals will be recruited from sites across the North of England. For Work packages&#xD;
      2 and 3: up to 60 stroke survivors who are at least four months post-stroke and experiencing&#xD;
      difficulties with adjustment and psychological distress will be recruited across the UK using&#xD;
      a variety of methods to explore optimal recruitment routes over a 12 month period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is underpinned by United Kingdom Medical Research Council (MRC) guidance on&#xD;
      developing and evaluating complex interventions. MRC advises that feasibility work can&#xD;
      uncover and explore problems of acceptability, compliance, delivery, recruitment and&#xD;
      retention; and they recommend that process evaluations are embedded to increase understanding&#xD;
      of the intervention and optimise its design and evaluation. At the feasibility stage, process&#xD;
      evaluation is an active and iterative process, and changes can and should be made and acted&#xD;
      upon while the trial is on-going. As such, the methodological principles are outlined in this&#xD;
      record, but it is likely that some specifics may be adjusted as data are collected and&#xD;
      learning is implemented.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All data (including recordings) will be handled in line with University of Manchester&#xD;
      approved protocols and Study-specific Data Management Plan to ensure the safety and security&#xD;
      of data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 5, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>We use a novel modified randomised consent design (Zelen), best represented by a figure, but a summary:&#xD;
Eligible Stroke Survivors are recruited and asked to a) provide self-reports on their wellbeing every 3 months for up to 12 months; b) opt in or out of invitation to group-based support.&#xD;
Those who consent only to a) form our non-randomised COHORT arm who but do not receive treatment.&#xD;
Those who consent to both a) and b) form our INTENTION TO TREAT (ITT) group. When sufficient numbers of ITT participants are recruited, they are randomised for invitation to either the intervention (Acceptance and Commitment Therapy group) or an active control (social support group). Both groups are delivered over 8 weekly sessions and involve homework. ITT participants are only be invited to the group to which they are randomised and those who accept invitation will begin allocated groups immediately.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participants are only invited to the group to which they are randomised.&#xD;
Care providers are trained and cannot be masked&#xD;
Key outcomes are provided through self-report data from participants and therefore are masked. However, other outcomes - related to acceptability and feasibility - are collected by the research team. The research team is small and funding is minimal so we cannot mask the research team.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Study-specific participant qualitative interviews</measure>
    <time_frame>Following 8 week group support delivery,</time_frame>
    <description>This is a feasibility and acceptability study so no defined primary outcome (although we are collecting many candidate measures to explore standard deviations and inform primary outcome for any eventual phase III trial).&#xD;
Participant interviews will help us understand more about acceptability and feasibility, alongside observational data e.g. recruitment rates; retention rates; satisfaction and acceptability; fidelity measures etc.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Study-specific participant feedback questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Following 8 week group support delivery</time_frame>
    <description>As above, with all participants being asked to complete feedback questionnaires after groups, even if they do not wish to participate in interviews</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptance and Commitment Therapy Fidelity Measure (ACT-FM)</measure>
    <time_frame>Following 8 week ACT group support delivery</time_frame>
    <description>To help us understand if we can /have achieved fidelity to intervention; a key piece of knowledge that will inform feasibility of a phase III trial. All ACT group sessions will be video recorded with a randomly selected sample reviewed against the ACT-FM.&#xD;
ACT groups will run in May 2020 (N=2) and October 2020 (N=2). There are 8 weekly recorded sessions per group, giving a maximum of 34 recorded sessions.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Psychological distress at baseline and every 3 months as measured by Clinical Outcomes in Routine Evaluation 10 (CORE-10)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline + every 3 months up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>PLEASE NOTE: We are finalising a systematic review and Patient and Carer Collaboration sessions that will determine which of these two tools we use in our research. The final choice will be made based on psychometric credentials as well as consideration of the overall burden of completion of outcome measure surveys.&#xD;
We are likely to use the Clinical Outcomes in Routine Evaluation 10 (CORE-10), as stated above but are also considering the Depression, Anxiety and Stress Scale - 21 Items (DASS-21)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mood at baseline and every 3 months as measured by General Health Questionnaire - 12 items (GHQ12)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline + every 3 months up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>PLEASE NOTE: We are finalising a systematic review and Patient and Carer Collaboration sessions that will determine which of these two tools we use in our research. The final choice will be made based on psychometric credentials as well as consideration of the overall burden of completion of outcome measure surveys.&#xD;
We are likely to use the General Health Questionnaire - 12 items (GHQ12), as stated above but are also considering the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Personal wellbeing at baseline and every 3 months as measured by the Office of National Statistics (ONS) four subjective well-being questions (ONS4)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline + every 3 months up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>PLEASE NOTE: We are finalising a systematic review and Patient and Carer Collaboration sessions that will determine which of these two tools we use in our research. The final choice will be made based on psychometric credentials as well as consideration of the overall burden of completion of outcome measure surveys.&#xD;
We are likely to use the Personal Wellbeing Score (PWS) based on the Office of National Statistics (ONS) four subjective well-being questions (ONS4), as stated above but are also considering the Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System Global 10 (PROMIS-10)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Psychological flexibility at baseline and every 3 months as measured by the Acceptance and. Action Questionnaire - Acquired Brain Injury (AAQ-ABI)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline + every 3 months up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>PLEASE NOTE: We are finalising a systematic review and Patient and Carer Collaboration sessions that will determine which of these two tools we use in our research. The final choice will be made based on psychometric credentials as well as consideration of the overall burden of completion of outcome measure surveys.&#xD;
Psychological flexibility is a concept representing adjustment and acceptance; it is the target process of Acceptance and Commitment Therapy interventions.&#xD;
We are likely to use the Acceptance and. Action Questionnaire - Acquired Brain Injury (AAQ-ABI), as stated above but are also considering the Acceptance and. Action Questionnaire (AAQ-II).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Valued living measure at baseline and every 3 months as measured by the Valuing Questionnaire (VQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline + every 3 months up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>PLEASE NOTE: We are finalising a systematic review and Patient and Carer Collaboration sessions that will determine which of these two tools we use in our research. The final choice will be made based on psychometric credentials as well as consideration of the overall burden of completion of outcome measure surveys.&#xD;
Like psychological flexibility, valued living is another target process measure of Acceptance and Commitment Therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>modified Barthel Index (self-report)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>measure of stroke severity</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Oxford Cognitive Screen (OCS) - Remote</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>means of describing participants baseline cognitive profile</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Frenchay Aphasia Screening Test (FAST) - remote &amp; Therapy Outcome Measure for Communication Activities</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>means of describing participants baseline communication profile</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <condition>Psychological Distress</condition>
  <condition>Cognitive Dysfunction</condition>
  <condition>Communication Disorders</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>non-randomised no treatment arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants who do not opt in to group support will only provide self-report data on their wellbeing and quality of life every 3 months for up to 12 months. Data collected through online survey platforms using validated questionnaires</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>randomised invite Acceptance and Commitment Therapy (ACT) Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Only those who opt in to invites for group support will be randomised. Randomisation will occur once sufficient numbers have been recruited and in a 2:1 ratio (intervention: attention control). Participants in this arm will be invited to 8 weekly ACT-informed therapy sessions involving core values identification, mindfulness practices and committed action plans. There will be homework in between sessions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>randomised invite Social Support Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Only those who opt in to invites for group support will be randomised. Randomisation will occur once sufficient numbers have been recruited and in a 2:1 ratio (intervention: attention control). Participants in this arm will be invited to 8 weekly group sessions involving social support activities. There will be homework in between sessions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acceptance and Commitment Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>eight two hour remote sessions (50 minutes activity + 20 minute break + 50 minutes activity). Acceptance and Commitment Therapy (ACT) is a third wave transdiagnostic cognitive-behavioural therapy that supports clients to adjust to current experiences and 'commit' to behaviours that are congruent with their personal values, in order to promote psychological well-being and prevent future mental health crisis. ACT uses a variety of experiential techniques to support this process including: mindfulness practices; exercises to identify personal values; commitment to goals for valued living.</description>
    <arm_group_label>randomised invite Acceptance and Commitment Therapy (ACT) Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Social Support (Attention Control)</intervention_name>
    <description>eight two hour remote sessions (50 minutes activity + 20 minute break + 50 minutes activity). The active comparator is a group-based, paraprofessional-facilitated socialisation protocol, which has been used as a credible control for factors such as enjoyment of therapy, dropout rates and client expectations. It is developed to be acceptable to potential trial participants and control for the Hawthorne and placebo effects of trial participation, without containing putative active elements of the ACT-based intervention. The goal of the attention control comparator group is to engage participants in neutrally loaded topics that are of interest to the participants for the same duration - and in the same remote medium - as the intervention group. This comparator also tackles the methodological issues of clustering caused by group delivery in the intervention arm.</description>
    <arm_group_label>randomised invite Social Support Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion / Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adults in the UK (at least 18 years old)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. At least 4 months post-stroke (no upper limit);&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Who identify as having unmet needs in terms of psychological adjustment to stroke and&#xD;
             psychological distress. Since exploring eligibility criteria is an aim of this&#xD;
             feasibility study, self-report of these symptoms will be sufficient for inclusion.&#xD;
             Participants who identify as severely anxious or depressed (or at risk of harm) are&#xD;
             likely to be excluded from this research, with information on referral to more&#xD;
             appropriate expert psychological support will be provided.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Sufficient English language to engage in groups / complete measures&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Ability to engage in remote group interventions. The groups will be designed to&#xD;
             include those who have traditionally been excluded from work like this e.g. those with&#xD;
             cognitive and/or communicative difficulties. However, it is important to highlight&#xD;
             that this is not an intervention designed for severe issues in these areas. We will&#xD;
             aim to include all participants who self-report a willingness and ability to engage in&#xD;
             the research, using the required technologies.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Ultimately, we aim to be as inclusive as possible for this study as there are many novel&#xD;
        components of the research that we are exploring in terms of feasibility and acceptability.&#xD;
        The data collected during the feasibility study describing sample characteristics,&#xD;
        acceptability and outcomes may inform formal cut offs to be used in an eventual phase III&#xD;
        RCT.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Emma Patchwood, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+441612753401</phone>
    <email>emma.patchwood@manchester.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Manchester</name>
      <address>
        <city>Manchester</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Emma Patchwood, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.research.manchester.ac.uk/portal/en/researchers/emma-patchwood(7ef3b4bb-aaae-40cb-a6e4-112efe225d5e).html</url>
    <description>Chief Investigator Research profile</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 4, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 7, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Manchester</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr Emma Patchwood</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Research Fellow</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Acceptance and Commitment Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Psychotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Paraprofessionals</keyword>
  <keyword>Feasibility trial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communication Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cognitive Dysfunction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

