<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04653025</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IIS0816</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04653025</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Immedaite vs Early Implant Placement in Aesthetic Area</brief_title>
  <official_title>Immediate Placement and Temporization of Tapered Implants in Extraction Sockets or Early Implant Placement Protocol? A Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vilniaus Implantologijos Centro (VIC) Klinika</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut Straumann AG</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vilniaus Implantologijos Centro (VIC) Klinika</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this randomized clinical trial, of 50 patients in need of a maxillary anterior&#xD;
      implant, was to assess the esthetic outcomes of immediate temporization of immediately placed&#xD;
      tapered implants in fresh extraction sockets with soft tissue and bone augmentation as&#xD;
      compared to early placed implants with conventional loading. Secondary objectives included&#xD;
      the influence of immediate provisionalization on the success rate of tapered implants and&#xD;
      crestal bone stability.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients with a failing maxillary anterior tooth were included in this study. After&#xD;
      atraumatic extraction, test group patients received an immediate implant with provisional&#xD;
      restoration, while patients in the control group received an implant after 6 weeks of&#xD;
      healing. After 4 months (test group) and 6 months (control group) definitive restorations&#xD;
      were delivered. All patients were followed for 1 year post restoration and pink esthetic&#xD;
      score (PES), mid-buccal mucosal level (MBML), crestal bone changes (CBC) and peri-implant&#xD;
      soft tissue parameters were recorded at several time points. In addition, patient chair time&#xD;
      was recorded.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 10, 2030</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 10, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients with a failing maxillary anterior tooth were included in this study. After atraumatic extraction, test group patients received an immediate implant with provisional restoration, while patients in the control group received an implant after 6 weeks of healing. After 4 months (test group) and 6 months (control group) definitive restorations were delivered. All patients were followed for 1 year post restoration and pink esthetic score (PES), mid-buccal mucosal level (MBML), crestal bone changes (CBC) and peri-implant soft tissue parameters were recorded at several time points. In addition, patient chair time was recorded</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of pink aesthetic score (PES) over time</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 year and 5 years after prosthetic delivery</time_frame>
    <description>pink esthetic score means evaluation of seven parameters of anterior tooth aesthetics - mesial and distal papila, soft tissue level, contour, texture, color and convexity. Each parameter may be evaluated by score 0,1 or 2, were the score 0 means the worst outcome, 2 - the best. Evaluation will be performed visually using digital photos.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of marginal bone level (MBL) around implant neck</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 year and 5 years after prosthetic delivery</time_frame>
    <description>Periapical x-rays will be used to measure crestal bone sability distally and mesially of dental implant using certificated x-ray program after calibration. Measurement will be recorded in millimetres from implant neck to the first bone to implant contact</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Recession changes of gingiva of restored tooth on the implant</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 year and 5 years after prosthetic delivery</time_frame>
    <description>Mid-buccal recession evaluation will be performed using standardised periodontal probe. Measurement of the crown hight will be done in the middle of the tooth from incisal edge to the highest point and recorded in millimetres.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Single Implant; Immediate Implant Treatment; Early Implant Treatment</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Test group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Test group patients received an immediate implant with provisional restoration, bone augmentation and soft tissue grafting</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in the control group received soft tissue grafting after tooth extraction and an implant with bone augmentation after 6 weeks of healing.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Implant placement</intervention_name>
    <description>After tooth extraction implants were placed either immediate or delayed approach</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Test group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. no recession of gingival contour of tooth to be extracted,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. no periodontal bone loss of neighboring anterior teeth,&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. no implants in neighboring teeth,&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. class I extraction socket (intact buccal wall),&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. atraumatic extraction of the tooth with intact socket walls remaining,&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. only one implant per patient to be inserted.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. deep bite (severe II class),&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. systemic disease (diabetes, osteoporosis),&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. heavy smokers (more than 10 cigarettes/day) were excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. atraumatic extraction of the tooth failed,&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. the primary stability (at least 25 Ncm) needed for implant temporization, after&#xD;
             implant placement, was not achieved.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VIC clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vilnius</city>
        <zip>10205</zip>
        <country>Lithuania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Lithuania</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 19, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 26, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 26, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 26, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 4, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Vilniaus Implantologijos Centro (VIC) Klinika</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Algirdas Puisys, DDS, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>There is no plan to share IPD</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

