<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04653896</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>A3228-R</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>RX-003228-01A2</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04653896</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Powered Exoskeleton for Veterans With Knee OA</brief_title>
  <official_title>Design Improvements and Evaluation of a Knee Stress-Relief Powered Exoskeleton for Veterans With Knee Osteoarthritis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>VA Pittsburgh Healthcare System</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate in-laboratory mobility outcomes, pain perception,&#xD;
      and user satisfaction with the Keeogo , a robotic exoskeleton for providing assistance on&#xD;
      knees during stand and swing for a population with impaired mobility, as compare with&#xD;
      standard knee braces. The investigators hypothesize that participants could have improved&#xD;
      performance outcomes on walk test, timed up and go test, stair test, pick up penny from floor&#xD;
      test, and the Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB) when using the Keeogo as compared&#xD;
      with their prescribed knee braces.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Knee osteoarthritis (OA) is a growing problem due to increased longevity and obesity with&#xD;
      estimates of 14 million people living with this impairment. Knee OA results in decreased&#xD;
      activity and lifestyle changes, further exacerbating an individual's health. Exoskeleton&#xD;
      technology (Keeogo , B-temia, Inc.) may be a viable alternative to standard knee OA treatment&#xD;
      by providing powered support to reduce pain during mobility. To the investigators' knowledge,&#xD;
      the Keeogo is the only commercially available (in Canada) robotic exoskeleton for a&#xD;
      non-paralyzed population who can stand and initiate a stepping action, but have impaired&#xD;
      mobility for functional tasks. Keeogo provides active assistance during stance and swing&#xD;
      phases and assists users to perform functional mobility tasks including walking, stair&#xD;
      climbing, sit-to-stand, bending, squatting, and kneeling. Preliminary studies with the Keeogo&#xD;
      in six persons with knee OA showed efficacy for pain reduction during different mobility&#xD;
      tasks. Keeogo may have the potential to address functional mobility problems and pain in&#xD;
      Veterans with knee OA but is not yet approved by the FDA. An in-laboratory evaluation of&#xD;
      performance outcomes using the Keeogo compared with standard knee braces are lacking. Absence&#xD;
      of published prescription and general guidelines for use in Veterans with knee OA were also&#xD;
      identified as limitations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate in-laboratory mobility outcomes, pain perception,&#xD;
      and user satisfaction with the Keeogo as compare with standard knee braces. The investigators&#xD;
      hypothesize that participants could have improved performance outcomes on mobility tests,&#xD;
      including a 6-minute walk test, timed up and go test, 13-step stair test, pick up penny from&#xD;
      floor test, and the Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB) when using the Keeogo as&#xD;
      compared with their prescribed knee braces and reduced pain with the Keeogo by the numeric&#xD;
      pain rating scale (NPRS) as compared with their prescribed knee braces for the mobility&#xD;
      tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A knee OA-specific tuning protocol will be developed and used in the in-laboratory&#xD;
      evaluations in 26 Veterans with knee OA at the James J. Peters VA Medical Center, Bronx, NY.&#xD;
      This in-laboratory study is expected to demonstrate improved walking velocities, stair&#xD;
      ascent/descent times, improved sit-to-stand, stand-to-sit, and object retrieval from the&#xD;
      floor with reduced pain while participants use the Keeogo.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>We will conduct a functional mobility comparison between Keeogo and knee braces among participants with knee OA. A within-subject design is selected. We plan to have 2 or 3 1-hour sessions per week (up to 12 sessions) for tuning the Keeogo and letting the participants be familiar with the device. After that, participants will be evaluated through a series of mobility tests using their prescribed knee braces and Keeogo configured with tuned parameters, respectively. If participants can complete the mobility tests without their knee braces we will also collect these data. The functional mobility tests will include the 6 Minute Walk Test, Timed Up and Go, 13-step Stair Test, Pick up Penny from Floor Test, and Short Physical Performance Battery. The investigators expect to use two separate sessions to finish the evaluations. The order of using the Keeogo and their knee braces will be randomized. There will be a 10-min break between each test. Participants could request a longer break time.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of 6-Minute Walk Test results among different conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 minutes for each condition: 1) using the Keeogo, 2) using the prescribed knee brace, and 3) using nothing on the knee (optional)</time_frame>
    <description>Walk as far as possible for 6 minutes. Distance in meters and speed in meter/second.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of Timed Up and Go Test results among different conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 minutes for each condition: 1) using the Keeogo, 2) using the prescribed knee brace, and 3) using nothing on the knee (optional)</time_frame>
    <description>Time in seconds to stand up from a chair, walk 10 feet, turn, walk back to the chair, and sit down.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of 13-Step Stair Test results among different conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 minutes for each condition: 1) using the Keeogo, 2) using the prescribed knee brace, and 3) using nothing on the knee (optional)</time_frame>
    <description>Ascend and descend a 13-step stair as quickly as possible but safely. Time in seconds till both feet on the top as ascent time. Time in seconds till both feet on the bottom as descent time.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of Pick Up Penny from Floor Test results among different conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 minutes for each condition: 1) Using the Keeogo; 2) Using the prescribed knee brace; 3) Using nothing on the knee (optional)</time_frame>
    <description>Time in seconds to bend, scoop, lunge, or squat to retrieve a penny from the floor and return to standing. Scored as: not able to perform, perform with physical assistance, perform unassisted</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of Short Physical Performance Battery results among different conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 15 minutes for each condition: 1) using the Keeogo, 2) using the prescribed knee brace, and 3) Using nothing on the knee (optional)</time_frame>
    <description>Three tests to assess lower extremity functioning: ability to stand for 10 seconds with feet in 3 different positions (together side-by-side, semi-tandem, and tandem), two timed 4-meter walk, and time to rise from a chair five times. Overall score from 0 to 12 with higher score indicating better lower extremity function.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of Numeric Pain Rating Scale results among different conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 minutes for each condition: 1) using the Keeogo, 2) using the prescribed knee brace, and 3) using nothing on the knee (optional)</time_frame>
    <description>Rate pain on an 11-point numerical scale (0- no pain at all; 10- worst imaginable pain)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>System Usability Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Reliable 10-item scale to evaluate device usability with a 5-point Likert scale from strongly disagree to strongly agree. Overall score from 0 to 100 with higher score indicating better usability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Usefulness Satisfaction and Ease of Use Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Reliable 30-item scale to evaluate four dimensions of usability including usefulness, ease of use, ease of learning, and satisfaction with a 7-point Likert scale. Average score from 0 to 7 for each dimension with higher score indicating better usability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">26</enrollment>
  <condition>Knee Osteoarthritis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Knee OA group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Individuals who are over 18 years and have medical diagnosis of Grade 3 or 4 knee OA</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Keeogo</intervention_name>
    <description>The Keeogo is the only commercially available (in Canada) robotic exoskeleton for a non-paralyzed population who can stand and initiate a stepping action, but have impaired mobility for functional tasks. Keeogo provides active assistance during stance and swing phases and assists users to perform functional mobility tasks including walking, stair climbing, sit-to-stand, bending, squatting, and kneeling.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Knee OA group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  medical diagnosis of Grade 3 or 4 knee OA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have a prescribed knee brace for at least three months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  self-reported knee pain when standing, walking, climbing stairs, squatting, or other&#xD;
             mobility activities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  self-reported limitations to mobility and walking activities due to knee pain,&#xD;
             stiffness, loss of range of motion&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  neurological paralysis causing an inability to stand, weight bear or take stepping&#xD;
             movements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  fixed contractures resulting in limited range of motion in the hip, knees, or ankles&#xD;
             that prevent sitting, standing, walking, and/or squatting activities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  able to walk at a normal walking speed (&gt;1.2 m/s) based on a 6-minute walk test (6MWT)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  anthropometric incompatibility with the device&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any medical complication or co-morbidity as judged by the study physician to be&#xD;
             contraindicated for wearing the device or walking (e.g., cardiovascular disorders,&#xD;
             pressure ulcers, open wounds, lower limb vascular disorders, or other medical&#xD;
             conditions)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a score of &lt;8/10 on the MacArthur Competence Assessment Tool for Treatment (MacCAT-T)&#xD;
             (as a proxy for cognitive competency screening); and 7) pregnancy or planning on&#xD;
             becoming pregnant&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ann M Spungen, EdD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>James J. Peters Veterans Affairs Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ann M Spungen, EdD</last_name>
    <phone>(718) 584-9000</phone>
    <phone_ext>5814</phone_ext>
    <email>Ann.Spungen@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Dan Ding, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>(412) 688-6000</phone>
    <email>dad5@pitt.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>James J. Peters VA Medical Center, Bronx, NY</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bronx</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10468</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ann M Spungen, EdD</last_name>
      <phone>718-584-9000</phone>
      <phone_ext>5814</phone_ext>
      <email>Ann.Spungen@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Chung-Yung Tsai, PT PhD</last_name>
      <phone>(718) 584-9000</phone>
      <phone_ext>3130</phone_ext>
      <email>chung-ying.tsai@va.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ann M Spungen, EdD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mcleod JC, Ward SJ, Hicks AL. Evaluation of the Keeogo™ Dermoskeleton. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. 2019 Jul;14(5):503-512. doi: 10.1080/17483107.2017.1396624. Epub 2017 Nov 2.</citation>
    <PMID>29092649</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McGibbon CA, Sexton A, Jayaraman A, Deems-Dluhy S, Gryfe P, Novak A, Dutta T, Fabara E, Adans-Dester C, Bonato P. Evaluation of the Keeogo exoskeleton for assisting ambulatory activities in people with multiple sclerosis: an open-label, randomized, cross-over trial. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2018 Dec 12;15(1):117. doi: 10.1186/s12984-018-0468-6.</citation>
    <PMID>30541585</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>knee</keyword>
  <keyword>arthritis</keyword>
  <keyword>walking</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

