<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04655365</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PROSTEP-002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04655365</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Detecting Metastases by PyL PET/CT in Subjects Starting Enzalutamide for Untreated Castration Resistant Prostate Cancer.</brief_title>
  <acronym>PROSTEP-002</acronym>
  <official_title>Detection and Monitoring of Metastasis by 18F-DCFPyL PET/CT in Subjects Starting Enzalutamide for Untreated Castration Resistant Prostate Cancer and Negative Conventional Imaging</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>CHU de Quebec-Universite Laval</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Astellas Pharma Europe Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>CHU de Quebec-Universite Laval</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aimed to evaluate the diagnostic performance of 18F-DCFPyL (PyL) PET/CT in&#xD;
      subjects presenting not previously treated for castration resistant prostate cancer and&#xD;
      showing negative or equivocal findings per institutional standard of care conventional&#xD;
      imaging&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Prostate cancer (PCa) is the most common solid organ cancer in North American men and is&#xD;
      initially androgen sensitive. Therefore, castration and/or androgen receptor blockade remains&#xD;
      the central palliative treatment once PCa has metastasized or failed to locoregional&#xD;
      therapies. Because androgen deprivation therapy is not curative, all patients will eventually&#xD;
      progress to the metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer state. About 5% of prostate&#xD;
      cancers will be metastatic by conventional imaging techniques at diagnosis while most&#xD;
      patients achieving CRPC state will first be localized and then progress to metastatic state&#xD;
      later in the disease course. Therefore, a significant proportion of patients will progress&#xD;
      through an intermediary state of disease defined as the non-metastatic CRPC state (M0CRPC).&#xD;
      Over the last year and a half, M0CRPC treatment landscape has completely changed with&#xD;
      demonstrating the benefits of second-generation antiandrogens (darolutamide, enzalutamide and&#xD;
      apalutamide) to prevent progression of M0CRPC patients. Enzalutamide have then been approved&#xD;
      by the Federal Drug Administration and Health Canada for the treatment of M0CRPC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the other hand, conventional imaging techniques based on bone turnover (bone scan (BS)) or&#xD;
      anatomical features (magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) or computed tomography (CT)) have&#xD;
      important limitations and poor accuracy. Bone scans (BS) is the commonest imaging technique&#xD;
      used to detect bone metastases in the clinics. BS does not image directly cancer cells, but&#xD;
      the effect of cancer on the bone. Other pathologies such as fractures, degenerative arthritis&#xD;
      and other benign bone lesions can also cause focal uptake on BS and lead to false-positive&#xD;
      results. Another drawback of BS is its poor sensitivity to image small metastases confined to&#xD;
      bone marrow. These limitations stress the importance to improve PCa imaging by using new&#xD;
      imaging modalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Because novel agents targeting the androgen synthesis and receptor axis (e.g. enzalutamide),&#xD;
      bone metastasis (radium-223) and microtubules assembly (docetaxel, cabazitaxel) have been&#xD;
      shown to increase metastatic CRPC patients overall survival, a burning question is to&#xD;
      determine if the non-metastatic CRPC status is real. There is growing evidence that newer&#xD;
      imaging techniques using positron emission tomography can improve metastasis detection&#xD;
      accuracy and may refine PCa patient prognostic stratification and treatment eligibility.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 4, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the metastasis detection rate by 18F -DCFPyL-PSMA PET/CT in patients presenting with non metastatic castration resistant prostate cancers defined by conventional imaging and a rising PSA&gt;1ng/mL</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The number of metastasis per compartment (bone, visceral, lymph node) will be determined by 18F-DCFPyL-PET/CT.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the intrapatient and interpatient 18F-DCFPyL-PSMA response rates defined by a 50% decrease in intralesional 18F-DCFPyL-PSMA uptake or 50% decrease in sum metastasis 18F-DCFPyL-PSMA uptake after 3 months of enzalutamide.</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the changes in 18F-DCFPyL-PSMA sum metastasis SUVmax for each patient and the changes of 18F-DCFPyL-PSMA SUVmax in each lesion after 3 months of enzalutamide.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number and sites of metastasis detected by 18F-DCFPyL-PSMA PET/CT at several PSA thresholds.</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of metastasis per compartment (bone, visceral, lymph node) determined by 18F-DCFPyL-PET/CT when PSA is &lt;1 ng/mL, 1 to 5 ng/mL and &gt; 5 ng/mL.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the percentage of patients showing metastatic lesions with enough 18F-DCFPyL uptake (above that of the liver) to justify radioligand therapy before and 3 months after enzalutamide treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Analyze if a patient shows one or several lesions with a 18F-DCFPyL uptake more than that of the liver.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Untreated Castration Resistant Prostate Cancer and Negative Conventional Imaging Subjects</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Enrolled subjects will receive a single dose of 9 mCi (333 MBq) 18F-DCFPyL Injection followed by a single PET/CT scan acquired at 1-2 hours post-dosing. After initial 18F-DCFPyL PET/CT, the patients with positive 18F-DCFPyL PET/CT imaging will be treated with enzalutamide (160 mg po id) for M0CRPC disease within less than two weeks. 18F-DCFPyL PET/CT scan will then be repeated 90 days after the start of enzalutamide treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Enzalutamide capsule</intervention_name>
    <description>160 mg po id</description>
    <arm_group_label>Untreated Castration Resistant Prostate Cancer and Negative Conventional Imaging Subjects</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Xantdi</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the prostate per original diagnosis, with&#xD;
             undergoing androgen deprivation therapy such as prior bilateral orchiectomy or&#xD;
             surgical castration or LHRH-agonists/LHRH-antagonists.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspected recurrence of prostate cancer based on rising PSA under androgen deprivation&#xD;
             therapy. Recurrent castration resistant prostate cancer patients is defined by a&#xD;
             rising PSA &gt;1 ng/mL under ADT or surgical castration and with testosterone castration&#xD;
             levels &lt; 1.7 nM (PCWG3 criteria).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative or equivocal findings for prostate cancer on conventional imaging bone scan&#xD;
             AND 2) abdomen-pelvis CT/MRI and chest CT or FDG-PET/CT) performed as standard of care&#xD;
             workup within 42 days of Day 1(accrual).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject is candidate for second line androgen axis targeted inhibitors such as&#xD;
             enzalutamide and planned to receive it.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy ≥6 months as determined by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to provide signed informed consent and comply with protocol&#xD;
             requirement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PSA doubling time less or equal to 10 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects administered any high energy (&gt;300 KeV) gamma-emitting radioisotope within 5&#xD;
             physical half-lives prior to study drug injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of investigational drug therapy for prostate cancer within 60 days of Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with any medical condition or other circumstances that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator, compromise obtaining reliable data, achieving study objectives, or&#xD;
             completing the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to enzalutamide&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with 5-α reductase inhibitors (finasteride, dutasteride) within 4 weeks of&#xD;
             randomization.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Frédéric Pouliot, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CHU de Québec-Université Laval</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Marjorie Besançon, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>418 525-4444</phone>
    <phone_ext>20417</phone_ext>
    <email>marjorie.besancon@crchudequebec.ulaval.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Marilyn Savard</last_name>
    <phone>418 525-4444</phone>
    <phone_ext>16848</phone_ext>
    <email>Marilyn.Savard@crchudequebec.ulaval.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU de Québec-Université Laval</name>
      <address>
        <city>Québec</city>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marjorie Besancon, PhD</last_name>
      <email>marjorie.besancon@crchudequebec.ulaval.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Marilyn Savard</last_name>
      <email>Marilyn.Savard@crchudequebec.ulaval.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Frédéric Pouliot, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 30, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 7, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 30, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 30, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 7, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Untreated Castration Resistant Prostate Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>18F-DCFPyL</keyword>
  <keyword>Enzalutamide</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

