<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04656015</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>cardiac MRI in IBD patient</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04656015</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cardiovascular Manifestation of Inflamatory Bowel Disease Patient ( Tissue Doppler Echocardiography and Cardiac MRI )</brief_title>
  <official_title>Cardiovascular Manifestation of Inflamatory Bowel Disease Patient ( Tissue Doppler Echocardiography and Cardiac MRI )</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      1. Evaluation of cardiovascular changes using Doppler echocardiography and cardiac MRI in&#xD;
           IBD patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To detect the frequency of myocardial injury in IBD patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To detect the sensitivity and specificity of echocardiography for the detection of&#xD;
           cardiac injury in comparison to cardiac MRI in IBD patients&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The burden of extra-intestinal disease is high in patients with IBD, some of whom respond to&#xD;
      or are prevented by treating the bowel inflammation, whereas others require specific&#xD;
      treatment because they are independent of the underlying bowel inflammation .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiovascular diseases are the major causes of mortality and morbidity worldwide. They may&#xD;
      arise for various reasons such as obesity, type 2 diabetes, genetic, environmental, dietary,&#xD;
      and lifestyle factors. Besides all these, there is much evidence suggesting that inflammation&#xD;
      is an important player in the pathogenesis of heart disease, as well as atherogenesis and&#xD;
      atherosclerosis . A most common systemic inflammatory disease is inflammatory bowel disease&#xD;
      (IBD), which is a collection of ulcerative colitis and Crohn's disease, a chronic intestinal&#xD;
      disease that may arise due to different factors, and is precipitated by environmental and&#xD;
      genetic susceptibility Tissue Doppler imaging (TDI) is a useful echocardiographic technique&#xD;
      to evaluate global and regional myocardial systolic as well as diastolic function. It can&#xD;
      also be used to quantify right ventricular and left atrial function.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date, cardiac magnetic resonance imaging (cMRI) is mostly used to detect significantly&#xD;
      decreased EFs and abnormalities in wall motion. Contrast enhancement (CE) CMR is a more&#xD;
      sensitive technique of cMRI and can detect areas of myocardial damage in patients with acute&#xD;
      myocarditis .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of cardiovascular affection in IBD patients</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of cardiovascular affection in IBD patients</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of cardiovascular affection in IBD patients</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of cardiovascular affection in IBD patients</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Cardiac MRI in IBD Patient</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MRI</intervention_name>
    <description>cMRI will be done only to patients presented with signs of HF, with raised cardiac biomarkers and echocardiographic signs of myocardial injury&#xD;
The Lake Louise diagnostic criteria for CMR in myocarditis:&#xD;
CMR findings are consistent with myocardial inflammation if at least two of the following criteria are present:&#xD;
Regional or global myocardial signal intensity increase in T2-weighted images&#xD;
Increased global myocardial early gadolinium enhancement ratio between myocardium and skeletal muscle in gadolinium-enhanced T1-weighted images&#xD;
There is at least one focal lesion with non-ischemic regional distribution on late gadolinium enhancement Presence of left ventricular dysfunction or pericardial effusion provides additional, supportive evidence for myocarditis 6. Carotid du</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        IBD patients presented with disease flare, which is grouped by the 3 domains of disease&#xD;
        severity:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable inflammatory burden (C-reactive protein, mucosal lesions, upper&#xD;
             gastrointestinal involvement, and disease extent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Disease course (including structural damage, history/extension of intestinal&#xD;
             resection, perianal disease, number of flares, and extraintestinal manifestations)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IBD patients presented with disease flare, which is grouped by the 3 domains of&#xD;
             disease severity:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Measurable inflammatory burden (C-reactive protein, mucosal lesions, upper&#xD;
                  gastrointestinal involvement, and disease extent.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Disease course (including structural damage, history/extension of intestinal&#xD;
                  resection, perianal disease, number of flares, and extraintestinal&#xD;
                  manifestations)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with poor echocardiographic window, previously diagnosed as IHD, complete&#xD;
             heart block, mitral stenosis, prosthetic mitral valve, congenital heart disease with a&#xD;
             left to right shunt, and CKD patients will be excluded from the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Khaled Mohamed</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut univerty</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mervat Sayed</last_name>
    <phone>01018602654</phone>
    <email>mervatsayed030@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bernstein CN, Benchimol EI, Bitton A, Murthy SK, Nguyen GC, Lee K, Cooke-Lauder J, Kaplan GG. The Impact of Inflammatory Bowel Disease in Canada 2018: Extra-intestinal Diseases in IBD. J Can Assoc Gastroenterol. 2019 Feb;2(Suppl 1):S73-S80. doi: 10.1093/jcag/gwy053. Epub 2018 Nov 2.</citation>
    <PMID>31294387</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Matsuura E, Atzeni F, Sarzi-Puttini P, Turiel M, Lopez LR, Nurmohamed MT. Is atherosclerosis an autoimmune disease? BMC Med. 2014 Mar 18;12:47. doi: 10.1186/1741-7015-12-47. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24642015</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fung G, Luo H, Qiu Y, Yang D, McManus B. Myocarditis. Circ Res. 2016 Feb 5;118(3):496-514. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.115.306573. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26846643</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 4, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 7, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 4, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 4, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 7, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mervat Sayed Kamal Sayed</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>resident doctor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Intestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

