<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04659330</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>17/41/458</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04659330</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lipohypertrophy Monitoring Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>LiMo</acronym>
  <official_title>Lipohypertrophy Monitoring Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Antwerp</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Becton, Dickinson and Company</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Antwerp</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators intend to audit the impact of optimal injection technique education&#xD;
      delivered through a multimodal tailored approach augmented with a digital 'tailorable'&#xD;
      patient learning platform on clinical parameters and self-care behaviours of insulin treated&#xD;
      patients in a prospective audit with follow-up in 6 months, conducted in multiple sites&#xD;
      across Belgium. Diabetes patients with or without lipohypertrophy will be entered into the&#xD;
      audit. The end points measured will include the impact on consumption of insulin, long term&#xD;
      blood glucose control (HbA1c), hypoglycaemia, glucose variability, needle reuse, patient&#xD;
      injection habits and clinician education, training and information inputs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Principle objective To assess the impact of optimal injection technique education, tailored&#xD;
      learning prescription and use of BD Micro-FineTM Ultra 4mm x 32G pen needle upon total daily&#xD;
      dose of insulin consumption in patients with or without clinically detectable&#xD;
      lipohypertrophy. To assess the cost of intervention vs. direct savings with a view to use of&#xD;
      the data in needle reimbursement discussions with the Belgian health care authorities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess the impact of the intervention on other parameters of glucose control (including&#xD;
      HbA1c, unexplained hypoglycaemia and glycaemic variability). To calculate direct and indirect&#xD;
      savings associated with better glucose control.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tertiary objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess the impact of the intervention (especially eLearning) on patients' injection&#xD;
      technique self-care knowledge and behaviors, including correct site rotation, non-injection&#xD;
      into lipohypertrophy and needle reuse patterns. To calculate direct and indirect savings&#xD;
      associated with better educational approaches and behavioral changes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Audit Targets and Standards The sample size targeted will be 190 completed patient records.&#xD;
      Each center will be asked to contribute between 20-50 subjects. Optimal injection technique&#xD;
      and optimal needle length selection are based on Belgian guidelines on Injection, which are&#xD;
      based on recently published FITTER worldwide recommendations. A study day will be held for&#xD;
      participant nurses to review the protocol and audit forms, and for refresher training in&#xD;
      lipohypertrophy detection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endpoints Total Daily Dose (TDD) of insulin HbA1c (as mmol/mol) Unexplained hypoglycaemic&#xD;
      episodes (defined in Entry/Exit Forms) Severe hypoglycaemia (requiring the intervention of a&#xD;
      third party) Glycaemic variability (defined in Entry/Exit Forms) Rotation of injection sites&#xD;
      with spacing apart of punctures by at least 1 cm Reuse of needles&#xD;
&#xD;
      Presence of lipohypertrophy Injections into lipohypertrophic lesions Injection technique&#xD;
      practices Adherence to proposed best practice intervention recommendations Data with cost&#xD;
      implications (resource usage, hypoglycaemic events) Self-care injection technique knowledge&#xD;
      and behaviours Qualitative and quantitative BD and MeTM patient user experience Clinician&#xD;
      education, training and information inputs required support behaviour modification and&#xD;
      adherence to treatment Quality of Life assessment Unplanned Interventions: ER, Ambulance,&#xD;
      Hospital Admission, Critical Cared admission&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 24, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 31, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Primary outcome parameter was the evolution between baseline and end-of-study percentage of needle reuse and injecting in a zone of lipohypertrophy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Severe and unexplained hypoglycemia</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Primary outcome parameter was the evolution between baseline and end-of-study percentage of needle reuse and injecting in a zone of lipohypertrophy.&#xD;
Hypoglycemia is defined as the occurrence of ≥ 1 symptom and a confirmed glucose reading ≤60 mg/dl. Unexplained hypoglycemia is defined as hypoglycemia occurring in the absence of a definable precipitating event such as a change in medication, diet or activity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>glucose variability</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Primary outcome parameter was the evolution between baseline and end-of-study percentage of needle reuse and injecting in a zone of lipohypertrophy.&#xD;
Increased glucose variability was defined as the occurrence of at least 3 times a week glucose values evolving from &lt;60 mg/dl (3.3 mmol/l) to &gt;250 mg/dl (13.9 mmol/l) or vice versa (i.e. a delta &gt;190 mg/dl or 10.6 mmol/l).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insulin dose in patients with and without lipohypertrophy</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary objectives were to evaluate the impact of the use of 4mm pen needles and an educational platform focused on correct injection technique, correct rotation of injection sites, non-injection into lipohypertrophy sites and stopping needle reuse on the insulin dose in patients with and without lipohypertrophy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">171</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <condition>Lipohypertrophy</condition>
  <condition>Hypoglycemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients underwent intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Online education (BdandMe) for injection technique</intervention_name>
    <description>patients were referred to the relevant modules on BD and Me™ (for online education)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>4mm needles</intervention_name>
    <description>Providing a supply of needles for single use of 4mm insulin injection needle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Patient Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 or above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Injecting insulin for at least 1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-managing injection therapy, including daily glucose monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to a device with internet&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confident in navigating the internet&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children &lt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or likely to become pregnant during study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impaired cognitive ability which would prevent informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Syringe only user&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insulin pump user&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  GLP-1 RA therapy only&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients declining to take part in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cannot read and understand Dutch&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No access to an internet enabled device&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Antwerp University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edegem</city>
        <state>Antwerp</state>
        <zip>2650</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Frid AH, Kreugel G, Grassi G, Halimi S, Hicks D, Hirsch LJ, Smith MJ, Wellhoener R, Bode BW, Hirsch IB, Kalra S, Ji L, Strauss KW. New Insulin Delivery Recommendations. Mayo Clin Proc. 2016 Sep;91(9):1231-55. doi: 10.1016/j.mayocp.2016.06.010. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27594187</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Grassi G, Scuntero P, Trepiccioni R, Marubbi F, Strauss K. Optimizing insulin injection technique and its effect on blood glucose control. J Clin Transl Endocrinol. 2014 Jul 23;1(4):145-150. doi: 10.1016/j.jcte.2014.07.006. eCollection 2014 Dec.</citation>
    <PMID>29159095</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Frid AH, Hirsch LJ, Menchior AR, Morel DR, Strauss KW. Worldwide Injection Technique Questionnaire Study: Injecting Complications and the Role of the Professional. Mayo Clin Proc. 2016 Sep;91(9):1224-30. doi: 10.1016/j.mayocp.2016.06.012. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27594186</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Blanco M, Hernández MT, Strauss KW, Amaya M. Prevalence and risk factors of lipohypertrophy in insulin-injecting patients with diabetes. Diabetes Metab. 2013 Oct;39(5):445-53. doi: 10.1016/j.diabet.2013.05.006. Epub 2013 Jul 22.</citation>
    <PMID>23886784</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ji L, Sun Z, Li Q, Qin G, Wei Z, Liu J, Chandran AB, Hirsch LJ. Lipohypertrophy in China: Prevalence, Risk Factors, Insulin Consumption, and Clinical Impact. Diabetes Technol Ther. 2017 Jan;19(1):61-67. doi: 10.1089/dia.2016.0334.</citation>
    <PMID>28099050</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 2, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 2, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University Hospital, Antwerp</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Christophe De Block</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>lipohypertrophy</keyword>
  <keyword>online education</keyword>
  <keyword>insulin injection technique</keyword>
  <keyword>diabetes mellitus</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypoglycemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

