<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04652206</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SCO101-002</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-002627-11</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04652206</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Trial to Investigate Safety, Tolerability and MTD for SCO-101 in Combination With Gemcitabine and Nab-paclitaxel in Inoperable Pancreatic Cancer Patients.</brief_title>
  <acronym>PANTAX-Ib</acronym>
  <official_title>An Open-label Phase Ib Prospective Clinical Trial to Investigate Safety, Tolerability and Maximum Tolerated Dose for SCO-101 in Combination With Gemcitabine and Nab-paclitaxel in Inoperable Pancreatic Cancer Patients.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Scandion Oncology A/S</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Alcedis GmbH</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Scandion Oncology A/S</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      An open-label dose escalating phase Ib study of SCO-101 in combination with gemcitabine and&#xD;
      nab-paclitaxel. The primary objectives are to establish the safety profile and the MTD of&#xD;
      SCO-101 when combined with gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel. The starting dose of SCO-101 is&#xD;
      150 mg and the dose may be increased to a maximum of 350 mg.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is an open-label dose escalating phase Ib study of SCO-101 in combination with&#xD;
      gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel. The primary objective is to establish the safety,&#xD;
      tolerability and MTD of SCO-101 when combined with gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel. Secondary&#xD;
      objectives are efficacy and to establish PK parameters of SCO-101. The target indication is&#xD;
      patients with inoperal pancreatic cancer who are to be treated with gemcitabine and&#xD;
      nab-paclitaxel. The study is designed as a standard 3+3 dose escalation study with increasing&#xD;
      doses of SCO-101 and a fixed dose (standard regimen) of gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel. An&#xD;
      interim report will be prepared once the last patient in the MTD cohort has completed one&#xD;
      treatment cycle. Patients will continue treatment until disease progression to evaluate&#xD;
      secondary objectives. One treatment Cycle is 28 days. The starting dose of SCO-101 is 150 mg&#xD;
      6 daily dosing in a bi-weekly schedule) and may be increased to a maximum of 350 mg (5&#xD;
      cohorts with 50 mg increments). A total of up to 18 patients are anticipated if dose&#xD;
      escalation to the 5th cohort. Gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel is administered according to&#xD;
      local standard recommendations once weekly for three weeks followed by one weeks treatment&#xD;
      holiday (dosing on day 6, day 13 and day 20). Patients may continue treatment until treatment&#xD;
      progression.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 27, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 15, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Standard 3+3 dose escalation design to determine the Maximum Tolerated dose (MTD) of SCO-101 when administered in combination with gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel, in patients with inoperable pancreatic cancer</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and Tolerability</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, assessed up to 100 months</time_frame>
    <description>Safety and tolerability by assessing the number, frequency, and severity of adverse events (AEs) collected from the time of first treatment until four weeks after end of treatment to evaluate safety of SCO-101 in combination with gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel determined according to the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (NCI-CTCAE v.5.0).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Tolerated Dose</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of Cycle 1 (each cycle is 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD) of SCO-101 in combination with gemcitabine and nab-Paclitaxel by assessment of Dose Limiting Toxicities (DLT) to SCO-101.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Tumor assessment is performed every two treatment cycles (2 months), assessed up to 100 months.</time_frame>
    <description>defined as CR and PR using the RECIST v. 1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Benefit Rate (CBR)</measure>
    <time_frame>From benefit (CR, PR or SD &gt; 16 weeks) to progression, assessed up to 100 months</time_frame>
    <description>defined as the number of patients obtaining CR, PR, or SD &gt; 16 weeks according to RECIST v.1.1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dosing to progression, assessed up to 100 months</time_frame>
    <description>defined as time in months from the date of first study treatment with SCO-101 to the date of disease progression or death from any cause, whichever comes first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, assessed up to 100 months</time_frame>
    <description>defined as time in months from the date of first study treatment to the date of death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic profile</measure>
    <time_frame>during the first 14 treatment days in the first treatment cycle.</time_frame>
    <description>Pharmacokinetic profile of SCO-101 alone and in combination with gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Novel predictive biomarker feasibility</measure>
    <time_frame>assessed from first administration to end of treatment, assessed up to 100 months.</time_frame>
    <description>assessment of biomarkers from blood and tumor</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">18</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Locally Advanced Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Inoperable Disease</condition>
  <condition>Localized Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SCO-101 in combination with gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive escalating doses of SCO-101 in combination with the standard recommended dose of gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel according to local clinical practice. Gemcintabine and nab-paclitaxel is the recommended treatment for the patient group.&#xD;
Starting dose of SCO-101 is 150 mg. Maximum dose tested is 350 mg. The dose is increased with 50 mg increments between each cohort.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SCO-101</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral tablets with a strength of 50 mg or 150 mg according to dose level (cohort). Administered for 6 consequtive days in a bi-weekly schedule in each treatment cycle. Treatment until disease progression.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SCO-101 in combination with gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Gemcitabine</intervention_name>
    <description>Used according to marketing authorisation</description>
    <arm_group_label>SCO-101 in combination with gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nab paclitaxel</intervention_name>
    <description>Used according to marketing authorisation</description>
    <arm_group_label>SCO-101 in combination with gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Ability to understand and willingness to provide written informed consent before&#xD;
             any trial-related activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Age 18 years or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Histologically verified pancreatic adenocarcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Inoperable localized, locally advanced or metastatic pancreatic cancer, not&#xD;
             amenable for curatively intended treatment, in patients who are to be treated with&#xD;
             gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel.&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. Measurable or non-measurable disease determined by CT scan or MRI, according to&#xD;
             RECIST 1.1.&#xD;
&#xD;
             6. Performance status of ECOG ≤ 2 and expected to tolerate the standard recommended&#xD;
             (100%) gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
             7. Recovered to Grade 1 or less from prior surgery or acute toxicities of prior&#xD;
             radiotherapy or treatment with cytotoxic or biologic agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
             8. ≥ 2 weeks must have elapsed since any prior surgery or radiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
             9. Adequate conditions as evidenced by the following clinical laboratory values:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophils count (ANC) ≥ 1.5 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin is at least 6,0 mmol/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥ 100 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤ 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total serum bilirubin ≤ 1.0 ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 2.5 x ULN*&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine ≤ 1.5 ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  eGFR within normal limits.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adequate blood clothing function as defined by the International Normalized Ratio&#xD;
                  (INR) ≤ 1.2.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  10. Life expectancy longer than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  11. Sexually active males and females of child-producing potential must use&#xD;
                  highly effective contraception (intrauterine devices, hormonal contraceptives&#xD;
                  (contraceptive pills, implants, transdermal patches, hormonal vaginal devices or&#xD;
                  injections with prolonged release) for the study duration and at least 6 months&#xD;
                  after the last dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
                  12. Signed informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Concurrent chemotherapy, radiotherapy, or other investigational drug except&#xD;
             non-disease related conditions (e.g. insulin for diabetes) during study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Previous surgeries with resection of the complete stomach or greater part of small&#xD;
             intestines (excluding the duodenum), whereby absorption of SCO-101 may be affected.&#xD;
             Treatment with Creon or similar is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Difficulty in swallowing tablets.&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. CNS metastases requiring steroids.&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. Treatment with antibiotics for infections or with clinical symptoms of active&#xD;
             infection. Patients showing symptoms of CoViD19 must be tested for active CoViD19&#xD;
             infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
             6. Known HIV positivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
             7. Known active hepatitis B or C.&#xD;
&#xD;
             8. Clinically significant (i.e. active) cardiovascular disease:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stroke, Transient ischemic attack (TIA) or myocardial infarction within ≤ 6&#xD;
                  months prior to day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable angina or NYHA Grade II or greater congestive heart failure (CHF)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring medication&#xD;
&#xD;
                  9. Mental status, symptomatic epilepsy or other CNS disease where the&#xD;
                  investigator assess the patient not fit for the clinical study.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  10. Other medications or conditions that in the Investigator's opinion would&#xD;
                  contraindicate study participation of safety reasons or interfere with the&#xD;
                  interpretation of study results. Other severe medical conditions, including&#xD;
                  serious heart disease, unstable diabetes, uncontrolled hypercalcemia or previous&#xD;
                  organ transplants. Participation in another clinical trial with experimental&#xD;
                  medication within 30 days prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  11. Known hypersensitivity to gemcitabine and/or nab-paclitaxel&#xD;
&#xD;
                  12. Pregnant women or women who are breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
                  13. Prior or present neuropathy &gt; grade I (NCI-CTCAE v.5.0)&#xD;
&#xD;
                  14. Curatively intended treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Peter M Vestlev, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+4522779696</phone>
    <email>pmv@scandiononcology.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aalborg University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aalborg</city>
        <zip>9000</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Morten Ladekarl, Prof., DMSc</last_name>
      <email>morten.ladekarl@rn.dk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Morten Ladekarl, Prof., DMSc</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 26, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 3, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 26, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 26, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 3, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>pancreatic</keyword>
  <keyword>cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>non-resectable</keyword>
  <keyword>inoperable</keyword>
  <keyword>pancreatic adenocarcinoma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

