<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04658355</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2008991024</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04658355</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Chlorhexidine Gluconate Versus Povidone-iodine</brief_title>
  <acronym>CHDvPI</acronym>
  <official_title>Effect of Chlorhexidine Gluconate Versus Povidone-iodine on the Vaginal Microbiome as Vaginal Operative Preparation During Gynecologic Surgeries</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Arizona</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Arizona</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A hysterectomy, or removal of the uterus, is a common surgery performed for a variety of&#xD;
      reasons. During this surgery, to prevent infection, the vagina is thoroughly prepped with a&#xD;
      cleansing solution, most commonly chlorhexidine gluconate or povidone-iodine. While studies&#xD;
      have shown that chlorhexidine gluconate is better at killing bacteria people have raised&#xD;
      concerns on how it affects the vaginal tissue. It is important to study these effects the&#xD;
      cleansing solution surgeons use for this surgery can not only prevent infection but not cause&#xD;
      harmful side effects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to examine the effects of different vaginal operative&#xD;
      preparations on the vaginal tissue and microbiome. Our primary working hypothesis is that&#xD;
      chlorhexidine prep is more deleterious to vaginal tissue than povidone-iodine preparations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 1: chlorhexidine gluconate is more disruptive to the vaginal microbiome than&#xD;
      povidone-iodine Hypothesis 2: chlorhexidine gluconate leads to more vaginal atrophy than&#xD;
      povidone-iodine&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Chlorhexidine Gluconate vs Povidone-iodine group</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of patient-reported vaginal and urinary symptoms after treatment with chlorhexidine gluconate or povidone-iodine vaginal cleansing solution</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of surgery to 24 hours post-operative</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the frequency of patient-reported vaginal and urinary symptoms after treatment with chlorhexidine gluconate or povidone-iodine vaginal cleansing solution utilizing questionnaires.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Relative abundances of vaginal microbiota species</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of surgery to 3-6 weeks postoperative</time_frame>
    <description>To measure the change in relative abundances of vaginal microbiota species after treatment with chlorhexidine gluconate or a povidone-iodine vaginal cleansing solution. Vaginal microbiota species include but not limited to health-associated Lactobacillus spp., bacterial-vaginosis associated anaerobes (Gardnerella, Prevotella, Sneathia, Atopobium, Megasphaera, Parvimonas, Mobiluncus and others), pathobionts (Streptococcus, Escherichia), and other bacterial taxa present in the collected vaginal swabs using 16S rRNA sequencing</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in level of genital cytokines and chemokines</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of surgery to 3-6 weeks post-operative</time_frame>
    <description>To measure the change in levels of genital cytokines and chemokines (IL-1alpha, IL-1beta, IL-8, MIP-1beta, MIP-3alpha, RANTES, TNFalpha) in the collected cervicovaginal lavages using multiplex cytometric bead arrays after treatment with chlorhexidine gluconate or a povidone-iodine vaginal cleansing solution. The cytokine levels will be used to determine the genital inflammatory score by using a previously described genital inflammation scoring system. Patients will be assigned one point for each mediator when the level was in the upper quartile</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in vaginal pH level</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of surgery to 3-6weeks post-operative</time_frame>
    <description>To measure the change vaginal pH after treatment with chlorhexidine gluconate or a povidone-iodine vaginal cleansing solution.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Vaginal Flora Imbalance</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Povidone-Iodine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Povidone-iodine to be used as the cleansing solution in this arm of patients for surgical vaginal preparation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Chlorhexidine Gluconate</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Chlorhexidine gluconate to be used as the cleansing solution in this arm of patients for surgical vaginal preparation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Chlorhexidine Gluconate</intervention_name>
    <description>4% Chlorhexidine Gluconate vaginal cleansing solution as a surgical preparation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Chlorhexidine Gluconate</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Povidone-iodine</intervention_name>
    <description>10% povidone-iodine vaginal cleansing solution as a surgical preparation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Povidone-Iodine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Females&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. all races and ethnicities&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. English-speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. pre-menoupausal&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. undergoing gynecologic surgeries requiring vaginal operative preparation at&#xD;
                  Banner University Medical Center - Phoenix.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with dx of vaginitis or vulvovaginal atrophy at time of surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with an allergy to povidone-iodine and/or Chlorhexidine Gluconate&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Individuals with any skin conditions, as determined by the physician, which could&#xD;
             interfere with the conduct of the study or increase the risks to the test subject&#xD;
             including any open or healing cuts/incisions, abrasions, or broken skin in the testing&#xD;
             area as determined by the physician&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Currently menstruating&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Be using or have used antibiotics, antifungals, topical steroids or antiviral (oral or&#xD;
             topical in the testing areas) less than 12 weeks prior to visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Have a history of or current, self-reported genital herpes&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Have current or in the past 6 weeks, conditions such as&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Vaginal infection/bacterial vaginosis/yeast infection or sexually transmitted&#xD;
                  infection (Chlamydia, Gonorrhea or Trichomonas)/Hepatitis/HIV&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Vulvar infection&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Urinary tract infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Sexual intercourse less than 48 hours prior to the visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Current treatment for any skin conditions on the testing area&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Female</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mike Foley, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Banner University Medical Center - Phoenix/ University of Arizona</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Elisa Martinez, MBA</last_name>
    <phone>480-430-4810</phone>
    <email>elisamartinez@arizona.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Regina Montero, MSN</last_name>
    <phone>480-239-8697</phone>
    <email>rmontero52@arizona.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Al-Niaimi A, Rice LW, Shitanshu U, Garvens B, Fitzgerald M, Zerbel S, Safdar N. Safety and tolerability of chlorhexidine gluconate (2%) as a vaginal operative preparation in patients undergoing gynecologic surgery. Am J Infect Control. 2016 Sep 1;44(9):996-8. doi: 10.1016/j.ajic.2016.02.036. Epub 2016 May 24.</citation>
    <PMID>27234011</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Amstey MS, Jones AP. Preparation of the vagina for surgery. A comparison of povidone-iodine and saline solution. JAMA. 1981 Feb 27;245(8):839-41.</citation>
    <PMID>7463676</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Aronson JK. Antiseptic drugs and disinfectants. In: Side effects of drugs annual. Vol 35. Elsevier Science &amp; Technology; 2014:435-445. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/B9780444626356.000243. 10.1016/B978-0-444-62635-6.00024-3.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists Women's Health Care Physicians; Committee on Gynecologic Practice. Committee Opinion No. 571: Solutions for surgical preparation of the vagina. Obstet Gynecol. 2013 Sep;122(3):718-20. doi: 10.1097/01.AOG.0000433982.36184.95.</citation>
    <PMID>23963423</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Costin GE, Raabe HA, Priston R, Evans E, Curren RD. Vaginal irritation models: the current status of available alternative and in vitro tests. Altern Lab Anim. 2011 Sep;39(4):317-37. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21942546</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Culligan PJ, Kubik K, Murphy M, Blackwell L, Snyder J. A randomized trial that compared povidone iodine and chlorhexidine as antiseptics for vaginal hysterectomy. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2005 Feb;192(2):422-5.</citation>
    <PMID>15695981</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fleischer W, Reimer K. Povidone-iodine in antisepsis--state of the art. Dermatology. 1997;195 Suppl 2:3-9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>9403248</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lewis LA, Lathi RB, Crochet P, Nezhat C. Preoperative vaginal preparation with baby shampoo compared with povidone-iodine before gynecologic procedures. J Minim Invasive Gynecol. 2007 Nov-Dec;14(6):736-9.</citation>
    <PMID>17980335</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mac Bride, Maire B., MBBCh, Rhodes DJ, MD, Shuster LT, MD. Vulvovaginal atrophy. Mayo Clinic Proceedings. 2010;85(1):87-94. https://www.clinicalkey.es/playcontent/1-s2.0-S0025619611603145. doi: 10.4065/mcp.2009.0413.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mahoney JB, Chernesky MA. Institutional infection control and prevention. Manual of clinical microbiology. 1999:108-190.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rastogi S, Glaser L, Friedman J, Carter IV, Milad MP. Tolerance of chlorhexidine gluconate vaginal cleansing solution: A randomized controlled trial. Journal of Gynecologic Surgery. 2019. doi: 10.1089/gyn.2019.0066.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>US National Library of Medicine.4% chlorhexidine gluconate skin cleansing kit; US food and drug administration (FDA) approved product information. DailyMed Web site. https://dailymed.nlm.nih.gov/dailymed/drugInfo.cfm?setid=65f87900-8d23-4fb3-be44-1d116aedac78. Updated 2015.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vorherr H, Vorherr UF, Mehta P, Ulrich JA, Messer RH. Antimicrobial effect of chlorhexidine and povidone-iodine on vaginal bacteria. J Infect. 1984 May;8(3):195-9.</citation>
    <PMID>6736662</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wilkinson EM, Łaniewski P, Herbst-Kralovetz MM, Brotman RM. Personal and Clinical Vaginal Lubricants: Impact on Local Vaginal Microenvironment and Implications for Epithelial Cell Host Response and Barrier Function. J Infect Dis. 2019 Nov 6;220(12):2009-2018. doi: 10.1093/infdis/jiz412.</citation>
    <PMID>31539059</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 1, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 8, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 1, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 1, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 8, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Arizona</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Gabriella Smith</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Resident Physician</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chlorhexidine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Chlorhexidine gluconate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Povidone-Iodine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Povidone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

