<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04658368</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-1466</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>A539730</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>SMPH/SURGERY/DENTL-PLASTC SRGY</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>Protocol Version 11/2020</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04658368</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Patient Reported Outcomes Following Targeted Muscle Reinnervation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Patient Reported Outcomes Following Targeted Muscle Reinnervation in Major Limb Amputees</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Wisconsin, Madison</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Wisconsin, Madison</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to characterize the functional status and quality of life of&#xD;
      patients undergoing Targeted Muscle Reinnervation (TMR) at time of major limb amputation&#xD;
      (primary) or subsequent to major limb amputation (secondary). Participants can expect to be&#xD;
      on study for about a year and will complete a short electronic survey and option phone&#xD;
      interview.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Residual limb pain and phantom limb pain (PLP) have been shown to be associated with decrease&#xD;
      in prosthetic function and poor quality of life. It is estimated that the prevalence of PLP&#xD;
      is as high as 85% and residual limb pain 10-76%. The treatment of amputee-related pain&#xD;
      continues to rely largely on pharmacologic therapy, and typically opioids. Targeted Muscle&#xD;
      Innervation (TMR) first performed by Dr. Dumanian, is a peripheral nerve transfer procedure&#xD;
      that reroutes amputated axons to motor endplates and sensory organelles in nearby muscles,&#xD;
      giving amputated nerves &quot;somewhere to go and something to do&quot; which may play a role in&#xD;
      preventing development of neuromas and phantom limb pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A multicenter retrospective study found that upper-extremity amputees who subsequently&#xD;
      underwent TMR (&quot;secondary TMR&quot;) experienced relief in neuroma pain post-operatively. Other&#xD;
      studies have shown that amputees who have undergone TMR have decreased narcotic use and&#xD;
      improvement in prosthetic tolerance. A randomized controlled trial demonstrated that major&#xD;
      limb amputees who underwent TMR had decreased phantom limb pain and residual limb pain&#xD;
      compared with those who underwent traditional treatment of neuroma excision and burying into&#xD;
      muscle. A subsequent study found that patients undergoing major limb amputation with&#xD;
      immediate TMR (&quot;primary TMR&quot;) had less PLP and residual limb pain than untreated amputee&#xD;
      controls. A recent prospective study of patients undergoing TMR at time of major limb&#xD;
      amputation secondary to trauma had overall low pain scores, and neuromodulator medication use&#xD;
      and overall high rate of daily prosthetic use. Oncologic patients who underwent amputation&#xD;
      with concurrent TMR demonstrated decreased neuroma symptoms, PLP and residual limb pain&#xD;
      compared to oncologic amputees who did not undergo TMR. However, 32% of patients who&#xD;
      underwent TMR for upper extremity amputation did not finish prosthetic rehabilitation,&#xD;
      despite showing overall improved functional outcome scores.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus, there is increasing evidence that TMR, both primary and secondary, can prevent or&#xD;
      improve pain from neuroma, phantom and residual limb pain. There is also evidence that TMR&#xD;
      may promote early use of prosthetics and reduce reliance on narcotic medications. Prior&#xD;
      studies have largely relied on outcome measures such as Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) for pain&#xD;
      and pain-related instruments from the Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information&#xD;
      System (PROMIS) toolbox. More comprehensive data is limited on patient's functional status&#xD;
      and quality of life, and thus far there is a lack of studies using patient-reported outcome&#xD;
      instruments specific to patients with upper or lower extremity conditions. There is also&#xD;
      limited data on patient desires and expectations for pursuing TMR, and subsequent&#xD;
      satisfaction after having undergone the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Retrospective Cross-sectional study: Medical record review, electronic survey, optional&#xD;
      interview This is a mixed methods, cross-sectional study assessing major limb amputee&#xD;
      patients who have undergone TMR. It includes a medical record review to collect demographic&#xD;
      information listed below, and an electronic survey (quantitative study), as well as&#xD;
      interviews with a subset of subjects (qualitative study). Patients who have had at least 6&#xD;
      months follow up will be invited to participate in the electronic survey, which will include&#xD;
      questions from validated patient-reported outcome instruments to measure function and quality&#xD;
      of life. Patients will also be invited to be interviewed by phone using a set of open-ended&#xD;
      questions. Thematic content analysis will be used to evaluate the participants' responses,&#xD;
      and with the objective to examine the patient's motivations for undergoing TMR and their&#xD;
      postoperative course, including pain, daily function, quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prospective Cohort study: Medical record review, electronic survey, optional interview This&#xD;
      is a mixed methods cohort study of patients with history of major limb amputation who will be&#xD;
      undergoing secondary TMR, and patients who will be undergoing a major limb amputation with&#xD;
      primary TMR. It includes a medical record review to collect demographic information listed&#xD;
      below. The pre-survey will be administered between time of pre-operative evaluation to just&#xD;
      prior to the operation, and the post-survey will be administered between 6-18 months after&#xD;
      surgery. Each subject will also be invited to be interviewed by phone (or in person if at&#xD;
      University of Wisconsin for follow up appointment), with set of open-ended questions focused&#xD;
      on motivations for undergoing TMR, and their postoperative course including pain, daily&#xD;
      function, quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      General amputee population: Electronic survey ONLY To define normative data for general&#xD;
      amputee population, the electronic survey with patient reported outcomes measures will be&#xD;
      administered to amputees recruited from prosthetic, orthotic, orthopedic, vascular, oncologic&#xD;
      or other amputee clinics and support groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For all above, the electronic survey, which will be administered via REDCap, will take&#xD;
      approximately 7-8 minutes to complete. The interview will take 15-20 minutes to complete.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Aim 1: Evaluate functional status and quality of life of patients who have undergone&#xD;
           primary or secondary TMR using patient reported outcome instruments&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Aim 2: Compare functional status and quality of life of primary TMR patients to those of&#xD;
           general amputee population&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Aim 3: Compare pre-operative and post-operative functional status and quality of life of&#xD;
           secondary TMR patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Aim 4: Compare post-operative functional status and quality of life of secondary TMR&#xD;
           patients to those of general amputee population&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Aim 5: Evaluate patient desire, expectations and satisfaction with undergoing TMR (via&#xD;
           survey and structured interview)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 29, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-Amputation Quality of Life Survey</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 18 months</time_frame>
    <description>The functional status and quality of life of patients who have undergone primary or secondary TMR will be measured using patient reported outcome instruments. 25-items scored on a 5 point likert scale will be combined for a score between 25 and 125, where higher scores indicate better quality of life. Items represent combined tools of the following PROMIS instruments: Ability to participate in social roles and activities, Global health, Pain intensity, self-efficacy for management chronic conditions social interactions, general self-efficacy, emotional support, social isolation. Higher scores mean better functioning.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Quality of Life Survey</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, post-surgery (up to 18 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Compare pre-operative and post-operative functional status and quality of life of secondary TMR patients. 25-items scored on a 5 point likert scale will be combined for a score between 25 and 125, where higher scores indicate better quality of life. See attachments for more details.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Qualitative Participant TMR Experience</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient desire, expectations and satisfaction with undergoing TMR will be measured qualitatively using survey and semi-structured interview responses. This measure will be analyzed with coding for recurring themes and reported narratively. A coding theme will be decided after preliminary review of interview transcripts.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Amputation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants with a history of major limb amputation at the University of Wisconsin (UW) that did not undergo TMR</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Retrospective TMR</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants with a history of major limb amputation that underwent primary or secondary TMR with attending plastic surgeon at UW</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective Secondary TMR</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants who are scheduled to undergo secondary TMR at the UW</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective Primary TMR</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants who are scheduled to undergo primary TMR at the UW</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Primary TMR</intervention_name>
    <description>TMR procedure as part of the primary major limb amputation surgery</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective Primary TMR</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Retrospective TMR</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Secondary TMR</intervention_name>
    <description>TMR procedure subsequent to major limb amputation surgery</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective Secondary TMR</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Retrospective TMR</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients that have undergone (retrospective) or are scheduled to undergo (prospective)&#xD;
        major limb amputation with primary or secondary TMR procedure at the UW. A control group of&#xD;
        participants that have had major limb amputation at the UW without the TMR procedure will&#xD;
        also be surveyed.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: Study cohort&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Retrospective&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Underwent primary or secondary TMR with attending plastic surgeon at UW&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prospective&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient with history of major limb amputation who is scheduled to undergo&#xD;
                  secondary TMR with attending plastic surgeon at UW&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient who is scheduled to undergo primary major limb amputation with concurrent&#xD;
                  TMR&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria: Control Cohort&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with history of major limb amputation recruited from local clinics who has not&#xD;
             been referred or seen for consultation for TMR by attending plastic surgeon at UW&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: Study Cohort&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Retrospective&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient underwent TMR at another institution&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Less than 6 months follow up&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Less than 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Enrolled in other studies relating to neuropathic pain&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Undergoing radiation therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Incarcerated&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Incomplete survey response&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Non-English speaking (chosen PROMIS measures only in English)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prospective&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Less than 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cognitive impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Enrolled in other studies relating to neuropathic pain&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Undergoing radiation therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Incarcerated&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Non-English speaking (chosen PROMIS measures only in English)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: Control Cohort&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Enrolled in other studies relating to neuropathic pain&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing radiation therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Incarcerated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Incomplete survey response&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major limb amputee seeking consultation for TMR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-English speaking (chosen PROMIS measures only in English)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Brett F Michelotti, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Wisconsin, Madison</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rosaline S Zhang, MD, MSTR</last_name>
    <phone>608-263-1367</phone>
    <email>rszhang2@wisc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Wisconsin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madison</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53792</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rosaline S Zhang, MD, MSTR</last_name>
      <phone>608-263-1367</phone>
      <email>rszhang2@wisc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Brett Michelotti, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 1, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 1, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 8, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

