<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04656925</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB 18376</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04656925</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Automated Reinforcement Management System (ARMS)</brief_title>
  <acronym>ARMS</acronym>
  <official_title>Automated Reinforcement Management System (ARMS): Phase I Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Washington State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Washington State University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Alcohol abuse remains a significant cause of preventable morbidity and mortality in the US.&#xD;
      Yet only 15% of those with alcohol use disorders receive treatment. Contingency Management&#xD;
      (CM) is a cost-effective intervention for drug addiction where individuals are rewarded when&#xD;
      they submit biological verification of drug abstinence. The researchers propose to develop an&#xD;
      integrated CM system capable of incorporating mobile device input, that would allow them to&#xD;
      deliver a CM intervention for problematic drinking to anyone who owns a smartphone. The&#xD;
      mobile device input will incorporate ecological momentary assessments (EMA), geospatial&#xD;
      mapping, and biomarker-based feedback from a portable measuring device.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The researchers propose to develop an integrated Contingency Management (CM) system capable&#xD;
      of incorporating mobile device input, which would allow them to deliver a CM intervention for&#xD;
      problematic drinking to anyone who owns a smartphone. The location of participants through&#xD;
      their cell phone will be recorded. The researchers will be using this data to create a&#xD;
      &quot;heat-map&quot; to find problem areas of drinking. The application works only on iPhone 7 or a&#xD;
      newer version with an (iPhone Operating System) iOS 13.5. If the participant does not have an&#xD;
      iPhone 7 or a newer version, the researcher can loan one to the participant if he/she knows&#xD;
      how to use it, but it must be returned at the end of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary aim is to combine mobile technology, geospatial mapping, and biomarker&#xD;
      measurement, with individual goal setting and ecological momentary assessments (EMA) feedback&#xD;
      to launch behavioral modification strategies and progress monitoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      People can participate if they are 1) age 18-65 years; 2) have an Alcohol Use Disorders&#xD;
      Identification Test (AUDIT) score of 8 or higher; 3) have the ability to read and speak&#xD;
      English; 4) have the ability to provide written informed consent; 5) have a breath alcohol of&#xD;
      0.00 during informed consent, and 6) can operate a smartphone with an active service&#xD;
      provider.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The researchers will utilize an A-B-A completely within-subject design with the intent of&#xD;
      recruiting twenty total participants from the Community in Spokane.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the first A phase, participants will receive reinforcement for simply submitting&#xD;
      breath samples 3 times per day between 4 and 6 hours apart.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the B phase, the delivery of reinforcers will be contingent upon the submission of an&#xD;
      alcohol negative breath sample on an escalating schedule.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The A phase or return to the baseline phase will involve the delivery reinforcers for simply&#xD;
      submitting a sample during the designated windows of time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The researchers will also collect other EMA data on stress, anxiety, depression, and other&#xD;
      brief measures daily through participants' smartphone. Each phase will last a total of 4&#xD;
      weeks (i.e., 2 weeks of the first A phase, 4 weeks of the B phase, and then 2 more weeks of&#xD;
      the A-phase) each for a total of 8 weeks of participation. Participants will be asked to&#xD;
      submit 3 breath samples per day through a Bluetooth enabled breathalyzer developed by&#xD;
      BACTrack no less than 8 hours apart and no more than 12 hours apart. Test results for breath&#xD;
      alcohol will be available instantly to the participant and uploaded to the CM response system&#xD;
      almost immediately.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As part of this CM system, participants will have the capability to receive multi-modal&#xD;
      message reminders when they enter a new window of needed biochemical sample submission and&#xD;
      additional reminders when the window of sample submission is about to close. While&#xD;
      participants will receive information messages to this effect during the A phase,&#xD;
      participants will receive additional personalized multi-modal message reminders once the CM&#xD;
      platform can detect that they have entered a cold or hot zone. For example, upon entering a&#xD;
      hot zone radius during the B phase wherein they had a greater 50% likelihood of drinking in&#xD;
      that zone during the A phase, they will receive a text message encouraging them to change&#xD;
      surroundings in order to better promote abstinence. Also, if the participant is within a&#xD;
      window of time where they are eligible to submit a sample and receive a dose of&#xD;
      reinforcement, this is another action that the individual can take to help bolster their&#xD;
      attempt to remain abstinent. All these data (i.e., biochemical results, location of sample&#xD;
      submission, time of submission, and other bits of data) will be collected and be presented in&#xD;
      summary form to the research team. This will help the team devise an action plan if the&#xD;
      participant's drinking behavior is proving impervious to intervention or if the participant's&#xD;
      goals are being met, this is something the researcher can encourage about.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A-B-A, or a return to baseline design.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Biochemically measured change in alcohol abstinence.</measure>
    <time_frame>Daily during 8 Weeks of study</time_frame>
    <description>Change in biochemically measured alcohol abstinence assessed through breath samples submitted three times daily.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self-reported frequency of Alcohol use</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported alcohol use measured by the Timeline Follow Back instrument to assess the frequency of daily drinking.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self-reported quantity of Alcohol use</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported alcohol use measured by the Timeline Follow Back instrument to assess the quantity of daily drinking.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Alcohol Use Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Contingency management A-B-A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All participants will be assigned a single arm where we will utilize an A-B-A, or return to baseline design where all participants will experience the intervention in between two baseline observation periods.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Contingency management</intervention_name>
    <description>Reinforcement, or incentives, in exchange for evidence of not drinking alcohol.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Contingency management A-B-A</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 18-65 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. An Alcohol Use Disorders Identification Test (AUDIT) score of 8 or higher.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Ability to read and speak English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Ability to provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Breath alcohol of 0.00 during informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Operate a smartphone with an active service provider.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, Fifth Edition (DSM-5) alcohol&#xD;
             use disorder, severe type.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Significant risk of dangerous alcohol withdrawal, defined as a history of alcohol&#xD;
             detoxification or seizure in the last 12 months and expression of concern by the&#xD;
             participant about dangerous withdrawal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Diagnosis of a psychotic disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Lifetime suicide attempt or suicidality in the past year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any other medical or psychiatric condition that would compromise safe participation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 15, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 4, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 7, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 4, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 4, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 7, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

