<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00507962</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2004-0568</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00507962</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cisplatin HAI Study in Patients With Advanced Cancer and Dominant Liver Involvement</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Study Dose Escalation Clinical Study Of Hepatic Intraarterial Cisplatin, In Combination With Systemic Intravenous Liposomal Doxorubicin Administered Every Four Weeks to Patients With Advanced Cancer And Dominant Liver Involvement</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical research study is find the highest safe dose of cisplatin that can&#xD;
      be given with liposomal doxorubicin in the treatment of advanced cancer involving the liver.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PRIMARY Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To determine the toxicity and safety of a monthly cytotoxic regimen combining intraarterial&#xD;
      hepatic (HAI) cisplatin with systemic intravenous liposomal doxorubicin in patients with&#xD;
      cancer metastatic to the liver.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To document in a descriptive fashion the antitumor efficacy of monthly hepatic intraarterial&#xD;
      cisplatin in combination with systemic liposomal doxorubicin.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cisplatin and Liposomal Doxorubicin are chemotherapy drugs designed to fight cancer growth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If you are eligible to take part in this study, you will enter a treatment period that is&#xD;
      divided into cycles. Each cycle is 28 days. You will be hospitalized to receive your&#xD;
      chemotherapy. The night of the hospital admission you will receive fluids (normal saline) in&#xD;
      your veins to help avoid kidney side effects from the chemotherapy. The morning after your&#xD;
      admission to the hospital you will be taken to the interventional radiology suite and a&#xD;
      catheter will be placed in your right groin. You must be on bedrest the entire time that the&#xD;
      catheter is in place. After the procedure, you will go to Nuclear Medicine and a test called&#xD;
      &quot;flow study&quot; will be carried out to confirm the right position of the catheter. After your&#xD;
      return to the room, the nurses will start the chemotherapy. You will first receive cisplatin&#xD;
      through the groin catheter followed by the liposomal doxorubicin given in one of your veins.&#xD;
      The treatment lasts less than three hours and is repeated once every month.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The catheter will be carefully taped so it can not move and to prevent it from coming out.&#xD;
      Following completion of chemotherapy infusion, the intra-arterial catheter will be pulled and&#xD;
      pressure applied to the groin for 15 minutes. In some cases, the catheter will be removed&#xD;
      immediately after your chemotherapy infusions is complete. In some cases, the catheter will&#xD;
      remain in longer. You will be on bedrest until the catheter is removed. The catheter will be&#xD;
      removed by the physician on call. The catheter will be placed and removed at each treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood (about 2 teaspoons) will be drawn for blood counts and liver function tests before each&#xD;
      dose to be sure researchers are safely giving you the liposomal doxorubicin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since most of the blood flow to your liver comes through the portal vein, your doctors will&#xD;
      try to cause an infarct (like a stroke) to the liver artery followed by the injection of&#xD;
      cisplatin to kill the tumor cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will be seen by a doctor or advanced practice practitioner every day while you are in the&#xD;
      hospital. You will be hospitalized for about 5-7 days until recovery from all immediate&#xD;
      treatment related side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will continue to receive therapy as mentioned above until the disease gets worse or&#xD;
      intolerable side effects occur.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of your participation in this study, you will have scans to see if your tumors are&#xD;
      growing or shrinking, and blood work (about 3 teaspoons) to make sure your blood counts and&#xD;
      the electrolytes (salts in your blood), kidney and liver function are at a safe level.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose (MTD)</measure>
    <time_frame>With each 4 week cycle (28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Dose level at which no dose limiting toxicities are seen for a monthly cytotoxic regimen combining intraarterial hepatic cisplatin with systemic intravenous liposomal doxorubicin.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">51</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cisplatin + Liposomal Doxorubicin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cisplatin 100 mg/m^2 Intraarterial and Liposomal Doxorubicin starting dose 20 mg/m^2 by vein on Day 1 every 4 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cisplatin</intervention_name>
    <description>100 mg/m^2 Intraarterial On Day 1 Every 4 Weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cisplatin + Liposomal Doxorubicin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Platinol-AQ</other_name>
    <other_name>Platinol</other_name>
    <other_name>CDDP</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Liposomal Doxorubicin</intervention_name>
    <description>Starting dose 20 mg/m^2 IV On Day 1 Every 4 Weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cisplatin + Liposomal Doxorubicin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Doxil</other_name>
    <other_name>Liposomal</other_name>
    <other_name>Doxorubicin Hydrochloride</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with Histologically confirmed diagnosis of malignancy and liver involvement&#xD;
             as dominant site of metastasis (over 50% of all tumor burden).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pediatric patients eligible at the discretion of the primary investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Performance Status Equivalent or Grater than 60% in the Karnofsky's Performance scale&#xD;
             (Requires occasional assistance but is able to care for own needs).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Adequate Renal Function (Serum CRE &lt;/= 1.5 mg/dL) or calculated Creatinine Clearance&#xD;
             &gt;/= 50 ml/min (Cockcroft Formula).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Adequate Hepatic Function (Total Bilirubin &lt;/= 1.5 mg/dL or ALT &lt;/= 5 times upper&#xD;
             normal reference value).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Adequate Bone Marrow Function (Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;/= 1.5 cells/uL;&#xD;
             number of platelets (PLT) &gt;/= 100,000 cells/uL).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. At least three weeks from previous cytotoxic chemotherapy before day 1 of HAI&#xD;
             infusion. After targeted or biologic therapy there should be 5 half-lives or three&#xD;
             weeks, whichever is shorter.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. All Females in Childbearing Age MUST have a negative urine or serum Human chorionic&#xD;
             gonadotropin or human chorionic gonadotrophin (hCG) test unless prior hysterectomy or&#xD;
             menopause (defined as age above 55 and six months without menstrual activity).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Ability to fully read, comprehend, and sign informed consent forms. In pediatric&#xD;
             patients, the informed consent forms will be signed by a parent or legal guardian.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with germ cell tumors and lymphoma MUST have had documented progression of&#xD;
             disease prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinical or radiographic evidence of Ascites.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pregnant females.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Hypersensitivity to platinum compounds or anthracyclines.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Inability to complete informed consent process and adhere to protocol treatment plan&#xD;
             and follow-up requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Jaundice. (Bilirubin &gt; 1.5 mg/dL).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Bleeding Diathesis.(Prothrombin time &gt; 20 secs or International Normalized Ratio (INR)&#xD;
             &gt; 2.0).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Portal vein thrombosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Grade 2 Peripheral Neuropathy (CTC V3.0: Sensory alteration interfering with function&#xD;
             but not interfering with ADL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Medical History or Clinical Evidence of Congestive Heart Failure.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Apostolia Tsimberidou, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UT MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>UT MD Anderson Cancer Center website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 25, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 25, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 27, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 1, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 1, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">August 2, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Advanced Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Dominant Liver Involvement</keyword>
  <keyword>Hepatic Intraarterial Cisplatin</keyword>
  <keyword>Cisplatin</keyword>
  <keyword>Liposomal Doxorubicin</keyword>
  <keyword>Platinol-AQ</keyword>
  <keyword>Platinol</keyword>
  <keyword>CDDP</keyword>
  <keyword>Doxil</keyword>
  <keyword>Liposomal</keyword>
  <keyword>Doxorubicin Hydrochloride</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

