<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00500344</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FVF4184S</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00500344</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>CAPTAIN:Choroidal Neovascularization Assessment by Pattern Electroretinography</brief_title>
  <acronym>CAPTAIN</acronym>
  <official_title>CAPTAIN: Choroidal Neovascularization Assessment by Pattern Electroretinography After Ranibizumab in Naive Age-related Macular Degeneration Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Washington University School of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Genentech, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Washington University School of Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      CNV from AMD is the leading cause of blindness in people over 50 in North America. The&#xD;
      hypothesis is to determine if there is an improvement in retinal function determined by ERG&#xD;
      following treatment with ranibizumab for AMD&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Background 1.1 Pathophysiology Age-related macular degeneration (AMD) is a progressive&#xD;
           disease that causes irreversible visual impairment and blindness in nearly 50 million&#xD;
           people globally 1. 2. Current estimates of patients affected with AMD are higher than&#xD;
           those affected by Alzheimer's disease 1.3 Although geographic atrophy and&#xD;
           neovascularization represent the advanced forms of AMD, neovascular AMD is the more&#xD;
           aggressive form and accounts for almost 90% of blindness from this disease. It is&#xD;
           characterized by choroidal neovascularization (CNV) which is the development of abnormal&#xD;
           blood vessels underneath the retina. Current treatments such as photodynamic therapy&#xD;
           (PDT) and intravitreal pegaptanib are designed to limit further visual loss, but these&#xD;
           are only marginally effective 4-6.&#xD;
&#xD;
           1.2 Treatment of on-label naive AMD patients Recent randomized clinical trials (Marina,&#xD;
           Anchor) have conclusively demonstrated that continued intravitreal therapy with&#xD;
           ranibizumab in patients with subfoveal CNV from AMD leads to stabilization of vision in&#xD;
           over 90% of patients and improvement in vision in at least a third of the patients and&#xD;
           has led to the approval of ranibizumab (0.5 mg) for the treatment of neovascular AMD.&#xD;
           Naive patients will be used in this study to determine if an improvement by ERG can be&#xD;
           determined in those without prior therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
           1.3 Electroretinography(ERG) Effects Of Ranibizumab Therapy AMD trials are typically&#xD;
           designed to address visual acuity outcomes but not designed to evaluate retinal function&#xD;
           outcomes. Global and macular retinal indices as measured by electroretinography (ERG)&#xD;
           are key indicators of retinal health which have largely been ignored in clinical trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
           1.4 Non-Clinical Experience With Ranibizumab 1.4.1 Nonclinical Pharmacokinetics The&#xD;
           pharmacokinetics of ranibizumab have been investigated in rabbits and cynomolgus monkeys&#xD;
           following intravitreal and intravenous administration. In both species, following&#xD;
           intravitreal administration, ranibizumab was cleared from the vitreous humor with a half&#xD;
           life of 2-3 days. Following single intravitreal administration to cynomolgus monkeys,&#xD;
           retinal concentrations of ranibizumab were approximately one third of vitreous&#xD;
           concentrations and declined in parallel with vitreous concentrations. In humans, the&#xD;
           intravitreal half-life of ranibizumab is estimated to be 7-8 days. Repeated intravitreal&#xD;
           injections of ranibizumab can lead to detectable antibodies in serum in rabbits and&#xD;
           cynomolgus monkeys.&#xD;
&#xD;
           1.4.2 Nonclinical Toxicology A series of nonclinical studies of ranibizumab administered&#xD;
           by intravitreal injection to cynomolgus monkeys have been performed (details regarding&#xD;
           study design and results can be found in the Investigator Brochure).&#xD;
&#xD;
           1.4.3 Stability Studies The stability of ranibizumab alone and in combination with&#xD;
           verteporfin was assessed in vitro. The combination of ranibizumab and verteporfin in a&#xD;
           5% dextrose solution at concentrations of 500 mg/mL and 1.4 mg/mL, respectively,&#xD;
           resulted in ranibizumab degradation and a decrease in ranibizumab capacity to bind VEGF.&#xD;
           The ranibizumab degradation products have not been fully characterized. Although it is&#xD;
           currently unknown if such degradation also occurs in vivo, sequential administration of&#xD;
           verteporfin followed by ranibizumab with an intervening washout period will decrease the&#xD;
           likelihood of loss of ranibizumab activity and degradation.&#xD;
&#xD;
           1.5 Clinical Experience With Ranibizumab Ranibizumab has been or is being clinically&#xD;
           evaluated in nine studies (additional details regarding study design and results can be&#xD;
           found in the Investigator Brochure).&#xD;
&#xD;
           The first clinical trial with ranibizumab, Study FVF1770g was a Phase Ia study of the&#xD;
           molecule given as a single intravitreal injection to subjects with neovascular AMD. The&#xD;
           goals of the study were to investigate safety and tolerability and to define the&#xD;
           maximally tolerated dose (MTD). The single intravitreal MTD was determined to be 0.5 mg&#xD;
           (limited by ocular inflammation).&#xD;
&#xD;
           The Phase I/II study FVF2128g was the first clinical trial of multiple-dose regimens of&#xD;
           intravitreally administered ranibizumab. Sixty-four subjects were enrolled in the study.&#xD;
           Data show that ranibizumab was safe and potentially efficacious in subjects with&#xD;
           subfoveal choroidal neovascularization due to AMD.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Study FVF2425g was a Phase I, open-label, randomized study of three escalating multiple&#xD;
           dose regimens of intravitreally administered ranibizumab. Data show that doses of&#xD;
           ranibizumab up to 2 mg could be safely given as part of an escalating dose regimen to&#xD;
           subjects with subfoveal choroidal neovascularization due to AMD.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Study FVF2428g was a Phase I/II, single masked, multicenter study of the safety,&#xD;
           tolerability, and efficacy of multiple dose intravitreal injections of ranibizumab in&#xD;
           combination with verteporfin PDT in subjects with neovascular AMD. Data show that the&#xD;
           combination of ranibizumab and verteporfin PDT had a good safety profile in the study&#xD;
           population, and the efficacy of ranibizumab and verteporfin PDT was better than that of&#xD;
           verteporfin PDT alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Preliminary findings from Study FVF2428g suggest that administration of ranibizumab&#xD;
           injections 7 days (plus/minus 2 days) after treatment with verteporfin PDT in the same&#xD;
           eye may result in a decrease in visual acuity of 30 letters due to temporary intraocular&#xD;
           inflammation (uveitis).&#xD;
&#xD;
           Study FVF2508g is an ongoing Phase I extension study designed to assess the safety and&#xD;
           tolerability of multiple-dose intravitreal injections of ranibizumab administered&#xD;
           monthly in subjects who have completed the treatment phase of a Genentech-sponsored&#xD;
           Phase I study.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Study FVF2587g is an ongoing Phase III active treatment-controlled study designed to&#xD;
           assess the efficacy and safety of intravitreal administered ranibizumab compared with&#xD;
           verteporfin in subjects with angiographically determined, predominantly classic&#xD;
           subfoveal neovascular AMD.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Study FVF2598g was an ongoing Phase III study designed to assess the efficacy and safety&#xD;
           of intravitreal injections of ranibizumab administered monthly compared with sham&#xD;
           injections administered monthly in subjects with angiographically determined, minimally&#xD;
           classic or occult subfoveal neovascular AMD. Data show that ranibizumab was safe and&#xD;
           efficacious in subjects with subfoveal CNV due to AMD.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Study FVF3192g is an ongoing Phase IIIb study designed to assess the efficacy and safety&#xD;
           of intravitreal injections of ranibizumab administered as three monthly injections&#xD;
           followed by quarterly injections for a total duration of 24 months, in subjects with&#xD;
           angiographically determined subfoveal neovascular AMD with or without classic CNV.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Study 3426g is an ongoing open-label extension study designed to assess the safety and&#xD;
           tolerability of intravitreal injections of ranibizumab in subjects who have completed&#xD;
           the treatment phase of a Genentech-sponsored ranibizumab study.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Study 3689g is an ongoing Phase IIIb, 1 year multicenter study of the safety and&#xD;
           tolerability of intravitreally administered ranibizumab at two different doses (0.3mg&#xD;
           and 0.5mg) to subjects with active subfoveal CNV secondary to AMD, administered once a&#xD;
           month for 3 months and thereafter as needed, based on criteria-based re-treatment&#xD;
           options.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
           2.1 Primary Objective To determine if there is an improvement in retinal function&#xD;
           determined by the pattern and full-field ERG following treatment with ranibizumab for&#xD;
           AMD&#xD;
&#xD;
           2.2 Secondary Objectives To determine if there is a correlation between improvement in&#xD;
           visual acuity and retinal function as determined by the ERG Visual acuity at 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Study Design 3.1 Description Of The Study This is an open-label, Phase I single arm&#xD;
           study of intravitreally administered ranibizumab in on-label treatment naive patients&#xD;
           following by an assessment of retinal function using the ERG.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consented, enrolled subjects will receive monthly open-label intravitreal injections of 0.5&#xD;
      mg ranibizumab administered every month for 6 months. ERG will be performed at baseline, 1&#xD;
      month, 3 months and 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Electroretinograms will be recorded using DTL fiber electrodes moistened with&#xD;
      carboxymethyl-cellulose sodium 1% lying in the inferior fornix of each eye. Each DTL fiber&#xD;
      will be laid along the top of the lower eyelids so that it contacts the inferior cornea.&#xD;
      Fibers will be anchored with small adhesive pads near the inner and outer canthi. A reference&#xD;
      electrode will be applied with adhesive paste lateral to the outer canthi. An adhesive&#xD;
      electrode placed on the forehead will serve as the ground. Prior to pupil dilation, PERG&#xD;
      responses will be recorded, including P50 (derived from macular photoreceptors) and N95&#xD;
      (post-photoreceptor, including optic nerve), in response to an alternating checkerboard&#xD;
      pattern. Pupils will then be dilated with tropicamide 1% and phenylephrine hydrochloride 2.5%&#xD;
      for the full-field ERG and PhNR recordings. The patient will be dark-adapted for 30 minutes.&#xD;
      For full-field recordings, stimuli will be brief white flashes presented by a Ganzfeld&#xD;
      integrating sphere. Responses to dim and bright flashes will be recorded under scotopic&#xD;
      conditions, and a- and b-wave amplitudes will be noted. Patients will then be light adapted&#xD;
      for ten minutes. Responses to bright flash and 30 Hz flicker responses will then be recorded&#xD;
      under photopic conditions. A- and b-wave amplitudes and implicit times will be noted.&#xD;
      Finally, the photopic negative response (PhNR) will be recorded with a red flash on a blue&#xD;
      background.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.2 Rationale For Study Design Per the package insert, naive AMD patients will receive&#xD;
      monthly injections of Lucentis as part of their usual care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.3 Outcome Measures 3.3.1 Primary Outcome Measures Percent of patients with Improvement in&#xD;
      ERG from baseline to 6 months based on international standards (determined by expert reader).&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.3.2 Secondary Outcome Measures&#xD;
&#xD;
      Percent of patients with Improvement in ERG from baseline to 3 months based on international&#xD;
      standards (determined by expert reader) Correlation between change in PERG and mean change in&#xD;
      VA at 6 months Mean change in VA from baseline to 3 months and 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.4 Safety Plan There are no safety issues associated with the ERG. All safety monitoring&#xD;
      will be as in standard care with the use of on-label ranibizumab. ERG testing is&#xD;
      non-invasive.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.5 Compliance With Laws And Regulations This study will be conducted in accordance with&#xD;
      current U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) Good Clinical Practices (GCPs), and local&#xD;
      ethical and legal requirements.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine if there is an improvement in retinal function determined by the ERG following treatment with ranibizumab</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine if there is an improvement in visual acuity and retinal function as determined by ERG</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between change in PERG and mean change in VA at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean change in VA from baseline to 0 months and 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">17</enrollment>
  <condition>Age-related Macular Degeneration</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lucentis (ranibizumab)</intervention_name>
    <description>intravitreal injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to provide written informed consent and comply with study assessments for the&#xD;
             full duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 50 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment naive AMD patients that are determined to be candidates for ranibizumab&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Visual acuity 20/40 to 20/320&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior enrollment in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous therapy for AMD or other retinal diseases which may be used in the treatment&#xD;
             of AMD&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition that the investigator believes would pose a significant hazard to&#xD;
             the subject if on-label ranibizumab were prescribed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that would interfere with the ERG recording (such as media opacities&#xD;
             including lens or corneal opacity)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent eye disease in the study eye that could compromise visual acuity (such as&#xD;
             diabetic retinopathy, advanced glaucoma)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition causing the patient to have a significant tremor that would interfere&#xD;
             with the patient's ability to remain still during the ERG (such as Parkinson's&#xD;
             disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in another simultaneous medical investigation or trial&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rajendra S. Apte, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Washington University School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Klein R, Peto T, Bird A, Vannewkirk MR. The epidemiology of age-related macular degeneration. Am J Ophthalmol. 2004 Mar;137(3):486-95. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15013873</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>van Leeuwen R, Klaver CC, Vingerling JR, Hofman A, de Jong PT. Epidemiology of age-related maculopathy: a review. Eur J Epidemiol. 2003;18(9):845-54. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>14561043</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 10, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 11, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 12, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 30, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 30, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 3, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Washington University School of Medicine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Rajendra S. Apte</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Rajendra S. Apte MD, PHD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Age-related Macular Degeneration</keyword>
  <keyword>Choroidal Neovascularization</keyword>
  <keyword>Electroretinography</keyword>
  <keyword>Retinal Function</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Choroidal Neovascularization</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neovascularization, Pathologic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ranibizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

