<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00098280</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>050048</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>05-H-0048</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00098280</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Eculizumab to Treat Paroxysmal Nocturnal Hemoglobinuria</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Hemoglobin Stabilization and Transfusion Reduction Efficacy and Safety Clinical Investigation, Randomized, Multi-Center, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Using Eculizumab in Paroxysmal Nocturnal Hemoglobinuria Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will examine the safety and effectiveness of the experimental drug eculizumab in&#xD;
      treating patients with paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria (PNH), a rare disorder of red&#xD;
      blood cells that leads to premature destruction of the cells and resulting anemia. Patients&#xD;
      may be at high risk of blood clots and may develop bone marrow failure or aplastic anemia,&#xD;
      with low white blood cell and platelet counts. Eculizumab is a monoclonal antibody that may&#xD;
      help improve the survival of red blood cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients 18 years of age and older with PNH who require blood transfusions for anemia and&#xD;
      have received at least four transfusions in the 12 months preceding evaluation for this study&#xD;
      may be eligible to enroll. Candidates are screened with a medical history, physical&#xD;
      examination, and check of vital signs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants have an electrocardiogram (EKG) and blood and urine tests, and are vaccinated&#xD;
      against Neisseria meningitides, a common bacteria that can cause a disabling or fatal type of&#xD;
      meningitis. They then enter an observation phase of the study, with monthly visits during&#xD;
      which they complete a questionnaire; update their health status, transfusion record, and&#xD;
      medication use; have their vital signs checked and PNH symptoms evaluated; have blood and&#xD;
      urine tests; and receive a transfusion, if necessary. These visits continue for up to 3&#xD;
      months until patients receive a &quot;qualifying&quot; transfusion; that is, a transfusion given as a&#xD;
      consequence of a certain hemoglobin level with symptoms or a different level without&#xD;
      symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients are then randomly assigned to receive either eculizumab or a placebo (salt solution&#xD;
      with no active ingredient). Both study medications are given intravenously (through a vein)&#xD;
      over 30 minutes once a week for five doses and then once every 2 weeks for another 11 doses.&#xD;
      At each treatment visit (study weeks 0-24), patients update their health status, transfusion&#xD;
      records, and medication use; have their vital signs checked; and provide a blood sample. At&#xD;
      various visits, they also complete a questionnaire, provide a urine sample and have an EKG.&#xD;
      At the last treatment visit (week 26 or the final visit for patients who end their&#xD;
      participation before visit 18) patients have a complete physical examination in addition to&#xD;
      the procedures listed above.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria (PNH) is an acquired clonal disorder of the hematopoietic&#xD;
      stem cell characterized by intravascular hemolysis, hemoglobinuria, anemia, and thrombosis.&#xD;
      The clinical features of PNH result from the lack of one or more of the GPI-linked proteins&#xD;
      that serve to protect cells from autologous complement mediated attack. Two such proteins,&#xD;
      CD55 (decay accelerating factor) and CD59 (reactive lysis inhibitor) have been shown to be&#xD;
      absent from PNH erythrocytes and platelets as well as other cell types.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Evidence strongly suggests that lack of the terminal complement inhibitor CD59 is responsible&#xD;
      for the sensitivity of PNH erythrocytes and platelets to the effects of autologous&#xD;
      complement. Since the pathogenesis of PNH is due to the inability of PNH red cells and&#xD;
      platelets to inhibit the activation of terminal complement, it is logical to hypothesize that&#xD;
      a terminal complement inhibitor could effectively stop the intravascular hemolysis, obviate&#xD;
      or lessen the need for transfusions, and possibly decrease the propensity of life threatening&#xD;
      thrombosis. Eculizumab is a humanized monoclonal antibody that like CD59 inhibits terminal&#xD;
      complement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is a randomized, double-blind, placebo controlled, multi-center study of&#xD;
      eculizumab or placebo administered intravenously to approximately 75 PNH patients. The study&#xD;
      is designed to evaluate the safety of eculizumab in transfusion dependent patients with&#xD;
      paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria (PNH) and to determine if the administration of this&#xD;
      terminal complement inhibitor could provide a safe and effective substitute for CD59&#xD;
      function.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2004</start_date>
  <completion_date>February 2006</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment>75</enrollment>
  <condition>Hemoglobinuria, Paroxysmal</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Eculizumab</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION CRITERIA - Screening Period:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Individuals at least 18 years of age;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients must have required at least 4 episodes of transfusions in the 12 months prior to&#xD;
        Visit 1 for anemia or anemia-related symptoms;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Presence of a GPI deficient red blood cell clone (type II cells) by flow cytometry of&#xD;
        greater than or equal to 10%;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients taking erythropoietin must be on a stable dose for 26 weeks prior to visit 1 and&#xD;
        the dose must be expected to remain stable during the Observation Period and the Treatment&#xD;
        Phase;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients taking immunosuppressants must be on a stable dose for at least 26 weeks prior to&#xD;
        Visit 1 and the dose must be expected to remain stable during the Observation period and&#xD;
        the Treatment Phase;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients taking corticosteroids must be on a stable dose for at least 4 weeks prior to&#xD;
        Visit 1. The dose level may be decreased during the study as clinically appropriate. If the&#xD;
        corticosteroids need to be increased, they may not be increased above the dose reported at&#xD;
        Visit 1;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients are allowed to take coumadin, but must be at a stable international normalized&#xD;
        ratio (INR) level for 4 weeks prior to Visit 1 and are expected to maintain a stable INR&#xD;
        level during the Observation Period and the Treatment Phase;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients taking iron supplements or folic acid must be on a stable dose for 4 weeks prior&#xD;
        to Visit 3 and be expected to remain stable during Observation Period and the Treatment&#xD;
        Phase;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients are allowed to take low molecular weight heparin, but must be on a stable dose for&#xD;
        4 weeks prior to Visit 1 and the dose must be expected to remain stable during Observation&#xD;
        period and the Treatment Phase;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient must be willing and able to give written informed consent;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients must be vaccinated against N. meningitidis at Visit 1 or at least 14 days prior to&#xD;
        Visit 3;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient must avoid conception during the trial using a method that is most appropriate for&#xD;
        their physical state and culture.&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA - Observation Period:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Documented LDH level greater than or equal to 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) either at&#xD;
        Visit 1 or during the Observation Period;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients who have received one PRBC transfusion during the Observation Period at a&#xD;
        hemoglobin value of less than or equal to 9 gm/dL with symptoms or at a hemoglobin value of&#xD;
        less than or equal to 7 gm/dL without symptoms, and also within 1.5 gm/dL of the mean&#xD;
        hemoglobin pre-transfusion value for the previous 12 months. This transfusion should be in&#xD;
        accordance with that patient's individual transfusion hemoglobin algorithm, and occur&#xD;
        within 48 hours of the hemoglobin sample that precipitated the transfusion;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Platelet count greater than or equal to 100,000/mm(3) either at Visit 1 or during the&#xD;
        Observation Period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients whose mean hemoglobin levels prior to transfusion over the previous 12 months is&#xD;
        greater than 10.5 gm/dL;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Absolute Neutrophil count less than or equal to 500/microL;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Presence or suspicion of active bacterial infection, in the opinion of the Investigator, at&#xD;
        Visit 3 or recurrent bacterial infections;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Known or suspected hereditary complement deficiency;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participation in any other investigational drug trial or exposure to other investigational&#xD;
        agent, device, or procedure within 30 days prior to Visit 1;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pregnant, breast-feeding, or intending to conceive during the course of the study,&#xD;
        including the Post-treatment Phase;&#xD;
&#xD;
        History of meningococcal disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
        History of bone marrow transplantation;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator, could increase the patient's risk&#xD;
        by participating in the study or confound the outcome of the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hillmen P, Lewis SM, Bessler M, Luzzatto L, Dacie JV. Natural history of paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria. N Engl J Med. 1995 Nov 9;333(19):1253-8.</citation>
    <PMID>7566002</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tabbara IA. Hemolytic anemias. Diagnosis and management. Med Clin North Am. 1992 May;76(3):649-68. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>1578962</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rosse WF. Phosphatidylinositol-linked proteins and paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria. Blood. 1990 Apr 15;75(8):1595-601. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>2183885</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2006</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 3, 2004</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 3, 2004</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 6, 2004</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 3, 2008</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 3, 2008</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 4, 2008</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>H5g1</keyword>
  <keyword>PNH</keyword>
  <keyword>TRIUMPH</keyword>
  <keyword>Paroxysmal Nocturnal Hemoglobinuria</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hemoglobinuria</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hemoglobinuria, Paroxysmal</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Eculizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

