<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00794508</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ADA Gene Therapy</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1R01FD003005-01</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>9908-337</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00794508</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>MND-ADA Transduction of CD34+ Cells From Children With ADA-SCID</brief_title>
  <official_title>MND-ADA Transduction of CD34+ Cells From the Bone Marrow Of Children With Adenosine Deaminase (ADA)-Deficient Severe Combined Immunodeficiency (SCID): Effect of Discontinuation of PEG-ADA and Marrow Cytoreduction With Busulfan</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Donald B. Kohn, M.D.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>FDA Office of Orphan Products Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health (NIH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Los Angeles</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Severe combined immune deficiency (SCID) may result from inherited deficiency of the enzyme&#xD;
      adenosine deaminase (ADA). Children with ADA-deficient SCID often die from infections in&#xD;
      infancy, unless treated with either a bone marrow transplant or with ongoing injections of&#xD;
      PEG-ADA (Adagen) enzyme replacement therapy. Successful BMT requires the availability of a&#xD;
      matched sibling donor for greatest success, and treatment using bone marrow from a less-well&#xD;
      matched donor may have a higher rate of complications. PEG-ADA may restore and sustain&#xD;
      immunity for many years, but is very expensive and requires injections 1-2 times per week on&#xD;
      an ongoing basis. This clinical trial is evaluating the efficacy and safety of an alternative&#xD;
      approach, by adding a normal copy of the human ADA gene into stem cells from the bone marrow&#xD;
      of patients with ADA-deficient SCID. Eligible patients with ADA-deficient SCID, lacking a&#xD;
      matched sibling donor, will be eligible if they meet entry criteria for adequate organ&#xD;
      function and absence of active infections and following the informed consent process. Bone&#xD;
      marrow will be collected from the back of the pelvis from the patients and processed in the&#xD;
      laboratory to isolate the stem cells and add the human ADA gene using a retroviral vector.&#xD;
      The patients will receive a moderate dosage of busulfan, a chemotherapy agent that eliminates&#xD;
      some of the bone marrow stem cells in the patient, to &quot;make space&quot; for the gene-corrected&#xD;
      stem cells to grow once they are given back by IV. Patients will be followed for two years to&#xD;
      assess the potentially beneficial effects of the procedure on the function of their immune&#xD;
      system and to assess possible side-effects. This gene transfer approach may provide a better&#xD;
      and safer alternative for treatment of patients with ADA-deficient SCID.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The proposed study population is affected with adenosine deaminase-deficient severe combined&#xD;
      immune deficiency (ADA-SCID), an autosomal recessive congenital immune deficiency. The basis&#xD;
      of the proposed study (and product) is retroviral-mediated transduction of autologous, bone&#xD;
      marrow derived CD34+ hematopoietic progenitor cells with the MND-ADA retroviral vector in a 5&#xD;
      day cell processing period. Transduction is followed by infusion of the washed cells into&#xD;
      subjects not receiving enzyme replacement therapy with Polyethylene-conjugated ADA (PEG-ADA,&#xD;
      ADAGEN7) who have had their PEG-ADA injections discontinued, and have undergone bone marrow&#xD;
      cytoreductive therapy with a single non-ablative treatment course of Busulfan. The dose of&#xD;
      cells infused will be determined by the patient-to-patient variation of the number of&#xD;
      progenitors available from individual patients. Statistical analyses post-infusion will help&#xD;
      determine the dose-response of the number of cells infused to the level of engraftment and&#xD;
      resulting level of immune reconstitution. Following cellular infusion, a primary clinical&#xD;
      end-point will be the absolute numbers of T and B lymphocytes containing the transduced ADA&#xD;
      gene by quantitative, real-time PCR analyses. Measurement of blood mononuclear cell ADA&#xD;
      enzyme levels will be analyzed. Based on the degree of marking of lymphocytes and of&#xD;
      granulocytes, the selective advantage of lymphocytes may be gauged. Subjects will be&#xD;
      monitored for the development of clonal proliferation, under the 15 year plan required by the&#xD;
      FDA. One major aim of the study will be to see if subjects can remain off PEG-ADA and&#xD;
      maintain protective immunity from the population of transduced lymphocytes arising from&#xD;
      transduced progenitors. If sufficient gene-modified cells result, and PEG-ADA enzyme&#xD;
      replacement therapy can be permanently discontinued, the advantage of this therapeutic&#xD;
      approach may change the standard of care for these patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Examine the safety of the procedure: harvesting bone marrow, isolating CD34+ hematopoietic stem/progenitor cells, performing ex vivo gene transduction with the MND-ADA gamma-retroviral vector, giving 90 mg/m2 busulfan to &quot;make space&quot; in the bone marrow to aid engraftment, and re-infusing the autologous gene-modified cells.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Greater Than 1% of Gene-Modified Cells in the Peripheral Blood</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>As measured by quantitative polymerase chain reaction in peripheral blood cells separated into mononuclear and granulocyte fractions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants Reaching the Normal Range of ADA Enzyme Activity</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>As measured by ADA enzyme activity in peripheral blood mononuclear cells</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Severe Combined Immunodeficiency</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Retroviral-mediated ADA gene transfer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Transfer of the human ADA gene to isolated CD34+ cells from the bone marrow.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ADA gene transfer</intervention_name>
    <description>Autologous CD34+ cells transduced with the retroviral vector MND-ADA, carrying the human ADA gene.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Retroviral-mediated ADA gene transfer</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Children &gt; 1.0 months of age with a diagnosis of ADA-deficient SCID based on:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Confirmed absence (&lt;3% of normal levels) of ADA enzymatic activity in peripheral&#xD;
                  blood or (for neonates) umbilical cord erythrocytes and/or leukocytes, or in&#xD;
                  cultured fetal cells derived from either chorionic villus biopsy or&#xD;
                  amniocentesis, prior to institution of enzyme replacement therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
             AND&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Evidence of severe combined immunodeficiency based on either:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Family history of first order relative with ADA deficiency and clinical and&#xD;
                       laboratory evidence of severe immunologic deficiency,&#xD;
&#xD;
             OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Evidence of severe immunologic deficiency in subject based on lymphopenia&#xD;
                  (absolute lymphocyte count &lt;200) or severely decreased T lymphocyte blastogenic&#xD;
                  responses to phytohemagglutinin (deltaCPM&lt;5,000), prior to institution of immune&#xD;
                  restorative therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
             OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fulfillment of criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  A in addition to evidence of genetic mutations affecting the ADA gene as&#xD;
                       determined by a CLIA certified laboratory and clinical evidence of combined&#xD;
                       immunodeficiency based on lymphopenia (absolute lymphocyte counts &lt;2SD of&#xD;
                       age-matched control values) and hypogammaglobulinemia (&lt;2SD of age-matched&#xD;
                       control values) or lack of specific antibody response to vaccination. In&#xD;
                       addition, for patients to be eligible under this criterion, they must&#xD;
                       present with a clinical history indicating life-threatening illness&#xD;
                       characterized by increased frequency and/or severity of infections resulting&#xD;
                       in hospitalization and/or the administration of intravenous antibiotics, for&#xD;
                       bacterial or opportunistic infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ineligible for allogeneic (matched sibling) bone marrow transplantation (BMT):&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absence of a medically eligible HLA-identical sibling with normal immune function&#xD;
                  who may serve as an allogeneic bone marrow donor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Written informed consent according to guidelines of the Institutional Review Board&#xD;
             (IRB) at the University of California Los Angeles (UCLA).&#xD;
&#xD;
        This study is also open to delayed/late onset ADA-deficient patients who fulfill the&#xD;
        criteria 1, 2.A, and 3 and who are not receiving PEG-ADA treatment after being invited to&#xD;
        discuss all alternative treatment options with a physician not connected with the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age less than 1 month&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Hematologic&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Anemia (hemoglobin &lt;10.5 mg/dl at &lt;2 years of age, or &lt; 11.5 at &gt;2 years of&#xD;
             age,with normal serum iron studies). b. Neutropenia i. absolute granulocyte count&#xD;
             &lt;500/mm3 or ii. absolute granulocyte count 500-999/mm3 (1 month - 1 year of age) or&#xD;
             500-1499/mm3 (&gt; 1 year of age)] and bone marrow aspirate and biopsy showing&#xD;
             myelodysplasia or other gross abnormality. c. Thrombocytopenia (platelet count&#xD;
             150,000/mm3, at any age). d. PT or PTT &gt;2X normal. e. Cytogenetic abnormalities on&#xD;
             peripheral blood, or on cells collected by amniocentesis, if diagnosed in utero.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Infectious&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Evidence of active opportunistic infection or infection with HIV-1, hepatitis B,&#xD;
             CMV or parvovirus B 19 by DNA PCR at time of assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pulmonary&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Resting O2 saturation by pulse oximetry &lt;95%.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Chest x-ray indicating active or progressive pulmonary disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Cardiac&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Abnormal electrocardiogram (EKG) indicating cardiac pathology.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Uncorrected congenital cardiac malformation.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Active cardiac disease, including clinical evidence of congestive heart&#xD;
                  failure,cyanosis, hypotension.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Neurologic&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Significant neurologic abnormality by examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Uncontrolled seizure disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Renal&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Renal insufficiency: serum creatinine &gt; or = 1.2 mg/dl, or &gt; or = 3+ proteinuria.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Abnormal serum sodium, potassium, calcium, magnesium, phosphate at grade III or&#xD;
                  IV by Division of AIDS Toxicity Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Hepatic/GI:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Serum transaminases &gt; 5X normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Serum bilirubin &gt; 3.0 mg/dl.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Serum glucose &gt; 250mg/dl.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Intractable severe diarrhea.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Oncologic (see below*)&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Evidence of active malignant disease other than dermatofibrosarcoma protuberans&#xD;
                  (DFSP)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Evidence of DFSP expected to require anti-neoplastic therapy within the 5 years&#xD;
                  following the infusion of genetically corrected cells&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Evidence of DFSP expected to be life limiting within the 5 years following the&#xD;
                  infusion of genetically corrected cells&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Known sensitivity to Busulfan&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. General&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Expected survival &lt;6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Major congenital anomaly.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Medically eligible HLA-matched sibling.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Other conditions which in the opinion of the P.I. or co-investigators,&#xD;
                  contra-indicate infusion of transduced cells or indicate patient's inability to&#xD;
                  follow protocol.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>1 Month</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Donald B. Kohn, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, Los Angeles</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California, Los Angeles</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90095</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Candotti F, Shaw KL, Muul L, Carbonaro D, Sokolic R, Choi C, Schurman SH, Garabedian E, Kesserwan C, Jagadeesh GJ, Fu PY, Gschweng E, Cooper A, Tisdale JF, Weinberg KI, Crooks GM, Kapoor N, Shah A, Abdel-Azim H, Yu XJ, Smogorzewska M, Wayne AS, Rosenblatt HM, Davis CM, Hanson C, Rishi RG, Wang X, Gjertson D, Yang OO, Balamurugan A, Bauer G, Ireland JA, Engel BC, Podsakoff GM, Hershfield MS, Blaese RM, Parkman R, Kohn DB. Gene therapy for adenosine deaminase-deficient severe combined immune deficiency: clinical comparison of retroviral vectors and treatment plans. Blood. 2012 Nov 1;120(18):3635-46. doi: 10.1182/blood-2012-02-400937. Epub 2012 Sep 11.</citation>
    <PMID>22968453</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 19, 2008</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 19, 2008</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 20, 2008</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>March 9, 2016</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>April 22, 2016</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Estimate">May 30, 2016</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, Los Angeles</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Donald B. Kohn, M.D.</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Severe Combined Immune Deficiency</keyword>
  <keyword>Adenosine Deaminase Deficiency</keyword>
  <keyword>Gene Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Hematopoietic Stem Cells</keyword>
  <keyword>Retroviral Vector</keyword>
  <keyword>ADA-deficient SCID</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Severe Combined Immunodeficiency</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Gamma-retroviral-mediated ADA Gene Transfer</title>
          <description>Transfer of the human ADA gene to isolated CD34+ cells from the bone marrow.&#xD;
ADA gene transfer: Autologous CD34+ cells transduced with the gamma-retroviral vector, MND-ADA, carrying the human ADA gene.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="10"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="10"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <population>Pre-treatment</population>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Experimental Retroviral-mediated ADA Gene Transfer</title>
          <description>Transfer of the human ADA gene to isolated CD34+ cells from the bone marrow</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="10"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>&lt;=18 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="10"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Between 18 and 65 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>&gt;=65 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="6"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Race (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>American Indian or Alaska Native</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Asian</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Black or African American</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>White</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="7"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>More than one race</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="2"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Region of Enrollment</title>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>United States</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="10"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Number of Participants With Adverse Events</title>
        <description>Examine the safety of the procedure: harvesting bone marrow, isolating CD34+ hematopoietic stem/progenitor cells, performing ex vivo gene transduction with the MND-ADA gamma-retroviral vector, giving 90 mg/m2 busulfan to &quot;make space&quot; in the bone marrow to aid engraftment, and re-infusing the autologous gene-modified cells.</description>
        <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Gamma-retroviral Mediated ADA Gene Transfer</title>
            <description>Transfer of the human ADA gene to isolated CD34+ cells from the bone marrow</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Number of Participants With Adverse Events</title>
          <description>Examine the safety of the procedure: harvesting bone marrow, isolating CD34+ hematopoietic stem/progenitor cells, performing ex vivo gene transduction with the MND-ADA gamma-retroviral vector, giving 90 mg/m2 busulfan to &quot;make space&quot; in the bone marrow to aid engraftment, and re-infusing the autologous gene-modified cells.</description>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="10"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Expected Grade 3 or 4 AE related to procedure</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="10"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Unexpected Grade 3 or 4 AE related to procedure</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Grade 3 or 4 AE related to study product</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Alive</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="10"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Deaths</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Number of Participants With Greater Than 1% of Gene-Modified Cells in the Peripheral Blood</title>
        <description>As measured by quantitative polymerase chain reaction in peripheral blood cells separated into mononuclear and granulocyte fractions.</description>
        <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Gamma-retroviral Mediated ADA Gene Transfer</title>
            <description>Transfer of the human ADA gene to isolated CD34+ cells from the bone marrow</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Number of Participants With Greater Than 1% of Gene-Modified Cells in the Peripheral Blood</title>
          <description>As measured by quantitative polymerase chain reaction in peripheral blood cells separated into mononuclear and granulocyte fractions.</description>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="10"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>For peripheral blood mononuclear cells</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="10"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>for peripheral blood granulocytes</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Number of Participants Reaching the Normal Range of ADA Enzyme Activity</title>
        <description>As measured by ADA enzyme activity in peripheral blood mononuclear cells</description>
        <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Gamma-retroviral Mediated ADA Gene Transfer</title>
            <description>Transfer of the human ADA gene to isolated CD34+ cells from the bone marrow</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Number of Participants Reaching the Normal Range of ADA Enzyme Activity</title>
          <description>As measured by ADA enzyme activity in peripheral blood mononuclear cells</description>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="10"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 8, 10, 12, 15, 18, 21, 24 months</time_frame>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Retroviral-mediated ADA Gene Transfer</title>
          <description>Transfer of the human ADA gene to isolated CD34+ cells from the bone marrow.&#xD;
ADA gene transfer: Autologous CD34+ cells transduced with the retroviral vector MND-ADA, carrying the human ADA gene.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <default_assessment>Systematic Assessment</default_assessment>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="10"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Immune system disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Infection requiring hospitalization</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="10"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>5</frequency_threshold>
        <default_assessment>Systematic Assessment</default_assessment>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="9" subjects_at_risk="10"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Blood and lymphatic system disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>neutropenia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="9" subjects_at_risk="10"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>Principal Investigators are NOT employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Dr. Donald B. Kohn</name_or_title>
      <organization>University of California Los Angeles</organization>
      <phone>310-794-1964</phone>
      <email>dkohn1@mednet.ucla.edu</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

