<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03648931</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MTN-041</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>UM1AI068633</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>UM1AI068615</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>UM1AI106707</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>38161</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03648931</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Microbicide/PrEP Acceptability Among Mothers and Male Partners in Africa</brief_title>
  <acronym>MAMMA</acronym>
  <official_title>Qualitative Assessment of Acceptability of Vaginal Ring (VR) and Oral Pre-exposure Prophylaxis (PrEP) Use During Pregnancy and Breastfeeding</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Microbicide Trials Network</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Microbicide Trials Network</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The MTN-041 study is a multi-site exploratory study using focus group discussions (FGDs) and&#xD;
      in-depth interviews (IDIs) to identify individual, interpersonal, social and cultural factors&#xD;
      that may affect potential uptake of two safe and effective HIV prevention products, the&#xD;
      monthly dapivirine (DPV) vaginal ring (VR) and daily oral pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP), by&#xD;
      pregnant and breastfeeding women in Africa.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      MTN-041 is an exploratory study primarily designed to identify individual, interpersonal,&#xD;
      social and cultural factors that may affect potential uptake of two safe and effective HIV&#xD;
      prevention products, the monthly DPV VR and daily oral PrEP, in a vulnerable yet&#xD;
      seldom-studied population, pregnant and breastfeeding women. MTN-041 will utilize FGDs and&#xD;
      IDIs to elicit community and health professional perceptions about vaginal practices, sexual&#xD;
      activity, use of medicines, and HIV risk during pregnancy or breastfeeding, including how&#xD;
      these perceptions may affect pregnant and breastfeeding women's acceptability of using&#xD;
      intravaginal products and oral medications like the DPV VR and Truvada oral tablet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The MTN-041 study population will consist of HIV-uninfected women 18-40 years old who are&#xD;
      currently or were recently (within two years) pregnant or breastfeeding, men aged 18 years or&#xD;
      older whose partners are currently or were recently (within two years) pregnant or&#xD;
      breastfeeding, grandmothers whose daughters or daughters-in-law are currently or were&#xD;
      recently (within two years) pregnant or breastfeeding, and key informants (KIs), which&#xD;
      include: health care professionals (HCPs), traditional birth attendants (TBAs), providers of&#xD;
      family planning, antenatal, and traditional health services to women, providers of other&#xD;
      social services to women, and community leaders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up to 60 men and women will be selected at each site for participation in this study, for a&#xD;
      maximum total of 240 study participants. This includes up to 50 FGD participants (currently&#xD;
      or recently pregnant or breastfeeding women, male partners of women who are currently or were&#xD;
      recently pregnant or breastfeeding, and grandmothers with currently or recently pregnant or&#xD;
      breastfeeding daughters/daughters-in-law) and up to 10 KIs selected at each site, for a&#xD;
      maximum total of 200 FGD participants and 40 KIs enrolled across all sites.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 31, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 2, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 2, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of VR during pregnancy and breastfeeding, including willingness to use the VR or support its use</measure>
    <time_frame>3-6 months during Q2/Q3 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Focus group discussions and key informant in-depth interviews</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of oral PrEP during pregnancy and breastfeeding, including willingness to use oral PrEP or support its use</measure>
    <time_frame>3-6 months during Q2/Q3 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Focus group discussions and key informant in-depth interviews</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Product preferences during pregnancy and breastfeeding</measure>
    <time_frame>3-6 months during Q2/Q3 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Focus group discussions and key informant in-depth interviews</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sexual activity and contraceptive use during pregnancy and breastfeeding</measure>
    <time_frame>3-6 months during Q2/Q3 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Focus group discussions and key informant in-depth interviews</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceptions of HIV risk during pregnancy and breastfeeding</measure>
    <time_frame>3-6 months during Q2/Q3 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Focus group discussions and key informant in-depth interviews</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Community beliefs and practices related to pregnancy and breastfeeding, including use of oral medications and intravaginal products</measure>
    <time_frame>3-6 months during Q2/Q3 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Focus group discussions and key informant in-depth interviews</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">232</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Prevention</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant or Breastfeeding Women</arm_group_label>
    <description>No actual intervention is planned. A single focus group discussion (FGD) with community members in the same group assignment will be conducted to assess study outcome measures.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Male Partners</arm_group_label>
    <description>No actual intervention is planned. A single focus group discussion (FGD) with community members in the same group assignment will be conducted to assess study outcome measures.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Grandmothers</arm_group_label>
    <description>No actual intervention is planned. A single focus group discussion (FGD) with community members in the same group assignment will be conducted to assess study outcome measures.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Key Informants</arm_group_label>
    <description>No actual intervention is planned. A single in-depth interview (IDI) will be conducted to assess study outcome measures.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Focus Group Discussion (FGD)</intervention_name>
    <description>No actual intervention is planned. A single focus group discussion (FGD) with community members in the same group assignment will be conducted to assess study outcome measures. In particular, the FGDs will focus on:&#xD;
Perceptions of taboos and acceptable and/or typical practices during pregnancy, childbirth and breastfeeding&#xD;
Perceptions of HIV risk during pregnancy and breastfeeding&#xD;
Perceived role of male partners during pregnancy and breastfeeding&#xD;
Main challenge(s) perceived with VR and oral PrEP use during pregnancy and breastfeeding&#xD;
Main factor(s) perceived to facilitate VR and oral PrEP use during pregnancy and breastfeeding&#xD;
Willingness to join a VR and/or oral PrEP study during pregnancy and breastfeeding</description>
    <arm_group_label>Grandmothers</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Male Partners</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant or Breastfeeding Women</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>In-depth Interview (IDI)</intervention_name>
    <description>No actual intervention is planned. A single in-depth interview (IDI) will be conducted to assess study outcome measures, focusing on the following topics:&#xD;
Perceptions of taboos and acceptable and/or typical practices during pregnancy, childbirth and breastfeeding&#xD;
Perceptions of HIV risk during pregnancy and breastfeeding&#xD;
Perceived role of male partners during pregnancy and breastfeeding&#xD;
Main challenge(s) perceived with VR and oral PrEP use during pregnancy and breastfeeding&#xD;
Main factor(s) perceived to facilitate VR and oral PrEP use during pregnancy and breastfeeding&#xD;
How others in their professional and social networks and communities would view the VR and/or oral PrEP use by pregnant and breastfeeding women</description>
    <arm_group_label>Key Informants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The MTN-041 study population will consist of HIV-uninfected women 18-40 years old who are&#xD;
        currently or were recently (within two years) pregnant or breastfeeding, men aged 18 years&#xD;
        or older whose partners are currently or were recently (within two years) pregnant or&#xD;
        breastfeeding, grandmothers whose daughters or daughters-in-law are currently or were&#xD;
        recently (within two years) pregnant or breastfeeding, and key informants (KIs), which&#xD;
        include: health care providers (HCPs), traditional birth attendants (TBAs), providers of&#xD;
        family planning, antenatal, and traditional health services to women, providers of other&#xD;
        social services to women, and community leaders.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Able and willing to provide written informed consent in one of the study languages.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able and willing to complete the required study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
             For currently or recently pregnant or breastfeeding women:&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Between the ages of 18 to 40 years old (inclusive) at Enrolment, verified per site&#xD;
             standard operating procedures (SOPs).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Currently or recently (within two years) pregnant or breastfeeding (by self-report).&#xD;
&#xD;
             For male partners:&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Aged 18 years or older at Enrolment, verified per site SOPs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Identifies as a primary sexual partner of a woman who is currently or was recently&#xD;
             (within two years) pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
             For grandmothers:&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Aged 18 years or older at Enrolment, verified per site SOPs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Identifies as the maternal or paternal grandmother of a daughter or daughter-in-law&#xD;
             who is currently or was recently (within two years) pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note: The term &quot;daughter-in-law&quot; includes women who are/were not married to their male&#xD;
             partner during or after pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
             For service provider KIs:&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Aged 18 years or older at Enrolment, verified per site SOPs.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Currently working as a clinician (e.g., obstetrician, nurse, pharmacist, etc.),&#xD;
             traditional care provider (e.g., TBA, healer, midwife, etc.), social service provider&#xD;
             (e.g., social worker, family planning counselor, etc.) or community health worker in&#xD;
             one of the study countries, verified per site SOPs.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Experienced in providing services to pregnant and/or breastfeeding women.&#xD;
&#xD;
             For community leader KIs:&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Aged 18 years or older at Enrolment, verified per site SOPs.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Currently acting in a community leadership role (e.g., local chief, religious leader,&#xD;
             etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Has any condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator of Record (IoR)/designee,&#xD;
             would preclude informed consent, make study participation unsafe, complicate&#xD;
             interpretation of study outcome data, or otherwise interfere with achieving the study&#xD;
             objectives.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. For currently or recently pregnant or breastfeeding women: known HIV-positive status,&#xD;
             verified per recent health record (e.g., health passport, ante-natal book, HIV test&#xD;
             card, or similar document) or by self-report if health record(s) not available.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ariane van der Straten, PhD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Women's Global Health Imperative Program, RTI International</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Blantyre Clinical Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Blantyre</city>
        <country>Malawi</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wits Reproductive Health and HIV Institute (WRHI) Clinical Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Johannesburg</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Makerere University - Johns Hopkins University (MU-JHU) Research Collaboration Clinical Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kampala</city>
        <country>Uganda</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Zengeza Clinical Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Harare</city>
        <country>Zimbabwe</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Malawi</country>
    <country>South Africa</country>
    <country>Uganda</country>
    <country>Zimbabwe</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>van der Straten A, Ryan JH, Reddy K, Etima J, Taulo F, Mutero P, Taylor J, Piper J, Musara P; MTN-041/MAMMA Study Team. Influences on willingness to use vaginal or oral HIV PrEP during pregnancy and breastfeeding in Africa: the multisite MAMMA study. J Int AIDS Soc. 2020 Jun;23(6):e25536. doi: 10.1002/jia2.25536.</citation>
    <PMID>32524700</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Flax VL, Hawley I, Ryan J, Chitukuta M, Mathebula F, Nakalega R, Seyama L, Taulo F, van der Straten A; MTN-041/MAMMA Study Team. After their wives have delivered, a lot of men like going out: Perceptions of HIV transmission risk and support for HIV prevention methods during breastfeeding in sub-Saharan Africa. Matern Child Nutr. 2021 Apr;17(2):e13120. doi: 10.1111/mcn.13120. Epub 2020 Dec 15.</citation>
    <PMID>33325126</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 2, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 23, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 28, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

