<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03641313</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCI-2018-01739</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2018-01739</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>VICC LOI#18012</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>10211</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>10211</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>UM1CA186689</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03641313</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Berzosertib and Irinotecan in Treating Patients With Progressive, Metastatic, or Unresectable TP53 Mutant Gastric or Gastroesophageal Junction Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2 Single-Arm Study of M6620 in Combination With Irinotecan in Patients With Progressive TP53 Mutant Gastric and Gastro-Esophageal Junction Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase II trial studies the how well berzosertib and irinotecan work in treating patients&#xD;
      with gastric or gastroesophageal junction cancer that is growing, spreading or getting worse&#xD;
      (progressive), has spread to other places in the body (metastatic), or cannot be removed by&#xD;
      surgery (unresectable). Berzosertib may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of&#xD;
      the enzymes needed for growth. Chemotherapy drugs, such as irinotecan, work in different ways&#xD;
      to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells, by stopping them from&#xD;
      dividing, or by stopping them from spreading. Giving berzosertib and irinotecan may work&#xD;
      better than irinotecan alone in treating patients with gastric and gastroesophageal junction&#xD;
      cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Determine objective response rate (ORR) superiority (target 35%) in TP53 mutant patients&#xD;
      with progressive metastatic or unresectable gastric/gastroesophageal junction (GEJ) cancer&#xD;
      who receive berzosertib (M6620) and irinotecan compared to ORR (15%) in historical control&#xD;
      patients treated with single agent irinotecan alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Determine duration of response (DOR), time to progression (TTP), progression-free survival&#xD;
      (PFS), and overall survival (OS) superiority in TP53 mutant gastric/GEJ cancer patients who&#xD;
      receive M6620 and irinotecan compared to these measures in historical control patients&#xD;
      treated with irinotecan alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. Perform the following correlative studies in 9 patients: gamma-H2AX, KAP1 phosphorylated&#xD;
      (p)-Ser 824 and p-ATR analysis from biopsies collected at 24 hours (+/- 1 hour)&#xD;
      post-irinotecan infusion on cycle 1 day 2 (C1D2) and at 24 hours (+/- 1 hour) post-M6620 on&#xD;
      cycle 2 day 2 (C2D2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Determine ORR, DOR, TTP, PFS, and OS in patients with other concomitant damage response&#xD;
      defects (DDRD), such as mutations in BRCA1, BRCA2, MRE11, RAD50, RAD51, RAD52, RAD54L, NBN,&#xD;
      ATM, H2AX, PALB2, RPA, BRIP1, BARD1, ATR, ATRX, CHK1, CHK2, MDM2, MDM4, FANCA, FANCC, FANCD2,&#xD;
      FANCE, FANCF, FANCG, FANCL, treated with the experimental combination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. Determine whether patients with first line platinum sensitivity (PFS &gt; 3 months)&#xD;
      demonstrate improved ORR, DOR, TTP, PFS, and OS compared to patients who were platinum&#xD;
      insensitive (PFS &lt; 3 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive irinotecan intravenously (IV) over 90 minutes and berzosertib IV over 60&#xD;
      minutes on days 1 and 15. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression&#xD;
      or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 30 days and then every 2&#xD;
      months for up to 1 year.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Suspended</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Scheduled Interim Monitoring&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR) according to Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) 1.1 response criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of responses (DOR)</measure>
    <time_frame>From when patients achieve their best response (complete response [CR] or partial response [PR]) to when they progress, assessed up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated using the method of Kaplan and Meier. 95% confidence intervals for all point estimates of variables overall and for effect sizes (odd ratios, hazard ratios, differential pre-post biomarker expression) among subgroups will be estimated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to progression (TTP)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment to disease progression or death due to progression, assessed up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated using the method of Kaplan and Meier. 95% confidence intervals for all point estimates of variables overall and for effect sizes (odd ratios, hazard ratios, differential pre-post biomarker expression) among subgroups will be estimated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment to disease progression or death for any reason, assessed up to 1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From study enrollment to death for any reason, assessed up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated using the method of Kaplan and Meier. 95% confidence intervals for all point estimates of variables overall and for effect sizes (odd ratios, hazard ratios, differential pre-post biomarker expression) among subgroups will be estimated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>ORR in sub-cohorts based on first-line platinum sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>DOR in sub-cohorts based on first-line platinum sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>TTP in sub-cohorts based on first-line platinum sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>PFS in sub-cohorts based on first-line platinum sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>OS in sub-cohorts based on first-line platinum sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Presence of other deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) damage response defects (DDRD)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Will be summarized as frequency counts and percent of study group.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">28</enrollment>
  <condition>Clinical Stage III Gastric Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Clinical Stage III Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Clinical Stage IV Gastric Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Clinical Stage IV Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Clinical Stage IVA Gastric Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Clinical Stage IVA Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Clinical Stage IVB Gastric Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Clinical Stage IVB Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Gastric Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage III Gastric Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage III Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IIIA Gastric Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IIIA Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IIIB Gastric Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IIIB Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IIIC Gastric Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IV Gastric Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IV Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IVA Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IVB Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Postneoadjuvant Therapy Stage III Gastric Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Postneoadjuvant Therapy Stage III Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Postneoadjuvant Therapy Stage IIIA Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Postneoadjuvant Therapy Stage IIIB Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Postneoadjuvant Therapy Stage IV Gastric Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Postneoadjuvant Therapy Stage IV Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Postneoadjuvant Therapy Stage IVA Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Postneoadjuvant Therapy Stage IVB Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Unresectable Gastric Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Unresectable Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (irinotecan and M6620)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive irinotecan IV over 90 minutes and berzosertib IV over 60 minutes on days 1 and 15. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Berzosertib</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (irinotecan and M6620)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>2-Pyrazinamine, 3-(3-(4-((Methylamino)methyl)phenyl)-5-isoxazolyl)-5-(4-((1-methylethyl)sulfonyl)phenyl)-</other_name>
    <other_name>M 6620</other_name>
    <other_name>M6620</other_name>
    <other_name>VX 970</other_name>
    <other_name>VX-970</other_name>
    <other_name>VX970</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Irinotecan</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (irinotecan and M6620)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have histologically or cytologically confirmed progressive metastatic or&#xD;
             unresectable gastric or GEJ adenocarcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have measurable disease, defined as at least one lesion that can be&#xD;
             accurately measured in at least one dimension (longest diameter to be recorded for&#xD;
             non-nodal lesions and short axis for nodal lesions) as &gt;= 20 mm (&gt;= 2 cm) by chest&#xD;
             x-ray or as &gt;= 10 mm (&gt;= 1 cm) with computed tomography (CT) scan, magnetic resonance&#xD;
             imaging (MRI), or calipers by clinical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have progressed after or been intolerant of at least one prior&#xD;
             chemotherapy regimen. Patients with HER2 positive gastric and GEJ adenocarcinoma must&#xD;
             have progressed on trastuzumab plus chemotherapy in the first line setting. Patients&#xD;
             with microsatellite unstable (MSI-H) tumors must have received prior immunotherapy&#xD;
             with pembrolizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both men and women of all races and ethnic groups are eligible for this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status =&lt; 1 (Karnofsky &gt;= 60%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Leukocytes &gt;= 3,000/mcL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,500/mcL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &gt;= 100,000/mcL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin within normal institutional limits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase&#xD;
             [SGOT])/alanine aminotransferase (serum glutamic pyruvic transaminase [SGPT]) =&lt; 2.5 x&#xD;
             institutional upper limit of normal (ULN); if liver involvement =&lt; 5 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine clearance &gt;= 45 mL/min/1.73 m^2 for patients with creatinine levels above&#xD;
             institutional normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a TP53 mutation (only those known hot-spot mutations that fall&#xD;
             within exon 2 or exons 4-11 will be accepted) determined from available archived tumor&#xD;
             tissue that has been subjected to next generation sequencing (NGS) through&#xD;
             FoundationOne/FoundationOneCDx or a similar assay performed in a Clinical Laboratory&#xD;
             Improvement Amendments (CLIA)-certified laboratory. Investigators from other sites,&#xD;
             who have potential patients who meet study eligibility, will send copies of NGS&#xD;
             reports from these patients via Medidata Rave case reports to the responsible study&#xD;
             coordinator. Our research team will review each report to ensure each patient&#xD;
             possesses the mutations of interest. Similar review will happen for each patient we&#xD;
             enroll on the study at our institution. Case reports from all screened patients will&#xD;
             be centrally available on the Rave study database.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nine patients must be willing to undergo endoscopic or CT guided tumor biopsies for&#xD;
             mandatory correlative studies. If the biopsy is deemed not safe by the treating&#xD;
             physician, the patient may still enroll given that the other eligibility criteria are&#xD;
             met.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The effects of M6620 on the developing human fetus are unknown. For this reason and&#xD;
             because deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA)-damage response (DDR) inhibitors, as well as&#xD;
             irinotecan, are known to be teratogenic, women of child-bearing potential and men able&#xD;
             to father children who have female partners of child-bearing potential must agree to&#xD;
             use adequate contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence)&#xD;
             prior to study entry, for the duration of study participation, and for 6 months after&#xD;
             trial participant's final dose of M6620 or irinotecan (whichever agent is completed&#xD;
             last). Should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while she or her&#xD;
             partner is participating in this study, she should inform her treating physician&#xD;
             immediately.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with early stage untreated or resectable gastric adenocarcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had chemotherapy or radiotherapy within 4 weeks (6 weeks for&#xD;
             nitrosoureas or mitomycin C) prior to entering the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have previously received irinotecan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have not recovered from adverse events due to prior anti-cancer therapy&#xD;
             (i.e., have residual toxicities &gt; grade 1, except alopecia) that was administered more&#xD;
             than four weeks prior to starting study therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are receiving any other investigational agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with untreated or symptomatic brain metastases should be excluded from this&#xD;
             clinical trial because of their poor prognosis and because they often develop&#xD;
             progressive neurologic dysfunction that would confound the evaluation of neurologic&#xD;
             and other adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to M6620 or irinotecan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  M6620 is primarily metabolized by CYP3A4, and irinotecan and its active metabolite,&#xD;
             SN-38, are metabolized by CYP3A4 and UGT1A1, respectively; therefore, concomitant&#xD;
             administration with strong inhibitors of CYP3A4 (e.g., ketoconazole, itraconazole,&#xD;
             clarithromycin, ritonavir, indinavir, nelfinavir and saquinavir) or inducers of CYP3A4&#xD;
             (e.g. rifampin, phenytoin, carbamazepine, phenobarbital, St. John's Wort) should be&#xD;
             avoided. Because the lists of these agents are constantly changing, it is important to&#xD;
             regularly consult a frequently-updated medical reference for a list of drugs to avoid&#xD;
             or minimize use of. As part of the enrollment/informed consent procedures, the patient&#xD;
             will be counseled on the risk of interactions with other agents, and what to do if new&#xD;
             medications need to be prescribed or if the patient is considering a new&#xD;
             over-the-counter medicine or herbal product.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with&#xD;
             study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women are excluded from this study because M6620 as a DNA-damage response&#xD;
             (DDR) inhibitor may have the potential for teratogenic or abortifacient effects.&#xD;
             Because there is an unknown but potential risk for adverse events in nursing infants&#xD;
             secondary to treatment of the mother with M6620, breastfeeding should be discontinued&#xD;
             if the mother is treated with M6620. These potential risks also apply to irinotecan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-positive patients are excluded unless they have an&#xD;
             undetectable viral load and are able to use anti-viral agents that do not interact&#xD;
             with CYP3A4 (or regimens with agents that are not major inhibitors of cytochrome P450&#xD;
             enzymes).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of other malignancy within 36 months prior to enrollment. Patients with local&#xD;
             cancers of any type, provided no recurrence over this timeframe, are eligible.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Satya Das</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale University Cancer Center LAO</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City of Hope Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Duarte</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Los Angeles County-USC Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90033</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>USC / Norris Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90033</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UC Irvine Health/Chao Family Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orange</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92868</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California Davis Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95817</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UM Sylvester Comprehensive Cancer Center at Coral Gables</name>
      <address>
        <city>Coral Gables</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33146</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UM Sylvester Comprehensive Cancer Center at Deerfield Beach</name>
      <address>
        <city>Deerfield Beach</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33442</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Miami Miller School of Medicine-Sylvester Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33136</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UM Sylvester Comprehensive Cancer Center at Kendall</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33176</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UM Sylvester Comprehensive Cancer Center at Plantation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Plantation</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33324</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Northwestern University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60611</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Clinical Research Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fairway</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>HaysMed University of Kansas Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hays</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>67601</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lawrence Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lawrence</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66044</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Olathe Health Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Olathe</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66061</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Cancer Center-Overland Park</name>
      <address>
        <city>Overland Park</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascension Via Christi - Pittsburg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburg</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66762</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Salina Regional Health Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salina</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>67401</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Health System Saint Francis Campus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Topeka</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66606</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Hospital-Westwood Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Westwood</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Truman Medical Centers</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>64108</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Cancer Center - North</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>64154</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Cancer Center - Lee's Summit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lee's Summit</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>64064</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Cancer Center at North Kansas City Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>North Kansas City</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>64116</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wake Forest University at Clemmons</name>
      <address>
        <city>Clemmons</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27012</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wake Forest Baptist Health - Wilkes Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wilkesboro</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28659</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wake Forest University Health Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winston-Salem</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27157</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ohio State University Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oklahoma City</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <zip>73104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vanderbilt University/Ingram Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Huntsman Cancer Institute/University of Utah</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84112</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 21, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 21, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 22, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>NCI is committed to sharing data in accordance with NIH policy. For more details on how clinical trial data is shared, access the link to the NIH data sharing policy page</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://grants.nih.gov/policy/sharing.htm</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

