<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03645980</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Dial-1</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2017-002468-41</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>AIO-HEP-0318</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03645980</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>DKN-01 Inhibition in Advanced Liver Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I/II Multicenter, Open-label Study of DKN-01 to Investigate the Anti-tumor Activity and Safety of DKN-01 in Patients With Hepatocellular Carcinoma and WNT Signaling Alterations</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Leap Therapeutics, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This clinical trial is a prospective, open label, single arm oncological phase I/II trial in&#xD;
      patients with hepatocellular carcinoma and WNT signaling alterations. The trial consists of&#xD;
      two parts: Part A is a phase I study investigating the safety of DKN-01 administered as mono-&#xD;
      as well as combination therapy with sorafenib in a 2 step dose escalation.Part B is a phase&#xD;
      II study to investigate the anti-tumor activity and safety of DKN-01 in patients with&#xD;
      advanced HCC. DKN-01 is administered at the recommend phase II dose (RP2D) for monotherapy&#xD;
      and at the recommend phase II dose for combination therapy established in Part A.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Part A is a phase I study investigating the safety of DKN-01 administered as mono- as well as&#xD;
      combination therapy with sorafenib in a 2 step dose escalation. Up to 20 patients with&#xD;
      advanced HCC will be included in Part A. Tumor assessment will be performed every 8 weeks.The&#xD;
      first 10 patients (cohort 1) will start with IV infusion of 300 mg DKN-01 on day 1 and 15&#xD;
      (monotherapy for 28 days). DLTs will be determined. After cycle 2 of monotherapy patients of&#xD;
      cohort 1 will continue with combination of 300 mg DKN-01 IV on day 1 and 15 and sorafenib&#xD;
      (recommended dose 800 mg per day or at discretion of the investigator) until disease&#xD;
      progression. After 2 cycles of combination therapy and prior to the start of the next cohort&#xD;
      DLTs will be determined. Part B is a phase II study to investigate the anti-tumor activity&#xD;
      and safety of DKN-01 in patients with advanced HCC. DKN-01 is administered at the recommend&#xD;
      phase II dose (RP2D) for monotherapy and at the recommend phase II dose for combination&#xD;
      therapy established in Part A. Depending on the tolerability, the doses may be different for&#xD;
      monotherapy and for combination therapy. Up to 50 additional patients with advanced HCC may&#xD;
      be enrolled in Part B. Every 8 weeks tumor assessment will be performed. If progression of&#xD;
      disease (PD1) is observed with DKN-01 monotherapy, patients will continue on study receiving&#xD;
      DKN-01 at the recommend phase II dose for combination therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 10, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase I: Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>assessment period is 2 cycles for monotherapy (each cycle is 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Absolute and relative incidences of treatment-emergent adverse events.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase I: Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>assessment period is 2 cycles for combination therapy (each cycle is 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Absolute and relative incidences of treatment-emergent adverse events.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Time to progression (TTP2)</measure>
    <time_frame>time from the first DKN-01 intake until PD2, assessed up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The TTP2 is defined as the time from the first DKN-01 intake until PD2. Tumor progression is assessed by mRECIST criteria (modified Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase I: pharmacokinetics of DKN-01</measure>
    <time_frame>monotherapy for 8 weeks and in combination with sorafenib for 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Serum DKN-01 levels to characterize the pharmacokinetics of DKN-01 when administered at the dose of 300 mg and 600 mg as monotherapy and in combination with sorafenib</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>time from first DKN-01 intake until death from any cause, assessed up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Overall survival is defined as the time from first DKN-01 intake until death from any cause, assessed up to 2 years</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: progression free survival (PFS1, PFS2)</measure>
    <time_frame>time from first DKN- 01 intake until death or PD1 or PD2 respectively whichever comes first, assessed up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Progression free survival (PFS1, PFS2) is defined as the time from first DKN-&#xD;
01 intake until death or PD1 or PD2 respectively whichever comes first, assessed up to 2 years</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II:objective response rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>2, 4 and 6 months after first DKN- 01 intake</time_frame>
    <description>ORR (CR or PR), binary measurement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: disease control rate (DCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>2, 4 and 6 months after first DKN- 01 intake</time_frame>
    <description>DCR (CR, PR or SD), binary measurement (CR, PR or SD) after 2, 4 and 6 months will be analyzed by absolute and relative frequencies.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Duration of disease control with DKN-01</measure>
    <time_frame>time from first to the last disease control (CR, PR, or SD), assessed up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of disease control is defined as the time from the first to the last occurrence of disease control (CR, PR, or SD), assessed up to 2 years</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>assessment period is during mono- and combination therapy with sorafenib (through study completion, estimated 2 years)</time_frame>
    <description>Absolute and relative incidences of treatment-emergent adverse events as assessed by NCI CTCAE v5.0</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>DKN-01 300 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Phase I Study treatment will be started as monotherapy with DKN-01 for up to 8 weeks or until unacceptable toxicity occurs. The study will be continued as combination therapy of DKN-01 and sorafenib until objective disease progression (PD) or unacceptable toxicity occurs. The dose of DKN-01 for cohort 1 will be 300 mg , depending on the results of the safety assessment. Phase II The dose of DKN-01 will be the recommended phase II dose (RP2D) determined from Part A. Study treatment will be started as monotherapy with DKN-01 until objective disease progression (PD1) or unacceptable toxicity occurs. After PD1, study treatment will be continued as combination therapy of DKN-01 and sorafenib until disease progression (PD2) or unacceptable toxicity occurs.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>DKN-01 600 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Phase I Study treatment will be started as monotherapy with DKN-01 for up to 8 weeks or until unacceptable toxicity occurs. The study will be continued as combination therapy of DKN-01 and sorafenib until objective disease progression (PD) or unacceptable toxicity occurs. The dose of DKN-01 for cohort 2 will be 600 mg or 150 mg, depending on the results of the safety assessment. Phase II The dose of DKN-01 will be the recommended phase II dose (RP2D) determined from Part A. Study treatment will be started as monotherapy with DKN-01 until objective disease progression (PD1) or unacceptable toxicity occurs. After PD1, study treatment will be continued as combination therapy of DKN-01 and sorafenib until disease progression (PD2) or unacceptable toxicity occurs.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>DKN-01 300 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>DKN-01 will be administered intravenous (IV) over a minimum of 30 minutes and up to a maximum of 2 hours given on days 1 and 15 of each 28 day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>DKN-01 300 mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>DKN-01 600 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>DKN-01 will be administered intravenous (IV) over a minimum of 30 minutes and up to a maximum of 2 hours given on days 1 and 15 of each 28 day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>DKN-01 600 mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sorafenib</intervention_name>
    <description>For combination with DKN-01, sorafenib will be administrated according to standard clinical practice. Part A: After 8 weeks monotherapy with DKN-01, the study will be continued as combination therapy of DKN-01 and sorafenib until objective disease progression (PD) or unacceptable toxicity occurs. Part B:After PD1, study treatment will be continued as combination therapy of DKN-01 and sorafenib until disease progression (PD2) or unacceptable toxicity occurs.</description>
    <arm_group_label>DKN-01 300 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>DKN-01 600 mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ambulatory male or female patients ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have histologically confirmed diagnosis (by either primary surgical&#xD;
             specimen or biopsy for recurrence) of advanced stage or recurrent diagnosis of HCC&#xD;
             based on histopathologic findings.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tumor tissue is mandatory for pre-treatment evaluation (baseline) (fresh biopsy during&#xD;
             4-weeks screening time preferred. Archived specimen is only acceptable, if ≤ 6 months&#xD;
             old. Baseline tumor biopsy samples must be available prior to the first dose of&#xD;
             DKN-01.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tumor tissue (FFPE) must be received by central histopathology laboratory for&#xD;
             correlative studies (fine needle aspiration and bone metastasis samples are not&#xD;
             acceptable).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with activated WNT/β-catenin signaling identified by glutamine synthetase&#xD;
             staining (high positive staining in tumor tissue) by an approved lab. Positive&#xD;
             staining must be confirmed prior to first dose of DKN-01.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Child-Pugh score &lt;7 (Child-Pugh Class A).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Barcelona Clinic Liver Cancer (BCLC) Stage C disease or BCLC Stage B disease not&#xD;
             amenable to resection, locoregional therapy or refractory to locoregional therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one tumor lesion measurable on radiographic imaging as defined by mRECIST for&#xD;
             HCC that has not been previously treated by locoregional therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Locoregional therapies or radiation therapy must be completed at least 4 weeks prior&#xD;
             to baseline scan. All toxic effects &gt; grade 1 (NCI CTCAE v5.0) related to any prior&#xD;
             HCC treatment must be resolved. Palliative radiotherapy for symptomic control is&#xD;
             acceptable and no additional radiotherapy for the same lesion is planned. (like bone&#xD;
             metastases should not be targets for RECIST).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG performance status (PS) of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Estimated life expectancy of at least 3 months, in the judgment of the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Disease-free of active second/secondary or prior malignancies for ≥2 years with the&#xD;
             exception of currently treated basal cell, squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, or&#xD;
             carcinoma in-situ of the cervix or breast.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients are eligible to enroll if they have non-viral-HCC, or if they have HBV-HCC,&#xD;
             or HCV-HCC defined as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HBV-HCC: Resolved HBV infection (as evidenced by detectable HBV surface antibody,&#xD;
                  detectable HBV core antibody, undetectable HBV DNA, and undetectable HBV surface&#xD;
                  antigen) or chronic HBV infection (as evidenced by detectable HBV surface antigen&#xD;
                  or HBV DNA). Patients with chronic HBV infection must have HBV DNA &lt; 2000 IU/mL&#xD;
                  and must be on antiviral therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HCV-HCC: Active or resolved HCV infection as evidenced by detectable HCV RNA or&#xD;
                  antibody&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acceptable liver function:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin ≤2.0 × upper limit of normal (ULN).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≤5 × ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acceptable renal function:&#xD;
&#xD;
             o Calculated creatinine clearance ≥50 mL/min using the Cockcroft and Gault Method&#xD;
             (Cockroft and Gault 1976).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acceptable hematologic status:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Neutrophil Granulocyte ≥1500 cells/μl.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 8,5 g/dL (transfusion permitted within 30 days of study entry).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count ≥75,000 cells/μl.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acceptable coagulation status:&#xD;
&#xD;
             o INR ≤ 1.7 and no active bleeding, (i.e., no clinically significant bleeding within&#xD;
             14 days prior to first dose of study therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects who are post-menopausal (defined as spontaneous amenorrhea for at&#xD;
             least a year) or permanently sterilized (e.g. bilateral oophorectomy, hysterectomy,&#xD;
             bilateral salpingectomy) can participate in the trial and are not required to use any&#xD;
             contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child bearing potential (WOCBP, a woman is considered of childbearing&#xD;
             potential i.e. fertile, following menarche and until becoming post-menopausal) must&#xD;
             have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test within 7 days prior to first dose of&#xD;
             DKN- 01. The minimum sensitivity of the pregnancy test must be 25 IU/L or equivalent&#xD;
             units of HCG.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential must be willing to practice a highly effective and&#xD;
             medically accepted contraception method during trial and for 18 months after last dose&#xD;
             of study drug. A highly effective method of birth control is defined as one which&#xD;
             results in a low failure rate (i.e. less than 1% per year) when used consistently and&#xD;
             correctly such as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  combined (estrogen and progestogen containing) hormonal contraception associated&#xD;
                  with inhibition of ovulation: oral, intravaginal, transdermal&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  progestogen-only hormonal contraception associated with inhibition of ovulation:&#xD;
                  oral, injectable, implantable&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  intrauterine device (IUD)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  intrauterine hormone-releasing system ( IUS)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  bilateral tubal occlusion&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  vasectomised partner (medical assessment must be present and done)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  sexual abstinence when this is in line with the preferred and usual lifestyle of&#xD;
                  the subject&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Periodic abstinence (calendar, symptothermal, post-ovulation methods), withdrawal&#xD;
             (coitus interruptus), spermicides only, and lactational amenorrhoea method (LAM) are&#xD;
             not acceptable methods of contraception. Female condom and male condom should not be&#xD;
             used together.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexually-active male subjects must be willing to use contraception (condom,&#xD;
             contraception for non-pregnant WOCBP partner) with their partners throughout the study&#xD;
             and for 18 months after last dose of study drug and agree to inform the Investigator&#xD;
             if the respective partner becomes pregnant during this time&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provided written informed consent prior to any study-specific procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability of patient to understand nature, importance and individual consequences of&#xD;
             clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with the following histology of hepatocellular cancer are not eligible for&#xD;
             enrollment: fibrolamellar carcinoma or mixed hepatocellular cholangiocarcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New York Heart Association Class III or IV cardiac disease, myocardial infarction&#xD;
             within the past 6 months, or unstable arrhythmia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Specific cardiac preconditions : Fridericia-corrected QT interval (QTcF) &gt;470 msec&#xD;
             (female) or &gt;450 msec (male), or history of congenital long QT syndrome. Any ECG&#xD;
             abnormality that in the opinion of the Investigator would preclude safe participation&#xD;
             in the study; patients with pacemakers where QTc is not a reliable measure will&#xD;
             require an evaluation by a cardiologist to exclude co-existing cardiac conditions&#xD;
             which would prohibit safe participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active, uncontrolled bacterial, viral, or fungal infections, within 7 days of study&#xD;
             entry requiring systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known to be human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) positive,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of major organ transplant (i.e., heart, lungs, liver, or kidney).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of autologous/allogenic bone marrow transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious non-malignant disease that could compromise protocol objectives in the opinion&#xD;
             of the Investigator and/or Sponsor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or nursing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgical procedures, open biopsy or significant traumatic injury within 4 weeks&#xD;
             prior to treatment start (minor procedures within 1 week)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of osteonecrosis of the hip or evidence of structural bone abnormalities in&#xD;
             the proximal femur on magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scan that are symptomatic and&#xD;
             clinically significant. Degenerative changes of the hip joint are not exclusionary.&#xD;
             Screening of asymptomatic patients is not required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptomatic central nervous system (CNS) malignancy or metastasis. Patients with&#xD;
             treated CNS metastases are eligible provided their disease is radiographically stable,&#xD;
             asymptomatic, and they are not currently receiving corticosteroids and/or&#xD;
             anticonvulsants. Screening of asymptomatic patients without a history of CNS&#xD;
             metastases is not required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known osteoblastic bone metastasis. Screening of asymptomatic patients without a&#xD;
             history of metastatic bone lesions is not required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical or psychological conditions that would jeopardise an adequate and orderly&#xD;
             completion of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thrombotic or embolic events (except HCC tumor thrombus &lt;pVT4) within the past 6&#xD;
             months (including cerebrovascular accidents)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of portal hypertension with bleeding esophageal or gastric varices within the&#xD;
             past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with portal vein thrombosis = pVT4&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jens U Marquardt, Dr med</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Universitätsklinikum Schleswig Holstein Campus Lübeck</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jens U Marquardt, Dr med</last_name>
    <phone>++49 451 500</phone>
    <phone_ext>44100</phone_ext>
    <email>Jens.Marquardt@uksh.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Markus Möhler, Dr.med</last_name>
    <phone>+49 6131 17</phone>
    <phone_ext>6076</phone_ext>
    <email>markus.möhler@unimedizin-mainz.de</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Köln</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cologne</city>
        <zip>50937</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dirk-Thomas Waldschmidt, Dr. med</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>20246</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Henning Wege, PD Dr.</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Med. Hochschule Hannover</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hannover</city>
        <zip>30625</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Arndt Vogel, Prof Dr med</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Schleswig Holstein Campus Lübeck</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lübeck</city>
        <zip>23538</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jens Marquardt, Professor</last_name>
      <email>Jens.Marquardt@uksh.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsmedizin Mainz, I. Med. Klinik und Poliklinik</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mainz</city>
        <zip>55131</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jens U Marquardt, Dr.med.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 6131 17</phone>
      <phone_ext>6863</phone_ext>
      <email>marquarj@uni-mainz.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>II. Medizinische Universitätsklinik Gastroenterologie, Hepatologie, Infektiologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mannheim</city>
        <zip>68167</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andreas Teufel, Professor</last_name>
      <email>studien.med2@umm.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 17, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 22, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 20, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 20, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. J. U. Marquardt</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Jun. Prof. Dr. J. U. Marquardt</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>DKN-01</keyword>
  <keyword>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>WNT signaling</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

