<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03644342</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H-40404</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03644342</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Niraparib With Radiotherapy for Treatment of Metastatic Invasive Carcinoma of the Cervix</brief_title>
  <acronym>NIVIX</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase I/II Study of Niraparib With Radiotherapy for Treatment of Metastatic Invasive Carcinoma of the Cervix</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Michelle S Ludwig</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Tesaro, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Baylor College of Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The most effective strategy for managing distantly metastatic invasive carcinomas of the&#xD;
      cervix is not defined. Based on the success of niraparib in breast and ovarian cancer trials&#xD;
      and the concern for toxicities and comorbidities limiting the compliance of concurrent&#xD;
      cisplatin for cervical cancer, this study is a phase I/II study of women diagnosed with&#xD;
      distantly metastatic (Stage IV) disease to determine the maximum tolerated dose and to&#xD;
      evaluate the safety, tolerability and preliminary efficacy of niraparib, an orally available&#xD;
      small molecule PARP inhibitor when administered concurrently with definitive regional&#xD;
      radiotherapy for treatment of cervical cancer. Women enrolled in this study will receive 3-6&#xD;
      cycles of induction-style carboplatin and paclitaxel followed by definitive doses of pelvic&#xD;
      radiotherapy along with the oral niraparib given at the same time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 15, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose of niraparib</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months after end of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of niraparib when administered concurrently with whole pelvic radiotherapy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in local progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months after end of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in local progression-free survival for patients who have received 1 or more doses of niraparib with pelvic radiation as part of their treatment for a metastatic cervical cancer.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>acute toxicity profile of niraparib</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months after end of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>acute toxicity profile of niraparib administered concurrently with whole pelvic radiotherapy according to the CTCAE version 4 as well as the grade of each toxicity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the quality of life measured using FACT-Cx questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months after end of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-Cervix (FACT Cx). It measures health related quality of life for people with cervical cancer in 4 domains: physical well being, social/family well being, emotional well being, and functional well being. All questions are a 0-4 scale. The total score is then calculated as the sum of the un-weighted subscale scores (0-27). For all FACIT scales and symptom indices, the higher the score the better the QOL</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>tumor response</measure>
    <time_frame>End of treatment (8 weeks) and every 3 months during follow-up phase for up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>tumor response outside the radiation field using RECIST 1.1 for women receiving niraparib concurrently with whole pelvic radiotherapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Carcinoma of the Cervix</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Niraparib Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>For the purposes of this study, two dose levels of Niraparib (100 mg and 200 mg) will be evaluated concomitant with the concurrent administration of pelvic radiotherapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nirapaib</intervention_name>
    <description>(see treatment regimen and method of treatment assignment)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Niraparib Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Zejula</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participant must have histologically confirmed diagnosis of invasive squamous cell or&#xD;
             adenocarcinoma of the cervix, FIGO Stage IIIC2 or IV (see Appendix 5 of the currently&#xD;
             approved protocol).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participant must have an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status&#xD;
             of ≤ 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participant must be ≥ 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participant must have adequate organ function within 28 days of registration, defined&#xD;
             as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/µL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥ 100,000/µL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) or calculated creatinine&#xD;
                  clearance ≥ 30 mL/min using the Cockcroft-Gault equation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN (≤2.0 in patients with known Gilberts syndrome) OR&#xD;
                  direct bilirubin ≤ 1 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate aminotransferase and alanine aminotransferase ≤ 2.5 x ULN unless liver&#xD;
                  metastases are present, in which case they must be ≤ 5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participant receiving corticosteroids may continue as long as their dose is stable for&#xD;
             least 4 weeks prior to initiating protocol therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participant must agree to not donate blood during the study or for 90 days after the&#xD;
             last dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Female participant of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test&#xD;
             within 14 days prior to registration. Pregnancy test should be repeated within 7 days&#xD;
             before CT simulation if more than 14 days has passed since the previous pregnancy&#xD;
             test. (If serum test is falsely positive, pregnancy can be excluded by appropriate&#xD;
             pelvic imaging.) Patient must agree to abstain from activities that could result in&#xD;
             pregnancy from screening through completion of 7 days of pelvic radiotherapy. Females&#xD;
             of non-childbearing potential is defined as follows (by other than medical reasons):&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ≥45 years of age and has not had menses for &gt;1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Post-hysterectomy, post-bilateral oophorectomy, post external beam radiation of 6&#xD;
                  Gy to the pelvis, or post-tubal ligation. Documented hysterectomy or oophorectomy&#xD;
                  must be confirmed with medical records of the actual procedure or confirmed by a&#xD;
                  physical exam or imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Participant must agree to not breastfeed during the study and for 180 days after the&#xD;
             last dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Participant must be able to understand the study procedures and agree to participate&#xD;
             in the study by providing written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Participant must have completed 3-6 cycles of platinum based chemotherapy (acceptable&#xD;
             regimens in Appendix 7) with clinical evidence of CR (complete response) or PR&#xD;
             (partial response) by RECIST criteria no less than 4 weeks and no greater than 12&#xD;
             weeks prior to initiation of protocol therapy. If bevacizumab used, 6 weeks must&#xD;
             elapse between administration of bevacizumab and start of radiation therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Participant must be eligible for chemoradiation treatment in the opinion of the&#xD;
             treating investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Participants who are HIV+ must have CD4 counts &gt;200/dL and demonstrate documented&#xD;
             HAART compliance&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Chemotherapy-related hematological toxicities must have resolved to Grade 1 or less.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Participant must have had a CT (chest/abdomen/pelvis) or PET-CT, within 56 days of&#xD;
             registration&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participant must not be simultaneously enrolled in any interventional clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participant must not have known documented intra-uterine pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participant must not have had major surgery ≤ 3 weeks prior to initiating protocol&#xD;
             therapy and participant must have recovered from any surgical effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participant must not have received investigational therapy ≤ 4 weeks, or within a time&#xD;
             interval less than at least 5 half-lives of the investigational agent, whichever is&#xD;
             shorter, prior to initiating protocol therapy. Participant that has received prior&#xD;
             treatment with a PARP inhibitor is excluded from this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participant last treatment with platinum based chemotherapy was ≥12 weeks from&#xD;
             initiation of protocol therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participant must not receive any additional chemotherapy while on study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Participant has had radiation therapy encompassing &gt;20% of the bone marrow within 2&#xD;
             weeks; or any radiation therapy within 1 week prior to Day 1 of protocol therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Participant must not have a known hypersensitivity to niraparib components or&#xD;
             excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Participant must not have received colony stimulating factors (e.g. granulocyte&#xD;
             colony-stimulating factor, granulocyte macrophage colony stimulating factor, or&#xD;
             recombinant erythropoietin) within 4 weeks prior to initiating protocol therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Participant must not have any known history of myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS) or acute&#xD;
             myeloid leukemia (AML).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Participant must not have a serious, uncontrolled medical disorder, nonmalignant&#xD;
             systemic disease, or active, uncontrolled infection. Examples include, but are not&#xD;
             limited to, uncontrolled ventricular arrhythmia, NYHA Class III/IV heart failure,&#xD;
             recent (within 90 days) myocardial infarction, uncontrolled major seizure disorder, or&#xD;
             any psychiatric disorder that prohibits obtaining informed consent. Participant must&#xD;
             not have had a CVA within 6 months of registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Participant must not have had diagnosis, detection, or treatment of another type of&#xD;
             cancer ≤ 2 years prior to initiating protocol therapy (except basal or squamous cell&#xD;
             carcinoma of the skin that has been definitively treated).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michelle S Ludwig, MD, MPH, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Baylor College of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Michelle S Ludwig, MD, MPH, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>713-566-3757</phone>
    <email>Michelle.Ludwig@bcm.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Matthew L Anderson, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>813-974-1806</phone>
    <email>mlander5@health.usf.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baylor College of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center McNair</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michelle S Ludwig, MD, MPH, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>713-566-3757</phone>
      <email>Michelle.Ludwig@bcm.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Harris Health System - Smith Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77054</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michelle S Ludwig, MD, MPH, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>713-566-3757</phone>
      <email>Michelle.Ludwig@bcm.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 4, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 21, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 23, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Baylor College of Medicine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michelle S Ludwig</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor Radiation Oncology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>cervical cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Niraparib</keyword>
  <keyword>radiotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>carcinoma of the cervix</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

