<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04638751</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PB-2020-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04638751</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>ARGONAUT: Stool and Blood Sample Bank for Cancer Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>ARGONAUT: Development and Analysis of a Blood and Stool Sample Bank for Cancer Patients, Enabling the Systematic Study of the Effect of Gut Microbiomes on Response to Treatment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Persephone Biosciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Persephone Biosciences</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      ARGONAUT is a longitudinal, prospective, observational study that will enroll up to 4,000&#xD;
      advanced-stage cancer patients of diverse racial backgrounds to collect data used to develop&#xD;
      precision microbiome medicines and for the identification of clinically actionable&#xD;
      cancer-specific biomarkers to guide therapeutic decisions. Four types of solid tumor cancers&#xD;
      will be profiled including non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC), triple negative breast cancer&#xD;
      (TNBC), colorectal cancer (CRC) and pancreatic cancer. Data collected from this study will be&#xD;
      used to develop the most effective new therapies, via microbiome optimization, all to the&#xD;
      benefit of patients and the physicians treating them. Stool and blood samples will be&#xD;
      collected longitudinally and analyzed to determine the impact of gut microbiome composition&#xD;
      and function on the immune system and efficacy of the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects who meet the entry criteria will provide 2 samples each of blood and stool over a&#xD;
      6-month period. Follow-up appointments will be held at 12, 18, and 24 months to collect tumor&#xD;
      scan results and any other updated medical data, with no samples collected.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine whether the microbiome composition can predict progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>6-12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Whole genome sequencing and metabolomics will be used to characterize the patient's microbiome, and whether there is any correlation with response to treatment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Identify correlations between microbiome composition and immune markers</measure>
    <time_frame>6-12 months</time_frame>
    <description>CyTOF and cytokine analysis will be performed on the blood samples to characterize the patient's immune phenotype</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine whether the microbiome composition can predict overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>6-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Survival and tumor progression will be monitored for an extended time beyond sample collection</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Build a library of samples and data for future research</measure>
    <time_frame>6-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Samples will be stored and data saved in a HIPAA-compliant database. Samples will be linked to patient metadata.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">4000</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Colorectal Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Triple Negative Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Pancreas Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NSCLC</arm_group_label>
    <description>Stage 3 or stage 4 non-small cell lung cancer patients, being administered checkpoint inhibitor therapy for the first time. Dosage form, dosage, frequency and duration will be either standard of care and accessed via normal commissioning arrangements, or will be part of an ethics-approved clinical trial, where co-enrollment into an observational study is permitted.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Triple-negative breast cancer</arm_group_label>
    <description>Stage 3 or stage 4 metastatic triple-negative breast cancer patients, being administered any type of treatment that the patient has not experienced before. Dosage form, dosage, frequency and duration will be either standard of care and accessed via normal commissioning arrangements, or will be part of an ethics-approved clinical trial, where co-enrollment into an observational study is permitted.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Colorectal cancer</arm_group_label>
    <description>Stage 3 or stage 4 colorectal cancer patients, being administered any type of treatment that the patient has not experienced before. Dosage form, dosage, frequency and duration will be either standard of care and accessed via normal commissioning arrangements, or will be part of an ethics-approved clinical trial, where co-enrollment into an observational study is permitted.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pancreatic cancer</arm_group_label>
    <description>Stage 3 or stage 4 pancreatic cancer patients, being administered any type of treatment that the patient has not experienced before. Dosage form, dosage, frequency and duration will be either standard of care and accessed via normal commissioning arrangements, or will be part of an ethics-approved clinical trial, where co-enrollment into an observational study is permitted.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Immunotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Use of any checkpoint inhibitor to treat a patient that is previously naive to immunotherapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Colorectal cancer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>NSCLC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Triple-negative breast cancer</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>pembrolizumab, nivolumab, ipilimumab, atezolizumab, durvalumab, avelumab, cemiplimab</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Chemotherapeutic Agent</intervention_name>
    <description>Any type of cancer chemotherapy that the patient has not yet been exposed to</description>
    <arm_group_label>Colorectal cancer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pancreatic cancer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Triple-negative breast cancer</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>any</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Stool and blood samples&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        It is anticipated that 4000 subjects will be enrolled in this study. It is preferred that&#xD;
        enrollment is balanced by sex; however, it is not required. All efforts will be made to&#xD;
        provide racial/ethnic balance, with a goal of 20% African American and 10% each of patients&#xD;
        with Asian or Hispanic descent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men or women who are ≥ 18 years old with stage III or stage IV non-small cell lung&#xD;
             cancer (NSCLC), colorectal cancer, triple-negative breast cancer, or pancreatic cancer&#xD;
             treated by a particular cancer treatment for the first time&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects able to provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with known HIV, Hepatitis A, Hepatitis B, Hepatitis C, or SARS-CoV2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects without the mental capacity to complete either a written or online&#xD;
             questionnaire, alone or with assistance, or make sound decisions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant or who plan on becoming pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are nursing&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Stephanie Culler, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>858-682-4777</phone>
    <email>support@persephonebiome.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Stephen Van Dien, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>858-682-4777</phone>
    <email>support@persephonebiome.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Persephone Biosciences, Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92121</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Stephanie Culler, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>858-682-4777</phone>
      <email>support@persephonebiome.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Stephen Van Dien, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>858-682-4777</phone>
      <email>support@persephonebiome.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 20, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>microbiome</keyword>
  <keyword>immunotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>checkpoint inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Triple Negative Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ipilimumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Durvalumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Avelumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cemiplimab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Atezolizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Antineoplastic Agents</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

