<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04636736</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HIVresistancePL</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04636736</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>HIV Drug Resistance Pattern Due to Migration in Poland</brief_title>
  <official_title>Possible Changes in HIV Drug Resistance Pattern Due to Migration of People From the Eastern Europe to Poland</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical University of Warsaw</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of Warsaw</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      According to the Polish governmental statistics migration of people from Ukraine to Poland is&#xD;
      growing and only in year 2020 have come to Poland about a quarter of a million of Ukrainian&#xD;
      migrants. As well, more than 40% of those diagnosed with HIV infection in the European Union&#xD;
      (EU)/European Economic Area (EEA) in 2018 were also migrants, originating from countries with&#xD;
      generalized HIV epidemics, such as Ukraine. Antiretroviral treatment should be started,&#xD;
      based, among others, on epidemiological data and evidence of presence of drug resistance&#xD;
      mutations in a the population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BACKGROUND:&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to the Polish governmental statistics during the year 2020 have come to Poland&#xD;
      about 240 thousand of ukarinian migrants, and it is estimated that nowadays in Poland live&#xD;
      and work about 1.2 million of people from Ukraine. In recent years substantial increases in&#xD;
      diagnosis of HIV infected people have been reported in some countries, including Poland. At&#xD;
      the same time 42% of those diagnosed in the EU/EEA in 2018 were migrants, defined as&#xD;
      originating from outside of the country in which they were diagnosed. More than one-third&#xD;
      (40%) of newly diagnosed cases due to heterosexual transmission were among migrants&#xD;
      originating from countries with generalized HIV epidemics, such as Ukraine. Overall in the&#xD;
      EU/ EEA, and even in some settings with decrease in newly diagnosed HIV infections in men&#xD;
      having sex with others men (MSM), new HIV diagnoses in migrant MSM have not declined at the&#xD;
      same rate as those who are not foreign-born. Antiretroviral treatment should be started&#xD;
      immediately in all HIV-positive patients, regardless of origin, race, gender or sexual&#xD;
      preferences. The choose of first-line antiretroviral regimen is based, among others, on&#xD;
      epidemiological data and evidence of presence of drug resistance mutations in a the&#xD;
      population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      AIM OF THE STUDY:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to changes in epidemiological pattern in newly diagnosed patients with HIV infection in&#xD;
      Poland and increase in number of HIV positive patients from Ukraine we aimed to asses whether&#xD;
      the presence of drug resistance mutations in the population of Ukrainian patients differs&#xD;
      from the pattern of resistance of not foreign born patients with newly diagnosed HIV&#xD;
      infection in Poland. The potential differences may have further implications on&#xD;
      antiretroviral regimens in drug naive HIV positive patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MATERIAL AND METHODS:&#xD;
&#xD;
      We have designed observational, prospective study which will be performed in several clinical&#xD;
      centers in Poland. As a part of the study we will collect epidemiological (age, gender,&#xD;
      origin, migration data, sexual preferences) and clinical data (HIV viral load, CD4+ cells&#xD;
      count, presence of AIDS-defining diseases, proposed combined antiretrovirat therapy (cART)&#xD;
      regimen and the response to the treatment, Hepatitis B (HBV) and C (HCV) co-infections).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In all patients, before starting antiretroviral treatment, presence of drug resistance&#xD;
      mutations of HIV will be assessed. The molecular diagnostics will cover mutations to the&#xD;
      nucleotide and non-nucleotide reverse transcriptase inhibitors (NRTI and NNRTI), protease&#xD;
      inhibitors (PI) and as well integrase inhibitors (InSTI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical evaluation will be performed in subgroups of migrants and in patients born in&#xD;
      Poland. The distribution of continuous variables will be analysed by the Shapiro-Wilk test.&#xD;
      The data will be expressed as the median and interquartile range (IQR). Quantitative data&#xD;
      will be analysed using the Mann-Whitney U test or Kruskal-Wallis ANOVA when appropriate.&#xD;
      Qualitative data will be compared using the χ² test or the Fisher exact test. A P value of&#xD;
      &lt;0.05 will be considered statistically significant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in HIV drug resistance pattern</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Differences between people originating from Poland and from Eastern Europe</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <condition>HIV-1-infection</condition>
  <condition>Resistant Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HIV POLISH (PL)</arm_group_label>
    <description>HIV infected people with polish nationality, who most probably acquired infection in Poland</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HIV MIGRANTS (M)</arm_group_label>
    <description>HIV infected people, originating from outside of Poland, where they were diagnosed with HIV infection</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HIV drug resistance testing</intervention_name>
    <description>HIV drug resistance testing in people newly diagnosed in HIV in Poland</description>
    <arm_group_label>HIV MIGRANTS (M)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>HIV POLISH (PL)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      HIV- RNA and standard analysis of drug-resistance pattern&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        People diagnosed with HIV infection in Poland, originating from Poland and other countries&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  recent diagnosis with HIV infection (&lt;6 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no history of antiretrovirals intake (PrEP, PEP)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age 18 years or olde&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - failure to meet any of the inclusion criteria&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alicja Wiercińska-Drapało, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases,Tropical Diseases and Hepatology, Medical University of Warsaw</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andrzej Zaleski, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>048600982185</phone>
    <email>andrzejzaleski84@wp.pl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Infectious Diseases, Tropical Diseases and Hepatology, Medical University of Warsaw</name>
      <address>
        <city>Warsaw</city>
        <state>Mazowia</state>
        <zip>01-201</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://ecdc.europa.eu/sites/default/files/documents/hiv-surveillance-report-2019.pdf</url>
    <description>Hiv surveillance report</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://migracje.gov.pl</url>
    <description>Migration report in Poland</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://obserwatorfinansowy.pl/tematyka/makroekonomia/trendy-gospodarcze/nowa-fala-migracji-obywateli-ukrainy-do-polski/</url>
    <description>Migration report in Poland</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://cms.hivdb.org/prod/downloads/resistance-mutation-handout/resistance-mutation-handout.pdf</url>
    <description>Hiv resistance pattern</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.ptnaids.pl/images/AIDS-2019-final.pdf</url>
    <description>HIV/AIDS Polish guidelines on diagnostics and treatment</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://eacsociety.org/files/2019_guidelines-10.0_final.pdf</url>
    <description>HIV/AIDS European guidelines on diagnostics and treatment</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wensing AM, Calvez V, Ceccherini-Silberstein F, Charpentier C, Günthard HF, Paredes R, Shafer RW, Richman DD. 2019 update of the drug resistance mutations in HIV-1. Top Antivir Med. 2019 Sep;27(3):111-121.</citation>
    <PMID>31634862</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shafer RW, Rhee SY, Pillay D, Miller V, Sandstrom P, Schapiro JM, Kuritzkes DR, Bennett D. HIV-1 protease and reverse transcriptase mutations for drug resistance surveillance. AIDS. 2007 Jan 11;21(2):215-23. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17197813</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 13, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 13, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 20, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 20, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Medical University of Warsaw</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Andrzej Załęski</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HIV-infection</keyword>
  <keyword>AIDS</keyword>
  <keyword>migration</keyword>
  <keyword>cART</keyword>
  <keyword>drug-resistance</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>there is no plan to share the data</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

