<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04636619</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>004</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04636619</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Trial Evaluating External Evaluation and Training on the Incomplete Resection (POLIPEVA Study)</brief_title>
  <acronym>POLIPEVA</acronym>
  <official_title>Clinical Trial Evaluating the Effect of External Evaluation and Training on the Incomplete Resection Rate in Cold Snare Polypectomies in Colonic Lesions &lt;10 mm (POLIPEVA Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital del Río Hortega</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital del Río Hortega</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Introduction It has been shown that some quality indicators in endoscopy can be improved&#xD;
      through educational interventions. There are marked differences in the proportion of&#xD;
      incomplete polypectomies among endoscopists. The effectiveness of measures to improve it has&#xD;
      not been evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      objective The main objective is to evaluate whether a training intervention or the&#xD;
      notification of the individual proportion of incomplete polypectomies (those in which&#xD;
      post-polypectomy biopsies of the resection margin show tissue other than normal mucosa) can&#xD;
      improve this proportion. As secondary objectives, we will compare the proportion of&#xD;
      fragmented polypectomies and adverse events. We will evaluate the factors associated with&#xD;
      incomplete excision or failed cold polypectomy, as well as the individual evolution of the&#xD;
      participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods Non-pharmacological clinical trial involving endoscopists with&gt; 1 year of experience&#xD;
      and patients scheduled for colonoscopy. After each polypectomy, 2 additional biopsies will be&#xD;
      taken and evaluated centrally by a blind pathologist. In a first phase, the basal rate of the&#xD;
      participants will be evaluated. After it, the endoscopists will be randomized: one group will&#xD;
      receive a course on endoscopic polypectomy and the other their rate of complete resection.&#xD;
      Randomization will be pure if there are&gt; 20 endoscopists; if the number is lower, the basal&#xD;
      rate will be stratified. The number of polyps required will vary depending on the number of&#xD;
      endoscopists; with 15-30 endoscopists, the sample size per phase will range from 750-1395&#xD;
      lesions / group). The primary objective will be compared using logistic regression models&#xD;
      based on generalized estimating equations (GEE), taking into account the within-subject&#xD;
      correlation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Design&#xD;
&#xD;
      Non-pharmacological clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population The population of endoscopists under study includes specialists in the&#xD;
      digestive system with more than one year of experience in endoscopies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Candidate patients to be included will be those scheduled to perform a colonoscopy on a&#xD;
      non-urgent basis. The patient will be invited to participate prior to the performance of the&#xD;
      colonoscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stages of the study Stage I: estimation of incomplete polypectomies&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participating endoscopists will include polyps in order to perform the baseline estimate.&#xD;
      To avoid that the estimation is made on the basis of a small group of participants, a minimum&#xD;
      number of lesions will be required and a maximum threshold for polyps will be established.&#xD;
      These thresholds will be estimated as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Minimum: sample size / (number of participating endoscopistsx1.5). It can never be less than&#xD;
      25 injuries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Maximum: sample size / (number of participating endoscopists / 1.5) Once there are a&#xD;
      sufficient number of endoscopists who are at the thresholds allowing their samples to reach&#xD;
      the established sample size, the end of patient recruitment will be set for the baseline&#xD;
      estimate 30 days later. After this period, all endoscopists who do not reach the minimum&#xD;
      threshold will be excluded from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stage II: Randomization of training measures Endoscopists who reach the minimum injury&#xD;
      threshold may participate in stage II. If the number of endoscopists is greater than 20, they&#xD;
      will be divided by pure randomization. If the number is 20 or less, they will be divided into&#xD;
      3 tertiles based on their proportion of incomplete polypectomies. The endoscopists from each&#xD;
      tertile will then be randomly divided into 2 groups so that each group has the same&#xD;
      proportion of endoscopists from the first, second and third tertiles. Each group will be&#xD;
      randomly assigned the intervention to receive between training course (group A) or&#xD;
      notification of its proportion of incomplete polypectomies (group B).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Online training course (group A) An online course will be offered that will explain the&#xD;
      technique for excision of lesions with a cold loop and the importance of complete resection,&#xD;
      techniques to determine the edges of the lesion and possible remains at the polypectomy base&#xD;
      through images, video clips. and interaction with the speakers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Incomplete polypectomy report (group B) Each participant will receive the global data, the&#xD;
      results obtained by all the endoscopists (anonymously except for each interested party, the&#xD;
      rest being identified by codes), as well as a detailed analysis of their results, comparing&#xD;
      them with the joint data and the 3 tertiles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the training measures, each endoscopist will proceed to recruit a minimum number of&#xD;
      polyps that will be determined based on the sample size reached in phase I. Once the&#xD;
      pre-established sample size has been reached, this phase will be closed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      E) Recruitment, procedure and follow-up Patient recruitment is the same in all phases.&#xD;
      Patients who meet the inclusion criteria and do not present any exclusion criteria&#xD;
      (pre-endoscopic) will be invited to participate in the study. Informed consent will be&#xD;
      completed in accordance with law 41/2002 on patient autonomy without thereby altering the&#xD;
      relationship with their doctor or causing any harm to their treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anonymized video clips of all polypectomies will be recorded in each of the phases, including&#xD;
      from when the polypectomy loop is inserted into the endoscope until the biopsies are taken&#xD;
      from the base of the polyp.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Endoscopic act The interventions will be carried out in each of the participating&#xD;
           centers. The examinations will be carried out under sedation, following the protocols&#xD;
           established in each center. Once the lesion is identified, it will be removed using a&#xD;
           cold loop. This will be carried out following the usual standards recommended by&#xD;
           international companies. If macroscopic remains of the lesion are observed, a fragmented&#xD;
           polypectomy should be performed using, in the same way, the cold loop.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Once the polypectomies are completed, its base will be carefully evaluated, taking&#xD;
           biopsies 2 random biopsies at the base of the polypectomy, at two of the ends of the&#xD;
           eschar.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Post-endoscopic follow-up In the 5th week post-colonoscopy from the endoscopic&#xD;
           examination, the patient will be contacted by telephone to collect possible&#xD;
           complications (they will be questioned about visits to the hospital and in a directed&#xD;
           way about the most frequent symptoms of the usual complications (fever, bleeding,&#xD;
           abdominal pain ), and if so, the medical history will be reviewed to assess the severity&#xD;
           of the complication.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Histological analysis The analysis of the polypectomy specimens will be carried out in&#xD;
           each center according to its usual protocol. The analysis of the biopsies of the base of&#xD;
           the polyp will be performed centrally by a pathologist with more than 5 years of&#xD;
           experience in digestive pathology. Samples from the base of the polyp will be sent from&#xD;
           each center for centralized study. The pathologist will be blinded as to the&#xD;
           histological diagnosis of the removed polyp. Samples submitted for centralized analysis&#xD;
           will not be kept, but will be destroyed once the study is completed according to&#xD;
           standard protocols&#xD;
&#xD;
      1) Endoscopic act The interventions will be carried out in each of the participating centers.&#xD;
      The examinations will be carried out under sedation, following the protocols established in&#xD;
      each center. Once the lesion is identified, it will be removed using a cold loop. This will&#xD;
      be carried out following the usual standards recommended by international companies. If&#xD;
      macroscopic remains of the lesion are observed, a fragmented polypectomy should be performed&#xD;
      using, in the same way, the cold loop.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once the polypectomies are completed, its base will be carefully evaluated, taking biopsies 2&#xD;
      random biopsies at the base of the polypectomy, at two of the ends of the mucosal defect.&#xD;
&#xD;
      F) Sample size According to the results obtained in our previous work, we observed an&#xD;
      intra-subject correlation coefficient (taking the endoscopists as subjects) of 0.017.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample size will depend on the number of participating endoscopists. Assuming a baseline&#xD;
      proportion of incomplete polypectomies of 7.5%, to detect an absolute risk reduction of 3.5%&#xD;
      (that is, to identify as different proportions equal to or less than 4%) with an alpha risk&#xD;
      of 5% and a 80% power, the required number of polyps will vary depending on the group of&#xD;
      participating endoscopists as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      No. endoscopists 15 20 25 30 No. of polyps 1395 960 825 750 Polyps / endoscopy 93 48 33 25&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to our previous work, a 2.5% loss should also be assumed. Given that to estimate&#xD;
      the proportion of incomplete polypectomies with a margin of error of +/- 1.5% for any value&#xD;
      below 3.5%, a maximum of 558 polyps would be needed, in case of presenting a baseline&#xD;
      proportion of incomplete polypectomies &lt; 4%, we could estimate the confidence intervals&#xD;
      accurately.&#xD;
&#xD;
      G) Data collection All the variables concerning the characteristics of the endoscopist, the&#xD;
      patient and the injuries included will be collected in each center. The variables related to&#xD;
      the histological diagnosis of the polypectomy specimen will be collected in the same way at&#xD;
      the respective center. The variables concerning the follow-up will be collected centrally,&#xD;
      through a telephone call that will be made the 5th week after the procedure. The variable&#xD;
      related to the histological study of the base of the polyp will be collected centrally by the&#xD;
      pathologist in charge of analyzing the samples. The video clips will be stored in a&#xD;
      collection created de novo and centralized in the main researcher center&#xD;
&#xD;
      2) Post-endoscopic follow-up In the 5th week post-colonoscopy from the endoscopic&#xD;
      examination, the patient will be contacted by telephone to collect possible complications&#xD;
      (they will be questioned about visits to the hospital and in a directed way about the most&#xD;
      frequent symptoms of the usual complications (fever, bleeding, abdominal pain ), and if so,&#xD;
      the medical history will be reviewed to assess the severity of the complication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3) Histological analysis The analysis of the polypectomy specimens will be carried out in&#xD;
      each center according to its usual protocol. The analysis of the biopsies of the base of the&#xD;
      polyp will be performed centrally by a pathologist with more than 5 years of experience in&#xD;
      digestive pathology. Samples from the base of the polyp will be sent from each center for&#xD;
      centralized study. The pathologist will be blinded as to the histological diagnosis of the&#xD;
      removed polyp. Samples submitted for centralized analysis will not be kept, but will be&#xD;
      destroyed once the study is completed according to standard protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection The data from the data collection notebooks will be collected anonymously by&#xD;
      the main investigator or collaborating investigators, encrypted and dissociated from the&#xD;
      clinical information by means of a patient identification code (ID), in a database created by&#xD;
      the program Research Electronic Data Capture Tool (RedCap) (17) attached to the Spanish&#xD;
      Society of Digestive Endoscopy, which allows coordinating data collection through access from&#xD;
      different national centers. Subsequently, for their analysis, they will be merged by the&#xD;
      principal investigator or the encrypted and dissociated collaborating investigators, in a&#xD;
      database created using the STATA Stata Corporation program. 2013. Stata Statistical Software:&#xD;
      Release 13. College Station, Texas: Stata Corporation. The data entered in the database will&#xD;
      be encrypted and the database will be protected with a password to which only researchers&#xD;
      will have access. The video clips will be completely anonymized and identified by a code,&#xD;
      which will be provided by the main researcher. In no case will identifying data of the&#xD;
      patient appear in said videos.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The unified file will be kept at the Río Hortega University Hospital and will be kept until&#xD;
      the end of the study. Regarding the application of the Organic Law on Data Protection 15/1999&#xD;
      and the Royal Decree 1720/2007 that develops it, it should be noted that the protocol defined&#xD;
      in the project aimed at epidemiological analysis determines that the files will record&#xD;
      information completely anonymized.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis In the quantitative variables, the arithmetic mean and standard&#xD;
      deviation will be calculated (the variables that do not follow a normal distribution&#xD;
      according to the Kolmogorov-Smirnov test will be described with median and interquartile&#xD;
      range), and the qualitative ones will be expressed as percentages and their intervals of 95%&#xD;
      confidence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective, the difference in the proportion of indicators collected in the reports&#xD;
      made with free fields or with standardized reports, will be compared using logistic&#xD;
      regression models based on generalized estimating equations (GEE), taking into account the&#xD;
      within-subject correlation. .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Among the secondary endpoints, the proportion of complications in both groups, the proportion&#xD;
      of fragmented polypectomies and polypectomies that require repositioning will be compared&#xD;
      using the homogeneity z-test without using the Yates correction. Multivariate logistic&#xD;
      regression techniques will be used to evaluate the factors associated with incomplete&#xD;
      polypectomies and those associated with a failed cold polypectomy. The individual evolution&#xD;
      of the endoscopists will be displayed graphically. Cumulative summatory learning curves will&#xD;
      be used to graphically represent the individual evolution of the endoscopists.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 12, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Non-pharmacological clinical trial evaluating the incomplete resection rate in colonic cold snare polypectomy between two groups of endoscopists, one receiving a polypectomy online course and the second one receiving a external report evaluating their previous resection rate</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Patients are blinded to know which group their endoscopist belongs to. Pathology is blinded to know which group of endoscopists performed each polypectomy.&#xD;
A centralized research nurse, blinded to procedure and groups, will made the telephonic follow up.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incomplete resection rate</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the change in the proportion of incomplete cold-snare polypectomies in polyps &lt;10mm.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1920</enrollment>
  <condition>Colonic Polyp</condition>
  <condition>Colorectal Adenoma</condition>
  <condition>Colorectal Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Incomplete polypectomy report</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>An online course will be offered that will explain the technique for excision of lesions with a cold loop and the importance of complete resection, techniques to determine the edges of the lesion and possible remains at the polypectomy base through images, video clips. and interaction with the speakers</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>On-line training course</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Each participant will receive the global data, the results obtained by all the endoscopists (anonymously except for each interested party, the rest being identified by codes), as well as a detailed analysis of their results, comparing them with the joint data and the 3 tertiles.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Colonic polypectomy</intervention_name>
    <description>Cold snare resection of colorectal polyps</description>
    <arm_group_label>Incomplete polypectomy report</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>On-line training course</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Online training course</intervention_name>
    <description>Polypectomy technique online course</description>
    <arm_group_label>On-line training course</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Incomplete resection report</intervention_name>
    <description>Each participant will receive the global data, the results obtained by all the endoscopists (anonymously except for each interested party, the rest being identified by codes), as well as a detailed analysis of their results</description>
    <arm_group_label>Incomplete polypectomy report</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients over 18 years of age scheduled for a non-urgent colonoscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of lesions &lt;10 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication for polypectomy (anticoagulant treatment that cannot be withdrawn,&#xD;
             treatment with clopidogrel, coagulopathy or severe thrombocytopenia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Loss of polypectomy specimen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refusal to participate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marina De Benito Sanz, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hospital Río Hortega</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Marina De Benito Sanz, MD</last_name>
    <phone>983420400</phone>
    <phone_ext>84326</phone_ext>
    <email>mbenitosa@saludcastillayleon.es</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Manuel Pérez-Miranda Castillo, MD PhD</last_name>
    <phone>983420400</phone>
    <phone_ext>84408</phone_ext>
    <email>mperezmiranda@saludacastillayleon.es</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Rio Hortega</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valladolid</city>
        <zip>47012</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marina De Benito, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bray F, Ferlay J, Soerjomataram I, Siegel RL, Torre LA, Jemal A. Global cancer statistics 2018: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2018 Nov;68(6):394-424. doi: 10.3322/caac.21492. Epub 2018 Sep 12. Erratum in: CA Cancer J Clin. 2020 Jul;70(4):313.</citation>
    <PMID>30207593</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ransohoff DF. Colon cancer screening in 2005: status and challenges. Gastroenterology. 2005 May;128(6):1685-95. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15887159</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baxter NN, Warren JL, Barrett MJ, Stukel TA, Doria-Rose VP. Association between colonoscopy and colorectal cancer mortality in a US cohort according to site of cancer and colonoscopist specialty. J Clin Oncol. 2012 Jul 20;30(21):2664-9. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2011.40.4772. Epub 2012 Jun 11.</citation>
    <PMID>22689809</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baxter NN, Goldwasser MA, Paszat LF, Saskin R, Urbach DR, Rabeneck L. Association of colonoscopy and death from colorectal cancer. Ann Intern Med. 2009 Jan 6;150(1):1-8. Epub 2008 Dec 15.</citation>
    <PMID>19075198</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mulder SA, van Soest EM, Dieleman JP, van Rossum LG, Ouwendijk RJ, van Leerdam ME, Kuipers EJ. Exposure to colorectal examinations before a colorectal cancer diagnosis: a case-control study. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2010 Apr;22(4):437-43. doi: 10.1097/MEG.0b013e328333fc6a.</citation>
    <PMID>19952765</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nishihara R, Wu K, Lochhead P, Morikawa T, Liao X, Qian ZR, Inamura K, Kim SA, Kuchiba A, Yamauchi M, Imamura Y, Willett WC, Rosner BA, Fuchs CS, Giovannucci E, Ogino S, Chan AT. Long-term colorectal-cancer incidence and mortality after lower endoscopy. N Engl J Med. 2013 Sep 19;369(12):1095-105. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1301969.</citation>
    <PMID>24047059</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Singh H, Nugent Z, Demers AA, Kliewer EV, Mahmud SM, Bernstein CN. The reduction in colorectal cancer mortality after colonoscopy varies by site of the cancer. Gastroenterology. 2010 Oct;139(4):1128-37. doi: 10.1053/j.gastro.2010.06.052. Epub 2010 Jun 20.</citation>
    <PMID>20600026</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bourke MJ. Making every colonoscopy count: Ensuring quality in endoscopy. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2009 Oct;24 Suppl 3:S43-50. doi: 10.1111/j.1440-1746.2009.06070.x. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19799697</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Grupo de Trabajo de &quot;Indicadores de calidad en endoscopia&quot; de la Sociedad Española de Patología Digestiva (SEPD). Quality indicators in colonoscopy. The colonoscopy procedure. Rev Esp Enferm Dig. 2018 May;110(5):316-326. doi: 10.17235/reed.2018.5408/2017.</citation>
    <PMID>29658767</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Coe SG, Crook JE, Diehl NN, Wallace MB. An endoscopic quality improvement program improves detection of colorectal adenomas. Am J Gastroenterol. 2013 Feb;108(2):219-26; quiz 227. doi: 10.1038/ajg.2012.417. Epub 2013 Jan 8.</citation>
    <PMID>23295274</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ussui V, Coe S, Rizk C, Crook JE, Diehl NN, Wallace MB. Stability of increased adenoma detection at colonoscopy. Follow-up of an endoscopic quality improvement program-EQUIP-II. Am J Gastroenterol. 2015 Apr;110(4):489-96. doi: 10.1038/ajg.2014.314. Epub 2014 Sep 30.</citation>
    <PMID>25267326</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pohl H, Srivastava A, Bensen SP, Anderson P, Rothstein RI, Gordon SR, Levy LC, Toor A, Mackenzie TA, Rosch T, Robertson DJ. Incomplete polyp resection during colonoscopy-results of the complete adenoma resection (CARE) study. Gastroenterology. 2013 Jan;144(1):74-80.e1. doi: 10.1053/j.gastro.2012.09.043. Epub 2012 Sep 25. Erratum in: Gastroenterology. 2021 Oct;161(4):1347.</citation>
    <PMID>23022496</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cotton PB, Eisen GM, Aabakken L, Baron TH, Hutter MM, Jacobson BC, Mergener K, Nemcek A Jr, Petersen BT, Petrini JL, Pike IM, Rabeneck L, Romagnuolo J, Vargo JJ. A lexicon for endoscopic adverse events: report of an ASGE workshop. Gastrointest Endosc. 2010 Mar;71(3):446-54. doi: 10.1016/j.gie.2009.10.027.</citation>
    <PMID>20189503</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Thielke R, Payne J, Gonzalez N, Conde JG. Research electronic data capture (REDCap)--a metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inform. 2009 Apr;42(2):377-81. doi: 10.1016/j.jbi.2008.08.010. Epub 2008 Sep 30.</citation>
    <PMID>18929686</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 15, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hospital del Río Hortega</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Marina de Benito Sanz</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Polypectomy,</keyword>
  <keyword>Cold Snare polypectomy</keyword>
  <keyword>Incomplete resection rate</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Colonic Polyps</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

