<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04631692</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-A01687-32</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04631692</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating a Health Literacy Intervention to Improve Colorectal Cancer Screening in Underserved Areas</brief_title>
  <acronym>DECODE</acronym>
  <official_title>Impact of Health Literacy Training for General Practitioners and a Consumer Facing Intervention to Improve Colorectal Cancer Screening in Underserved Areas: A Multicentric Cluster Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Paul Sabatier of Toulouse</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut National de la Santé Et de la Recherche Médicale, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centre Régional de Coordination des Dépistages des Cancers en Occitanie CRCDC-OC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Aix Marseille Université</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Assistance Publique Hopitaux De Marseille</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centre Régional de Coordination des Dépistages des Cancers Sud PACA</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Laboratoire HESPER-EA 7425</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>INSERM, UMR-S 1123 ECEVE Université de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centre Régional de Coordination du dépistage des cancers - Ile-de-France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Paris 7 - Denis Diderot</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centre Régional de Coordination du dépistage des cancers - Auvergne-Rhône-Alpes</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut Paoli-Calmettes</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Paul Sabatier of Toulouse</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this project is to assess the impact of a health literacy (HL) intervention&#xD;
      combining HL and CRC screening training for general practitioners with a short brochure and&#xD;
      video targeting eligible patients to increase CRC screening and other secondary outcomes in&#xD;
      four underserved geographic areas in France. The investigators will use a two-arm randomized&#xD;
      controlled cluster trial at 8 clusters (2 per area) primarily serving underserved populations&#xD;
      across 4 geographic areas in France with 32 primary care physicians and 1024 patients&#xD;
      recruited.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background Colorectal cancer (CRC) is a leading cause of cancer burden worldwide and the&#xD;
      third most commonly diagnosed cancer in France (with 44,000 new cases in France each year).&#xD;
      Systematic uptake of CRC screening can improve survival rates. However, people with limited&#xD;
      health literacy (HL) and lower socioeconomic position rarely participate. The overall goal is&#xD;
      to assess the impact of a HL intervention combining HL and CRC screening training for general&#xD;
      practitioners with a short brochure and video targeting eligible patients to increase CRC&#xD;
      screening and other secondary outcomes in four underserved geographic areas in France.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods The investigators will use a two-arm randomized controlled cluster trial at 8&#xD;
      clusters (2 per area) primarily serving underserved populations across 4 geographic areas in&#xD;
      France with 32 primary care physicians and 1024 patients recruited. Primary care physicians&#xD;
      practicing in underserved areas (identified using the European Deprivation Index and French&#xD;
      Deprivation index) will be block-randomized to: 1) a combined intervention (HL and colorectal&#xD;
      cancer training + brochure and video for eligible patients) or 2) usual care. The&#xD;
      investigators will include all people between 50 and 74 years old who are eligible for CRC&#xD;
      screening. The project will follow a community-based participatory research approach. The&#xD;
      primary outcome is CRC screening uptake. The project will also include a qualitative needs&#xD;
      assessment (focus groups and interviews) prior to finalizing the intervention and to test the&#xD;
      acceptability of the combined intervention before the trial. After completing recruitment,&#xD;
      semi-structured interviews will be conducted with up to 8 health professionals in each region&#xD;
      (up to 24) and 6 to 12 patients per region (up to 48) based on data saturation. The&#xD;
      investigators will explore strategies that promote the intervention's sustained use and rapid&#xD;
      implementation using the Normalization Process Theory. A regression framework and mediation&#xD;
      analyses will be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Discussion Limited HL and its impact on the general population is a growing public health and&#xD;
      policy challenge worldwide. It has received limited attention in France. A combined HL&#xD;
      intervention could reduce disparities in CRC screening, increase screening rates among most&#xD;
      vulnerable populations, and increase knowledge and activation (beneficial in the context of&#xD;
      repeat screening).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>We will use a two-arm randomized controlled cluster trial design trial with 8 clusters in total (2 clusters per region) and 4 general practitioners per cluster (i.e. 32 doctors in total). We will target disadvantaged areas in the following regions: Marseille, Lyon, Toulouse and Paris. We will use two ecological indexes of disadvantage: the European Deprivation Index (EDI) and the French Deprivation Index (FDEP). A community-based participatory research approach will be privileged throughout this project as well as focus groups and interviews</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Masking investigator, research assistants and data analyst</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Colorectal cancer screening uptake</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 1-year post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>This information will be collected by each regional screening coordination center of the four participating regions, in collaboration with the health insurance (CPAM) at 6 months (for feedback to general practitioners in the intervention arm) and 1-year post enrollment into the study. It will also be collected using self-report in the patient questionnaire 1-year post enrollment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1024</enrollment>
  <condition>Colorectal Cancer Screening</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Usual care in participating primary care practices.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Health literacy intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Health literacy intervention combining health literacy and colorectal cancer screening training for general practitioners with a short brochure and video targeting eligible patients.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Health literacy intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>We will translate and adapt an intervention developed by Ferreira et al. to address health literacy and improve CRC screening. This intervention combined a 2-hour health literacy training targeting primary care physicians (which also included information about CRC screening) and a patient level intervention that consisted of a brochure and video.&#xD;
In order to promote generalizability, large-scale diffusion, dissemination and sustained use beyond the funded-research period, we will use blended learning to develop a 2-hour e-learning health literacy training in French and a one-hour booster session.&#xD;
The patient-facing intervention (video + brochure) will follow key plain language and health literacy principles to translate evidence-based information in content that all patients can understand. Existing materials developed in France will be used and adapted as relevant.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Health literacy intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People between 50 and 74 years old who are eligible for colorectal cancer screening&#xD;
             and seen by a participating general practitioner.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People who are able to complete a questionnaire in French, either alone or with help&#xD;
             from a caregiver or relative.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People with intellectual disability will be included as long as they are able to&#xD;
             complete a questionnaire alone or with help from a caregiver or relative.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - People whose mental health status does preclude participation in the study, as determined&#xD;
        by the participating primary care practitioner or their qualified staff.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>74 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Marie-Anne Durand, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0033648038356</phone>
    <email>marie-anne.durand@univ-tlse3.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Aurore Lamouroux, PhD</last_name>
    <email>aurore.lamouroux@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Service de recherche et épidémiologie cliniques</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lyon</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Myriam Kaou</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Espace santé APHM</name>
      <address>
        <city>Marseille</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Françoise Couranjou</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Assistance Publique Hopitaux de Paris</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Zineb Doukhi</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Faculté de médecine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Niamh Redmond</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 10, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University Paul Sabatier of Toulouse</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Marie-Anne Durand</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Researcher</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

