<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04633538</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PID13040</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04633538</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of a New 6 Minute Walk Test Smartphone App in Patients With Pulmonary Hypertension</brief_title>
  <acronym>6-APP</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of a New 6 Minute Walk Test Smartphone App in Patients With Pulmonary Hypertension (The 6-APP Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Oxford</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Comparison of standard 6 minute walk test with 6 minute walk test smartphone app.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension (PAH) is a progressive illness that; if not diagnosed early&#xD;
      or left untreated, can be a severe life limiting condition . It is a chronic disease of the&#xD;
      pulmonary vasculature, with vascular proliferation and remodelling of the small pulmonary&#xD;
      arteries leading to a progressive increase in pulmonary vascular resistance (PVR). This can&#xD;
      ultimately lead to right heart failure and premature death . The predominant symptom of PAH&#xD;
      is dyspnoea on exertion, with a decrease in exercise capacity, and most patients present with&#xD;
      this symptom .&#xD;
&#xD;
      PAH is an uncommon condition, affecting about 6000 patients in the United Kingdom , and due&#xD;
      to its rarity, the NHS commissions 7 centres to care for patients with PAH. Oxford University&#xD;
      Hospital NHS Foundation Trust works closely with the Royal Brompton Hospital to provide care&#xD;
      for patients with PAH in Oxfordshire and the surrounding region.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The six-minute walk test (6MWT) is a standard method for measuring exercise capacity in&#xD;
      patients with cardiopulmonary disease such as PAH. The 6MWT measures how far a patient can&#xD;
      walk in 6 minutes. Walking is an activity performed every day, by most patients except for&#xD;
      those most severely limited. By assessing patients' ability to exercise, the 6MWT provides a&#xD;
      global assessment of respiratory, cardiovascular, neuromuscular and cognitive function. The&#xD;
      6MWT does not differentiate what limits the patient, nor does it assess maximal exercise&#xD;
      capacity. Instead, the 6MWT allows the patient to exercise at a daily functional level, and&#xD;
      is a useful tool for assessing changes after a therapeutic intervention, and correlates with&#xD;
      a subjective improvement in dyspnoea .&#xD;
&#xD;
      In PAH the 6MWT is used to evaluate patients' response to treatment, with an increase in 6MWT&#xD;
      distance of greater than 42m being considered a clinically significant improvement .&#xD;
      Furthermore, change in 6MWT distance correlates with VO2 max (maximum rate of oxygen&#xD;
      consumption measured during exercise), NYHA class (classification of patients' daily&#xD;
      limitation) and mortality in PAH patients, providing an objective assessment of disease&#xD;
      progression, prognosis and response to treatment. It is a universally accepted test as it is&#xD;
      safe and easily performed by the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The 6MWT has become the primary end-point for many trials, and as a surrogate invalidated&#xD;
      survival outcome for all placebo controlled trials of PAH therapy . It is used by regulatory&#xD;
      bodies to determine whether a treatment should be approved. However, there is much&#xD;
      discrepancy between whether it is the total distance walked at baseline prior to treatment, a&#xD;
      decrease in total distance walked over time or a percentage increase in walking distance that&#xD;
      correlates best with survival outcome. The investigators hypothesize that it is all 3 of&#xD;
      these measures, and that having a validated and more reproducible 6MWT would help assess&#xD;
      patients and guide treatment strategies better.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The test is usually performed in hospital, by walking along a hospital corridor, where many&#xD;
      factors on the day of the test can affect patients' performance, including tiredness,&#xD;
      unfamiliarity with the environment or anxiety. The test typically requires 2 physiologists to&#xD;
      monitor the distance walked by the patient, their oxygen saturations by pulse oximetry, and&#xD;
      to record symptoms felt during the test. To improve the assessment of a patient's exercise&#xD;
      capacity using a 6MWT, the investigators hypothesize that the test would reflect more the&#xD;
      patient's functional status, if it were undertaken prior to the hospital outpatient&#xD;
      appointment. The investigators have designed a mobile-phone &quot;app&quot; that allows patients to&#xD;
      perform the 6MWT within the patient's home environment. This is felt to be more appealing to&#xD;
      the patients, and would reduce the time spent in hospital on the day of their outpatient&#xD;
      appointment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The 6MWT app is categorised as a mobile-health (m-health) system, a form of telehealth&#xD;
      whereby healthcare is delivered at a distance using smartphones. By utilizing biometric&#xD;
      collection devices such as a pulse oximeter monitor with Bluetooth capability, m-health can&#xD;
      be used to measure the oxygen saturation levels in the blood from patients, and transmit them&#xD;
      to a secure server, allowing them to be reviewed by cardiologists and other healthcare&#xD;
      professionals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The evidence-base for m-health as a tool for assessing physical fitness is increasingly&#xD;
      established. This new approach not only offers the opportunity for reliable collection of&#xD;
      data, but provides the infrastructure to do this at scale and will allow decisions on&#xD;
      patients' health to be based on more frequent and more accurate information.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are no known risks to undertaking a 6MWT in the community as walking is an activity of&#xD;
      daily living, and all patients are encouraged to walk daily.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The population to be studied will be those with PAH who are currently assessed with a 6MWT.&#xD;
      Once the app has been validated, patients with any type of cardiorespiratory disease who are&#xD;
      assessed with a 6MWT could use the app, for example patients with chronic obstructive airways&#xD;
      disease, heart failure, renal failure, and pre-transplantation work up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The 6MWT results form part of the NHS data set collected by NHS England for patients with&#xD;
      PAH, and it would be beneficial to have a more reproducible assessment, whose results could&#xD;
      be compared between the 7 centres providing care for these patients. At present, there is&#xD;
      much variability in how 6MWTs are performed between units, and the app would reduce this&#xD;
      variability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The 6MWT has been undertaken at the John Radcliffe hospital for 5 years and the investigators&#xD;
      will also retrospectively analyse the data from the 6MWT that have previously been&#xD;
      undertaken. The data on patients will be pseudo-anonymised, i.e. no personal information like&#xD;
      name, surname or address, will be used, but the investigators will keep date of birth,&#xD;
      gender, diagnosis, dates and results of the 6MWT, date and causes of death. As part of the&#xD;
      clinical care team, reviewing the data is part of the normal standard of care for patients&#xD;
      with PHT. The data is collected on the Solus cardiac reporting system and can be extracted&#xD;
      from this database. The data will be pseudo-anonymised by the Principle Investigator for&#xD;
      analysis, and then shared with the wider research team. The data will be analysed to look at&#xD;
      distance walked, and change in oxygen saturation and heart rate during the test. The&#xD;
      investigators will analyse the data over time, to look for changes in these parameters and&#xD;
      correlate these with outcome data, i.e. mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study aims at demonstrating that patients are able and willing to use the app for the&#xD;
      6MWT and the measurements obtained by the app are comparable to the ones obtained in&#xD;
      hospital.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 15, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 28, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants who perform app-based home 6MWT</measure>
    <time_frame>At 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants who perform app-based home 6MWT</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average and variability of the difference in distance as measured by physiologists and the app.</measure>
    <time_frame>At 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean and standard deviation of the difference in distance as measured by physiologists and the app.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Relationship between outdoor 6MWT app distance with the hospital 6MWT test</measure>
    <time_frame>At 6-month OPD 6MWT compared with home test at time of OPD</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation of outdoor 6MWT app walking distance with the hospital 6MWT test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Pulmonary Hypertension</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Smartphone app</intervention_name>
    <description>Use of smartphone app to measure 6 minute walk test (6MWT)</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients undergoing follow up in the PAH clinic will be eligible for participation. They&#xD;
        will be approached by a member of the clinical team for consideration and recruited. We&#xD;
        will recruit 30 compliant patients to enrol in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is willing and able to give informed consent for participation in the&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or Female, aged 18 years or above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed with PAH who are able to undertake 6MWT off-oxygen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being of PAH group 1 or 4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant owns a compatible smartphone (Android or iPhone) and is able to use it.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Long term oxygen therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive impairments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Rheumatological diseases that limit the measurement of finger Oxygen saturations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PAH groups 2, 3 or 5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cannot use a smartphone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elizabeth Orchard</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Agarwal R, Gomberg-Maitland M. Current therapeutics and practical management strategies for pulmonary arterial hypertension. Am Heart J. 2011 Aug;162(2):201-13. doi: 10.1016/j.ahj.2011.05.012. Epub 2011 Jul 13. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21835279</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Galiè N, Brundage BH, Ghofrani HA, Oudiz RJ, Simonneau G, Safdar Z, Shapiro S, White RJ, Chan M, Beardsworth A, Frumkin L, Barst RJ; Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension and Response to Tadalafil (PHIRST) Study Group. Tadalafil therapy for pulmonary arterial hypertension. Circulation. 2009 Jun 9;119(22):2894-903. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.108.839274. Epub 2009 May 26. Erratum in: Circulation. 2011 Sep 6;124(10):e279. Dosage error in article text.</citation>
    <PMID>19470885</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tan MP, Bansal SK, Wynn NN, Umerov M, Gillham A, Henderson A, Hildreth A, Junejo S. Long term survival of patients with raised pulmonary arterial systolic pressure utilizing echocardiography-a five-year prospective study. J Geriatr Cardiol. 2012 Dec;9(4):328-35. doi: 10.3724/SP.J.1263.2012.06191.</citation>
    <PMID>23341836</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gabler NB, French B, Strom BL, Palevsky HI, Taichman DB, Kawut SM, Halpern SD. Validation of 6-minute walk distance as a surrogate end point in pulmonary arterial hypertension trials. Circulation. 2012 Jul 17;126(3):349-56. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.112.105890. Epub 2012 Jun 13.</citation>
    <PMID>22696079</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mathai SC, Puhan MA, Lam D, Wise RA. The minimal important difference in the 6-minute walk test for patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2012 Sep 1;186(5):428-33. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201203-0480OC. Epub 2012 Jun 21.</citation>
    <PMID>22723290</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Miyamoto S, Nagaya N, Satoh T, Kyotani S, Sakamaki F, Fujita M, Nakanishi N, Miyatake K. Clinical correlates and prognostic significance of six-minute walk test in patients with primary pulmonary hypertension. Comparison with cardiopulmonary exercise testing. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2000 Feb;161(2 Pt 1):487-92.</citation>
    <PMID>10673190</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Barst RJ, Rubin LJ, Long WA, McGoon MD, Rich S, Badesch DB, Groves BM, Tapson VF, Bourge RC, Brundage BH, Koerner SK, Langleben D, Keller CA, Murali S, Uretsky BF, Clayton LM, Jöbsis MM, Blackburn SD, Shortino D, Crow JW; Primary Pulmonary Hypertension Study Group. A comparison of continuous intravenous epoprostenol (prostacyclin) with conventional therapy for primary pulmonary hypertension. N Engl J Med. 1996 Feb 1;334(5):296-301.</citation>
    <PMID>8532025</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 26, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Trust</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Elizabeth Orchard</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Primary Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertension, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <pending_results>
    <submitted>November 2, 2021</submitted>
  </pending_results>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

