<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04636398</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R21HD101786</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R21HD101786</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04636398</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Postnatal mHealth Intervention Development</brief_title>
  <acronym>MESSAGE</acronym>
  <official_title>Development and Pilot Test of an mHealth Interactive Education and Social Support Intervention for Improving Postnatal Health - Phase 1</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, San Francisco</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of California, Los Angeles</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology Delhi</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Survival for Women and Children Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, San Francisco</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a six-week exploratory developmental phase (phase 1) of a larger project to&#xD;
      develop an mHealth intervention targeting health education and social support for Indian&#xD;
      women in the postnatal period. Phase 1 of the trial exposes study participants to various&#xD;
      intervention modalities and seeks to understand their experiences and perspectives on these&#xD;
      using mixed-methods. Results from this trial will inform modifications to the intervention to&#xD;
      be tested in Phase 2.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Most mHealth interventions for maternal and child health (MCH) in low and middle-income&#xD;
      countries, including India, have focused on unidirectional and non-interactive approaches,&#xD;
      primarily text messaging. However, ample evidence suggests that provider-led, interactive&#xD;
      educational programming and social support are key for improving health behaviors and&#xD;
      outcomes. Thus innovative mHealth approaches that promote interactive education and&#xD;
      facilitate social support have great potential to improve MCH outcomes. The two-phase&#xD;
      development of MeSSSSage will include Phase 1: exploratory development on functions and&#xD;
      platforms and Phase 2: a mixed-methods randomized pilot study using a factorial design of&#xD;
      specific intervention functions and platforms confirmed in Phase 1. Study activities&#xD;
      described herein are associated with Phase 1. The study's specific aim is: To develop optimal&#xD;
      intervention functions, processes, and mHealth platforms for education and peer support among&#xD;
      postnatal women in rural India. In Phase 1, the investigators will explore potential&#xD;
      interactive education and peer support group intervention functions (education, emotional&#xD;
      support, instrumental support, referrals, linkages, follow-up on postnatal visits), processes&#xD;
      (group interactions; frequency, length and timing of groups; engagement opportunities,&#xD;
      participant profiles) and mHealth delivery platforms (voice, text chat, app options,&#xD;
      interaction features). This six-week developmental component will include up to four groups&#xD;
      (n=48; 12 per group) to assess different modalities and functions. The investigators will&#xD;
      ascertain women's preferences for functions, processes, and platform features using survey&#xD;
      and in-depth interviews (IDIs), and capture levels of engagement via back-end data. This&#xD;
      process will also inform the intervention's health information content. Findings will be used&#xD;
      to formalize the group mobile intervention details to be examined in Phase 2.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Non-randomized quasi-experimental exploratory study. All small groups will receive the same intervention which is exposure to a variety of intervention modalities (3 main modalities: information delivery, facilitation strategy, text management).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Satisfied or very satisfied about their overall intervention experience</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants reporting to be &quot;satisfied&quot; or &quot;very satisfied&quot; with their overall intervention experience, assessed through a five-point Likert scale at six weeks.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Health Attitude</condition>
  <condition>Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</condition>
  <condition>Post Partum Depression</condition>
  <condition>Acceptability of Health Care</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MESSAGE mHealth group intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the one arm will be exposed to the mHealth group intervention. As this is a pilot developmental study, the participants will be exposed to various strategies for information delivery (live presentation at a scheduled time versus voice recording accessible at any time), discussion facilitation (heavily managed with request to speak vs. natural discussion participation), and text communication management (moderator-facilitated vs. group-led).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MESSAGE - mHealth intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>A group-based moderated six-week intervention with didactic, discussion, and text communication components.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MESSAGE mHealth group intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Postnatal (within 2 weeks)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18+ years old&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women below 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with high risk pregnancies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who delivered preterm, suffer severe maternal complications or they or their&#xD;
             baby are otherwise sick in the first week&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alison El Ayadi, ScD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, San Francisco</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nadia G Diamond-Smith, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, San Francisco</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Post Graduate Institute for Medical Education and Research (PGIMER)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chandigarh</city>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 13, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 13, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression, Postpartum</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

