<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04639882</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R21AA022369</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04639882</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Motivating Recruitment and Efficacy in Normative Feedback Interventions</brief_title>
  <official_title>Motivating Recruitment and Efficacy in Normative Feedback Interventions</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Houston</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Houston</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Excessive alcohol consumption among college students continues to be a serious public health&#xD;
      concern associated with a wide range of negative consequences. Brief computer-based social&#xD;
      norms interventions, including personalized normative feedback (PNF), have shown consistent&#xD;
      effects in reducing problematic drinking in this population, and there is some evidence that&#xD;
      in-lab computer-delivered interventions may be more effective than remote interventions. Most&#xD;
      studies have been conducted using generous incentives which may reduce the feasibility of&#xD;
      dissemination on a larger scale and may undermine trial efficacy. In accordance with NIAAA&#xD;
      aims, this research aims to (a) investigate delivery modality (i.e., in lab versus remotely)&#xD;
      and incentives as important factors affecting the efficacy of PNF interventions and (b)&#xD;
      develop intervention strategies that facilitate wider dissemination of inexpensive&#xD;
      empirically-supported brief interventions for college students, thereby reducing problem&#xD;
      drinking during a high-risk time period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The current application evaluates motivational factors associated with recruitment into and&#xD;
      efficacy of brief computer-delivered interventions for heavy drinking college students.&#xD;
      College students are at increased risk for alcohol misuse compared to other adults, and&#xD;
      development of efficacious intervention approaches is an urgent priority for NIAAA. Over the&#xD;
      past several years empirical evidence has demonstrated support for computer-based&#xD;
      personalized normative feedback (PNF) interventions which correct normative misperceptions of&#xD;
      drinking and thereby reduce drinking behavior. Two specific questions which have remained&#xD;
      largely unaddressed include whether the effectiveness of computer-based interventions depends&#xD;
      on the location in which they are completed, and what is the optimal incentive structure to&#xD;
      balance recruitment with motivational biases in intervention trials. A preliminary comparison&#xD;
      of findings across several studies suggests that remote PNF interventions may be less&#xD;
      effective than in-lab PNF interventions. However, the evidence is not conclusive because no&#xD;
      study provides a direct comparison between delivery methods based on random assignment within&#xD;
      the same study. This R21 recruited 498 heavy drinking college students and randomly assigned&#xD;
      them to a 2 × 2 × 2 repeated measures design. Participants were randomly assigned to in-lab&#xD;
      PNF, remote PNF, in-lab attention control, or remote attention control. Participants were&#xD;
      also randomly assigned to receive no incentive ($0) or an incentive ($30) for participation.&#xD;
      Assessments included baseline, postintervention, 3-month, and 6-month follow-ups. College&#xD;
      students' motivational orientations, incentives, and typical drinking are expected to&#xD;
      moderate differences between delivery methods. We expect that students who receive incentives&#xD;
      for participating in intervention studies will be more likely to participate, but less likely&#xD;
      to reduce drinking because they will be more likely to attribute their participation to&#xD;
      extrinsic motivation. Further, students who receive computer-based PNF in the laboratory for&#xD;
      no incentive are expected to exhibit the largest reductions in drinking. In contrast,&#xD;
      students administered attention-control feedback remotely for an incentive ($30) are expected&#xD;
      to exhibit the smallest reductions in drinking. Perceived value of intervention, retention of&#xD;
      intervention content, and attribution for participation are expected to mediate incentive&#xD;
      effects and differential efficacy of in-lab versus remote delivery. This research is expected&#xD;
      to yield theoretical and practical improvements to feedback-based intervention strategies&#xD;
      with potential to reduce drinking and related negative consequences with a stronger&#xD;
      theoretical basis and at lower cost than have been previously available.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 10, 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 31, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 1, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Heavy drinking college students (N=498) participated in a 2 (in-person vs. remote delivery) × 2 (compensation vs. no compensation) × 2 (PNF vs. control) design with follow-up assessments occurring remotely three and six months later.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of drinks in past month - Timeline Follow-back (TLFB)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>This measure asks participants to indicate how many drinks they consumed on each day of the previous month. Scores are summed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of drinks on a typical week - Daily Drinking Questionnaire (DDQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Participants are asked how many drinks they typically drink on each day of a typical week. These values are summed to create a drinks per week score. From Collins, Parks, and Marlatt (1985).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of peak drinks consumed</measure>
    <time_frame>One month</time_frame>
    <description>Participants are asked to indicate the maximum number of drinks consumed on one occasion.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Alcohol-related consequences: Brief Young Adult Alcohol Consequences Questionnaire (BYAACQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>One month</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of 27 alcohol consequences. Participants indicate whether they have experienced the consequence or not and responses are summed to create a total score.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Alcohol-related consequences: Rutgers Alcohol Problems Index (RAPI)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of alcohol consequences. Participants indicate the frequency with which they have experienced each consequence; responses are summed to create a total score.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perception of number of drinks a typical college student drinks</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The DDQ (Outcome 2) was modified to ask participants how often they think the typical college student of their same sex drinks in a typical week. Responses are again summed to create a total score. This measure is posited as a mediator of intervention efficacy on changes in drinking.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>8</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">498</enrollment>
  <condition>Heavy Drinking</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control-Remote-$0</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this condition, Participants:&#xD;
receive attention control feedback&#xD;
complete the baseline and intervention procedure remotely&#xD;
are compensated $0 for completing the baseline and intervention procedure</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control-Remote-$30</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this condition, Participants:&#xD;
receive attention control feedback&#xD;
complete the baseline and intervention procedure remotely&#xD;
are compensated $30 for completing the baseline and intervention procedure</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control-InPerson-$0</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this condition, Participants:&#xD;
receive attention control feedback&#xD;
complete the baseline and intervention procedure in the research lab&#xD;
are compensated $0 for completing the baseline and intervention procedure</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control-InPerson-$30</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this condition, Participants:&#xD;
receive attention control feedback&#xD;
complete the baseline and intervention procedure in the research lab&#xD;
are compensated $30 for completing the baseline and intervention procedure</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PNF-Remote-$0</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this condition, Participants:&#xD;
receive personalized normative feedback&#xD;
complete the baseline and intervention procedure remotely&#xD;
are compensated $0 for completing the baseline and intervention procedure</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PNF-Remote-$30</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this condition, Participants:&#xD;
receive personalized normative feedback&#xD;
complete the baseline and intervention procedure remotely&#xD;
are compensated $30 for completing the baseline and intervention procedure</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PNF-Inperson-$0</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this condition, Participants:&#xD;
receive personalized normative feedback&#xD;
complete the baseline and intervention procedure in the research lab&#xD;
are compensated $0 for completing the baseline and intervention procedure</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PNF-Inperson-$30</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this condition, Participants:&#xD;
receive personalized normative feedback&#xD;
complete the baseline and intervention procedure in the research lab&#xD;
are compensated $30 for completing the baseline and intervention procedure</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Personalized normative feedback</intervention_name>
    <description>Information presenting perceived and actual drinking norms.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control-InPerson-$0</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Control-InPerson-$30</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Control-Remote-$0</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Control-Remote-$30</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>PNF-Inperson-$0</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>PNF-Inperson-$30</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>PNF-Remote-$0</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>PNF-Remote-$30</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Reporting one or more heavy drinking occasions (4/5 drinks on one drinking occasion for&#xD;
        women/men) in the previous month Reporting one or more negative alcohol-related consequence&#xD;
        in the previous month Being between 18 and 26 years of age Being a registered University of&#xD;
        Houston student Providing consent to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Not meeting any of the inclusion criteria Unwillingness to participate Failure to provide&#xD;
        consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>26 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Houston</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77204</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 26, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Houston</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Clayton Neighbors</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

