<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04639531</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-300003874</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04639531</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Virtual Reality-Base Intelligent Orientation and Mobility Specialists Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>VR-IOMS</acronym>
  <official_title>Automated Orientation &amp; Mobility Training in Virtual Reality for Low Vision Rehabilitation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alabama at Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alabama at Birmingham</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The human subject research is a randomized, controlled training trial that tests the&#xD;
      effectiveness of three Virtual Reality-based Intelligent Orientation and Mobility Specialists&#xD;
      (VR-IOMSs) in teaching orientation and mobility (O&amp;M) task skills to low vision patients. It&#xD;
      will be conducted on two sites, University of Alabama at Birmingham (UAB) and Alabama&#xD;
      Institute for Deaf and Blind (AIDB). The same protocol will be used on both sites. UAB will&#xD;
      be the sIRB for the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three O&amp;M tasks will be studied, timing to cross a signalized street using the near lane&#xD;
      parallel traffic surge skill, timing to cross an uncontrolled street using the traffic gap&#xD;
      judgment skill and learning outdoor numbering system. A VR-IOMS will be develop for each&#xD;
      task. The training does not involve research subjects walking into street traffic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Low vision subjects who have difficulties with these O&amp;M tasks due to their impaired vision&#xD;
      will be randomized into three groups, learning the task from a VR-IOMS (experimental group),&#xD;
      from a human Certified Orientation &amp; Mobility Specialist (COMS) in real streets (active&#xD;
      control group) and not learning the task but spending the same amount of time watching low&#xD;
      vision education videos (placebo group). All subjects will be evaluated by COMSs in real&#xD;
      streets around the two study sites before training (pre-training), within 3 days after the&#xD;
      completion of training (post-training) and 3 months after the completion of training (follow&#xD;
      up). Their ability to perform the O&amp;M tasks will be assess quantitatively using objective&#xD;
      methods. COMSs who conduct these evaluations will be blinded for subject training assignment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome measure is the training effect, the difference in task performance&#xD;
      between the pre-training and post-training real street evaluations. The training effects of&#xD;
      the 3 groups will be compared to determine the training effectiveness of the VR-IOMS relative&#xD;
      to human COMS. Secondary outcome measures include the retainment of the training effect.&#xD;
      Objective assessment of the VR-IOMS training process and trainee subjective evaluation of the&#xD;
      VR-IOMS training will also be analyzed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The human subject research is a randomized, controlled training trial that tests the&#xD;
      effectiveness of three Virtual Reality-based Intelligent Orientation and Mobility Specialists&#xD;
      (VR-IOMSs) in teaching orientation and mobility (O&amp;M) task skills to individuals with low&#xD;
      vision (LV). It will be conducted on two sites, University of Alabama at Birmingham (UAB) and&#xD;
      Alabama Institute for Deaf and Blind (AIDB). The same protocol will be used on both sites.&#xD;
      UAB will be the sIRB for the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three O&amp;M tasks will be studied, timing to cross a signalized street using the near lane&#xD;
      parallel traffic surge skill (Task NLPT), timing to cross an uncontrolled street using the&#xD;
      traffic gap judgment skill (Task TGJ) and learning outdoor numbering system (Task ONS). A&#xD;
      VR-IOMS will be developed and validated for each task. The training does not involve research&#xD;
      subjects walking into street traffic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Low vision subjects who have difficulties with these O&amp;M tasks due to their impaired vision&#xD;
      will be recruited from UAB and AIDB according to procedures approved by UAB IRB.&#xD;
      Specifically, clinicians of UAB Center for Low Vision Rehabilitation will identify potential&#xD;
      study subjects from records of existing patients and from new patient population. Recruitment&#xD;
      letters from the clinicians will be sent to potential subjects. Patients who are interested&#xD;
      in participating will initiate contact with UAB research team for initial evaluation and&#xD;
      scheduling an enrollment visit. Certified O&amp;M specialist (COMS) faculty of AIDB's School for&#xD;
      the Blind, the Gentry Facility and Alabama Freedom Center for the Blind will identify&#xD;
      potential study subjects from new students/clients and will use a recruitment script to&#xD;
      inform them about the study. Students/clients who are interested will contact the AIDB team&#xD;
      to arrange initial evaluation and enrollment session.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Initial evaluation includes inquiries of visual and hearing impairment, mental status and O&amp;M&#xD;
      training history. Potential subjects who pass the initial evaluation will attend an&#xD;
      enrollment session where demographic information will be collect, visual and hearing&#xD;
      functions will be assessed, if necessary and functional vision and ability to perform the&#xD;
      study O&amp;M tasks will be evaluated by COMS on real streets. Informed consent/assent material&#xD;
      approved by UAB IRB will be presented to potential subjects who meet the inclusion criteria&#xD;
      and/or their legally authorized representatives. Research activity will not begin until&#xD;
      written informed consent/assent is obtained according to approved procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrolled subjects will be randomized into three groups, learning the task from a VR-IOMS&#xD;
      (experimental group), from a human COMS in real streets (active control group) and not&#xD;
      learning the task but spending the same amount of time watching LV education videos (placebo&#xD;
      group). All subjects will be evaluated by COMSs in real streets around the two study sites&#xD;
      before training (pre-training), within 3 days after the completion of training&#xD;
      (post-training) and 3 months after the completion of training (follow up). Their ability to&#xD;
      perform the O&amp;M tasks in real streets will be assessed quantitatively using objective&#xD;
      methods. Specifically, in Task NLPT, the performance is measured by a safety score, which is&#xD;
      determined by the time of the onset of the steady pedestrian WALK signal, the time when the&#xD;
      first straight going car in the same direction as the traveler's crossing direction entering&#xD;
      the street intersection and the time when the subject decides to start crossing (say GO).&#xD;
      These times will be measured by the COMS using a stopwatch. The safety score, ranges from 0&#xD;
      to 1, represents the proportion of the duration of the pedestrian phase after the subject&#xD;
      says GO. A larger score indicate a larger portion of pedestrian phase is available for the&#xD;
      subject to walk across the street and is thus safer. A GO call in the steady DON'T WALK phase&#xD;
      will be recorded as a negative number and is unsafe. This safety score was developed and used&#xD;
      in the investigators' pilot research. The rule of thumb used by COMSs, start crossing within&#xD;
      7 seconds after the onset of the pedestrian WALK signal, will also be used. In Task TGJ, the&#xD;
      performance is measured by a safety margin, which is the traffic gap width in seconds (the&#xD;
      time interval in seconds between the first and second car passing in front of the traveler)&#xD;
      minus the delay of the subject's crossing decision (say GO) and minus the time needed for the&#xD;
      subject to walk across the street at the participant's preferred walking speed. Validated&#xD;
      objective methods to measure the three times involved in safety margin determination have&#xD;
      been used in previous studies of low vision patient TGJ performance and will be used in this&#xD;
      research. A positive safety margin represents the time left of the traffic gap when the&#xD;
      subject has reached the opposite side of the road, thus indicates a safe crossing decision. A&#xD;
      negative safety margin represents the time when the subject is still in the road after the&#xD;
      traffic gap has closed. It indicates an exposure of the subject to the traffic and thus&#xD;
      indicates an unsafe decision. In Task ONS, the performance is measured by the correctness of&#xD;
      the subject's plan to reach a destination in the neighborhood. The subject earns two points&#xD;
      for making no error in the direction and the side of street of the destination, earns 1 point&#xD;
      for getting one wrong and earns no point for getting both wrong. The subject will not walk&#xD;
      into the traffic in any of the task evaluations in real streets.&#xD;
&#xD;
      COMSs who conduct real street evaluations will use paper data-entry forms to record objective&#xD;
      performance assessment and subjective observation of subject performance. The original&#xD;
      data-entry forms will be placed in the subject's data folder and secured in the PI's file&#xD;
      locker after the data is transcribed to corresponding electronic forms and the transcription&#xD;
      accuracy is versified by the PI or the research coordinator. Only computer generated subject&#xD;
      IDs will be used on paper and electronic data forms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      COMSs who conduct real street evaluations will be blinded for subject training assignment.&#xD;
      The objective nature of the performance measures ensures high inter-rater agreement, as shown&#xD;
      in the investigators' pilot study. Nevertheless, COMSs of the UAB and AIDB sites will test&#xD;
      the agreement of their evaluation outcome by evaluating the performance of the same subjects&#xD;
      on real streets before the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      COMSs who are not involved in evaluation will train the active control group in real streets.&#xD;
      The COMS will use their routine training procedure to conduct real street training to reflect&#xD;
      the current practice in O&amp;M rehabilitation. COMSs have the freedom to customize their&#xD;
      training procedure according to each subject's ability and need. However, the COMSs on UAB&#xD;
      and AIDB who will conduct training will come to consensus on the exiting performance levels&#xD;
      for the O&amp;M tasks and will confirm consistency of their exiting performance levels on the&#xD;
      same low vision subjects before trial. The experimental group will be trained by the&#xD;
      automated VR-IOMSs. A member of the research team will be in the room of the simulator for&#xD;
      safety reason, but will not intervene VR-IOMS training. Members of the experimental group&#xD;
      will also be asked to complete a survey of their learning experience with the VR-IOMSs.&#xD;
      Members of the placebo group will watch low vision education video and discuss low vision&#xD;
      issues not related to O&amp;M with COMSs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      COMSs who train subjects in real streets will keep an electronic training diary for each&#xD;
      subject, which will include the participant's assessment of the subject's ability to perform&#xD;
      the O&amp;M task entering and exiting training, observation of the subject's performance and&#xD;
      progress during training. The VR-IOMSs automatically maintain detailed records of the&#xD;
      teaching/practicing material, results of assessment, the errors made, the feedback/guidance&#xD;
      provided and results of exit assessment. Subject will only be referred to using their study&#xD;
      IDs in all training records.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size computation for Task NLPT is based on the results of the investigators' pilot&#xD;
      study, in which LV subjects received the NLPT surge training from COMSs. The mean pre- and&#xD;
      post-training safety scores were 0.24±0.32 and 0.79±0.18. If the trial is designed to detect&#xD;
      a 25% difference between the post-NLPT training safety scores of COMS and VR-IOMS training,&#xD;
      and the enrollment is selectively stratified such that each group has an equal number of&#xD;
      central and peripheral vision loss subjects, a sample size of 8 per group can achieve a power&#xD;
      of 91% at a significance level of 0.05 in a one-way ANOVA study. Assuming that 20% of the&#xD;
      enrolled subjects may not be able to complete the multi-session study, 30 LV subjects will be&#xD;
      enrolled for the Task NLPT training trial. There have been no quantitative studies on TGJ&#xD;
      training effect on LV patients. A quantitative study of 10 experienced LV travelers with&#xD;
      mixed central and peripheral vision losses found a close match between their gap width&#xD;
      judgments (safe gap width 4.6±0.54 sec) and cross times (0.48±0.88 sec). The authors' power&#xD;
      analysis showed that the sample size, N=10, had 86% power to resolve a 0.5 second difference&#xD;
      in the safety margin of the TGJ task. This resolution is good from a practical point of view&#xD;
      (time for moving one step). the investigators will enroll 36 LV subjects (10 per group + 20%&#xD;
      extra) for the TGJ VR-IOMS trial. No quantitative studies on LV patients learning the outdoor&#xD;
      numbering system have been conducted. The investigators will use the subjects recruited for&#xD;
      Task TGJ to conduct a pilot study to obtain training effects and standard deviations for&#xD;
      sample size computation. For programmatic purpose, the investigators assume a sample size of&#xD;
      36 for the ONS VR-IOMS trial. This yields a total number of 102 LV subjects for the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 15, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>randomized, controlled training trial with experimental, active control and placebo groups</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Separate Certified Orientation &amp; Mobility Specialists (COMS) conduct training and outcome evaluation</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Training effectiveness</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 3 days before commencement of Orientation and Mobility training</time_frame>
    <description>Performance in Orientation and Mobility task in real streets before training (Percent of success)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Training effectiveness</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 3 days after completion of Orientation and Mobility training</time_frame>
    <description>Performance in Orientation and Mobility task in real streets after training (Percent of success)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Training effect retainment</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 3 days after completion of Orientation and Mobility training</time_frame>
    <description>Performance in Orientation and Mobility task in real streets after training (Percent of success)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Training effect retainment</measure>
    <time_frame>At 3 months after completion of orientation and mobility training</time_frame>
    <description>Performance in Orientation and Mobility task in real streets 3 months after training (Percent of success)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective learning experience with VR-IOMS</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 30 minutes after completion of VR-IOMS training</time_frame>
    <description>Structured and/or open-end questionnaire about automated skill learning in virtual streets.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Training duration</measure>
    <time_frame>From the commencement of orientation &amp; mobility training to its completion (may spread in multiple days) / within one week</time_frame>
    <description>Time taken (in hours) to complete orientation and mobility training</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">102</enrollment>
  <condition>Low Vision, Both Eyes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Orientation and Mobility Training with VR-IOMSs</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Low vision subjects with Orientation and Mobility (O&amp;M) difficulties learning O&amp;M skills from Virtual Reality-base Intelligent O&amp;M Specialists (VR-IOMSs). VR-IOMSs are intelligent, computer-controlled automatic O&amp;M skill training programs in virtual streets.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Orientation and Mobility Training with COMS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Low vision subjects with Orientation and Mobility (O&amp;M) difficulties learning O&amp;M skills from human Certified O&amp;M Specialists (COMS) in real streets</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No Orientation and Mobility Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Low vision subjects with Orientation and Mobility (O&amp;M) difficulties watching low vision education videos and discuss low vision issues not related to O&amp;M with COMSs.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Orientation and Mobility Training with VR-IOMSs</intervention_name>
    <description>Learning Orientation and Mobility skills from virtual-reality-based, automated, intelligent computer training programs - VR-IOMSs</description>
    <arm_group_label>Orientation and Mobility Training with VR-IOMSs</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Orientation and Mobility Training with COMS</intervention_name>
    <description>Learning Orientation and Mobility skills from human Certified Orientation and Mobility Specialists (COMS)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Orientation and Mobility Training with COMS</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No Orientation and Mobility Training</intervention_name>
    <description>No Orientation and Mobility training. Watch low vision education videos and discuss low vision issues not related to O&amp;M with COMS</description>
    <arm_group_label>No Orientation and Mobility Training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have stable, late-onset visual impairment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not have had formal O&amp;M training. Potential participants will be taken to real streets&#xD;
             by COMS and their performance on the 3 studied tasks will be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Following visual function requirements for the three studied O&amp;M tasks&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Task NLPT: best corrected visual acuity of 20/650 or worse&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Task TGJ:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  central vision loss - acuity 20/100-20/300, radius of field 50-80 deg&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  peripheral vision loss - acuity 20/15-20/100, radius of field 5-55 deg&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Task ONS: visual function requirements for both Tasks NLPT &amp; TGJ&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Possess sufficient functional vision to learn the O&amp;M tasks (evaluated by COMS in real&#xD;
             streets)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have O&amp;M as a rehabilitation goal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal or corrected to normal hearing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No cognitive impairment (Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA) or MoCA-blind (MoCA-B)&#xD;
             score exceeds education-adjusted cutoffs)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dexterity to operate a pointing mouse or a joystick&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physical stamina to walk a few street blocks under guidance of COMSs and to stand or&#xD;
             sit for 30-min training sessions on the street or in the VR simulator&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients in the rapid progression phase of ocular diseases, such as wet macular&#xD;
             degeneration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under aggressive treatment of ocular diseases, such as VEGF injection for&#xD;
             retinal diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with congenital visual impairment will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants will be excluded from the training for the skills that they already&#xD;
             master.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have a history of epileptic seizure or are prone to motion sickness&#xD;
             will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have difficulty in verbal communication in English.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lei Liu, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lei Liu, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>2059966627</phone>
    <email>liul7788@uab.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ellen L Bowman, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>2057990422</phone>
    <email>elbowman@uab.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama at Birmingham</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35226</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lei Liu, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>212-923-3723</phone>
      <email>liul7788@uab.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Ellen L Bowman, PhD/COMS</last_name>
      <phone>2057990422</phone>
      <email>elbowman@uab.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lei Liu, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ellen L Bowman, PhD/COMS</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 13, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 20, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lei Liu</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Orientation &amp; Mobility</keyword>
  <keyword>Virtual Reality</keyword>
  <keyword>Intelligent Tutoring</keyword>
  <keyword>Low Vision</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vision, Low</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Only summary data will be published and made available to other researchers.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

