<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04631159</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>202000635B0</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04631159</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness of Health Management of Glycemic Control and Physical Activity in Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus Using Smartphone Application</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of Health Management of Glycemic Control and Physical Activity in Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus Using Smartphone Application:a Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mei-fang Huang</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Chang Gung Memorial Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Medical cost in Taiwan for management of diabetes has accounted for the top three. Diabetic&#xD;
      patients often have poor self-health managements, there by leading to occurrence of&#xD;
      complications. investigators team has previously published that medical staff directly&#xD;
      instructed to the elderly with diabetes comorbid with knee osteoarthritis by performing&#xD;
      elastic band resistance exercise, participants can improve functional activity after 12 weeks&#xD;
      of intervention. However, there was a decrease in glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c), but it did not&#xD;
      reach a significant improvement.Investigators also found that how to improve the glycemic&#xD;
      control, particularly in during the follow-up periods, and how to increase the amount of&#xD;
      physical activity of diabetic patients that may affect the changes in glycated hemoglobin.&#xD;
      With the rapid development of up-to-date medical technology, medical applications (apps) has&#xD;
      emerging developing to aid self-health management by themselves. Therefore, this project will&#xD;
      continue to explore the effectiveness of using simple tracking, monitoring, and immediate&#xD;
      feedback on the health management of diabetic patients. Although various apps have been&#xD;
      adopted for the monitoring of diabetic patients, few medical professionals regularly use&#xD;
      smartphone apps to directly supervise diabetic patients to make immediate remote medical&#xD;
      intervention regarding blood glucose, medications, blood pressure, body composition, and even&#xD;
      monitor physical activity concurrently.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Purpose: To investigate the effectiveness of health management of glycemic control and&#xD;
      physical activity in type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) using Smartphone application.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: Clinical medical personnel can monitor data through the mobile app platform and&#xD;
      provide personalized lifestyle adjustments based on the information provided by patients,&#xD;
      thereby improving patient compliance and effectively self-health management in patients with&#xD;
      T2DM. At the same time, through this system, medical personnel can understand the amount of&#xD;
      physical activity of the patient during this period, and investigators can promptly encourage&#xD;
      patients to reach the set goal of physical activity, which can improve the patient's physical&#xD;
      status, so this study can bring a positive effect in both blood glucose and related&#xD;
      biomarkers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: This study will be a randomized controlled trial. Seventy adults (aged 20 to 60&#xD;
      years) diagnosed with T2DM by the physician will recruited and randomly assigned to the&#xD;
      mobile app group and the control group. Both groups will receive education by health&#xD;
      professionals at Southern Medical Center and participants are required to wear fitness&#xD;
      watches to record steps. Mobile app group: patients will need to download and use the&#xD;
      Health2Sync app and report blood glucose data weekly, and be monitored and advised by medical&#xD;
      personnel. Control group: Patients will be asked to self-manage and there is no intervention&#xD;
      during the tracking process.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This study will be a randomized controlled trial. Seventy adults (aged 20 to 60 years) diagnosed with T2DM by the physician will recruited and randomly assigned to the mobile app group and the control group. Both groups will receive education by health professionals at Southern Medical Center and they are required to wear fitness watches to record steps. Mobile app group: patients will need to download and use the Health2Sync app and report blood glucose data weekly, and be monitored and advised by medical personnel. Control group: Patients will be asked to self-manage and there is no intervention during the tracking process. Each subject will be required to measure body composition, blood pressure, blood biochemical analysis (HbA1C, fasting blood glucose, total cholesterol, low-density cholesterol, high-density cholesterol, triglycerides), and number of steps before and after 12 weeks</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline HbA1c through a mobile app.</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline HbA1c at 3 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The number of participants who have related every day steps as assessed by Mi Smart Band 4.</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline at 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The number of participants who have related per day steps as assessed by Mi Smart Band 4. Achieve the goal value of 7500 steps per day.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>To Investigate the Effectiveness of Health Management of Glycemic Control and Physical Activity in Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus Using Smartphone Application</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mobile app group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>They are required to wear fitness watches to record steps ,patients will need to download and use the Health2Sync app and report blood glucose data weekly, and be monitored and advised by medical personnel.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>they are required to wear fitness watches to record steps ,patients will be asked to self-manage and there is no intervention during the tracking process.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Health2Sync app and report blood glucose data weekly</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will need to download and use the Health2Sync app and report blood glucose data weekly</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mobile app group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>self-manage</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will be asked to self-manage and there is no intervention during the tracking process</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical diagnosis of type2 diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 20 to 60 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No smartphone, cannot operation of smartphone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to move&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use insulin pump&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis neuropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis retinopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis diabetic foot&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis severe nephropathy ,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis severe liver disease Cognitive impairment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Chang Nai-Jen</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Kaohsiung Medical University Department of Sports Medicine professor</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Huang Mei-fang</last_name>
    <phone>866-978839897</phone>
    <email>yopag2003@cgmh.org.tw</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mei-fang Huang</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kaohsiung City</city>
        <state>No. 20, Ln. 125, Wenbin Rd., Fengshan Dist.,</state>
        <zip>830009</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Huang Mei-fang</last_name>
      <phone>077317123</phone>
      <phone_ext>2166</phone_ext>
      <email>yopag2003@cgmh.org.tw</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Chang Gung Memorial Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mei-fang Huang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>ChangGungMH Certified Diabetes Educator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Currently in the submission stage ,and then share with other researchers after publication</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

