<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04637100</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>5200471</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04637100</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Gaming Apps Post-Stroke</brief_title>
  <acronym>GAPS</acronym>
  <official_title>Effect of Free Mobile or Tablet-based Applications on Stroke-Related Cognitive Impairment in Inpatient Rehabilitation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Loma Linda University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Loma Linda University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators aim to explore the effect of puzzle mobile or tablet-based games on&#xD;
      problem-solving impairment resulting from a first-time stroke. This is a&#xD;
      randomized-controlled trial with the intervention arm consisting of puzzle gaming&#xD;
      applications and the control arm consisting of stroke-relevant educational videos provided&#xD;
      and encouraged throughout the course of participants' acute inpatient rehabilitation stay.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study subjects will be randomized to a control or experimental group and allocation will be&#xD;
      concealed. The experimental group will consist of the subject utilizing their personal mobile&#xD;
      or tablet device to play a pre-selected set of problem-solving games for a goal of 1 hour&#xD;
      daily. The control group will utilize their personal mobile or tablet device to perform the&#xD;
      non-problem-solving task of watching educational videos of their choice from a pre-selected&#xD;
      set of videos for the same amount of time daily. The intervention gaming arm will be provided&#xD;
      different gaming apps if they lose interest or find a particular game too easy or too&#xD;
      difficult. The control video arm will be provided different educational videos according to&#xD;
      their needs that may change throughout their inpatient stay.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Change in research personnel&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Scales of Cognitive and Communicative Ability for Neurorehabilitation (SCCAN)</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until the day of discharge, assessed at beginning and end of this period, up to 5 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assesses cognitive-communicative deficits and functional ability in patients in rehabilitation hospitals, clinics, and skilled nursing facilities. The SCCAN contents relate to daily activities that adults would be expected to perform for independent living. The SCCAN has eight scales and a total score:&#xD;
Oral Expression, Orientation, Memory, Speech Comprehension, Reading Comprehension, Writing, Attention, Problem Solving&#xD;
Typical functioning = 87-94 Mild impairment = 69-86 Moderate impairment = 47-68 Severe impairment = 0-46</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MOCA)</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until the day of discharge, assessed at beginning and end of this period, up to 5 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Rapid screen of cognitive abilities designed to detect mild cognitive dysfunction consisting of 16 items and 11 categories assessing multiple cognitive domains&#xD;
No cognitive impairment &gt;=25 Mild cognitive impairment = 20-24 Severe cognitive impairment &lt; 20</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Modified Gaming Engagement Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until the day of discharge, assessed at end of this period, up to 5 weeks. Qualitative feedback only.</time_frame>
    <description>15-item questionnaire for feedback on engagement during game-playing or video watching</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Program Evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until the day of discharge, assessed at end of this period, up to 5 weeks. Qualitative feedback only.</time_frame>
    <description>11 item questionnaire for feedback on participant experience</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <condition>Cognitive Impairment</condition>
  <condition>Executive Dysfunction</condition>
  <condition>Cognitive Change</condition>
  <condition>Cognitive Deficit</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The patient will utilize their personal mobile or tablet device to play a pre-selected set of problem-solving games for a goal of 1 hour daily for the duration of their inpatient rehabilitation stay (approximately 3 weeks).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The patient will utilize their personal mobile or tablet device to watch a pre-selected set of stroke-related educational videos for a goal of 1 hour daily for the duration of their inpatient rehabilitation stay (approximately 3 weeks).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mobile or tablet-based gaming applications</intervention_name>
    <description>Subject will use their own personal smartphone or tablet device to play from a collection of pre-selected gaming applications. The collection is made of puzzle-type games available on both Android and iOS without excessive ads and with clear or self-explanatory instructions. Subject will be instructed to play for 1 hour daily for the duration of their acute inpatient rehabilitation stay (approximately 3 weeks).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Stroke-related educational videos</intervention_name>
    <description>Subject will use their own personal smartphone or tablet device to watch videos from a collection of pre-selected educational videos. These include topics on stroke recognition, stroke recovery process, patient experiences with stroke, rehabilitation after stroke, activities of daily living equipment instructions. Subject will be instructed to watch for 1 hour daily for the duration of their acute inpatient rehabilitation stay (approximately 3 weeks).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 18-89&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Hospitalized at Loma Linda East Campus Rehabilitation Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. First time stroke patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. mild to moderate problem-solving impairment without severe deficit in any other&#xD;
             cognitive domain on admission speech evaluation&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Have daily access while inpatient to a personally owned Apple or Android smartphone or&#xD;
             tablet device prior to the initial session.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Unable to understand and follow verbal and written instructions in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Presence of aphasia that limits device use or ability to provide consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Presence of pre-stroke speech, language, or cognitive disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Unable to operate device due to cognitive, physical, or visual impairment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christopher Tarver, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Loma Linda University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tom and Vi Zapara Rehabilitation Pavilion</name>
      <address>
        <city>Loma Linda</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92354</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Loma Linda University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Christopher Tarver</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Stroke</keyword>
  <keyword>cerebrovascular accident</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cognitive Dysfunction</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

