<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04637009</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TAS1553-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04637009</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of TAS1553 in Subjects With Relapsed or Refractory Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML) and Other Myeloid Neoplasms</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1 Study of Safety, Pharmacokinetics and Preliminary Activity of TAS1553 in Subjects With Relapsed or Refractory (R/R) Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML) and Other Myeloid Neoplasms</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Astex Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Astex Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 1, 2-part, open-label, multicenter, first-in-human (FIH) study to assess the&#xD;
      safety, pharmacokinetics (PK), pharmacodynamics (PD), and preliminary clinical activity of&#xD;
      TAS1553 administered orally to participants ≥18 years of age with relapsed or refractory&#xD;
      (R/R) acute myeloid leukemia (AML) or other myeloid neoplasms where approved therapies have&#xD;
      failed or for whom known life-prolonging therapies are not available. The AML population&#xD;
      includes de novo AML, secondary AML, and myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS)-transformed into AML.&#xD;
      Other myeloid neoplasms include accelerated phase myeloproliferative neoplasms (MPN), and&#xD;
      chronic or accelerated phase MPN-unclassifiable (MPN-U) and MDS-MPN. Blast crisis phase of&#xD;
      MPNs are considered secondary AML and will be included in the AML cohort.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part 1 is a multicenter, sequential group treatment feasibility study with 1 treatment arm&#xD;
      and no masking (dose escalation). Part 2 is a multicenter, two-stage, multiple group, dose&#xD;
      confirmation study with 1 treatment arm and no masking (exploratory dose expansion).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 21, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety: Number of participants with treatment-emergent adverse events in Part 1</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety: Number of participants with dose-limiting toxicities in Part 1</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Response rate in Cohort 1 (AML): Number of participants with complete response (CR) + complete response with partial hematological recovery (CRh), and with CR + incomplete blood count recovery (CRi) in Part 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 33 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Response rate in Cohort 2 (other myeloid neoplasms): Number of participants with overall response rate (ORR) of CR + partial response (PR) in Part 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 33 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic parameter: Area under the curve (AUC)</measure>
    <time_frame>At specific timepoints from predose up to Day 8 of Cycle 6 (28 days per cycle)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic parameter: Maximum plasma concentration (Cmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>At specific timepoints from predose up to Day 8 of Cycle 6 (28 days per cycle)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic parameter: Minimum plasma concentration (Cmin)</measure>
    <time_frame>At specific timepoints from predose up to Day 8 of Cycle 6 (28 days per cycle)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic parameter: Time to reach maximum plasma concentration (Tmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>At specific timepoints from predose up to Day 8 of Cycle 6 (28 days per cycle)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic parameter: Half-life (t½)</measure>
    <time_frame>At specific timepoints from predose up to Day 8 of Cycle 6 (28 days per cycle)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hematological improvement: Number of participants in Cohort 2 (other myeloid neoplasms) with hematological improvement in Part 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 33 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to response (TTR): Number of days from the first dose to the first documented evidence of response</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 33 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response (DOR): Number of days from the start of response until disease progression or relapse</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 33 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS): Number of days from date of first dose until death due to any cause</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 33 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety: Number of participants with treatment-emergent adverse events in Part 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 33 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacodynamic biomarker: Change from baseline in deoxyadenosine triphosphate (dATP) pool levels in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs)</measure>
    <time_frame>At specific timepoints from predose up to Day 2 of Cycle 2 (28 days per cycle)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacodynamic biomarker: Change from baseline in phosphorylated checkpoint kinase 1 (pCHK1) levels in bone marrow</measure>
    <time_frame>At specific timepoints from predose up to Day 2 of Cycle 2 (28 days per cycle)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Myeloid Leukemia</condition>
  <condition>Myeloproliferative Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Myelodysplastic/Myeloproliferative Neoplasm</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1 (dose escalation)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral administration of TAS1553 once daily at specific time points.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 (dose expansion)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral administration of TAS1553 once daily at specific time points.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TAS1553</intervention_name>
    <description>Form: tablet; Route of Administration: oral</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1 (dose escalation)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 (dose expansion)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Capable of giving signed informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participant must be 18 years of age or older, at the time of signing the informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks as assessed by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participants with R/R AML or other myeloid neoplasms where approved therapies have&#xD;
             failed or for whom known life-prolonging therapies are not available. The AML&#xD;
             population includes de novo AML, secondary AML, and MDS transformed into AML. Other&#xD;
             myeloid neoplasms include accelerated phase MPN, and chronic or accelerated phase&#xD;
             MPN-U and MDS-MPN. Blast crisis phase of MPN, MPN-U, and MDS-MPN are considered&#xD;
             secondary AML and will be included in the AML cohort.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Have an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 to 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Have platelet count ≥10,000/μL (transfusions to achieve this level are allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Have adequate renal function as demonstrated by a 24-hour urine measured creatinine&#xD;
             clearance ≥60 mL/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Adequate hepatic function as evidenced by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤3× upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≤3×ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. total bilirubin ≤1.5×ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Participants must be amenable to serial bone marrow biopsies, peripheral blood&#xD;
             sampling, and urine sampling during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Women of child-bearing potential (according to recommendations of the Clinical Trial&#xD;
             Facilitation Group [CTFG]) must not be pregnant or breastfeeding and must have a&#xD;
             negative pregnancy test at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participants who have MPN, MPN-U, or MDS/MPN and display hypoplastic bone marrow and&#xD;
             would also not ordinarily benefit from cytoreductive therapy such as hydroxyurea (HU).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participants with highly proliferative disease are excluded as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Part 1/AML: white blood cells (WBC) &gt;20,000/μL and &gt;50% blasts in blood. Measures&#xD;
                  to reduce WBC, such as HU treatment within the last 2 weeks and cytotoxic&#xD;
                  chemotherapy within the last 4 weeks are not allowed to meet this eligibility&#xD;
                  criterion.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Part 1/other myeloid neoplasms: WBC &gt;20,000/μL. A short course of HU may be used&#xD;
                  to meet this eligibility criterion, as long as HU is discontinued 96 hours and&#xD;
                  any encountered drug-related toxicity must be resolved to Grade ≤1 before the&#xD;
                  first dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Part 2/Cohort 1, AML: WBC&gt;20,000/μL and &gt;50% blasts in blood. A short course of&#xD;
                  HU may be used to meet this eligibility criterion, as long as HU is discontinued&#xD;
                  96 hours, and any encountered drug-related toxicity must be resolved to Grade ≤1&#xD;
                  before the first dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Part 2/Cohort 2, other myeloid neoplasms: Specific WBC exclusion criterion not&#xD;
                  defined. A short course of HU may be used to reduce WBC if judged to be necessary&#xD;
                  by the investigator, as long as HU is discontinued 96 hours and any encountered&#xD;
                  drug-related toxicity must be resolved to Grade ≤1 before the first dose of study&#xD;
                  treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Known clinically active central nervous system (CNS) leukemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Diagnosis of BCR-ABL-positive leukemia, acute promyelocytic leukemia (M3 AML or APML),&#xD;
             or juvenile myelomonocytic leukemia (JMML).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Second malignancy requiring active systemic therapy, except breast or prostate cancer&#xD;
             stable on or responding to endocrine therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Ongoing Grade ≥3 Graft Versus Host Disease (GVHD), or any grade GVHD requiring active&#xD;
             treatment (for example, calcineurin inhibitors, ≥5mg/day prednisone or other steroid&#xD;
             equivalent, or other immunosuppressive agents). (Note: Prednisone at any dose for&#xD;
             other indications is allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Advanced human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection, active hepatitis B virus (HBV)&#xD;
             or hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection; Inactive hepatitis carrier status and&#xD;
             participants with laboratory evidence of no active replication and participants on&#xD;
             antiviral medication(s) who have a viral load below limit of detection will be&#xD;
             permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Known significant mental illness or other condition such as active alcohol or other&#xD;
             substance abuse or addiction that, in the opinion of the investigator, predisposes the&#xD;
             participant to high risk of non-compliance with the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Active infection resistant to antibiotics; or non-leukemia-associated pulmonary&#xD;
             disease requiring &gt;2 liters per minute oxygen or any other condition that puts the&#xD;
             participant at an imminent risk of death.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. 24-hour urinary protein excretion ≥1g or urinalysis of 2+proteinuria.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of, or at risk for, cardiac disease, as evidenced by any of the following&#xD;
             conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Abnormal left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF; &lt;50%) on echocardiogram (ECHO)&#xD;
                  or multiple-gated acquisition (MUGA) scan at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Congestive cardiac failure of Class ≥III severity according to New York Heart&#xD;
                  Association (NYHA) functional classification defined as patients with marked&#xD;
                  limitation of activity and who are comfortable at rest, while Class IV patients&#xD;
                  have symptoms of heart failure at rest.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Unstable cardiac disease including unstable angina or hypertension as defined by&#xD;
                  the need for overnight hospital admission within the last 3 months (90 days).&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Ventricular arrhythmias including ventricular bigeminy, clinically significant&#xD;
                  brady arrhythmias such as sick sinus syndrome, third-degree atrioventricular (AV)&#xD;
                  block, presence of cardiac pacemaker or defibrillator, or other clinically&#xD;
                  significant arrhythmias.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Screening 12-lead electrocardiogram (ECG) with measurable QTcF interval of ≥470&#xD;
                  msec (Fridericia's formula should be used).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Known hypersensitivity to TAS1553 or any of its components.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Allogenic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HSCT) within 180 days of the first&#xD;
             dose of TAS1553, or participants on immunosuppressive therapy post HSCT at the time of&#xD;
             screening (calcineurin inhibitors or similar must be discontinued ≥4 weeks prior to&#xD;
             the time of study drug initiation).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Treated with any systemic anticancer therapy within 2 weeks of the first dose of study&#xD;
             treatment. Any encountered treatment-related toxicities (excepting alopecia) must be&#xD;
             resolved to Grade 1 or less.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Phase 1 Part 1 only: participants who require concomitant use of strong CYP3A4&#xD;
             inducers.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Inability to swallow oral medication.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jason Taylor, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Astex Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>General Inquiries</last_name>
    <phone>9255600100</phone>
    <email>info@astx.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama - Birmingham Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35233</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tonya Cole</last_name>
      <phone>205-975-7162</phone>
      <email>tdcole@uabmc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Pankit Vachhani, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>HonorHealth Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Scottsdale</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>82528</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nyssa Hoffman</last_name>
      <phone>480-946-4455</phone>
      <email>Nyssa.Hoffman@HonorHealth.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Christine Canilao</last_name>
      <phone>480-323-1323</phone>
      <email>ccanilao@honorhealth.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Veena Fauble, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christina Pierce, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kathryn Steenstra, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Southern California Keck School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90033</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christine Duran</last_name>
      <phone>323-865-0089</phone>
      <email>duran_c@med.usc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Casey O'Connell, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Augusta University - Georgia Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Augusta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30912</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kelly Jenkins</last_name>
      <phone>706-721-1206</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jorge Cortes, M.D</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Norton Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Louisville</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40241</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Heather Woolridge</last_name>
      <phone>502-899-3366</phone>
      <phone_ext>19211</phone_ext>
      <email>heather.woolridge@nortonhealthcare.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Joshua Roberts</last_name>
      <phone>502-899-3386</phone>
      <phone_ext>19291</phone_ext>
      <email>joshua.roberts@nortonhealthcare.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joseph Maly, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Don Stevens, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sandy Stencavage, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Amy McCaa, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Dana Haycraft, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Dale Vincent, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Weill Cornell Medicine and New York - Presbyterian Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alekya Kaveli</last_name>
      <phone>347-233-9068</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gail Roboz, M.D</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cleveland Clinic Taussig Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Brielle Brath</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sudipto Mukherjee</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Vicky Zoeller</last_name>
      <phone>713-745-8461</phone>
      <email>vhzoelle@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Yesid Alvarado-Valero, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Allison Pike</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alberta Hospital - Hematology Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edmonton</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T6G 2V2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michelle Chu</last_name>
      <phone>780-266-7337</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joseph Brandwein</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Princess Margaret Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5G 2L7</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Karen Yee, MD</last_name>
      <phone>416-946-4501</phone>
      <phone_ext>7808</phone_ext>
      <email>Karen.Yee@uhn.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Karen Yee, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 15, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>MDS/MPN, unclassifiable in chronic phase</keyword>
  <keyword>Accelerated phase MPN</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic neutrophilic leukemia (CNL), accelerated phase</keyword>
  <keyword>Polycythemia vera (PV), accelerated phase</keyword>
  <keyword>Primary myelofibrosis (PMF), accelerated phase</keyword>
  <keyword>Essential thrombocythemia (ET), accelerated phase</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic eosinophilic leukemia, not otherwise specified (NOS), accelerated phase</keyword>
  <keyword>MPN, unclassifiable</keyword>
  <keyword>MDS/MPN</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic myelomonocytic leukemia (CMML)</keyword>
  <keyword>Atypical chronic myeloid leukemia (aCML), BCR-ABL1-negative</keyword>
  <keyword>MDS/MPN with ring sideroblasts and thrombocytosis (MDS/MPN-RS-T)</keyword>
  <keyword>MDS/MPN, unclassifiable</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myeloproliferative Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myelodysplastic-Myeloproliferative Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

