<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03416530</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ONC014</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03416530</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>ONC201 in Pediatric H3 K27M Gliomas</brief_title>
  <official_title>ONC201 in Newly Diagnosed Diffuse Intrinsic Pontine Glioma and Recurrent/Refractory Pediatric H3 K27M Gliomas</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Chimerix</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Chimerix</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter, open-label, seven arm, dose escalation, phase I study of oral ONC201&#xD;
      in pediatric patients with newly diagnosed Diffuse Intrinsic Pontine Glioma (DIPG) and&#xD;
      recurrent/refractory H3 K27M gliomas. Arm A will define the RP2D for single agent ONC201 in&#xD;
      pediatric patients with glioma who are positive for the H3 K27M mutation (positive testing in&#xD;
      CLIA laboratory) and have completed at least one line of prior therapy. This will allow for&#xD;
      recurrent patients and also patients who have not yet recurred, but have completed radiation&#xD;
      and will inevitably recur based on prior clinical experience and the literature. Arm B will&#xD;
      define the RP2D for ONC201 in combination with radiation in pediatric patients with newly&#xD;
      diagnosed DIPG. Arm C will determine intratumoral drug concentrations and biomarker&#xD;
      expression in pediatric patients with midline gliomas. Arm D will determine H3 K27M DNA&#xD;
      levels and drug concentrations in the CSF of pediatric H3 K27M-mutant glioma patients. Arm E&#xD;
      will determine the RP2D for single agent ONC201 administered as a liquid formulation in&#xD;
      Ora-Sweet to patients with DIPG and/or H3 K27M glioma. Arm F is a dose expansion cohort to&#xD;
      confirm the safety and estimate the efficacy in recurrent H3 K27M-mutant glioma population at&#xD;
      the RP2D. Arm G will define the RP2D for single agent ONC201 given on two consecutive days of&#xD;
      each week in pediatric patients with glioma who are positive for the H3 K27M mutation and&#xD;
      have completed at least one line of prior therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 29, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>RP2D</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Determination of recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D) as a single agent or in combination with radiation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>7</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">130</enrollment>
  <condition>Diffuse Intrinsic Pontine Glioma</condition>
  <condition>Glioma, Malignant</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ONC201 in relapsed/refractory H3 K27M glioma</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pediatric patients with glioma who are positive for the H3 K27M mutation (positive testing in CLIA laboratory) and have completed at least one line of prior therapy. Evidence of progression is not required so that ONC201 may be administered to patients in the maintenance setting or to patients with recurrent/refractory disease.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ONC201 in newly diagnosed DIPG</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pediatric patients with newly diagnosed diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma (DIPG), defined as tumors with a pontine epicenter and diffuse involvement of the pons, are eligible with or without histologic confirmation. If H3 K27M status of tumor is unknown or archival tumor tissue is not available, then patients must agree to submit a post-mortem biopsy specimen.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Midline Glioma Biopsy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pediatric patients midline gliomas are eligible with or without histologic confirmation and must be eligible for tumor biopsy as deemed by the site Investigator.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>H3 K27M CSF Biopsy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pediatric patients with recurrent glioma who are positive for the H3 K27M mutation (positive testing in CLIA laboratory), have completed at least one line of prior therapy, must be willing to undergo serial lumbar puncture to obtain cerebrospinal fluid (CSF), and must be scheduled to undergo sedated MRIs.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Liquid ONC201 in relapsed/refractory H3 K27M glioma</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with glioma who are positive for the H3 K27M mutation (positive testing in CLIA laboratory) or have diagnosed diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma (DIPG), defined as tumors with a pontine epicenter and diffuse involvement of the pons, are eligible with or without histologic confirmation. Patients must be 2-12 weeks from completion of first-line radiation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Expansion Cohort in relapsed/refractory H3 K27M glioma</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pediatric patients with previously-treated, histologically confirmed high-grade glioma with a known H3 K27M mutation, evidence of progressive disease contrast-enhanced brain MRI as defined by RANO-HGG criteria. Prior therapy with at least radiotherapy is required.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ONC201 given on two consecutive days of each week</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pediatric patients with glioma who are positive for the H3 K27M mutation (positive testing in CLIA laboratory) and have completed at least one line of prior therapy will be enrolled to define the RP2D for single agent ONC201 given on two consecutive days of each week.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ONC201</intervention_name>
    <description>ONC201 is a orally active, small molecule DRD2 antagonist that kills cancer cells but not normal cells.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Expansion Cohort in relapsed/refractory H3 K27M glioma</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>H3 K27M CSF Biopsy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Liquid ONC201 in relapsed/refractory H3 K27M glioma</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Midline Glioma Biopsy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ONC201 given on two consecutive days of each week</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ONC201 in newly diagnosed DIPG</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ONC201 in relapsed/refractory H3 K27M glioma</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 2 to less than 19 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient body weight must be above the minimum necessary for the patient to receive the&#xD;
             ONC201 dose indicated for the currently enrolling dose level. The minimum body weight&#xD;
             ranges from 10-27.5kg depending on the dose level.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Arm A and G: Patients with glioma who are positive for the H3 K27M mutation (positive&#xD;
             testing in CLIA laboratory) and have completed at least one line of prior therapy.&#xD;
             Evidence of progression is not required so that ONC201 may be administered to patients&#xD;
             in the maintenance setting or to patients with recurrent disease. No more than two&#xD;
             episodes of recurrence from radiotherapy and/or chemotherapy are allowed. Use of&#xD;
             bevacizumab solely for treatment of radiation necrosis, pseudoprogression, or&#xD;
             treatment effect will not be considered a recurrence. Post-mortem biopsy is required&#xD;
             if H3 K27M status of tumor is unknown and archival tumor tissue not available.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Arm B: Patients with newly diagnosed diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma (DIPG), defined&#xD;
             as tumors with a pontine epicenter and diffuse involvement of the pons, are eligible&#xD;
             with or without histologic confirmation. Post-mortem biopsy is required if H3 K27M&#xD;
             status of tumor is unknown and archival tumor tissue not available.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Arm C: Patients with midline gliomas are eligible with or without histologic&#xD;
             confirmation and must be eligible for tumor biopsy as deemed by the site Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Arm D: Patients with recurrent glioma who are positive for the H3 K27M mutation&#xD;
             (positive testing in CLIA laboratory), have completed at least one line of prior&#xD;
             therapy, must be willing to undergo serial lumbar puncture to obtain cerebrospinal&#xD;
             fluid (CSF), and must be scheduled to undergo sedated MRIs. Local anesthesia for&#xD;
             spinal tap is also allowed. Evidence of progression is not required so that ONC201 may&#xD;
             be administered to patients in the maintenance setting or to patients with recurrent&#xD;
             disease. No more than two prior episodes of recurrence from radiotherapy and/or&#xD;
             chemotherapy are allowed. Use of bevacizumab solely for treatment of radiation&#xD;
             necrosis, pseudoprogression, or treatment effect will not be considered a recurrence.&#xD;
             Spinal tap should not be performed if treating clinician or lumbar puncture&#xD;
             proceduralist has concern of signs of elevated intracranial pressure, including recent&#xD;
             worsening in headache or somnolence.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Arm E: Patients with glioma who are positive for the H3 K27M mutation (positive&#xD;
             testing in CLIA laboratory) or have diagnosed diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma (DIPG),&#xD;
             defined as tumors with a pontine epicenter and diffuse involvement of the pons, are&#xD;
             eligible with or without histologic confirmation. Patients must be 2-12 weeks from&#xD;
             completion of first-line radiation. Evidence of progression is not required so that&#xD;
             ONC201 may be administered to patients in the maintenance setting or to patients with&#xD;
             recurrent disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Arm F:&#xD;
&#xD;
             Pediatric patients with histologically confirmed diagnosis of high-grade glioma in any&#xD;
             tumor sample with a known histone H3 K27M mutation identified by IHC or DNA sequencing&#xD;
             test performed in a CLIA setting. Evidence of progressive disease on contrast-enhanced&#xD;
             brain MRI as defined by RANO-HGG criteria is required. Patients must have had previous&#xD;
             therapy with at least radiotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Karnofsky ≥ 50 for patients ≥ 16 years of age, and Lansky ≥ 50 for patients &lt; 16 years&#xD;
             of age. For Arm F, Karnofsky ≥ 60 for patients ≥ 16 years of age, and Lansky ≥ 60 for&#xD;
             patients &lt; 16 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. From the projected start of scheduled study treatment, the following time periods must&#xD;
             have elapsed: 5 half-lives from any investigational agent, 4 weeks from cytotoxic&#xD;
             therapy (except 23 days for temozolomide and 6 weeks from nitrosoureas), 6 weeks from&#xD;
             antibodies, or 4 weeks (or 5 half-lives, whichever is shorter) from other anti-tumor&#xD;
             therapies. For patients who have received radiotherapy, patients in any arm must be at&#xD;
             least 2 weeks from the completion of local palliative radiotherapy (re-irradiation for&#xD;
             progressive disease or upfront radiation at initial diagnosis). For Arm F, patients&#xD;
             must be at least 90 days from prior radiation to the first dose of ONC201unless the&#xD;
             progressive lesion is outside of the high-dose radiation target volume or there is&#xD;
             unequivocal evidence of progressive tumor on a biopsy specimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Adequate organ function defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
             Bone Marrow:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Peripheral absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1000/mm3 and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm3 (transfusion independent, defined as not receiving&#xD;
                  platelet transfusions for at least 7 days prior to enrollment).&#xD;
&#xD;
             Renal Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
             • Creatinine clearance or radioisotope glomerular filtration rate (GFR) ≥&#xD;
             70mL/min/1.73 m2 or normal serum creatinine based on age as shown below or GFR &gt;&#xD;
             70ml/min/1.73m^2: Age &lt; 5 years: 0.8 mg/dL maximum Age 5 to &lt; 10 years: 1.0 mg/dL&#xD;
             maximum Age 10 to &lt; 15 years: 1.2 mg/dL maximum Age &gt; 15 years: 1.5 mg/dL maximum&#xD;
&#xD;
             Liver Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total Bilirubin (sum of conjugated + unconjugated) ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of&#xD;
                  institutional normal and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  SGPT (ALT) ≤ 110 U/L and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum albumin ≥ 2 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Neurologic Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
             • Patients with seizure disorder may be enrolled if seizure disorder is well&#xD;
             controlled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Ability to understand a written informed consent document, and the willingness to sign&#xD;
             it. Assent will be obtained when appropriate based on the subjects age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. All adverse events Grade &gt; 1 related to prior therapies (chemotherapy, radiotherapy,&#xD;
             and/or surgery) must be resolved to grade 1 or baseline, except for alopecia and&#xD;
             sensory neuropathy Grade ≤ 2, or other Grade ≤ 2 not constituting a safety risk based&#xD;
             on investigator's judgment, are acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. For patients post pubertal: Female patients must agree to use effective contraception&#xD;
             during the period of the trial and for at least 90 days after completion of treatment.&#xD;
             Male patients must be surgically sterile or must agree to use effective contraception&#xD;
             during the period of the trial and for at least 90 days after completion of treatment.&#xD;
             The decision of effective contraception will be based on the judgment of the principal&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Corticosteroid dose must be stable or decreasing for at least 3 days prior to the&#xD;
             baseline CT or MRI scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. MRI brain and entire spine MRI within 14 days prior to start of study drug for Arms A,&#xD;
             B, C, E, F and G. Subjects undergoing screening for Arm D must have an MRI of brain&#xD;
             and entire spine within 3 months prior to start of study drug. Subjects in Arm D will&#xD;
             have a baseline MRI of brain and spine with lumbar puncture after study consent is&#xD;
             signed and other eligibility criteria are fulfilled.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. For Arms A, B, C, D, F and G: Ability to swallow and retain orally administered&#xD;
             capsules.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Archival tumor specimen: Subjects in all arms must submit at least 5 unstained slides&#xD;
             from a tumor specimen that harbors H3 K27M mutation if archival tissue is available.&#xD;
             For subjects in Arms A, B, E or G, if no archival tumor tissue is available, or if H3&#xD;
             K27M status of tumor is unknown, then subjects must agree to submit a post-mortem&#xD;
             biopsy specimen. Subjects in Arm C do not require prior tumor biopsy or confirmation&#xD;
             of the presence of the H3 K27M mutation. Subjects in Arm D must have confirmation of&#xD;
             the presence of the H3 K27M mutation in any glioma sample prior to enrollment.&#xD;
             Subjects in Arm F must submit at least 5 unstained slides from a tumor specimen that&#xD;
             harbors H3 K27M mutation. Note that the H3 K27M mutation is often reported as H3 K28M&#xD;
             in gene sequencing assays.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. For Arms A, B, D, E, F and G: Evidence of diffuse leptomeningeal disease or evidence&#xD;
             of CSF dissemination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Current or planned participation in a study of another investigational agent or using&#xD;
             an investigational device.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to ONC201 or its excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with&#xD;
             study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any known clinically significant active infection including bacterial, fungal or viral&#xD;
             including hepatitis B (HBV), hepatitis C (HCV) or any underlying disease or in the&#xD;
             recent past which could compromise enrollment and safety of the patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Known history of cardiac arrhythmias including atrial fibrillation, tachyarrhythmias&#xD;
             or bradycardia, unless arrhythmia is controlled and after Cardiology has cleared&#xD;
             patient to receive ONC201. Receiving therapeutic agents known to prolong QT interval&#xD;
             will be excluded, however the use of Zofran is permitted. History of CHF, or MI or&#xD;
             stroke in the last 3 months will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Active illicit drug use or diagnosis of alcoholism.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Known additional malignancy that is progressing or requires active treatment within 3&#xD;
             years of start of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Concomitant use of potent CYP3A4/5 inhibitors during the treatment phase of the study&#xD;
             and within 72 hours prior to starting study drug administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Concomitant use of potent CYP3A4/5 inducers, which include enzyme inducing&#xD;
             antiepileptic drugs (EIAEDs) (see Appendix B), during the treatment phase of the study&#xD;
             and within 2 weeks prior to starting treatment. Concurrent dexamethasone is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. For Arm F: Exclusively non-contrast-enhancing disease or primary malignant lesion&#xD;
             located in the pons or spinal cord.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. For Arm F: Atypical non-astrocytic histologies such as ependymoma, ganglioma and&#xD;
             pleomorphic xanthoastrocytoma, pilocytic astrocytoma, or pilocytic astrocytoma and&#xD;
             subependymal giant cell astrocytoma (SEGA).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Prior treatment with ONC201&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Samuel Ramage, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>19198061074</phone>
    <email>sramage@chimerix.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Tabatha Rodebaugh</last_name>
    <email>TRodebaugh@chimerix.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCSF, Benioff Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94158</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pediatric Neuro-Oncology Clinical Trial Inquiries</last_name>
      <email>PedsNeuroOncClinicalTrials@ucsf.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Cassie Kline, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sabine Mueller, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Miami Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33176</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yazmin Odia, MD, MS</last_name>
      <phone>786-596-2000</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Yazmin Odia, MD, MS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Healthcare of Atlanta, Emory University School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tobey MacDonald, MD</last_name>
      <phone>404-785-1112</phone>
      <email>AflacDevTReferral@choa.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tobey MacDonald, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Michigan Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carl Koschmann, MD</last_name>
      <phone>734-936-9814</phone>
      <email>ckoschma@umich.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Carl Koschmann, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>New York University</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10016</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sharon Gardner, MD</last_name>
      <phone>646-929-7870</phone>
      <email>Sharon.Gardner@nyumc.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sharon Gardner, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cincinnati</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>45229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maryam Fouladi, MD</last_name>
      <phone>513-636-2799</phone>
      <email>cancer@cchmc.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Maryam Fouladi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Soumen Khatua, MD</last_name>
      <phone>713-792-2121</phone>
      <email>SKhatua@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Wafik Zaky, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Soumen Kahtua, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seattle Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98105</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lindsey Jackson</last_name>
      <email>cbdcintake@seattlechildrens.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nicholas Vitanza, MD PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 23, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 29, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 31, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diffuse Intrinsic Pontine Glioma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>TIC10 compound</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

