<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03417765</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GLY-211-2017</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03417765</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety, Tolerability, PK/PD of FE 203799 in Adults With Lymphomas</brief_title>
  <official_title>Double-blind, Placebo Controlled, Ascending Dose, Randomized Phase 1B/2A Study, Investigating Safety, Tolerability, PK/PD of FE 203799 in Lymphoma Patients, Undergoing Myeloablative Chemotherapy Before Autologous Transplantation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GlyPharma Therapeutics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>VectivBio AG</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VectivBio AG</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      RATIONALE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The integrity of the intestinal mucosa is a key factor for the preservation of a normal gut&#xD;
      function. Damage of the epithelium (i.e. by chemotherapy) results in significant cellular and&#xD;
      molecular alterations that ultimately lead to intestinal dysfunction/failure. This intestinal&#xD;
      dysfunction manifests as several pathological processes, such as inability to absorb&#xD;
      nutrients, intestinal inflammation, immune system dysregulation, and disequilibrium of normal&#xD;
      intestinal microbiota leading to increased risk of infection due to bacterial translocation&#xD;
      and septicaemia. Gastrointestinal (GI) mucositis is a well-known, frequent and debilitating&#xD;
      side effect of most anticancer regimens with a very high incidence in hemato-oncology. The&#xD;
      most common symptoms are nausea, vomiting, weight loss, abdominal cramps and pain, diarrhea,&#xD;
      and electrolyte imbalance. Patients may also experience ulceration/bleeding and injury of the&#xD;
      lining of the entire gastrointestinal tract from the esophagus to the colon. Currently no&#xD;
      therapy is available for the prevention or treatment of GI intestinal injury. Treatment of&#xD;
      related symptoms is limited to supportive measures to decrease diarrhea and to preventive&#xD;
      antibiotic therapy. The GLP-2 analogue, FE 203799, has a favorable pharmacology profile for&#xD;
      clinical development in the intended therapeutic indication of myeloablative&#xD;
      chemotherapy-induced GI damage. The data collected from animal studies has shown that FE&#xD;
      203799 stimulates the proliferation of the intestinal epithelium and protects the GI mucosa&#xD;
      from chemotherapy-induced injury. Hence, the primary pharmacologic activity of FE 203799&#xD;
      would promote a healthy GI microenvironment, thus preventing intestinal dysfunction and&#xD;
      related complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PURPOSE: Prevention by FE 203799 of chemotherapy-induced intestinal damage and related&#xD;
      complications in patients with lymphoma receiving Melphalan based (BEAM) myeloablative&#xD;
      conditioning regimen followed by hematopoietic stem cell transplantation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Multi-center, double-blind, placebo-controlled, ascending dose, randomized Phase IB/2A study&#xD;
      to assess the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetic (PK) and pharmacodynamic (PD) profile of&#xD;
      s.c. FE 203799 in patients diagnosed with Hodgkin's lymphoma (HL) or non-Hodgkin's lymphoma&#xD;
      (NHL) undergoing Melphalan-based myeloablative chemotherapy (BEAM) followed by autologous&#xD;
      human stem cell transplantation (AHSCT). In addition, the impact of FE 203799 on&#xD;
      post-transplantation outcomes will be assessed. These outcomes include assessment of&#xD;
      intestinal mucosal injury and inflammation, incidence of infection and bacteremia,&#xD;
      development of neutropenic fever, assessment of nutritional parameters, modification of the&#xD;
      composition of the gut microbiome, recovery of the hematopoietic system and quality of life.&#xD;
      More specifically:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - PRIMARY OBJECTIVE: Safety and tolerability of s.c. FE 203799&#xD;
&#xD;
      - SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Determine the PK profile and dose-effect of s.c. FE 203799.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Determine the PD profile of s.c. FE 203799, based on the plasma concentration of&#xD;
           citrulline (indicative of intestinal mass) and of C-Reactive Protein (CRP) (indicative&#xD;
           of inflammation).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Determine the dose/response (PK/PD) relationship of s.c. FE 203799.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Determine the impact of treatment with s.c. FE 203799 on the incidence and severity of&#xD;
           chemotherapy induced intestinal toxicity, as assessed by both symptomatic and visual&#xD;
           manifestations of mucosal injury and associated complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Assess the effect of s.c. FE 203799 on the prevention of development of neutropenic&#xD;
           fever and bacteremia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODOLOGY - STUDY DESIGN The patient population will consist of adult female and male&#xD;
      Hodgkin's or non-Hodgkin's lymphomas patients who are eligible to receive BEAM as&#xD;
      conditioning regimen followed by autologous type AHSCT using peripheral blood or bone marrow&#xD;
      stem cells. At the time of enrollment, patients must be in complete or partial remission&#xD;
      following their most recent anti-neoplastic therapy. Patients are required to have available&#xD;
      a cryopreserved autologous stem cell graft with a minimum CD34+ cell dose of 2 x 106&#xD;
      cells/kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three ascending dose levels of FE 203799 will be investigated (5 mg, 10 mg and 25 mg), with&#xD;
      16 patients required per dose cohort. Patients in each dose cohort will be randomized to FE&#xD;
      203799 vs. Placebo in a 3:1 ratio (12 patients per dose level receiving FE 203799, and 4&#xD;
      patients receiving Placebo), in a double-blind manner. Randomization will occur during the&#xD;
      screening period upon confirmation that the patient has met all inclusion and exclusion&#xD;
      criteria. A total of 48 subjects, completing the study, is targeted for enrollment. The study&#xD;
      will be conducted in approximately 10 clinical centers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility will be determined at the Screening Visit following signature of the informed&#xD;
      consent form (ICF). The inclusion and exclusion criteria will be used to qualify the patient&#xD;
      for study entry. Within each cohort, patients will receive 4 doses of the Study Drug (FE&#xD;
      203799 or Placebo). As such, patients will be required to be dosed with the Study Drug the&#xD;
      day prior the initiation of the BEAM regimen and subsequently on a weekly basis for 3&#xD;
      consecutive weeks after initiation of chemotherapy. Assessments performed prior to the first&#xD;
      dose, will be considered as Baseline. Serial blood samples for determination of the plasma&#xD;
      concentration of FE 20799/Placebo, as well as the plasma levels of citrulline and C-Reactive&#xD;
      protein (CRP) will be obtained at pre-specified time points. During the Study, patients will&#xD;
      be hospitalized during the duration of the conditioning chemotherapy to approximately 3 or 4&#xD;
      weeks post-transplantation depending on their recovery and physical condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients who received at least one treatment, will be required to return to the hospital&#xD;
      for the End of Study Visit (Day 30 ±5 post-transplantation) and for two additional follow-up&#xD;
      safety visits on Days 45 (±5) and 100 (±5) post-transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Data Monitoring Committee (DMC) will convene at pre-determined timepoints, or as needed.&#xD;
      The grading of adverse events (AEs) will be based on the Common Terminology Criteria for&#xD;
      Adverse Events version 4.03 (CTCAE v4.03) (Grade 1 to 5).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Business decision&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Placebo-control, ascending dose</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double-blind</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of treatment-emergent adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -8 to Day 100</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events as assessed by CTCAE v4.03</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum observed plasma concentration (Cmax) of FE 203799</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -8 to Day 13</time_frame>
    <description>Cmax in ng/ml</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative area under the plasma concentration (AUC) time curve from 0-168 hours of FE 203799</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -8 to Day 13</time_frame>
    <description>AUC0-168 in ng*hr/ml</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative area under the plasma concentration (AUC) from time zero to infinity of FE 203799</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -8 to Day 13</time_frame>
    <description>AUC0-inf in ng*hr/ml</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal elimination half-life (T1/2) of FE 203799</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -8 to Day 13</time_frame>
    <description>T1/2 in hours</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent total body clearance (CL) of the drug from plasma of FE 203799</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -8 to Day 13</time_frame>
    <description>CL in ml/hr</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent volume of distribution (Vz) of FE 203799 during terminal phase</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -8 to Day 13</time_frame>
    <description>Vz in ml</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Biomarker assessment for gut healing</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -8 to Day -1, Day 1 to Day 14 and Day 30</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma concentration of citrulline (ng/ml)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Biomarker assessment for gut inflammation</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -8 to Day -1, Day 1 to Day 14 and Day 30</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma concentration of C-Reactive Protein (ng/ml)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of infection - Incidence and duration of fever</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -8 to Day 20 and Day 30</time_frame>
    <description>Body temperature ≥38.2oC</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of infection - Incidence and duration of neutropenic fever</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -8 to Day 20 and Day 30</time_frame>
    <description>Development of fever when absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≤ 0.5 x 109 and body temperature ≥ 38.2 ◦C for two consecutive values over a 30 minute period of time; or ANC &lt; 0.5 x 109 and body temperature ≥ 38.5◦C at any single timepoint</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of microbiologically detected infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 5 to Day 15</time_frame>
    <description>Blood cultures once daily</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of gastrointestinal mucositis and related clinical symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -8 to Day 20 and Day 30</time_frame>
    <description>Grading as by the CTCAE v4.03</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of gastrointestinal mucositis by video-capsule endoscopy</measure>
    <time_frame>Day -8, Day 6 and Day 20</time_frame>
    <description>Gastrointestinal damage assessed by the Lewis Score; this is evaluation of villous edema, ulcers and stenosis graded collectively; Normal &lt; 135, Mild 135-790, Moderate - severe ≥790</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of nutrients absorption</measure>
    <time_frame>Days -8, -1, 6, 13 and 30</time_frame>
    <description>Body weight (kg)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of nutrients absorption</measure>
    <time_frame>Days -8, 0, 3, 6, 9, 12, 15, 18</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of duration of parenteral nutrition (L)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of nutrients absorption</measure>
    <time_frame>Days -8, 0, 3, 6, 9, 12, 15, 18</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of caloric intake (calories)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbiome composition</measure>
    <time_frame>Once a week over 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Determination of microbial populations by genomic analysis (relative abundance of taxonomic levels)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to neutrophil and platelet engraftment</measure>
    <time_frame>Day-8 and then on Days -2, 5, 12 and 30</time_frame>
    <description>Hematological analysis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Days -8, -1, 6, 13 and 30</time_frame>
    <description>Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-Bone Marrow Transplant (FACT-BMT) questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin's, Adult</condition>
  <condition>Lymphoma, Hodgkin's, Adult</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort A: 5 mg (FE 203799/Placebo)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drug: FE 203799 Drug: BEAM Procedure: myeloablative chemotherapy Procedure: autologous stem cell transplantation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort B: 10 mg (FE 203799/Placebo)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drug: FE 203799 Drug: BEAM Procedure: myeloablative chemotherapy Procedure: autologous stem cell transplantation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort C: 25 mg (FE 203799/Placebo)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drug: FE 203799 Drug: BEAM Procedure: myeloablative chemotherapy Procedure: autologous stem cell transplantation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>FE 203799</intervention_name>
    <description>GLP-2 analogue, once weekly, subcutaneous administration</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort A: 5 mg (FE 203799/Placebo)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort B: 10 mg (FE 203799/Placebo)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort C: 25 mg (FE 203799/Placebo)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adult male and non-pregnant or lactating female patients diagnosed with Hodgkin's&#xD;
             lymphoma (HL) or non- Hodgkin's lymphoma (NHL; T- or B-cell variants) based on&#xD;
             histological or cytological evidence.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients are eligible to receive myeloablative chemotherapy as per center eligibility&#xD;
             criteria, followed by AHSCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients between 18 years and 65 years of age with a Hematopoietic Cell Transplant-&#xD;
             Co-morbidity Index (HCT-CI) ≤5. Patients between 65 years and 70 years will be&#xD;
             eligible if their HCT-CI score is ≤3.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients, or their legal representatives, must have the ability to read, understand&#xD;
             and provide written informed consent prior to the initiation of any study related&#xD;
             procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients must have chemo-sensitive disease and be in partial or complete remission&#xD;
             following the most recent anti-neoplastic therapy regimen, according to the Lugano&#xD;
             revision of the International Working Group (IWG) response criteria [1].&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients must have available a cryopreserved autologous hematopoietic stem cell graft&#xD;
             containing ≥ 2.0 x 106 cryopreserved CD34+ cells/kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients must have a Karnofsky score ≥ 70%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients must have adequate hepatic function as evidenced by bilirubin ≤ upper limit&#xD;
             of normal (ULN), unless felt to be related to Gilbert's syndrome or hemolysis;&#xD;
             patients must also have AST and ALT ≤ 1.5 x ULN and alkaline phosphatase ≤ 2.5 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients must have an estimated or measured creatinine clearance ≥ 30 ml/min/1.73 m2&#xD;
             by the Cockcroft-Gault equation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients must have left ventricular ejection fraction ≥ 50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients must have forced vital capacity (FVC), forced expiratory volume in 1 second&#xD;
             (FEV1) and diffusing capacity corrected for hemoglobin (DLCOc) ≥ 50% of predicted.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients must have recovered from the effects of any prior chemotherapy, radiotherapy&#xD;
             or surgery; for patients who have been on monoclonal antibody therapy, at least one&#xD;
             half-life or 4 weeks (whichever is longer) should have elapsed prior to the first&#xD;
             scheduled day of dosing with FE 203799.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. A female recipient of childbearing potential must meet the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Participant has a negative pregnancy test at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Participant agrees to use one of the accepted contraceptive regimens from at&#xD;
                  least 14 days prior to the first administration of the Study Drug, during the&#xD;
                  study and for at least 90 days after the last dose of the Study Drug. An&#xD;
                  acceptable method of contraception includes one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Abstinence from heterosexual intercourse&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Systemic contraceptives (birth control pills, injectable/implant/insertable&#xD;
                       hormonal birth control products, transdermal patch)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Intrauterine device (with or without hormones)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Diaphragm with spermicidal gel&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Condom with spermicide gel&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. A male patient, with sexual partners who are pregnant, possibly pregnant, or who could&#xD;
             become pregnant, agrees to use one of the accepted contraceptive regimens throughout&#xD;
             the entire duration of the study and until at least 3 months after the last drug&#xD;
             administration. An acceptable method of contraception includes one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Abstinence from heterosexual intercourse&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Condom with spermicide&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient is unable or unwilling to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who are unable to comply with the treatment protocol including appropriate&#xD;
             supportive care, follow-up and tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with known hypersensitivity to FE 203799, or any related products (including&#xD;
             excipients of the formulations) as well as severe hypersensitivity reactions to any&#xD;
             drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with an active infection or with a fever ≥38.5oC within 3 days of the first&#xD;
             scheduled day of dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients who had an autologous stem cell transplant within 24 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients who had an available cryopreserved autologous graft with a CD34+ cell count&#xD;
             of &lt; 2 x 106/kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients undergoing AHSCT for conditions other than lymphoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Presence of a malignancy other than the one for which the transplant is being&#xD;
             performed (except for baso-cellular skin carcinoma).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients who are receiving investigational therapies or who have been treated with&#xD;
             investigational therapies or investigational devices within 30 days prior to the first&#xD;
             scheduled day of dosing with FE 203799.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with cardiovascular congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris,&#xD;
             cardiac arrhythmias requiring a pacemaker; myocardial infarction within the past six&#xD;
             months; stroke within the past 6 months; or uncontrolled hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients with mean QTcF values of &gt;450 msec (in males) or &gt;470 msec (in females)&#xD;
             following ECGs conducted in triplicate 5 minutes apart from each other; patients who&#xD;
             are known to have congenital prolonged QT syndromes, including patients who are&#xD;
             already on medication known to cause prolonged QT intervals on ECG.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Presence of out-of-range cardiac interval (PR &lt; 110 msec, PR &gt; 220 msec, QRS &lt; 60&#xD;
             msec, QRS &gt;119 msec) on the screening ECG or other clinically significant ECG&#xD;
             abnormalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients with history or presence of GI tract cancer, polyps, ulcerative colitis,&#xD;
             Crohn's disease, coeliac disease, tropical sprue, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Presence of active pancreatic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Presence of active liver disease (i.e. cirrhosis; bilirubin &gt; ULN; transaminases &gt; 1.5&#xD;
             x ULN; alkaline phosphatase &gt; 2.5 x ULN).&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Presence of autoimmune disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Patients with suicidal tendency or clinically relevant psychiatric diseases or&#xD;
             substance abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Positive results to HIV Ag/Ab Combo, Hepatitis B surface Antigen (HbsAG (B) (hepatitis&#xD;
             B)) or anti-Hepatitis C Virus (HCV (C)) tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Any abnormal condition or laboratory result that is considered by the PI capable of&#xD;
             altering patient's condition or study outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Patients who are pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Patients who are unwilling to use appropriate contraception.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Silvy Lachance, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hôpital Maisonneuve Rosemont, Montréal, QC, Canada</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Micheline St-John, BSc</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>JSS Research</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>October 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 13, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 30, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 31, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 22, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 22, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>gastrointestinal mucositis</keyword>
  <keyword>myeloablative chemotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>autologous transplantation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hodgkin Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

