<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03413553</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>100100</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03413553</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Evaluation of Soft Tissue Augmentation Using CTG and PRF Around Immediately Placed Dental Implants Versus Immediate Implant Alone in Esthetic Zone .</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Evaluation of Soft Tissue Augmentation Using Connective Tissue Graft and Platelet Rich Fibrin Around Immediately Placed Dental Implants Versus Immediate Implant Alone in Esthetic Zone</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Abeer hassan sharafuddin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main hypothesis to be certified is that the addition of Subepithelial Connective Tissue&#xD;
      Graft (SCTG) and Platelet rich Fibrin (PRF) to immediately placed implants will not&#xD;
      significantly differ from immediately placed implant alone as regard gingival tissue&#xD;
      stability.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      -  The primary objective Evaluation of connective tissue graft and platelet rich fibrin&#xD;
           combined with immediate implant placement as an innovative option for more pink esthetic&#xD;
           score, versus immediate implant alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The secondary objective Evaluation of patient satisfaction, width of keratinized mucosa,&#xD;
           crestal bone level after the use of platelet rich fibrin and connective tissue graft&#xD;
           combined with immediate implant versus immediate implant alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
           8. Trial design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A Randomized clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Uni center: A trial will be carried out in one hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Equal randomization: participants with equal probabilities for intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Positive controlled: Both groups receiving treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Parallel group study: Each group of patients receives a single treatment simultaneously.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Two assessors will assess the result (1st Assessor Perryhan.M.) &amp; (2nd Assessor Nada&#xD;
           Farouk)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: Participants, interventions, and outcomes 9. Study setting: This study will be&#xD;
      carried out on patients attending outpatient clinics in Oral Medicine, Diagnosis and&#xD;
      Periodontology Department- Faculty of Dentistry Cairo University-Egypt. Post graduate&#xD;
      Periodontology clinic 1st floor old section. Sirona dental units with LED light.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preoperative measures (for both groups):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Phase I therapy (Supragingival scaling, subgingival debridement and oral hygiene&#xD;
           instructions) should apply for the two groups before any surgical procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  4 weeks later both groups will be examined to determine patient compliance with oral&#xD;
           hygiene procedures (tooth brushing twice daily and chlorhexidine HCL 1.25% mouthwash*&#xD;
           twice daily).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Radiographic measurements for marginal bone changes will be performed at baseline ( time&#xD;
           of implant placement), three months and six months after implant placement or crown&#xD;
           construction. Intra oral periapical radiographs performed with paralleling technique&#xD;
           will facilitate bone level measurement on distal and mesial aspects of the implant . The&#xD;
           highest coronal area of healing abutment will be recorded as a static reference line.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Width of keratinized mucosa measured at the line of mucogingival junction to the groove&#xD;
           of free gingiva by Williams graduated periodontal probe 1 using the roll technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ttissue biotype measured after anasthesia application and percing the keratinized&#xD;
           gingiva perpendicular to the tooth against the alveolar bone. using Williams graduated&#xD;
           periodontal probe .&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Crestal bone level at the mesial and distal side of each implant was measured with using&#xD;
           Kodak D speed films with a reference point before and after the surgical procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Study casts for case study will be fabricated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CBCT scan using OnDemand 3D ** will be performed to record preoperative bone height and width&#xD;
      measurements used to determine implant diameter, length, position&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgical phase :&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The same operator will perform all procedures under local anesthesia (4% articaine with&#xD;
           1/200 000 adrenaline Solution) ***, using a local infiltration technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Atraumatic extraction will be performed for target tooth using periotome2.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Once the tooth/root is luxated, a dental forceps may be used gently without harming the&#xD;
           socket walls for getting the tooth out of the socket.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Iintrasulcular incisions will be performed Using #15 blade to elevate the proximal&#xD;
           interdental papillae and marginal gingiva then the periosteal elevator is used to&#xD;
           reflect the flap to expose the crestal bone around the socket which allow the direct&#xD;
           vizion and evaluation of the crestal bone level.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Once the tooth/root stump is pulled up a dental forceps (Bilot) should be used carefully&#xD;
           and ovoid harming the socket walls .&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The socket completely debride using surgical bone curette,. appropriate irrigation of&#xD;
           the socket perform .&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the test group:&#xD;
&#xD;
      o Full thickness flap will be performed using mucoperiosteal flap raised up to the&#xD;
      muco-gingival junction, partial thickness flap is then elevated in order to facilitate&#xD;
      coronal advancing of the flap.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the control group:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  (Full thickness flap will be done on the buccal and palatal area to expose the crestal&#xD;
           bone only).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Measuring the root length and width of the extracted tooth and using the cone beam CT&#xD;
           the dimensions of the implants will be identified.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Tapered self drilling self tapping tapered dental implant(s) (JD Evolution® S, or JD&#xD;
           Evolution® Plus+ or JD ICON® Ultra S, 2-piece implants)* are going to be placed till the&#xD;
           implant's platform is 2 mm apical to the crest of the ridge.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cover screws are attached to the implants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention for test group :&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At the time of implant placement:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Preparation of recipient site:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The graft will be placed on the top of the implant, while trying to augment the buccal&#xD;
           soft tissue&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Preparation of donor site: A subepithelial connective tissue graft will be obtained from&#xD;
           the palate. Using 15 C scalpels the graft will be harvested down to bone. A single&#xD;
           incision parallel to the gingival margin will be performed to harvest a subepithelial&#xD;
           connective tissue graft, including the periosteum attached to the bone and stabilized by&#xD;
           horizontal mattress 6-0 sutures, to the periosteum with an absorbable suture (Vicryl&#xD;
           6-0)* (26-29)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  SCTG should be slightly pressed with wet gauze for 10 minutes to decrease blood clot and&#xD;
           dead space formation between the graft and the bone.(29)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  PRF preparation and placement: The PRF will be prepared immediately just before&#xD;
           placement at the surgical site.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  For the PRF preparation10 ml of blood will be obtained from the antecubital vein and&#xD;
           transferred to the free anticoagulant test-tube .The blood sample will be immediately&#xD;
           centrifuged at 3000 rpm for 10-12 min. After centrifugation fibrin clot will be squeezed&#xD;
           between gauze-piece to obtain PRF membrane.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The centrifuge machine should be close to the operatory site and, time should be limited&#xD;
           between the preparation of PRF and its placement to create maximum regenerative&#xD;
           potential. (32-33) The fibrin clot procured is then squeezed in a special dish and it&#xD;
           will adapted over the connective tissue graft .&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After grafting, flaps will be sutured with a non-absorbable polyamide suture (Assut&#xD;
           suturs® 5-0, Switzerland)** at both sites, submerging the implants, graft and PRF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention for control group (Group B):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Implant placement as in manufacturer instruction.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient in both groups will receive restoration after implant being placed by 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post-operative care:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Post-surgically patients will be instructed for cold therapy immediately after the&#xD;
           surgery. After 12 hours 875 mg of&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Amoxicillin 1 g capsules 1 hour prior to the surgery for prophylaxis then every 6 hours&#xD;
           after the surgery and continue for 5 days (Beecham Manufactured in Egypt and marketed in&#xD;
           Egypt).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Brufen 600 mg once daily (Sanofi Aventis manufactured in Egypt and marketed in Egypt).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Instructions in the first week, no brushing or flossing at the gingival margin and no&#xD;
           chewing of hard food on the surgical site but oral hygiene is a must for the other&#xD;
           sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Sutures will be removed after 7-14 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Follow up regimen (evaluating same preoperative parameters) will be entailed: 1, 3 and 6&#xD;
           months after final restoration to monitor and evaluate the soft tissue changes.&#xD;
           Postoperative intraoral photographs and, periapical radiographs will be taken with the&#xD;
           paralleling technique using customized x-ray holders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up (T1, T2):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pink esthetic score : measured by clinical evaluation. The PES contains the following&#xD;
           seven variables: mesial papilla, distal papilla, soft-tissue level, soft tissue contour,&#xD;
           alveolar process deficiency, soft-tissue color and texture at the facial aspect of the&#xD;
           implant site. It is measured as score (0-14), 0 is the lowest score and 14 is the&#xD;
           highest score. Each single-tooth and implant will be photographed two blind observers of&#xD;
           different specialty (one general practionar, one periodontist) evaluated all&#xD;
           photographs. Observers applied the PES index for the soft tissue around the implants.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  - Patient satisfaction: The questionnaire a achieved 6 months after placement of the&#xD;
           final restoration Patient questionnaire contains all satisfaction score with a Visual&#xD;
           Analogue Scale (range 0-10) and a number of questions related with final restoration and&#xD;
           the peri-implant mucosa (score 0-1)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Healing Index: Obtained Healing Index on the 1st , 2nd and 3rd week post - surgery. The&#xD;
           HI scores healing on the basis of the bleeding , redness, granulation tissue,&#xD;
           suppuration and epithelialization . It's given 1 to 5 . 1 related with very poor healing&#xD;
           and 5 related with excellent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient should be checked once weekly for I month figuring out any infection or undesirable&#xD;
      soft tissue color/texture change.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Prosthetic phase (T3):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After 6 months radiographic CBCT scans will be performed (T3).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Implant exposure procedure will be performed under local anesthesia. Healing collars&#xD;
           will be inserted for 1 week then replaced by permanent abutments.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Impressions* will be taken and fixed prosthesis will be fabricated accordingly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Criteria for discontinuing intervention:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Bone plate fracture.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Implant mobility.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Poor implant positioning. 12. c. Criteria for modifying intervention: Flap dehiscence:&#xD;
           Irrigation with chlorhexidine (1%) will be carried out with weekly follow up visits till&#xD;
           flap closure with normal healing pattern.&#xD;
&#xD;
           12. d. Strategies to improve adherence to intervention protocol: Patient preparation in&#xD;
           terms of improving oral hygiene and first phase therapy procedures will be performed for&#xD;
           patient to build doctor trust. Complete information concerning the protocol will be&#xD;
           provided and simplified to the patient with reasoning of all the steps included as the&#xD;
           importance of the follow up visits and home medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
           12. e. Relevant concomitant care and interventions that are permitted or prohibited&#xD;
           during the trial: Postoperatively the patients will use analgesics, oral antibiotic&#xD;
           therapy, and 0.12% chlorhexidine gluconate mouthwash for at least one week.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 15, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 30, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pink Esthatic score</measure>
    <time_frame>should be measured after 6 months below implant and graft placement</time_frame>
    <description>measured by clinical evaluation. The PES contains the following seven variables: mesial papilla, distal papilla, soft-tissue level, soft tissue contour, alveolar process deficiency, soft-tissue color and texture at the facial aspect of the implant site.(26) It is measured as score (0-14), 0 is the lowest score and 14 is the highest score</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Soft Tissue Augmentation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>patient will receive immediate implant alone.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>immediate implant combined with connective tissue graft and platelet rich fibrin .&#xD;
.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>immediate implant</intervention_name>
    <description>Patient will receive immediate implant alone.</description>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>post extraction immediate implant.</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>connective tissue graft</intervention_name>
    <description>patient will receive immediate implant with connective tissue graft and platelet rich fibrin</description>
    <arm_group_label>intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>sub epithelial graft</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>platelet rich fibrin</intervention_name>
    <description>patient will recieve immediate implant combined with connective tissue graft and platelet rich fibrin</description>
    <arm_group_label>intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>platelet concentrate</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        • Inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age: 18-60.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with single or multiple non-restorable teeth in anterior or premolar area.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient consent approval and signing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intact labial/buccal bone plate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should be free from untreated periodontal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The recipient site of the implant is free from any pathological condition&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smokers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic disease that contraindicates implant placement or surgical procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No or poor patient's compliance.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychological problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pathology at the site of intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy females.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Abeer Hassan Sharafuddin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 18, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 26, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 29, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Abeer hassan sharafuddin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant lecturer of Oral Diagnosis, Oral Medicine and Periodontology, Queen Arwa University.- yemen</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>immediate implant</keyword>
  <keyword>connective tissue graft</keyword>
  <keyword>platelet rich fibrin</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

