<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04418895</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LCCC 1933</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04418895</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neoadjuvant Therapy for Localized Rectal Adenocarcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Biomarkers and Clinical Outcomes in Localized Rectal Adenocarcinoma Treated With Neoadjuvant Therapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>UNC Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>UNC Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a prospective, single-arm, single-center study of investigator's choice of&#xD;
      total neoadjuvant therapy (TNT) or neoadjuvant chemoradiation in locally advanced rectal&#xD;
      cancer. The standard of care for rectal adenocarcinomas that are triiodothyronine-thyroxine&#xD;
      (T3-T4) or node positive has generally been comprised of neoadjuvant chemoradiation, followed&#xD;
      by surgical resection and then adjuvant chemotherapy. More recently, TNT, comprised of&#xD;
      neoadjuvant chemotherapy and chemoradiation followed by surgical resection, has been&#xD;
      increasingly used as a standard therapy approach. While the use of TNT is increasingly&#xD;
      common, prospective study of outcomes following TNT has been limited. Moreover, there are not&#xD;
      any biomarkers known at this time that impact clinical decision-making or personalization of&#xD;
      therapy in the treatment of rectal cancer. In this study, we will collect pre-treatment&#xD;
      rectal adenocarcinoma specimens and determine clinical outcome, including pathologic complete&#xD;
      response rate, post-treatment pathologic downstaging rate, recurrence-free survival (RFS),&#xD;
      overall survival (OS) and neoadjuvant rectal score, among patients who are treated with&#xD;
      standard neoadjuvant chemoradiation or TNT, with an aim to investigate how baseline&#xD;
      biomarkers and changes in biomarkers with standard therapies may be associated with, and&#xD;
      modulate, clinical outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      At enrollment, subjects should be planned to receive either neoadjuvant chemoradiation or&#xD;
      total neoadjuvant therapy, with the choice of regimen at the discretion of treating&#xD;
      investigators. Subjects will have been staged as deemed consistent with standard of care,&#xD;
      including either a pelvic Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and/or an endorectal ultrasound,&#xD;
      and deemed to have either T3-T4 primary tumor or node-positive tumor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neoadjuvant Chemoradiation Subjects will undergo endoscopic tumor biopsy within 6 weeks of&#xD;
      the start of standard of care chemoradiation. Subjects will also have a baseline peripheral&#xD;
      blood sample collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will receive neoadjuvant chemoradiation per standard of care. This is typically&#xD;
      comprised of radiotherapy with concurrent capecitabine 825 mg/m2 by mouth (po) two times&#xD;
      daily (bid) (typically rounded to the nearest 500 mg dose) or infusional 5-fluorouracil&#xD;
      (5FU). However, dosing and administration are at the discretion of the treating medical and&#xD;
      radiation oncologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An acceptable alternative approach is short-course radiation therapy per standard of care,&#xD;
      which is typically comprised of radiotherapy, with surgery within 1 week of completion of&#xD;
      therapy or delayed for 6-8 weeks. Selection of the optimal radiation therapy approach is at&#xD;
      the discretion of the treating medical oncologist, radiation oncologist, and surgical&#xD;
      oncologist. However, generally, short-course radiation therapy is not recommended for&#xD;
      low-lying tumors less than 5 centimeters (cm) from the anal verge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Occasionally patients with inadequate response after neoadjuvant chemoradiation may be&#xD;
      recommended to proceed with subsequent consolidative chemotherapy with 5-Fluorouracil,&#xD;
      leucovorin, and oxaliplatin (mFOLFOX6) or capecitabine and oxaliplatin (CAPOX) for 16-18&#xD;
      weeks before surgical resection. This treatment is at the discretion of the treating medical&#xD;
      oncologist, radiation oncologist, and surgical oncologist. These subjects will be allowed to&#xD;
      remain on study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgery will occur approximately 4-8 weeks after chemoradiation or consolidative&#xD;
      chemotherapy, depending on clinical factors (i.e. resectability, presence or absence of&#xD;
      metastatic disease), although it may occur as soon as 1 week after completing short-course&#xD;
      radiation therapy. The timing of surgical resection after completion of neoadjuvant therapy&#xD;
      is at the discretion of the treating surgical oncologist. At the time of surgery, tumor&#xD;
      samples and peripheral blood samples for correlative studies will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects who do not receive preoperative mFOLFOX6 or CAPOX typically receive postoperative&#xD;
      adjuvant chemotherapy with a fluoropyrimidine +/- oxaliplatin for an additional 16-18 weeks&#xD;
      of therapy, if permitted based on recovery after surgical resection and post-surgical&#xD;
      performance status. This treatment is at the discretion of the treating medical oncologist.&#xD;
      Subjects will remain on study regardless of postoperative therapy administration or duration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Total Neoadjuvant Therapy Subjects will undergo endoscopic tumor biopsy within 6 weeks of the&#xD;
      start of standard of care treatment with chemotherapy. Subjects will also have a baseline&#xD;
      peripheral blood sample collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects who are intended to receive total neoadjuvant therapy will typically receive&#xD;
      chemotherapy with mFOLFOX6 or CAPOX for 16-18 weeks, followed by chemoradiation. Dosing and&#xD;
      administration are at the discretion of the primary medical and radiation oncologist.&#xD;
      Alternative subsequent approaches such as short-course radiotherapy are also acceptable at&#xD;
      the discretion of the treating medical and radiation oncologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgery will occur approximately 4-8 weeks after chemoradiation depending on clinical factors&#xD;
      (i.e. resectability, presence or absence of metastatic disease), although it may occur as&#xD;
      soon as 1 week after completing short-course radiation therapy. The timing of surgical&#xD;
      resection after completion of neoadjuvant therapy is at the discretion of the treating&#xD;
      surgical oncologist. At the time of surgery, tumor samples and peripheral blood samples for&#xD;
      correlative studies will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Duration of Therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
      The duration of therapy should be defined per the subject's standard of care. Reasons to&#xD;
      discontinue treatment may include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Disease progression&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Inter-current illness that prevents further administration of treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Unacceptable adverse event(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Subject decides to withdraw from study treatment, or&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  General or specific changes in the subject's condition render the subject unacceptable&#xD;
           for further treatment in the judgment of the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Subject has completed the treatment regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Subject is lost to follow up&#xD;
&#xD;
      Duration of Follow Up After surgery, subjects will be followed with routine surveillance at&#xD;
      the discretion of treating investigators. Subjects will be followed for survival and disease&#xD;
      status for at least 3 years after surgery or until death, whichever occurs first.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    lack of resources&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 13, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>complete pathologic response (pCR) rate</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of surgery (1- 26 weeks after completion of standard of care neoadjuvant treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Anatomic stage for rectal cancer uses the American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC) Tumor/Node/Metastasis (TNM) system, which is based on:Size of primary tumor (T) and whether it has grown into nearby areas. Spread to regional lymph nodes (N). Spread (metastasis; M) to other organs of the body. Once the T, N, and M categories have been determined, this information is combined into a prognostic group. Higher numbers mean the cancer is more advanced. Stage prefixes include &quot;c&quot; for clinical stage, &quot;p&quot; for pathological stage, and &quot;y&quot; to indicate that the clinical or pathologic classification has been determined after preoperative therapy&#xD;
Complete pathologic response is defined as no disease on pathology at resection (ypT0N0).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>pathologic down staging rate</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of surgery (1-26 weeks after completion of standard of care neoadjuvant treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as a decrease in Tumor (T) and/or Nodal (N) stage from baseline to pathologic post-treatment determination, without any increase in T, N, or M stage.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>near pathological complete response (near-pCR) rate</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of surgery (1-26 weeks after completion of standard of care neoadjuvant treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Near-pCR will be defined as minimal tumor on pathology at resection (ypT0-1 N0).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>R0 resection rate</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of surgery (1-26 weeks after completion of standard of care neoadjuvant treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>R0 resection will be defined as resection of all appreciable disease with a margin &gt; 1 millimeter (mm) distally, proximally, and radially/circumferentially.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrence Free Survival (RFS) rate</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years after surgical resection</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the time from day 1 of neoadjuvant chemotherapy until definitive local or metastatic disease recurrence or death as a result of any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS) rate</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years after surgical resection</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the time from day 1 of neoadjuvant chemotherapy until death as a result of any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median Neoadjuvant Rectal Score (NAR)</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of surgery (1-26 weeks after completion of standard of care neoadjuvant treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>With clinical T stage (cT) comprised of 1, 2, 3, or 4; pathologic T stage (pT) comprised of 0, 1, 2, 3, or 4; and pathologic N stage (pN) comprised of 0, 1, or 2 (according to AJCC clinical rectal staging criteria)., the Neoadjuvant rectal score (NAR)will be calculated after resection as follows:&#xD;
NAR = [5 pN - 3 (cT-pT) + 12]2 / 9.61&#xD;
A higher score indicates poorer prognosis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Rectal Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm: Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Investigator's choice of total neoadjuvant therapy (TNT) comprised of neoadjuvant chemotherapy and chemoradiation followed by surgical resection; or neoadjuvant chemoradiation followed by surgical resection and then adjuvant chemotherapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Chemoradiation</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will receive neoadjuvant chemoradiation per standard of care. This is typically comprised of radiotherapy of 5040 cGy (centigray) with concurrent capecitabine 825 mg/m2 by mouth (po) two times daily (bid) (typically rounded to the nearest 500 mg dose) or infusional 5-fluorouracil (5FU). However, dosing and administration are at the discretion of the treating medical and radiation oncologist.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm: Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>short course radiation therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>An acceptable alternative approach is short-course radiation therapy per standard of care, which is typically comprised of radiotherapy of 25 Gy (gray) in 5 fractions, with surgery within 1 week of completion of therapy or delayed for 6-8 weeks. Selection of the optimal radiation therapy approach is at the discretion of the treating medical oncologist, radiation oncologist, and surgical oncologist. However, generally, short-course radiation therapy is not recommended for low-lying tumors less than 5 centimeters (cm) from the anal verge.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm: Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>mFOLFOX6</intervention_name>
    <description>possible consolidative neo-adjuvant chemotherapy. This treatment is at the discretion of the treating medical oncologist, radiation oncologist, and surgical oncologist.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm: Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>leucovorin calcium (folinic acid), fluorouracil, and oxaliplatin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CAPOX</intervention_name>
    <description>possible consolidative neo-adjuvant chemotherapy. This treatment is at the discretion of the treating medical oncologist, radiation oncologist, and surgical oncologist.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm: Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Capecitabine, Oxaliplatin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>fluoropyrimidine +/- oxaliplatin</intervention_name>
    <description>possible adjuvant chemotherapy regimen. Subjects who do not receive preoperative mFOLFOX6 or CAPOX typically receive postoperative adjuvant chemotherapy with a fluoropyrimidine +/- oxaliplatin for an additional 16-18 weeks of therapy, if permitted based on recovery after surgical resection and post-surgical performance status. This treatment is at the discretion of the treating medical oncologist. Subjects will remain on study regardless of postoperative therapy administration or duration.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm: Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent obtained to participate in the study and HIPAA authorization&#xD;
             for release of personal health information.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years at the time of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group) Performance Status of 0-2 (See Appendix A.&#xD;
             ECOG Performance Status Scale).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histological or cytological confirmation of rectal adenocarcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned to receive treatment with neoadjuvant therapy, comprised of either 1)&#xD;
             chemoradiation with concurrent fluoropyrimidine or short-course radiotherapy, or 2)&#xD;
             total neoadjuvant therapy with fluoropyrimidine +oxaliplatin followed by&#xD;
             chemoradiation or short-course radiotherapy. Rectal adenocarcinoma patients deemed&#xD;
             candidates for neoadjuvant therapy include:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Tumor staged as T3-4 or node-positive by pelvic MRI or endorectal ultrasound, or&#xD;
                  node-positive by CT scan; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Tumor fixed to extra colonic structures as determined by digital rectal&#xD;
                  examination; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Tumor &lt; 5 cm from sphincter mechanism.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to undergo baseline rectal tumor biopsy, and willing and able to&#xD;
             donate blood for research purposes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of childbearing potential must be willing to abstain from heterosexual&#xD;
             activity or to use 2 forms of effective methods of contraception from the time of&#xD;
             informed consent until 12 weeks after treatment discontinuation. The two contraception&#xD;
             methods can be comprised of two barrier methods, or a barrier method plus a hormonal&#xD;
             method or an intrauterine device that meets &lt;1% failure rate for protection from&#xD;
             pregnancy in the product label.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male subjects with female partners must have had a prior vasectomy or agree to use an&#xD;
             adequate method of contraception (i.e., double barrier method: condom plus spermicidal&#xD;
             agent) starting with the first dose of study therapy through 12 weeks after the last&#xD;
             dose of study therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects are willing and able to comply with study procedures based on the judgement&#xD;
             of the investigator or protocol designee.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with colon carcinomas that are too proximal to receive neoadjuvant therapy&#xD;
             per routine clinical practice (i.e. with primary tumor proximal to or at the sigmoid&#xD;
             colon).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding (NOTE: breast milk cannot be stored for future use while the&#xD;
             mother is being treated on study).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known additional malignancy that is active and/or progressive and is requiring&#xD;
             treatment; exceptions include basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, in situ&#xD;
             cervical or bladder cancer, or other cancer for which the subject Is not currently&#xD;
             receiving anti-cancer therapy such as chemotherapy, radiation therapy, targeted&#xD;
             therapy, immunotherapy, or hormonal therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are not candidates at the discretion of their treating physicians to&#xD;
             receive neoadjuvant chemoradiation or total neoadjuvant therapy (e.g. poor performance&#xD;
             status, significant comorbidities, clinically significant organ dysfunction).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael S Lee, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UNC Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center at University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27599-7295</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://unclineberger.org/patientcare/clinical-trials/clinical-trials</url>
    <description>University of North Carolina Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center Clinical Trials</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leucovorin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Levoleucovorin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

