<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04412005</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1R01AI123050</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04412005</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pregnant Women for Malaria Surveillance</brief_title>
  <acronym>MiPMon</acronym>
  <official_title>Pregnant Women as a Sentinel Group for Malaria Surveillance in an Era of Changing Malaria Transmission</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Barcelona Institute for Global Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Barcelona Institute for Global Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Close monitoring of malaria in pregnancy can help to quickly identify changes in malaria&#xD;
      burden and related adverse outcomes, especially in areas embarking in malaria elimination&#xD;
      activities. The easy access of pregnant women through antenatal clinics, combined with the&#xD;
      potential of pregnancy-specific serology to assess cumulative exposure to malaria, can&#xD;
      provide the basis for new sentinel surveillance methods. Such an approach has the potential&#xD;
      to guide clinical practice and the choice of malaria control/preventive tools adapted to&#xD;
      areas of different transmission intensity, as well as to generate sensitive metrics of&#xD;
      transmission during malaria elimination activities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Continued monitoring of malaria in pregnancy is lacking in most endemic settings, in spite of&#xD;
      its significant disease burden. Increases in malaria-related harmful effects observed among&#xD;
      Mozambican pregnant women after drastic malaria declines during the last decade [2] suggest&#xD;
      that closely monitoring of the transmission is needed to quickly identify rebounds in adverse&#xD;
      outcomes, especially in areas embarking in malaria elimination activities. Moreover, several&#xD;
      evidences point to IgGs against VAR2CSA (the parasite antigen that mediates sequestration of&#xD;
      P. falciparum in the placenta) as a marker of cumulative exposure to P. falciparum during&#xD;
      pregnancy that can provide estimates of malaria transmission. The investigators hypothesize&#xD;
      that dynamics of malaria in pregnancy and pregnancy-specific immunity reflect changes in the&#xD;
      intensity of transmission through location and time, not only among pregnant women but also&#xD;
      in the underlying community. The goal of this study is to provide epidemiological, molecular&#xD;
      and immunological insights of the value of pregnant women attending health facilities to&#xD;
      generate estimates of malaria burden and its adverse consequences in situation of varying&#xD;
      levels of malaria transmission, with the ultimate hope of developing new tools for the&#xD;
      monitoring of malaria in endemic countries. To address this, the investigators will conduct a&#xD;
      three-year prospective observational study at three health facilities with different levels&#xD;
      of malaria transmission in Maputo Province to determine the relationship between malaria&#xD;
      transmission, parasitological outcomes and the clinical impact of malaria infection in&#xD;
      pregnant women at their first antenatal visit, delivery and during sick visits (Aim 1.1).&#xD;
      Moreover, the investigators will create a sample repository biobank for future investigations&#xD;
      on host and parasite factors influencing malaria disease during pregnancy (Aim 1.2). The&#xD;
      investigators will also determine the relationship between malaria estimates obtained from&#xD;
      pregnant women, children at hospital visits, (Aim 2.1) and seroprevalences against VAR2CSA&#xD;
      (Aim 2.2). The impact of interrupting malaria transmission on pregnancy-specific serology&#xD;
      (Aim 2.3) will be assessed in pregnant women from Magude after mass drug administration in&#xD;
      the community. Finally, scientific capacity in the Manhiça Health Research Center (Aim 3)&#xD;
      will be developed through training on a) epidemiological research and management of malaria&#xD;
      data; b) molecular tools for detection of malaria parasites and molecular markers of&#xD;
      antimalarial resistance for rapid mapping of drug resistance; and c) pregnancy-specific&#xD;
      immunity as an innovative tool to assess malaria transmission. This study will contribute to&#xD;
      promote a pregnancy malaria research agenda by improving our scientific knowledge on&#xD;
      determinants of malaria susceptibility during pregnancy and demonstrating the feasibility and&#xD;
      value of an easy-to-implement new generation serological tool for malaria surveillance in&#xD;
      malaria elimination contexts.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 31, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 31, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of pregnant women with a P. falciparum infection</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>P. falciparum detected by qPCR</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of pregnant women with maternal anemia</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Hemoglobin levels (Hemocue)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of pregnant women delivering a newborn with low birthweight</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>grams in a digital scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">16958</enrollment>
  <condition>P. Falciparum</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Manhiça</arm_group_label>
    <description>Pregnant women attending the Manhiça District Hospital</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ilha Josina</arm_group_label>
    <description>Pregnant women attending the Ilha Josina Health Center</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Magude</arm_group_label>
    <description>Pregnant women attending the Magude Health Center</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>No intervention</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ilha Josina</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Magude</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Manhiça</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Dried blood spots Plasma and PBMCS from a random selection of study participants&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Pregnant women attending three health centers in areas of Maputo Province with different&#xD;
        levels of malaria transmission (Manhiça District Hospital [Manhiça District], Ilha Josina&#xD;
        Health Center [Manhiça District] and Magude Health Center [Magude District])&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women attending their first routine ANCs or pregnant women seen at the moment&#xD;
             of delivery or pregnant women with signs/symptoms of malaria (axillary temperature ≥&#xD;
             37.5°C, referred history of fever in the last 24 hours, pallor, arthromyalgias,&#xD;
             headache and/or history of convulsions)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being equal or older than 16 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being from the study area&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwillingness to participate in the study or to have samples obtained&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not being from the study area.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Being pregnant</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>May 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 4, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 4, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>malaria</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

