<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03290937</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017-0180</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2018-01036</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2017-0180</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>P30CA016672</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03290937</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Utomilumab, Cetuximab, and Irinotecan Hydrochloride in Treating Patients With Metastatic Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I Clinical Trial Evaluating the Safety and Response With PF-05082566, Cetuximab, and Irinotecan in Patients With Advanced Colorectal Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I trial studies the best dose and side effects of irinotecan hydrochloride when&#xD;
      given with utomilumab and cetuximab in treating patients with colorectal cancer that has&#xD;
      spread to other places in the body (metastatic). Monoclonal antibodies, such as utomilumab&#xD;
      and cetuximab, may interfere with the ability of tumor cells to grow and spread. Drugs used&#xD;
      in chemotherapy, such as irinotecan hydrochloride, work in different ways to stop the growth&#xD;
      of tumor cells, either by killing the cells, by stopping them from dividing, or by stopping&#xD;
      them from spreading. Giving utomilumab, cetuximab, and irinotecan hydrochloride may work&#xD;
      better in treating patients with colorectal cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate maximal tolerated dose (MTD), and recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) of the&#xD;
      combination of utomilumab (PF-05082566), cetuximab and irinotecan hydrochloride (irinotecan)&#xD;
      (PCI) in patients with metastatic colorectal cancer refractory to standard therapy. (Dose&#xD;
      escalation) II. To determine the antitumor activity overall response rate (ORR) by&#xD;
      immune-related Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (irRECIST) of the study regimen&#xD;
      specifically in patients with advanced colorectal cancer who are RAS-RAF wild type (WT) (Arm&#xD;
      A) or RAS mutant (Arm B). (Dose expansion)&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate overall safety profile. II. To evaluate the anti-tumor activity. III. To&#xD;
      evaluate pharmacodynamics (PD) biomarkers expressed by peripheral blood mononuclear cells&#xD;
      (PBMC) and tissue samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To characterize serum biomarkers linked to immunomodulation and cytokine release.&#xD;
&#xD;
      V. To assess markers of T and natural killer (NK) cell phenotype (such as CD3, CD4, CD8,&#xD;
      FoxP3, CD14, CD33, CCR7, CD45RO, CD16, CD56, CD69, CD25, or VCAM1), TNF alpha, IFN gamma,&#xD;
      IL10, IL-8, IL-6, IL-4, IL-2, IL-1b, or IL-12p70, CD127, Ki67, eomesodermin, KLRG1, CD14,&#xD;
      CD33, human leukocyte antigen- D related (HLA-DR), CD16, CD56, granzyme B, CD68, PD-1, CD11c,&#xD;
      sCD137, and 4-1BB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: This is a dose escalation study of irinotecan hydrochloride.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive irinotecan hydrochloride intravenously (IV) over 90 minutes and cetuximab IV&#xD;
      over 1-2 hours on days 1 and 15, and utomilumab IV over 1 hour on day 2. Cycles repeat every&#xD;
      28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 3 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 27, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recommended phase 2 dose of irinotecan hydrochloride (Dose escalation)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>A modified 3+3 design will be used to determine the maximum tolerated dose.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (Dose expansion)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by using the immune-related Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (irRECIST).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Characterized by type, frequency, severity (as graded by National Cancer Institute [NCI] Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events [CTCAE] version [v.]4.03), timing, seriousness and relationship to study therapy utolimumab (PF-05082566); Laboratory abnormalities as characterized by type, frequency, severity (as graded by NCI CTCAE v.4.03) and timing.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be analyzed using Kaplan-Meier methods and descriptive statistics.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 years.</time_frame>
    <description>Will be analyzed using Kaplan-Meier methods and descriptive statistics.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">42</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Colorectal Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVA Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVB Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVC Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (irinotecan hydrochloride, cetuximab, utomilumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive irinotecan hydrochloride IV over 90 minutes and cetuximab IV over 1-2 hours on days 1 and 15, and utomilumab IV over 1 hour on day 2. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cetuximab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (irinotecan hydrochloride, cetuximab, utomilumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cetuximab Biosimilar CDP-1</other_name>
    <other_name>Cetuximab Biosimilar CMAB009</other_name>
    <other_name>Cetuximab Biosimilar KL 140</other_name>
    <other_name>Chimeric Anti-EGFR Monoclonal Antibody</other_name>
    <other_name>Chimeric MoAb C225</other_name>
    <other_name>Chimeric Monoclonal Antibody C225</other_name>
    <other_name>Erbitux</other_name>
    <other_name>IMC-C225</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Irinotecan Hydrochloride</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (irinotecan hydrochloride, cetuximab, utomilumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Campto</other_name>
    <other_name>Camptosar</other_name>
    <other_name>Camptothecin 11</other_name>
    <other_name>Camptothecin-11</other_name>
    <other_name>CPT 11</other_name>
    <other_name>CPT-11</other_name>
    <other_name>Irinomedac</other_name>
    <other_name>Irinotecan Hydrochloride Trihydrate</other_name>
    <other_name>Irinotecan Monohydrochloride Trihydrate</other_name>
    <other_name>U-101440E</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pharmacodynamic Study</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (irinotecan hydrochloride, cetuximab, utomilumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PHARMACODYNAMIC</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Utomilumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (irinotecan hydrochloride, cetuximab, utomilumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PF 05082566</other_name>
    <other_name>PF 5082566</other_name>
    <other_name>PF-05082566</other_name>
    <other_name>PF-2566</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have histologically and or cytologically confirmed metastatic colorectal&#xD;
             cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a wild type or mutated RAS tumor status known prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metastatic colorectal cancer patients have progressed following at least one line of&#xD;
             fluorouracil (5-FU)-based chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 to 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have measurable disease per irRECIST criteria for part 2 (dose&#xD;
             expansion)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1.0 x 10^9/L (1,000/uL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &gt;= 75 x 10^9/L (75000/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 8.0 g/dL (&gt;= 5.0 mmol/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be transfusion independent (i.e., no blood product transfusions for a&#xD;
             period of at least 14 days prior to screening)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine &lt; 2 x upper limit of normal (ULN) or estimated creatinine clearance &gt;&#xD;
             30 ml/min as calculated using the method standard for the institution&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total serum bilirubin &lt; 1.5 x ULN, unless the patient has documented Gilbert syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate and Alanine Aminotransferase (AST and ALT) &lt; 3 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) that is greater than 40%, or the absence of&#xD;
             New York Heart Association (NYHA) classification of greater than stage II congestive&#xD;
             heart failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Resolved acute effects of any prior therapy to baseline severity or grade =&lt; 2 Common&#xD;
             Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version (v.) 4.03 except for adverse&#xD;
             events (AEs) not constituting a safety risk by investigator judgment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum or urine pregnancy test (for females of childbearing potential) negative at&#xD;
             screening and at the baseline visit (before the patient may receive the&#xD;
             investigational product)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and female patients of childbearing potential and at risk for pregnancy must&#xD;
             agree to use two highly effective methods of contraception throughout the study and&#xD;
             for at least 90 days after the last dose of assigned treatment. Female patients who&#xD;
             are not of childbearing potential (permanently sterilized or postmenopausal; i.e.,&#xD;
             meet at least one of the following criteria):&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Have undergone a documented hysterectomy and/or bilateral oophorectomy; or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Have medically confirmed ovarian failure; or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Achieved postmenopausal status, defined as follows: cessation of regular menses&#xD;
                  for at least 12 consecutive months with no alternative pathological or&#xD;
                  physiological cause; status may be confirmed by having a serum follicle&#xD;
                  stimulating hormone (FSH) level within the laboratory's reference range for&#xD;
                  postmenopausal women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High microsatellite instability (MSI-H) colorectal cancer patients must have received&#xD;
             an approved PD-1 targeted agent prior to enrolling in this trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of a personally signed and dated informed consent document indicating that&#xD;
             the patient has been informed of all pertinent aspects of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Co-consent for protocol LAB10-0982&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness and ability to comply with the study scheduled visits, treatment plans,&#xD;
             laboratory tests and other procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known symptomatic brain metastases requiring steroids. Patients with&#xD;
             previously diagnosed brain metastases are eligible if they are asymptomatic or have&#xD;
             completed their treatment and have recovered from the acute effects of radiation&#xD;
             therapy or surgery prior to the start of study medication, have discontinued&#xD;
             corticosteroid treatment for these metastases for at least 4 weeks and are&#xD;
             neurologically stable&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has had any treatment specific for tumor control within 3 weeks of dosing, or&#xD;
             for investigational drugs and cytotoxic agents, within 5 half-lives or 3 weeks,&#xD;
             whichever is shorter&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving any medications or substances that are strong inhibitors or&#xD;
             inducers of CYP3A4 complex. Lists including medications and substances known or with&#xD;
             the potential to interact with the CYP3A4 isoenzymes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior therapy with a compound of the same mechanism as PF-05082566 (immunomodulation&#xD;
             of 4-1BB)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery within 28 days of starting study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiation therapy within 14 days of starting study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Autoimmune disorders (e.g., Crohn's disease, rheumatoid arthritis, scleroderma,&#xD;
             systemic lupus erythematosus) and other diseases that compromise or impair the immune&#xD;
             system except patients who have grade 1 psoriasis (in remission or controlled with&#xD;
             topical steroids) or mild degree of autoimmune thyroiditis that are controlled with&#xD;
             medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active and clinically significant bacterial, fungal or viral infection including&#xD;
             hepatitis B (HBV), hepatitis C (HCV), known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or&#xD;
             acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS)-related illness (HIV testing is not&#xD;
             required)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unstable or serious concurrent medical conditions in the previous 6 months, e.g.,&#xD;
             pancreatitis, severe/unstable angina, prolonged QT interval corrected by Fridericia's&#xD;
             formula (QTcF) &gt; 470 msec (calculated as average of triplicate readings, taken no&#xD;
             greater than 2 minutes apart, and no history of torsades de pointes or symptomatic&#xD;
             corrected QT [QTc] abnormality), symptomatic congestive heart failure, myocardial&#xD;
             infarction and/or pulmonary hypertension, ongoing maintenance therapy for&#xD;
             life-threatening ventricular arrhythmia, stroke, and uncontrolled major seizure&#xD;
             disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent active malignancy other than non-melanoma skin cancer or carcinoma in situ&#xD;
             of the cervix&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with intolerance to or who have had a severe allergic or anaphylactic&#xD;
             reaction to antibodies or infused therapeutic proteins, or patients who have had a&#xD;
             severe allergic or anaphylactic reaction to any of the substances included in the&#xD;
             study drug (including excipients)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other severe acute or chronic medical or psychiatric condition, including recent&#xD;
             (within the past year) or active suicidal ideation or behavior, or laboratory&#xD;
             abnormality that may increase the risk associated with study participation or&#xD;
             investigational product administration or may interfere with the interpretation of&#xD;
             study results and, in the judgment of the investigator, would make the patient&#xD;
             inappropriate for entry into this study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David S Hong</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M D Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 20, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 20, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 25, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Antineoplastic Agents, Immunological</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cetuximab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Camptothecin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulin G</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

