<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04985422</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Flow EMI - Depressive Symptom</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04985422</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ecological Momentary Intervention for Depressive Symptoms in a Community Sample in Hong Kong</brief_title>
  <official_title>Ecological Momentary Intervention for Depressive Symptoms in a Community Sample in Hong Kong: a Randomised Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Hong Kong</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Hong Kong</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The key aim of the study is to test the efficacy of a 4-week ecological momentary&#xD;
      intervention (EMI), as compared with the regular weekly-based intervention (control group),&#xD;
      in reducing (1) symptoms of depression and (2) rumination in community-dwelling individuals.&#xD;
      The efficacy of the EMI in reducing distress and improving functioning is also examined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For both EMI and control groups, the intervention will be delivered through SMS text&#xD;
      messages, with a link to a user-friendly and locally-adapted intervention platform designed&#xD;
      using Qualtrics (online survey programme).&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is hypothesised that (1) those in the EMI group, as compared to the control group, will&#xD;
      show greater reductions in (1) depressive symptoms, (2) rumination level, (3) distress, and&#xD;
      in (4) improving functioning. These effects are hypothesised to be observed in individuals&#xD;
      with varying levels of symptom severity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Despite the growth of online-based interventions, there remains a lack of highly adaptive and&#xD;
      personalised smartphone-based interventions that can be implemented in the course of everyday&#xD;
      life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current study examines the effectiveness of a newly-developed smartphone-based ecological&#xD;
      momentary intervention (EMI) in reducing symptoms of depression as well as rumination and&#xD;
      distress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rumination is a common experience in individuals with major depressive disorder (MDD). These&#xD;
      psychopathological symptoms occur in a population on a continuous spectrum, which may be&#xD;
      especially pronounced after the community has experienced a series of highly stressful and&#xD;
      traumatic events. On the high end of the spectrum, manifestations of symptoms may be&#xD;
      considered to be clinical disorders, and professional intervention may be indicated.&#xD;
      Rumination may affect prognosis and there are suggestions that interventions to reduce and&#xD;
      modify rumination can improve outcomes. At the less severe end of the spectrum (i.e., not yet&#xD;
      reached the threshold for disorders), rumination may be a risk factor that compromises&#xD;
      outcomes and adjustment, one that can cause significant distress and functional impairment.&#xD;
      Targeting rumination in both below- and above- threshold populations therefore has important&#xD;
      research and clinical implications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mental Health Needs in Hong Kong The Hong Kong population has undergone a series of highly&#xD;
      stressful events traceable since June 2019, from large-scale social unrest, to the outbreak&#xD;
      of Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) first in January 2020 and a second wave of COVID-19&#xD;
      cases in March 2020. Each of these population-level events is accompanied by other related&#xD;
      social, economic, and political consequences, all of which can result in significant&#xD;
      psychological distress and mental health burdens especially when added up to individual-level&#xD;
      stressors. Local studies have reported heightened depressive symptoms in relation to such&#xD;
      population-level events in addition to personal stressful events. The rates observed are&#xD;
      considerably higher than the average global prevalence, which marks it as particularly&#xD;
      concerning when help-seeking is severely minimal in the general local population. It is&#xD;
      anticipated that these rates will continue rising and would manifest with symptoms of other&#xD;
      conditions (such as anxiety, as is already seen in China during COVID-19). Unsurprisingly,&#xD;
      the widespread pandemic has already led researchers in many other countries to call for&#xD;
      enhanced and novel psychological interventions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A local online self-help initiative has recently been launched by the Department of&#xD;
      Psychiatry of the University of Hong Kong, offered to individuals via different channels&#xD;
      (including various social media platforms, non-governmental organisations, social and&#xD;
      personal connections) in the form of an anonymous mental health recognition and support tool.&#xD;
      The key aims of the tool are to provide users with a space to reflect on the ongoing events&#xD;
      in their lives and their feelings, provide them with an individualised understanding of their&#xD;
      current mental health conditions (MDD symptoms) and the potential contributing factors, as&#xD;
      well as offer individualised suggestions for self-help and professional help when necessary.&#xD;
      A high level of MDD as well as significant levels of rumination in response to the community&#xD;
      stressors have been reported, particularly in young people. Of importance, rumination about&#xD;
      such large-scale external events (&quot;event-based rumination&quot;) was seen to be highly associated&#xD;
      with MDD symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rumination and its Consequences In the presence of significant external stressors, an&#xD;
      excessive level of symptoms, together with rumination about the stressors or their&#xD;
      psychological responses characterise a state described as adjustment disorder (AjD) in the&#xD;
      International Classification of Diseases, 11th Revision (ICD-11). The presence of AjD carries&#xD;
      an increased level of risk for transition into other clinical disorders, such as MDD. The&#xD;
      role of rumination as a mechanism that predisposes individuals towards the development of&#xD;
      major depressive episodes has been well studied. Researchers have shown that particular types&#xD;
      of rumination, such as brooding (i.e., passive and judgmental comparison of current situation&#xD;
      and an unachieved alternative outcome), are specifically responsible for the development of&#xD;
      depression. The presence of this rumination type for people with MDD also predicted poorer&#xD;
      outcomes. Because of its importance, interventional strategies (such as cognitive-behavioural&#xD;
      therapy, CBT) targeting rumination have been developed and have been shown to be effective in&#xD;
      improving mental health outcomes. Rumination-focused CBT generally involves increasing one's&#xD;
      ability to become aware of their own (brooding) ruminations and supporting them to eventually&#xD;
      replace them with alternative thinking habits).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ecological Momentary Assessment and Intervention Recent years have seen the growth of a new&#xD;
      avenue for mental health that appears highly suitable for the Hong Kong population, namely&#xD;
      ecological momentary assessment (EMA) and ecological momentary intervention (EMI). These&#xD;
      mobile health (mHealth) approaches offered new opportunities for mental health research,&#xD;
      management, detection, and intervention via smartphones. In EMA, individuals can&#xD;
      self-initiate assessments when an emotion or specific event is experienced (event-sampling),&#xD;
      or are prompted several times a day to complete brief assessments over a number of days&#xD;
      (time-sampling). While EMIs have been used to augment usual treatments, EMIs have also been&#xD;
      coupled with EMA to deliver interventions based on symptoms reported in the moment. The&#xD;
      essence of these two approaches is their abilities to be implemented in real-time and in&#xD;
      everyday life contexts, be designed flexibly according to specific objectives, and be adapted&#xD;
      to individual needs. Capturing prospective information on interactions between micro-level&#xD;
      experiences and real-world contexts, as well as providing in-the-moment interventions, EMA&#xD;
      and EMI impart benefits that cannot be achieved in traditional in-person treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Importantly, increasing evidence from randomised controlled trials (RCTs) has shown EMI to be&#xD;
      an efficacious and effective means to augment interventions in different disorders, including&#xD;
      depression, anxiety, bipolar disorders, psychosis. Furthermore, although EMA in addition to&#xD;
      treatment-as-usual (TAU) has shown to be more effective than TAU alone in reducing depressive&#xD;
      symptoms in patients with MDD, the positive impact of EMI was shown to be more long-lasting&#xD;
      in the EMI+TAU group compared with EMI+TAU, with the effects lasting for up to 3 months for&#xD;
      EMA+TAU, and up to 6 months for EMI+TAU.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Current Study EMI appears to be a promising approach to support individuals with distress&#xD;
      in the Hong Kong population in reducing symptoms and ruminative thoughts. This is also&#xD;
      possibly the only means to reach those less motivated to seek help due to stigma, as well as&#xD;
      potential worries over in-person contacts especially after the COVID-19 outbreak.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The key aim of the study is to test the efficacy of a 4-week ecological momentary&#xD;
      intervention (EMI), as compared with the regular weekly-based intervention (control group),&#xD;
      in reducing (1) symptoms of depression and (2) rumination in community-dwelling individuals.&#xD;
      The efficacy of the EMI in reducing distress and improving functioning is also examined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is hypothesised that (1) those in the EMI group, as compared to the control group, will&#xD;
      show greater reductions in (1) depressive symptoms, (2) rumination level, (3) distress, and&#xD;
      in (4) improving functioning. These effects are hypothesised to be observed in individuals&#xD;
      with varying levels of symptom severity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 26, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in depressive symptoms, as assessed using the Depression subscale of the Depression, Anxiety and Stress Scales (DASS-D)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after intervention (post 4-week intervention) and up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The DASS-D is a 7-item measure rated on a 4-point Likert scale. Scores range from 0 to 42, where a higher score represents a higher level of depressive symptoms. The DASS-D has been validated in Hong Kong (epidemiological and clinical samples) as well as in both young people and adults.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in rumination level, as assessed using the 10-item ruminative response scale (RRS-10)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after intervention (post 4-week intervention) and up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The RRS-10 is a 10-item measure rated on a 4-point Likert scale. Scores range from 10 to 40, where a higher score represents a higher level of ruminative experience.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in psychological distress, as assessed using the Kessler Psychological Distress Scale (K6)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after intervention (post 4-week intervention) and up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The K6 is a 6-item measure rated on a 5-point Likert scale. Scores range from 0 to 24, where a higher score represents a higher level of distress symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in level of functioning, as assessed using Sheehan Disability Scale (SDS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after intervention (post 4-week intervention) and up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The SDS is a 3-item measure rated on a 11-point Likert scale. The items assess functional impairment in three interrelated domains (work/school, social, and family life). Scores of global functional impairment (sum of the three items) range from 0 to 30, where a higher score represents a higher level of functional impairment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">262</enrollment>
  <condition>Depressive Symptoms</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group: Smartphone-based daily ecological momentary intervention (EMI)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The experimental group receives 4 weeks of smartphone-based daily EMI. Participants are prompted 6 times a day (with an interval of at least 30 minutes between each digital prompt), on a daily basis over the 4-week period. Within 15 minutes of the digital prompt, participants are to first complete a brief (1-2 minutes) momentary survey (&quot;ecological momentary assessment&quot; [EMA]), and subsequently select 1 out of 5 personalised intervention actions of interest to complete in the moment (time to complete spans from 1 minute to 5 minutes).&#xD;
The interventions are brief simple behavioural actions (mostly 1-2 minutes, up to 5 minutes) which could be done in the moment. Simple action tasks include guided breathing, mindful walking, and mindful sound hearing (etc.).&#xD;
Participants could also use the platform at any other times to redo intervention actions when preferred. Individualised reports for the EMI completed are provided.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group: Smartphone-based weekly-delivered information</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group receives 4 weeks of smartphone-based weekly-delivered information. The smartphone system (SMS + Qualtrics) as well as the contents of the interventions are identical to those provided to the EMI group. Rather than interventions delivered in the moment on a daily basis over the 4-week period, participants in the control group are provided with a new set of information on a weekly basis over the 4-week period (4 sets in total, 1 new set each week). Participants in the control group are also required to complete a brief 5-minute assessment within 3 days.&#xD;
The information includes brief simple behavioural actions (mostly 1-2 minutes, up to 5 minutes) which could be done anytime. Simple action tasks include guided breathing, mindful walking, and mindful sound hearing (etc.).&#xD;
Participants could complete any intervention of interest in the information provided at any time throughout the 4-week period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Smartphone-based Daily Ecological Momentary Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Interventions are delivered through smartphones (SMS text message + Qualtrics) at a low cost with high accessibility. Participants are prompted 6 random times a day over the set intervention period (4 weeks) to complete brief EMA and EMI intervention actions) across contexts in daily lives for the reduction of depressive symptoms, as well as rumination distress, and improve functioning.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group: Smartphone-based daily ecological momentary intervention (EMI)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Smartphone-based Weekly-delivered Information</intervention_name>
    <description>Information with simple actions for reducing depressive symptoms are delivered through smartphones (SMS text message + Qualtrics) at a low cost with high accessibility. Participants are prompted weekly with a new set of information, together with a 5-min assessment. The information includes intervention actions provided in the EMI group.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group: Smartphone-based weekly-delivered information</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptoms of depression indicated by DASS-D score of 10 or above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 15 to 64 years (parental or guardian consent is required for those below 18&#xD;
             years)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Possess a smartphone with access to the Internet&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant developmental disorder, psychotic disorder, substance abuse or organic&#xD;
             brain disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active suicidal risk&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving active structured intervention or anticipating to receive such treatment&#xD;
             (e.g., biweekly psychotherapy sessions, receiving pharmacotherapy)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eric YH Chen, MA</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The University of Hong Kong</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Stephanie MY Wong, BSocSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The University of Hong Kong</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Eric YH Chen, MA</last_name>
    <phone>(+852) 22554486</phone>
    <email>eyhchen.hk@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Stephanie MY Wong, BSocSc</last_name>
    <phone>(+852) 90371111</phone>
    <email>steph.my.wong@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Hong Kong</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hong Kong</city>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Eric YH Chen</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lam LC, Chan WC, Wong CS, Chen EY, Ng RM, Lee EH, Chang WC, Hung SF, Cheung EF, Sham PC, Chiu HF, Lam M, Chiang TP, van Os J, Lau JT, Lewis G, Bebbington P; Hong Kong Mental Morbidity Survey Team. The Hong Kong mental morbidity survey: background and study design. East Asian Arch Psychiatry. 2014 Mar;24(1):30-6.</citation>
    <PMID>24676485</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Echiverri AM, Jaeger JJ, Chen JA, Moore SA, Zoellner LA. &quot;Dwelling in the Past&quot;: The Role of Rumination in the Treatment of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder. Cogn Behav Pract. 2011 Aug;18(3):338-349.</citation>
    <PMID>22190846</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nolen-Hoeksema S, Wisco BE, Lyubomirsky S. Rethinking Rumination. Perspect Psychol Sci. 2008 Sep;3(5):400-24. doi: 10.1111/j.1745-6924.2008.00088.x.</citation>
    <PMID>26158958</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Watkins ER. Constructive and unconstructive repetitive thought. Psychol Bull. 2008 Mar;134(2):163-206. doi: 10.1037/0033-2909.134.2.163. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18298268</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ni MY, Yao XI, Leung KSM, Yau C, Leung CMC, Lun P, Flores FP, Chang WC, Cowling BJ, Leung GM. Depression and post-traumatic stress during major social unrest in Hong Kong: a 10-year prospective cohort study. Lancet. 2020 Jan 25;395(10220):273-284. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(19)33160-5. Epub 2020 Jan 9.</citation>
    <PMID>31928765</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wang C, Pan R, Wan X, Tan Y, Xu L, Ho CS, Ho RC. Immediate Psychological Responses and Associated Factors during the Initial Stage of the 2019 Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) Epidemic among the General Population in China. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020 Mar 6;17(5). pii: E1729. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17051729.</citation>
    <PMID>32155789</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wind TR, Rijkeboer M, Andersson G, Riper H. The COVID-19 pandemic: The 'black swan' for mental health care and a turning point for e-health. Internet Interv. 2020 Apr;20:100317. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2020.100317. Epub 2020 Mar 19.</citation>
    <PMID>32289019</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wong SMY, Hui CLM, Wong CSM, Suen YN, Chan SKW, Lee EHM, Chang WC, Wong GHY, Chen EYH. Induced ideas of reference during social unrest and pandemic in Hong Kong. Schizophr Res. 2021 Mar;229:46-52. doi: 10.1016/j.schres.2021.01.027. Epub 2021 Feb 19.</citation>
    <PMID>33618286</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wong SM, Hui CL, Wong CS, Suen YN, Chan SK, Lee EH, Chang WC, Chen EY. Prospective prediction of PTSD and depressive symptoms during social unrest and COVID-19 using a brief online tool. Psychiatry Res. 2021 Apr;298:113773. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2021.113773. Epub 2021 Jan 29.</citation>
    <PMID>33545423</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wong SMY, Hui CLM, Wong CSM, Suen YN, Chan SKW, Lee EHM, Chang WC, Chen EYH. Mental Health Risks after Repeated Exposure to Multiple Stressful Events during Ongoing Social Unrest and Pandemic in Hong Kong: The Role of Rumination: Risques pour la santé mentale après une exposition répétée à de multiples événements stressants d'agitation sociale durable et de pandémie à Hong Kong: le rôle de la rumination. Can J Psychiatry. 2021 Jun;66(6):577-585. doi: 10.1177/0706743720979920. Epub 2020 Dec 15.</citation>
    <PMID>33317325</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Myin-Germeys I, Kasanova Z, Vaessen T, Vachon H, Kirtley O, Viechtbauer W, Reininghaus U. Experience sampling methodology in mental health research: new insights and technical developments. World Psychiatry. 2018 Jun;17(2):123-132. doi: 10.1002/wps.20513.</citation>
    <PMID>29856567</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kramer I, Simons CJ, Hartmann JA, Menne-Lothmann C, Viechtbauer W, Peeters F, Schruers K, van Bemmel AL, Myin-Germeys I, Delespaul P, van Os J, Wichers M. A therapeutic application of the experience sampling method in the treatment of depression: a randomized controlled trial. World Psychiatry. 2014 Feb;13(1):68-77. doi: 10.1002/wps.20090.</citation>
    <PMID>24497255</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 30, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The University of Hong Kong</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Professor Eric Y.H. Chen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chi-Li Pao Foundation Professor in Psychiatry, Chair Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Depressive symptoms</keyword>
  <keyword>Ecological momentary intervention</keyword>
  <keyword>Rumination</keyword>
  <keyword>Distress</keyword>
  <keyword>Stressors</keyword>
  <keyword>Mental health</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

