<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04986722</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>G-5097-2019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04986722</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting Incidence in Patients With Mastectomy Surgery According to Apfel Risk Scoring System</brief_title>
  <official_title>Cukurova University</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cukurova University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cukurova University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Objective: To evaluate the symptoms of postoperative nausea and vomiting (PONV) in patients&#xD;
      undergoing mastectomy with breast cancer according to the Apfel Risk Scoring System.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials and Methods: The descriptive and cross-sectional study was conducted between June&#xD;
      2020 and August 2020 in the surgical oncology department of a tertiary hospital. A total of&#xD;
      57 female patients who were scheduled for surgical treatment for breast cancer were included&#xD;
      in the study. Data including demographic and clinical characteristics of the patients were&#xD;
      recorded by face-to-face interview method. The incidence of PONV was evaluated using the&#xD;
      Patient Evaluation Form and the Apfel Risk Scoring System.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      METHODOLOGY This descriptive, cross-sectional study was conducted at Department of Surgical&#xD;
      Oncology of a tertiary care hospital between June 2020 and August 2020. The study centre has&#xD;
      a 1,200-bed capacity and the surgical oncology clinic has a 30-bed capacity. A total of 57&#xD;
      women who were scheduled for elective mastectomy for breast cancer were included. Inclusion&#xD;
      criteria were as follows: women aged ≥18 years, hospitalization 6 hours prior to surgery,&#xD;
      American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) Class I-III, having no chronic pain or alcohol&#xD;
      and/or substance abuse, having no cognitive impairment, no need for mechanical ventilation,&#xD;
      having a confirmed diagnosis of breast cancer, and being scheduled for mastectomy. Prior to&#xD;
      study, all patients were informed about the nature of the study and a written informed&#xD;
      consent was obtained. The study protocol was approved by the institutional Non-Interventional&#xD;
      Clinical Research Ethics Committee (No: 15.05.2020/99). The study was conducted in accordance&#xD;
      with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preoperative and postoperative data within 48 hours were collected via face-to-face&#xD;
      interviews. The Patient Assessment Form, which was developed in accordance with the previous&#xD;
      studies in the literature, was used to collect data including age and body mass index (BMI)&#xD;
      pre- and postoperatively. For the postoperative evaluation, the four-item, simplified Apfel&#xD;
      Risk Scoring System was used. It is a valid tool which assesses PONV and/or motion sickness,&#xD;
      non-smoking status, and postoperative use of opioids. Accordingly, 0-1 indicate low, 2&#xD;
      indicate moderate, and ≥3-4 indicate high risk for PONV [12]. In our study, PONV was&#xD;
      evaluated using the Patient Assessment Form at 0, 2, 4, 8, 24, and 48 hours as &quot;Yes/No&quot;&#xD;
      scoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis was performed using the SPSS version 22.0 software (IBM Corp., Armonk,&#xD;
      NY, USA). Descriptive data were expressed in mean ± standard deviation (SD), median (min-max)&#xD;
      or number and frequency, where applicable. The chi-square test was used to evaluate&#xD;
      relationship between categorical variables. The Mann-Whitney U test (Z table values) was&#xD;
      performed to compare two independent groups which did not meet the normal distribution. The&#xD;
      continuity correction and Fisher exact test were used to examine the relationship between two&#xD;
      quantitative variables. The independent samples t-test (t table values) was used to compare&#xD;
      two independent groups which met the normal distribution. A p value of &lt;0.05 was considered&#xD;
      statistically significant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the Apfel risk score before surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>Preoperative 0-1 days</time_frame>
    <description>Apfel Risk Scoring ; It is a tool in which the patient's previous postoperative nausea, vomiting and/or motion sickness history, non-smoking status, and postoperative opioid use are questioned to assess the patient's postoperative nausea and vomiting (PONV) risk score. The patient is evaluated with the Apfel Risk Score preoperatively. As a result of the evaluation, the patient is considered 0-1 point low risk, 2 points medium risk, and ≥3-4 points high risk for PONV.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of postoperative nausea and vomiting</measure>
    <time_frame>Postoperative 0-2 days</time_frame>
    <description>Using the Patient Evaluation Form, the patient's nausea and vomiting at 0, 2, 4, 8, 24 and 48 hours after the surgery was evaluated as &quot;Yes/No&quot; scoring.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">57</enrollment>
  <condition>Surgery</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        - Patients diagnosed with breast cancer, female, scheduled for mastectomy, over 18 years of&#xD;
        age and who agreed to participate in the study were included in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed with breast cancer,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have female gender,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mastectomy planned&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having speech, comprehension and language barriers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who do not agree to participate in the study,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with male gender&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>female patients scheduled for mastectomy</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cukurova University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Adana</city>
        <zip>01130</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cukurova University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Hamide Sisman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>There is not a plan to make IPD available.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

