<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04983251</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10000441</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>000441-E</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04983251</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Women s Health Awareness Community Resiliency, Environmental Action and Collaborations for Health (REACH) Equity</brief_title>
  <official_title>Women's Health Awareness Community Resiliency, Environmental Action and Collaborations for Health (REACH) Equity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences (NIEHS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inequalities in COVID-19 infection, hospitalization, and death in under-studied,&#xD;
      under-represented, and under-reported groups of people are severe. A growing number of&#xD;
      studies have assessed the impact of individual risk factors. But few studies have assessed&#xD;
      which factors are the greatest drivers of COVID-19 disparities from a wider perspective.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To understand the long-term impacts of COVID-19 on minority women and their families to&#xD;
      assist in developing community-based programs to help in recovery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy people aged 18 and older.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with a 1-hour online survey. The survey will cover their&#xD;
      demographics, community, health, lifestyle, household, and environment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may choose to have tests. They may visit the Clinical Research Unit. They may&#xD;
      also have a home visit for these tests. In some cases, they may mail samples to the study&#xD;
      team in prepaid envelopes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may give a blood sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may give saliva samples. They will be asked to give 5 samples on 2 different&#xD;
      days during a 1-week period. They will fill out a log with each sample they collect.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will give toenail samples from each toe.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will give dust samples. They will be given 8 alcohol swabs. Two will be for&#xD;
      testing. They will be asked to swipe a total of 3 door frames. Each door frame should be in a&#xD;
      different room of the house.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be given silicone wristbands to wear for 1 week. This is to measure their&#xD;
      exposure to air pollutants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may be contacted in the future for follow-up. They may be contacted by phone,&#xD;
      email, or letter.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a cross-sectional population-based survey designed within a syndemic framework to&#xD;
      characterize the impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic on women in under-studied,&#xD;
      under-represented, and under-reported (U3) populations. We hypothesize that U3 women are&#xD;
      experiencing and will have experienced a worsening of mental, physical, and socio-economic&#xD;
      status as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic and that pre-pandemic indicators of U3 status and&#xD;
      related exposures will be associated with adverse mental, physical, and SES effects of the&#xD;
      COVID-19 pandemic. The study ultimately seeks to collect baseline data for a long-term&#xD;
      follow-up study of U3 women, as well as identify high impact targets for public health&#xD;
      interventions to build resiliency in U3 communities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterize the mental, physical, and socio-economic effects</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>(1)Characterize the mental, physical, and socio-economic effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on women in under-studied, under-represented, and under-reported (U3) populations within a syndemic framework. (2) Determine whether there was a worsening of mental, physical, and socio-economic status before, during, and following the COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantify cross-sectional associations between retrospective pre-pandemic indicators of U3 status and related exposures</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>(1) Quantify cross-sectional associations between retrospective pre-pandemic indicators of U3 status and related exposures (i.e., urban vs. rural; pre-existing physical and mental health disparities; risk factors for maternal mortality; experiences of racism; social factors, and environmental, occupational, and housing exposures) with adverse mental, physical, and SES effects of the COVID-19 pandemic. (2) Characterize the direct and indirect experiences of U3 women with SARS-CoV-2 infection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">700</enrollment>
  <condition>Mental Health</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>U3 Women</arm_group_label>
    <description>Women in under-studied, under-represented, and under-reported (U3) populations.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Women will be recruited from a community-based sample in North Carolina following a&#xD;
        recruitment plan developed in collaboration with Women's Health Awareness (WHA) partners.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In order to be eligible to participate in this study, an individual must meet all of the&#xD;
        following&#xD;
&#xD;
        criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females who are African American or Black, Hispanics or Latinos, American Indians or&#xD;
             Alaska Natives, Asian Americans, Native Hawaiian or other Pacific Islander.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 18 years or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reside in North Carolina.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        An individual who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from participation&#xD;
        in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Any condition that, in the investigator's opinion, places the participant at undue risk&#xD;
        for complications associated with required study procedures.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joan P Packenham, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences (NIEHS)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jaslyn A Grullon</last_name>
    <phone>(984) 287-4999</phone>
    <email>jaslyn.grullon@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NIEHS Clinical Research Unit (CRU)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Research Triangle Park</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27709</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jaslyn Grullon</last_name>
      <phone>984-287-4999</phone>
      <email>jaslyn.grullon@nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_000441-E.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>July 26, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Disparities</keyword>
  <keyword>Vaccination</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

