<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04984174</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCC2021-0211</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04984174</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Survival Rate and Treatment Cost in Patients With Pancreatic Cancer With the Advent of New Chemotherapeutic Agents in Korea: An Analysis Using NHIS Database and K-PaC Registry Focusing on the Newest One, Liposomal Irinotecan</brief_title>
  <official_title>Survival Rate and Treatment Cost in Patients With Pancreatic Cancer With the Advent of New Chemotherapeutic Agents in Korea: An Analysis Using NHIS Database and K-PaC Registry Focusing on the Newest One, Liposomal Irinotecan</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Center, Korea</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Seoul National University Bundang Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Center, Korea</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The past 15 years, using National Health Insurance Service (NHIS) database and K-PaC&#xD;
      registry, and to analyze the cost and cost-effectiveness along with the change in survival&#xD;
      rate after the emergence of the aforementioned regimens, which is very important for policy&#xD;
      decisions such as reimbursement of second-line treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Pancreatic cancer is a disease with a very poor prognosis and incurs large medical and&#xD;
      economic costs in a short course of disease. According to data from Cancer registration&#xD;
      Statistics Program released in 2020, 243,837 new cancers occurred in Korea in 2018, of which&#xD;
      pancreatic cancer (C25) was ranked 8th with 7,611 cases, 3.1% of total cancer incidences. The&#xD;
      crude incidence rate was 14.8 cases/100,000 (https://www.cancer.go.kr/). According to a 2002&#xD;
      report, Korean pancreatic cancer patient's per capita medical expenses and income loss&#xD;
      totaled 93 million won, showing the largest economic loss among cancers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pancreatic cancer is known to have a 5-year survival rate of around 10% worldwide, and it is&#xD;
      thought that the survival rate is gradually increasing after the introduction of FOLFIRINOX,&#xD;
      and albumin-bound paclitaxel (GnP). Since the measures to strengthen the coverage of severe&#xD;
      diseases in 2005, the coverage of severe diseases has also been strengthened. Since 2016,&#xD;
      with the reimbursement of the use of FOLFIRINOX and GnP, one of these two regimens has been&#xD;
      the first-line chemotherapy in most pancreatic cancer patients who are eligible for&#xD;
      chemotherapy in Korea. In addition, these two regimens can be administered in the first and&#xD;
      second alternations of each other. Recently, after the first gemcitabine-based treatment for&#xD;
      metastatic pancreatic cancer, the second-line treatment with 5-FU and folinic acid with&#xD;
      liposomal irinotecan demonstrated significant increased survival rates compared with 5FU/LV&#xD;
      in a randomized Phase 3 Trial (NAPOLI-1).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since the introduction of the aforementioned chemotherapy, the change in survival rate is not&#xD;
      yet well known, and real-world data on the cost and cost-effectiveness of pancreatic cancer&#xD;
      treatment are still lacking in Korea. In the United States, in 2012, research results on the&#xD;
      cost and trend analysis of pancreatic cancer treatment were published, and in that paper, the&#xD;
      treatment cost for pancreatic cancer was a high economic burden, especially in the elderly,&#xD;
      and targeted therapy or screening tests are required to reduce future treatment costs. A&#xD;
      recent study reported by Investigator research group showed that FOLFIRINOX and GnP have&#xD;
      similar efficacy and comparable toxicity in patients with metastatic pancreatic cancer using&#xD;
      Korean Pancreatic Cancer (K-PaC) registry. In particular, patients who could receive&#xD;
      second-line chemotherapy survived for about 17 months in the K-PaC registry. The K-PaC&#xD;
      results provided the actual results of pancreatic cancer treatment in Korea relatively well,&#xD;
      but the data has disadvantages that do not represent all pancreatic cancer patients in Korea,&#xD;
      and cost analysis was not performed. Therefore, it is necessary to evaluate the change in&#xD;
      survival rate and costs with the advent of the aforementioned chemotherapy by analyzing big&#xD;
      data representing the whole pancreatic cancer patients in Korea.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 4, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 28, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 28, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cost-effectiveness analysis of chemotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>15 years</time_frame>
    <description>Analysis of chemotherapy to report annual survival rates and treatment-related for past 15 years in Korea</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>age, sex, types of institutions and chemotherapy regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>15 years</time_frame>
    <description>Subgroup analysis to report annual survival rates and treatment-related for past 15 years in Korea</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">54000</enrollment>
  <condition>Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        * Codes: malignant neoplasm of pancreas (C25 code) + registered cancer patients codes&#xD;
        (V026, V027, V008, V193, V011, V198, V194)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pancreatic cancer patients with records of medical users and billing data from 2005 to&#xD;
             2020&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who underwent surgery for pancreatic cancer&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sangmyung Woo, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Nation Cancer Center, Republic of Korea</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sangmyung Woo, MD</last_name>
    <phone>82 31 920 1733</phone>
    <email>wsm@ncc.re.kr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Meeyoung Lee, bachelor</last_name>
    <phone>82 31 920 0740</phone>
    <email>leemyyoung@ncc.re.kr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NATIONAL CANCER CENTER 323, Ilsan-ro, Ilsandong-gu,</name>
      <address>
        <city>Goyang-si</city>
        <state>Gyeonggi-do</state>
        <zip>10408</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>SANGMYUNG WOO, MD</last_name>
      <phone>82-31-920-1733</phone>
      <email>wsm@ncc.re.kr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kim SG, Hahm MI, Choi KS, Seung NY, Shin HR, Park EC. The economic burden of cancer in Korea in 2002. Eur J Cancer Care (Engl). 2008 Mar;17(2):136-44. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2354.2007.00818.x. Epub 2007 Sep 20.</citation>
    <PMID>18302650</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mizrahi JD, Surana R, Valle JW, Shroff RT. Pancreatic cancer. Lancet. 2020 Jun 27;395(10242):2008-2020. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30974-0. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32593337</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Conroy T, Desseigne F, Ychou M, Bouché O, Guimbaud R, Bécouarn Y, Adenis A, Raoul JL, Gourgou-Bourgade S, de la Fouchardière C, Bennouna J, Bachet JB, Khemissa-Akouz F, Péré-Vergé D, Delbaldo C, Assenat E, Chauffert B, Michel P, Montoto-Grillot C, Ducreux M; Groupe Tumeurs Digestives of Unicancer; PRODIGE Intergroup. FOLFIRINOX versus gemcitabine for metastatic pancreatic cancer. N Engl J Med. 2011 May 12;364(19):1817-25. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1011923.</citation>
    <PMID>21561347</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Von Hoff DD, Ervin T, Arena FP, Chiorean EG, Infante J, Moore M, Seay T, Tjulandin SA, Ma WW, Saleh MN, Harris M, Reni M, Dowden S, Laheru D, Bahary N, Ramanathan RK, Tabernero J, Hidalgo M, Goldstein D, Van Cutsem E, Wei X, Iglesias J, Renschler MF. Increased survival in pancreatic cancer with nab-paclitaxel plus gemcitabine. N Engl J Med. 2013 Oct 31;369(18):1691-703. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1304369. Epub 2013 Oct 16.</citation>
    <PMID>24131140</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wang-Gillam A, Li CP, Bodoky G, Dean A, Shan YS, Jameson G, Macarulla T, Lee KH, Cunningham D, Blanc JF, Hubner RA, Chiu CF, Schwartsmann G, Siveke JT, Braiteh F, Moyo V, Belanger B, Dhindsa N, Bayever E, Von Hoff DD, Chen LT; NAPOLI-1 Study Group. Nanoliposomal irinotecan with fluorouracil and folinic acid in metastatic pancreatic cancer after previous gemcitabine-based therapy (NAPOLI-1): a global, randomised, open-label, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2016 Feb 6;387(10018):545-557. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(15)00986-1. Epub 2015 Nov 29. Erratum in: Lancet. 2016 Feb 6;387(10018):536.</citation>
    <PMID>26615328</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>O'Neill CB, Atoria CL, O'Reilly EM, LaFemina J, Henman MC, Elkin EB. Costs and trends in pancreatic cancer treatment. Cancer. 2012 Oct 15;118(20):5132-9. doi: 10.1002/cncr.27490. Epub 2012 Mar 13.</citation>
    <PMID>22415469</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Lee JC, Woo SM, Shin DW, Kim J, Yang SY, Kim MJ, Kim JW, Kim JW, Lee WJ, Cha HS, Park P, Kim J, Hwang JH. Comparison of FOLFIRINOX and Gemcitabine Plus Nab-paclitaxel for Treatment of Metastatic Pancreatic Cancer: Using Korean Pancreatic Cancer (K-PaC) Registry. Am J Clin Oncol. 2020 Sep;43(9):654-659. doi: 10.1097/COC.0000000000000730.</citation>
    <PMID>32889836</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>National Cancer Center, Korea</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sang Myung Woo</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>medical doctor, Senior scientist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>pancreatic cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

