<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04986995</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BIA-91067-405</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-001176-15</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04986995</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>OpicApone Sleep dISorder</brief_title>
  <acronym>OASIS</acronym>
  <official_title>Open-label, Single-arm, Pilot Study to Evaluate the Effect of Opicapone 50 mg on Parkinson's Disease Patients With End-of-dose Motor Fluctuations and Associated Sleep Disorders</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bial - Portela C S.A.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bial - Portela C S.A.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to To investigate in an exploratory manner the efficacy of 50 mg&#xD;
      opicapone when administered with the existing treatment of levodopa (L-dopa) plus a dopa&#xD;
      decarboxylase inhibitor (DDCI), in Parkinson's disease (PD) patients with end-of-dose motor&#xD;
      fluctuations and associated sleep disorders&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label, single-arm, multi-centre, interventional clinical study in PD patients&#xD;
      with end-of-dose motor fluctuations and associated sleep disorders. The study consists of a&#xD;
      1-week screening period, a 6-week treatment period and 2 weeks of follow-up period. Expected&#xD;
      duration of treatment for the individual patient is up to 6 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 9, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Total score of Parkinson's Disease Sleep Scale - version 2 (PDSS-2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Parkinson's Disease Sleep Scale version 2 (PDSS-2) is a patient-completed clinical rating scale that assesses the frequency of sleep disturbances over the past week. Each question is scored between 0 (&quot;never&quot;) and 4 (&quot;very often&quot;), and a total score is calculated by summing a patient's responses to each of the 15 questions (minimum 0 to maximum 60)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Parkinson Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Opicapone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>50 mg hard capsules</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Opicapone</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral administration, once daily, at least 1 hour before or after the last daily dose of L-dopa/DDCI</description>
    <arm_group_label>Opicapone</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BIA 9-1067</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Able to comprehend and willing to sign an informed consent form and to comply with all&#xD;
             aspects of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Male or female patients aged 30 years or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Diagnosed with idiopathic PD according to the UK Parkinson's Disease Society Brain&#xD;
             Bank Clinical Diagnostic Criteria (2006) or according to MDS Clinical Diagnostic&#xD;
             Criteria (2015).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Signs of &quot;wearing-off&quot; phenomenon (end-of-dose motor fluctuations) with average total&#xD;
             daily OFF time while awake of at least 1.5 hours, excluding the early morning&#xD;
             pre-first dose OFF, despite optimal anti-PD therapy (based on investigator's&#xD;
             assessment).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Disease severity Stages I-III (modified Hoehn &amp; Yahr staging) at ON.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Experiencing PD associated sleep disorders for at least 4 weeks prior to V1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Total PDSS-2 score ≥ 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Treated with 3 to 8 intakes per day of L-dopa/DDCI (which may include a slow-release&#xD;
             formulation), on a stable regimen for at least 4 weeks before V1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. In case of any other anti-PD treatment, it should be on a stable regimen for at least&#xD;
             4 weeks before V1, and not likely to need any adjustment until V4.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. No change in the chronic treatment regimen within the last 4 weeks before V1 of the&#xD;
             following medication: sedatives, hypnotics, anti-depressants, anxiolytics or other&#xD;
             medications prescribed for the treatment of sleep disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. For females: Postmenopausal for at least 2 years before V1, surgically sterile for at&#xD;
             least 6 months before V1, or practicing an effective method of contraception until V4.&#xD;
             Female patients who request to continue with oral contraceptives must be willing to&#xD;
             use non-hormonal methods of contraception in addition during the course of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             For males: Male patients who are sexually active with a partner of childbearing&#xD;
             potential must use, with their partner, a condom plus an approved method of highly&#xD;
             effective contraception during the treatment period until V4.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Have filled-in self-rating diary in accordance with the diary instructions and with ≤&#xD;
             3 errors per day when awake, in the 3 days preceding V2a/V2b.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. With at least 1.5 OFF hours per day, excluding the early morning pre-first dose OFF&#xD;
             period (i.e. the time between wake-up and response to the first L dopa/DDCI dosage),&#xD;
             as recorded in at least 2 of the 3 days in the self-rating diary for the 3 days&#xD;
             preceding V2a/V2b.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Total PDSS-2 score ≥ 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Adequate compliance to relevant (PD and sleep disorders) concomitant medication during&#xD;
             the screening period (based on the investigator's judgment).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Non-idiopathic PD (atypical parkinsonism, secondary [acquired or symptomatic]&#xD;
             parkinsonism, Parkinson-plus syndrome).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Severe and/or unpredictable OFF periods, according to investigator judgement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Major/prominent non-PD-related sleep disorders (e.g. sleep apnoea or narcolepsy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Treatment with prohibited medication: entacapone, tolcapone, monoamine oxidase (MAO)&#xD;
             inhibitors (except selegiline up to 10 mg/day in oral formulation or 1.25 mg/day in&#xD;
             buccal absorption formulation, rasagiline up to 1 mg/day or safinamide up to 100&#xD;
             mg/day), or antiemetics with antidopaminergic action (except domperidone) within the&#xD;
             last 4 weeks before V1 or likely to be needed at any time until V4.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Treatment with apomorphine within the last 4 weeks before V1 or likely to be needed at&#xD;
             any time until V4.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Previous or current use of opicapone.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Previous or planned (until the end of this study) L-dopa/carbidopa intestinal gel&#xD;
             infusion, deep brain stimulation or stereotactic surgery (e.g. pallidotomy,&#xD;
             thalamotomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Use of any other investigational product (IP), currently or within the 3 months (or&#xD;
             within 5 half-lives of the IP, whichever is longer) before V1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Past (within the past year) or present history of suicidal ideation or suicide&#xD;
             attempts.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Current or previous (within the past year) alcohol or substance abuse excluding&#xD;
             caffeine or nicotine.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Phaeochromocytoma, paraganglioma, or other catecholamine secreting neoplasms.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Known hypersensitivity to the excipients of IP (including lactose intolerance,&#xD;
             galactose intolerance, Lapp lactase deficiency or glucose-galactose malabsorption).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. History of neuroleptic malignant syndrome or non-traumatic rhabdomyolysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. History of severe hepatic impairment (Child-Pugh Class C).&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Previous history of psychosis or psychiatric disorders, including severe major&#xD;
             depression.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Any medical condition that might place the patient at increased risk or interfere with&#xD;
             assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. For females: Pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Employees of the investigator, study centre, sponsor, clinical research organisation&#xD;
             and study consultants, when employees are directly involved in this study or other&#xD;
             studies under the direction of this investigator or study centre, and their family&#xD;
             members.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Persons committed to an institution by virtue of an order issued either by the&#xD;
             judicial or other authorities.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>André Garrido</last_name>
    <phone>229866100</phone>
    <email>andre.garrido@bial.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital da Senhora da Oliveira - Guimarães, E.P.E, Serviço de Neurologia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Guimarães</city>
        <zip>4835-044</zip>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>PI</last_name>
      <email>geral@hospitaldeguimaraes.min-saude.pt</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Portugal</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21312275/</url>
    <description>Parkinson's disease sleep scale--validation of the revised version PDSS-2</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Trenkwalder C, Kohnen R, Högl B, Metta V, Sixel-Döring F, Frauscher B, Hülsmann J, Martinez-Martin P, Chaudhuri KR. Parkinson's disease sleep scale--validation of the revised version PDSS-2. Mov Disord. 2011 Mar;26(4):644-52. doi: 10.1002/mds.23476. Epub 2011 Feb 10.</citation>
    <PMID>21312275</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Wake Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Opicapone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

