<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04981886</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HMS1311</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04981886</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intraocular Pressure Reduction Efficacy of Rhopressa and Lumigan in Normal Tension Glaucoma</brief_title>
  <acronym>NTG</acronym>
  <official_title>Intraocular Pressure Reduction Efficacy of Rhopressa and Lumigan in Normal Tension Glaucoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Salus University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Salus University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Glaucoma is the second leading cause of blindness and the first leading cause of irreversible&#xD;
      vision loss worldwide. The intraocular pressure (IOP) is the only modifiable risk factor for&#xD;
      all the spectrum of glaucoma. Reducing IOP in glaucoma increases the likelihood of preventing&#xD;
      progression of the disease and preserving the quality of life of the patient. Although&#xD;
      prostaglandin analogs (PGAs) and prostamides (PMs) are de facto first-line treatment options&#xD;
      for managing glaucoma, it is a common clinical experience to see their treatment effects&#xD;
      plateau to a level beyond which no clinically significant IOP reduction is likely. It is also&#xD;
      common to find minimal IOP treatment effects in the following conditions: patients with&#xD;
      normal tension glaucoma (NTG), patients with thicker central corneal thickness (CCT), and&#xD;
      patients with higher levels of corneal hysteresis (CH). CH is a possible proxy for the&#xD;
      ability of the scleral tissue around the optic nerve to dissipate energy away from the optic&#xD;
      nerve fibers. Netarsudil, a rho-kinase inhibitor was recently approved by the FDA for the&#xD;
      treatment of glaucoma and ocular hypertension. There is a paucity of research on the efficacy&#xD;
      of netarsudil in patients with NTG, thicker CCT, and higher levels of CH. This study aims to&#xD;
      investigate the above issues by evaluating the efficacy of netarsudil and bimatoprost in&#xD;
      subjects with NTG, thicker corneas, and higher levels of CH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypotheses&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Netarsudil will have non-inferior efficacy compared to Bimatoprost in treating NTG.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Corneal thickness and corneal hysteresis will reduce the efficacy of netarsudil similar&#xD;
           to bimatoprost in NTG.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Netarsudil will change corneal thickness and corneal hysteresis similar to bimatoprost&#xD;
           in NTG.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      CHARACTERISTICS OF THE SUBJECT POPULATION&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Target Accrual. The target number of participants we aim to recruit is one hundred and&#xD;
           fifteen (115). Participants will be recruited from the patient base of Roberts Eyecare&#xD;
           Associates in Vestal, New York, and from referrals from other practices.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Gender of the Subjects. There will be no gender restriction in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Age Range of Adult Subjects. The age range of participants is 21 to 89 years. This age&#xD;
           range is based on the Collaborative Normal Tension Glaucoma Study (CNTGS).&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Age Range of Pediatric Subjects. Not applicable.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Racial and Ethnic Origin. There will be no restriction based on race or ethnicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Vulnerable Subjects. It is not anticipated that the study will include vulnerable&#xD;
           subjects like pregnant persons, breastfeeding persons, persons considering becoming&#xD;
           pregnant, children, prisoners, individuals with impaired decision-making capacity, Salus&#xD;
           employees and/or students. However, if any subject meeting the inclusion criteria is&#xD;
           determined to be a vulnerable subject as defined above, they will be excluded for&#xD;
           participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS AND PROCEDURES&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patient History&#xD;
&#xD;
           The initial examination will include a comprehensive patient history that will include&#xD;
           the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  date of birth&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  race/ethnicity&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  ocular and general medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  list of the medications&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  family ocular and general medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  allergy history&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  social history, including history of smoking, alcohol, and recreational drug use.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Procedures at first visit&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Ocular Response Analyzer (ORA: Reichert ophthalmic instrument, Buffalo, NY, USA):&#xD;
&#xD;
                This test will be used to automatically measure corneal hysteresis (CH), corneal&#xD;
                corrected intraocular pressure (IOPcc), and Goldman equivalent intraocular pressure&#xD;
                (IOPg). At least 5 readings will be taken and the highest 3 wave score readings&#xD;
                above 6.5 will be averaged to get measurements for CH, CRF, IOPcc, and IOPg.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Humphrey's Threshold Visual field test:&#xD;
&#xD;
                The 24-2 threshold Humphrey's visual field analyzer with the sita standard&#xD;
                algorithm will be used to determine the status of visual field for all&#xD;
                participants. Three visual field tests will be conducted to ensure reliability and&#xD;
                repeatability. Visual field test results with &gt; 33% fixation losses, &gt; 33% false&#xD;
                positive, or 33% false negative errors will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Spectral-Domain Optical Coherence Tomography (SD-OCT) Test The SD-OCT is a medical&#xD;
                imaging technique for acquiring high resolution images of the retina and optic&#xD;
                nerve. This instrument emits a broad bandwidth, near infrared light from a&#xD;
                super-luminescent diode onto the retina. Reflected light rays from the retina are&#xD;
                analyzed by interferometry and Fourier-transformed into high resolution&#xD;
                quasi-histologic images of the retina and optic nerve.&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Slit-Lamp Biomicroscopy Slit-lamp examination of the eyes of all participants will&#xD;
                be performed. The slit-lamp utilizes a beam of light and a pair of microscopes to&#xD;
                aid in the detailed examination of the ocular tissues from the external parts of&#xD;
                the eye, the adnexa, to the posterior aspect including the optic nerve and retina.&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. Goldman Applanation Tonometry (GAT) Goldman Applanation Tonometry (GAT). Goldman&#xD;
                applanation tonometry is a routine test for measuring intraocular pressure (IOP).&#xD;
                It is a contact tonometer, therefore, 1 drop of the anesthetic, proparacaine will&#xD;
                be used to numb the eye. Two GAT measurements will be taken. If the readings differ&#xD;
                by more than 2 mmHg, a third measurement will be carried out. The principal&#xD;
                investigator will be masked to the readings. A second optometrist (study&#xD;
                optometrist 1) will record the IOPs and the average of two readings with a&#xD;
                difference ≤ 2 mmHg will be taken.&#xD;
&#xD;
             6. Dynamic contour tonometry (DCT) The DCT is a contact tonometer with a concave tip&#xD;
                which has an electronic sensor. The radius of curvature of the tip is 10.5 mm. An&#xD;
                electronic pressure sensor is integrated into the center of the contacting tip&#xD;
                surface. When the tip of the DCT contacts the corneal surface, it conforms to the&#xD;
                curvature of the tip. This allows the electronic sensor measure IOP independent of&#xD;
                corneal properties. The measured IOP is displayed on the instrument. Two readings&#xD;
                with the best quality scores will be averaged and recorded by a study optometrist&#xD;
                1. The principal investigator will be masked to the IOP readings. Intraocular&#xD;
                pressure (IOP) measured by most tonometers typically have errors associated with&#xD;
                corneal parameters like CCT, CH, and corneal curvature. The DCT will help overcome&#xD;
                the influences of these corneal parameters on IOP measurement.&#xD;
&#xD;
             7. Gonioscopy Gonioscopy is a procedure used to examine the anterior chamber angles of&#xD;
                the eye. The procedure is carried out by means of a contact lens called the Gonio&#xD;
                lens. Gonioscopy will be performed immediately after GAT. A drop of Proparacaine 1%&#xD;
                may be added as needed to prolong local anesthetic effects. Gonioscopy will be used&#xD;
                to rule out other forms of glaucoma like Angle closure glaucoma, Inflammatory&#xD;
                glaucoma, pigmentary, and pseudo-exfoliation glaucoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
             8. Dilated Fundus Examination (DFE) Pupillary dilation will be done with the&#xD;
                instillation of 1% tropicamide in both eyes. Detailed examination of the anterior&#xD;
                chamber, lens, vitreous, optic nerve, macular, retinal up to the periphery of the&#xD;
                retina, will be performed. The purpose of the DFE is to establish the baseline&#xD;
                ocular status and to rule out ocular diseases that may confound the findings of the&#xD;
                study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             9. Systemic blood pressure (BP) The BP of all participants will be measured using an&#xD;
                automatic blood pressure measuring device. The ocular perfusion pressure (OPP) will&#xD;
                be calculated by taking the difference of the systolic blood pressure (SBP) and the&#xD;
                IOP (OPP = SBP - IOP). Arterial pulse amplitude (APA) will be calculated by taking&#xD;
                the difference of the SBP and diastolic BP (DBP) (APA = SBP - DBP).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Adherence to treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
           In order to monitor adherence to treatment, participants will be given a calendar log to&#xD;
           write in the number of drops instilled, the date and time of instillation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Follow-up visit schedule:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Follow-up visits after the onset of treatment will be 2 weeks, 6 weeks, and 3 months&#xD;
           after the onset of treatment. Please see below for what data will be collected for these&#xD;
           follow-up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Procedures to be carried out at follow-up visits The following procedures will be&#xD;
           carried out at all the follow-up visits outlined above.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Assessment of participants' logbook to ensure adherence to treatment. Level of&#xD;
                adherence will be quantified based on the number of drops, and days missed.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  A traditional paper survey will be used to assess possible adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Slit lamp examination to elicit any signs of adverse events and signs of disease&#xD;
                progression.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  GAT to measure IOPs.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  ORA to measure CH, CRF, IOPcc, and IOPg.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  DCT to measure IOP and OPA.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Statistical analysis and sample size calculation&#xD;
&#xD;
           a. Intent-to-treat analyses (ITT) This protocol shall follow the ITT analyses. All&#xD;
           participant data shall be analyzed in the original treatment assignment even if they&#xD;
           discontinue study mid-way or change treatment assignments.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Two sample size calculations were performed. The first was for non-inferiority between&#xD;
           netarsudil and bimatoprost. The second was for a sub-group analysis of the effect of&#xD;
           corneal thickness and CH on the efficacy of both drugs. Since the sub-group analysis&#xD;
           yielded the highest sample size, details were presented here. Subjects were classified&#xD;
           into 2 CCT sub-groups (thin corneas: ≤ 540 µm, thick: &gt; 540 µm) based on the&#xD;
           classification scheme used by Johnson et al (2008). The change in IOP in those with thin&#xD;
           corneas treated with netarsudil will be compared to those with thin corneas treated with&#xD;
           Lumigan. The same comparison will be made for those with thick corneas. An effect size&#xD;
           of 2.4 mmHg was used based on derivation from a SD of 3.0. Assuming a power = 80%, and&#xD;
           an alpha = 0.05, the calculated sample size was 26. Since we have 2 groups (thin and&#xD;
           thick corneas) with 2 treatment arms (netarsudil and bimatoprost), the total calculated&#xD;
           sample size for the 4 groups was 104. A 10% increase was added to the calculated sample&#xD;
           size to account for attrition. The total sample size needed to detect the effects of all&#xD;
           the aims of research is therefore 115.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Data Storage and Confidentiality.&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Data Storage:&#xD;
&#xD;
                Hard copies of data including OCT, Visual field, Ocular Response Analyzer printouts&#xD;
                will be collected and kept in the individual participant record folder. All&#xD;
                individual record folders will be stored in secure, locked metal cabinets. All&#xD;
                digital data will be stored in a password-protected computer. All data will be made&#xD;
                available to the Salus University Institutional Review Board (IRB) upon request.&#xD;
                The analysis of the data for presentation will only show participants ID and age.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Data management:&#xD;
&#xD;
           All data shall be kept in the Essential document folder, and pertinent data from all&#xD;
           individual participant forms shall be stored in a safe, password-protected computer. All&#xD;
           individual participant data will further be aggregated in a spreadsheet, de-identified,&#xD;
           and made ready for analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. RISK/BENEFIT ASSESSMENT&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Potential Risks. The risks involved in the intervention are the same risks patients&#xD;
                are normally exposed to in clinical practice with the treatment of NTG.&#xD;
&#xD;
                Expected risks with the use of netarsudil and bimatoprost include conjunctival&#xD;
                hyperemia, redness, stinging or burning sensation, and dry eyes. Changes in iris&#xD;
                pigmentation could result from the use of bimatoprost.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Risk Classification. The overall risk classification for the study is minimal and&#xD;
                not greater than what is normally experienced in clinical practice. This definition&#xD;
                of minimal risk is in accordance with the Health and Human Services/Food and Drugs&#xD;
                Administration (HHS/FDA) Regulations which classifies minimal risk as &quot;the&#xD;
                probability and magnitude of harm or discomfort anticipated in the research are not&#xD;
                greater in and of themselves than those ordinarily encountered in daily life or&#xD;
                during the performance of routine physical or psychological examinations or tests.&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Protection Against Risks. The safety of treatment will be assessed at every visit&#xD;
                with a patient interview and a thorough eye examination. The study does not have a&#xD;
                Data Safety Monitoring Board (DSMB). However, all adverse events will be promptly&#xD;
                reported to the Salus University IRB.&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Potential Benefits to the Subject. The study protocol involves the treatment of NTG&#xD;
                with standard FDA-approved medical treatment for glaucoma. This is necessary to&#xD;
                prevent progression of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. Potential Benefits to Society. This project may provide evidence for a more&#xD;
                efficacious treatment of NTG. Secondly, it may provide evidence for the adequate&#xD;
                control of IOP in NTG patients with thicker corneas, and or greater CH.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Therapeutic Alternatives. Many therapeutic alternatives exist for the study&#xD;
           participants. These alternatives include, latanoprost, travoprost, latanoprostene bunod,&#xD;
           combigan, timolol, dorzolamide, etc. The therapeutic agents used in this study, and&#xD;
           other agents will also be available to any participant who chooses not to continue in&#xD;
           the study but wishes to continue with the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Risk/Benefit Relationship. netarsudil and bimatoprost have been shown to be efficacious&#xD;
           anti-glaucoma agents. These agents are already being widely used in clinical practice.&#xD;
           The risks posed by these agents do not exceed that of alternatives. The benefits include&#xD;
           reduction of IOPs, and reduction in the risk of progression of glaucoma. The benefits of&#xD;
           this study therefore outweigh the potential risks.&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Financial Compensation for Participation. Subjects who complete the 3 months of&#xD;
           follow-up visit will receive a $20 Target gift card.&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. SUBJECT IDENTIFICATION, RECRUITMENT, AND CONSENT Method of Subject Identification and&#xD;
           Recruitment. Potential participants will be recruited from patients attending regular&#xD;
           clinic at Roberts Eyecare Associates in Vestal New York. Flyers will be designed and&#xD;
           handed to other eyecare practices announcing the clinical trial. All potential&#xD;
           participants will undergo a complete eye examination to determine their eligibility for&#xD;
           inclusion. All those meeting the inclusion criteria will be informed of the study. Those&#xD;
           who agree to participate will be given an informed consent form to read. Only those who&#xD;
           agree to participate after reading and demonstrating understanding of the entailments of&#xD;
           the study and has duly signed, will be recruited.&#xD;
&#xD;
       13. Competing Protocols. After searching the National Institute of Health (NIH) registered&#xD;
           clinical trials, at this time, there seem to be no competing protocol with substantial&#xD;
           eligibility criteria as this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
       14. Subject Competency. All subjects are expected to be competent to give informed consent.&#xD;
           If a subject who meets the eligibility criteria is not competent to give informed&#xD;
           consent, an informed consent shall be sought from the participant's legal healthcare&#xD;
           proxy.&#xD;
&#xD;
       15. Process of Informed Consent. Informed consent will be sought from all subjects to be&#xD;
           recruited for the study. The inform consent will include a detailed explanation of the&#xD;
           purpose of the study in a language that is accessible to a fifth-grade student. It will&#xD;
           also include an explanation of the risks and benefits of the study interventions.&#xD;
           Participants in the study will also be advised of expected adverse events they may&#xD;
           experience. They will be informed of their rights to discontinue participation in the&#xD;
           study at any time. A statement reassuring participants that treatment for glaucoma will&#xD;
           continue even if they choose to leave the study, will also be included in the informed&#xD;
           consent form. Only subjects who have received instructions on the study and have signed&#xD;
           the informed consent form will be recruited for the study. The informed consent form&#xD;
           will be filled at least two weeks before the commencement of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The consent form shall contain no statement penalizing subjects for non-participation,&#xD;
           or statements absolving the study researchers of legal responsibilities in cases of&#xD;
           severe adverse events or misconduct.&#xD;
&#xD;
       16. Subject/Representative Comprehension. All subjects or their legal representatives will&#xD;
           be asked if they understand the content of the informed consent. If they confirm&#xD;
           understanding they will be encouraged to explain, to the best of their understanding,&#xD;
           what the study entails, and the content of the formed consent form. This will include,&#xD;
           purpose of the study, procedures, potential risks, potential benefits, alternatives, and&#xD;
           any other information pertinent to informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
       17. Information Purposely Withheld. No information will be purposely withheld from the&#xD;
           subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
       18. Documentation of Consent/Assent. Edgar U Ekure (OD, MS, FAAO) shall be responsible for&#xD;
           documenting the obtainment of informed consent from the subject.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-treatment IOP</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Change in IOPs (GAT, DCT, and ORA) from baseline.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-treatment IOP change by CCT</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Change in IOPs (GAT, DCT, and ORA) from baseline among subjects with thin and thick corneas.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-treatment IOP change by CH</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Change in IOPs (GAT, DCT, and ORA) from baseline among subjects with the lower and higher 50 percentile of CH.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-treatment change in CCT</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Change in CCT from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-treatment change in CH</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Change in CH from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">115</enrollment>
  <condition>Normal Tension Glaucoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Normal tension glaucoma subjects with thin corneas</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>NTG subjects with CCT ≤ 540 nm will be randomized to receive either netarsudil or bimatoprost.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Normal tension glaucoma subjects with thick corneas</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>NTG subjects with CCT &gt; 540 nm will be randomized to receive either netarsudil or bimatoprost.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Netarsudil Ophthalmic</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will be randomly assigned to this group</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Normal tension glaucoma subjects with thin corneas</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Normal tension glaucoma subjects with thick corneas</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Rhopressa</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bimatoprost Ophthalmic</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will be randomly assigned to this group</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Normal tension glaucoma subjects with thin corneas</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Normal tension glaucoma subjects with thick corneas</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lumigan</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New NTG patients naïve to treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with 360 degrees open angles on gonioscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with glaucomatous optic neuropathies (GON).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with three repeatable visual field defects over two visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have IOPs ≤ 21 mmHg and no recorded IOPs &gt; 21 mmHg at any time.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Glaucomatous optic neuropathy and visual field criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Category 1 and 2 of the glaucoma diagnostic criteria of the International Society of&#xD;
        Geographical and Epidemiological Ophthalmology (ISGEO) will be adopted in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        ISGEO Category 1 classification of glaucoma:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Reliable and repeatable visual field defects consistent with a glaucomatous optic&#xD;
        neuropathy, and either a vertical cup-disc ratio (VCDR) at the 97.5th percentile of the&#xD;
        normal population (about 0.7 VCDR), or VCDR asymmetry between the right and left eyes at&#xD;
        the 97.5th percentile of the normal population (i.e., about 0.2).&#xD;
&#xD;
        ISGEO Category 2 classification of glaucoma:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Visual field results are not definitive or are unattainable due to patient inability to&#xD;
        perform an adequate quality test, and optic disc has VCDR of at the 99.5th percentile of&#xD;
        the normal population (i.e., VCDR of about 0.9) or VCDR asymmetry between the right and&#xD;
        left eyes at the 99.5th percentile of the normal population (i.e a CDR asymmetry of about&#xD;
        0.3).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with IOPs greater than 21 mmHg at any previous point in time&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with corneal pathology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous ocular surgery in the past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any other types of glaucoma other than NTG&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are unwilling or unable to follow-up for a 3-month period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with systemic conditions where a non-glaucomatous optic neuropathy cannot be&#xD;
             ruled out.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are pregnant, breastfeeding, or considering becoming pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who could be pregnant will be screened for pregnancy thus: Those who are not&#xD;
             pregnant nor considering becoming pregnant and are not on any birth-control at the&#xD;
             time of recruitment will be excluded from participation because of the risk of&#xD;
             pregnancy unknown to the patient at the time of recruitment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jingyun Wang, Ph.D</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Salus University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Edgar U Ekure, OD, MS</last_name>
    <phone>3157532421</phone>
    <email>exe0003@salus.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Roberts Eyecare Associates</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vestal</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>13850</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Edgat U Ekure, OD, MS</last_name>
      <phone>315-753-2421</phone>
      <email>exe0003@salus.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Edgar U Ekure, OD, MS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Glaucoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Normal tension glaucoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Intraocular pressure</keyword>
  <keyword>Central corneal thickness</keyword>
  <keyword>Corneal hysteresis</keyword>
  <keyword>Prostaglandin analog</keyword>
  <keyword>Prostamide</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Low Tension Glaucoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bimatoprost</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Raw clean data for statistical analyses&#xD;
Other data will be shared as needed</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>6 months to 1 year after after completion of study</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Access to IPD shall be obtained through email request from Edgar U Ekure (OD, MS, FAAO). Email: exe0003@salus.edu</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

