<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04988711</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HbOxymeter</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04988711</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Non-invasive Tool for Measuring Hemoglobin in Severe Trauma Patients in the ED</brief_title>
  <acronym>HbOxymeter</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Reliability of a Non-invasive Tool for Measuring Hemoglobin in Severe Trauma Patients in the Emergency Room</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hôpital Universitaire Sahloul</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hôpital Universitaire Sahloul</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The development of miniaturized analytical technologies has facilitated the gradual&#xD;
      decentralization of part of the laboratory examinations to the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, investigators are currently seeing the development of tools for non-invasive&#xD;
      measurement of certain biological parameters. Thanks to their ease of use, results are&#xD;
      obtained almost immediately and with good performance. These &quot;rapid&quot; tests or techniques&#xD;
      should, in theory, reduce the time taken to take charge of patients, particularly in&#xD;
      emergencies or in critical situations where the therapeutic decision should be as rapid and&#xD;
      efficient as possible. These means, by their ease and speed of results, could be associated&#xD;
      with the clinical examination of the practitioner to increase his diagnostic performance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      It should be remembered that the journey of samples from the emergency room to the central&#xD;
      laboratory, then the return of results is broken down into three phases: 1) the&#xD;
      pre-analytical phase which includes medical prescription, sampling, request for analysis and&#xD;
      delivery to 'at the central laboratory; 2) the analytical phase, specific to the laboratory,&#xD;
      and which includes handling the sample and the analysis itself. This stage ends with the&#xD;
      provision of the results (computer notification) and 3) the third stage (post analytical)&#xD;
      represents the time between the provision of the results, their reading and their&#xD;
      interpretation. All of these three phases constitute the recognized&#xD;
      prescription-results-treatment time: Therapeutic Turn-around Time (TTAT). The main objective&#xD;
      of these revolutionary techniques is to reduce this time or the duration of these three&#xD;
      stages.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Several techniques, in particular delocalized biology, have been evaluated and validated in&#xD;
      emergencies or even at home. In addition, non-invasive means remain underestimated in terms&#xD;
      of relevance and reliability, mainly by lack of evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These measurement techniques relocated to the patient's bed allow rapid, non-invasive&#xD;
      measurement without the need for intravenous access or the need to draw venous, arterial or&#xD;
      capillary blood. These non-invasive devices can be portable, inexpensive, easy to use, and&#xD;
      offer great benefits especially in emergency departments and pre-hospital settings. The&#xD;
      accuracy of these methods is acceptable in the stable ICU patient. But that remains&#xD;
      unassessed in an emergency.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pulse co-oximetry or low perfusion oximetry is one of these technological advances being&#xD;
      designed to allow the measurement of hemoglobin in a non-invasive manner. In addition, the&#xD;
      automated spectrophotometric detection technique from a blood sample represents the Gold&#xD;
      standard for the measurement of hemoglobin and has been recommended for several decades by&#xD;
      the International Committee for Standardization in Hematology. This technique, performed in a&#xD;
      hematology laboratory, allows precise, reliable and reproducible measurement. However, it&#xD;
      requires a blood sample and above all imposes an incompressible delay. This dosage is one of&#xD;
      the most prescribed samples in current practice in the emergency room. The possibility of&#xD;
      determining the hemoglobin concentration in the patient's bed and non-invasively is a very&#xD;
      attractive solution for the emergency physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The value of such a technique in trauma pathology seems indisputable. In fact, injuries&#xD;
      represent a major problem for public health, representing more than 9% of deaths in the world&#xD;
      each year. In particular, post-traumatic hemorrhage is the most common cause of preventable&#xD;
      deaths, accounting for 50% of preventable deaths in the first 24 hours after major trauma.&#xD;
      Early detection of hypovolaemia due to hemorrhage can be difficult, but essential for the&#xD;
      patient's prognosis through an appropriate and adapted transfusion strategy. The hemoglobin&#xD;
      dosage is essential for the emergency physician. Therefore, in the hospital setting, there is&#xD;
      growing interest in rapid techniques for measuring hemoglobin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, a new device, Pronto-7, a point-controlled pulse CO-oximeter, has been developed.&#xD;
      The Pronto-7 Spot Check Pulse CO-Oximeter has a spectrophotometric sensor (Rainbow DCI) that&#xD;
      detects multiple wavelengths of light. The pulse CO-oximetry method discerns the distinctive&#xD;
      light absorption characteristics of different hemoglobin species and applies proprietary&#xD;
      algorithms to determine hemoglobin levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Few studies have investigated the effectiveness of this non-invasive hemoglobin measurement&#xD;
      tool in trauma patients. No study in Tunisia has looked at the validation of this tool in&#xD;
      terms of reliability, hence the interest of this study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>descriptive</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy</measure>
    <time_frame>during the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The accuracy of Hb Oxymeter</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>the impact Hb Oxymeter</measure>
    <time_frame>during the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>the impact Hb Oxymeter</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Trauma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hb Oxymeter</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Hb mesurment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hb Oxymeter</intervention_name>
    <description>Measurement of Hb Oximeter</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hb Oxymeter</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe trauma patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients having benefited from a blood sample to measure hemoglobin.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients less than 3 years old.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Riadh Boukef, professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CHU Sahloul, Sousse, Tunisia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>HU Sahloul, sousse, Tunisia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sousse</city>
        <state>Itinéraire Ceinture Cité Sahloul</state>
        <zip>4054</zip>
        <country>Tunisia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Riadh Boukef</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sahloul</city>
        <state>Sousse</state>
        <country>Tunisia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Tunisia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hôpital Universitaire Sahloul</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Riadh Boukef</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PROFESSOR</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>all data will be presented in the article publication</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

