<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04985175</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>202104009RINA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04985175</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of Decision Quality by Using Question Prompt List</brief_title>
  <official_title>Impact of Decision Quality by Using Question Prompt List on the Shared Decision Making in End-stage Renal Disease Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Taiwan University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Taiwan University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To investigate the effects of a question prompt list (QPL) on a shared decision-making&#xD;
      consultation among facing decision for dialysis in end-stage renal disease (ESRD) patients. A&#xD;
      randomized controlled trial was conducted at the university medical center of North Taiwan.&#xD;
      Subjects were randomized assigned to QPL group or usual care group. Decisional quality and&#xD;
      decision control preferences were assessed with questionnaires. Measurements were performed&#xD;
      at before the counseling (T0), immediately after counseling (T1), and evaluate decision&#xD;
      regret at one month after treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study was to investigate the effectiveness of decisional quality and&#xD;
      decisional control preferences by using a specific question prompt list (QPL) during a shared&#xD;
      decision-making consultation among facing decision for dialysis in end-stage renal disease&#xD;
      (ESRD) patients. A randomized controlled trial was conducted at the university medical center&#xD;
      of North Taiwan. Recruit subjects are those who are about to receive the nurse-led coaching&#xD;
      of shared decision-making (SDM) for patients with ESRD and attend the program. By using&#xD;
      blocked Randomization design, the investigators assigned participants to QPL group or usual&#xD;
      care. Prior to a clinic visit to discuss treatment, two-pages ESRD QPL leaflets are provided&#xD;
      to QPL group, while usual care group without receiving provision of QPL. Measurements of&#xD;
      outcome included decision quality (decision conflict, decisional self-efficiency) and&#xD;
      decision control preference at before the counseling (T0), immediately after counseling (T1),&#xD;
      and evaluate decision regret at one month after treatment (T2), at this time the patient has&#xD;
      decided and started to accept the selected treatment (hemodialysis, peritoneal dialysis or&#xD;
      conservative treatment). All statistical analyses were performed in SAS statistical software,&#xD;
      version 9.4 (SAS, Cary, NC). The effects of the intervention were assessed by generalized&#xD;
      estimating equation (GEE) analysis with the coefficient of interaction ( group × time) term.&#xD;
      Statistical tests were two-sided with a significance level of 0.05. Hierarchical Linear Model&#xD;
      was used to detect the impact of nested within physician.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Subjects were randomized assigned to QPL group or usual care group.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Decision conflict</measure>
    <time_frame>before the counseling (T0), immediately after counseling(T1)</time_frame>
    <description>Decision conflict was measured by Decision conflict scale(DCS). The scale consists of 16 items into 5 subscales: Uncertainty(3 items), Informed(3 items), values clarity(3 items), support(3 items), and effective decision(4 items) that are rated on a 5-point likert-scale from &quot;strongly agree&quot; (0) to &quot;strongly disagree&quot; (4). The sum of scores are calculated from 0 to 100. The higher the score, the higher the level of decision conflict.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Decisional self-efficiency</measure>
    <time_frame>before the counseling (T0), immediately after counseling(T1)</time_frame>
    <description>Decision self-efficiency was measured by Decisional Self-Efficiency Scale(DSES). The scale represents self-confidence or belief in decision making. The scale consists of 11 items that are rated on a 5-point likert-scale from &quot;not at all confident&quot; (0) to&quot; very confident &quot;(4) . The sum of scores are calculated from 0 to 100. The higher the score, the higher the level of self-confidence.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Decision control preference</measure>
    <time_frame>one month after treatment (T2)</time_frame>
    <description>Decision regret was measured by Decision regret Scale(DRS) .The scale consists of 5 items that are rated on a 5-point likert-scale from &quot;strongly agree &quot;(1) to&quot; strongly disagree&quot; (5) . The sum of scores are calculated from 0 to 100. The higher the score, the higher the level of regret.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Decision control preference</measure>
    <time_frame>before the counseling (T0), immediately after counseling(T1)</time_frame>
    <description>Decision control preference was measured by Decision control preference Scale(DCPS) .The scale asks two question:(1)control preference measured at before the counseling; (2) actual decision control level measured after counseling immediately.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">154</enrollment>
  <condition>Decision Making</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>QPL group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>receive 2-pages ESRD QPL leaflets, circle the questions they want to ask before consultation. encourage asking questions with doctor during consultation. receive the nurse-led coaching of shared decision-making (SDM)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>without receiving provision of QPL encourage asking questions with doctor during consultation. receive the nurse-led coaching of shared decision-making (SDM)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Question prompt list</intervention_name>
    <description>The specific QPS was a one page leaflet for chronic kidney disease which developed by applied literature and public QPL from the National Health Agency. It contains 3 domains 25 questions related to treatment, dialysis, and Kidney transplant. The QPL group participants were asked to read and mark those questions they concerned or write down additional problems.</description>
    <arm_group_label>QPL group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with stage 5 chronic kidney disease who facing decision for dialysis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  normal cognitive functions;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  be able to read, communicate in Mandarin or Taiwanese;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ability to express willingness;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  vision or hearing function impairment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe illness;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Urgent to dialysis for extend life;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dialysis modalities Already decided.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Taiwan University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei City</city>
        <state>Xindian</state>
        <zip>231</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Question prompt list</keyword>
  <keyword>Shared decision making</keyword>
  <keyword>End-stage renal disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Health literacy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

