<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04983498</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STU00214245</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04983498</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Enhanced Recovery Pathway for Endoscopy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of an Enhanced Recovery Pathway for Endoscopy Patients Receiving Moderate Sedation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Northwestern University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Northwestern University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to compare an Enhanced Recovery Pathway to the current&#xD;
      pre-operative/recovery practices of the endoscopy department on patient post-procedure&#xD;
      outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Every 4th to 5th patient that checks in to the endoscopy department for their procedure will&#xD;
      be screened for eligibility requirements. If eligible for the study, the patient will be&#xD;
      informed about the study and potential risks. All patients giving written informed consent&#xD;
      will be enrolled into the enhanced recovery protocol (ERP) [nursing managed ERP:&#xD;
      goal-directed fluid management (Lactated Ringer's Solution at 5mL/kg/hr), PONV prophylaxis&#xD;
      for an apfel score of 2 or greater (ondansetron 4 mg IV), early mobilization up to chair&#xD;
      (within 5-30 minutes of admission to the recovery room), and early PO intake within 15-30&#xD;
      minutes of admission to the recovery room post-procedure] for their procedure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To compare recovery time stamps before and after implementing a modified ERAs for endoscopy patients in the recovery period.</measure>
    <time_frame>1-2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>We will compare mean recovery times between control and intervention groups using analysis of variance (ANOVA).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To compare the incidence of postoperative nausea and vomiting before and after implementing a modified ERAs for endoscopy patients in the recovery period.</measure>
    <time_frame>1-2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>We will perform a Chi-square analysis for presence or absence of nausea and/or vomiting in the recovery period (measured by: administration of anti-emetic, documentation on N/V flowchart, and/or documentation in nursing narrative note) between control and intervention groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To compare patient satisfaction scores before and after implementing a modified ERAs for endoscopy patients in the recovery period.</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>We will perform a t-test of patient satisfaction scores (Press Ganey scores) between control and intervention groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Enhanced Recovery Pathway</condition>
  <condition>Endoscopy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective Experimental Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>For the experimental group, we will recruit 200 participants who will receive the Enhanced Recovery Pathway, which will be ordered as a standing order set by the attending provider and managed by their peri-procedural nurses. The modified ERP for this study includes the following interventions: nursing managed order sets with ERP instructions to receive goal-directed fluid management within anesthesia approved parameters utilizing the NMH Colorectal ERAS protocol for IV fluid administration, PONV prophylaxis for participants with an apfel score of 2 or greater (ondansetron 4 mg IV), an additional dose of ondansetron 4mg IV will be available in recovery if the patient has nausea/vomiting despite prophylaxis, early mobilization up to chair (within 5-30 minutes of admission to the recovery room) based on nursing parameters, and early PO intake within 15-30 minutes of admission to the recovery room post-procedure based on nursing parameters.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Retrospective Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The retrospective group will consist of 200 randomly selected medical records of patients who had colonoscopy procedures for a 6 month period prior to study implementation (between 10/1/2019 to 4/1/2020). The retrospective control group will have received the current standard of care including: IV fluids for management of intra-procedural hypotension as indicated/ordered by the physician, PO intake at 30-45 minutes, up to a chair at 60 minutes, and all procedure related complications will have been treated (e.g. PONV) per physician order as is the current standard of practice in the GI Lab recovery area.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ondansetron 4 MG</intervention_name>
    <description>PONV prophylaxis for participants with an apfel score of 2 or greater (ondansetron 4 mg IV), an additional dose of ondansetron 4mg IV will be available in recovery if the patient has nausea/vomiting despite prophylaxis.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective Experimental Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Post-operative Nausea &amp; Vomiting Prophylaxis</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lactated Ringers, Intravenous</intervention_name>
    <description>Goal directed IV fluids to be administered starting preop per the NMH Colorectal ERAS protocol (LR @ 5mL/kg/hr).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective Experimental Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Intravenous Hydration</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Early Mobilization</intervention_name>
    <description>Patient transferred up to the chair (within 5-30 minutes of admission to the recovery room) based on nursing parameters and patient safety.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective Experimental Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Early PO Intake</intervention_name>
    <description>Patient will be offered PO intake within 15-30 minutes of admission to the recovery room post-procedure based on nursing parameters and patient safety.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective Experimental Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Outpatient colonoscopy under moderate sedation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Colonoscopy Indications: Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  More than one sedation procedure scheduled same day&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to ondansetron&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Past PONV requiring scopolamine patches&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnoses: ESRD, heart failure, cirrhosis, long QT syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients requiring fluid restrictions, such as dialysis patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Post-procedure NPO requirements, such as procedure-related NPO status (stent&#xD;
             placement, pneumatic dilation, etc.) or second procedure in another location&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High Fall Risk Patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults unable to consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Angela Maeder, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Northwestern Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Chelsea Robinson</last_name>
    <phone>312-926-7594</phone>
    <email>chelsea.robinson@nm.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Northwestern Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60611</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Chelsea Robinson</last_name>
      <phone>312-926-7594</phone>
      <email>chelsea.robinson@nm.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alghanem SM, Massad IM, Rashed EM, Abu-Ali HM, Daradkeh SS. Optimization of anesthesia antiemetic measures versus combination therapy using dexamethasone or ondansetron for the prevention of postoperative nausea and vomiting. Surg Endosc. 2010 Feb;24(2):353-8. doi: 10.1007/s00464-009-0567-3. Epub 2009 Jun 11.</citation>
    <PMID>19517165</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Amornyotin S. Sedation-related complications in gastrointestinal endoscopy. World J Gastrointest Endosc. 2013 Nov 16;5(11):527-33. doi: 10.4253/wjge.v5.i11.527.</citation>
    <PMID>24255744</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brown JK, Singh K, Dumitru R, Chan E, Kim MP. The Benefits of Enhanced Recovery After Surgery Programs and Their Application in Cardiothoracic Surgery. Methodist Debakey Cardiovasc J. 2018 Apr-Jun;14(2):77-88. doi: 10.14797/mdcj-14-2-77. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29977464</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Apfel CC, Korttila K, Abdalla M, Kerger H, Turan A, Vedder I, Zernak C, Danner K, Jokela R, Pocock SJ, Trenkler S, Kredel M, Biedler A, Sessler DI, Roewer N; IMPACT Investigators. A factorial trial of six interventions for the prevention of postoperative nausea and vomiting. N Engl J Med. 2004 Jun 10;350(24):2441-51.</citation>
    <PMID>15190136</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ellett ML. Review of propofol and auxiliary medications used for sedation. Gastroenterol Nurs. 2010 Jul-Aug;33(4):284-95; quiz 296-7. doi: 10.1097/SGA.0b013e3181eac371. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20679780</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Crenshaw JT, Winslow EH. Preoperative fasting: old habits die hard. Am J Nurs. 2002 May;102(5):36-44; quiz 45.</citation>
    <PMID>12006853</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gan TJ. Postoperative nausea and vomiting--can it be eliminated? JAMA. 2002 Mar 13;287(10):1233-6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11886298</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Joliat GR, Ljungqvist O, Wasylak T, Peters O, Demartines N. Beyond surgery: clinical and economic impact of Enhanced Recovery After Surgery programs. BMC Health Serv Res. 2018 Dec 29;18(1):1008. doi: 10.1186/s12913-018-3824-0.</citation>
    <PMID>30594252</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lichtenstein GR, Cohen LB, Uribarri J. Review article: Bowel preparation for colonoscopy--the importance of adequate hydration. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2007 Sep 1;26(5):633-41. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17697197</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ljungqvist O, Scott M, Fearon KC. Enhanced Recovery After Surgery: A Review. JAMA Surg. 2017 Mar 1;152(3):292-298. doi: 10.1001/jamasurg.2016.4952. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28097305</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Saraghi M. Intraoperative Fluids and Fluid Management for Ambulatory Dental Sedation and General Anesthesia. Anesth Prog. 2015 Winter;62(4):168-76; quiz 177. doi: 10.2344/0003-3006-62.4.168. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26650497</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shaikh SI, Nagarekha D, Hegade G, Marutheesh M. Postoperative nausea and vomiting: A simple yet complex problem. Anesth Essays Res. 2016 Sep-Dec;10(3):388-396. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27746521</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Som A, Bhattacharjee S, Maitra S, Arora MK, Baidya DK. Combination of 5-HT3 Antagonist and Dexamethasone Is Superior to 5-HT3 Antagonist Alone for PONV Prophylaxis After Laparoscopic Surgeries: A Meta-analysis. Anesth Analg. 2016 Dec;123(6):1418-1426. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27870735</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weinberg L, Faulkner M, Tan CO, Liu DH, Tay S, Nikfarjam M, Peyton P, Story D. Fluid prescription practices of anesthesiologists managing patients undergoing elective colonoscopy: an observational study. BMC Res Notes. 2014 Jun 10;7:356. doi: 10.1186/1756-0500-7-356.</citation>
    <PMID>24916073</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Northwestern University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Angela Maeder</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PhD, RNC-OB, Clinical Nurse, Labor and Delivery Northwestern Memorial Hospital</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ondansetron</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

