<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04986670</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PR0340</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04986670</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>NutriCare Plus a Medically Tailored Meal Intervention Among Patients With Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>NutriCare Intervention on Optimizing Nutritional Status, Reducing Treatment-Related Toxicities, and Improving Quality of Life Among Vulnerable Patients With Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tufts University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Fox Chase Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ohio State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Tufts Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tufts University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The NutriCare study aims to develop, implement, and evaluate the efficacy of an innovative&#xD;
      intervention strategy (medically tailored meals plus nutrition counseling) to integrate&#xD;
      nutrition into the standard of care for oncology to improve outcomes of vulnerable patients&#xD;
      with lung cancer. The NutriCare study evaluates the efficacy of the intervention on&#xD;
      optimizing nutritional status, reducing treatment-related toxicities, and improving the&#xD;
      quality of life of patients with lung cancer who are economically disadvantaged, uninsured,&#xD;
      racial and ethnic minorities, elderly, and/or rural residents from four major medical centers&#xD;
      in diverse regions of the United States (U.S.).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 24, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>For the proposed study, we will randomize participants into two groups at a 1:1 ratio to an intervention or an enhanced control group. For participants randomized to the enhanced control group, the NutriTool, the oncology care team will provide participants with a nutrition toolkit involving printed educational materials. For participants randomized to the intervention group, the NutriCare, the oncology care team will additionally provide participants with home-delivery of medically tailored meals and referral to registered dietitians (RDs) for remotely-delivered nutrition counseling.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Nutritional Intake</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3-month, and 8-month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in diet quality and intake of key food groups and nutrients as assessed by the National Cancer Institute Diet History Questionnaire (DHQ III)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Weight</measure>
    <time_frame>Recorded at each clinical visit. From date of beginning baseline until the date of completing the 8-month study visit, an average of 3-4 clinic visits dependent on course of treatment.</time_frame>
    <description>Change in weight and percent weight loss as measured in the clinic</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment Compliance</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of beginning baseline until the date of completing the 8-month study visit or date of censoring from any cause, whichever comes first, assessed up to 8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Treatment completion (dose reductions and treatment delays) assessed by the treating medical oncologist</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment-related Toxicities</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of beginning baseline until the date of completing the 8-month study visit or date of censoring from any cause, whichever comes first, assessed up to 8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Treatment-related toxicities assessed by the treating medical oncologist using the National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalizations and ED visits</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of beginning baseline until the date of completing the 8-month study visit or date of censoring from any cause, whichever comes first, assessed up to 8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Hospitalizations and ED visits assessed by medical record review and linkage with discharge data</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported Symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3-month, and 8-month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in patient-reported symptoms (fatigue, pain, nausea, vomiting, appetite loss, and sleep disturbance) as assessed by a Patient-Reported Outcomes version of the CTCAE (PRO-CTCAE)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3-month, and 8-month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in quality of life as assessed by EORTC-QLQ-30</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3-month, and 8-month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in quality of life as assessed by EORTC-QLQ-LC13</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported Functional Outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3-month, and 8-month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in patient-reported functional outcomes (physical, social, and cognitive functioning) assessed by GAD-7</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported Functional Outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3-month, and 8-month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in patient-reported functional outcomes (physical, social, and cognitive functioning) assessed by PHQ-9</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Food Insecurity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3-month, and 8-month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in food insecurity measured by the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) Household Food Security Survey</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gut Microbial Composition</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3-month, and 8-month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in gut microbiome via metagenomic whole shotgun sequencing (mWGS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Program Implementation</measure>
    <time_frame>From consent through study completion, 8-months</time_frame>
    <description>(a) participation; (b) retention; (c) compliance</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Cancer, Small Cell</condition>
  <condition>Lung Cancer Metastatic</condition>
  <condition>Lung Cancer Recurrent</condition>
  <condition>Treatment Side Effects</condition>
  <condition>Lung Cancer, Non-small Cell</condition>
  <condition>Nutritional Imbalance</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NutriCare</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The oncology care team will provide participants with nutrition toolkit involving printed educational materials, a nutrition prescription, referral to registered dietitians (RDs) for remotely-delivered medical nutrition therapy counseling, and home-delivery of medically tailored meals.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NutriTool</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The oncology care team will provide participants with a nutrition toolkit involving printed educational materials.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nutritional Counseling</intervention_name>
    <description>Medical oncology providers will refer participants to oncology RDs for remotely-delivered motivational interviewing-based nutrition counseling to address participants individualized nutritional needs. After baseline visits, participants assigned to the NutriCare group will be contacted by a RD for a phone-based orientation where the RD will discuss nutrition assessment results, and assess participant values, ambivalence, readiness to change, and arrive at a mutually agreeable nutrition care plan. Participants will be contacted weekly during the first 6 months of the intervention (Active Phase) and contacted every other week during the next 2 months of the intervention (Maintenance Phase).</description>
    <arm_group_label>NutriCare</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Medically Tailored Meals (MTMs)</intervention_name>
    <description>Medically tailored meals will be provided to participants in the intervention group for a total of 24 weeks. During the first 8 weeks of the intervention, 3 meals/day will be provided each week for a total of 168 meals per participant. It will be followed by less frequent meal provision during the subsequent 16 weeks following this schedule: 3 meals/day will be provided every other week for the next 8 weeks (a total of 84 meals per participant); and 3 meals/day will be provided every four weeks during the last 8 weeks (a total of 42 meals per participant). Upon the completion of the meal provision, the RD team will continue providing nutrition counseling for another 8 weeks that aims to promote self-efficacy in home meal preparation and adherence to the evidence-based dietary pattern guidelines.</description>
    <arm_group_label>NutriCare</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nutrition Prescription</intervention_name>
    <description>Oncology providers will advise participants with lung cancer to follow evidence-based nutrition recommendations using a Nutrition Prescription. The Nutrition Prescription aims to enhance providers' role in communicating basic nutrition advice to participants with lung cancer. It contains seven recommendations, adapted from the newly released Cancer Prevention Recommendations by WCRF/AICR with strong evidence-base.</description>
    <arm_group_label>NutriCare</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nutrition Assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>Oncology care providers will assess the nutritional status of patients with lung cancer using PG-SGA Short Form (the Scored Patient-Generated Subjective Global Assessment). PG-SGA is an interdisciplinary patient assessment in oncology and other chronic catabolic conditions. The short form contains four patient generated historical components (weight history, food intake symptoms, and activities and function).</description>
    <arm_group_label>NutriCare</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nutrition Toolkit</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive a printed copy of a Nutrition Toolkit from providers. Evidence-based nutrition recommendations have been compiled for cancer survivors from 4 sources into a Nutrition Toolkit. The sources include: (1) AmericanCancer Society (ACS) Nutrition and Physical Activity Guidelines for Cancer Survivors; (2)World Cancer Research Fund / American Institute for Cancer Research (WFRF/AICR) Cancer Nutrition Guide; (3) National Cancer Institute (NCI) Eating Hints; and (4) National Comprehensive Cancer Network (NCCN) Guidelines for Cancer Survivors. The Nutrition Toolkit outlines topics about the impact of cancer treatment on dietary intake patterns and quality, strategies to manage treatment-related eating issues, maintaining a healthy weight post treatment, and evidence-based recommendations and practical. Nutrition Toolkit strategies for improving diet quality and maintaining an optimal weight for cancer survivors.</description>
    <arm_group_label>NutriCare</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>NutriTool</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Monthly Emails</intervention_name>
    <description>Monthly emails will be sent to participants to encourage the use of the toolkit with healthy recipes and general nutrition information.</description>
    <arm_group_label>NutriCare</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>NutriTool</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adults (18+ years of age)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Newly diagnosed patients with lung cancer (non-small cell and small cell lung cancer):&#xD;
&#xD;
             o Patients with stages I-III lung cancer: Eligible at diagnosis for up to 6 weeks&#xD;
             after: 1) starting multimodality therapy with combination chemoradiation or&#xD;
             chemoradiation followed by surgery; or 2) starting adjuvant therapy after lung&#xD;
             resection (chemotherapy alone or chemotherapy followed by radiation therapy)&#xD;
&#xD;
             o Patients with stage IV lung cancer or recurrent/metastatic: Eligible at diagnosis&#xD;
             and for up to 3 months after starting treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
             o Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status (PS) 0-3&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Vulnerable patients who meet at least one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Economically disadvantaged (household gross monthly income at or below 130% of&#xD;
                  the Federal Poverty Level)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Racial and ethnic minorities (African Americans, American Indians and Alaska&#xD;
                  Natives, Asians and Pacific Islanders, and Hispanics)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No health insurance&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Elderly patients (ages 65 years or older)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Reside in rural areas (non-metropolitan counties with less than 50,000 people)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Voluntarily provide consent, HIPPA authorization form, and consent from treating&#xD;
             oncologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Able to speak and read English themselves or with minimal help.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Able to receive medically-tailored meals for the course of the study if being assigned&#xD;
             to the intervention arm, and willing to sign the MTM agreement.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Cognitively unable to consent or have physical or mental limitations that would&#xD;
             prevent full participation in the program.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have medical conditions that significantly impact digestion, metabolism, or food&#xD;
             intake (e.g., surgical loss of esophagus, stomach, or colon; pancreas dysfunction;&#xD;
             brain surgery that alters cognition; severe food allergies; etc.) or have active&#xD;
             metabolic or digestive illnesses (i.e., Celiac disease, IBS, renal insufficiency,&#xD;
             hepatic insufficiency).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pregnant or planning to become pregnant during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Unable to receive medically-tailored meals for the course of the study if being&#xD;
             assigned to the intervention arm, including lack of a permanent address to which meals&#xD;
             can be delivered (a friend or home address is acceptable given it is used on a&#xD;
             consistent basis), not having a fully functioning kitchen with a microwave or oven for&#xD;
             cooking, not having a standard-sized refrigerator with a freezer with storage capacity&#xD;
             to hold one week's worth of meals; or unwilling to sign the MTM agreement.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>FangFang Zhang, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Tufts University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Colleen Spees, PhD, MEd, RD, LD, FAND</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ohio State University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Fang Fang Zhang, MD,PhD</last_name>
    <phone>6176363706</phone>
    <email>Fang_Fang.zhang@tufts.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Mary Cohen, MS,RD</last_name>
    <email>mary_kathryn.cohen@tufts.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tufts Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02111</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lori Pai, MD</last_name>
      <phone>617-636-4143</phone>
      <email>LPai@tuftsmedicalcenter.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lori Pai, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The James Cancer Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carolyn Presley, MD</last_name>
      <phone>614-293-6453</phone>
      <email>carolyn.presley@osumc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Carolyn Presley, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fox Chase Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19111</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jessica Bauman, MD</last_name>
      <phone>215-728-4297</phone>
      <email>Jessica.Bauman@fccc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jessica Bauman, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Joya Chandra, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>713-563-5405</phone>
      <email>jchandra@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joya Chandra, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 30, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Tufts University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Fang Fang Zhang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor, The Neely Family Professor and Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>malnutrition</keyword>
  <keyword>vulnerability</keyword>
  <keyword>medically tailored meals</keyword>
  <keyword>nutrition counseling</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>June 15, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/70/NCT04986670/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

