<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04985929</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro000108975</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04985929</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Impact of Sildenafil on the Pulmonary Circulation in Healthy Trained and Untrained Humans</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Impact of the Vasodilator, Sildenafil, on the Pulmonary Circulation During Exercise in Healthy Trained and Untrained Humans</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alberta</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alberta</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There is emerging evidence suggesting that the pulmonary vasculature and right heart may play&#xD;
      a role in the limitation of exercise capacity in healthy individuals. It is well established&#xD;
      that aerobic training improves cardiovascular function. While the pulmonary system is&#xD;
      integral to the function of the cardiopulmonary system, it has been traditionally accepted&#xD;
      that lung function does not respond to exercise training. However, recent research suggests&#xD;
      pulmonary vascular function adaptations may occur with aerobic training, and this may&#xD;
      contribute to enhanced exercise tolerance. Research has highlighted that increased capillary&#xD;
      blood volume (Vc) and diffusion capacity for carbon monoxide (DLCO) are correlated with&#xD;
      higher cardiorespiratory fitness at rest. Additionally, endurance trained participants have&#xD;
      increased exercise DLCO concomitant to higher resting Vc when compared to untrained&#xD;
      participants, and during exercise this difference seems to be driven by higher membrane&#xD;
      diffusing capacity (Dm), independent of Vc or VA (alveolar volume). Of importance is also the&#xD;
      evidence that highlights endurance trained participants having reduced pulmonary arterial&#xD;
      pressures at rest and during exercise. Reduced pulmonary arterial pressure in endurance&#xD;
      trained participants despite endurance trained participants consistently displaying increased&#xD;
      diffusion capacity/pulmonary perfusion at rest and during exercise suggests a lower threshold&#xD;
      pressure for pulmonary capillary recruitment. Together, this cross-sectional evidence&#xD;
      suggests improvements in the pulmonary circulation due to exercise training in order to&#xD;
      facilitate gas exchange. Whether this apparent improvement in pulmonary circulation is due to&#xD;
      enhanced pulmonary vascular function via NO mediated vasodilation must be determined&#xD;
      experimentally. If sildenafil administration improves DLCO, Vc, and Dm, this would provide&#xD;
      evidence that the NO mediated vasodilatory pathway plays a role in the regulation of vascular&#xD;
      tone, function, and perfusion across the pulmonary vasculature. Should a larger response to&#xD;
      sildenafil be observed in untrained persons, this would suggest better baseline vascular&#xD;
      function in trained participants compared to untrained. This would provide strong evidence&#xD;
      that aerobic training improves pulmonary vasculature function which is contrary to the&#xD;
      conventional understanding of aerobic training on the cardiopulmonary system.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is emerging evidence suggesting that the pulmonary vasculature and right heart may play&#xD;
      a role in the limitation of exercise capacity in healthy individuals. It is well established&#xD;
      that aerobic training improves cardiovascular function. While the pulmonary system is&#xD;
      integral to the function of the cardiopulmonary system, it has been traditionally accepted&#xD;
      that lung function does not respond to exercise training. However, recent research suggests&#xD;
      pulmonary vascular function adaptations may occur with aerobic training, and this may&#xD;
      contribute to enhanced exercise tolerance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research has highlighted that increased capillary blood volume (Vc) and diffusion capacity&#xD;
      for carbon monoxide (DLCO) are correlated with higher cardiorespiratory fitness at rest.&#xD;
      Additionally, endurance trained participants have increased exercise DLCO concomitant to&#xD;
      higher resting Vc when compared to untrained participants, and during exercise this&#xD;
      difference seems to be driven by higher membrane diffusing capacity (Dm), independent of Vc&#xD;
      or VA (alveolar volume). Of importance is also the evidence that highlights endurance trained&#xD;
      participants having reduced pulmonary arterial pressures at rest and during exercise. Reduced&#xD;
      pulmonary arterial pressure in endurance trained participants despite endurance trained&#xD;
      participants consistently displaying increased diffusion capacity/pulmonary perfusion at rest&#xD;
      and during exercise suggests a lower threshold pressure for pulmonary capillary recruitment.&#xD;
      Together, this cross-sectional evidence suggests improvements in the pulmonary circulation&#xD;
      due to exercise training in order to facilitate gas exchange. Whether this apparent&#xD;
      improvement in pulmonary circulation is due to enhanced pulmonary vascular function via NO&#xD;
      mediated vasodilation must be determined experimentally. If sildenafil administration&#xD;
      improves DLCO, Vc, and Dm, this would provide evidence that the NO mediated vasodilatory&#xD;
      pathway plays a role in the regulation of vascular tone, function, and perfusion across the&#xD;
      pulmonary vasculature. Should a larger response to sildenafil be observed in untrained&#xD;
      persons, this would suggest better baseline vascular function in trained participants&#xD;
      compared to untrained. This would provide strong evidence that aerobic training improves&#xD;
      pulmonary vasculature function which is contrary to the conventional understanding of aerobic&#xD;
      training on the cardiopulmonary system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some investigations on the pulmonary vasculature have been completed with the known pulmonary&#xD;
      vasodilator, sildenafil. Sildenafil administration has been shown to reduce pulmonary artery&#xD;
      pressure and improve exercise tolerance in normobaric hypoxic conditions in young healthy&#xD;
      individuals. Further, one of these investigations determined sildenafil did not alter maximal&#xD;
      oxygen consumption (V̇O2peak) in normoxia in moderately fit participants; however, this study&#xD;
      was likely underpowered to detect a response. While some sildenafil interventional work has&#xD;
      been conducted, no study to date has determined the effect of sildenafil on DLCO, Vc, and Dm&#xD;
      during exercise in untrained vs. trained participants. If sildenafil administration improves&#xD;
      DLCO, Vc, and Dm, this would provide evidence that the NO mediated vasodilatory pathway plays&#xD;
      a role in the regulation of vascular tone, function, and perfusion across the pulmonary&#xD;
      vasculature. Should a larger response to sildenafil be observed in untrained persons, this&#xD;
      would suggest better baseline vascular function in trained participants compared to&#xD;
      untrained. This would provide strong evidence that aerobic training improves pulmonary&#xD;
      vasculature function which is contrary to the conventional understanding of aerobic training&#xD;
      on the cardiopulmonary system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Purpose&#xD;
&#xD;
      To examine the effects of the pulmonary vasodilator sildenafil on DLCO, Vc, and Dm in trained&#xD;
      and untrained participants at rest and during exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis&#xD;
&#xD;
      If sildenafil administration improves DLCO, Vc, and Dm, this would provide evidence that the&#xD;
      NO mediated vasodilatory pathway plays a role in the regulation of vascular tone, function,&#xD;
      and perfusion across the pulmonary vasculature. Should a larger response to sildenafil be&#xD;
      observed in untrained persons, this would suggest better baseline vascular function in&#xD;
      trained participants compared to untrained. This would provide strong evidence that aerobic&#xD;
      training improves pulmonary vasculature function which is contrary to the conventional&#xD;
      understanding of aerobic training on the cardiopulmonary system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Design&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomized, double-blinded, placebo controlled cross-over design.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Trial Treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment: Sildenafil (oral), 50 mg Placebo: Medical grade placebo pill&#xD;
&#xD;
      Duration&#xD;
&#xD;
      This randomized, double-blind, placebo controlled, cross-over, cross-sectional study will&#xD;
      include 6 sessions and will be a crossover design with participants acting as their own&#xD;
      controls. All exercise protocols will be conducted on an electronically braked cycle&#xD;
      ergometer and will begin with a standardized warm-up and end with a standardized cool-down.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Session 1) During session 1, participants will provide informed consent and health screening&#xD;
      (PAR-Q+), be familiarized to the laboratory and experimental measurement protocols, conduct a&#xD;
      pulmonary function test, and conduct an incremental maximal exercise test to determine&#xD;
      V̇O2peak on the cycle ergometer. A small blood sample will be collected via finger prick to&#xD;
      measure hemoglobin (to correct DLCO). Specific relative workloads will be calculated&#xD;
      cardiorespiratory and power output data obtained from the V̇O2peak protocol conducted during&#xD;
      session 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Session 2 and 3) During sessions 2 and 3, participants will ingest either a placebo or 50 mg&#xD;
      sildenafil, then rest a minimum of 30 minutes. Testing will start with measurement of resting&#xD;
      diffusion capacity, pulmonary capillary blood volume (Vc), and membrane diffusion capacity&#xD;
      (Dm) using the multiple fractional inspired oxygen (FIO2)-DLCO technique, with the order of&#xD;
      FIO2 administration randomized and the participant in supine position. Supine DLCO&#xD;
      measurements are to determine maximal resting DLCO and to quantify the impact of postural&#xD;
      change on participant DLCO. Next, participants will complete resting baseline DLCO&#xD;
      measurements seated on the cycle ergometer, followed by an absolute workload protocol with&#xD;
      the exercise intensity set at 60 Watts for a duration of ten minutes. A small blood sample&#xD;
      will be collected via finger prick to measure hemoglobin (to correct DLCO). During the&#xD;
      absolute workload protocol, measurements will occur after the 4th minute of exercise, in&#xD;
      order to allow verification of measurement equipment operation during exercise and to give&#xD;
      the participant sufficient time to warm-up and hit steady state. Steady state will be defined&#xD;
      as minute-by-minute change in heart rate ≤ 5 bpm. A minimum of 9 and no more than 12&#xD;
      breath-holds will be performed during this session. The order of sessions 2 and 3 will be&#xD;
      randomized and the participant and laboratory technicians will be blinded to the&#xD;
      administration of the pharmacological intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Session 4 and 5) During sessions 4 and 5, participants will ingest either a placebo or 50 mg&#xD;
      sildenafil, rest a minimum of 30 minutes, and then complete exercise DLCO sessions. The&#xD;
      exercise DLCO sessions will include exercise intensities set at 30%, 60%, and 90% of&#xD;
      individual V̇O2peak with the order of FIO2 administration and workload randomized. A minimum&#xD;
      of 9 and no more than 12 breath-holds will be performed during this session. DLCO&#xD;
      measurements will be taken after participants have attained steady-state at each workload. A&#xD;
      small blood sample will be collected via finger prick to measure hemoglobin (to correct&#xD;
      DLCO). Participants will complete active recovery (&lt;100W) between workloads to minimize&#xD;
      fatigue and metabolite accumulation similar to previous work. The order of sessions 4 and 5&#xD;
      will be randomized and the participant and laboratory technicians will be blinded to the&#xD;
      administration of the pharmacological intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Session 6) During session 6, participants will undergo echocardiography measurements at rest&#xD;
      and during exercise after taking placebo and sildenafil. The order of drug administration&#xD;
      during this session will not be randomized. Resting echocardiography will be conducted during&#xD;
      quiet seated rest and exercise will be conducted exercising at 60 Watts, both on the same&#xD;
      cycle ergometer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Session 1 is anticipated to take ~2 hours. Sessions 2 and 3 are anticipated to take ~1.5&#xD;
      hours. Sessions 4 and 5 are anticipated to take 2 hours. Session 6 is anticipated to take 2&#xD;
      hours. The anticipated total study duration is ~11 hours. All sessions will be planned within&#xD;
      a 6-week timeframe.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be analyzed using commercially available software. A priori α = 0.05. Diffusion&#xD;
      capacity response will be analyzed by group mean analysis with a two-way repeated measures&#xD;
      ANOVA with the groupings as HI-FIT and LO-FIT (key variables DLCO, Dm, Vc) across all&#xD;
      exercise intensities, consistent with previous work with similar methods and primary&#xD;
      outcomes. Post-hoc testing will be conducted via Holm-Sidak method. The same approach will be&#xD;
      used to determine differences in key variables from echocardiography (e.g. PASP).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled cross-over design</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double-blind, placebo-controlled</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Diffusion capacity of carbon monoxide (DLCO)</measure>
    <time_frame>Minimum of 30 minutes post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>Diffusion capacity of carbon monoxide (DLCO) in selected body positions and exercise intensities. DLCO is measured with the Roughton-Forster Multiple FIO2 single-breath DLCO procedure.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Capillary blood volume (Vc)</measure>
    <time_frame>Minimum of 30 minutes post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>Capillary blood volume is a component of DLCO and is measured with the Roughton-Forster Multiple FIO2 single-breath DLCO procedure.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Membrane diffusing capacity (Dm)</measure>
    <time_frame>Minimum of 30 minutes post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>Membrane diffusing capacity is a component of DLCO and is measured with the Roughton-Forster Multiple FIO2 single-breath DLCO procedure.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pulmonary artery systolic pressure (PASP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Minimum of 30 minutes post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>Pulmonary artery systolic pressure at rest and during exercise as determined via echocardiography.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy, Untrained</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Untrained participants will be defined as having a V̇O2peak of 30-45 ml.kg-1.min-1 and will be between 18-40 years of age.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy, Trained</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Trained participants will be defined as having a V̇O2peak above 55 ml.kg-1.min-1 (females) and 60 ml.kg-1.min-1 (males) and will be between 18-40 years of age.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sildenafil 50 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>Sildenafil is a phosphodiesterase type-5 inhibitor, which augments/prolongs the naturally occurring nitric oxide mediated vasodilatory pathway. Sildenafil pill is over-encapsulated to be identical in appearance to the placebo intervention.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy, Trained</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy, Untrained</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Accel-Sildenafil - 50 mg</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Medical-grade placebo pill, over-encapsulated to be identical in appearance to the sildenafil intervention.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy, Trained</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy, Untrained</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Untrained participants will be defined as having a V̇O2peak of 30-45 ml.kg-1.min-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Trained participants will be defined as having a V̇O2peak above 55 ml.kg-1.min-1&#xD;
             (females) and 60 ml.kg-1.min-1 (males).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All participants will be between the ages of 18-40 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute contraindication to exercise testing or an orthopedic condition that may&#xD;
             limit exercise testing as identified by standardized health screening tool (PAR-Q+).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existing cardiac conditions (heart failure, congenital heart defect, valvular&#xD;
             disease) that may limit exercise testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A diagnosis of pulmonary hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current prescription drug use (excluding oral contraception for females).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or lactation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential must be willing to use an acceptable method of&#xD;
             contraception to avoid pregnancy throughout the study. Acceptable methods of&#xD;
             contraception include tubal ligation, oral contraceptive, barrier methods&#xD;
             (intra-uterine device, diaphragm, female condom, male condom). Abstinence is an&#xD;
             acceptable form of contraception, only insofar as patients agree to use another&#xD;
             acceptable method of birth control, preferably a barrier method, if they become&#xD;
             sexually active.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Postmenopausal female participants must be amenorrheic for ≥12 months.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sean van Diepen, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alberta</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael K Stickland, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alberta</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Desi P Fuhr, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>7804921121</phone>
    <email>fuhr@ualberta.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Cameron M Ehnes, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>7804921121</phone>
    <email>cmehnes@ualberta.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Physiology Laboratory</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edmonton</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T6G2R3</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Desi Fuhr, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>780-492-1121</phone>
      <email>fuhr@ualberta.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Michael K Stickland, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>780-492-3995</phone>
      <email>michael.stickland@ualberta.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sildenafil Citrate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>No IPD sharing plan.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

