<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04985513</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>05-2021-156</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04985513</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>EIT Based Regional Lung Ventilation in Minimally Invasive Cardiac Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Electrical Impedance Tomography Based Regional Lung Ventilation Evaluation According to Ventilation Strategy During Cardiopulmonary Bypass in Minimally Invasive Cardiac Surgery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pusan National University Yangsan Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pusan National University Yangsan Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Electrical impedance tomography (EIT) is a non-invasive, radiation-free imaging technique&#xD;
      that measures local pulmonary ventilation and ventilation distribution through potential&#xD;
      changes on the skin surface of the chest wall during the respiratory cycle. Recently, a&#xD;
      global inhomogeneity (GI) index has been proposed and used to quantify the distribution of&#xD;
      tidal volume in the lungs. Currently, there are research results showing that ventilation&#xD;
      improves postoperative oxygenation and gas exchange when ventilation is applied during CPB,&#xD;
      but the evidence for long-term prognosis is lacking. In this study, researchers performed&#xD;
      electrical impedance tomography in the intensive care unit immediately after surgery on&#xD;
      patients who had undergone endotracheal tube extubation in the operating room immediately&#xD;
      after completing minimally invasive cardiac surgery by collapsing the right lung through&#xD;
      right minimal thoracotomy. The purpose of this study is to measure local pulmonary&#xD;
      ventilation and ventilation distribution using this method and to find the optimal left lung&#xD;
      ventilation method during minimally invasive cardiac surgery based on this. Identifying the&#xD;
      difference in postoperative pulmonary ventilation disorders and functional regional&#xD;
      ventilation according to the pulmonary ventilation strategy at the time of CPB in minimally&#xD;
      invasive cardiac surgery can help predict the risk of pulmonary complications and improve the&#xD;
      prognosis of patients after surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Minimally invasive cardiac surgery (MICS) is a safe and effective surgical method that&#xD;
      reduces bleeding, number of reoperations, postoperative pain, and length of stay in the ICU,&#xD;
      and promotes faster recovery compared to conventional open thoracic cardiac surgery. In&#xD;
      general, since cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB) is used during minimally invasive cardiac surgery&#xD;
      using right thoracotomy, both lungs can be maintained in a lung rest state. Except for 2-3&#xD;
      ventilations when releasing the aortic forceps during surgery, there is no ventilation at all&#xD;
      during CPB, and both lung ventilation starts when CPB is stopped. In order to secure the&#xD;
      surgical field of view during surgery, most anesthetists do not ventilate the right lung and&#xD;
      maintain a collapsed state. Even during CPB, ventilation can be performed without affecting&#xD;
      the field of vision at the surgical site. However, to date, it is not well known about the&#xD;
      proper ventilation method for the left lung during cardiac surgery using CPB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pulmonary complications are major postoperative complications of minimally invasive cardiac&#xD;
      surgery and are factors that increase postoperative pulmonary complications, such as age,&#xD;
      preoperative lung disease, and duration of CPB, which are well-known. Failure to ventilate&#xD;
      the entire lung field at the time of CPB may cause atelectrauma, and even if normal&#xD;
      ventilation is performed after CPB, and shearing force from repeated collapse and expansion&#xD;
      of the atelectasis area may occur. In addition, such atelectasis can lead to not only&#xD;
      ventilation disorders, ventilation/perfusion imbalances, but also postoperative pneumonia and&#xD;
      poor prognosis. In particular, since right thoracotomy is mainly performed in minimally&#xD;
      invasive cardiac surgery, the right lung collapses through one lung ventilation from the&#xD;
      start of the operation to the access to the surgical site or at the end of the operation to&#xD;
      check for bleeding at the surgical site. Therefore, one lung ventilation may be required even&#xD;
      after weaning from the CPB, which may increase the risk of atelectasis in the operated side.&#xD;
      Depending on the ventilation of the left lung during surgery and the tidal volume (TV), it&#xD;
      may affect postoperative atelectasis and may cause functional ventilation. This can lead to&#xD;
      the occurrence of respiratory complications such as pneumonia after surgery, resulting in&#xD;
      poor prognosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 2, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>postoperative pulmonary ventilation disorders</measure>
    <time_frame>after ICU transferring (up to 1hour)</time_frame>
    <description>Confirmation of postoperative pulmonary ventilation disorders according to the lung ventilation strategy at the time of cardiopulmonary bypass in minimally invasive cardiac surgery</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>incidence of postoperative pulmonary complications</measure>
    <time_frame>during ICU hospitalization (up to 7 days)</time_frame>
    <description>the difference in the incidence of postoperative pulmonary complications according to the pulmonary ventilation strategy at the time of cardiopulmonary bypass in minimally invasive cardiac surgery</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Patients Who Underwent CPB for MICS</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group N</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Stopping ventilation during cardiopulmonary bypass</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group V</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Ventilation was performed using an inhaled oxygen fraction of 20% and a tidal volume of 5ml/kg at the time of cardiopulmonary bypass.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ventilation during cardiopulmonary bypass</intervention_name>
    <description>Ventilation was performed using an inhaled oxygen fraction of 20% and a tidal volume of 5ml/kg at the time of cardiopulmonary bypass.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group V</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adults over 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who underwent one lung ventilation using a bronchial blocker for minimally&#xD;
             invasive cardiac surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. If there is no atelectasis on chest X-ray or chest computed tomography performed&#xD;
             before surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. If there is evidence of atelectasis, pneumonia, or lung disease that can reduce lung&#xD;
             volume in a chest X-ray examination or chest computed tomography performed before&#xD;
             surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients scheduled for sternotomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. If there is a skin disease in the chest that requires EIT measurement&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. If there is a plan to transfer to the intensive care unit while maintaining the&#xD;
             endotracheal tube&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pusan National University Yangsan Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Yangsan</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hee Young Kim, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>82553602129</phone>
      <email>yuvi1981@naver.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Hyung Gon Je, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Pusan National University Yangsan Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Hyung Gon Je</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

