<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04987775</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GWICTIC-NAC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04987775</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Physical Health Function and Oxidative Stress After Antioxidant Treatment in GWI: NAC</brief_title>
  <acronym>NAC</acronym>
  <official_title>Physical Health Function and Oxidative Stress After Antioxidant Treatment in GWI: N-Acetyl Cysteine (NAC)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nova Southeastern University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>RTI International</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Miami VA Healthcare System</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Boston University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Nova Southeastern University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase II study will test if N-Acetyl Cysteine (NAC) promotes CNS recovery from chronic&#xD;
      oxidative stress and depletion of antioxidants in Gulf War Illness (GWI) participants.&#xD;
      Physical function assessments and neuroimaging will be used to determine whether NAC improves&#xD;
      the CNS redox state when compared to placebo.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      During the 1990-91 Gulf War (GW), military personnel were exposed to numerous chemical and&#xD;
      environmental agents during deployment including spraying of pesticides, petroleum combustion&#xD;
      products, and nerve gas (White et al., 2016). Exposure to these chemical and environmental&#xD;
      agents can damage cell function and more specifically, mitochondrial function, which&#xD;
      negatively affects energy production and can lead to oxidative stress and neuroinflammation.&#xD;
      Animal models using similar exposures have documented this in the central nervous system&#xD;
      (CNS) compartment (Shetty, GA., et al., 2017). This disruption in mitochondrial function and&#xD;
      energy production is likely tied to resulting symptoms of Gulf War Illness (GWI) including&#xD;
      fatigue, headaches, joint and muscle pain, gastrointestinal and sleep disturbances,&#xD;
      neurologic and neuropsychological symptoms, respiratory issues, and cardiovascular problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Gulf War Illness Clinical Trials and Interventions Consortium (GWICTIC) plans to evaluate&#xD;
      N-Acetyl Cysteine (NAC) as a promising approach to help the CNS recover from chronic&#xD;
      oxidative stress and depletion of antioxidants. The Congressionally Directed Medical Research&#xD;
      Program's (CDMRP's) two Gulf War Illness Consortiums (GWICs) and others have added to the&#xD;
      growing evidence of the role of CNS oxidative stress and neuroinflammation in symptoms of&#xD;
      GWI, yet there is little definitive work on the delivery of antioxidants to the CNS&#xD;
      environment. In this phase II clinical trial, we aim to determine if NAC has the ability to&#xD;
      target mitochondrial dysfunction and reverse oxidative stress in the CNS. Based on our early&#xD;
      experiences with antioxidants in GWI and other complex disease states along with the proven&#xD;
      record of NAC in reducing glutathione (GSH) deficits, it is possible that this antioxidant&#xD;
      will help to restore mitochondrial function and provide a more targeted approach to improve&#xD;
      outcomes in Veterans with GWI.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants enrolled will be randomized into one of two arms: NAC or Placebo.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Veterans RAND 36 Item Health Survey (VR-36©)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in subscore from baseline after 12 weeks in the physical component of the health survey. The minimum score is 0 and the maximum score is 100. The higher the score the better health the veteran is in.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Glutathione levels</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Glutathione levels according to MRS imaging after 8 weeks of intervention</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom Severity</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in symptom severity measured by DePaul symptom questionnaire after 12 weeks of intervention</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of Intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events as assessed by a safety questionnaire at baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of Intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>4 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in number of participants with treatment-related adverse events from baseline to 4 weeks during the intervention period as assessed by a safety questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of Intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>8 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in number of participants with treatment-related adverse events from 4 weeks to 8 weeks during the intervention period as assessed by a safety questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of Intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in number of participants with treatment-related adverse events from 8 weeks to 12 weeks during the intervention period as assessed by a safety questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">156</enrollment>
  <condition>Gulf War Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>N-Acetyl Cysteine (NAC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants who are randomized to the intervention arm will receive N-Acetyl-L-Cysteine (Free-Form/NAC) 900mg two times a day for 20 weeks after the initiation of the first dose of study drug.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants who are randomized to the placebo arm will take matching placebo two times a day for 20 weeks after the initiation of the first dose of study drug.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>N-Acetyl Cysteine</intervention_name>
    <description>900mg 2x daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>N-Acetyl Cysteine (NAC)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>NAC</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Matching placebo bid</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>NAC Placebo</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  47 to 70 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Served in the Gulf War Theater for any period between August 1990 and July 1991.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meets modified Kansas case definition criteria for Gulf War Illness. The modified&#xD;
             Kansas definition includes the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Allowance of normal illness of aging, such as hypertension and diabetes, if the&#xD;
                  conditions are treated and are in demonstrable stable and normal ranges at the&#xD;
                  time of screening and assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Allowance of stable comorbid conditions such as PTSD, MDD, and mild TBI that have&#xD;
                  not required hospitalization in the 2 years prior to recruitment. Severe TBI is&#xD;
                  excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide written consent to the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees to participate in follow-up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-report of current treated or untreated major depression with psychotic or&#xD;
             melancholic features (as determined by self-report and Hamilton Depression Inventory&#xD;
             (Ham-D)), schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, delusional disorders, dementias of any&#xD;
             type, or a history of CNS disorders that may affect cognitive function (e.g.,&#xD;
             epilepsy, stroke, brain tumor, multiple sclerosis, Parkinson's Disease, Alzheimer's&#xD;
             disease), or alcoholism or drug abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe claustrophobia or serious difficulty being in an MRI scanner or other enclosed&#xD;
             space (MRS substudy only)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of ferrous implanted medical devices or metal fragments or objects that are&#xD;
             embedded under the skin (MRS substudy only)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current heavy alcohol or tobacco use (self-report). Alcohol consumption not to exceed&#xD;
             approximately 15 drinks per week (with a drink defined as 12 oz beer, 5 oz wine, or&#xD;
             1.5 oz distilled spirits) and tobacco use not to exceed 20 cigarettes (or equivalent)&#xD;
             per day.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic active infections such as HIV, Hepatitis B Virus (HBV), and Hepatitis C Virus&#xD;
             (HCV) (self-report or antibody titer)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal disease (self-report or laboratory results: renal insufficiency with serum&#xD;
             creatinine &gt; 2.0 mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Liver disease (self-report or laboratory results: hepatic insufficiency (bilirubin&#xD;
             &gt;2.5mg/dL or transaminases &gt; 3X the upper limits of normal)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled diabetes (HgbA1c &gt; 7.5) without adequate medical care. Individuals with&#xD;
             HgbA1c &gt; 7.5 will be reviewed and judged by the PI or delegate; if potential&#xD;
             participant has adequate medical care to manage diabetes, enrollment is allowed;&#xD;
             otherwise HgbA1c &gt; 7.5 is exclusionary&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed vascular disease (including congestive heart failure)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed bleeding disorders or use of blood-thinning medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of stavudine or didanosine for more than 7 days within 30 days prior to&#xD;
             screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently have exclusionary diagnoses that could reasonably explain the symptoms of&#xD;
             their fatiguing illness and their severity, using the exclusion criteria best&#xD;
             described in the Ambiguities in case definition paper for CFS, as described in detail&#xD;
             in Reeves, et. al., 2003, which clarifies exclusionary conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are scheduled for a surgery during the period of study participation or had surgery&#xD;
             within 6 weeks prior to screening&#xD;
&#xD;
        Prohibited Concomitant or Prior Therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently on dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous or current receipt of any antiviral medication, such as pegylated interferon,&#xD;
             ribavirin, entecavir, tenofovir, or didanosine for more than 7 days within 30 days&#xD;
             prior to screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participating in another interventional (including social-behavioral therapy) clinical&#xD;
             trial of an investigational therapy within 6 weeks prior to consent, or planning to&#xD;
             participate in another interventional clinical trial of an investigational therapy&#xD;
             during the course of this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any herbal medicine within 30 days prior to consent and screening blood draw&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>47 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nancy Klimas, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Nova Southeastern Univeristy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nancy Klimas, MD</last_name>
    <phone>9542622855</phone>
    <email>nklimas@nova.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Rebecca McNeil, MD</last_name>
    <email>rmcneil@rti.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nova Southeastern University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Lauderdale</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33314</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nancy Klimas, MD</last_name>
      <email>nklimas@nova.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Amaanpreet Cheema, PhD</last_name>
      <email>acheema@nova.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nancy Klimas, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Amaanpreet Cheema, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>RTI International</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27709</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rebecca McNeil, MD</last_name>
      <email>rmcneil@rti.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Stephanie Zimmer, PhD</last_name>
      <email>sazimmer@rti.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rebecca McNeil, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CNS Recovery</keyword>
  <keyword>N-Acetyl Cysteine (NAC)</keyword>
  <keyword>Gulf War Illness</keyword>
  <keyword>Placebo</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Persian Gulf Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acetylcysteine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>N-monoacetylcystine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The plan is to release primary results from the study. Data are the property of Nova Southeastern University, but data and publication thereof will not be unduly withheld.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

