<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04985383</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AKST1210-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04985383</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Compare Safety and Tolerability of AKST1210 Column at 2 Blood Flow Rates in Subjects With ESRD on Hemodialysis</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open Label Phase 1 Study to Compare the Safety and Tolerability of the AKST1210 Column at Different Blood-Flow Rates in Patients With End-Stage Renal Disease Undergoing Hemodialysis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Alkahest, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Alkahest, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of the AKST1210 column at blood-flow&#xD;
      rates greater than 250 mL/min in subjects with end-stage renal disease (ESRD) undergoing&#xD;
      hemodialysis (HD). The study will assess the safety, tolerability, and impact on HD&#xD;
      parameters when the AKST1210 column is used at a blood-flow of up to 450 mL/min.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label study in 12 to 15 subjects between 40 and 75 years of age with ESRD on&#xD;
      HD. The objective of this study is to explore the safety and tolerability of the AKST1210&#xD;
      column at blood-flow rates greater than 250 mL/min in subjects with ESRD undergoing HD. The&#xD;
      proposed study will assess the safety, tolerability, and impact on HD parameters when the&#xD;
      AKST1210 column is used at a blood-flow rates of up to 450 mL/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The incidence of IDH events will be one factor used to determine column size/blood-flow rate&#xD;
      escalation/de-escalation as well as discontinuation from the study. The planned duration of&#xD;
      subject participation is approximately 12 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 11, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of each column size at each blood-flow rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Safety as evaluated by rate and severity of all adverse events (AEs), treatment-emergent AEs (TEAEs), number of IDH events, and changes in total and free hemoglobin (Hgb) Tolerability will be assessed by the proportion of subjects who can escalate to and tolerate each column size and blood-flow-rate combination.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Kt/V and URR</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 6</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total fluid balance for each column-size flow-rate combination</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 6</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects who are able to achieve the dry weight goal during the allotted HD duration for each column size and flow rate combination</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 6</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in plasma b2M concentrations (before and after HD) and contribution of the AKST1210 column to b2M removal at each column size and blood-flow rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 7</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of occurrences of visible thrombosis (clotting) in the AKST1210 column, dialyzer, and/or tubing</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 6</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in plasma levels of complement factors, including total CH50, SC5b-9, and C5a</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 6</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in plasma levels of other proteins, including insulin, ACTH, IGFBP1</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 6</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">15</enrollment>
  <condition>End-Stage Renal Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AKST1210 b2M apheresis device</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>AKST1210 column will be connected in series for the duration of each hemodialysis session.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AKST1210</intervention_name>
    <description>Procedure: Hemodialysis</description>
    <arm_group_label>AKST1210 b2M apheresis device</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Males and females aged 40 - 75 years, inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ESRD requiring HD.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Dialysis vintage ≥ 24 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Absence of clinically-relevant residual renal function.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Regular HD sessions done at blood-flow rates between 400 and 500 mL/min, and with&#xD;
             inter-dialysis intervals of 48 hours or more.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Stable health status for at least 4 weeks prior to screening based on medical history,&#xD;
             and findings from physical examination, laboratory tests, vital signs, and ECG, as&#xD;
             assessed by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Life expectancy &gt; 6 months (as determined by the investigator).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Body mass index (BMI) between 18 and 37 kg/m2, inclusive, with a minimum body weight&#xD;
             of 52 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Must be on stable doses (&gt; 4 weeks) of all treatments for concomitant diseases (e.g.,&#xD;
             diabetes, hypertension), but this does not apply to medications for conditions related&#xD;
             to ESRD (e.g., medications for calcium and phosphate control, anemia).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Must be able to follow the study protocol and receive the treatment in the established&#xD;
             timeframe.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Must provide a signed and dated informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients for whom adequate anticoagulation cannot be achieved, such as those with&#xD;
             severe anemia, severe hemorrhagic diathesis, severe gastrointestinal ulcers, or who&#xD;
             are receiving anticoagulant medications for any reason other than as required for HD.&#xD;
             Use of antiplatelet drugs (e.g., aspirin or clopidogrel) is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients for whom extracorporeal circulation therapy is contraindicated, such as those&#xD;
             with severe cardiac insufficiency, acute myocardial infarction, severe cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia, acute seizure disorder, or severe uncontrolled hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with Kt/V &lt; 1.2 during recent 8-week period prior to run-in.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of hypersensitivity to heparin, including heparin-induced thrombocytopenia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of hypersensitivity to the AKST1210 column or its components.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients who are not anticipated to be able to tolerate blood-flow rates of 450 mL/min&#xD;
             during HD (e.g., new vascular access that cannot be used with 14G or 15G needles).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients who are at higher risk for IDH including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Medical records indicating the occurrence IDH (SBP &lt; 90 mmHg) in more than 30% of&#xD;
                  HD sessions during a recent 8-week period prior to run-in;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patients requiring or expected to require extensive fluid management as&#xD;
                  determined by the investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Presence of pre-dialysis hypotension, defined as SBP &lt; 90 mmHg and/or diastolic&#xD;
                  blood pressure (DBP) &lt; 50 mmHg, before any of the last 3 dialysis sessions prior&#xD;
                  to screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Diagnosis of IDH in medical records;&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Diagnosis of autonomic dysfunction;&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Patients who frequently require a UFR above 13 mL/kg/h.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients who are pregnant or breast-feeding or who are planning to become pregnant.&#xD;
             Female subjects must not be pregnant or breastfeeding. Women of childbearing potential&#xD;
             (WOCBP) must have a negative serum pregnancy test at screening and prior to start of&#xD;
             treatment. WOCBP and men must agree to use highly-effective contraception (Clinical&#xD;
             Trial Facilitation Group 2014) prior to study entry. A woman is considered of&#xD;
             childbearing potential following menarche and until becoming postmenopausal (no menses&#xD;
             for at least 2 years without an alternative cause). Should a woman become pregnant or&#xD;
             suspect she is pregnant while she or her male partner is participating in the study,&#xD;
             she should inform her treating physician immediately.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Clotting disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Sickle cell anemia, hereditary spherocytosis, or autoimmune hemolysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Clinically significant abnormalities on screening ECG including QT interval corrected&#xD;
             for heart rate (QTc) using Fridericia's correction formula [QTcF] of ≥ 500 ms in men&#xD;
             and ≥ 520 ms in women.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Delirium (encephalopathy).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Out of range value for complete blood count (CBC), complete metabolic panel, or&#xD;
             coagulation that the investigator deems clinically significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Thyroid stimulating hormone (TSH) below 0.2 or above 6.0 mIU/L, and/or&#xD;
             clinically-relevant abnormalities in T3 or T4.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Hemoglobin level &lt; 9.0 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and/or aspartate transaminase (AST) &gt; 3 times upper&#xD;
             limit of normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Uncontrolled type 2 diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Concurrent or have recent participation in another interventional clinical trial.&#xD;
             Prior clinical trial subjects must have discontinued investigational agents/devices at&#xD;
             least 30 days prior to planned first use of the AKST1210 column.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. History of severe depression/suicidality requiring hospitalization in the last 6&#xD;
             months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Significant drug or alcohol abuse within the past 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Patients planning to receive renal transplantation during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Patients with any other condition and/or situation the investigator believes may&#xD;
             interfere with the safety of the subject during study participation, study conduct, or&#xD;
             interpretation of study data.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alkahest Medical Monitor</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Alkahest, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Renal Consultant Medical Group</name>
      <address>
        <city>Granada Hills</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91344</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Valley Renal Medical Group Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Northridge</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91324</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>US Renal Care</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gallup</city>
        <state>New Mexico</state>
        <zip>87301</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>US Renal Care - Westover Hills Dialysis</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78251</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

