<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04980638</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ER004-CLIN01/F60082AI201</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04980638</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intraamniotic Administrations of ER004 in Male Subjects With X-linked Hypohidrotic Ectodermal Dysplasia</brief_title>
  <acronym>EDELIFE</acronym>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Open-label, Genotype-match Controlled, Multicenter Clinical Trial to Investigate the Efficacy and Safety of Intra-amniotic ER004 as a Prenatal Treatment for Male Subjects With XLHED</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>EspeRare Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Pierre Fabre Medicament (co-developer)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>IQVIA (clinical CRO)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>EspeRare Foundation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label, prospective, genotype-match controlled for primary estimand, non&#xD;
      randomized, multicenter, international Phase 2 clinical trial designed to investigate the&#xD;
      efficacy and safety of ER004 administered intraamniotically as a treatment for unborn XLHED&#xD;
      male subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      X-linked hypohidrotic ectodermal dysplasia (XLHED) is a rare developmental disease affecting&#xD;
      body parts derived from the embryonal ectoderm. It is caused by a broad spectrum of mutations&#xD;
      in the ectodysplasin A gene (EDA). The main symptoms of XLHED are hypo- or anhidrosis, oligo-&#xD;
      or anodontia, and hypotrichosis. Current treatment options are limited to the management of&#xD;
      disease symptoms and prevention of complications. Effective corrective treatment for XLHED&#xD;
      remains a high unmet medical need. ER004 represents a first-in-class signaling protein&#xD;
      replacement molecule designed for specific, high affinity binding to the endogenous EDA1&#xD;
      receptor (EDAR). The proposed mechanism of action of ER004 is the replacement of the missing&#xD;
      EDA1 protein in patients with XLHED. The aim of this prospective, open-label, genotype-match&#xD;
      controlled, multicenter Phase 2 trial is to confirm the efficacy and safety results for ER004&#xD;
      administered intra-amniotically in a larger cohort of subjects. The target population will&#xD;
      consist of male XLHED fetuses/subjects with EDA mutation confirmed by genetic diagnosis of a&#xD;
      mutation in one of the maternal EDA alleles and ultrasonographic diagnosis of a significantly&#xD;
      reduced number of fetal tooth germs, or by documented direct genetic diagnosis of a&#xD;
      hemizygous EDA mutation. In the main study phase, efficacy and safety of the treated subjects&#xD;
      will be assessed up to 6 months of age and safety of the mothers will be assessed up to 1&#xD;
      month after delivery of the child. In long-term follow-up phase, efficacy and safety of the&#xD;
      treated subjects will be assessed up to 5 years of age. Treated subjects sweating ability&#xD;
      will be compared to an untreated relative from his family, when available, or from a matched&#xD;
      controlled subject from a previous natural history.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2029</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is an open-label, single-arm, genotype-match controlled for primary estimand, non randomized study. The primary efficacy outcome will be compared to genotype matched untreated male relatives with XLHED or to genotype-matched controls from an external XLHED database (clinical and natural history studies from which untreated genotype-matched controls will be identified).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean sweat volume</measure>
    <time_frame>at 6 months of age (corrected age for subjects born at &lt; 37 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>For treated subject, mean sweat volume is collected on both forearms after local stimulation with pilocarpine (pilocarpine-induced sweating)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean sweat pore density (number/cm2)</measure>
    <time_frame>at 6 months of age (key secondary) and other timepoints : 3, 12, 18, 24, 36, 48 and 60 months(secondary)</time_frame>
    <description>Mean sweat pore density (number/cm2) determined by direct visualization with a VivaScope® at 2 different sites on the soles of the feet (up to 12 months) or at 2 different sites on the soles of the feet and/or palms (&gt;12 months)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dental development</measure>
    <time_frame>at 6 months of age (key secondary) and other timepoints : 12, 18, 24, 36, 48 and 60 months (secondary)</time_frame>
    <description>Dental development evaluated by the number of erupted teeth and tooth germs (palpable alveolar structures in the alveolar ridge) as determined by dental examination</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean sweat volume</measure>
    <time_frame>At 3, 12, 18, 24, 36, 48, 60 months</time_frame>
    <description>For treated subject, mean sweat volume is collected on both forearms after local stimulation with pilocarpine (pilocarpine-induced sweating)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dry eye issues</measure>
    <time_frame>At different timepoints from 6 to 60 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of Meibomian glands, Ocular surface assessment, Tear film break-up time</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Salivation</measure>
    <time_frame>At 60 months</time_frame>
    <description>Saliva assessed with Quantisal oral fluid collection device</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>XLHED-related hospitalizations</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 60 months</time_frame>
    <description>XLHED-related hospitalisation because of hyperthermia or because of unexplained fever, respiratory, skin, eye or ear infections</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of eczema</measure>
    <time_frame>At different timepoints from 6 to 60 months</time_frame>
    <description>Eczema will be assessed using the EASI score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of TEAEs (treatment-emergent adverse events)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 60 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of TESAEs (treatment-emergent serious adverse events)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 60 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of TEAEs (treatment-emergent adverse events) leading to treatment discontinuation.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 60 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>X-Linked Hypohidrotic Ectodermal Dysplasia (XLHED)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ER004</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Human immunoglobulin G1 constant region - human ectodysplasin-A1 receptor binding domain fusion protein.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ER004</intervention_name>
    <description>Intra-amniotic route 100 mg/kg of estimated fetal weight per injection. 3 injections, approximately 3 weeks apart starting from gestational week 26</description>
    <arm_group_label>ER004</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For mother: Adult mother with confirmed pregnancy no later than week 23+6 and genetically&#xD;
        confirmed as carrier of an EDA mutation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For fetal Subject : Male Fetal subject with confirmed diagnosis of XLHED&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For untreated relative: Untreated male relative subject ages between 6 months and 60&#xD;
             years with the same EDA mutation as the treated subject&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For mother: Any evidence of active maternal infection associated with a risk of&#xD;
             preterm birth and/or congenital anomalies of prenatal and postnatal risk to the child.&#xD;
             Documented maternal HIV infection. Any pre-existing maternal medical condition that&#xD;
             increases the risk of preterm birth or increases the risk of a serious untoward event&#xD;
             occurring to the mother during pregnancy. Any pregnancy disorder associated with an&#xD;
             increased risk of preterm birth, and/or maternal, fetal or neonatal&#xD;
             morbidity/mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For fetal Subject : Second major anatomic anomaly (not related to the underlying&#xD;
             XLHED) that contributes to a significant morbidity or mortality risk, or&#xD;
             echocardiogram or ultrasonography or other findings that indicate a high risk of fetal&#xD;
             demise or risk of preterm birth. Any condition other than XLHED that is likely to have&#xD;
             an impact on the number of tooth germs. Any other medical condition which in the&#xD;
             opinion of the investigator would not allow for safe conduct of the study for the&#xD;
             subject, or that would interfere with efficacy assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For untreated relative: Carrier of an hypomorphic EDA mutation. Known hypersensitivity&#xD;
             to pilocarpine or pilocarpine-like muscarinic agonists. Presence of an implanted&#xD;
             device (e.g., defibrillator, neurostimulator, pacemaker). Previous treatment with the&#xD;
             study intervention by any route of administration prior to study start.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Pregnant female</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Holm Schneider, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Erlangen-Nürnberg Erlangen, Germany</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Florence Porte-Thormé, PharmD</last_name>
    <phone>+41 22 794 4004</phone>
    <email>Info.er004@esperare.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Athmane Bouroubi, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+33 5 34 50 60 00</phone>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <link>
    <url>http://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29694819/</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schneider H, Faschingbauer F, Schuepbach-Mallepell S, Körber I, Wohlfart S, Dick A, Wahlbuhl M, Kowalczyk-Quintas C, Vigolo M, Kirby N, Tannert C, Rompel O, Rascher W, Beckmann MW, Schneider P. Prenatal Correction of X-Linked Hypohidrotic Ectodermal Dysplasia. N Engl J Med. 2018 Apr 26;378(17):1604-1610. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1714322.</citation>
    <PMID>29694819</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ectodermal Dysplasia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ectodermal Dysplasia 1, Anhidrotic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

