<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04987320</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20190095</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04987320</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Pharmacokinetics, Pharmacodynamics, Safety and Tolerability of Olpasiran in Chinese Participants With Elevated Serum Lipoprotein(a)</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-label, Single-dose Study to Evaluate the Pharmacokinetics, Pharmacodynamics, Safety and Tolerability of Olpasiran in Chinese Subjects With Elevated Serum Lipoprotein(a)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Amgen</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Amgen</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main objective of this study is to evaluate the pharmacokinetics (PK) of a single dose of&#xD;
      Olpasiran in Chinese participants with elevated serum lipoprotein(a) (Lp[a]).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 28, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 23, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 23, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Observed Concentration (Cmax) of Olpasiran</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 4</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Concentration-time Curve (AUC) of Olpasiran</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 4</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Maximum Observed Concentration (tmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 4</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hlaf-life (t1/2) of Olpasiran</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 4</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent Volume of Distribution During the Terminal Elimination Phase (Vz/F) of Olpasiran</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 4</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent Total Body Clearance (CL/F) of Olpasiran</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 4</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Treatment-emergent Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 4</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with a Clinically Significant Change from Baseline in Clinical Laboratory Tests</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Day 4</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with a Clinically Significant Change from Baseline in 12-lead Electrocardiograms (ECGs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Day 4</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with a Clinically Significant Change from Baseline in Vital Signs</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Day 4</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with a Clinically Siginificant Change from Baseline in Lipid Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Day 4</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with a Clinically Significant Change from Baseline in Serum Lipoprotein(a) (LP[a])</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Day 4</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Elevated Serum Lipoprotein(a)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Olpasiran Dose A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be administered Olpasiran dose A as a subcutaneous injection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Olpasiran Dose B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be administered Olpasiran dose B as a subcutaneous injection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Olpasiran</intervention_name>
    <description>Subcutaneous injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Olpasiran Dose A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Olpasiran Dose B</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>AMG 890</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion eligibility criteria will be evaluated in 2 parts during the screening period:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Part 1: After written informed consent is obtained, subjects will provide a blood&#xD;
             sample for a preliminary Lp(a) assessment to determine eligibility for Part 2&#xD;
             screening. Subjects with Lp(a) ≥ 70 nmol/L (or approximately ≥ 27 mg/dL) will be&#xD;
             eligible to return to the CRU Part 2 screening. Subjects not eligible to return for&#xD;
             Part 2 screening will be screen failed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Part 2: Eligible subjects will complete all remaining screening procedures and tests&#xD;
             that establish eligibility within 40 days prior to the Day 1 visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Part 1:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be a resident in mainland China, Hong Kong, or Taiwan, and of Chinese Ancestry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female subjects, between 18 and 60 years of age (inclusive) at the time of&#xD;
             Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Screening serum Lp(a) ≥ 70 nmol/L (or approximately ≥ 27 mg/dL).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Part 2:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In good health, determined by no clinically significant findings from medical history,&#xD;
             physical examination, 12-lead ECG, vital sign measurements, and clinical laboratory&#xD;
             evaluations (congenital nonhemolytic hyperbilirubinemia [e.g., suspicion of Gilbert's&#xD;
             syndrome based on total and direct bilirubin] is not acceptable) as assessed by the&#xD;
             Investigator (or designee).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index between 18 and 32 kg/m^2 (inclusive) at the time of Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are on statin must be on a stable dose of the same statin for at least 6&#xD;
             weeks prior to enrollment, and plan to remain on a stable dose (i.e., no change in&#xD;
             medication or dosage) for the duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females must be of non-reproductive potential:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Postmenopausal defined as: i. Age of ≥ 55 years with no menses for at least 12&#xD;
             months; OR ii. Age of &lt; 55 years with no menses for at least 12 months AND with a&#xD;
             follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) level &gt; 40 IU/L or according to the definition of&#xD;
             &quot;postmenopausal range&quot; for the laboratory involved; OR b. History of hysterectomy; OR&#xD;
             c. History of bilateral oophorectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or clinical evidence of peripheral neuropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently receiving apheresis as lipid reducing therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or clinical evidence of bleeding diathesis or any coagulation disorder,&#xD;
             including prothrombin time (PT), activated partial thromboplastin time (APTT), or&#xD;
             platelet count outside of the laboratory's normal reference range at screening.&#xD;
             Subjects with PT and/or APTT values that are outside of the laboratory's normal&#xD;
             reference range at screening may still be eligible to proceed to enrollment if the&#xD;
             results are judged by the investigator in consultation with the study medical monitor&#xD;
             to not be clinically significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or clinical evidence of diabetes mellitus, including a fasting glucose ≥ 125&#xD;
             mg/dL (6.9 mmol/L) at Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any herbal medicines, vitamins or dietary supplements known to affect lipid&#xD;
             metabolism (e.g. sigh oils &gt; 100mg/day, red yeast extract), within 30 days prior to&#xD;
             dosing on Day 1 and for the duration of the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Amgen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Queen Mary Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hong Kong</city>
        <state>HK</state>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.amgentrials.com</url>
    <description>AmgenTrials clinical trials website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Elevated serum lipoprotein(a)</keyword>
  <keyword>Olpasiran</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified individual patient data for variables necessary to address the specific research question in an approved data sharing request.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data sharing requests relating to this study will be considered beginning 18 months after the study has ended and either 1) the product and indication have been granted marketing authorization in both the US and Europe or 2) clinical development for the product and/or indication discontinues and the data will not be submitted to regulatory authorities. There is no end date for eligibility to submit a data sharing request for this study.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Qualified researchers may submit a request containing the research objectives, the Amgen product(s) and Amgen study/studies in scope, endpoints/outcomes of interest, statistical analysis plan, data requirements, publication plan, and qualifications of the researcher(s). In general, Amgen does not grant external requests for individual patient data for the purpose of re-evaluating safety and efficacy issues already addressed in the product labelling. Requests are reviewed by a committee of internal advisors. If not approved, a Data Sharing Independent Review Panel will arbitrate and make the final decision. Upon approval, information necessary to address the research question will be provided under the terms of a data sharing agreement. This may include anonymized individual patient data and/or available supporting documents, containing fragments of analysis code where provided in analysis specifications. Further details are available at the URL below.</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>http://www.amgen.com/datasharing</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

