<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05105269</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ETH2021-1779</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05105269</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Managing Achilles Pain II</brief_title>
  <acronym>MAP II</acronym>
  <official_title>Do Working Alliance, Patient Outcome Expectations and Self-efficacy Predict Change in Pain and Disability From Treatment With a Physiotherapist for Achilles Tendinopathy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Essex</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Chartered Society of Physiotherapy</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Essex</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Although some people are more at risk than others, developing a painful Achilles tendon&#xD;
      (known as Achilles tendinopathy) can affect anyone. It is a common and disabling condition&#xD;
      affecting walking, running and work. To reduce the pain and disability, exercise is a&#xD;
      commonly used treatment by physiotherapists. However, success varies. This is why the&#xD;
      proposed research is needed, to identify the factors that predict changes in pain and&#xD;
      disability from treatment with a physiotherapist. Our previous research suggests the working&#xD;
      relationship or 'alliance' between the physiotherapist and patient, the patient's&#xD;
      expectations, and the patient's confidence to carry out exercise might be important, but&#xD;
      further research is needed to determine this.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We have designed a multi-centre, longitudinal cohort study to assess whether working&#xD;
      alliance, patient expectations of treatment success, and confidence to perform exercise&#xD;
      (self-efficacy) predict changes in pain and disability from a treatment programme prescribed&#xD;
      by a physiotherapist for Achilles tendinopathy at twelve weeks. Patients, diagnosed with&#xD;
      Achilles tendinopathy by their treating physiotherapist, will be introduced to the study&#xD;
      through a verbal discussion and provided with details of the study's website&#xD;
      (www.managing-achilles-pain.com). The website provides password protected information (the&#xD;
      participant information sheet, consent form and a questionnaire measuring clinical outcomes&#xD;
      and the predictive factors). The participant is asked to complete the questionnaire on three&#xD;
      occasions; baseline, six weeks later and twelve weeks after baseline.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Pain related to a tendon, termed tendinopathy, can be traumatic or insidious in onset and&#xD;
      short-lasting or persistent in nature. Tendinopathy is common musculoskeletal condition; the&#xD;
      incidence of tendinopathy is higher than osteoarthritis, for example. Achilles tendinopathy&#xD;
      (AT) affects both active and sedentary individuals and can be characterised by reduced&#xD;
      activity tolerance to specific tasks that load the tendon. This results in decreased activity&#xD;
      participation such as walking, running and working.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Current clinical guidelines recommend exercise as the first line treatment for people with&#xD;
      Achilles tendinopathy. However, the rate and extent of improvement in pain and disability&#xD;
      varies. This variation suggests we need to understand what factors predict change so we can&#xD;
      enhance our care. Previously it was suggested that exercise worked by improving the strength&#xD;
      or structure of the tendon, but it has been reported that pain and disability can change&#xD;
      without corresponding changes in strength or structure. This suggests that other factors&#xD;
      might be important predictors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent literature suggests cognitive and contextual influences such as self-efficacy, working&#xD;
      alliance and expectations may be important factors for predicting change in pain and&#xD;
      disability in tendinopathy and need investigation. Based on this need, high-quality research&#xD;
      is warranted. To inform the development of this research, two recent studies have been&#xD;
      undertaken. Firstly, a feasibility study was completed. This study aimed to understand if it&#xD;
      was feasible to collect data using a secure website to explore the association and predictive&#xD;
      relationship of working alliance, outcome expectations and self-efficacy with pain and&#xD;
      disability in the management of AT. The second study was a process evaluation to gain insight&#xD;
      into the procedures undertaken in the feasibility study. Seven patients were interviewed to&#xD;
      discover what worked (and did not) from their perspective during the study. Based on the&#xD;
      results from the feasibility study and the information from the interviews with patients,&#xD;
      using this website is feasible, but we have made some changes before proposing this larger&#xD;
      study. These changes include better promotion of the study, how verbal recruitment strategies&#xD;
      could be improved, and how communication between clinicians and researchers could be made&#xD;
      better. Based upon this knowledge this proposal aims to understand if working alliance,&#xD;
      patient outcome expectations and self-efficacy predict response to treatment for AT.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 7, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 7, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Lower Extremity Functional Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The LEFS is a self-report questionnaire designed to measure physical function of people with lower extremity dysfunctions, such as AT. Twenty items covering a range of lower extremity functional activities are scored on a numerical rating scale from zero (extreme difficulty or unable to perform activity) to four (no difficulty). This provides maximum scale points of eighty, with zero representing maximum dysfunction.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Numerical Pain Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The NPRS is an 11-point scale designed to measure self-reported pain intensity on a scale ranging between 0 (no pain at all) and 10 (the worst pain ever possible)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">159</enrollment>
  <condition>Achilles Tendinopathy</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Treatment from a physiotherapist</intervention_name>
    <description>Any treatment provided by a physiotherapist e.g. exercise, advice and massage</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Diagnosis of Achilles tendinopathy will be based on criteria from expert consensus: local&#xD;
        mid-portion Achilles tendon pain reproduced with load-based activity and tenderness on&#xD;
        palpation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  be a minimum of 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have access to the internet&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have an available email address&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  to have support in place to understand written English if it is required&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  be diagnosed with AT by their treating physiotherapist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  be undertaking treatment prescribed by a physiotherapist.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  not provided informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  been diagnosed with Achilles tendon tear/rupture&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  received surgery to the affected Achilles tendon&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pain in the Achilles region with movements of the spine or neural tissue&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tendinopathy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 12, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/69/NCT05105269/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

