<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05109026</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Connect-5 Needs Assessment</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05109026</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Connect-5 Needs Assessment</brief_title>
  <acronym>CONNECT-5</acronym>
  <official_title>Connect-5 Needs Assessment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Royal College of Surgeons, Ireland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Royal College of Surgeons, Ireland</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an anonymous needs assessment survey of the population of an Irish urban town. We&#xD;
      plan to collect anonymous survey data in order to better understand residents needs and to&#xD;
      determine the desired functionality of a new coach-led wellness app operated by our partners.&#xD;
      This platform is currently trialled for health care professionals working in the RCSI&#xD;
      Hospital Group. The survey will collect information on participants demographics, their&#xD;
      lifestyle (including sleep, exercise, food, relationships, meaning and purpose, substance use&#xD;
      and stress management). We will also ask participants about their use of wellness apps to&#xD;
      support healthy choices related to their lifestyle. We also plan to conduct a qualitative&#xD;
      assessment to further explore needs related to lifestyle health in specific cohorts, namely,&#xD;
      older people (65 years and older), recent migrants, members of the travelling community,&#xD;
      perinatal women, lone-parents, individuals with physical disabilities, secondary school&#xD;
      students and remote workers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      There has been an increase in lifestyle related diseases worldwide (World Health&#xD;
      Organisation, 2018b). Living a healthy lifestyle is important to prevent lifestyle-related&#xD;
      diseases such as heart disease, obesity, diabetes, mental health issues, certain cancers,&#xD;
      autoimmunity and gastro-intestinal disease. The economic impact of these lifestyle-related&#xD;
      diseases in Europe alone is set to exceed €200 billion by 2030. Worldwide, one in five people&#xD;
      are at an increased risk of developing severe COVID-19, mostly as a result of underlying&#xD;
      lifestyle-related diseases. Additionally, global efforts to manage COVID-19 infection have&#xD;
      disrupted regular care required by those with these issues. Dealing with this requires that&#xD;
      people better manage their own health and address lifestyle related factors that increase the&#xD;
      risk associated with such diseases, including inactivity, substance abuse and unhealthy diet&#xD;
      (Ng et al. 2020). These risk factors are modifiable and can be reduced by health&#xD;
      interventions and tools to support a healthy lifestyle.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The COVID-19 pandemic caused prolonged feelings of fear, uncertainty and isolation among the&#xD;
      general population (Ghebreyesus, 2020). This is likely to impact vulnerable members of&#xD;
      society, such as young people, elderly people and those in ethnic minority communities in&#xD;
      greater proportions. Children and adolescents are experiencing increased adverse mental&#xD;
      health effects such as social isolation, loneliness, depression and anxiety, during the&#xD;
      Covid-19 pandemic (O'Sullivan et al. 2021; Loades et al. 2020). Irish adults aged 70 and over&#xD;
      have reported worse mental health and increased feelings of loneliness due to cocooning&#xD;
      throughout the pandemic (Bailey et al. 2021; Ward et al. 2020). This social isolation and&#xD;
      loneliness puts them at increased risk of cognitive and cardiovascular decline (Fried et al.&#xD;
      2020; Valtorta et al. 2016). It is important that we prioritise the development of strategies&#xD;
      to maintain social engagement, manage loneliness and encourage continued physical activity&#xD;
      among older people (Bailey et al. 2021).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Work habits are currently changing at a rapid pace. Significant sections of our workforces&#xD;
      are now working from home and at least 50% are expected to remain at home, even after the&#xD;
      current pandemic has resolved. Reports indicate that a significant proportion of this&#xD;
      workforce is experiencing issues with disconnection and mental health. As a result,&#xD;
      understanding the impact of remote and flexible working arrangements on employee health and&#xD;
      mental wellbeing has been included as a research priority within psychological science&#xD;
      (O'Connor et al. 2020). While there is evidence that remote working has positive effects on&#xD;
      well-being, these effects are not consistent. Remote working may also lead to greater levels&#xD;
      of professional isolation, reduced work-life balance, increase work-related fatigue and have&#xD;
      negative impacts on well-being (O'Connor et al., 2020; Palumbo, 2020).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is being done to better understand people's needs in relation to living a&#xD;
      healthier lifestyle. We aim to conduct a needs assessment the population of one Irish urban&#xD;
      town. We want to check how a new coach-led wellness app could help people make healthy&#xD;
      choices related to their lifestyle. In order to better understand the populations' needs&#xD;
      around a healthy lifestyle, we will ask questions about participants background, lifestyle&#xD;
      and their use of digital technology for health, including smart phone apps. We will also ask&#xD;
      questions about what participants would like to see in a perfect smart phone app; an app that&#xD;
      would help them make healthy choices related to their lifestyle. Qualitative interviews will&#xD;
      also be conducted to further explore individuals needs related to lifestyle health in&#xD;
      specific cohorts, namely, older people (65 years and older), recent migrants, members of the&#xD;
      travelling community, perinatal women, lone-parents, individuals with physical disabilities,&#xD;
      and remote workers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Needs assessment survey</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2022-February 2022</time_frame>
    <description>An anonymous needs assessment survey (online and hard copies) will be conducted.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Needs assessment interivews</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2022-March 2022</time_frame>
    <description>Anonymous qualitative interviews will be conducted in conjunction with community liaison officers, over the telephone with up to 5 members of the following target groups - older people (65 years and older), recent migrants, members of the travelling community, perinatal women, lone-parents, individuals with physical disabilities, and remote workers.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>March 2022- April 2022</time_frame>
    <description>Analysis of summary anonymous aggregate data will be used to inform future stages of this research.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>8</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1820</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Lifestyle</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Older people</arm_group_label>
    <description>Members of the population aged 65 years and older.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Recent migrants</arm_group_label>
    <description>Members of the population who are recent migrants to the community.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Members of the travelling community</arm_group_label>
    <description>Members of the population who are members of the travelling community.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Perinatal women.</arm_group_label>
    <description>Members of the population who are pregnant or within a year of giving birth.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lone-parents</arm_group_label>
    <description>Members of the population who are raising children alone.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Individuals with physical disabilities</arm_group_label>
    <description>Members of the population who have a physical disability.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Secondary school students</arm_group_label>
    <description>Members of the population attending secondary school.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Remote workers</arm_group_label>
    <description>Members of the population currently working from home.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        We aim to collect survey data from at least 1,820 participants (20% response rate).&#xD;
&#xD;
        We will conduct interviews with up to 5 members of each target cohort from the community (&#xD;
        older people, recent migrants, members of the travelling community, perinatal women,&#xD;
        lone-parents, individuals with physical disabilities, and remote workers).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Participants will be members of the urban town being studied.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Non a member of the urban town being studied.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Róisín O'Donovan</last_name>
    <phone>0851554968</phone>
    <email>roisinodonovan@rcsi.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Royal College of Surgeons, Ireland</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Padraic Dunne</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Survey</keyword>
  <keyword>Interviews</keyword>
  <keyword>Needs Assessment</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Only summary aggregate data will be shared.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

