<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05109195</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CR109066</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>42847922MDD3009</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05109195</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Standard of Care Study of Patients With Major Depressive Disorder Who Have Had an Inadequate Response to a Selective Serotonin Reuptake/Serotonin-Norepinephrine Reuptake Inhibitor Antidepressant</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Observational Standard of Care Study of Patients With Major Depressive Disorder Who Have Had an Inadequate Response to a Selective Serotonin Reuptake /Serotonin-Norepinephrine Reuptake Inhibitor Antidepressant as a Control Arm for the Safety Assessments in the Seltorexant Phase 3 Program</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to assess the safety (adverse events, serious adverse events,&#xD;
      deaths, suicidality) of participants with major depressive disorder (MDD) treated according&#xD;
      to the standard of care (SOC).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 26, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 29, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 29, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Spontaneously Reported Adverse Events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with spontaneously reported AEs as recorded in the electronic health record (EHR) will be reported. An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant participating in a clinical study that does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the pharmaceutical/biological agent under study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with AEs Collected through Generic Assessment of Side Effects (GASE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with AEs collected through GASE will be reported. The GASE is an instrument to assess side effects in clinical studies that allows the detection of drug induced AEs.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Hospitalization for Psychiatric Reasons</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with hospitalizations for psychiatric reasons according to the EHR will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Hospitalization for Medical Reasons</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with hospitalizations for medical reasons according to the EHR will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Other Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>SAE is any untoward medical occurrence that at any dose results in any of the following outcomes: death; initial or prolonged inpatient hospitalization; life-threatening experience (immediate risk of dying); persistent or significant disability/incapacity; congenital anomaly/birth defect; suspected transmission of any infectious agent via a medicinal product or medically important.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Deaths</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with deaths will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Suicide Attempts and Completed Suicides</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with suicide attempts and completed suicides as recorded in the EHR and using the structured Columbia Suicide Severity Rating Scale (C-SSRS) will be reported. C-SSRS is semi structured clinician-administered questionnaire designed to solicit the occurrence, severity, and frequency of suicide-related ideation and behaviors.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Suicidal Ideation as Assessed by C-SSRS</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with suicidal ideation as assessed by C-SSRS, particularly codes of 4 or 5 will be reported. C-SSRS is semi structured clinician-administered questionnaire designed to solicit the occurrence, severity, and frequency of suicide-related ideation and behaviors. Scale consists of 28 items in 4 sections: suicide behavior, actual attempts, suicidal ideation, and intensity of ideation. Suicidal ideation consists of 5 yes/no items: wish to be dead, non-specific active suicidal thoughts, active suicidal ideation with any methods (not plan) without intention to act, active suicidal ideation with some intent to act without specific plan, active suicidal ideation with specific plan and intent. Worsening of suicidal ideation will be an increase in severity of suicidal ideation from baseline.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Adverse Events of Special Interest (AESI) Collected through GASE and EHR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with AESI: Cataplexy, Sleep paralysis, Complex sleep-related behaviors, Falls, Motor vehicle accidents, collected through GASE and EHR will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Weight Over Time</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (Week 1) up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in weight over time from the clinical outcome assessments (COA) will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Clinically Meaningful Change in Weight</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (Week 1) to end of study (up to 1 Year)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with clinically meaningful change in weight (greater than or equal to [&gt;=] 7 percent [%]) from baseline to end of study will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Hemoglobin Level Over Time in EHR</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (Week 1), Week 26 and Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in hemoglobin level over time in EHR will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Platelet and White Blood Cell (WBC) Count Over Time in EHR</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (Week 1), Week 26 and Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in platelet and WBC count with differential over time in EHR will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Hematocrit Level Over Time in EHR</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (Week 1), Week 26 and Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in hematocrit level over time in EHR will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Red Blood Cell (RBC) Count Over Time in EHR</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (Week 1), Week 26 and Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in RBC count over time in EHR will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Sodium, Potassium, Chloride and Bicarbonate Level Over Time in EHR</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (Week 1), Week 26 and Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in sodium, potassium, chloride and bicarbonate level over time in EHR will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Blood Urea Nitrogen (BUN), Creatinine, Glucose, Total and Direct Bilirubin, Calcium and Phosphate Level Over Time in EHR</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (Week 1), Week 26 and Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in BUN, creatinine, glucose, total and direct bilirubin, calcium and phosphate level over time in EHR will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Aspartate Aminotransferase (AST), Alanine Aminotransferase (ALT), Alkaline Phosphatase Level Over Time in EHR</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (Week 1), Week 26 and Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in AST, ALT, alkaline phosphatase level over time in EHR will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Albumin and Total Protein Level Over Time in EHR</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (Week 1), Week 26 and Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in albumin and total protein level over time in EHR will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Total Cholesterol, Low-density Lipoprotein Cholesterol, Triglycerides, High-density Lipoprotein Cholesterol Level Over Time in EHR</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (Week 1), Week 26 and Week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in total cholesterol, low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (calculated), triglycerides, high-density lipoprotein cholesterol level over time in EHR will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Depressive Disorder, Major</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MDD Participants with Insufficient Response to SSRI/SNRI (antidepressant)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Major Depressive Disorder (MDD) participants with insufficient response to a selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor (SSRI)/serotonin-norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor (SNRI) (antidepressant) and starting an adjunctive therapy will be observed to create an external control arm (ECA) based on real world data (RWD) from electronic health records (EHR) data during routine medical care (standard of care [SOC]) combined with scheduled research assessments.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard of Care (SOC)</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will not receive any intervention as a part of this study. Participants will receive SOC treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MDD Participants with Insufficient Response to SSRI/SNRI (antidepressant)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study population will consists of participants who will have one of the augmenting&#xD;
        agents started.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have a confirmed diagnosis of Major Depressive Disorder (MDD) with a diagnostic&#xD;
             code at least twice in the past year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with an selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor&#xD;
             (SSRI)/serotonin-norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor (SNRI) for at least 6 weeks at an&#xD;
             adequate dose (per Massachusetts General Hospital-Antidepressant Treatment Response&#xD;
             Questionnaire [MGH-ATRQ]) and for no more than a year. Specifically, one of the&#xD;
             following in any formulation: SSRIs: citalopram, duloxetine, escitalopram,&#xD;
             fluvoxamine, fluoxetine, milnacipran, levomilnacipran, paroxetine, sertraline; SNRIs:&#xD;
             venlafaxine, desvenlafaxine, vilazodone, or vortioxetine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently on a single SSRI/SNRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current episode of MDD has lasted less than 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a body mass index (BMI) of 18-37 kilograms per meter square (Kg/m^2), (inclusive)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking more than one antidepressant (regardless of class) at therapeutic doses&#xD;
             (therapeutic doses per MGH-ATRQ). A second antidepressant is allowed to be taken at a&#xD;
             lower dose if for sleep or pain management&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently taking a benzodiazepine at higher doses than the equivalent of 3&#xD;
             milligrams (mg) of lorazepam&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any coding of a psychotic disorder in the past 5 years including MDD with psychosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any coding of borderline personality disorder, bipolar disorder, autism spectrum&#xD;
             disorder, intellectual disability, somatoform disorder, or fibromyalgia in the past 5&#xD;
             years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any coding of dementia or mild cognitive impairment in the past 5 years&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>74 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC Clinical Trial</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Study Contact</last_name>
    <phone>844-434-4210</phone>
    <email>JNJ.CT@sylogent.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California San Francisco</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94143</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brigham &amp; Women's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The University of Pittsburgh of the Commonwealth System of Higher Education</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15260</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Warneford Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <zip>OX3 7JX</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://pam.sylogent.com/cr/CR109066</url>
    <description>To learn how to participate in this trial please click here.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

