<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05106790</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APUTRA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05106790</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Factorial Approach to Improve Treatment Adherence</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of a mHealth Intervention for Treatment Adherence in Adult Hypertensive Patients: a Randomized Controlled Trial With Factorial Design</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universiti Putra Malaysia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universiti Putra Malaysia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Poor medication adherence is a crucial operational factor for uncontrolled hypertension&#xD;
      prevalence in Pakistan. Technology-based mobile phone interventions are available at the&#xD;
      forefront and a relatively cheap tool to combat the recent health challenges related to poor&#xD;
      adherence. This study will assess the impact of mobile health-based multimodal approach&#xD;
      intervention to enhance medication adherence in patients with hypertension.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Hypertension is indeed a significant public health concern in Pakistan. Hypertension&#xD;
      drastically affects 18.9% of adolescents of age greater than 15 and 33% of adults above 45;&#xD;
      less than 3% of hypertensive patients, however, have their blood pressure controlled to&#xD;
      140/90 mm Hg or below. The results of the meta-analysis showed optimal adherence can result&#xD;
      in poor outcomes by 26%. Poor medication adherence is the cause of poor control of blood&#xD;
      pressure in Pakistan. The majority of patients on hypertensive medication are found to have&#xD;
      uncontrolled blood pressure. A majority of the population on treatment were found to be&#xD;
      non-adherent. The adherence to cardiac medicines was reported as ranging from 27-77% and&#xD;
      about 68% to stroke medicines. In a recent study, 37.7% of patients were non-adherent to the&#xD;
      prescribed antihypertensive therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will seek mobile health interventions' effectiveness by using our different&#xD;
      modules in improving patients' treatment adherence and alleviating blood pressure in&#xD;
      hypertensive patients. If this study finds significant results it can help develop&#xD;
      educational guidelines for patients to improve their medication adherence and reduce related&#xD;
      complications at the same time. We will give a new line of research for coming researchers&#xD;
      eventually.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 15, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>It is a factorial design, intention-to-treat, four-arm, single-blinded randomized controlled trial, six months of duration with an intervention pre-test and post-test evaluation to analyze the efficacy of mobile health using four different educational and reminder modules interventions to improve treatment adherence on clinical grounds in hypertensive patients in a tertiary care hospital of Lahore, Pakistan.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Single blinded</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in systolic blood pressure (SBP)</measure>
    <time_frame>6- month from baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome is a change in systolic blood pressure (SBP) of participants at 0, 3, and 6 months. The blood pressure will be recorded by sphygmomanometer used was calibrated upper-arm electronic sphygmomanometer (OMRON HEM-7200, OMRON Corporation, Dalian). Two separate readings will be taken within 5 min, and the average measurement will be the final. If the difference between the two measurements will be more than 5mmHg, then a third recording will be done and the average is considered.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in medication adherence to antihypertensive treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>6- month from baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The secondary outcome is the change in medication adherence to antihypertensive treatment. Using the SEAMS questionnaire and &quot;pills taken over a certain period, divided by pills prescribed for that specific period&quot;, the primary outcome will be measured. Both of the above-mentioned information will be self-reporting. The SEAMS is a 13-item questionnaire that has three-point responses. The score for the 13-item scale ranges from 13 to 39. Higher scores show better levels of self-efficacy for medication adherence and vice versa. A cut-off value of 80% has been established from previous literature. Non-adherents will make up less than 80% of the population, while adherents will make up more than 80%.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">772</enrollment>
  <condition>Treatment Adherence and Compliance</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The first group will be on standard care as usually being practiced in hospitals.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The second group will receive daily written notes and voice messages in addition to standard care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The third group will receive daily Graphic based reminders and once weekly an animated video along with standard care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm D</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The fourth group along with standard care will receive written notes, voice messages, Graphic based reminders on daily basis, and once the weekly animated video in addition to standard care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Written notes and voice messages</intervention_name>
    <description>Group B will receive daily written notes and voice messages (For example, &quot;Good Morning, &quot;It's your medicine time.&quot; &quot;Good Morning, &quot;This is to remind you of your medication&quot; in Urdu and English languages), in addition to standard care through WhatsApp as a reminder for medication</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Graphic based reminders and once weekly an animated video</intervention_name>
    <description>Group C will receive daily Graphic based reminders and once weekly an animated video regarding educational support and the outcome of disease, The video has three parts 1) knowledge about hypertension 2) complications of uncontrolled hypertension 3) medical and lifestyle adaptation for good health which resultantly improves adherence. along with standard care.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>written notes, voice messages, Graphic based reminders , and animated video</intervention_name>
    <description>Group D will receive written notes, voice messages (For example, &quot;Good Morning, &quot;It's your medicine time.&quot; &quot;Good Morning, &quot;This is to remind you of your medication&quot; in Urdu and English languages), Graphic based reminders daily, and once weekly an animated video regarding educational support and the outcome of disease, The video has three parts 1) knowledge about hypertension 2) complications of uncontrolled hypertension 3) medical and lifestyle adaptation for good health which resultantly improves adherence. along with standard care.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm D</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with age more than 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients diagnosed with hypertension and registered in the OPDs of Cardiology and&#xD;
             Medicine department in Shaikh Zayed Hospital, Lahore, for at least last one month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on antihypertensive drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with poor medication adherence ( Less than 80% measured by SEAMS and pill&#xD;
             counting information)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Single-member from one family&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with smartphones and using &quot;WhatsApp&quot; application&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who sufferers with the planned journey within two months without internet&#xD;
             signals area Participants who suffer from some type of malignancy and require&#xD;
             adjustment of drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who sufferers with any planned procedure like CABG, PCI, or CEA (Carotid&#xD;
             Endarterectomy), as need immediate changes in their medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants in hypertensive emergency blood pressure &gt;220/120 mmHg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with pregnancy(self-reporting)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants in their period of lactation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Arshed MUHAMMAD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UPM</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Arshed MUHAMMAD, MBBS,MPH</last_name>
    <phone>+923337474464</phone>
    <email>drarshedchaudhary@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Maaz Arif Muhammad, MBBS</last_name>
    <phone>00923481816881</phone>
    <email>maazarifbutt@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>NCD Risk Factor Collaboration (NCD-RisC). Worldwide trends in blood pressure from 1975 to 2015: a pooled analysis of 1479 population-based measurement studies with 19·1 million participants. Lancet. 2017 Jan 7;389(10064):37-55. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(16)31919-5. Epub 2016 Nov 16. Erratum in: Lancet. 2020 Sep 26;396(10255):886.</citation>
    <PMID>27863813</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lewington S, Clarke R, Qizilbash N, Peto R, Collins R; Prospective Studies Collaboration. Age-specific relevance of usual blood pressure to vascular mortality: a meta-analysis of individual data for one million adults in 61 prospective studies. Lancet. 2002 Dec 14;360(9349):1903-13. Erratum in: Lancet. 2003 Mar 22;361(9362):1060.</citation>
    <PMID>12493255</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>NIPS/Pakistan and ICF NI of PS-. Pakistan Demographic and Health Survey 2017-18. 2019 [cited 4 Jan 2021]. Available: https://dhsprogram.com/publications/publication-fr354-dhs-final-reports.cfm</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mahmood S, Jalal Z, Hadi MA, Orooj H, Shah KU. Non-Adherence to Prescribed Antihypertensives in Primary, Secondary and Tertiary Healthcare Settings in Islamabad, Pakistan: A Cross-Sectional Study. Patient Prefer Adherence. 2020 Jan 14;14:73-85. doi: 10.2147/PPA.S235517. eCollection 2020.</citation>
    <PMID>32021119</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhai P, Hayat K, Ji W, Li Q, Shi L, Atif N, Xu S, Li P, Du Q, Fang Y. Efficacy of Text Messaging and Personal Consultation by Pharmacy Students Among Adults With Hypertension: Randomized Controlled Trial. J Med Internet Res. 2020 May 20;22(5):e16019. doi: 10.2196/16019.</citation>
    <PMID>32432556</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chan AW, Tetzlaff JM, Altman DG, Laupacis A, Gøtzsche PC, Krleža-Jerić K, Hróbjartsson A, Mann H, Dickersin K, Berlin JA, Doré CJ, Parulekar WR, Summerskill WS, Groves T, Schulz KF, Sox HC, Rockhold FW, Rennie D, Moher D. SPIRIT 2013 statement: defining standard protocol items for clinical trials. Ann Intern Med. 2013 Feb 5;158(3):200-7. doi: 10.7326/0003-4819-158-3-201302050-00583.</citation>
    <PMID>23295957</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bhide A, Shah PS, Acharya G. A simplified guide to randomized controlled trials. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2018 Apr;97(4):380-387. doi: 10.1111/aogs.13309. Epub 2018 Feb 27. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29377058</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Risser J, Jacobson TA, Kripalani S. Development and psychometric evaluation of the Self-efficacy for Appropriate Medication Use Scale (SEAMS) in low-literacy patients with chronic disease. J Nurs Meas. 2007;15(3):203-19.</citation>
    <PMID>18232619</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Strobl J, Cave E, Walley T. Data protection legislation: interpretation and barriers to research. BMJ. 2000 Oct 7;321(7265):890-2.</citation>
    <PMID>11021874</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Del Re AC, Maisel NC, Blodgett JC, Finney JW. Intention-to-treat analyses and missing data approaches in pharmacotherapy trials for alcohol use disorders. BMJ Open. 2013 Nov 12;3(11):e003464. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2013-003464.</citation>
    <PMID>24227870</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Montgomery AA, Peters TJ, Little P. Design, analysis and presentation of factorial randomised controlled trials. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2003 Nov 24;3:26.</citation>
    <PMID>14633287</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Whelan DB, Dainty K, Chahal J. Efficient designs: factorial randomized trials. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2012 Jul 18;94 Suppl 1:34-8. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.L.00243.</citation>
    <PMID>22810445</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universiti Putra Malaysia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Arshed Muhammad</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PhD scholar</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

