<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05108298</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EAQ202</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05108298</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Improving Adolescent and Young Adult Self-Reported Data in ECOG-ACRIN Trials</brief_title>
  <official_title>Improving Adolescent and Young Adult Self-Reported Data in ECOG-ACRIN Trials</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate feasibility and acceptability of completing PROs&#xD;
      among AYAs randomized to Choice PRO vs Fixed PRO.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Primary Aim: Conduct a pilot randomized controlled trial with AYAs to determine the&#xD;
      feasibility and acceptability of completing PROs informed by AYAs' priorities. AYAs will be&#xD;
      consented and randomized to select five HRQOL domains from a dashboard (Choice PRO) at each&#xD;
      assessment period or to five standard HRQOL domains (Fixed PRO; physical function, pain,&#xD;
      cognitive function, social support, finances) at each assessment period. AYAs will complete&#xD;
      baseline, 1-, 3-, 6-, and 12-month assessments which will include a combination of CATs and&#xD;
      static short forms. Feasibility will be operationalized as ≥ 75% completed PROs and ≥ 75%&#xD;
      acceptability. Feasibility and acceptability will be compared between AYAs randomized to&#xD;
      Choice PRO vs Fixed PRO. Adherence boosters (reminder calls, text messages) will be used to&#xD;
      minimize missing data and evaluated as moderators.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory Aim: Solicit AYA preferences for how their PRO data should be shared with them&#xD;
      and/or their providers. To inform future research, AYAs will be asked if and how participants&#xD;
      want their PRO data to be used by their medical teams as well as if and how participants want&#xD;
      their PRO data to be shared with them and their families.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators anticipate PROMIS CATs will increase capacity for PRO data capture, AYAs&#xD;
      randomized to Choice PRO, who are given the opportunity to choose which PRO domains to&#xD;
      complete, will have less missing data. The investigators expect the majority of AYAs will&#xD;
      want PRO feedback for themselves, their families, and their providers. Findings will promote&#xD;
      and sustain the inclusion of PROs in clinical and supportive care trials, providing AYA's a&#xD;
      voice and informing future patient-centered care tailored to the diverse needs of AYAs. By&#xD;
      offering AYAs the opportunity to choose which PRO domains to complete based on relevance to&#xD;
      their health-related quality of life, as opposed to completing domains pre-determined by the&#xD;
      research team, the investigators raise the patient-centeredness of investigators assessment&#xD;
      approach.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 28, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate completion of PROs among AYAs randomized to Choice PRO vs Fixed PRO.</measure>
    <time_frame>Feasibility at 1 month and acceptability at baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate feasibility and acceptability of completing PROs among AYAs randomized to Choice PRO vs Fixed PRO.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate AYAs' HRQOL priorities and HRQOL PRO trajectories</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The goal of the ranking exercise is to evaluate the importance of HRQOL domain rank choice PROs and examine their changes over time.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Access and Utilization</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed up to 52 months</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate access to and utilization of psychosocial and financial resources using items from the Consumer-Based Cancer Care Value Index (CCVI).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>To summarize AYAs' preferences for how their PRO data should be shared with them, their families, and/or their providers.</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed up to 52 months</time_frame>
    <description>Solicit AYAs preferences with regard to possible applications for their PRO data, including sharing PRO data with their medical teams and/or their families, and providing participants with summary feedback.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer, NOS</condition>
  <condition>CNS Primary Tumor, NOS</condition>
  <condition>Cervical Cancer, NOS</condition>
  <condition>Colorectal Cancer, NOS</condition>
  <condition>Leukemia, NOS</condition>
  <condition>Lymphoma, NOS</condition>
  <condition>Miscellaneous Neoplasm, NOS</condition>
  <condition>Non-Rhabdomyosarcoma Soft Tissue Sarcoma, NOS</condition>
  <condition>Testicular Nonseminomatous Germ Cell Tumor, NOS</condition>
  <condition>Thyroid Cancer, NOS</condition>
  <condition>Melanoma</condition>
  <condition>Bone Cancer, NOS</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
    <description>5 domain-specific HRQOL measures</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control arm</arm_group_label>
    <description>5 pre-selected HRQOL measures</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaires</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will complete questionnaires online through EASEE-PRO. There will be a set of fixed questionnaires at each timepoint for both arms. The patients will be asked to rank the 15 types of PROs according to their importance. The participants randomized to the choice arm will be asked to choose 5 of the 15 PROs to complete. The participants randomized to the fixed arm will be given a fixed 5 of the 15 PROs at each time point.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adolescent &amp; Young Adult (AYAs) with cancer from participating NCTN, LAPS and NCORP sites,&#xD;
        including minority/underserved sites.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient must be ≥ 18 years and ≤ 39 years of age at registration. Patient must have a&#xD;
        histologically confirmed diagnosis of primary cancer of any stage within 12 weeks (84 days)&#xD;
        at registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient must have received, be currently receiving or planning to receive treatment for&#xD;
        cancer, including surgery and/or chemotherapy and/or radiation therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient must have an ECOG performance status 0-3. Patient must have a life expectancy &gt;24&#xD;
        months. Patient must be able to complete questionnaires in English. Patient must have&#xD;
        internet access through computer, tablet, or smartphone. Patient must have an email&#xD;
        address. Patient must have a mobile phone able with text messaging capabilities. Patient&#xD;
        must be able to accurately provide self-report data (e.g. per clinical judgment, cognitive&#xD;
        function is intact).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient must be able to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient must not have a recurrence or second primary cancer. Patients must not have basal&#xD;
        cell skin carcinoma.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>39 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wake Forest School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winston-Salem</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27157</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>John M Salsman, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>336-713-3613</phone>
      <email>jsalsman@wakehealth.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>John M Salsman</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thyroid Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Germ Cell and Embryonal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bone Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

