<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05104671</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>shoulder impingement</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05104671</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Thoracic Manipulation Versus Myofascial Release in Patients With Shoulder Impingement Syndrome</brief_title>
  <official_title>Thoracic Manipulation Versus Myofascial Release in Patients With Shoulder Impingement Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>manar sameh el taher</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      aims: • To investigate the effect of adding thoracic manipulation vs myofascial release to&#xD;
      scapular stabilization exercise on pain intensity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To investigate the effect of adding thoracic manipulation vs myofascial release to&#xD;
           scapular stabilization exercise on pain pressure threshold.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To investigate the effect of adding thoracic manipulation vs myofascial release to&#xD;
           scapular stabilization exercise on shoulder proprioception.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To investigate the effect of adding thoracic manipulation vs myofascial release to&#xD;
           scapular stabilization exercise on shoulder range of motion(Rom)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To investigate the effect of adding thoracic manipulation vs myofascial release to&#xD;
           scapular stabilization exercise on disability of shoulder and hand questionnaire(DASH).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Various researches have been done on rehabilitation of shoulder impingement by addressing&#xD;
      either osseous structure or myofascial structure and found to be effective. But no studies&#xD;
      could retrieve to compare these two: myofascial release and thoracic manipulation. (Dash &amp;&#xD;
      Deepak, 2020). so in this study we will investigate the effect of adding thoracic&#xD;
      manipulation versus myofascial release in patients with shoulder impingement syndrome. we&#xD;
      will investigate the effect on each of the following: pain intensity will measure by vas.&#xD;
&#xD;
      proprioception of the shoulder by isokinetic dynamomemter. pain pressure thershold by&#xD;
      algometer. function by DASH questionnare and finally ROM by kineovea software.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The subjects will be arranged into three groups: Group I (control group) will receive&#xD;
      scapular stabilization exercises.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Group II will receive scapular stabilization exercises and thoracic manipulation&#xD;
           combined with shoulder mobilization.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Group III will receive scapular stabilization exercises and myofascial release by&#xD;
           instrument assisted soft tissue mobilization techniques(IASTM).&#xD;
&#xD;
      the measurments will take before and after treatment programe and after one month of follow&#xD;
      up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain in shoulder movement</measure>
    <time_frame>change from max pain point at 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>will be measured by Visiual analoug scale(VAS). It consists of a line, often 10 cm long(100mm); its ends are generally labelled with verbal pain anchors (e.g., &quot;no pain&quot; and &quot;pain as bad as it could be&quot;). Patients are asked to indicate the point along the line that best reflects their pain intensity. The majority of the studies showed that visual analogue scale is a valid and reliable scale. Also, it is an interval scale. So, in clinical practice we can use this scale in case of pain measurement as an outcome measure tool</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>shoulder function</measure>
    <time_frame>change from limitation of funtion at 2months</time_frame>
    <description>by DASH is a reliable and valid tool for the assessment of shoulder pain and disability in both clinical practice and research</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Shoulder Proprioception (joint of position error)</measure>
    <time_frame>change from poor proprioception at 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>will be measured by isokinetic dynamometer. Isokinetic dynamometry is considered a valid instrument for assessing muscle strength, and it is often used as a reference standard for other strength assessments</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Shoulder ROM</measure>
    <time_frame>change from limitation in shoulder rom at 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>will be measured by Kinovea. Kinovea is a free software used for the analysis, comparison, and evaluation of sports and training. it is a reliable tool for measuring shoulder flexion, abduction, and Internal rotation&amp;external rotation in healthy individuals. Thus, it could be used as a simple alternative to universal goniometry.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain pressure threshold in shoulder muscles</measure>
    <time_frame>change from baseline pain pressure threshold at 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>that Pressure algometer is a worthwhile tool in the diagnosis and treatment evaluation of different orthopaedic disorders. . Three consecutive Pressure pain threshold measurements were taken at each point with 20 s rest between measurements, and the mean of the three trialswill be used for analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Impingement Shoulder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Scapular stabilization exercises</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group I (control group) will receive scapular stabilization exercises.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Thoracic manipulation.</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group II will receive scapular stabilization exercises and thoracic manipulation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Myofascial release</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group III will receive scapular stabilization exercises and myofascial release by instrument assisted soft tissue mobilization techniques.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>scapular stabilization exercises.</intervention_name>
    <description>General Instructions: For all exercises, perform the retraction of the scapula, without performing the elevation of the shoulders, taking the lower angle of the scapula &quot;back and down&quot;.&#xD;
The exercise intensity was described as repetitions, sets, and holding time. Commonly, 10-20 repetitions and three to five sets held for 3-10 seconds were performed.and the exercises will be:&#xD;
towel slide&#xD;
Scapular Clock:&#xD;
Scapular Proprioceptive Neuromuscular facilitation:&#xD;
Inferior Glide.&#xD;
Scapular Orientation Exercise (SOE):&#xD;
Protraction and retraction in front of a mirror:</description>
    <arm_group_label>Myofascial release</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Scapular stabilization exercises</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Thoracic manipulation.</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Thoracic manipulation.</intervention_name>
    <description>• Thoracic Thrust Manipulation: The participants were in high sitting and in prone lying position. The therapist was standing next to the patient in a diagonal stance and also behind the patient during high sitting. Thoracic thrust manipulation demonstrated to manipulate specific thoracic segment mainly mid thoracic.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Thoracic manipulation.</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>scapular stabilization exercises</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Myofascial release.</intervention_name>
    <description>The subject will be treated with IASTM.applied to the pectoral muscles and medial brachium with the subject in supine and the GH joint placed in 120 º abduction to place adequate tension on the selected tissues in the style of pectoral tightness test .The IASTM technique was performed for 20 seconds parallel to the muscle fibers followed by 20 seconds perpendicular to the muscle fibers with the instrument held at a 45 º angle to the skin.The same IASTM protocol of 20 seconds parallel to the muscle fibers and 20 seconds perpendicular to the muscle fibers was applied to the posterior cuff musculature of the GH joint with the subject in prone and arms in 90 º abduction and internal rotation draped over the side of the plinth . While in the same position, the technique was applied to the periscapular musculature including the, trapezius, rhomboids, teres minor, teres major, and latissimus dorsi.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Myofascial release</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>scapular stabilization exercises</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Sixty patients with shoulder impingement syndrome from both genders their age will be&#xD;
             ranged and divided into three groups from 25-40 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of shoulder pain for at least one month.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Positive Neer's impingement test and Hawkin's kiennedy test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Presence of thoracic hypomobility from clinical evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Provocation of pain above 60 degrees of flexion and abduction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Palpable trigger points on shoulder muscles.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of Shoulder girdle fracture, dislocation and surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Diagnosed with frozen shoulder or rotator cuff tear&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of cervicobrachial pain&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Any neuromuscular pain in upper limb and use of corticosteroids or pain subsiding&#xD;
             medication&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 21, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>manar sameh el taher</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Researcher</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Shoulder Impingement Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Undecided</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

