<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05100407</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MDR and predictive factors</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05100407</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Factors Impacting the Prevalence of MDR Bacteria</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Prevalence and Antibiotic Susceptibility Pattern of Multidrug Resistance Bacteria and Its Association With Patients' Predictive Factors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kufa University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kufa University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      1. To determine the prevalence of multidrug resistance bacteria in patient with different&#xD;
           infections&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To evaluate patients' predictive risk factors of antimicrobial resistance&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To assess the association between patients' factors and prevalence of MDR bacteria&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Antimicrobial resistance is one of the most critical public health issue in this century .&#xD;
      WHO declared antimicrobial resistance as one of the top ten global health threats that impend&#xD;
      the effective management and prevention of evolving infections .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Antimicrobial resistance nowadays poses a big challenge because of the emerging of resistance&#xD;
      to the antibiotics that previously effective and development of multidrug resistance&#xD;
      infections with subsequent increase in morbidity, mortality and financial loss .&#xD;
&#xD;
      In spite of WHO health strategies that taken to face multidrug resistance problem, the burden&#xD;
      of antimicrobial resistance in Europe is compared with combined burden of influenza and HIVS&#xD;
      .while in USA the estimated antibiotics resistance infections is 2.8 millions and the related&#xD;
      deaths exceeded 35,000 every year and expected to reach to ten million deaths with collective&#xD;
      cost of 100 trillion USD annually in 2050 .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Numerous studies reported that self-medications, improper prescription, overuse of&#xD;
      antibiotics, deficiency of antibiotics susceptibility test and limited knowledge and attitude&#xD;
      of population towards antibiotics are the main factors that lead to antibiotics efficacy&#xD;
      being reduced with long hospital stay. Other studies stated that the predictive indicators of&#xD;
      MDR tragedy are age, gender, comorbidities, previous hospital stay or antibiotic use .&#xD;
&#xD;
      In low and middle income countries like IRAQ there is a difficulty in estimation the scope of&#xD;
      antibiotics resistance problem and its evolving over time due to the lack of surveillance,&#xD;
      besides alarmingly excessive antibiotics consumption added other challenges and urged us to&#xD;
      aim this study .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of multidrug resistance bacteria in isolated patient specimen</measure>
    <time_frame>based line value (zero months)</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of MDR bacteria that detected in isolated specimen</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Association of patient's factors with prevalence of multidrug resistance Bacteria.</measure>
    <time_frame>based line value (zero months)</time_frame>
    <description>exploring the association between patient's factors and the prevalence of MDR bacteria by multivariate analysis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of Methicillin resistance staph. Aureus (MERSA)</measure>
    <time_frame>based line value (zero months)</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of participants with MERSA bacteria that detected in isolated specimen</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of vancomycin (-resistant Enterococci VRE)</measure>
    <time_frame>based line value (zero months)</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of participants with VRE bacteria that detected in isolated specimen</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of extended spectrum β lactamase producers (ESBL)</measure>
    <time_frame>based line value (zero months)</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of participants with ESBL bacteria that detected in isolated specimen</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowledge, attitude and practice (KAP) toward antibiotic use</measure>
    <time_frame>based line value (zero months)</time_frame>
    <description>the score indicator of KAP through a module of KAP survey by 20 categorized questions the knowledge is individual understanding about antibiotic resistance the attitude is the perceptions and beliefs that respondents (+),(-) perceive towards antibiotic resistance the practice is the observable actions of individual towards antibiotic use</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Risk factors for antibiotic resistance</measure>
    <time_frame>based line value (zero months)</time_frame>
    <description>asses patient's predictive factors and their role in prevalence of multidrug resistance bacteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Multi-antibiotic Resistance</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        patients hospitalized with bacterial infection and screened for MDR bacteria in AL-Zahraa&#xD;
        teaching hospital or AL-Sader medical city&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who were screened for MDR bacteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who accepted to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with no growth media&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who cannot communicated&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hayder Asaad, assist. prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>college of pharmacy kufa university</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Zahraa Najah, Ms.Ph.</last_name>
    <phone>07800259989</phone>
    <email>ph.zhraafakhreldain@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Hayder Assad, assist. prof</last_name>
    <phone>07705652560</phone>
    <email>phhaydernajaf@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Prestinaci F, Pezzotti P, Pantosti A. Antimicrobial resistance: a global multifaceted phenomenon. Pathog Glob Health. 2015;109(7):309-18. doi: 10.1179/2047773215Y.0000000030. Epub 2015 Sep 7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26343252</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Who.int. 2021. Antimicrobial resistance. [online] Available at: https://www.who.int/health-topics/antimicrobial-resistance</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bhardwaj, K., Shenoy M, S., Baliga, S., Unnikrishnan, B. and Baliga, B., 2021. Knowledge, attitude, and practices related to antibiotic use and resistance among the general public of coastal south Karnataka, India - A cross-sectional survey. Clinical Epidemiology and Global Health, 11, p.100717</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mallah N, Rodríguez-Cano R, Figueiras A, Takkouche B. Design, reliability and construct validity of a Knowledge, Attitude and Practice questionnaire on personal use of antibiotics in Spain. Sci Rep. 2020 Nov 26;10(1):20668. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-77769-6.</citation>
    <PMID>33244041</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Marzan M, Islam DZ, Lugova H, Krishnapillai A, Haque M, Islam S. Knowledge, Attitudes, and Practices of Antimicrobial Uses and Resistance Among Public University Students in Bangladesh. Infect Drug Resist. 2021 Feb 11;14:519-533. doi: 10.2147/IDR.S289964. eCollection 2021.</citation>
    <PMID>33603416</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rodríguez-Villodres Á, Martín-Gandul C, Peñalva G, Guisado-Gil AB, Crespo-Rivas JC, Pachón-Ibáñez ME, Lepe JA, Cisneros JM. Prevalence and Risk Factors for Multidrug-Resistant Organisms Colonization in Long-Term Care Facilities Around the World: A Review. Antibiotics (Basel). 2021 Jun 7;10(6). pii: 680. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics10060680. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>34200238</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>eLife. 2021. Epidemiology and burden of multidrug-resistant bacterial infection in a developing country. [online] Available at: &lt;https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.18082.001&gt;</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Kufa University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Zahraa Najah Mohsin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>general pharmacist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

