<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05100134</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CLDK378A2401</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05100134</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>MAP to Provide Access to Ceritinib, for ALK Positive Tumors Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Managed Access Program (MAP) to Provide Access to Ceritinib, for ALK Positive Tumors Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Novartis</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this Cohort Treatment Plan is to allow access to ceritinib for eligible&#xD;
      patients diagnosed with ALK positive tumors, previously pre-treated with ALK inhibitors or&#xD;
      naive. The patient's Treating Physician should follow the suggested treatment guidelines and&#xD;
      comply with all local health authority regulations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Available</overall_status>
  <study_type>Expanded Access</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <expanded_access_info>
    <expanded_access_type_intermediate>Yes</expanded_access_type_intermediate>
  </expanded_access_info>
  <condition>ALK Positive Tumors</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ceritinib</intervention_name>
    <description>LDK378 will be administered orally once daily at a dose of 750 mg (fasting) or 450 mg (with food) on a continuous dosing schedule.</description>
    <other_name>LDK378</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients eligible for inclusion in this Treatment Plan have to meet all of the following&#xD;
        criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The patient is diagnosed with ALK-positive tumor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The patient has been previously pre-treated with ALK inhibitor or naive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The patient has progression of disease at screening or is intolerant to prior therapy&#xD;
             and does not qualify or have access to LDK378 through a clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The patient has a performance status (WHO) of 0-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The following laboratory criteria have been met:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1.5 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin (Hgb) ≥ 8 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥75 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN), except for patients&#xD;
                  with Gilbert's syndrome who may be included if total bilirubin ≤ 3.0 x ULN or&#xD;
                  direct bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate transaminase (AST) ≤ 3.0 x ULN, except for patients with liver&#xD;
                  metastasis, who are only included if AST ≤ 5.0 x ULN;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine transaminase (ALT) ≤3.0 x ULN, except for patients with liver metastasis,&#xD;
                  who are only included if ALT ≤ 5.0 x ULN;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  alkaline phosphatase (ALP) ≤ 5.0 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine &lt;1.5 mg/dL and or Calculated creatinine clearance (CrCL) (using&#xD;
                  Cockcroft-Gault formula) ≥ 30 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum amylase ≤ 2 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum lipase ≤ ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fasting plasma glucose ≤175 mg/dL (≤9.8 mmol/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patient must have the following laboratory values within normal limits or corrected to&#xD;
             within normal limits with supplements before the first dose of ceritinib:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Potassium&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Magnesium&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Phosphorus&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total calcium (corrected for serum albumin) Written patient informed consent must&#xD;
                  be obtained prior to start of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients eligible for this Treatment Plan must not meet any of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. A history of pancreatitis or history of increased amylase or lipase that was due to&#xD;
             pancreatic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Other concurrent severe, acute, or chronic and/or uncontrolled medical conditions&#xD;
             (e.g. diabetes mellitus or psychiatric conditions or laboratory abnormalities&#xD;
             uncontrolled heart disease in the last 6 months, active or uncontrolled infection)&#xD;
             that, in the opinion of the treating physician, could cause unacceptable safety risks,&#xD;
             interfere with the interpretation of the results or compromise compliance with the&#xD;
             treatment plan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient who has received thoracic radiotherapy to lung fields ≤4 weeks prior to&#xD;
             starting the study treatment or patients who have not recovered from&#xD;
             radiotherapy-related toxicities. For all other anatomic sites (including radiotherapy&#xD;
             to thoracic vertebrae and ribs) radiotherapy ≤2 weeks prior to starting the study&#xD;
             treatment or has not recovered from radiotherapy-related toxicities. Palliative&#xD;
             radiotherapy for bone lesions ≤2 weeks prior to starting study treatment is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Known history of interstitial lung disease or interstitial pneumonitis including&#xD;
             clinically significant radiation pneumonitis (i.e. affecting activities of daily&#xD;
             living or requiring therapeutic intervention).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Clinically significant, uncontrolled heart disease and/or recent cardiac event (within&#xD;
             6 months), such as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable angina within 6 months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Myocardial infarction within 6 months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of documented congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association&#xD;
                  functional classification III-IV).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled hypertension defined by a Systolic Blood Pressure (SBP) ≥160 mm Hg&#xD;
                  and/or Diastolic Blood Pressure (DBP) ≥100 mm Hg, with or without&#xD;
                  antihypertensive medication. Initiation or adjustment of antihypertensive&#xD;
                  medication (s) is allowed prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ventricular arrhythmias&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Supraventricular and nodal arrhythmias not controlled with medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Other cardiac arrhythmia not controlled with medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Corrected QT (QTcF) &gt;470 ms using Fridericia's correction on the screening ECG&#xD;
                  (as mean of triplicate ECGs).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Known hypersensitivity to any excipients of LDK378 (microcrystalline cellulose,&#xD;
             mannitol, crospovidone, colloidal silicon dioxide and magnesium stearate)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Impaired GI function or GI disease that may significantly alter absorption of LDK378&#xD;
             (e.g., ulcerative disease, uncontrolled nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, or malabsorption&#xD;
             syndrome).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patient must not be participating in other ongoing trials, or ALK inhibitors trials or&#xD;
             other compassionate use programs. Patients eligible for this program are also&#xD;
             ineligible for other ALK inhibitors trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Receiving medications that meet one of the following criteria and that cannot be&#xD;
             discontinued at least 1 week prior to the start of treatment with LDK378 and for the&#xD;
             duration of the program:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Strong inhibitors or strong inducers of CYP3A4/5&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Medications with a low therapeutic index that are primarily metabolized by&#xD;
                  CYP3A4/5 and/or CYP2C9&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Medications with a known risk of prolonging the QT interval or inducing Torsades&#xD;
                  de Pointes.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Receiving treatment with warfarin sodium (Coumadin) or any other coumadinderived&#xD;
                  anti-coagulant&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Receiving unstable or increasing doses of corticosteroids. If patients are on&#xD;
                  corticosteroids for endocrine deficiencies or tumor-associated symptoms (non-&#xD;
                  CNS), dose must have been stabilized (or decreasing) for at least 5 days before&#xD;
                  first dose of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has had major surgery (e.g., intra-thoracic, intra-abdominal or&#xD;
                  intra-pelvic) within 4 weeks prior to starting treatment or has not recovered&#xD;
                  from side effects of such procedure. Video-assisted thoracic surgery (VATS) and&#xD;
                  mediastinoscopy will not be counted as major surgery and patients can receive&#xD;
                  treatment ≥1 week after these procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Receiving enzyme-inducing anticonvulsives that cannot be discontinued at least 1&#xD;
                  week before first dose of treatment, and for the duration of the treatment.&#xD;
                  Patients on non-enzyme-inducing anticonvulsants are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Sexually active males unless they use a condom during intercourse while taking the&#xD;
             drug and for 3 months after the last dose of program drug. Patient should not father a&#xD;
             child in this period. A condom is required to be used also by vasectomized men in&#xD;
             order to prevent delivery of the drug via seminal fluid.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Women of child-bearing potential, defined as all women physiologically capable of&#xD;
             becoming pregnant, unless they are using highly effective methods of contraception&#xD;
             during dosing and for 3 months after stopping medication. Highly effective&#xD;
             contraception methods include:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total abstinence (no sexual relations), when this is in line with your preferred&#xD;
                  and usual lifestyle. Periodic abstinence like calendar, ovulation, symptothermal,&#xD;
                  postovulation methods, and withdrawal are not acceptable methods of&#xD;
                  contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Female sterilization, when you have been already surgically sterilized prior to&#xD;
                  the program by surgical removal of both ovaries (woman's reproductive system that&#xD;
                  stores and releases eggs for fertilization and produces female sex hormones),&#xD;
                  total hysterectomy (surgical removal of the uterus and cervix), or tubal ligation&#xD;
                  (getting your &quot;tubes tied&quot;) at least six weeks before taking program treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Your male partner has already been sterilized at least 6 months prior to&#xD;
                  screening with the appropriate documentation. The sterilized male partner should&#xD;
                  be your sole partner.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Use of oral, injected, or implanted hormonal methods of contraception or&#xD;
                  placement of an intrauterine device (IUD) or intrauterine system (IUS) or other&#xD;
                  forms of hormonal contraception that have comparable efficacy (failure rate &lt;1%),&#xD;
                  for example hormone vaginal ring or transdermal hormone contraception (in case of&#xD;
                  oral contraception you should have been using the same pill on a stable dose for&#xD;
                  a minimum of 3 months before taking program treatment).&#xD;
&#xD;
        In case of use of oral contraception, women should have been stable on the same pill for a&#xD;
        minimum of 3 months before taking study treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</last_name>
    <phone>1-888-669-6682</phone>
    <email>novartis.email@novartis.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</last_name>
    <phone>+41613241111</phone>
    <email>novartis.email@novartis.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>MAP</keyword>
  <keyword>Manage access program</keyword>
  <keyword>ceritinib</keyword>
  <keyword>ALK positive tumors</keyword>
  <keyword>LDK378</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ceritinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

