<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05100277</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1/2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05100277</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of Oncotype DX® on Treatment Recommendation and Its Economic Evaluation Under the Brazilian Society Perspective</brief_title>
  <official_title>Impact of Oncotype DX® on Treatment Recommendation of for Early-stage Hormone Receptor-positive Breast Cancer and Its Economic Evaluation Under the Brazilian Society Perspective</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital Perola Byington</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Fleury Laboratory</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital Perola Byington</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      155 Pérola Byington Hospital patients presenting early stage luminal BC were submitted to&#xD;
      Oncotype Dx® evaluation. Changes in treatment recommendations and costs were obtained from&#xD;
      Pérola Byington Hospital. Oncotype DX® incorporation in the Brazilian Public Health System&#xD;
      should be considered, as it results in high clinical impact for patient and high economic&#xD;
      impact for health system, being a tool that safely and accurately delimits the subgroup of&#xD;
      patients who really need AC.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background: It is known that there is significant over administration (and under&#xD;
      administration) of adjuvant chemotherapy (AC) when standard clinical parameters (SCP) are&#xD;
      used for patients diagnosed with early stage RE+ breast cancer (BC). Although absolute&#xD;
      clinical benefit of AC may be modest, its toxicity and economic burden is highly significant;&#xD;
      therefore, selecting appropriate patients for AC remains an important issue. Oncotype DX®&#xD;
      identifies high-risk patients who are likely to benefit from AC, which otherwise might not be&#xD;
      identified through SCP and low-risk patients who will not benefit from AC, thus avoiding&#xD;
      toxicities and inherent risks. This study aimed to evaluate the impact of the Oncotype DX®&#xD;
      test on treatment decisions in N0 and N1 early-stage breast cancer patients at a Public&#xD;
      Brazilian hospital and to estimate the incremental cost-effectiveness ratio (ICER) and budget&#xD;
      impact (BI) of incorporating Oncotype DX® under the perspective of the Brazilian Society.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Changes in treatment recommendations and costs will be obtained from Pérola Byington&#xD;
      Hospital. Additional data will be obtained from literature. Medical costs (test, chemotherapy&#xD;
      and adverse events), productivity loss, transportation and employment leave will be&#xD;
      considered.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 8, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 4, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 4, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>5 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of patients whose choice of treatment is changed as a result of Oncotype Test Low risk</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes based on initial clinical measures</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Economic evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">155</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Adjuvant Treatment</condition>
  <condition>Cost-effectiveness Ratio</condition>
  <condition>Oncotype DX</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single arm</arm_group_label>
    <description>All patients will have the test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Genetic</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Oncotype DX® Assay</intervention_name>
    <description>After surgery, tumoral tissue was used to perform Oncotype Dx®. Patients were evaluated and therapy recommendations - adjuvant chemotherapy (CT) plus hormone therapy (HT) or HT alone - were captured before and after revealing the test results. Results from TAILORx10 were used to guide decisions for or against CT for individual patients. Changes in treatment recommendations were obtained.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cost</intervention_name>
    <description>Changes in treatment costs were estimated from Pérola Byington Hospital.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patient with early stage breast cancer, positive ER and negative HER2 with negative lymph&#xD;
        node or positive lymph node.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Women ≥ 18 years Patient with early stage breast cancer, positive ER and negative HER2 with&#xD;
        negative lymph node or positive lymph node.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The patient has an application completed and submitted to Genomic Health, Inc. to order the&#xD;
        Oncotype DX Breast Cancer Test as part of the routine treatment he receives.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The patient provides written and signed informed consent. Patients need to have clinical&#xD;
        data available in medical and pathological reports for entry into the electronic data&#xD;
        capture system. At a minimum, the following data must be available for inclusion in the&#xD;
        patient's repository: patient's age, tumor size, tumor grade, histology, lymph node stage,&#xD;
        RE and PR by IHC, and HER2 by IHC and / or FISH.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients who have been newly diagnosed with more than one operable primary breast tumor;&#xD;
        Patients who have multifocal or multicentric tumors; Patients who have had metastatic&#xD;
        breast cancer; Patients who have a previous history of breast cancer; Patients who have an&#xD;
        invasive tumor &lt;2 mm when evaluated by the local pathologist; Patients who have poor&#xD;
        performance status (ECOG 2, 3, 4) and / or other clinical factors that would make the&#xD;
        patient a non-viable candidate for adjuvant chemotherapy; Patients who received hormonal or&#xD;
        chemotherapy treatment before having an Oncotype DX Breast Cancer Test performed; Patients&#xD;
        with a current medical condition, such as psychiatric illness, that would interfere with&#xD;
        their ability to consent and participate in this questionnaire&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Andre Mattar</name>
      <address>
        <city>São Paulo</city>
        <state>SP</state>
        <zip>04112080</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hospital Perola Byington</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Andre Mattar</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PI</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All data will be available upon request</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The data will be available when the paper is published upon request</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>described above</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

