<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05102578</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021UA003E-281537</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05102578</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Understanding Persistent Pain Using a Decision Aid Tool in a Scottish Pharmacy Setting.</brief_title>
  <acronym>UPP</acronym>
  <official_title>Understanding Persistent Pain: A Feasibility Study for the Use of a Digital Decision Aid Tool for Persistent Pain in a Pharmacy Setting</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Aberdeen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Pharmacy Research UK</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Aberdeen</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Persistent pain describes long term pain that is present nearly every day. It is common and&#xD;
      affects millions of people in the United Kingdom. The investigators want to explore people's&#xD;
      experience of living with persistent pain and investigate how pharmacists can help people&#xD;
      manage their pain. For this, the investigators will be testing a digital Decision Aid Tool&#xD;
      (DAT) that includes a pain and lifestyle assessment as part of a pain consultation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study design is a randomised feasibility study. Patient participants will take part in a&#xD;
      pain consultation with a pharmacist to discuss pain management in a shared decision making&#xD;
      (SDM) process. The unit of randomisation will be the patient participant. Thus, pharmacists&#xD;
      will randomise patients to one of two groups: an intervention group who will receive a&#xD;
      digital DAT for self-completion as part of the consultation and a control group which not use&#xD;
      the digital DAT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      How the study will be implemented will be dependent on research restrictions due to the&#xD;
      COVID-19 pandemic. If restrictions on research are in place, all study activities will be&#xD;
      done remotely. If research restrictions are lifted the investigators will offer both remote&#xD;
      and in person activities, depending on the participants preference.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Registered pharmacists in National Health Service (NHS) Grampian (see Section 5.1.) will be&#xD;
      invited to take part in the study. As part of the assessment of feasibility for a future&#xD;
      randomised control trial (RCT), a mixture of community and General Practitioner (GP)-surgery&#xD;
      based pharmacists will be recruited. Recruited pharmacists will identify and invite patients&#xD;
      living with persistent pain to a pain consultation. Pharmacists and patients will discuss&#xD;
      current lifestyle and pain history, after which the pharmacist will recommend pain management&#xD;
      plans that follow a person centred care (PCC) approach. Patients in the intervention group&#xD;
      will receive the digital DAT - named UPP (Understanding Persistent Pain) - for&#xD;
      self-completion with the help of the pharmacist. The DAT will generate a personalised report&#xD;
      on the patient's preferences that can be used to discuss different PCC management plans.&#xD;
      Management plans will be based on strategies routinely available in clinical practice4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Heterogeneity in pharmacist-led pain consultations means that consultations are likely to&#xD;
      differ across pharmacists. This study will allow the researchers to characterise different&#xD;
      types of pharmacist-led pain consultations for a future larger study. As such, having a&#xD;
      standardised control consultation falls beyond the scope of this feasibility study.&#xD;
      Similarly, heterogeneity in current practice will cause agreed plans to differ across&#xD;
      pharmacists and patients. These will also depend on the prescribing qualifications of the&#xD;
      pharmacist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patient's GP will be informed of the person's participation and, in some cases, the&#xD;
      recommendations/findings of the consultation. Where a prescription only medicine is deemed&#xD;
      beneficial, pharmacists who are qualified independent prescribers will recommend this&#xD;
      directly. Pharmacists without this qualification will, with the agreement of the patient,&#xD;
      suggest to patients that they should book an appointment with the GP and send a referral&#xD;
      letter to the GP with the recommendation for the prescription only medicine. Follow up&#xD;
      consultations with the pharmacist will be arranged according to each pharmacist's current&#xD;
      practice.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain assessed using the Chronic Pain Grade</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Self-administered questionnaire that records subscale scores for pain intensity and disability are combined to calculate a chronic pain grade that enables classification of chronic pain patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>EuroQol's 5D-5L</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Self-administered questionnaire that records state and quality of life using EuroQol's five dimensions and 5 levels.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Personal Well-being Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Self-administered questionnaire that records personal wellbeing using the UK's Office of National Statistics (ONS) Measuring Subjective Well-being for Public Policy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Usual care. Consultation with pharmacist with no decision aid tool.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Digital Decision Aid Tool</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Consultation with pharmacist using the digital decision aid tool.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Digital Decision Aid Tool</intervention_name>
    <description>The digital DAT will ask people about their current pain levels, medications and physical activity. Following this, it will include a Discrete Choice Experiment (DCE)-like component with a series of questions that ask users to choose between different pain management packages. Similar to a standard DCE, packages (or plans) are described by attributes and levels, which include broad categories of guideline-based pain management strategies routinely available in clinical practice. The descriptors used for the attributes and levels were informed by a previous qualitative research study and based on therapeutic options that are helpful and important to people with persistent pain .</description>
    <arm_group_label>Digital Decision Aid Tool</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Above 18 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suffer from non-malignant persistent pain (defined as pain lasting for more than three&#xD;
             months).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Managed entirely within a primary care setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not fluent in the English language.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have concomitant severe mental health problems or terminal illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suffer from pain caused by cancer or other malignancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not able to give informed consent (e.g. because of mental state)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Takes part in another research study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Luis E Loria-Rebolledo, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+4401224437199</phone>
    <email>luis.loria@abdn.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NHS Grampian</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aberdeen</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Any data shared with other researchers will be anonymised.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

