<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05104450</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IIR 20-240</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>I01HX003319</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05104450</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pragmatic Obstructive Sleep Apnea Weight Loss Trial Assessing Effectiveness and Reach</brief_title>
  <acronym>POWER</acronym>
  <official_title>Pragmatic Obstructive Sleep Apnea Weight Loss Trial Assessing Effectiveness and Reach (POWER)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Prevalent obesity related conditions like obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) represent an&#xD;
      important opportunity to improve population health. OSA reduces quality of life and is&#xD;
      associated with greater risk for cardiovascular disease. Although obesity is the single&#xD;
      greatest reversible risk factor for OSA, patients with OSA and obesity rarely receive weight&#xD;
      loss care to reverse OSA and other serious comorbidities. Efficacy trials reinforce that time&#xD;
      and resource intensive lifestyle-based weight loss programs improve weight and physiologic&#xD;
      measures of OSA severity (apnea hypopnea index, AHI). However, there are barriers to&#xD;
      translating these findings into meaningful gains for population health. To meet these&#xD;
      challenges, the investigators propose a pragmatic trial of proactively offering a remote&#xD;
      video-based and self-directed lifestyle-based weight loss intervention with remote coaching&#xD;
      to patients with OSA. The investigators primary aim is to test the effectiveness of a&#xD;
      proactively delivered and pragmatic lifestyle intervention to improve co-primary endpoints of&#xD;
      sleep-related quality of life and weight among patients with OSA and obesity. Secondarily,&#xD;
      the investigators will compare additional outcomes between groups: cardiovascular risk&#xD;
      scores, sleep symptoms, and AHI. Finally, the investigators will also conduct an&#xD;
      implementation process evaluation informed by the RE-AIM framework to identify barriers and&#xD;
      facilitators to widespread implementation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will identify patients with OSA and obesity nationwide (n=696) in VA using&#xD;
      data from the VA's Corporate Data Warehouse (CDW), and the investigators will contact&#xD;
      potentially eligible patients. After confirming eligibility and consent, the investigators&#xD;
      will randomly assign subjects to receive the study's lifestyle intervention or usual care&#xD;
      alone. The study uses CDW to assess weight change, supplemented by self-report when&#xD;
      necessary. Subjects will complete questionnaires at baseline at 3, 12 and 24 months after&#xD;
      randomization. The lifestyle intervention in POWER focuses on gradual lifestyle behavior&#xD;
      change aimed at improving eating habits and increasing physical activity. It encourages&#xD;
      participants to gradually achieve and maintain a 5-10% loss of baseline body weight and at&#xD;
      least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity physical activity, such as brisk walking, each week.&#xD;
      The lifestyle intervention program consists of watching one video, completing corresponding&#xD;
      written self-guided learning materials, and tracking food intake and physical activity each&#xD;
      week for the first 12 weeks, then working through 10 additional written handouts and&#xD;
      continued food and activity tracking for the next nine months. Intervention participants will&#xD;
      have access to a lifestyle coach as desired for the full 12-month intervention period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Objective(s) and Hypotheses:&#xD;
&#xD;
           The investigators primary aim is to test the effectiveness of a proactively delivered&#xD;
           and pragmatic weight loss intervention to improve co-primary endpoints of sleep-related&#xD;
           quality of life and weight among Veterans with obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) and&#xD;
           obesity.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Secondarily, the investigators will compare additional outcomes between groups:&#xD;
           cardiovascular risk scores, sleep symptoms, and AHI. The investigators will also conduct&#xD;
           an implementation process evaluation informed by the RE-AIM framework to identify&#xD;
           predictors and determinants of population uptake of the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Research Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
           The investigators plan a hybrid type 1 pragmatic randomized controlled trial assessing&#xD;
           effectiveness and an implementation process evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Methodology The investigators will proactively identify patients with OSA and obesity&#xD;
           nationwide in VA using data from the CDW (n=696), randomizing patients 1:1 to usual care&#xD;
           plus the lifestyle-based weight loss intervention or usual care alone. The investigators&#xD;
           will collect primary outcomes at 12 months, but will also collect outcomes at 3 and 24&#xD;
           months to assess trends over time.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Findings/Progress to Date:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This trial is yet to begin.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The investigators will randomly assign participants to one of two groups.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change in sleep-related quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline to 12 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare change in Functional Outcomes of Sleep questionnaire (FOSQ) score between groups.&#xD;
The minimum value of FOSQ is 5, the maximum is 20, and a higher value indicates a better outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change in weight</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline to between 9 and 15 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare weights between intervention and control using clinic weights from VA medical record or, if missing, substitute with self-reported weights</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>cardiovascular risk scores</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline to 12 and 24 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare cardiovascular risk scores between intervention and control using the non-laboratory Framingham algorithm. The minimum value in this risk score is -2, the maximum is 32, and a higher value indicates greater risk of cardiovascular disease (worse outcome).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS - Sleep Disturbance Survey change</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline to 3, 12, and 24 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare sleep-related disturbance between intervention and control using the Patient Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) - Sleep Disturbance Survey.&#xD;
The minimum value for PROMIS Sleep Disturbance is a T-score of 28.9, the maximum is a T-score of 76.5, and a greater value indicates greater sleep disturbance (worse outcome).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS - Sleep Related Impairment Survey change</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline to 3, 12, and 24 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare sleep-related disturbance between intervention and control using the Patient Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) -Sleep Related Impairment Survey.&#xD;
The minimum value for PROMIS Sleep Related Impairment is a T-score of 30.0, the maximum is a T-score of 80.1, and a greater value indicates greater sleep related impairment (worse outcome).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>blood pressure from VA medical record</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline to 12 and 24 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare both systolic and diastolic blood pressure values between intervention and control.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>treatment usage per day</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline to 3, 12, and 24 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare daily OSA treatment usage between groups using self-report. Among those using PAP, the investigators will compare objective daily PAP usage between groups using remote downloads of PAP use.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>change in apnea hypopnea index</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline to 12 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will conduct home sleep apnea tests among a subset of patients in each group to compare change in apnea hypopnea index (a physiologic measure of OSA severity) between groups. The apnea hypopnea index measures the number of times per hour of sleep in which an individual stops breathing (apnea) or nearly stops breathing (hypopnea). We will measure apneas and hypopneas using the most recent definitions of the American Academy of Sleep Medicine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>short-term change in self-reported weight</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline to 3 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare short-term change in self-reported weight between intervention and control groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>longer-term change in weight</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline to between 15 and 27 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare longer-term change in weight between intervention and control using clinic weights from VA medical record or, if missing, substitute with self-report weights.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>short-term change in sleep-related quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline to 3 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare short-term change in Functional Outcomes of Sleep questionnaire (FOSQ) between groups. The minimum value of FOSQ is 5, the maximum is 20, and a higher value indicates a better outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>longer-term change in sleep-related quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline to 24 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare longer-term change in Functional Outcomes of Sleep questionnaire (FOSQ) between groups. The minimum value of FOSQ is 5, the maximum is 20, and a higher value indicates a better outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">696</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <condition>Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>lifestyle intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The investigators will provide participants with the behavioral lifestyle intervention in addition to usual care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>usual care control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will continue with usual care without the lifestyle intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>lifestyle intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Intervention Arm: Usual Care plus a lifestyle behavior change intervention aimed at improving eating habits and increasing physical activity. The lifestyle behavior change intervention encourages participants to gradually achieve and maintain a 5-10% loss of baseline body weight and at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity physical activity, such as brisk walking, each week. The lifestyle intervention program consists of watching one video, completing corresponding written self-guided learning materials, and tracking food intake and physical activity each week for the first 12 weeks, then working through 10 additional written handouts and continued food and activity tracking for the next nine months. Intervention participants will have access to a lifestyle coach as desired for the full 12-month intervention period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>lifestyle intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) confirmed by sleep study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent body mass index between 30.0-44.9 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to DVD player, computer, and/or internet&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to participate fully in all study protocol/procedures including informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to speak, read, or understand English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent weight loss interventions including use of prescription weight-loss&#xD;
             medications, participation in group or individual weight loss programs provided by&#xD;
             trained personnel, bariatric surgery (or plans for during the study period)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected weight loss because of alternate explanations such as from illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High variability in weight due to fluctuations in volume status (e.g. ascites - liver&#xD;
             disease, chronic heart failure)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Safety and/or adherence concerns due to severe physical or mental health issues, or&#xD;
             life expectancy &lt;24 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant, lactating, or planning to become pregnant during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in other intervention studies&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lucas M Donovan, MD MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>VA Puget Sound Health Care System Seattle Division, Seattle, WA</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jennifer McDowell</last_name>
    <phone>(206) 277-6223</phone>
    <email>Jennifer.McDowell@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Margaret P Collins, PhD MS</last_name>
    <phone>(206) 764-2085</phone>
    <email>margaret.collins@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA Puget Sound Health Care System Seattle Division, Seattle, WA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98108</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Peter J Storm, MHA FACHE</last_name>
      <phone>206-764-2520</phone>
      <email>Peter.Storm@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Gage C Doehlert</last_name>
      <phone>(206) 277-1471</phone>
      <email>Gage.Doehlert@va.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lucas M Donovan, MD MS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>weight loss</keyword>
  <keyword>lifestyle</keyword>
  <keyword>diet</keyword>
  <keyword>exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>randomized controlled trial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

