<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05102526</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Tel-Hai</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05102526</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Increasing the Impact of a School Prevention Program Among Young Adolescents by Adding a Teacher Component</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Impact of a School-based Program on the Psychological Health of Young Adolescents: The Facilitator Role of a Teacher Component and Content Delivered in the School</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tel Hai College</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tel Hai College</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A randomized clinical trial in clusters, including the development and implementation of an&#xD;
      intervention program among young adolescents and their teachers. The research hypothesis is&#xD;
      that the intervention program will yield improvement in adolescents whose parents&#xD;
      participated in the program, compared with adolescents whose teachers were not involved in&#xD;
      the intervention. The results will be measured using the research questionnaire, which&#xD;
      participants will complete before, after and three months after the end of the program. The&#xD;
      questionnaire will include approved questionnaires with good psychometric properties. In&#xD;
      addition, there will be a quality interview. The study protocol was approved by the Tel Hai&#xD;
      College Institutional Audit Committee. Parents of all participants in the intervention and&#xD;
      control group as well as the teachers involved in the program received information about the&#xD;
      program and research and were asked to give informed consent.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Early adolescence (10-13 years) is characterized by hormonal changes and accelerated&#xD;
      physiological growth. Significant risk factors for the physical and mental health of children&#xD;
      and adolescents include, among other things, reduced physical activity, low self-esteem and&#xD;
      self-esteem.&#xD;
&#xD;
      &quot;Mili - a unique shield for daily resilience&quot; is a preventive intervention program. The main&#xD;
      goal of the program is to increase the self-care behaviors and self esteem of adolescents and&#xD;
      prevent negative physical self-image, as well as to develop media literacy. In this study,&#xD;
      researchers will focus on a school-based program designed for ages 10-12, grades 5-6, with a&#xD;
      primary goal to develop self-care, media literacy, self-esteem, and positive body image. To&#xD;
      increase the impact of the &quot;Young Mili&quot; program on adolescents, the researchers developed a&#xD;
      teacher component as an adjunct to the school-based intervention, usually facilitated only by&#xD;
      college students. The study will first evaluate the impact of teachers on the program, and&#xD;
      then evaluate the difference between adolescent outcomes from the program with or without&#xD;
      this supplement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results will be measured using the research questionnaire, to be completed by the&#xD;
      participants (both teachers and adolescents) before, after, and three months after the end of&#xD;
      the program. The questionnaire will include validated scales with good psychometric&#xD;
      properties. In addition, qualitative interviews will be conducted among teachers. The study&#xD;
      protocol was approved by the Tel Hai College Institutional Audit Committee. Parents of all&#xD;
      participants, in the intervention and the control group, as well as teachers involved in the&#xD;
      program, were given information about the program and the research and were asked to provide&#xD;
      informed consent.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in the Sociocultural Attitudes towards Appearance Questionnaire-4, Affects by Media subscale.</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured three times over six months: at baseline, at program termination (immediately after last session), and three months after the completion of the program, measuring a change in scores</time_frame>
    <description>The Sociocultural Attitudes Towards Appearance Questionnaire (Schaefer et al., 2015). The investigators included the Media subscale, including 4 items. Items are rated on a 5-point scale: (1) always, (2) often, (3) sometimes, (4) rarely, (5) never. The total score is based on computing the average. A higher score indicates higher pressure from the media to change one's look.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Rosenberg Self Esteem Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured three times over six months: at baseline, at program termination (immediately after last session), and three months after the completion of the program, measuring a change in scores</time_frame>
    <description>Rosenberg Self Esteem Scale (Rosenberg, 1965)- 10 items. Scoring involves a method of combined ratings. Low self-esteem responses are &quot;disagree&quot; or &quot;strongly disagree&quot; on items 1, 3, 4, 7, 10, and &quot;strongly agree&quot; or &quot;agree&quot; on items 2, 5, 6, 8, 9. Two or three out of three correct responses to items 3, 7, and 9 are scored as one item. One or two out of two correct responses for items 4 and 5 are considered as a single item; items 1,8, and 10 are scored as individual items; and combined correct responses (one or two out of two) to items 2 and 6 are considered to be a single item.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Body Esteem Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured three times over six months: at baseline, at program termination (immediately after last session), and three months after the completion of the program, measuring a change in scores</time_frame>
    <description>Body Esteem Scale- This questionnaire examines self-esteem of body and physical appearance and consists of 3 subscales: appearance (10 items), weight (8 items) and attribution 187 to others (5 items). Items are rated on a 5-point scale: (1) never, (2) rarely, (3) sometimes, (4) 188 often, and (5) always. A higher score indicates higher body-esteem (Mendelson, Mendelson, &amp; White, 2001)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Advertising Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured three times over six months: at baseline, at program termination (immediately after last session), and three months after the completion of the program, measuring a change in scores</time_frame>
    <description>The Advertising scale contains 1 item- Identification of strategies used by media. This question is reflected as a protective factor. It contains 8 different strategies which participants choose from: higher number of strategies identified indicate better media literacy. (Golan et al., 2013).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Self-Care behaviors</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured three times over six months: at baseline, at program termination (immediately after last session), and three months after the completion of the program, measuring a change in scores</time_frame>
    <description>Developed by Prof. Moria Golan and assessed in previous research. Includes 14 items which are rated on a 4-point scale: (1) never, (2) rarely, (3) sometimes, (4) always. Items are summed, and higher scores indicate higher self-care behaviors. This questionnaire was designed to assess self care behaviors in adolescents.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in The Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale (CD-RISC)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured three times over six months: at baseline, at program termination (immediately after last session), and three months after the completion of the course, measuring a change in scores</time_frame>
    <description>The CD-RISC is based on Connor and Davidson's operational definition of resilience, which is the ability to &quot;thrive in the face of adversity.&quot; The scale includes 25 items, from 5 sub-scales:</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Primary Prevention</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>&quot;Young Millie&quot; prevention program, active teachers</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The &quot;Young Mili&quot; program will be delivered to teens ages 10-12, over 3 months. The program contains nine 90-minute weekly sessions focusing on media literacy, self-esteem, self-esteem and physical self-esteem. Teachers will also participate by delivering planned activities to their students in addition to each week's theme, in parallel with an externally delivered program. All participants will complete a self-report questionnaire at the beginning of the study, after the end of the program and three months after the end of the program.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>&quot;Young Mili&quot; prevention program, passive teachers</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The &quot;Young Mili&quot; program will be delivered to teens ages 10-12, over 3 months. The program contains nine 90-minute weekly sessions focusing on media literacy, self-esteem, self-esteem and body image. Teachers will not participate in the program, they will be present in class only during the program on transfer abroad. All participants will complete a self-report questionnaire at the beginning of the study, after the end of the program and three months after the end of the program.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Experimental: &quot;Young Millie&quot; prevention program, active teachers</intervention_name>
    <description>Prevention program: &quot;Young Mili&quot;, in collaboration with the teacher</description>
    <arm_group_label>&quot;Young Millie&quot; prevention program, active teachers</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prevention program: &quot;Young Mili&quot;, non active teachers</intervention_name>
    <description>Prevention program: &quot;Young Mili&quot;, without the participation of the teacher</description>
    <arm_group_label>&quot;Young Mili&quot; prevention program, passive teachers</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Teachers of elementary school classes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  10-12-year-old students of participating teachers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who filled out the questionnaires before and after the program&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants whose parents signed a letter of informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who didn't complete the questionnaires at baseline or at least twice.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tel Hai College</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kiryat Shmona</city>
        <state>Upper Galilee</state>
        <zip>1220800</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>prevention-program</keyword>
  <keyword>Physical assessment</keyword>
  <keyword>self-esteem</keyword>
  <keyword>self-care</keyword>
  <keyword>Teachers</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

