<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05050201</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GN21MH015</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05050201</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Implementation of Digital CBT for Insomnia in First Episode Psychosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Implementation of a Digital Cognitive Behavioural Therapy Intervention for Insomnia in First Episode Psychosis in the Context of Covid19: A Mixed Methods Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Glasgow</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Big Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study uses mixed methods to investigate the implementation of digital cognitive&#xD;
      behavioural therapy for insomnia (Sleepio) in a first episode of psychosis service (FEP).&#xD;
      Interviews will be conducted with keyworker clinicians and service users to consider their&#xD;
      expectations for digital sleep intervention. The rates of recruitment into the study,&#xD;
      eligibility, completion of baseline measures, completion of the intervention sessions,&#xD;
      attrition from the intervention and completion of follow up measures will be recorded.&#xD;
      Interviews will be conducted with keyworker clinicians and service users to consider their&#xD;
      experiences of digital sleep intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome will be a logic model describing factors acting upon the implementation&#xD;
      of Sleepio in this population. The investigators will provide signal data in relation to&#xD;
      changes in insomnia severity, psychosis symptomatology, and general mental health.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      First episode psychosis (FEP) services present a unique opportunity to effect change in&#xD;
      outcomes in those affected by experiences of psychosis. Sleep disorder, particularly&#xD;
      insomnia, is common in those affected by psychosis, including those experiencing a first&#xD;
      episode and are associated with increased symptomatology. Mood and worry mediate the&#xD;
      relationship between sleep and psychosis symptomatology and research suggests that improving&#xD;
      sleep in this population can improve mental health symptomatology and longer term outcomes.&#xD;
      Cognitive Behavioural Therapy is effective in treating insomnia (CBT-I). Pilot research&#xD;
      suggests that insomnia is a tractable clinical target in psychosis. Furthermore, there is an&#xD;
      appetite for therapeutic interventions for sleep in this population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      &quot;Sleepio&quot; is an online Cognitive Behavioural Therapy for Insomnia (CBT-I) programme.&#xD;
      Sleepio's components are those common to CBT-I interventions: i) Psychoeducation on sleep&#xD;
      hygiene and processes; ii) cognitive components including restructuring, mindfulness,&#xD;
      positive imagery, paradoxical intention training (trying to stay awake), and resolving&#xD;
      thoughts about one's day; and iii) behavioural components including sleep restriction,&#xD;
      stimulus control, and relaxation techniques. Sleepio is composed of six 20-minute sessions&#xD;
      presented by an animated therapist (&quot;the Professor&quot;), which are unlocked weekly. Participants&#xD;
      complete an initial assessment (please see 'Sleepio Onboarding Questions') and chose a&#xD;
      treatment goal, which drives initial personalisation of the application. Participants book&#xD;
      digital 'appointments' with the Professor and receive prompts to complete these 6 sessions,&#xD;
      to enter sleep data and to complete the Sleep Condition Indicator. The Sleepio algorithm&#xD;
      tailors ongoing intervention based on this sleep data and other data about participants'&#xD;
      physical and mental health. Sleepio also provides access to online psychoeducation and a&#xD;
      clinician-moderated user forum. This intervention has been shown to be as effective as 1-1&#xD;
      CBT-I in the general population. Sleepio has been used in mental health populations but has&#xD;
      not yet been tested in people experiencing a first episode of psychosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study aims to use mixed methods to determine how digital CBT-I can be implemented in&#xD;
      first episode psychosis services. These data will be integrated to build a logic model, based&#xD;
      on the Medical Research Council (MRC) complex interventions framework.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Keyworkers in Esteem FEP services will be approached to identify service users affected by&#xD;
      sleep difficulties that may benefit from Sleepio. Service user participants will be recruited&#xD;
      through their treatment as usual (TAU) with their Esteem keyworker (sleep monitoring is part&#xD;
      of this). Where service users report sleep difficulties, keyworkers will offer an information&#xD;
      leaflet about the study and referral into the research study or contact details for&#xD;
      researchers (study email address). Keyworkers will record that service users have agreed to&#xD;
      keyworkers providing their details to researchers and to being contacted by the researchers&#xD;
      in their casefile.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Those service users who wish to find out more about the study and meet eligibility criteria&#xD;
      will be sent an easy-read Participant Information Sheet and Consent Form. They will be given&#xD;
      the opportunity to ask questions and will be encouraged to speak to others about their&#xD;
      potential participation (such as their keyworker). It will be made clear that in consenting&#xD;
      to participate they are consenting to participate in sleep assessment, complete&#xD;
      symptomatology measures pre- and post-intervention and use the Sleepio intervention. It will&#xD;
      be made clear that participation does not affect their TAU. They will provide written consent&#xD;
      if they wish to participate. Consenting service user study participants will receive access&#xD;
      to Sleepio. They will register for the intervention with a researcher during the baseline&#xD;
      symptomology measures assessment session.&#xD;
&#xD;
      They will be given the option of additionally participating in semi-structured interviews&#xD;
      prior to and after using the intervention, to talk about their expectations and experiences&#xD;
      of Sleepio. Service user participants will not be randomized to treatment. All service user&#xD;
      participants will be provided with access to Sleepio. Research will focus on developing a&#xD;
      model for the implementation of this intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Keyworkers will be introduced to and supported in their role in referring service users to&#xD;
      the study and monitoring use of Sleepio through presentations, psychosocial supervision, and&#xD;
      reflection sessions. Keyworkers will be provided with an easy read information sheet which&#xD;
      clarifies their role as clinicians (attending a session to reflect on their caseload and&#xD;
      service user suitability for the study and providing suitable service users with information&#xD;
      about the study) and potentially as research participants (in semi-structured interviews) via&#xD;
      email and letter. They will be given the opportunity to ask questions and will be encouraged&#xD;
      to speak to others about their potential interview participation (such as their colleagues).&#xD;
      They will provide written consent if they wish to participate in semi-structured interviews,&#xD;
      to talk about their expectations and experiences of Sleepio use in Esteem.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcomes comprise implementation data and qualitative data concerning the&#xD;
      perspectives of clinicians and service users, which inform the resulting logic model.&#xD;
      Secondary outcome data comprises insomnia severity (Insomnia Severity Index), mental health&#xD;
      symptomatology (Depression Anxiety and Stress Scales; The Revised Green et al., Paranoid&#xD;
      Thoughts Scale (R-GPTS); Specific Psychotic Experiences Questionnaire (SPEQ) - Hallucinations&#xD;
      Subscale) and worry about Covid19 (Fear of Covid19 Scale).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 20, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 20, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>All service users who would like to trial the Sleepio intervention will be able to do so.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participation is not masked - any service users who would like to participate may do so and their keyworker will be notified as a mandatory condition of consent</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Implementation data - rates of consenting</measure>
    <time_frame>Across study timeline (8 months), across 10 weeks for Sleepio specific measures</time_frame>
    <description>Rates of consenting and nonconsenting interested participants</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Implementation data - eligibility</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of eligible vs. ineligible participants and reasons for ineligibility</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Implementation data - completion of measures</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Participant completion of measures assessment appointments and measures (ISI measure of insomnia severity, DASS-21 measure of mental wellbeing, R-GPTS measure of paranoia, SPEQ measure of hallucination, and Fear of Covid19). This outcome records whether or not these were completed by participants, whereas secondary outcomes 6-10 examine participant scores on these measures.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Implementation data - completion of intervention sessions</measure>
    <time_frame>Across 10 weeks per participant</time_frame>
    <description>Measures attrition from intervention by recording how many sessions of intervention were completed by participant.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Qualitative data</measure>
    <time_frame>Across study timeline (8 months), across 12 weeks for service users (pre and post intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>Service user and clinician expectations and experiences of digital CBT-I intervention</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insomnia severity</measure>
    <time_frame>10 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>As measured by the Insomnia Severity Index (ISI). Possible scores range from 0 to 28 and higher scores indicate more severe insomnia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mental Wellbeing</measure>
    <time_frame>10 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>As measured by the Depression, Anxiety and Stress Scales (DASS-21). Possible scores range from 0 to 126 and higher scores indicate more psychological distress. The maximum score on each subscale (depression, anxiety, stress) is 42.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Paranoia symptomatology</measure>
    <time_frame>10 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>As measured by the Revised Green et al., Paranoid Thoughts Scale (R-GPTS). Possible scores range from 0 to 72 and higher scores indicate more severe paranoia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hallucination symptomatology</measure>
    <time_frame>10 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>As measured by the Specific Psychotic Experiences Questionnaire (SPEQ) - Hallucinations subscale. Possible scores range from 0 to 45 and higher scores indicate more severe hallucinatory experience.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety regarding Covid19</measure>
    <time_frame>10 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>As measured by the Fear of Covid19 Scale. Possible scores range from 7 to 35 and higher scores indicate more fear of Covid19.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">22</enrollment>
  <condition>Insomnia</condition>
  <condition>Psychosis</condition>
  <condition>First Episode Psychosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sleepio Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants using the Sleepio application - access for 6 sessions, over 10 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sleepio</intervention_name>
    <description>Digital CBT application for insomnia</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sleepio Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Service users under the care of Esteem First Episode Psychosis Service in NHS GGC&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Potentially affected by Insomnia Disorder (defined by Sleep Condition Indicator-02&#xD;
             score ≤2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who have access to a device they can use Sleepio on (a computer device with Safari or&#xD;
             Google Chrome browser, or an iPhone device).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate to severe learning disability&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute Psychosis (recent crisis contact or hospitalisation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Incapacity to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insufficient English to access intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Organic impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No access to a device which can be used for Sleepio intervention.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andrew Gumley</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde; University of Glasgow</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Elaine O'Neill - Senior Research Administrator</last_name>
    <phone>0141 314 4011</phone>
    <email>Elaine.O'Neill2@ggc.scot.nhs.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Esteem North, NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde</name>
      <address>
        <city>Glasgow</city>
        <zip>G213UW</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Fiona Robb</last_name>
      <phone>0141 531 3207</phone>
      <email>Fiona.Robb2@ggc.scot.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mairi Spanswick, DClinPsy</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Fiona Robb, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Louise Beattie, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Esteem South and Clyde, NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde</name>
      <address>
        <city>Glasgow</city>
        <zip>G53 7TU</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Fiona Robb</last_name>
      <phone>01415313207</phone>
      <email>Fiona.Robb2@ggc.scot.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Fiona Robb, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mairi Spanswick, DClinPsy</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Louise Beattie, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 20, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>insomnia</keyword>
  <keyword>psychosis</keyword>
  <keyword>first episode psychosis</keyword>
  <keyword>digital CBT</keyword>
  <keyword>CBT-I</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>March 12, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/01/NCT05050201/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

