<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05051007</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MD-239-2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05051007</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Opioid-based Versus Lidocaine-based Induction of Anesthesia With Propofol in Elderly</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison of the Hemodynamic Effects of Opioid-based Versus Lidocaine-based Induction of Anesthesia With Propofol in Elderly: A Randomized Controlled Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kasr El Aini Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kasr El Aini Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Advances in the medical service and public health increased longevity; hence, more elderly&#xD;
      patients (&gt;65 years) are encountered by the anesthetists for variety of surgical&#xD;
      interventions. Even with the absence of comorbidity, older patients represent a challenge to&#xD;
      the anesthetist in comparison to the younger patients due to their limited physiologic&#xD;
      reserve and their aberrant response to the varies perioperative medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intraoperative hypotension increases the risk of postoperative kidney injury, myocardial&#xD;
      injury, cerebral ischemia, and perioperative mortality. Postinduction hypotension is mainly&#xD;
      caused by anesthetic drugs. Hence, developing a technique for induction of anesthesia that&#xD;
      provide adequate hypnosis with stable hemodynamics during surgery is critical, especially for&#xD;
      elderly patients. The elderly patients are at increased risk of post-induction hypotension&#xD;
      due to increased drug sensitivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Propofol is the most commonly used drug for anesthesia induction; however, its use is usually&#xD;
      associated with hypotension through vasodilation and direct myocardial depression. Opioid&#xD;
      drugs are usually added as analgesics to propofol during induction of anesthesia. However,&#xD;
      addition of opioids to propofol potentiates the risk of postinduction hypotension.&#xD;
      Furthermore, opioids increase the risk of postoperative delirium in elderly patients and this&#xD;
      risk is further increased with intraoperative hypotension.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lidocaine is a local anesthetic drug with multiple systemic uses. Lidocaine was proposed to&#xD;
      have an anesthetic sparing effect. Lidocaine was previously reported to enhance the hypnotic&#xD;
      effect of thiopentone, propofol, and midazolam during procedural sedation. Lidocaine/ketamine&#xD;
      combination showed favorable hemodynamic profile following rapid-sequence induction of&#xD;
      anesthesia in septic shock patients. Therefore, the use of lidocaine as an adjuvant to&#xD;
      propofol might provide a stable cardiovascular profile during induction of anesthesia in&#xD;
      elderly compared to fentanyl. To the best of our knowledge, there is no previous data&#xD;
      comparing the efficacy of adding lidocaine versus fentanyl to the induction of anesthesia&#xD;
      with propofol in elderly&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Upon arrival to the operating room, patient's airway will be assessed by trained anesthetist&#xD;
      (modified Mallampati test, mouth opening, jaw protrusion, thyromental height, neck extension,&#xD;
      dentation). If the patient is considered to be difficult and alternative device other than&#xD;
      endotracheal tube is considered, the patients will be excluded. Routine monitors&#xD;
      (electrocardiogram, pulse oximetry, and non-invasive blood pressure monitor) will be applied;&#xD;
      intravenous line will be secured, and routine pre-medications {ranitidine 50 mg,&#xD;
      dexamethasone 4 mg (0.5 mg/ml slow I.V injection)} will be administrated. Baseline&#xD;
      preoperative blood pressure will be recorded form the preoperative visit in the supine&#xD;
      position as average of 3 readings with difference less than 5 mmHg.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before induction of anesthesia for all study patients, Electrical cardiometry device (ICON;&#xD;
      Cardiotonic, Osypka; Berlin, Germany) will be applied to the patient through 4 electrodes at&#xD;
      the following sites: Below the left ear, Above the midpoint of the left clavicle, Left&#xD;
      mid-axillary line at level of the xiphoid process and 5 cm inferior to the third electrode.&#xD;
      Stroke volume variability (SVV) was measured while patient maintaining standard calm&#xD;
      breathing at 8 breath/minute for one-minute. Patients with SVV ≥ 13% will be considered fluid&#xD;
      responder and will receive a fluid bolus of 8 mL/kg Ringer acetate over 10 minutes. The fluid&#xD;
      bolus will be repeated until the SVV is less than 13%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be allocated into two groups: lidocaine group and fentanyl group. In all&#xD;
      patients, propofol will be injected slowly in 0.25 mg/kg increments every 20 s till clinical&#xD;
      loss of consciousness or reaching a maximum dose of 1-1.5 mg/kg in addition to the study&#xD;
      drug. Clinical loss of consciousness (defined as no response to auditory command and&#xD;
      disappearance of a patient's eyelash reflex) will be assessed by asking the patients&#xD;
      repeatedly every 10 s to open their eyes, when there is no response to auditory commands, the&#xD;
      eyelid reflex will be tested. After loss of consciousness, rocuronium (0.6 mg/kg) will be&#xD;
      administered, and anesthesia will be maintained by isoflurane (0.9-1% end-tidal).&#xD;
      Endotracheal tube will be inserted after 2-minutes of mask ventilation. Ringer lactate&#xD;
      solution will be infused at a rate of 2 mL/kg/hour. If the patient did not achieve adequate&#xD;
      hypnosis, an additional bolus of propofol (0.5 mg/kg) will be administered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any episode of hypotension (defined as mean arterial pressure ≤ 80% of the baseline reading&#xD;
      and/or mean arterial pressure &lt;60 mmHg) will be managed by 5 mcg norepinephrine (which can be&#xD;
      repeated if hypotension persisted for 2 minutes).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Severe post-induction hypotension defined as mean arterial pressure ≤60% of baseline, will be&#xD;
      managed by 5 mcg norepinephrine and the blood pressure will be measure at 1-min interval.&#xD;
      Norepinephrine bolus will be repeated if severe hypotension persisted for 1-minute.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If bradycardia occurred (defined as heart rate less than 45 bpm), it will be managed by IV&#xD;
      atropine bolus (0.5 mg).&#xD;
&#xD;
      After skin incision, hemodynamic and anesthetic management will be according to the attending&#xD;
      anesthetist discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Postoperative Confusion assessment method (CAM) assessment will be performed by trained&#xD;
      research member at and 24- and 48-hours after surgery. CAM will be assessed through a&#xD;
      four-step algorithm identifying the following: 1) acute onset of mental status changes or a&#xD;
      fluctuating course, 2) inattention, 3) disorganized thinking, 4) an altered level of&#xD;
      consciousness. Patients will be diagnosed to be delirious if both features {(1) and (2)} will&#xD;
      be present plus either feature (3) or (4)}&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>total norepinephrine dose</measure>
    <time_frame>1 minute after induction of anesthesia until 15 minutes after induction or surgical incision</time_frame>
    <description>mcg</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of post-induction hypotension</measure>
    <time_frame>1 minute after induction of anesthesia until 15 minutes after induction or surgical incision</time_frame>
    <description>mean arterial pressure ≤80% of baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of severe post-induction hypotension</measure>
    <time_frame>1 minute after induction of anesthesia until 15 minutes after induction or surgical incision</time_frame>
    <description>mean arterial pressure ≤60% of baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of hypertension</measure>
    <time_frame>1 minute after induction of anesthesia until 15 minutes after induction or surgical incision</time_frame>
    <description>mean arterial pressure 120% of baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>tachycardia</measure>
    <time_frame>1 minute after induction of anesthesia until 15 minutes after induction or surgical incision</time_frame>
    <description>heart rate &gt;120% of baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>loss consciousness time</measure>
    <time_frame>1 second after starting drug injection until one second after loss of consciousness</time_frame>
    <description>time to achieve no response to auditory command and disappearance of a patient's eyelash reflex</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>total propofol dose</measure>
    <time_frame>1 second after starting drug injection until one second after loss of consciousness</time_frame>
    <description>mg/kg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>intubation time</measure>
    <time_frame>1 second after insertion of direct laryngoscopy into the mouth till one second after its removal after tracheal intubation</time_frame>
    <description>second</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>incidence of postoperative delirium</measure>
    <time_frame>at 24 and 48 hour postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Confusion assessment method will be assessed through a four-step algorithm identifying the following: 1) acute onset of mental status changes or a fluctuating course, 2) inattention, 3) disorganized thinking, 4) an altered level of consciousness. Patients will be diagnosed to be delirious if both features {(1) and (2)} will be present plus either feature (3) or (4)}</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Postinduction Hypotension</condition>
  <condition>Elderly</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>fentanyl group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>lidocaine group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>fentanyl</intervention_name>
    <description>patients will receive 1 mcg/kg of fentanyl (the drug will be diluted to 10 mcg/mL)</description>
    <arm_group_label>fentanyl group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lidocaine IV</intervention_name>
    <description>patients will receive 1 mg/kg lidocaine (the drug will be diluted to10mg/mL)</description>
    <arm_group_label>lidocaine group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  American society of anesthesiologists I-III,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  scheduled for elective non-cardiac surgery under general anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with severe cardiac morbidities (impaired contractility with ejection&#xD;
             fraction &lt; 50%, heart block, arrhythmias, tight valvular lesions, metabolic equivalent&#xD;
             less than 4),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients on angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors and angiotensin receptor blockers&#xD;
             medications,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with uncontrolled hypertension,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with body mass index &lt;18 or &gt; 35 Kg/m2,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patient with allergy of any of the study drugs&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>ahmed hasanin</last_name>
    <phone>01095076954</phone>
    <email>ahmedmohamedhasanin@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kasr Alaini Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <zip>11562</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Kasr El Aini Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Maha Mostafa Ahmad, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypotension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fentanyl</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

