<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05057182</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BJC050</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05057182</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Third Dose of mRNA Vaccination to Boost COVID-19 Immunity</brief_title>
  <official_title>mRNA Vaccination to Boost Antibodies Against SARS-CoV-2 in Recipients of Inactivated Vaccines (the &quot;mBoost&quot; Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Hong Kong</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Hong Kong</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In 100 adults ≥30 years of age who have previously received two doses of an inactivated&#xD;
      COVID-19 vaccine at least 3 months earlier, we will administer a third dose with an mRNA&#xD;
      vaccine (BNT162b2, BioNTech). We will monitor reactogenicity and measure the immune response&#xD;
      to the third dose.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background: The accrual of population immunity to COVID-19 could allow life to return to pre-&#xD;
      pandemic normality. Immunity can be acquired through natural infections or, preferably, by&#xD;
      vaccination. An unprecedented global effort has succeeded in developing a number of COVID-19&#xD;
      vaccines. All vaccines against COVID-19 approved until now have originally been developed as&#xD;
      either a single dose or following a homologous two-dose regimen. Inactivated COVID-19&#xD;
      vaccines have shown inferior immunogenicity compared to mRNA vaccines but there are no&#xD;
      studies looking into the immunogenicity, reactogenicity and safety profile of mRNA&#xD;
      vaccination provided as a booster dose in individuals who have previously received two doses&#xD;
      of an inactivated COVID-19 vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims and Objectives: The aims of this study are: (1) to determine whether one dose of mRNA&#xD;
      vaccine can boost neutralizing antibodies against SARS-CoV-2 in individuals who have&#xD;
      previously received two doses of inactivated COVID-19 vaccines, and (2) to assess the&#xD;
      reactogenicity and safety of heterologous 3rd doses of vaccination. The specific primary&#xD;
      objective of our study is to assess the vaccine (humoral) immunogenicity, proxy by SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      serum neutralizing antibody titers, of a 3rd dose dose of mRNA vaccine (using BNT162b2,&#xD;
      Fosun/BioNTech) at 28 days after the booster dose in individuals who have previously received&#xD;
      two doses of any inactivated COVID-19 vaccines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: Randomized open label trial in adults aged 30 years of age or older (at&#xD;
      enrolment). The duration of participation for each participant will be 12 months from the&#xD;
      administration of the 3rd vaccine dose. We will investigate the immune response and&#xD;
      reactogenicity of one dose of BNT162b2 in individuals who previously received two doses of&#xD;
      any inactivated COVID-19 vaccines at least 3 months earlier. Participants will be enrolled&#xD;
      shortly before receiving the booster dose of BNT162b2 (day 0), with blood collection at days&#xD;
      0, 28, 182 and 365 days after enrolment for analysis of humoral immune responses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main outcomes: The primary outcome is the vaccine immunogenicity measured as SARS-CoV-2 serum&#xD;
      neutralizing antibodies in individuals who previously received two doses of any inactivated&#xD;
      COVID-19 vaccines, evaluated as the geometric mean titer (GMT) at 28 days after the 3rd dose.&#xD;
      The secondary outcomes include (1) a comparison of SARS- CoV-2 serum neutralizing antibodies&#xD;
      as the geometric mean fold rise from baseline to each post-vaccination timepoint (i.e. at&#xD;
      days 28, 182 and 365), and (2) descriptive analysis of the reactogenicity and safety profile&#xD;
      of the 3rd dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Target population: Adults aged 30 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
      Number of Subjects Planned: 100 participants to be recruited between September 2021 and&#xD;
      December 2021&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study duration: 12 months for each participant&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential implications: Our study will provide important evidence into the effects of using a&#xD;
      3rd dose of mRNA vaccines to boost the immune response in individuals that had previously&#xD;
      received two doses of inactivated vaccines. This information together with data collected on&#xD;
      reactogenicity and safety could inform COVID-19 vaccination policy locally and&#xD;
      internationally.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Titer of SARS-CoV-2 serum neutralizing antibodies</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days after vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome measure is the vaccine (humoral) immunogenicity at 28 days after the booster dose of BNT162b2 in individuals who have previously received two doses of any inactivated COVID-19 vaccines, measured as geometric mean titer (GMT) of SARS-CoV-2 serum neutralizing antibodies using plaque reduction neutralization test (PRNT).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Titer of SARS-CoV-2 serum neutralizing antibodies</measure>
    <time_frame>182 and 365 days after vaccination</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The geometric mean fold rise (GMFR) of SARS-CoV-2 serum neutralizing antibody titers from baseline to each post-vaccination timepoint measured.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28, 49, 182 and 365 after vaccination</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reactogenicity</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days after vaccination or until the last symptom disappears</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of solicited local and systemic adverse events after the booster dose of vaccination.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalizations from any cause</measure>
    <time_frame>365 days after vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of hospitalizations during the year after receipt of the booster dose.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID 19 Vaccine</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BNT162b2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>BNT162b2 mRNA vaccine (Cominarty®, BioNTech/Fosun Pharma), one dose (0.3mL after dilution) contains 30 micrograms of COVID-19 mRNA Vaccine embedded in lipid nanoparticles.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BNT162b2</intervention_name>
    <description>BNT162b2 mRNA vaccine (Cominarty®, BioNTech/Fosun Pharma), one dose (0.3mL after dilution) contains 30 micrograms of COVID-19 mRNA Vaccine embedded in lipid nanoparticles.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BNT162b2</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Comirnaty</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 30 years or older at enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have received two doses of any inactivated COVID-19 vaccines (for example Sinovac-&#xD;
             CoronaVac, Sinopharm-BIBP) with the most recent dose at least 90 days prior to&#xD;
             enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently resident and planning to remain resident in Hong Kong during the duration of&#xD;
             the study, i.e. for 12 months after enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agreement to refrain from blood donation during the course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to provide blood samples for all the required time points.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The individual or their caregiver have a home phone or cellular or mobile phone for&#xD;
             communications purpose.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capable of providing informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of laboratory-confirmed or clinically confirmed COVID-19 infection. Have&#xD;
             received (at least one dose of) any COVID-19 vaccines other than inactivated vaccines.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who report any medical condition, or as determined by a clinician, not&#xD;
             suitable to receive mRNA vaccines, including but not limited to allergies to the&#xD;
             active substance or other ingredients of the vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With diagnosed medical conditions related to their immune system.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of medication that impairs immune system in the last 6 months, except topical&#xD;
             steroids or short-term oral steroids (course lasting ≤ 14 days).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have used immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within 90 days prior to enrolment&#xD;
             (administration of the study vaccine).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, lactation or intention to become pregnant in the coming 3 months.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Benjamin J Cowling, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+85239176711</phone>
    <email>bcowling@hku.hk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The University of Hong Kong</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hong Kong</city>
        <zip>00000</zip>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Julie Au</last_name>
      <phone>+852 3917 6791</phone>
      <email>ju1ieau@hku.hk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Benjamin J Cowling, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

