<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05055765</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Anjali Yadav perio</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05055765</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparative Evaluation of Microneedling and Injectable Platelet Rich Fibrin in Thin Periodontal Phenotype</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparative Evaluation Of Microneedling vs Injectable Platelet Rich Fibrin In Thin Periodontal Phenotype: A Randomised Split Mouth Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Postgraduate Institute of Dental Sciences Rohtak</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Postgraduate Institute of Dental Sciences Rohtak</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Evaluation of microneedling vs injectable -platelet rich fibrin on gingival phenotype in thin&#xD;
      periodontal phenotype.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      INTRODUCTION The gingival phenotype and different parts of the masticatory mucosa have become&#xD;
      the subject of considerable interest in Periodontics, especially from an aesthetic and&#xD;
      therapeutic perspective. The periodontal phenotype has been defined as the combination of&#xD;
      gingival phenotype and buccal bone plate thickness (bone morphotype). Gingival phenotype&#xD;
      refers to gingival thickness (GT) and keratinized tissue width (KTW).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Gingival phenotypes can be classified as scalloped and thin or flat and thick gingiva. A&#xD;
      gingival thickness of ≥1 mm is defined as thick phenotype and a gingival thickness of ≤1 mm&#xD;
      as thin phenotype1. Thin gingival phenotype are very friable and might be prone to recede in&#xD;
      response to traumatic insults, such as plaque-related inflammation and traumatic&#xD;
      toothbrushing. Gingival recession is usually observed in the presence of trauma and&#xD;
      inflammation in individuals with thin phenotypes, whereas pocket formation has been reported&#xD;
      in individuals with thick phenotypes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Soft tissue grafting in areas of thin phenotypes can enhance the quality of the gingival&#xD;
      tissue. The best way to convert a thin soft tissue to a thick phenotype is through&#xD;
      subepithelial connective tissue grafting Various other soft tissue augmentation procedures&#xD;
      include: - modified roll technique and use of acellular dermal matrix. There were many&#xD;
      drawback of these techniques such as were not cost effective, complications, second surgical&#xD;
      site creation, healing and time consuming, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore marked transformation in the field of periodontics has led to the development of&#xD;
      newer, less invasive therapeutic approaches, which allows proper management of surrounding&#xD;
      tissues to provide best outcome of periodontal therapy. Minimally invasive treatment&#xD;
      approaches help to achieve satisfactory therapeutic results with minimum trauma to tissues.&#xD;
      Recent study has shown i-PRF (injectable Platelet Rich Fibrin) and Microneedling procedures&#xD;
      to be effective in increasing gingival tissue thickness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      I-PRF prepared according to low-speed centrifugation concept can provide a significant&#xD;
      advantage for the regeneration process, as it is rich in platelets, leucocytes and growth&#xD;
      factors. I-PRF clots and forms a gel form after approximately 10-15 min and preserves its&#xD;
      content in the tissue for sustained release. Recent studies have shown that in comparison to&#xD;
      PRP and the blood clot even though there is slight or no increases in blood cell&#xD;
      concentrations and growth factors; i- PRF was capable of inducing higher cell migration and&#xD;
      mRNA expression of TGF- β, PDGF, osteocalcin and significant increase in type I collagen gene&#xD;
      expression. It has been suggested that i- PRF provides a three- dimensional fibrin clot&#xD;
      network embedding platelets, leucocytes, type I collagen, osteocalcin and growth factors&#xD;
      acting as a dynamic gel with additional release of growth factors up to 10 days. Hence&#xD;
      studies have documented that i-PRF results in increased gingival thickness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Microneedling (MN) is also known as &quot;percutaneous collagen induction therapy.&quot; Microinjuries&#xD;
      created by MN result in minimal superficial bleedings and create a wound- healing cascade&#xD;
      from which various growth factors, such as platelet-derived growth factors, transforming&#xD;
      growth factors, connective tissue growth factor and fibroblast growth factors, are released.&#xD;
      In MN, the tissue responds as if experiencing tissue trauma and the body's own collagen&#xD;
      production is induced to preserve skin integrity. Study has shown a statistically significant&#xD;
      increase in gingival thickness when microneedling was performed along with i- PRF in&#xD;
      comparison to standalone i-PRF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Only one study have evaluated effect of i-PRF alone and with microneedling on thin phenotype&#xD;
      . To the best of our knowledge no studies have been conducted till now using microneedling&#xD;
      alone to observe its effect on gingival thickness on thin periodontal phenotype. Considering&#xD;
      the effects of MN and i-PRF on the biological potential, neoangiogenesis, neocollagenesis and&#xD;
      wound, the present Randomized clinical trial is designed to compare and evaluate the effects&#xD;
      of MN and i-PRF alone in thin periodontal phenotype. The null hypothesis is that there is no&#xD;
      significant difference in the clinical outcome in microneedling and i-PRF on thin periodontal&#xD;
      phenotype.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MATERIALS AND METHODOLOGY&#xD;
&#xD;
      SETTINGS: The present prospective, analytical, split mouth clinical trial will be conducted&#xD;
      in the Department of Periodontics, Post Graduate Institute of Dental Sciences, Rohtak STUDY&#xD;
      DESIGN: Interventional study. TIME FRAME: 12-14 months STUDY&#xD;
&#xD;
      Written and verbal consent will be taken from the willing participants. This Split mouth&#xD;
      clinical trial will include 20 systemically healthy patients, with thin periodontal phenotype&#xD;
      in mandibular anteriors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Test group I : microneedling Test group II : i-PRF METHOD OF RECRUITMENT&#xD;
&#xD;
      In power analysis, it was found that a minimum of 18 cases will be required for each group at&#xD;
      a 95% confidence level and 80% power when analysed with a mean difference of 0.5 mm and a&#xD;
      standard deviation of 0.47 using the soft tissue thickness as a reference.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Estimating a 10% drop-out rate, the study includes 20 individuals with thin periodontal&#xD;
      phenotypes who will consult to the Department of Periodontology, Post Graduate Institute of&#xD;
      Dental Sciences, Rohtak .&#xD;
&#xD;
      BLINDING/MASKING Single blinding will be adopted where the investigator analysing the results&#xD;
      will be unaware to which group the patient belongs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PHASE I THERAPY All the participants will undergo phase-I therapy with a combination of hand&#xD;
      scalers and curettes and ultrasonic scaler. Oral hygiene instructions will be imparted and&#xD;
      will be reinforced at each appointment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      INTERVENTION Local anaesthesia will be administered. TEST GROUP I Thin periodontal phenotype&#xD;
      will be treated with microneedling. A total of 4 sessions will be done with an interval of 10&#xD;
      days each. And all the parameters will be measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TEST GROUP II Thin periodontal phenotype will be treated with i-PRF procedure. A total of 4&#xD;
      sessions will be done with an interval of 10 days each. And all the parameters will be&#xD;
      measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DATA COLLECTION METHODS To measure GT from the apical 1.5 mm of the gingival margin, a No:15&#xD;
      endodontic spreader with a 3-mm-diameter silicone disc will be placed in the centre and will&#xD;
      be measured on Vernier caliper.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Keratinised tissue width will be measured with the help of UNC 15 probe with silicon disc&#xD;
      stopper from the mucogingival junction to the free gingival margin and will be measured on&#xD;
      Vernier caliper.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PPD will be measured using UNC 15 periodontal probe at six sites (mesiobuccal, distobuccal,&#xD;
      mesiolingual , distolingual , and median points at buccal and lingual aspect).&#xD;
&#xD;
      GI, PI will be measured using UNC 15 periodontal probe at four sites (distofacial,&#xD;
      mesiofacial, facial, lingual gingival margin).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All clinical parameters will be measured at baseline, 3 months and 6 months and 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DATA MANAGEMENT AND STATISTICAL ANALYSIS Data recorded will be processed by standard&#xD;
      statistical analysis. The normality of distribution of data will be examined by Shapiro Wilk&#xD;
      test. Statistical analysis will be performed according to distribution of data. If it is in&#xD;
      normal distribution inter group comparison will be done by using Independent T test and&#xD;
      paired t test will be use for intragroup comparison and if non-normal distributionof data,&#xD;
      inter group comparison will be done by Mann-Whitney U test and intragroup by signed rank&#xD;
      test. The Chi square test will be applied to analyze categoric data. Correlation and&#xD;
      association between predictors and dependent variables will be analyzed by correlation&#xD;
      analysis and regression analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Single blinding will be adopted where the investigator analysing the results will be unaware to which group the patient belongs.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Gingival thickness (GT)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>GT was determined at a mid-buccal location about 1mm apical to the Pocket Depth with a #15 endodontic reamer.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Keratinized tissue width (KTW)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Keratinised tissue width will be measured with the help of UNC 15 probe with silicon disc stopper from the mucogingival junction to the free gingival margin.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pocket Probing Depth (PD)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>PD will be measured using UNC 15 periodontal probe at six sites (mesiobuccal, distobuccal, mesiolingual , distolingual , and median points at buccal and lingual aspect).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Thin Gingiva</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TEST GROUP I</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Thin periodontal phenotype will be treated with microneedling. A total of 4 sessions will be done with an interval of 10 days each. And all the parameters will be measured.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TEST GROUP II</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Thin periodontal phenotype will be treated with i-PRF procedure. A total of 4 sessions will be done with an interval of 10 days each. And all the parameters will be measured.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Microneedling</intervention_name>
    <description>MN will be carried out 1mm below of the gingival margin on the gingiva of the tooth to be treated with thirty-gauge (0.255 mm) lancet needles.</description>
    <arm_group_label>TEST GROUP I</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>injectable- platelet rich fibrin</intervention_name>
    <description>I-PRF will be prepared according to Choukroun PRF method.</description>
    <arm_group_label>TEST GROUP II</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  GT of the mandibular and maxillary anterior teeth &lt; 1 mm, gingival index (GI) of &lt; 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18-40 years and otherwise systemically healthy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who had completed etiological periodontal therapy with Plaque index &lt;1,&#xD;
             gingival index &lt;1 and showing adequate compliance and willing to participate in the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients having systemic diseases such as hypertension, diabetes, hyperthyroidism or&#xD;
             on medications that influence the outcome of periodontal procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant and lactating women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smokers, tobacco users&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous periodontal surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No haematological disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of blood thinners&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any drugs that might lead to gingival enlargement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stress, bruxism.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>ANJALI YADAV</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>PGIDS,ROHTAK</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>SANJAY TEWARI</last_name>
    <phone>01262-283876</phone>
    <email>principalpgids@yahoo.in</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>NISHI TANWAR</last_name>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Post Graduate Institute of Dental Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rohtak</city>
        <state>Haryana</state>
        <zip>124001</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>periodontal phenotype</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

