<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05057533</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Primary Headaches and IBS</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05057533</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Primary Headaches and Irritable Bowel Syndrome.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Association Between Primary Headaches and Irritable Bowel Syndrome.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To assess the relationship between primary headaches and irritable bowel syndrome&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The association between primary headaches and functional gastrointestinal disorders has been&#xD;
      confirmed by many clinical observations. In most patients during the attacks of headache,&#xD;
      apart from various neurological and vascular symptoms, gastrointestinal disturbances occur .&#xD;
      Functional gastrointestinal disorders, such as irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), are reported&#xD;
      in primary headache patients in periods between the attacks as well. On the other hand 23-53%&#xD;
      of IBS patients have frequent headaches.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Migraine typically presents relapsing episodes of symptoms including headache, nausea,&#xD;
      vomiting, sensory hypersensitivity and mood changes that last for hours to days . Similar to&#xD;
      migraine, IBS is characterized by recurrent abdominal pain or discomfort with altered&#xD;
      gastrointestinal motility and visceral hypersensitivity that returns to normal between&#xD;
      attacks . Both pain disorders lack detectable organic causes .&#xD;
&#xD;
      An emerging model of the brain-gut axis was proposed to explain migraine and IBS as a result&#xD;
      of a genetically sensitive nervous system that develops hyperexcitability over time as a&#xD;
      response to multiple environmental and immunological factors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cluster headache (CH) characterized by its distinctive circadian and circannual periodicity,&#xD;
      implicating the role of the hypothalamus in its underlying pathophysiology. CH and IBS are&#xD;
      featuring recurrent attacks of pain that possess relationships with circadian rhythms and&#xD;
      potentially hypothalamic derangements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tension headache that's associated with pain in head described as feeling like a tight band&#xD;
      around head, also show many similarities with IBS such causes for both are unknown, and some&#xD;
      studies suggest a possible link that could shed light on shared genetics of both condition .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Association between primary headaches and irritable bowel syndrome</measure>
    <time_frame>Basline</time_frame>
    <description>To Detect the prevalence of IBS among patients with primary headaches</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subtypes of primary headachecs and IBS</measure>
    <time_frame>Basline</time_frame>
    <description>Detect the intimate correlation between each type of primary headaches and IBS</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">197</enrollment>
  <condition>Primary Headache Disorder</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>a questionnaire based on Rome IV Diagnostic criteria of IBS</intervention_name>
    <description>The Rome IV criteria for the diagnosis of IBS require that patients have had recurrent abdominal pain on average at least 1 day per week during the previous 3 months that is associated with two or more of the following&#xD;
Related to defecation (may be increased or unchanged by defecation)&#xD;
Associated with a change in stool frequency&#xD;
Associated with a change in stool form or appearance The Rome IV criteria (May 2016) only require abdominal pain in defining this condition; &quot;discomfort&quot; is no longer a requirement owing to its nonspecificity, and the recurrent abdominal pain. [2] Supporting symptoms include the following:Altered stool frequency Altered stool form Altered stool passage (straining and/or urgency) Mucorrhea Abdominal bloating or subjective distention.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        A group of patients attending headache outpatient clinic of Assuit University hospital&#xD;
        diagnosed with primary headaches (migraine , tension Headache or cluster headache)according&#xD;
        to a questionnaire based on diagnostic criteria established by the International Headache&#xD;
        Society will interviewed with a questionnaire based on Rome IV Diagnostic criteria of IBS&#xD;
        to detect the prevalence of IBS among patients with primary headaches&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age more than 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  both sex.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history suggestive of any type of primary headaches.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  accept to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intake of medications that can aggravate Headache or IBS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of neurological disease other than primary headaches.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of gastrointestinal disease other than IBS.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Reda Badry, MD prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wael Abbas</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mohamed Helmy, Resident doctor</last_name>
    <phone>+201018517954</phone>
    <email>Mohamedgamahelmy@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Wafaa Fargaly, MD prof</last_name>
    <phone>+201000104904</phone>
    <email>Wafmaf2002@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Assiut University hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mohamed Helmy, Resident doctor</last_name>
      <phone>+201018517954</phone>
      <email>Mohamedgamahelmy@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Reda Badry, MD prof</last_name>
      <phone>+01008336450</phone>
      <email>redaalbady@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Soares RL, Moreira-Filho PF, Maneschy CP, Breijão JF, Schmidte NM. The prevalence and clinical characteristics of primary headache in irritable bowel syndrome: a subgroup of the functional somatic syndromes. Arq Gastroenterol. 2013 Oct-Dec;50(4):281-4. doi: 10.1590/S0004-28032013000400008.</citation>
    <PMID>24474230</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Martami F, Ghorbani Z, Abolhasani M, Togha M, Meysamie A, Sharifi A, Razeghi Jahromi S. Comorbidity of gastrointestinal disorders, migraine, and tension-type headache: a cross-sectional study in Iran. Neurol Sci. 2018 Jan;39(1):63-70. doi: 10.1007/s10072-017-3141-0. Epub 2017 Oct 11.</citation>
    <PMID>29022143</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Doulberis M, Saleh C, Beyenburg S. Is there an Association between Migraine and Gastrointestinal Disorders? J Clin Neurol. 2017 Jul;13(3):215-226. doi: 10.3988/jcn.2017.13.3.215. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28748672</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mohamed Gamal Helmy</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Resident doctor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Headache Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Headache Disorders, Primary</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Headache</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

