<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05054517</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Athens Medical 2281/26-04-2013</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05054517</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Oral Glutamine and Thoracic/Upper Aerodigestive Tumors Radiation Toxicity</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Use of Oral Glutamine in Patients With Thoracic and Upper Aerodigestive Malignancies Who Undergo Radiotherapy: Results of a Prospective Observational Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National and Kapodistrian University of Athens</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National and Kapodistrian University of Athens</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      PROTOCOL FOR PREVENTIVE ADMINISTRATION OF GLUTAMINE TO AVOID RADIATE SIDE EFFECTS IN PATIENTS&#xD;
      UNDER RADIOTHERAPY IN THE CHEST AND HEAD &amp; NECK&#xD;
&#xD;
      PURPOSE OF THE STUDY&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of the protocol is to study the acute and distant toxicity of the mucosa of the&#xD;
      oral cavity and esophagus after radiotherapy for head-neck and tumors of the chest. Radiation&#xD;
      therapy in all cases is a three-dimensional conformal technique with a linear accelerator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      INCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients undergoing radiotherapy with or without concomitant chemotherapy for Ca nasopharynx,&#xD;
      hypopharynx, palate, tonsils, mouth base, parotid, tongue, cervix and esophagus as well as&#xD;
      mediastinal and lung cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with psychiatric problems and inability to cooperate, as well as patients with&#xD;
      gluten intolerance, as well as patients with hepatic encephalopathy or hyperammonemia, are&#xD;
      excluded from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Oral glutamine administration starting 4 days before the start of radiotherapy and for a&#xD;
      total of 3 months. The preparation is dissolved in water and taken orally 4 hours before&#xD;
      radiotherapy and 4 hours before dinner.&#xD;
&#xD;
      FOLLOW UP&#xD;
&#xD;
      Immediately after completion of radiotherapy at 3, 6 and 12 months, orthoscopy (on symptoms)&#xD;
      and oral mucosal examination will be performed on patients who have undergone cervical and&#xD;
      mediastinal radiotherapy and their evaluation based on the EORTC-RTOG scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      REFERENCES&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Anderson PM, Schroeder G, Skubitz KM. &quot;Oral glutamine reduces the duration and severity&#xD;
           of stomatitis after cytotoxic cancer chemotherapy&quot;. Cancer: 1998; 83: 1433-1439.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Cerchietti LC, Navigante AH, Lutteral MA, Castro MA, Kirchuk R, Bonomi M et al.&#xD;
           &quot;Double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial on intravenous L-alanyl-L-glutamine in the&#xD;
           incidence of oral mucosis following chemotherapy in patients with head-and-neck cancer.&#xD;
           Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2006 Aug 1; 65 (5): 1330-7.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Peterson DE, Jones JB, Petit RG 2nd. &quot;Randomized, placebo-controlled trial of Saforis&#xD;
           for prevention and treatment of oral mucositis in breast cancer patients receiving&#xD;
           anthracycline-based chemotherapy. Cancer. 2007 Jan 15; 109(2): 322-31.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Kozelsky TF, Meyers GE, Sloan JA, Shanahan TG, Dick SJ et al; North Central Cancer&#xD;
           Treatment Group. Mayo Clinic &quot;Phase III double-blind study of glutamine versus placebo&#xD;
           for the prevention of acute diarrhea in patients receiving pelvic radiation therapy&quot;. J&#xD;
           Clin Oncol 2003 May 1; 21 (9):1669-74.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Topkan E, Yavuz MN, et al &quot;Prevention of acute radiation-induced esophagitis with&#xD;
           glutamine in non-small cell lung cancer patients treated with radiotherapy: Evaluation&#xD;
           of clinical and dosimetric parameters&quot;. Lung Cancer, 2008 August 6.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Ismael Membrive Conejo, Ana Reig Castillejo, Nuria Rodriguez de Dios, Palmira Foro&#xD;
           Arnalot, Javier Sanz Latiesas, et al: &quot;Prevention of acute radiation enteritis: efficacy&#xD;
           and tolerance of glutamine&quot;. Clinical and Translational Oncology. Vol 13, Number 10&#xD;
           (2011), 760-763, DOI: 10.1007/st 2094-011-0729-3.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Yoshida S, Kaibara A, Ishibashi N, Shirouzu K. &quot;Glutamine supplementation in cancer&#xD;
           patients&quot; Nutrition. 2001: 17:766-768.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Klimberg SV, McClellan Jl. &quot;Glutamine, cancer and its therapy. Am J Surg. 1996;172:&#xD;
           172:418-424.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Rouse K, Nwokedi E, Woodliff JE, Epstein J, Klimberg VS. &quot;Glutamine enhances selectivity&#xD;
           of chemotherapy through changes in glutathione metabolism. Ann Surg. 1995; 221:420-426.&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Baxevanis CN, Reclos GJ, Grittapis AD et al &quot;Elevated PGE2 production by monocytes is&#xD;
           responsible for the depressed levels of NK&amp;LAK cell function in patients with breast&#xD;
           cancer&quot; Cancer. 1993; 12:491-501.&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Erdem NZ, Yasti AC, Atli M, et al. &quot;The effects of perioperative oral enteral support&#xD;
           with glutamine added elemental formulas in patients with gastrointestinal cancers: a&#xD;
           prospective randomized clinical study. Nutr Res.2002:22:977-988.&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Berk L, James J, Schwartz A, Hug E, Mahadevan A, Samuels M et al. &quot;A randomized,&#xD;
           double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of a beta hydroxyl beta-methyl butyrate,&#xD;
           glutamine, and arginine mixture for the treatment of cancer cachexia&quot;. Support Care&#xD;
           Cancer. 2008 Oct; 16 (10): 1179-88. Epub 2008 Feb 22.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary endpoints were the incidence of grade 2 or greater in the observed toxicities, weight loss and the need for analgesic therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>one month</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The secondary endpoint was the length of the irradiated esophagus from radiotherapy (RT) treatment planning correlated with the use of opioids as analgesics.</measure>
    <time_frame>one month</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">72</enrollment>
  <condition>Biopsy Confirmed Head and Neck Cancer and Tumors of the Chest</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Glutamine</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral Supplement</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        A total of 72 patients with biopsy-diagnosed T&amp;UAM were prospectively recruited. The mean&#xD;
        age of patients was 65.6 ± 1.2 years, ranging between 54 and 77 years. Most participants&#xD;
        were male (n=54, 75%).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing radiotherapy with or without concomitant chemotherapy for Ca&#xD;
             nasopharynx, hypopharynx, palate, tonsils, mouth base, parotid, tongue, cervix and&#xD;
             esophagus as well as mediastinal and lung cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with psychiatric problems and inability to cooperate, as well as patients&#xD;
             with gluten intolerance, as well as patients with hepatic encephalopathy or&#xD;
             hyperammonemia are excluded from the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>National and Kapodistrian University of Athens</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nikolaos Drakoulis, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prof. Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Glutamine; chest tumors; lung cancer; head and neck cancer; clinical studies; human subjects</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>no availability of any data</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

