<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05051995</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0721-20</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05051995</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Combined N-of-1 Trials to Assess Open-Label Placebo Treatment for Antidepressant Discontinuation Symptoms</brief_title>
  <acronym>FAB</acronym>
  <official_title>Combined N-of-1 Trials to Assess Open-Label Placebo Treatment for Antidepressant Discontinuation Symptoms</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Universitätsklinikum Marburg</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital, Essen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Helmut Schmidt University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It has been widely recognized that the placebo effect has a profound impact on treatment&#xD;
      outcome in many different conditions. Recent studies imply that this effect appears even if&#xD;
      placebos are openly administered; so called &quot;open-label placebos&quot; (OLP). Compelling evidence&#xD;
      suggests the efficacy of OLP in the treatment of pain disorders, neuropsychological&#xD;
      syndromes, menopausal hot flushes, depression and allergic rhinitis. Research on the&#xD;
      underlying mechanisms of OLP is scarce, yet studies indicate that psychological mechanisms as&#xD;
      well as neurobiological processes related to expectation- and prediction mechanisms may play&#xD;
      a role. While these effects have been linked to OLP as additional treatment, to date, it has&#xD;
      not been examined whether OLP could support discontinuation of drug treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Antidepressant discontinuation has been frequently associated with negative side effects,&#xD;
      interfering with the discontinuation process and generally discouraging discontinuation.&#xD;
      Patients frequently report negative expectations towards the discontinuation process, such as&#xD;
      fear of experiencing a relapse and negative side effects. Interestingly, OLP may support&#xD;
      antidepressant discontinuation, not only through the generation of (positive) expectations,&#xD;
      but also mechanisms related to habituation (i.e. taking pills). The objective of this study&#xD;
      is to investigate whether OLP is efficacious in reducing negative side effects caused by&#xD;
      discontinuation of antidepressant medication.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Rationale: A current issue in the frame of antidepressant medication is the rise of long-term&#xD;
      antidepressant use associated with noticeable adverse effects such as withdrawal effects,&#xD;
      sexual difficulties, weight gain and emotional numbness. A key factor hindering patients in&#xD;
      the discontinuation of antidepressant medication is the emergence of discontinuation&#xD;
      symptoms, reported by over half of fully remitted patients discontinuing antidepressants. To&#xD;
      date, there is no study examining open-label placebo responses on antidepressant&#xD;
      discontinuation symptoms. However, several findings imply that open-label placebos may&#xD;
      support the discontinuation process in remitted depressed patients. The susceptibility to&#xD;
      placebo responses is encouraged by findings indicating substantial placebo effects in&#xD;
      antidepressant trials (67-82%). Additionally, evidence suggests the central role of&#xD;
      expectation effects influencing the course of antidepressant discontinuation. Open-label&#xD;
      placebos have been found to work through the generation of positive expectations, induced by&#xD;
      a positive framing (e.g. verbal instructions). A recent meta-analysis suggests a medium to&#xD;
      large effect size of open-label placebos. Regarding the treatment of antidepressant&#xD;
      discontinuation symptoms, open-label placebos have the potential to reduce symptoms not only&#xD;
      by inducing positive expectations, but also by triggering automatic (positive) responses to&#xD;
      the intake of a pill (i.e. conditioning).The aim of this study is to investigate the effect&#xD;
      of open-label placebos on antidepressant discontinuation symptoms in fully remitted depressed&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: In the proposed study, a pilot sample will discontinue their antidepressant intake&#xD;
      under extensive medical and psychological supervision, according to the national and&#xD;
      international guidelines over a 13-week course. After a run-in week and the baseline&#xD;
      assessment, antidepressant medication will be gradually reduced with individualized&#xD;
      discontinuation plans over a period of 4 weeks. Weekly measurements serve to monitor the&#xD;
      condition of the participants. After discontinuation, patients will be monitored (with&#xD;
      biweekly study visits) for another 8 weeks (experimental phase). Finally, a follow-up&#xD;
      measurement 6 months after the study start constitutes long-term monitoring and the&#xD;
      assessment of relapse after antidepressant discontinuation. During the experimental phase,&#xD;
      patients experiencing moderate discontinuation symptoms are allocated to the intervention&#xD;
      group, aimed to examine the effect of open-label placebo on antidepressant discontinuation&#xD;
      symptoms. For this purpose, N-of-1 trials comprising multiple crossovers (A: open-label&#xD;
      placebo; B: no treatment) within each individual, and varying in a biweekly rhythm, are&#xD;
      applied. Patients are randomized to different treatment orders (ABAB; BABA). Twice daily&#xD;
      smartphone-measurements are implemented to assess discontinuation symptoms, expectations and&#xD;
      mood. Additionally, study visits consist of extensive measurements related to discontinuation&#xD;
      symptoms, depressive symptomatology, psychological well-being and treatment expectations.&#xD;
      These serve as observational measurement of different effects related to antidepressant&#xD;
      discontinuation. During the experimental phase, outcome assessors will be blind to the&#xD;
      randomization (i.e. treatment order) of the patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives: At the end of the study, the investigators will determine whether open-label&#xD;
      placebo reduces negative side effects caused by antidepressant discontinuation by aggregating&#xD;
      the N-of-1 trials. Underlying mechanisms such as treatment expectations, as well as the&#xD;
      relation to depressed mood, will be under explorative investigation. Additionally, the course&#xD;
      of discontinuation symptoms, depressive symptoms (self-report and expert-rated) and treatment&#xD;
      adherence during the entire study will be explored. Therefore, potential modulators such as&#xD;
      psychopathology, demographics, adverse events, expectations, prior experience, subjective&#xD;
      stress, side effects of antidepressants and anxiety vs. depression (trait/state) will be&#xD;
      taken into account in data analyses.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>To investigate the efficacy of open-label placebo in the reduction of antidepressant discontinuation symptoms, patients experiencing moderate discontinuation symptoms after successful discontinuation (4 weeks) receive open-label placebo treatment or no treatment during the experimental phase (8 weeks).&#xD;
For this purpose, a series of N-of-1 trials is implemented, consisting of multiple crossover trials within each participant. The factor treatment (open-label placebo vs. no treatment) varies intra-individually with a biweekly rhythm, to assess the treatment effect on discontinuation symptoms. A block-randomization is applied, with patients either receiving (A) open-label placebo or (B) no treatment in a biweekly rhythm (group 1: ABAB; group 2: BABA).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The person performing the data collection (assessor) will be blind to the randomization of the participant for the entire duration of the experimental phase.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in antidepressant discontinuation symptoms assessed by the 'Generic rating scale for treatment effects' (GEEE_ACT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Continuous measurement (2xdaily) for 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The generic rating scale for treatment effects assesses the current treatment effects (i.e. antidepressant discontinuation effects) regarding side effects as well as positive and negative aspects on 3 numeric rating scales with eleven response options (0-10); total score range from 0-30 with higher scores indicating higher antidepressant discontinuation effects.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in treatment expectations assessed by 'Generic rating scale for treatment expectations' (GEEE_EXP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Continuous measurement (2xdaily) for 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The generic rating scale for treatment expectations assesses treatment expectations (i.e. antidepressant discontinuation expectations) regarding positive and negative aspects as well as side effects on 3 numeric rating scales (ranging from 0-10); total score range from 0-30 with higher scores indicating higher treatment expectations.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in (depressed) mood assessed by the 'Patient-Healthcare-Questionnaire' (PHQ-2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Continuous measurement (2xdaily) for 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report comprising 2 items, inquiring the degree to which an individual experiences the core symptoms of depression (i.e. anhedonia and depressed mood); items are scored on a four level Likert scale ranging from 0 (not at all) - 3 (almost constant); total score range from 0-6 (higher scores indicate a higher degree of depressed mood).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Discontinuation symptoms - 'Discontinuation Related Signs and Symptoms Scale' (DESS) - observational</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly during discontinuation phase (4 weeks); biweekly during experimental phase (8 weeks); follow-up (6 months later)</time_frame>
    <description>The discontinuation related signs and symptoms scale is a self-report questionnaire to assess discontinuation symptoms, incorporating 43 discontinuation symptoms of antidepressant with intensity ratings ranging from 0 (not present) - 3 (severe); total score range from 0-129 with higher scores indicating more severe discontinuation symptoms.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective depressive symptomatology - 'Beck Depression Inventory' (BDI-II) - observational</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly during discontinuation phase (4 weeks); biweekly during experimental phase (8 weeks); follow-up (6 months later)</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report measure to assess depressive symptoms, including 21 items with 4 response options (0-3); total scores range from 0 - 63 (higher scores indicating higher depression severity).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Expert-rated depression severity scores - 'Montgomery-Åsberg Depression Scale' (MADRS) - observational</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly during discontinuation phase (4 weeks); biweekly during experimental phase (8 weeks); follow-up (6 months later)</time_frame>
    <description>Expert-rated interview to assess the severity of depression by 10 items with up to 7 rating categories (0-6) for each item; total scores range between 0-60 with higher scores indicating more severe depression severity.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Mental well-being - 'Short Warwick-Edinburgh Mental Wellbeing Scale' (SWEMWBS) - observational</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly during discontinuation phase (4 weeks); biweekly during experimental phase (8 weeks); follow-up (6 months later)</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report questionnaire to assess mental well-being by 7 statements about thoughts and feelings using 5 response options; total score range from 7-35 with higher sum scores reflecting a higher level of mental well-being.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Adherence - single item - observational</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly during discontinuation phase (4 weeks); biweekly during experimental phase (8 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Treatment adherence assessed by a single item in the clinical interview about adherence to medication or placebo (i.e. experimental phase) intake.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment expectations - 'Treatment Expectation Questionnaire' (TEX-Q) - observational</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly during discontinuation phase (4 weeks); biweekly during experimental phase (8 weeks); follow-up (6 months later)</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported measure to assess patients' treatment expectations, consisting of 15 items with 11 response options, total score range from 0-150 (higher scores implying more positive treatment expectations).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Pre-experiences with antidepressant discontinuation - 'Generic rating scale for previous treatment experiences' (GEEE_PRE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported previous experiences with antidepressant discontinuation. If experience with antidepressant discontinuation is indicated, the following 3 items rate the experiences regarding side effects as well as positive and negative aspects on 3 numeric analogue scales (ranging from 0-10); total score range from 0-30; higher scores indicate more pre-experiences with antidepressant discontinuation effects.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective Stress - 'Perceived Stress Scale' (PSS-10)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported measure of subjective stress, including 10 items with 5 rating categories, total scores range between 0-40; higher scores are suggestive of more subjective stress.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety vs Depression - 'State-Trait-Anxiety-Depression-Inventory' (STADI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report questionnaire as indicator of state and trait anxiety and depression, divided in 2 sections (state vs. trait) consisting of 20 statements with 4 response options, respectively. Total scores per scale range between 20 and 80 with higher sum scores indicating higher state/trait anxiety or depression.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Side effects of SSRIs - 'Generic Assessment of Side Effects' (GASE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report measure to assess side effects of antidepressant medication, including 36 items (symptom descriptions) with 4 response options. Items are additionally evaluated on their relation to antidepressant medication (Yes/ No questions). Total scores range from 0-108 (higher scores are reflective of stronger experiences of side effects).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events - single safety items</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly during discontinuation phase (4 weeks); biweekly during experimental phase (8 weeks); follow-up (6 months later)</time_frame>
    <description>Interview-based measure assessing adverse events by 3 questions (Yes/ No questions), followed by an expert-rating of the intensity of the adverse events (1-5) and relation to treatment (1-5). Higher scores indicate more and/or a higher intensity of adverse events.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Psychopathology - 'Structured Clinical Interview for DSM-5, Clinician Version' (SCID-5-CV)</measure>
    <time_frame>Screening</time_frame>
    <description>Expert-rated semi-structured interview to assess DSM-5 diagnoses.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>SSRI/SNRI blood serum level - blood analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-antidepressant discontinuation (1 week after baseline); post-antidepressant discontinuation (5 weeks after baseline)</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Depressive Symptoms</condition>
  <condition>Expectations</condition>
  <condition>Antidepressants</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Open-label placebo ABAB Sequence</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The N-of-1 trial will, on the level of the individual patient, test whether open-label placebo reduces negative side effects caused by discontinuation of antidepressants compared to no treatment. After antidepressant discontinuation, subjects will be randomized to 2 arms differing in the treatment order (ABAB; BABA). Subjects in this arm (ABAB) will start with open-label placebo (A) for 2 weeks; they will then crossover to no treatment (B) for 2 weeks and repeat this sequence once again.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Open-label placebo BABA Sequence</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The N-of-1 trial will, on the level of the individual patient, test whether open-label placebo reduces negative side effects caused by discontinuation of antidepressants compared to no treatment. After antidepressant discontinuation, subjects will be randomized to 2 arms differing in the treatment order (ABAB; BABA). Subjects in this arm (BABA) will start with no treatment (B) for 2 weeks; they will then crossover to open-label placebo (A) for 2 weeks and repeat this sequence once again.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Open-label placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Prior to the open-label placebo administration, an explanation why placebos without concealment might be effective is offered. Participants receive placebo pills with the instruction to take 2 pills daily for 2 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Open-label placebo ABAB Sequence</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Open-label placebo BABA Sequence</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No-treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>During the no-treatment phase, participants receive no treatment for 2 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Open-label placebo ABAB Sequence</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Open-label placebo BABA Sequence</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult participants (18+years) with a former diagnoses of major depressive disorder&#xD;
             (MDD), single or recurrent as main diagnosis confirmed by prescribing physician and&#xD;
             currently remitted&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intake of selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRI)/ serotonin-norepinephrine&#xD;
             reuptake inhibitors (SNRI) (citalopram: 20-40mg, duloxetine: 60-100mg, escitalopram:&#xD;
             10-20mg, paroxetine: 20-40mg, sertraline: 50-150mg, venlafaxine: 75-150mg) or&#xD;
             noradrenergic and specific serotonergic antidepressants (NaSSA) (mirtazapine: 30-45mg)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Discontinuation wish by patient supported by prescribing physician&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fulfils the criteria of the S3 national guideline recommendations &quot;Depression&quot; to&#xD;
             discontinue antidepressant medication: a) response to antidepressant; b) symptom&#xD;
             remission for at least 4 months (first episode) or for 2 years (2 or more episodes&#xD;
             with significant functional impairment), constant intake of antidepressant medication&#xD;
             (at least 4 weeks on a steady dose)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current moderate or severe psychopathological symptoms or psycho-social impairments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute or chronic somatic illness which might interfere with depressive disorder,&#xD;
             antidepressant or proposed study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute suicidality, psychotic symptoms, substance abuse, or addiction, current mania,&#xD;
             or hypomania confirmed by SCID-5 or other psychopathology which might interfere with&#xD;
             depressive disorder, antidepressant or proposed study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any history of bipolar disorder or psychosis confirmed by SCID-5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe stressful life events (e.g., death of a family member) within six months prior&#xD;
             to study participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insufficient German language proficiency.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yvonne Nestoriuc, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tilo Kircher, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Universitätsklinikum Marburg</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amke Müller, M.Sc.</last_name>
    <phone>+49(0)40 6541-3918</phone>
    <email>muellera@hsu-hh.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Tahmine Fadai, Dr.</last_name>
    <phone>+49(0)40 741053217</phone>
    <email>t.fadai@uke.de</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Marburg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Marburg</city>
        <state>Hessen</state>
        <zip>35039</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christoph Vogelbacher, Dr.</last_name>
      <email>vogelbac@staff.uni-marburg.de</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tilo Kircher, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>20251</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Amke Müller, M.Sc.</last_name>
      <phone>+49(0)40 65413918</phone>
      <email>muellera@hsu-hh.de</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Tahmine Fadai, Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49(0)40 741053217</phone>
      <email>t.fadai@uke.de</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Yvonne Nestoriuc, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nestoriuc Y, Pan Y, Kinitz T, Weik E, Shedden-Mora MC. Informing About the Nocebo Effect Affects Patients' Need for Information About Antidepressants-An Experimental Online Study. Front Psychiatry. 2021 Apr 27;12:587122. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2021.587122. eCollection 2021.</citation>
    <PMID>33986697</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rief, W., Nestoriuc, Y., Mueller, E. M., Hermann, C., Schmidt, K., &amp; Bingel, U. Generic rating scale for previous treatment experiences, treatment expectations, and treatment effects (GEEE). PsychArchives. 2021 https://doi.org/10.23668/PSYCHARCHIVES.4717</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pan Y, Meister R, Löwe B, Kaptchuk TJ, Buhling KJ, Nestoriuc Y. Open-label placebos for menopausal hot flushes: a randomized controlled trial. Sci Rep. 2020 Nov 18;10(1):20090. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-77255-z.</citation>
    <PMID>33208855</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bowers HM, Kendrick T, Glowacka M, Williams S, Leydon G, May C, Dowrick C, Moncrieff J, Laine R, Nestoriuc Y, Andersson G, Geraghty AWA. Supporting antidepressant discontinuation: the development and optimisation of a digital intervention for patients in UK primary care using a theory, evidence and person-based approach. BMJ Open. 2020 Mar 8;10(3):e032312. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2019-032312.</citation>
    <PMID>32152159</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Meister R, Lanio J, Fangmeier T, Härter M, Schramm E, Zobel I, Hautzinger M, Nestoriuc Y, Kriston L. Adverse events during a disorder-specific psychotherapy compared to a nonspecific psychotherapy in patients with chronic depression. J Clin Psychol. 2020 Jan;76(1):7-19. doi: 10.1002/jclp.22869. Epub 2019 Oct 1.</citation>
    <PMID>31576565</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shedden-Mora, M. C., Pan, Y., Heisig, S. R., von Blanckenburg, P., Rief, W., Witzel, I., Albert, U.-S., &amp; Nestoriuc, Y. Optimizing expectations about endocrine treatment for breast cancer: Results of the randomized controlled psy-breast trial. Clinical Psychology in Europe. 2020; 2(1), e2695.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pan Y, Meister R, Löwe B, Winkelmann A, Kaptchuk TJ, Buhling KJ, Nestoriuc Y. Non-concealed placebo treatment for menopausal hot flushes: Study protocol of a randomized-controlled trial. Trials. 2019 Aug 16;20(1):508. doi: 10.1186/s13063-019-3575-1.</citation>
    <PMID>31420050</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pan Y, Kinitz T, Stapic M, Nestoriuc Y. Minimizing Drug Adverse Events by Informing About the Nocebo Effect-An Experimental Study. Front Psychiatry. 2019 Jul 25;10:504. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00504. eCollection 2019.</citation>
    <PMID>31427995</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>N-of-1 trials</keyword>
  <keyword>open-label placebo</keyword>
  <keyword>discontinuation symptoms</keyword>
  <keyword>antidepressant medication</keyword>
  <keyword>expectation effects</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

