<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05059574</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>13092021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05059574</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Breast Crawling,Breastfeeding Success and Mothers' Attitudes to Feeding Their Babies</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Breast Crawling After Vaginal Delivery on Breastfeeding Success and Mothers' Attitudes to Feeding Their Babies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sakarya University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sakarya University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It has been clearly demonstrated by the literature that the way of initiation of&#xD;
      breastfeeding is highly correlated with the success and continuation of breastfeeding and the&#xD;
      level of breastfeeding intention. Crawling to the breast is the reflex of seeking the breast&#xD;
      by smelling the breastmilk of the newborn as the first form of breastfeeding. Although&#xD;
      crawling to the breast is a studied subject in the international literature, it has remained&#xD;
      only in the compilation stage in the national literature. The fact that research on breast&#xD;
      crawling has not yet been conducted in our country constitutes the original value of this&#xD;
      study. This study was planned to examine the effect of crawling to the breast after vaginal&#xD;
      delivery compared to biological breastfeeding on breastfeeding success and mothers' attitude&#xD;
      to feed their babies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Breastfeeding is one of the most effective ways to ensure child health and survival. Breast&#xD;
      milk is the ideal food for babies. It is safe and clean. It contains antibodies that help&#xD;
      protect against many common childhood diseases. Breast milk provides all the energy and&#xD;
      nutrients a baby needs in the first months of life. However, about 2 out of 3 babies cannot&#xD;
      be exclusively breastfed for the recommended 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      WHO and UNICEF,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  early start of breastfeeding within 1 hour after birth,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  exclusive breastfeeding for the first 6 months of life&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Providing nutritionally sufficient and safe complementary (solid) foods in the 6th&#xD;
           month, It recommends continuing breastfeeding up to 2 years of age. Early initiation of&#xD;
           breastfeeding within 1 hour after birth protects the newborn from infection and reduces&#xD;
           neonatal mortality. However, many infants and children do not receive optimal nutrition.&#xD;
           For example, only about 44% of infants aged 0-6 months worldwide were exclusively&#xD;
           breastfed during the 2015-2020 period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Breastfeeding Success The most important reason for breastfeeding failure is the inability to&#xD;
      start breastfeeding. For this reason, it is necessary to provide the necessary comfort of the&#xD;
      mother in order to ensure breastfeeding success. In order to initiate and maintain a&#xD;
      successful breastfeeding, mothers should be educated about being physically and mentally&#xD;
      healthy, have a balanced diet, and be able to give breast milk with the right technique&#xD;
      during pregnancy and the period following birth. Many mothers need help, especially when&#xD;
      starting to breastfeed their first baby. A good start to breastfeeding affects the mother's&#xD;
      determination to continue breastfeeding. However, difficulties encountered in breastfeeding&#xD;
      during this period may lead to anxiety, causing mothers to lose their self-confidence and&#xD;
      thus to a decrease in breastfeeding. Therefore, if the mother and baby are suitable, it is&#xD;
      very important to initiate the first breastfeeding in this period called the 1st Stage (1st&#xD;
      Reactive Period) after the birth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Odent talked about the ability of a newborn to search for the breast for &quot;that important&#xD;
      first sucking action&quot; within the first hour of opening his eyes to the world and to use the&#xD;
      search reflex to find it. Widström et al. Crawling to the breast is defined as an organized,&#xD;
      spontaneous behavior sequence of newborns to seek and move towards the nipple and initiate&#xD;
      breastfeeding. In order to find the breast, newborns first use the stepping reflex to climb&#xD;
      into the mother's belly, and then the search reflex to find the nipple, catch and suck. This&#xD;
      is called newborn attachment or crawling to the breast. They stated that this behavior of the&#xD;
      newborn can be observed in its most intact form within the first few hours of its birth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study was planned as a randomized controlled and experimental study in order to evaluate&#xD;
      the effect of crawling on the breast after vaginal delivery on breastfeeding success and&#xD;
      mothers' attitude to feed their babies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Women who had vaginal delivery between October 2021 and April 2022 in the delivery room of&#xD;
      S.B.Ü Darıca Farabi Training and Research Hospital will be included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The population of the research will be women who gave vaginal birth in the delivery room of&#xD;
      S.B.Ü Darıca Farabi Training and Research Hospital between T October 2021 and April 2022, and&#xD;
      the sample will be 68 women (34 control/34 experiment-intervention).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>While crawling to the breast is tried in the experimental group, biological breastfeeding will be applied in the control group.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Since there is no placebo group, masking will not be done.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Breastfeeding success measurement</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Determining the success of breastfeeding by getting a higher score on the LATCH Breastfeeding Diagnostic Scale in the experimental group, in which the first breast-feeding was applied by crawling to the breast compared to the control group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Measuring mothers' feeding attitudes of their babies</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>In the experimental group in which the first breast-feeding was applied by crawling to the breast, the mothers' milk feeding behavior increased by getting a higher score on the &quot;The Iowa Infant Feeding Attitude Scale&quot; compared to the control group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">68</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Feeding</condition>
  <condition>Feeding Behavior</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Mothers in this group will begin their baby's first breastfeeding by crawling to the breast.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Mothers in this group will begin their baby's first breastfeeding with biological breastfeeding.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Breast Crawling</intervention_name>
    <description>The mother's first breast-feeding of her baby is not routine biological breast-feeding, but as a cradle to the breast.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Volunteer to participate in the research,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vaginal birth,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Over 18 years old,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to read and write&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Can speak Turkish,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having a full-term and healthy birth (38-42 weeks old, born 2500-4000gr, born with a&#xD;
             5th minute apgar of 7 and above, no known congenital disease),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Does not have a disease that prevents breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not voluntarily to participate in the research,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cesarean delivery,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having a health problem in which the mother or baby is at risk,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who have a disease that prevents breastfeeding.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kevser Özdemir, Dr</last_name>
    <phone>+90 264 295 66 24</phone>
    <email>kevserozdemir@sakarya.edu.tr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sakarya University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sakarya</city>
        <zip>54050</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kevser Özdemir, Dr</last_name>
      <phone>+90 264 295 66 24</phone>
      <email>kevserozdemir@sakarya.edu.tr</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Kevser Çimen</last_name>
      <phone>90 534 944 31 96</phone>
      <email>kvsrcmn1@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hym C, Forma V, Anderson DI, Provasi J, Granjon L, Huet V, Carpe E, Teulier C, Durand K, Schaal B, Barbu-Roth M. Newborn crawling and rooting in response to maternal breast odor. Dev Sci. 2021 May;24(3):e13061. doi: 10.1111/desc.13061. Epub 2020 Dec 5.</citation>
    <PMID>33174352</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Henderson A. Understanding the breast crawl: implications for nursing practice. Nurs Womens Health. 2011 Aug-Sep;15(4):296-307. doi: 10.1111/j.1751-486X.2011.01650.x.</citation>
    <PMID>21884495</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Heidarzadeh M, Hakimi S, Habibelahi A, Mohammadi M, Shahrak SP. Comparison of Breast Crawl Between Infants Delivered by Vaginal Delivery and Cesarean Section. Breastfeed Med. 2016 Aug;11(6):305-308. Epub 2016 May 12.</citation>
    <PMID>27171469</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sakarya University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Kevser Ozdemir</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PhD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Breast Crawling</keyword>
  <keyword>Vaginal Delivery</keyword>
  <keyword>Breastfeeding Success</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The follow-up of the study data will be provided by both researchers.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The data will be kept by the researchers until the study is reported. After the study is published, it will contribute to the literature.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>After the study is reported and published, it will be shared.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

