<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05057741</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CEI DVO005 1567-CV1324</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>B- 17-2020</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05057741</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Surgical Prehabilitation in Abdominal Surgery</brief_title>
  <acronym>SPAS</acronym>
  <official_title>Surgical Prehabilitation of Patients Taken to Major Gastrointestinal Surgery.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universidad del Rosario</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital Universitario Mayor Mederi</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universidad del Rosario</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Randomized clinical trial evaluating changes in functional capacity, postoperative&#xD;
      complications and 30-day mortality in patients over 65 years of age undergoing major&#xD;
      gastrointestinal surgery who participate in a multimodal prehabilitation program, compared to&#xD;
      non-prehabilitated patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction: A surgical procedure can have repercussions on the functionality and quality of&#xD;
      life of patients, reducing their functional capacity by up to 40%; poor preoperative physical&#xD;
      performance increases the risk of perioperative morbidity and mortality by 30% (1) and&#xD;
      prolongs functional recovery (2), increasing the hospital stay of the older adult.&#xD;
      Prehabilitation is a preoperative intervention that improves the physical, psychological and&#xD;
      nutritional condition of the patient to obtain a better postoperative recovery (3), mobility&#xD;
      and functional independence (4).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: To evaluate changes in functional capacity, postoperative complications and 30-day&#xD;
      mortality in patients over 65 years of age undergoing major gastrointestinal surgery who&#xD;
      participate in a multimodal prehabilitation program (exercise, nutrition and relaxation).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology: Randomized clinical trial. Two study groups will be compared, an experimental&#xD;
      group that will receive the educational intervention (multimodal prehabilitation program) and&#xD;
      a control group that will continue with the usual management in the Hospital. The project&#xD;
      activities will be carried out in Telehealth modality due to Covid 19 contagion containment&#xD;
      measures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Expected results: To encourage interprofessional work based on common goals with&#xD;
      standardization of data and processes to improve physical condition and reduce post-surgical&#xD;
      complications; to establish traceability of care, clinical and functional condition of the&#xD;
      patient. It is intended to generate scientific evidence, integrate the research groups&#xD;
      Méderi, Rehabilitation Sciences and Clinical Research.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A randomized clinical trial will be performed. Two study groups will be compared, an experimental group that will receive the educational intervention (multimodal prehabilitation program) and a control group that will continue with the usual management in the Hospital. The project activities will be carried out in Telehealth modality. When the patient accepts to participate in the study and signs the informed consent, he/she will be evaluated by nutrition and physiotherapy. After the initial evaluation that confirms the selection criteria, the patient will be randomly assigned to the study groups, by means of closed envelopes / file / image that will be chosen by the patient.&#xD;
The evaluators of the initial and final conditions of the patients will not know the group to which each patient entering the study has been assigned. The study will be conducted following good clinical practice. The estimated duration of recruitment is eleven months.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>functional capacity</measure>
    <time_frame>One to six weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in the maximum capacity to carry and use oxygen measured with the 2-minute stationary gait test (2MSG)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>postoperative complications</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Presence of morbidities, whether or not requiring hospital readmission, generated by the surgical procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">104</enrollment>
  <condition>Older People</condition>
  <condition>Prehabilitation</condition>
  <condition>Surgical Procedure</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>B-17E</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Multimodal prehabilitation: exercise, nutrition and relaxation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>B-17C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Usual care group: advice of surgeons about self care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Multimodal prehabilitation</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients who will receive a multimodal prehabilitation program consisting of guided self-care activities at home that include exercise, nutrition and relaxation. Information Will be share by e health. Monitored by telephone daily during the first week and three times a week between the second and fourth week.&#xD;
The final evaluation of the program will be performed one working day after the control appointment with surgery, which will be scheduled ten days after hospital discharge; and the satisfaction survey will be applied. At 30 days after surgery, a telephone follow-up will be made to inquire about complications and mortality. On that day, self-care recommendations will be given.</description>
    <arm_group_label>B-17E</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Experimental group</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients scheduled by the General Surgery, Coloproctology and Hepatobiliary Surgery&#xD;
             services with cognitive ability to follow instructions, understand the material&#xD;
             delivered (basic reading comprehension - through physical or digital media) and&#xD;
             perform physical exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Aptitude to exercise according to the cardiovascular risk assessment performed by the&#xD;
        treating physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients scheduled for surgery from the emergency department Patients with sepsis,&#xD;
             with metastatic disease, with dysphagia Patients with incapacitating psychiatric or&#xD;
             neurological illnesses Patients with documented previous immunosuppression status&#xD;
             (corticosteroid users) and/or HIV Patients on home hospitalization plans Diabetic&#xD;
             patients, with renal failure, with heart failure, with independent mobility&#xD;
             restrictions, with history of second primary neoplasm&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 15, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>surgical procedure</keyword>
  <keyword>exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>nutritional</keyword>
  <keyword>functional condition</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

