<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05051111</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21054586</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05051111</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pre-stroke Physical Activity in Patients With Stroke</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pre-stroke Physical Activity in Patients With Stroke</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Herlev Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Herlev Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to explore the level of pre-stroke physical activity in patients&#xD;
      with stroke and to investigate associations between physical activity and sociodemographic&#xD;
      variables, e.g. history of stroke, co-morbidities and subtype of stroke.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical inactivity is a great risk factor for stroke; thus, the investigators hypothesise&#xD;
      that patients hospitalised with stroke will present with a lower level of pre-stroke physical&#xD;
      activity than recommended by World Health Organization (WHO) guidelines on physical activity&#xD;
      for health. Additionally, the investigators expect to find an association between pre-stroke&#xD;
      physical activity and specific sociodemographic variables, e.g. stroke subtype, and&#xD;
      re-stroke.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Physical inactivity and low cardiorespiratory fitness are important risk factors for stroke.&#xD;
      To design future secondary non-pharmacological prevention strategies in stroke, detailed&#xD;
      information on current level of physical activity is essential.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the Danish adult population, 28,8% do not adhere to the WHO guidelines on physical&#xD;
      activity for health, with an increasing number (33%) in the population older than 55 years of&#xD;
      age. Diverging results have been given on level of physical activity in patients with stroke&#xD;
      which warrants further investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistics: Descriptive statistics will be used to characterise the study population. To&#xD;
      evaluate whether the participants adhere to recommendations on physical activity the&#xD;
      proportion of participants adhering will be estimated. To evaluate the association between&#xD;
      pre-stroke physical activity using MET-values (dependent variable) and sociodemographic&#xD;
      variables (age, gender, previous event of stroke, subtypes of stroke, cardiovascular risk&#xD;
      factors, living status and educational level) a multiple linear regression analysis will be&#xD;
      performed. The aim is to include 120 participants in the multiple linear regression analyses.&#xD;
      This is based on the number of variables (a maximum of seven). p &lt; 0.05 will be used as level&#xD;
      of statistical significance. All tests will be two-sided. Data will be analysed using&#xD;
      Microsoft Excel 2019 and Stata 17.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 23, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical Activity</measure>
    <time_frame>The measurement will be performed between day 1 and day 7 of hospitalisation. The questionnaire evaluate the participants´ habitual physical activity level two weeks prior to hospitalisation.</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by a self-reported questionnaire, the Physical Activity Scale (PAS2), consisting of nine questions: Six measuring daily hours and minutes of sleep, work (sitting down, standing/walking and heavy physical activities), active transport and sedentary behaviour during leisure time, and three questions measuring weekly hours and minutes during leisure time at three intensities (light, moderate and vigorous)). Each question corresponds to a specific level of metabolic equivalent of task (MET). The total measurement will provide an estimation of a daily MET-score.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants will be enrolled consecutively during their hospitalisation for a stroke.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical symptoms of acute stroke, verified by a neurologist with diagnosis of stroke&#xD;
             (intracerebral haemorrhage, cerebral infarction, &quot;stroke, not specified as haemorrhage&#xD;
             or infarction&quot; or transient ischemic attack (TIA)).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute/subacute stroke or TIA verified on MRI-scan or CT-scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to speak, read and understand Danish.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide informed consent, including being awake, alert and oriented (personal&#xD;
             data, place, and time).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aphasia that hinders responding to the PAS2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive deficits that hinder responding to the PAS2 (Mini-Mental State&#xD;
             Examination-score (MMSE) ≤ 23, diagnosis of dementia at hospital admission).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christina Kruuse, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Herlev Gentofte Hospital, Dept. of Neurology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Christina Kruuse, Professor</last_name>
    <phone>+4538681233</phone>
    <email>christina.kruuse.01@regionh.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Rikke Steen Krawcyk, MSc, Phd</last_name>
    <phone>+4538686159</phone>
    <email>rikke.steen.krawcyk@regionh.dk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Herlev Gentofte Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Herlev</city>
        <zip>2730</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christina Kruuse, Professor</last_name>
      <phone>+4538681233</phone>
      <email>christina.kruuse@regionh.dk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Herlev Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Christina Kruuse</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor, Ph.d., MSci, MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Physical activity</keyword>
  <keyword>Stroke</keyword>
  <keyword>Questionnaire</keyword>
  <keyword>Patient reported outcome measure</keyword>
  <keyword>Inpatient</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

