<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05059145</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Chlorhex-KKDS-2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05059145</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Clinical Trial for Chlorhexidine as Treatment for Vulvovaginal Candidiasis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A RCT for Chlorhexidine Gluconate as Treatment and Prophylaxis for Recurrent Vulvovaginal Candidiasis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Karolinska Institutet</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Karolinska Institutet</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The overall aim of this study is to investigate if vaginally applied 1% chlorhexidine&#xD;
      gluconate (CHG) could be an alternative treatment to oral fluconazole (FLZ), both during an&#xD;
      acute episode and as prophylaxis, against recurrent infections of vulvovaginal candidiasis&#xD;
      (RVVC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      RVVC is very common in fertile women. Up to six months of treatment with FLZ is recommended&#xD;
      for RVVC. Over the last ten years, the use of FLZ has increased markedly in many countries.&#xD;
      No major problems have been noted with resistance development, but there is concern that this&#xD;
      will occur in the future and alternative treatments are requested. In recent years, it has&#xD;
      emerged that flukonazol interacts with several different types of drugs that are common in&#xD;
      the patient group; several antidepressants, pain relief at dysmenorrhea (NSAID) and oral&#xD;
      contraceptives to name a few.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Sweden an over-the-counter vaginal cream consisting of 1% chlorhexidine gluconate&#xD;
      (Hibitane®) is available with the indication antiseptic use in vaginal examinations,&#xD;
      especially during childbirth. The product has been used for a long time in various&#xD;
      gynecological and obstetric surgical procedures. Hibitane® is approved during pregnancy and&#xD;
      the cream is usually well tolerated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our research group has previously done an in vitro study in which we analyzed the effect of&#xD;
      FLZ and CHG's ability to kill fungal cells and to break down existing biofilm or prevent new&#xD;
      biofilm formation. The biofilm formation is an important stage for the fungal cells to attach&#xD;
      to surfaces such as skin and mucosa and is considered a first step in the development of an&#xD;
      infection. In the biofilm, the fungus can hide from the immune system and also to some extent&#xD;
      for various treatments aimed against the fungus. The results of the study showed that CHG was&#xD;
      better than FLZ both at killing the fungal cells and preventing new biofilm from forming and&#xD;
      dissolving already established &quot;old&quot; biofilm. This effect is absolutely crucial for&#xD;
      successful treatment with antimycotics. These encouraging results form the basis of the&#xD;
      planned study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If CHG is at least as effective as FLZ with little impact on vaginal lactobacillus, with high&#xD;
      tolerability and without cytotoxic effect on epithelial cells, the results of the study might&#xD;
      lead to major benefits to the patients with reduced risk of systemic side effects such as&#xD;
      drug interactions, development of drug resistance and reduced drug costs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is a 6 months clinical Phase II trial to compare if 1% chlorhexidine gluconate&#xD;
      vaginal cream (Hibitane®) is at least as effective and safe as fluconazole (reference&#xD;
      treatment) for culture-verified recurrent vulvovaginal candidiasis. The study is a randomized&#xD;
      open non-inferiority trial with parallel treatment groups. The trial is not possible to blind&#xD;
      for neither participants nor investigators due to the differences between study treatments.&#xD;
      There is low risk of bias since the primary outcome variable is objective (negative vaginal&#xD;
      culture for Candida albicans).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants will be randomization to;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Investigational medication with Hibitane® vaginal cream 8 ml every night for a week and&#xD;
           then prophylactic treatment with 8 ml/week for another 11 weeks or&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Reference treatment with Fluconazole® 150 mg (oral capsule) every 3 days for the first 3&#xD;
           doses, then prophylactic treatment with 150 mg/week for another 11 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The randomization ratio between the treatment groups will be 1:1. A computer generated block&#xD;
      randomization of 15 participants will be performed by the research midwife. Allocation to the&#xD;
      study medications will be carried out via opening of opaque sealed envelopes in consecutive&#xD;
      order. All women will be identified through a patient log with name and Swedish personal&#xD;
      identification number and the randomization number. The randomization number will be used on&#xD;
      all paper and CRFs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Five research visits are planned:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 1 Screening - oral and written study information, signing of informed consent, vaginal&#xD;
      culture for Candida albicans and chlamydia/gonorrhea (PCR test).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 2 Inclusion (baseline), within 1 week after Visit 1. Control for inclusion/exclusion&#xD;
      criteria, randomization to study medication after positive culture for Candida albicans and&#xD;
      negative chlamydia/gonorrhea (PCR test) - health survey, control of concomitant medications,&#xD;
      examination, pregnancy test and control of adequate contraceptive methods to avoid pregnancy&#xD;
      throughout the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 3 1 week (+2 days) after completed treatment. Control of AE, culture for Candida&#xD;
      albicans and examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 4 After 12 weeks (+ 1 week) from inclusion when prophylactic treatment is completed.&#xD;
      Control of AE and relapses, culture for Candida albicans and examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 5 Follow-up 6 months (+ 1-2 weeks) from baseline/inclusion. Control of AE and relapses,&#xD;
      culture for Candida albicans and examination. End of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A weekly web-based dairy (eCRF (Entermedic)) will be used for follow-up of treatment&#xD;
      compliance, efficacy and adverse events. During the prophylactic treatment (Visits 2-3) and&#xD;
      during the observational phase of the study (Visit 4-5), the participants are asked to report&#xD;
      any suspicious relapses in the dairy and contact the research midwife if needed. They will&#xD;
      also receive equipment for vaginal cultures that can be used for self-sampling at home to&#xD;
      detect true relapses. In case of positive cultures for Candida albicans, they will be offered&#xD;
      the same medication as previously used in the study if the treatment was effective and no&#xD;
      adverse events occurred. Otherwise, an individual treatment option will be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The end of study is defined as completion of the last visit of the last subject. The sponsor&#xD;
      and the investigators reserve the rights to discontinue the study at any time for safety&#xD;
      reasons or other reasons jeopardizing the justifications of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Supply, labelling, handling and storage:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chlorhexidine gluconate (Hibitane®) vaginal cream is commercially available in Sweden and&#xD;
      will be prescribed from the hospital pharmacy for each participant. It will be stored and&#xD;
      kept according to the instructions of the manufacturer.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants randomized to Hibitane® will receive a bottle (250ml) with the vaginal&#xD;
           cream together with 10 ml syringes for vaginal administration. The Hibitane® bottle can&#xD;
           be stored in the fridge at home between use. Women will receive specific written&#xD;
           information as well as oral information on how to self-administer drug vaginally with&#xD;
           the syringe.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants randomized to Fluconazole® will receive 14 oral capsules of 150 mg&#xD;
           according to the dosage describe above.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Compliance:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Compliance will be evaluated at the follow up visits and the participants will fill out a&#xD;
      dairy how the study medications have been taken.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection and data handling:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Every participant will be given an individual, study specific number (i.e. study identifying&#xD;
      code) at the time of inclusion. A code key with each individual personal data connected to&#xD;
      the identifying code will be created (i.e. patient identification log) and stored separately&#xD;
      at the research department at the department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Danderyd Hosptial,&#xD;
      Stockholm, Sweden.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be recorded on individual printed case report forms (CRFs) after which they will be&#xD;
      entered into a computerized database before statistical analyses. The database will contain&#xD;
      information on demographic variables, type of treatment and measurements in addition to the&#xD;
      variables above.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of women in each group that has cleared the vulvovaginal infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Negative vaginal culture for Candida albicans</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prophylactic effect</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of women with negativ vaginal culture for Candida albicans at follow ups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of women i each treatment arm repoting AEs</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom score</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion ov women with symptom score &gt;2 of composite index 0-5 (typical discharge, itching, dryness of the skin/mucosa, burning and pain)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Examination score</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion ov women with examination score &gt;2 of composite index 0-5 (redness skin/mucosa, typical discharge, dry skin/mucosa, fissures in skin/mucosa, visible candida hyphae in wet mount)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vaginal lactobacillus content</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of women with reduced vaginal lactobacilli content in vaginal smears measured by a semi-quantitative method as normal or reduced quantity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Infection relapse</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of women in each treatment arm with relapses of Candida albicans infection</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Candidiasis, Vulvovaginal</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Chlorhexidine gluconate, 1% vaginal cream</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>8 ml vaginal cream every night for a week and then prophylactic treatment with 8 ml/week for another 11 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fluconazole, 150 mg oral capsule</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Fluconazole150 mg (oral capsule) every 3 days for the first 3 doses, then prophylactic treatment with 150 mg/week for another 11 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Chlorhexidine Gluconate</intervention_name>
    <description>Vaginal cream 1%</description>
    <arm_group_label>Chlorhexidine gluconate, 1% vaginal cream</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Hibitane vaginal cream</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fluconazole</intervention_name>
    <description>150 mg oral capsule</description>
    <arm_group_label>Fluconazole, 150 mg oral capsule</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18-50 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of &gt; 2 candida infections the last year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptoms of acute vulvovaginal candida infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Culture verified infection with Candida albicans&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate contraceptive method&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to understand oral and written information in Swedish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has given written consent to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe somatic or mental illness (including liver and kidney failure and cardiac&#xD;
             disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunosuppressive medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other ongoing gynecological infections&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to fluconazole or chlorhexidine gluconate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Citalopram or other medication that might have impact on the QT interval (terfenadin,&#xD;
             cisaprid, astemizol, pimozid, kinidin, erythromycin, halofantrin, amiodaron)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation or recent participation (30 days) in a clinical study with an&#xD;
             investigational product. Previous participation in this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Cathrin Alvendal, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Karolinska Institutet</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nina Bohm-Starke, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+46812355000</phone>
    <email>nina.bohm-starke@sll.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Helen Fagraeus, Midwife</last_name>
    <phone>+46812355000</phone>
    <email>helen.fagraeus@sll.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Danderyd Hospital, Dep. of Obstetrics and Gynecology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stockholm</city>
        <zip>182 88</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Karolinska Institutet</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nina Bohm-Starke</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Recurrent vulvovaginal candidiasis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Candidiasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Candidiasis, Vulvovaginal</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chlorhexidine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Chlorhexidine gluconate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fluconazole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

