<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05058430</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IU12473</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05058430</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SaliPen Human Factors Study for OTC Labeling</brief_title>
  <acronym>SaliPen</acronym>
  <official_title>SaliPen Human Factors Study for OTC Labeling</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Saliwell Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Indiana University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Saliwell Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This Human Factors Validation Testing will assess user interactions to verify the capability&#xD;
      of potential users to assess if the study product fits their needs and if they can use it&#xD;
      correctly based on the provided Information For User (IFU)?&#xD;
&#xD;
      More specifically, this is a non-comparative case series study and is subdivided into two&#xD;
      major parts. Those parts are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Phase I: aimed at testing if, based on the IFU, the potential subjects can decide&#xD;
           whether the study product is or is not appropriate to treat their condition and,&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Phase II: aimed at assessing whether the users can use the study product correctly&#xD;
           without counseling by a health care provider.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Phase I To simulate an OTC setting, potential subjects will be requested to read the label&#xD;
      text on the outside of the study product package (external labeling) and determine whether&#xD;
      the study product addresses their needs, without a provider direction or assistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase II The study product will be dispensed only to those subjects who will indicate that&#xD;
      they voluntarize to participate in this phase of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Phase II subjects with xerostomia and that are willing to try the study product, will be&#xD;
      requested to use it with no training, except for their understanding of the User Manual&#xD;
      (internal labeling). Those subjects will use the study product in a supervised clinical&#xD;
      setting. Subjects who report any discomfort will be offered the option to pause and remove&#xD;
      the device upon such a request.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Correct use verification will be performed by the study investigators. Subjects will answer&#xD;
      questions regarding product use, clarity of the IFU, ease of use, etc. Subjects will also&#xD;
      receive an exam of their oral cavity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 16, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 15, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Single-center, prospective, open-label study.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants who appropriately will self-select the study product for use under simulated OTC conditions [Phase I]</measure>
    <time_frame>One hour</time_frame>
    <description>Following the standard norms for the Rx-to-OTC switch process, this outcome is a validation of potential consumers' ability to self-diagnose the condition and to decide that treatment with the product is appropriate for them.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants who correctly will use the study product when dispensed under simulated OTC conditions [Phase II].</measure>
    <time_frame>1.5 hour</time_frame>
    <description>Correct use means that the participants will demonstrate the use of the study product according to the guidelines outlined in the User Manual.&#xD;
Following the standard norms for the therapy of Rx-to-OTC switch process, this outcome is a validation of potential consumers' ability to self-treat with the product according to the product's supplied IFU.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Xerostomia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Human Factors</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The primary objective of this research is to assess the human factors in relabeling the SaliPen from a prescription-based device to an OTC.&#xD;
Primary performance endpoints:&#xD;
The user can select the device properly.&#xD;
The user can use the device as instructed in the IFU.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Electrical salivary stimulator system</intervention_name>
    <description>SaliPen is an electrical salivary stimulator system, intended to electrically stimulate a relative increase in saliva production. It is an intraoral device indicated for use in patients with xerostomia (dry mouth).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Human Factors</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For Phase I: 8 subjects with xerostomia and 8 without that are 18 years old or older For&#xD;
        Phase II: Subjects with xerostomia that are 18 years old or older&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For Phase I:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children and adolescents (persons under 18 years of age)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons with experience in the use of SaliPen&#xD;
&#xD;
        For Phase II: Subjects for them the study product is not indicated and/or do not agree to&#xD;
        participate in Phase II. For the avoidance of doubt, the following conditions are exclusion&#xD;
        criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons with experience in the use of SaliPen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children and adolescents (persons under 18 years of age)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Epileptic disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons that are allergic to the surface materials of the device&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Electrodes: coated with gold&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Body: made of methyl vinyl silicone rubber&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of a pacemaker&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric or psychological disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Involuntary muscle movement disorder (such as Parkinson's)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurologic disorder in head and neck area&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Susan Zunt, DDS, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Indiana University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Susan Zunt, DDS, MS</last_name>
    <phone>317-274-5250</phone>
    <email>szunt@iu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jennifer Tran</last_name>
    <phone>317-274-3306</phone>
    <email>jelbruce@iu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Indiana University School of Dentistry, Oral Health Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Xerostomia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

