<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00261105</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HMR3647A_4026</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00261105</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Telithromycin in Respiratory Tract Infections</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open, Multicenter, Non-comparative, Phase IV Trial of Efficacy and Safety of Ketek(Telithromycin) 800mg</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sanofi</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sanofi</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Primary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The primary objective of the study is to evaluate clinical efficacy i.e. to show that&#xD;
           with respect to clinical cure rate, Ketek® (telithromycin) in the treatment of community&#xD;
           acquired respiratory tract infections: community acquired pneumonia (CAP), acute&#xD;
           bacterial exacerbation of chronic bronchitis (AECB) and acute sinusitis (AS), in&#xD;
           outpatients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives are to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Further assess the efficacy of Ketek® (telithromycin) by considering the rate at which&#xD;
           additional antibacterials were prescribed to treat the primary infection; the rate of&#xD;
           hospitalisation due to a complication of the primary infection and assessment of&#xD;
           bacteriological data, chest X-ray and sinus X-ray if available.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Evaluate safety of Ketek® (telithromycin) through Adverse Event (AE) and Serious Adverse&#xD;
           Event (SAE) reporting&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2005</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2005</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Outcome (Global Assessment by the participating physicians)</measure>
    <time_frame>During the Study Conduct</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate at which additional antibacterials were prescribed to treat the primary infection</measure>
    <time_frame>During the study conduct</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of hospitalisation due to a complication of the primary infection</measure>
    <time_frame>During the study conduct</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of chest X-ray and sinus X-ray if available.</measure>
    <time_frame>During the study conduct</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Event (AE) and Serious Adverse Event (SAE) reported</measure>
    <time_frame>from the inform consent signed up to the end of the study</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <condition>Respiratory Tract Infections</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>telithromycin</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        General Conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Outpatients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fulfillment of clinical diagnostic criteria for one of the following indications:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Mild to moderate Community Acquired Pneumonia (CAP)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acute bacterial Exacerbation of Chronic Bronchitis (AECB)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acute Sinusitis (AS)&#xD;
&#xD;
        For CAP&#xD;
&#xD;
        The Criteria to be fulfilled are:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New onset of at least two of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cough&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Production of purulent sputum&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Auscultatory findings compatible with pneumonia, e.g. rales, evidence of&#xD;
                  pulmonary consolidation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Dyspnea or tachypnea&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fever&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Elevated total white blood cell count &gt; 10 000/mm3 or &gt;15% bands regardless of&#xD;
                  total count&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chest X-ray findings supporting a clinical diagnosis of bacterial pneumonia (e.g. new&#xD;
             infiltrate)&#xD;
&#xD;
        For AECB&#xD;
&#xD;
        The Criteria to be fulfilled are:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic bronchitis defined as cough and excessive sputum production for more than 2&#xD;
             consecutive years and on most days in a 3-month consecutive period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exacerbation defined by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Increase in sputum purulence, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Increase in sputum volume, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Increase in dyspnea&#xD;
&#xD;
        For AS&#xD;
&#xD;
        The criteria to be fulfilled are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        At least two of the major or one major and two minor factors listed below, for more than&#xD;
        one week and less than 4 weeks:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major factors:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Facial pressure and/or pain&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Facial congestion or fullness&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Nasal obstruction&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Nasal purulence or postnasal discharge&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hyposmia or anosmia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fever&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minor factors:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Headache&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Halitosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fatigue&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Dental pain&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cough&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ear pain, pressure or fullness&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        General Conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects presenting with any of the following will not be included in the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment required during the study with ergot alkaloid derivatives, pimozide,&#xD;
             astemizole, terfenadine, cisapride, simvastatin, atorvastatin and lovastatin, and the&#xD;
             oral use of the benzodiazepines midazolam, triazolam and alprazolam.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of congenital or family history of long QT syndrome (if not excluded by ECG)&#xD;
             or known acquired QT interval prolongation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to telithromycin or to macrolide antibiotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hospital acquired infections (hospitalization for more than 72 hours within 7 days of&#xD;
             study entry).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast-feeding women. For the women of childbearing potential it is left&#xD;
             to the investigators discretion to establish a lack of pregnancy, e.g. with&#xD;
             contraceptive use, menstrual pattern, urinary pregnancy test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with severely impaired renal function (creatinine clearance &lt;30 ml/min).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects that had received anti-bacterials for more than 24 hours within 7 days prior&#xD;
             to enrollment in the study, unless the treatment has failed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects receiving medications, including other anti-microbials or anti-cancer drugs,&#xD;
             that could interfere with the evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Microbiologically documented infection with a pathogen known prior to inclusion to be&#xD;
             resistant to the study medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infection, other than the primary infection for which the subject is being included in&#xD;
             the study that requires use of other systemic anti-bacterial drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Splenectomised subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of Ketek® (telithromycin) or participation in a study using Ketek® (telithromycin)&#xD;
             in the previous 30 calendar days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects that have received any investigational drug within 4 weeks of enrollment in&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No subject will be allowed to enroll in this study more than once.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For CAP&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional exclusion criteria are:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe pneumonia defined by any one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Judged as needing Intensive Care Unit admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Need of parenteral antibiotic treatment (if the attending physician wants to&#xD;
                  prescribe a parenteral treatment for adherence reasons or local prescription&#xD;
                  habits this is accepted, provided that the patient does not have a severe&#xD;
                  pneumonia).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acute respiratory failure or requirement for mechanical ventilation.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Altered mental status resulting from the infective process.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Resting respiratory rate &gt; 30 breaths/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chest X-ray showing increase in opacity by &gt; 50% within 48 hours of current&#xD;
                  evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total white blood cell count &lt; 4 000/mm3.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspiration pneumonia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pneumonia suspected to be non-bacterial (due to fungus or viral).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects suffering from severe bronchiectasis (production of more than 125 mL of&#xD;
             sputum/day), cystic fibrosis, active tuberculosis, pulmonary infarction or embolism,&#xD;
             bronchial obstruction, lung cancer or lung metastasis, lung abscess, extra-pulmonary&#xD;
             extension (like meningitis, septic arthritis, endocarditis).&#xD;
&#xD;
        For AECB&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional exclusion criteria are:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Need of parenteral antibiotic treatment (if the attending physician wants to prescribe&#xD;
             a parenteral treatment for adherence reasons or local prescription habits this is&#xD;
             accepted, provided that the patient does not have a severe infection).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute respiratory failure (respiratory distress, hypercarbia, worsening hypoxemia) or&#xD;
             requirement for mechanical ventilation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe bronchiectasis, cystic fibrosis, active tuberculosis, pulmonary infarction or&#xD;
             embolism, bronchial obstruction, lung cancer or lung metastasis, lung abscess.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For AS&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional exclusion criteria are:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Need of immediate surgery for the treatment of AS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic sinusitis (symptoms lasting more than 4 weeks).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recurrent sinusitis (4 or more episodes of sinusitis requiring antibiotic therapy in&#xD;
             the previous 12 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nosocomial acquired sinusitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cystic fibrosis, immotile cilia syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Obstructive lesions in nasopharynx (e.g. polyps, tumor).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of nasal, nasogastric or nasotracheal catheters.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Won-Sik Lee, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Sanofi</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>September 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 1, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 1, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 2, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 24, 2009</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 24, 2009</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">September 25, 2009</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Medical Affairs Study Director</name_title>
    <organization>sanofi-aventis</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Telithromycin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

