<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00261872</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>060004</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>06-AA-0004</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00261872</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment of Patients With Alcoholism and Attention Deficit Disorder</brief_title>
  <official_title>Treatment of Patients With Alcoholism and Attention Deficit Disorder</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study of persons with both alcoholism and ADHD will determine whether adding the drug&#xD;
      methylphenidate to a standard treatment program will decrease alcohol use. In approximately&#xD;
      half of patients with ADHD, symptoms persist into adulthood, and the untreated condition is&#xD;
      associated with a significantly increased incidence of substance use disorder. Also, more&#xD;
      than one-third of adults with substance use disorder have symptoms of ADHD. This study will&#xD;
      evaluate the effectiveness of adding methylphenidate to a standard alcohol treatment program&#xD;
      in improving patients' treatment compliance and decreasing adverse consequences of drinking,&#xD;
      as well as monitoring their attention deficit/hyperactivity symptoms,&#xD;
&#xD;
      People 21 to 65 years of age with alcoholism and attention deficit hyperactivity disorder&#xD;
      (ADHD) may be eligible for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants are randomly assigned to receive either slow-release methylphenidate (an&#xD;
      approved medication for ADHD) or placebo. All subjects participate in NIAAA's alcohol&#xD;
      treatment program, which includes a standardized 12-week behavioral therapy course and&#xD;
      treatment with naltrexone, a medication to prevent relapse. Patients are assessed once a week&#xD;
      with the standard NIAAA treatment evaluation battery, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Timeline Followback: A validated self-report method to assess a person's drinking over a&#xD;
           defined interval in time&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Addiction Severity Index: A validated interview that measures problem severity in seven&#xD;
           areas related to drug and alcohol abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Biomarkers for alcohol abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Conners Adult ADHD Rating Scale (a rating scale for ADHD symptoms and severity)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background: Several pharmacological therapies for relapse prevention in alcoholism have now&#xD;
      been documented for efficacy. A key issue that has emerged is the role of patient compliance&#xD;
      with medication in mediating efficacy. Psychological traits common among alcoholics interact&#xD;
      with treatment compliance. Thus, a considerable proportion of alcoholics, e.g. more than one&#xD;
      third of treatment seeking populations, display signs and symptoms of adult ADHD. The&#xD;
      impaired ability for long term planning and sustained goal-oriented behaviors in this group&#xD;
      is likely to impair compliance with pharmacological treatment, thus reducing its potential&#xD;
      beneficial effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Well documented pharmacological treatments are also available for ADHD. Among these,&#xD;
      methylphenidate has a strong documentation, and has been demonstrated to be as efficacious in&#xD;
      adult ADHD as in the childhood condition. A recently introduced slow release preparation of&#xD;
      methylphenidate appears to offer considerable advantages, in that it eliminates most of the&#xD;
      abuse potential, and allows once daily administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims: The aim of this study is to evaluate whether addition of methylphenidate to a state of&#xD;
      the art treatment program for alcohol dependence will improve clinically relevant treatment&#xD;
      outcomes such as validated measures of alcohol drinking.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: The hypothesis will be addressed in a 12 week randomized, placebo controlled double&#xD;
      blind add-on trial. Participation will be offered to subjects with alcohol dependence, aged&#xD;
      21-65 years, who enter the NIAAA alcohol treatment program, do not have any severe&#xD;
      psychiatric or physical morbidity, and meet criteria for adult ADHD. All patients who are&#xD;
      included will be given a standardized state of the art 12 week behavioral treatment package,&#xD;
      as well as naltexone, an approved medication for relapse prevention. In addition subjects&#xD;
      will be randomized to slow release methylphenidate or corresponding placebo. Patients will be&#xD;
      evaluated upon weekly visits using the standard NIAAA treatment evaluation battery TLFB, ASI,&#xD;
      biomarkers, as well as the established CAARS rating scale for attention deficit /&#xD;
      hyperactivity. Primary outcome will be measures of drinking obtained by the TLFB methodology.&#xD;
      Secondary outcomes will measures of attention deficit and hyperactivity, as measured by the&#xD;
      CAARS scores.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 1, 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date>April 9, 2007</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment>100</enrollment>
  <condition>Alcoholism</condition>
  <condition>Attention Deficit Disorder</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Methylphenidate</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Age 21 or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
        DSM-IV diagnosis of alcohol dependence or alcohol abuse on SCID, and alcohol problems as&#xD;
        primary complaint among SUD:s&#xD;
&#xD;
        DSM-IV diagnosis of ADHD on SCID, confirmed by CAARS-INV&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        General exclusion criteria for the NIAAA intramural treatment program:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. People who present with complicated medical problems requiring intensive medical or&#xD;
             diagnostic management, such as hypertensive emergency, serious GI bleeding, major&#xD;
             organ or body system dysfunction such as decompensated liver disease, renal failure,&#xD;
             myocardial ischemia, congestive heart failure or cerebrovascular disease, major&#xD;
             endocrine problems such as uncontrolled diabetes, pancreatic or thyroid disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. People who are infected with the Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Serious neuro-psychiatric conditions which impair judgment or cognitive function to an&#xD;
             extent that precludes them from providing informed consent or complying with&#xD;
             treatment, such as psychotic illness or severe dementia (incompetent individuals).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. People who are unlikely or unable to complete the treatment program because they&#xD;
             become or are likely to be incarcerated while on the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. People who are required to receive treatment by a court of law or who are&#xD;
             involuntarily committed to treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. People with uncontrolled hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. People with a history of withdrawal seizures&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study specific exlusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnancy or lactation (negative pregnancy test required)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Use of psychotropic medication (antidepressant, lithium, antipsychotic, anxiolytic,&#xD;
             antiepileptic) within last 4 weeks, except when given within the program as part of&#xD;
             medically supervised withdrawal. Use of these medications constitutes prima facie&#xD;
             evidence of general exclusion category 3 (above). Persons identified with psychiatric&#xD;
             conditions deemed exclusionary will be referred to community resources for inpatient&#xD;
             or outpatient treatment as indicated. Persons with acute psychiatric emergencies (e.g.&#xD;
             bipolar disorder, manic phase, significant depressive symptoms, or active suicidal&#xD;
             ideation) will be referred for immediate care to ensure safety and stabilization; such&#xD;
             actions will be appropriately documented.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Past DSM-IV diagnosis of dependence (but not abuse, or reported occasional use of)&#xD;
             drugs of abuse other than alcohol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Present DSM-IV diagnosis (but not sporadic use) of dependence on any central stimulant&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Present use of guanethidine or yohimbine&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Contraindications / warnings for naltrexone (in addition to those included in the&#xD;
             general exclusion criteria):&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. known supersensitivity to the drug&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. acute hepatitis (any transaminase great than 3 x upper normal interval limit)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. ongoing (within last month) use of opid analgesics, or illicit opiates&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Contraindications / warnings for methylphenidate (in addition to those included in the&#xD;
        general exclusion criteria):&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. known supersensitivity to the drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. marked anxiety, tension or agitation, since the drug may aggravate these symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. glaucoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. motor tics, or family history or diagnosis of Tourettes syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. history of seizures&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. hypertension, or known disease which can be aggravated by an elevation of blood&#xD;
             pressure or increased pulse rate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>COMBINE Study Research Group. Testing combined pharmacotherapies and behavioral interventions for alcohol dependence (the COMBINE study): a pilot feasibility study. Alcohol Clin Exp Res. 2003 Jul;27(7):1123-31.</citation>
    <PMID>12878918</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 9, 2007</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 3, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 2, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 5, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Alcoholism</keyword>
  <keyword>Attention Deficit Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>ADHD</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Methylphenidate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

