<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00268814</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ZIS-HV9-0701</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00268814</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The German Project of Heroin Assisted Treatment of Opiate Dependent Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase III Study of Maintenance Treatment for Opiate Dependence With Heroin (Diamorphine) Compared to Methadone</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Federal Ministry of Health, Germany</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>State of Northrhine-Westfalia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>State of Hessen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>State of Lower-Saxony</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>City of Hamburg</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>City of Hanover</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>City of Frankfurt</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>City of Bonn</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>City of Cologne</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>City of Munich</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study will test the hypotheses that heroin assisted treatment, compared to methadone&#xD;
      maintenance treatment, is more effective with regard to&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the improvement of health,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  reduction of illicit drug consumption,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  decrease of criminal behaviour,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  rise in the accessibility and retainment,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  detachment from a social drug context,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  social stabilisation in the sense of new drug-free contacts, improved vocational&#xD;
           circumstances, financial security, stabilisation of the living situation,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  enrollment in subsequent treatment in the case of heroin dependent persons who could not&#xD;
           be effectively reached or successfully treated so far, and it will check which is the&#xD;
           optimal treatment setting with regard to these aims.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The medication is injectable pure heroin (diacetylmorphine) 3x/d, or d l methadone 1x/d&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study design is multicentre, open, randomised, 4 x 2 stratified. The study duration is 24&#xD;
      months (individual period of investigation), 1. study phase: 12 moths (protocol part B) and&#xD;
      2. study phase: 12 moths (part C). Patients recruited have an opiate dependency according to&#xD;
      ICD-10, who are not being treated currently or who are in a methadone maintenance programme&#xD;
      with an unsatisfactory course of treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Detailed description of study phase 1 (randomized, controlled part of study) only.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part B - Study phase 1 B1.1 Clinical hypothesis Compared to maintenance with oral methadone,&#xD;
      heroin treatment leads to&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  significant improvement of the physical and/or mental state of health,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  greater reduction of illicit drug use and therefore greater detachment from the drug&#xD;
           scene,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  significant improvement of the social situation,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  higher retention rate or attachment to treatment, in the case of those heroin dependent&#xD;
           persons who could not be effectively reached or could not sufficiently profit from&#xD;
           methadone maintenance programmes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B1.2 Primary outcome criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Improvement of the physical and mental state of health (A) AND&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Reduction of illicit heroin use and non-increase of cocaine use (B). B1.3 Secondary&#xD;
           outcome criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Retention rate&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Reduction of benzodiazepine, amphetamine, alcohol and other drug use&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Reduction of scene contacts / of contacts to other drug consumers&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Decrease of delinquent behaviour&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Stabilisation of housing situation&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Establishment of new social contacts&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Improvement of quality of life&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Mortality rate. B2. STUDY DESIGN Phase 1 of the clinical trial consists in a 4 x&#xD;
           2-branched randomised multicentre study. The sample is stratified and consists on the&#xD;
           one hand of heroin dependent persons in methadone maintenance treatment that do not&#xD;
           sufficiently profit from treatment (MS), and on the other hand of heroin dependent&#xD;
           persons who are currently not being treated for their addiction (NE). Patients of both&#xD;
           target groups who meet the admission criteria will be randomised to four arms:&#xD;
           experimental groups (MS-E-C) and (NE-E-C): heroin treatment with concurrent case&#xD;
           management, experimental groups (MS-E-P) and (NE-E-P): heroin treatment with concurrent&#xD;
           psychoeducation/drug counseling and control groups (MS-K-C) and (NE-K-C): methadone&#xD;
           treatment with concurrent case management, control groups (MS-K-P) and (NE-K-P):&#xD;
           methadone treatment with concurrent psychoeducation/drug counseling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B2.2 Recruitment of patients The period of registration is not part of the individual study&#xD;
      period. A screening is carried out at registration concerning certain inclusion criteria. The&#xD;
      patients are given the opportunity of a thorough information concerning the conditions and&#xD;
      course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      First of all, patients are asked to sign their consent to participate in the study. This is&#xD;
      followed by the indication assessment (T-1) by the study physician and the external interview&#xD;
      (EuropASI). Certain (particularly medical) characteristics are again examined at the&#xD;
      beginning of treatment (T0).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The regionally responsible study physician will decide on the inclusion in the study. His&#xD;
      decision needs the confirmation of a regional committee of experts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B2.3 Randomisation The allocation to treatment places of the experimental or control group is&#xD;
      carried out according to a randomisation code. Randomisation is done separately for both&#xD;
      groups (MS and NE) based on permuted blocks of fixed size.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the evaluation of the indication assessment and the first interview (at T-1), patients&#xD;
      who have been recruited and who fulfil the inclusion criteria are then asked to give a second&#xD;
      consent of participation in the study, and the results of randomisation will be communicated&#xD;
      to them.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B2.4 Course of the study, examinations and times of the investigations The first phase of the&#xD;
      clinical trial covers a period of 12 months. All questioning is done in a personal interview&#xD;
      (&quot;face to face&quot;) with the assurance that all information will be confidential.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients who take part in the interviews receive an expense allowance of Euro 15.- for&#xD;
      each survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A hair sample is already taken at the indication examination (T-1). This allows taking a hair&#xD;
      sample fit for analysis at the beginning of treatment (T0) from those patients whose hair was&#xD;
      too short at T-1. The CIDI will be carried out after one month of treatment in order to&#xD;
      minimise initial influences requiring treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to determine the use of illicit heroin, which is a main target criterion, five urine&#xD;
      controls will be thoroughly examined by GC/MS both in the 6th and the 12th month of&#xD;
      treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B3. PATIENTS The adequate treatment of the questions posed by this study requires a number of&#xD;
      at least 140 patients in each test group (4 experimental and 4 control groups). Therefore,&#xD;
      the sample size for the entire study will be N=1,120.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B3.1 Inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who fulfil following criteria can be included in the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Minimum age 23 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Opiate dependence for at least 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Current main diagnosis of opiate dependency according to the ICD-10 criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Current daily and predominantly intravenous heroin use or continuing heroin use in&#xD;
           maintenance treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Symptoms of physical illness indicating a poor state of health according to the OTI&#xD;
           health scale; at least 13 current symptoms must be found OR Current mental symptoms or&#xD;
           disturbances, i.e. a standardised GSI value of the SCL-90-R of at least 60 points&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  No participation in an addiction treatment programme (a.a. maintenance, inpatient or&#xD;
           outpatient treatment) at least within the last 6 months, but documented previous&#xD;
           experience with drug therapies OR Negative course of maintenance treatment according to&#xD;
           the guidelines of the German Medical Council due to (a) continuous additional use of&#xD;
           heroin (50% of the urine samples positive within the last 6 months) or cocaine (harmful&#xD;
           use of cocaine/crack according to ICD-10) in a documented maintenance period of at least&#xD;
           6 months with a current maintenance dose of at least 60 mg d l methadone (or 30 mg&#xD;
           levomethadone) daily&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Residence in the city (or city state) or region for at least 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Voluntary participation and ability to comply with the treatment conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Written consent to comply with the treatment conditions. B3.2 Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
      Persons with at least one of the following criteria cannot be included in the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Persons who are currently in prison or awaiting trial or who can be expected to be taken&#xD;
           into custody within the next 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Persons who had voluntary phases of abstinence of at least 2 months during the last 12&#xD;
           months&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Known epilepsy or generalised convulsions during the last 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hypersensitivity to test substances and additives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Regular intake of MAO inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Serious bronchial asthma, COPD, Cor pulmonale&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Serious cardiac arrhythmia&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Prostatic hypertrophy (with urinary retention)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Urethral stricture&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Life threatening liver disorders (exogenous hepatic coma)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Serious renal disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Insulin dependent diabetes mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Diagnosed malignancies during the last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pregnant women or nursing mothers&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients unable to comply with the study conditions, i.e. participation in the&#xD;
           therapeutic and scientific programmes, due to serious physical or mental illness&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients who are currently participating in another clinical study concerned with the&#xD;
           evaluation of an addiction treatment programme.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B3.3 Dropping out of treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation in the study is voluntary i.e. the patient can withdraw his consent to be&#xD;
      treated (and to further participation in the study) at any time. Patients having at least one&#xD;
      of the following characteristics are removed from treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients suffering from serious somatic complications in connection with heroin or&#xD;
           methadone treatment for whom a continuation of treatment would be irresponsible in the&#xD;
           opinion of the test study physician and the safety board&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with abnormally changed laboratory values for whom a continuation of treatment&#xD;
           would incur great health risks according to the safety board's decision&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients who have not turned up at the treatment centre or who have discontinued the&#xD;
           study medication for a period of 14 days (or longer) for self-provoked reasons or&#xD;
           without giving reasons&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients who are taken into custody for one month or longer&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Heroin patients whose treatment must be discontinued for more than 3 months due to&#xD;
           hospitalisation or other special treatments&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients who, in the opinion of the study physician, cannot or do not want to comply&#xD;
           with the conditions of the model project any longer, i.e. participation in the&#xD;
           therapeutic and scientific programme&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In case of violence, threat of violence against persons involved in the project or other&#xD;
           patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In case of drug trafficking on the premises of the model project&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In case of theft, passing on or sale of prescribed substances. B4. TREATMENT B4.1&#xD;
           Treatment setting Patients will be treated in an outpatient clinic. The setting is based&#xD;
           on at least weekly contacts to the treating physician. Detailed physical examinations&#xD;
           and blood counts (10 ml for each withdrawal) take place at the start of treatment and&#xD;
           after 1, 3, 6 and 12 months. There will be weekly urine analyses (qualitative proofs).&#xD;
           In addition, a hair sample will be taken from an inconspicuous place at the back of the&#xD;
           head at the beginning of treatment (at admission), after 6 months and at the examination&#xD;
           after 12 months. Patients under the influence of alcohol, barbiturates or&#xD;
           benzodiazepines can be refused their heroin or methadone dose. If excessive alcohol&#xD;
           consumption is suspected (smell of alcohol) a breath test is undertaken. If the breath&#xD;
           test is above 0.1, heroin or methadone will be refused.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B4.3 Dose regimen Heroin (in combination with methadone) An additional medication of d-1&#xD;
      methadone at night will be offered from the start, i.e. on the second day of treatment at the&#xD;
      earliest. The administration of heroin will occur up to 3 times a day during the opening&#xD;
      hours of the setting, in the morning, at noon and in the evening. In accordance with the&#xD;
      Swiss and Dutch studies, the maximum daily dose of i.v. heroin will be 1,000 mg, the single&#xD;
      dose 400 mg. If methadone is claimed at night, it can be taken on the premises during the&#xD;
      evening opening hours or taken out as a drinkable, not injectable single dose. The daily&#xD;
      maximum dose of additionally prescribed d,l methadone should not exceed 60 mg. Methadone&#xD;
      consumption will be controlled by regular urine analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Heroin will be handed out as injectable single doses (in filled syringes) and administered by&#xD;
      the patient himself under observation. Patients should stay in the centre for at least 30&#xD;
      minutes after the injection, in order to control for possible unwanted effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The different dose regimens (dose regulation at the beginning of treatment or after&#xD;
      interruptions starting from different points, fading out in case of (un-)planned treatment&#xD;
      conclusions) are based on methadone daily equivalence doses (MTQ). According to the basic&#xD;
      rule of the different dose regimens, an individual dose of i.v. heroin for one day, alone or&#xD;
      in combination with oral methadone, must not exceed the MTQ of the previous day by more than&#xD;
      50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methadone Oral methadone will be administered once a day. It is taken on the premises under&#xD;
      observation as drinkable, not injectable single dose. There is no fixed maximum daily dose;&#xD;
      according to experience, dosages between 40 and 160 mg/d of methadone (in individual cases up&#xD;
      to 250 mg/d) must be expected. A 1% methadone HCL solution is recommended.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dose regimen at the conclusion of treatment The conclusion of treatment is done by a&#xD;
      step-by-step discontinuation of i.v. heroin or change to oral methadone. The discontinuation&#xD;
      of medication (i.v. heroin alone or in combination with methadone) will be done slowly.&#xD;
      Preferably, the reduction should not be more than 10%-20% of the MTQ of the previous day. In&#xD;
      most cases discontinuation can be completed within 2 weeks. Possible withdrawal symptoms can&#xD;
      be treated by concomitant medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B5. VARIABLES B5.1 General patient characteristics General and specific sample&#xD;
      characteristics such as gender, age, length of opiate dependency, number of previous&#xD;
      treatments, current social situation are documented.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B5.2 Medical examination and prescription data, laboratory parameters The daily amounts of&#xD;
      heroin or methadone handed out are registered and all further prescriptions are documented.&#xD;
      Medical examinations are documented in the CRF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B5.3 Pharmacokinetics Since pharmacokinetics, the analgetic effects, the tolerance effects&#xD;
      and the addiction potential of heroin are well known and new findings are not to be expected&#xD;
      within the framework of this study, the study focuses mainly on questions concerning the&#xD;
      effects and safety of medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B5.4 Efficacy Primary outcome variables Efficacy is investigated with regard to two primary&#xD;
      outcome measures - improvement of the state of health (A) and reduction of illicit drug&#xD;
      consumption (B). These criteria will be evaluated independently by the statistical&#xD;
      comparative analysis; the success of one treatment in comparison to the other treatment is&#xD;
      only proven, if both analyses have significant results pointing in the same direction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      State of health (A)&#xD;
&#xD;
      A1. Physical state of health:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Number of symptoms according to the health scale of the Opiate Treatment Index OTI at T 1 and&#xD;
      T12.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VA1n = OTI-Health Scale (0 ≤ VA1n ≤ 50).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A2. Mental state of health:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Global Severity Index GSI of the SCL-90-R at T 1 and T12. VA2n = GSI value (0 ≤ VA2n ≤ 4).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The treatment response concerning the improvement of the state of health is given, if one of&#xD;
      the two criteria (VA1 or VA2) shows an improvement and the other criteria shows no&#xD;
      aggravation. Improvement and aggravation are defined as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  For the physical state of health (VA1): An improvement is indicated by a decrease on the&#xD;
           OTI health scale by at least 20% and at least 4 points if T12 is compared with T-1, an&#xD;
           aggravation is an increase of at least 20%.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  For the mental state of health (VA2): An improvement is indicated by a decrease of the&#xD;
           GSI value by at least 20% if T12 is compared with T-1, an aggravation is an increase of&#xD;
           at least 20%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Illicit drug consumption (B)&#xD;
&#xD;
      B1. Use of illicit heroin:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Number of illicit heroin-positive urine analyses during the 12 months of treatment, i.e.&#xD;
      among the last 5 urine samples before T12.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VB1n = number of positive urine samples (0 ≤ VB1 ≤ 5). If the patient has dropped out of&#xD;
      treatment, and results at T12 are missing and the LOCF procedure is not possible because of&#xD;
      missing urine samples in the 6th month of treatment, but if at least one follow-up has&#xD;
      occurred within the ITT method, the patient's self-reported data on use of illicit heroin&#xD;
      (physician-CRF) will be used. If these are also missing, self-reported data from the external&#xD;
      interview can be used. This will be based on the number of days with illicit heroin&#xD;
      consumption during the last 30 days (VB1') before the corresponding time of investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VB1'n = number of illicit heroin consumption days (0 ≤ VB1' ≤ 30).&#xD;
&#xD;
      B2. Cocaine use:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cocaine concentration of hair based on hair analyses (HAs) at T-1 and T12 within following&#xD;
      proof limits:&#xD;
&#xD;
      VB2 n = cocaine concentration (VB2 n ≥ 1 μg/g). If the patient has dropped out of treatment,&#xD;
      if results at T12 are missing and the LOCF procedure is not possible because of missing HA at&#xD;
      T6, but if at least one follow-up has occurred within the ITT method, the patient's&#xD;
      self-reported data on cocaine consumption (physician-CRF) will be used. If these are also&#xD;
      missing, self-reported data from the external interview can be used. This will be based on&#xD;
      the number of days with cocaine use during the last 30 days (VB2') before the corresponding&#xD;
      time of investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VB2'n = number of cocaine consumption days (0 ≤ VB2' ≤ 30). HA does not represent the&#xD;
      frequency but the integral intensity within the (past) period of observation assuming an&#xD;
      average hair growth of 10 mm per month. The lower limit of proof is assumed to be 1μg/g. An&#xD;
      increase of cocaine consumption can be accurately proven, if the value at T12 has increased&#xD;
      by 30% in comparison to T-1. (If the hair is too short - less than 1.5 cm - to take a sample&#xD;
      at T-1, it will be done at T0.)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Decrease and non-increase of consumption are defined as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A decrease of illicit heroin use is assumed to be proven, if not more than 2 of the 5&#xD;
           urine samples tested by GC/MS by the 12th month of treatment are positive. If only 4&#xD;
           urine samples are available by the 12th month of treatment, only one urine sample may be&#xD;
           positive to illicit heroin. If only 3 urine samples are available, none may be positive&#xD;
           to illicit heroin in order to be rated as response. If fewer urine samples are available&#xD;
           by the 12th month of treatment, the analyses at the 6th month will be used (LOCF),&#xD;
           proceeding according to the same evaluation pattern. Only if no usable urine analyses of&#xD;
           the 6th month of treatment exist, the patient's self-report will be used (VB1'). A&#xD;
           reduction of illicit heroin consumption of at least 60% between T-1 and T12 in relation&#xD;
           to the number of consumption days during the last 30 days is rated as a response.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The non-increase of cocaine use is proven by the (provable) cocaine concentration in the&#xD;
           hair. If a HA cannot be carried out at T12, the hair sample at T6 will be used (LOCF).&#xD;
           Only if a usable HA is neither available at T6 (due to a premature discontinuation of&#xD;
           treatment), the patient's self report (VB2') will be used. A decrease or no change (with&#xD;
           a tolerance of ± 2 days) of the number of consumption days within the last 30 days&#xD;
           between T-1 and T12 is rated as a response. I.e. an increase of the number of days with&#xD;
           cocaine consumption during the last month of not more than 2 days compared to T-1 is&#xD;
           still rated as a response; only an increase at T12 by more than 2 days is rated as&#xD;
           non-response.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It has to be assumed that a certain number of patients will prematurely (before initiation of&#xD;
      treatment or within the first 3 months) drop-out of treatment (in the case of methadone about&#xD;
      20% up to 40%, in the case of heroin 10%-20%), but that they can be reached again for the&#xD;
      examinations and investigations. These patients can be summoned for examination at the fixed&#xD;
      times, but 5 urine samples during the last month will not be available from them. These&#xD;
      patients without valid data are rated as non-responders in the heroin group and as &quot;worst&#xD;
      case&quot; responders in the methadone group. Thus, because a rather high percentage of dropouts&#xD;
      in the control group have to be expected, it would be hardly possible to prove the&#xD;
      su¬periority of the experimental treatment. In that case, the (negative) result of the study&#xD;
      would be caused by problems attributable to the implementation and measuring circumstances of&#xD;
      the target criteria so that the evaluation of changes cannot be carried out adequately. Under&#xD;
      the specified evaluation strategy, the procedure of measuring the consumption primary outcome&#xD;
      measures exclusively by objective methods cannot be maintained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If 5 urine samples are required within a defined period and 2 at most may be positive, a&#xD;
      deviation of this pattern (e.g. urine samples are missing or cannot be used, the patient does&#xD;
      not turn up any more) prevents that the primary outcome measures can be reliably investigated&#xD;
      and documented. If this happens at T12, a compensation with data at T6 is possible (LOCF). It&#xD;
      must be assumed, however, that dropouts occur most often during the first weeks, days or even&#xD;
      im¬mediately before the beginning of treatment so that a great number of patients never&#xD;
      reaches point T6 for the necessary objective measuring; therefore, it is not realistic to&#xD;
      summon dropouts for urine samples 5 times with weekly intervals during the 6th and the 12th&#xD;
      month.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An increase of cocaine use is proven by hair analyses (HA). It must be expected also in this&#xD;
      case that, for various reasons, a certain number of patients (though much less) will not&#xD;
      provide a hair sample at T6 or T12.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, missing or not useable data concerning the primary outcome measures of illicit&#xD;
      heroin use (VB1) and cocaine use (VB2) respectively will be compensated by the patient's&#xD;
      report on his consumption during the last 30 days. This procedure is as objective as&#xD;
      possible; results are only compensated by subjective data in exceptional cases (dropouts,&#xD;
      incorrect or missing data).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The general treatment response is shown by an improvement of the state of health (physical or&#xD;
      mental symptoms) and by a decrease of illicit heroin consumption as well as by the&#xD;
      non-increase of cocaine consumption between the beginning of treatment and the conclusion of&#xD;
      phase 1 of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B5.5 Safety Serious adverse events (SUE), adverse events (UE) and side effects (UAW) must be&#xD;
      recorded consistently throughout the study. Side effects will be investigated quantitatively.&#xD;
      At each investigation, following effects and side effects related to intoxication will be&#xD;
      examined routinely.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The blood controls carried out within the study will be checked for laboratory test&#xD;
      abnormalities. Such changes will be documented in the CRF and added to the adverse events&#xD;
      (UE) and, if applicable, to the unwanted side effects (UAW).&#xD;
&#xD;
      B6. STATISTICAL ANALYSES B6.1 Safety analysis Under inclusion of all persons who have been&#xD;
      randomised, an analysis of emergencies, adverse events (UE) and serious adverse events (SUE)&#xD;
      will be carried out. With regard to such events (prevalence, severity classification)&#xD;
      potential group differences will be checked for statistical significance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B6.2 Efficacy analysis The primary outcome analysis will be carried out according to the&#xD;
      &quot;intention to treat&quot; principle (ITT), which includes all randomised patients, i.e. all&#xD;
      patients who were assigned to one of the treatment groups after twice repeated written&#xD;
      consent. With regard to the 4 x 2-branched study design, a 4-factorial logistic regression&#xD;
      model will be used. In case of missing information, the &quot;last observation carried forward&quot;&#xD;
      method (LOCF) will be applied.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcome analysis For the experimental and the control groups, this proof of&#xD;
      superiority of heroin will be furnished by a 4-factorial logistic regression model; two&#xD;
      separated analyses will be calculated for the criterion &quot;improvement of the state of health&quot;&#xD;
      (A) and for the criterion &quot;reduction of illicit drug consumption&quot; (B).&#xD;
&#xD;
      An overall success of the study (proof of the superiority of heroin treatment compared to&#xD;
      methadone treatment) is assumed if, both for the main target criterion (A) &quot;improvement of&#xD;
      the state of health&quot; and the main target criterion (B) &quot;reduction of illicit drug&#xD;
      consumption&quot;, a superiority of heroin treatment in comparison to methadone treatment can be&#xD;
      proven in the respective logistic regression model with an α-error of 5%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcome criterion (A) - Improvement of the state of health:&#xD;
&#xD;
      H0A: OR ≤ 1 (Response rate in heroin treatment ≤ Response rate in methadone treatment), H1A:&#xD;
      OR &gt; 1 (Response rate in heroin treatment &gt; Response rate in methadone treatment).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis is tested one-tailed with a 2.5% alpha error level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcome criterion (B) - reduction of illicit drug consumption:&#xD;
&#xD;
      H0B: OR ≥ 1 (Rate of illegal drug use in heroin treatment ≥ in methadone treatment), H1B: OR&#xD;
      &lt; 1 (Rate of illegal drug use in heroin treatment &lt; in methadone treatment).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This hypothesis is also tested one-tailed with a 2.5% alpha error level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Proof of the overall effect of heroin treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The experimental treatment (controlled heroin treatment) will be rated to be successful, if&#xD;
      the logistic regression has following results:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  a response rate for the outcome criterion &quot;improvement of the state of health&quot; (A)&#xD;
           signifi¬cantly higher in comparison with the control treatment (methadone maintenance)&#xD;
           AND&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  a response rate for the outcome criterion &quot;reduction of illicit drug consumption&quot; (B)&#xD;
           significantly higher in comparison with the control treatment (methadone maintenance).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary outcome analyses The secondary evaluations are carried out according to the scale&#xD;
      levels of the variables or of the indices formed (maintenance rate, drug consumption, scene&#xD;
      contacts, delinquency, housing situation, social contacts, quality of life, mortality rate),&#xD;
      i. e. by bivariate or multivariate analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B6.3 Sample size determination&#xD;
&#xD;
      The calculation of the sample size is based on following efficacy expectation:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Primary outcome criterion (A) - improvement of the state of health: Efficacy expectation in&#xD;
      control groups: ≤ 30% of responders, Efficacy expectation in experimental groups: &gt; 50% of&#xD;
      responders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Primary outcome criterion (B) - reduction of illicit drug consumption: Efficacy expectation&#xD;
      in control groups: ≤ 30% of responders, Efficacy expectation in experimental groups: &gt; 50% of&#xD;
      responders. Within the framework of the 4 x 2-branched study design, each primary outcome&#xD;
      criterion will be analysed by a 4-factorial logistic regression analysis. With the&#xD;
      (conservative) assump¬tion that both target criteria are stochastically independent, a power&#xD;
      of 90% for each main out¬come criterion guarantees that a (multiple) total power of 80% is&#xD;
      maintained [(1-β)2 ≈ 0.80 for β = 0.10]. Since the total success of the study is only assumed&#xD;
      if treatment effects are evident for both primary outcome measures, a correction of&#xD;
      type-1-error is not necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A certain number of patients will (prematurely) drop-out of treatment and not be included in&#xD;
      the evaluation by LOCF, because they cannot be reached any more for examinations and&#xD;
      interviews. These are patients who dropped out prior to T6 or have not started treatment or&#xD;
      refused their consent to the investigation of the two primary outcome variables. According to&#xD;
      the conservative evaluation strategy, these patients must be treated as &quot;worst cases&quot;.&#xD;
      Therefore, the size of the assumed effect decreases in relation to the percentage of these&#xD;
      &quot;not reached&quot; patients in the heroin and methadone group. Realistic estimations of these&#xD;
      percentages are 10% drop-outs in the methadone group and 5% in the heroin group. According to&#xD;
      these expected percentages, the estimated effect size on which the calculation of the sample&#xD;
      size is based, is reduced from 0.3 vs. 0.5 to 0.370 vs. 0.475.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on this assumption, a multiple total power of 80% requires a number of cases of at&#xD;
      least N=482 test persons for each sample group (based on Chi2-test for odds ratio, sample&#xD;
      size approximation according to Nam 1992). Related to the individual strata, this means at&#xD;
      least four heroin and four methadone strata with at least 121 patients each are necessary to&#xD;
      prove the expected effect with a statistical power of 80%. For practical reasons (adequate&#xD;
      distribution to the study cen¬tres, increased measuring precision), this number is rounded up&#xD;
      to N=140 resulting in eight strata with a total number of N=1,120 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Under the described conditions, this sample size guarantees that in both tests a significant&#xD;
      difference between methadone and heroin treatment can be proven with a statistical total&#xD;
      power of at least 80%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B6.4 Missing data If data of the 12-months examination are missing and concern the primary&#xD;
      outcome criteria and cannot be replaced by the LOCF method, a non-fulfillment of the&#xD;
      criterion must be assumed, which will be interpreted as &quot;worst case&quot; in the individual case.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B6.5 Drop-outs Patients dropping out of treatment will continue to be included in the&#xD;
      investigations and evaluations (ITT-analysis). According to the LOCF method, the latest&#xD;
      information of each patient will be used for the analysis if a patient cannot be interviewed&#xD;
      at the conclusion of the study. As far as the primary outcome criterion of illicit heroin&#xD;
      consumption is concerned, the 12-month information can only be completed by the investigation&#xD;
      at T6, because only the five urine samples in the 6th month of treatment can be tested for&#xD;
      illicit heroin by GC/MS. Similarly, a missing hair analysis for cocaine consumption at T12&#xD;
      can only be completed by a hair sample precautiously taken at T6. If no objective measure&#xD;
      results of the primary outcome measures illicit heroin and cocaine consumption are available,&#xD;
      the patient's self-report will be included in the analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who did not participate in any further investigation after the inclusion in the&#xD;
      study are rated as &quot;worst case&quot;, i.e. not reached patients of the methadone group are rated&#xD;
      as success (responders) and not reached patients of the heroin group as failures&#xD;
      (non-responders). Patients who died in the first phase of the study are rated (in the&#xD;
      experimental and the control group) as non-responders. Patients, who withdraw their consent&#xD;
      after randomisation and do not initiate the study treatment, are excluded from the&#xD;
      ITT-analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2007</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2003</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>(A) Improvement of physical or mental state of health,</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>(B) Reduction of consumption of street heroin and no increase of cocaine use.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Retention rate</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction of consumption of, benzodiazepines, amphetamine, alcohol and other substances</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detachment from the drug scene</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Decrease of criminal behaviour</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stabilisation of the living situation</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Establishment of new social contacts</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Improvement of quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality rate</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>8</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1015</enrollment>
  <condition>Opioid Dependence</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MTF, Psycho-education, Heroin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Stratum: Methadone treatment failures (MTF) Intervention: Psycho-education and Counselling, Drug: Diacetylmorphine (i.v.)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MTF, Case management, Heroin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Stratum: Methadone treatment failures (MTF) Intervention: Case Management and Motivational Interviewing, Drug: Diacetylmorphine (i.v.)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MTF, Psycho-education, Methadone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Stratum: Methadone treatment failures (MTF) Intervention: Psycho-education and Counselling, Drug: Methadone (p.o.)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MTF, Case management, Methadone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Stratum: Methadone treatment failures (MTF) Intervention: Case Management and Motivational Interviewing, Drug: Methadone (p.o.)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NIT, Psycho-education, Heroin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Stratum: Not in treatment (NIT) Intervention: Psycho-education and Counselling, Drug: Diacetylmorphine (i.v.)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NIT, Case management, Heroin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Stratum: Not in treatment (NIT) Intervention: Case Management and Motivational Interviewing, Drug: Diacetylmorphine (i.v.)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NIT, Psycho-education, Methadone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Stratum: Not in treatment (NIT) Intervention: Psycho-education and Counselling, Drug: Methadone (p.o.)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NIT, Case management, Methadone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Stratum: Not in treatment (NIT) Intervention: Case Management and Motivational Interviewing, Drug: Methadone (p.o.)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Diacetylmorphine</intervention_name>
    <description>Diacetylmorphine (i.v.), daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>MTF, Case management, Heroin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>MTF, Psycho-education, Heroin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>NIT, Case management, Heroin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>NIT, Psycho-education, Heroin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Heroin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Psycho-education and Counselling</intervention_name>
    <description>Psycho-educational group therapy and individual counselling</description>
    <arm_group_label>MTF, Psycho-education, Heroin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>MTF, Psycho-education, Methadone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>NIT, Psycho-education, Heroin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>NIT, Psycho-education, Methadone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Methadone</intervention_name>
    <description>Methadone (p.o.), daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>MTF, Case management, Methadone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>MTF, Psycho-education, Methadone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>NIT, Case management, Methadone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>NIT, Psycho-education, Methadone</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>racemic d,l-methadone</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Case management and Motivational interviewing</intervention_name>
    <description>Individual Case Management combined with Motivational interviewing</description>
    <arm_group_label>MTF, Case management, Heroin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>MTF, Case management, Methadone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>NIT, Case management, Heroin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>NIT, Case management, Methadone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minimum age 23 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Opiate dependency for at least 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current main diagnosis of opiate dependency according to the ICD-10 criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current daily and predominantly intravenous heroin consumption or continuing heroin&#xD;
             consumption in maintenance treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptoms of physical illness indicating a poor state of health according to the OTI&#xD;
             health scale; at least 13 current symptoms must be found OR Current mental symptoms or&#xD;
             disturbances, i.e. a standardised GSI value of the SCL-90-R (Franke 1995) of at least&#xD;
             60 points&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No participation in an addiction treatment programme (a.a. maintenance, inpatient or&#xD;
             outpatient treatment) at least within the last 6 months, but documented previous&#xD;
             experience with drug therapies OR Negative course of maintenance treatment according&#xD;
             to the guidelines of the German Medi¬cal Council (Bundesärztekam¬mer 1997) due to (a)&#xD;
             continuous additional consumption of heroin (50% of the urine samples positive within&#xD;
             the last 6 months) or cocaine (harmful use of cocaine/crack according to ICD-10) in a&#xD;
             documented maintenance period of at least 6 months with a current maintenance dose of&#xD;
             at least 60 mg d l methadone (or 30 mg levo¬methadone) daily&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residence or registration in the city (or city state) or region that conducts the&#xD;
             heroin treat¬ment for at least 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Voluntary participation and ability to comply with the treatment conditions&#xD;
             (willingness to change treatment location; compliance; treatment&#xD;
             control/documentation; evalua¬tion)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written consent to comply with the treatment conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons who are currently in prison or awaiting trial or who can be expected to be&#xD;
             taken into custody within the next 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons who had voluntary phases of abstinence of at least 2 months during the last 12&#xD;
             months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known epilepsy or generalised convulsions during the last 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypersensitivity to test substances and additives&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Regular intake of MAO inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious bronchial asthma, COPD, Cor pulmonale&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious cardiac arrhythmia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prostatic hypertrophy (with urinary retention)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Urethral stricture&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life threatening liver disorders (exogenous hepatic coma)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious renal disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insulin dependent diabetes mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed malignancies during the last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women or nursing mothers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients, who, according to the study physician's judgement, are not able to comply&#xD;
             with the conditions of the model project, i.e. participation in the therapeutic and&#xD;
             scientific pro¬grammes, due to serious physical or mental illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are currently participating in another clinical study concerned with the&#xD;
             evalua¬tion of an addiction treatment programme.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>23 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dieter Naber, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Hamburg-Eppendorf</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christian Haasen, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University of Hamburg-Eppendorf</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AWO Ambulanz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Karlsruhe</city>
        <state>Baden-Wuertenberg</state>
        <zip>76133</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Heroinambulanz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Munich</city>
        <state>Bavaria</state>
        <zip>80336</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Studienambulanz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Frankfurt</city>
        <state>Hessen</state>
        <zip>60316</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Drogenambulanz Hannover</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hannover</city>
        <state>Lower-Syxony</state>
        <zip>30159</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Heroinambulanz Bonn</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bonn</city>
        <state>Northrhine-Westfalia</state>
        <zip>53111</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Heroinambulanz Koeln</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cologne</city>
        <state>Northrhine-Westfalia</state>
        <zip>50676</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pro Vivere Drogenambulanz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>20097</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.heroinstudie.de</url>
    <description>Webpage with information on the trial</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 21, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 21, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 22, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 7, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 7, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">September 9, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>PD Dr. Uwe Verthein</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of Centre for Interdisciplinary Addiction Research</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Opioid-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Methadone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heroin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

