<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04683003</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TAK-755-3002</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-003348-10</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04683003</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of TAK-755 in Participants With Congenital Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic Purpura</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 3b, Prospective, Open-label, Multicenter, Single Treatment Arm, Continuation Study of the Safety and Efficacy of TAK-755 (rADAMTS-13, Also Known as BAX 930/SHP655) in the Prophylactic and On-demand Treatment of Subjects With Severe Congenital Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic Purpura (cTTP; Upshaw-Schulman Syndrome, or Hereditary Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic Purpura)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Takeda</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Takeda Development Center Americas, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Shire</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Takeda</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main aim of the study is to check for side effects of TAK-755. Participants will either&#xD;
      receive TAK-755 every week or every other week to prevent bleeds (prophylactic arm) or they&#xD;
      will receive TAK-755 to treat an acute bleed (on-demand arm).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in the prophylactic arm will receive treatment in the clinic or at home for 3&#xD;
      years. They will visit the clinic at least every 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in the on-demand arm will receive treatment for the acute bleed until the bleed&#xD;
      has stopped. They will have a follow-up visit at the clinic 4 weeks later.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a follow-up study to the Phase 3 pivotal study (281102 [NCT03393975]) and will&#xD;
      comprise of two treatment cohorts (Prophylactic and On-demand) consisting of TAK-755 naïve&#xD;
      and non-naïve participants with a total duration of 6 years. A total of 77 participants will&#xD;
      be enrolled in this study (up to 57 participants who have completed study 281102&#xD;
      [NCT03393975] study [non-naïve participants] and at least 20 TAK-755-naïve participants&#xD;
      (participants who are naïve to TAK-755). In addition, participants from Expanded Access&#xD;
      Programs or participants from study 281102 (NCT03393975) who had an allergic reaction to&#xD;
      standard of care prophylactic treatment will also be eligible for enrollment in this&#xD;
      continuation study. Participants on prophylactic regimen will be able to opt for treatment in&#xD;
      a home setting by caregiver or self-infusion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 14, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 27, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 27, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Related Treatment-emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs) and Related Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>TEAE: any event emerging or manifesting at or after the initiation of treatment with an investigational product (IP) or medicinal product or any existing event that worsens in either intensity or frequency following exposure to the IP or medicinal product. SAE: Signs, symptoms or outcomes which results in death, requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of hospitalization, results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity, results in a congenital abnormality/birth defect, important medical event, bronchospasm, reviewed and confirmed seroconversion for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis A virus (HAV), hepatitis B virus (HBV), hepatitis C virus (HCV), hepatitis E virus (HEV), or parvovirus B19 (B19V). Product related AE: event emerging or manifesting at or after the initiation of treatment with an IP or medicinal product or any existing event that worsens. Vital signs, clinical chemistry parameters and hematology parameters will be recorded as AEs.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Acute Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic Purpura (TTP) Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of acute TTP Events with severe cTTP receiving prophylactic treatment with TAK-755 (rADAMTS-13) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Acute TTP Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with acute TTP Events with severe cTTP receiving prophylactic treatment with TAK-755 (rADAMTS-13) will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Acute TTP Events Resolved With TAK-755</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with acute TTP events that have resolved after treatment with TAK-755 while enrolled in the study will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Acute TTP Events on Their Final Dose and Dosing Regimen</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with TTP events on their final dose and dosing regimen will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Resolution of Clinical Symptomatology</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Time to resolution of clinical symptomatology, if present, and normalization of laboratory parameters platelet count greater than or equal to (&gt;=) 150,000/microliters (mcL); lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) lesser than or equal to (&lt;=) 1.5*upper limit of normal (ULN) following initiation of treatment in acute TTP episodes with TAK-755.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total Quantity of TAK-755 Administered During the Treatment of Acute Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Total quantity of TAK-755 administered during the treatment of acute events will be assessed. Acute events typically require 3-4 days of intensified treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Thrombocytopenia</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Thrombocytopenia is defined as a drop in platelet count &gt;=25 percent (%) of baseline or a platelet count less than (&lt;) 150,000/mcL. Number of participants with thrombocytopenia in the prophylactic cohort will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Microangiopathic Hemolytic Anemia</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Microangiopathic hemolytic anemia is defined as an elevation of LDH greater than (&gt;) 1.5*ULN. Number of participants with microangiopathic hemolytic anemia in the prophylactic cohort will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Neurological Symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 Years</time_frame>
    <description>Neurological symptoms include (e.g., headache, confusion, dysphonia, dysarthria, focal or general motor symptoms including seizures). Number of participants with neurological symptoms in the prophylactic cohort will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Renal Dysfunction</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Renal dysfunction is defined as an increase in serum creatinine &gt;1.5*baseline at screening. Number of participants with renal dysfunction in the prophylactic cohort will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Abdominal Pain</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with abdominal pain in the prophylactic cohort will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants who will Require Supplemental Doses</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who will require supplemental doses prompted by subacute manifestations in the prophylactic cohort will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants who will Require Dose Modifications</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who will require dose modifications not prompted by an acute event in the prophylactic cohort will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Shift From Baseline in Biomarkers of Organ Damage</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with shift from baseline in biomarkers of organ damage, includes cardiac troponin T (cTnT) and troponin I (cTnI) , creatine kinase myocardial band (CK-MB), fraction (cardiac), neuron-specific enolase (NSE) (brain), S100B (brain), and serum creatinine (kidney), in the prophylactic and on-demand cohorts will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Congenital Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic Purpura (cTTP) Manifestations Receiving TAK-755 as a Prophylactic Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>cTTP manifestations is defined as a composite of thrombocytopenia, microangiopathic hemolytic anemia, renal dysfunction, neurologic signs and symptoms, and abdominal pain in participants receiving TAK-755 as a prophylactic treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with cTTP Manifestations While Receiving the Final Prophylactic Treatment Regimen with TAK-755</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>cTTP manifestations is defined as a composite of thrombocytopenia, microangiopathic hemolytic anemia, renal dysfunction, neurologic signs and symptoms, and abdominal pain in participants while receiving the final prophylactic treatment regimen with TAK-755.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with cTTP Manifestations who will Require Acute Management Regimen</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>cTTP manifestations is defined as a composite of thrombocytopenia, microangiopathic hemolytic anemia, renal dysfunction, neurologic signs and symptoms, and abdominal pain in participants who will require acute management regimen.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with TAK-755 Related and Unrelated Adverse Events (AEs) and Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical investigation participant administered a pharmaceutical product and that does not necessarily have a causal relationship with this IP or medicinal product. A SAE is an AE with any untoward clinical manifestation of signs, symptoms or outcomes which results in death, requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of hospitalization, results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity, results in a congenital abnormality/birth defect, important medical event, bronchospasm associated with anaphylaxis, reviewed and confirmed seroconversion for HIV, HAV, HBV, HCV, HEV, or B19V.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Antibodies Binding to ADAMTS-13</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with anti-ADAMTS-13 binding antibodies and neutralizing antibodies following ADAMTS-13 administration will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with TAK-755 Related AEs and SAEs in the Home Setting</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is defined as any untoward medical occurrence in a participant administered IP that does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the treatment. A SAE is an AE with any untoward clinical manifestation of signs, symptoms or outcomes which results in death, requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of hospitalization, results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity, results in a congenital abnormality/birth defect, important medical event, bronchospasm associated with anaphylaxis, reviewed and confirmed seroconversion for HIV, HAV, HBV, HCV, HEV, or B19V. A product related AE is any event emerging or manifesting at or after the initiation of treatment with an investigational product or medicinal product or any existing event that worsens.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with AEs and SAEs After Receiving TAK-755 in the Home Setting</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is defined as any untoward medical occurrence in a participant administered IP that does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the treatment. A SAE is an AE with any untoward clinical manifestation of signs, symptoms or outcomes which results in death, requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of hospitalization, results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity, results in a congenital abnormality/birth defect, important medical event, bronchospasm associated with anaphylaxis, reviewed and confirmed seroconversion for HIV, HAV, HBV, HCV, HEV, or B19V. A product related AE is any event emerging or manifesting at or after the initiation of treatment with an investigational product or medicinal product or any existing event that worsens.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Acute TTP Events Receiving TAK-755 Prophylactically in the Home Setting</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with acute TTP events receiving TAK-755 prophylactically in the home setting will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health Related Quality of Life (HRQoL): cTTP-Specific Patient reported outcomes (PROs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>The cTTP specific patient-reported outcomes (PRO) instrument consists of 26 questions designed to assess the participants experience of fatigue, joint, muscle, abdominal and chest pain in the previous 24 hours, neurologic manifestations, bruising, feelings of depression and mood alterations, and activity limitation in the past 7 days, and participants attitudes, experienced side effects, work/school absences and travel impact associated with treatment received for TTP during the previous 2 weeks. The cTTP PRO assessment is focused on measuring the symptoms and impacts of the disease. The scores range from 0 to 152. Higher scores indicate a better quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HRQoL: 36-Item Short Form Health Survey (SF-36)</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>The SF-36 is a generic quality-of-life instrument that has been widely used to assess HRQoL of participants. Generic instruments are used in general populations to assess a wide range of domains applicable to a variety of health states, conditions, and diseases. The SF-36 consists of 36 items that are aggregated into 8 multi-item scales (physical functioning, role-physical, bodily pain, general health, vitality, social functioning, role-emotional, and mental health), with scores ranging from 0 to 100. Higher scores indicate better HRQoL.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HRQoL: Abbreviated 9-item Treatment Satisfaction Questionnaire for Medication (TSQM-9)</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>TSQM is a global satisfaction scale used to assess the overall level of participant's satisfaction or dissatisfaction with their medications. TSQM-9 is a 9-item, validated, self-administered instrument used to assess participant's satisfaction with medication. The three domains assessed are effectiveness, convenience, and global satisfaction. The score of each of the 3 domains is based on an algorithm to create a score of 0 to 100. Higher score indicated greater satisfaction in that domain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HRQoL: EuroQol 5 Dimensions Questionnaire 3-Level (EQ-5D-3L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>EQ-5D-3L health questionnaire is a participant answered questionnaire scoring 5 dimensions - mobility, self-care, usual activities, pain/discomfort and anxiety/depression. The EQ-5D total score ranges from 0 (worst health state) to 1 (perfect health state) and 1 reflects the best outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HRQoL: EQ-5D-youth (EQ-5D-Y)</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>EQ-5D-Y health questionnaire is a participant answered questionnaire scoring 5 dimensions - mobility, self-care, usual activities, pain/discomfort and anxiety/depression. The EQ-5D total score ranges from 0 (worst health state) to 1 (perfect health state) and 1 reflects the best outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HRQoL: Pediatric Quality of Life Inventory (Ped QL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>The Peds QL is a generic health related quality of life instrument designed specifically for a pediatric population and captures following domains: physical functioning, emotional functioning, social functioning, school functioning, psychosocial summary, physical health and total score. The Peds-QL total score consist of all 23 items of all domains. This modular instrument uses a 5-point scale: from 0 (never) to 4 (almost always). Items are reversed scored and linearly transformed to a 0-100 scale as follows: 0=100, 1=75, 2=50, 3=25, 4=0. Higher scores indicate better quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HRQoL: Infusion Experience Satisfaction Assessment Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Infusion experience satisfaction assessment questionnaire will assess participant satisfaction on various aspects of the infusion experience (ie, Convenience, impact on daily life, comfort in the treatment environment, time invested to receive infusion, concerns on handling potential complications, interaction with members of health care team and with other participants). Each item is rated on a 5-point scale from 1 (very poor) to 5 (very good) with a total score ranging from 93 to 465. Higher scores indicate greater satisfaction.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resource Utilization: Length of Hospital Stay for Acute TTP Episodes</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days of participants stay in hospital for Acute TTP episodes will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resource Utilization: Number of Hospitalizations</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of hospitalizations for Acute TTP episodes will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resource Utilization: Number of Participants with Healthcare Resource Utilization During Prophylaxis</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with healthcare resource utilization during prophylaxis will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resource Utilization: Number of Participants with Days Missed From School or Work due to TTP-Related Illness</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study period of approximately 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with days missed from school or work due to TTP-related illness will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Trough Levels of ADAMTS-13</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 60 minutes pre-infusion and 65 minutes post-infusion at interval study visits every 12 weeks (up to 6 years)</time_frame>
    <description>Trough levels of ADAMTS-13 activity and antigen levels from participants in prophylactic and on-demand cohorts during acute and subacute events will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of Von Willebrand Factor: Antigen (VWF:Ag)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 60 minutes pre-infusion and 65 minutes post-infusion at interval study visits every 12 weeks (up to 6 years)</time_frame>
    <description>VWF:Ag is a measure of total VWF protein and will be assessed using a sandwich enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) employing polyclonal anti-human-VWF antibodies. Assessments of VWF:Ag at baseline and following infusion of the TAK-755 treatment during the initial PK assessment in prophylactic and on-demand cohorts and during acute events will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of Von Willebrand Factor: Ristocetin Cofactor Activity (VWF:RCo)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 60 minutes pre-infusion and 65 minutes post-infusion at interval study visits every 12 weeks (up to 6 years)</time_frame>
    <description>VWF:RCo will provide a measure of the ability of VWF to bind platelet glycoprotein Ib. Stabilized platelets are agglutinated in the presence of VWF and the antibiotic Ristocetin. Assessments of VWF:RCo at baseline and following infusion of the TAK-755 treatment during the initial PK assessment in prophylactic and on-demand cohorts and during acute events will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in VWF:Ag in Relation with ADAMTS-13 Activity Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 60 minutes pre-infusion and 65 minutes post-infusion at interval study visits every 12 weeks (up to 6 years)</time_frame>
    <description>VWF:Ag is a measure of total VWF protein and will be assessed using a sandwich ELISA employing polyclonal anti-human-VWF antibodies. Longitudinal relationship of ADAMTS-13 activity levels to change in VWF:Ag at baseline and following infusion of the TAK-755 treatment during the initial PK assessment will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in VWF:RCo in Relation With ADAMTS-13 Activity Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 60 minutes pre-infusion and 65 minutes post-infusion at interval study visits every 12 weeks (up to 6 years)</time_frame>
    <description>VWF:RCo will provide a measure of the ability of VWF to bind platelet glycoprotein Ib. Stabilized platelets are agglutinated in the presence of VWF and the antibiotic Ristocetin. Longitudinal relationship of ADAMTS-13 activity levels to change in VWF:RCo at baseline and following infusion of the TAK-755 treatment during the initial PK assessment will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Platelets in Relation With ADAMTS-13 Activity Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 60 minutes pre-infusion and 65 minutes post-infusion at interval study visits every 12 weeks (up to 6 years)</time_frame>
    <description>Longitudinal relationship of ADAMTS-13 activity levels to change in platelets will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Lactate Dehydrogenase (LDH) in Relation With ADAMTS-13 Activity Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 60 minutes pre-infusion and 65 minutes post-infusion at interval study visits every 12 weeks (up to 6 years)</time_frame>
    <description>Longitudinal relationship of ADAMTS-13 activity levels to change in LDH will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Acute and Subacute Events in Relation with ADAMTS-13 Activity Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 60 minutes pre-infusion and 65 minutes post-infusion at interval study visits every 12 weeks (up to 6 years)</time_frame>
    <description>Longitudinal relationship of ADAMTS-13 activity levels and participants with acute and subacute events will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">77</enrollment>
  <condition>Congenital Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic Purpura</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prophylactic Cohort: TAK-755</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants who are TAK-755 non-naïve will receive prophylactic treatment, a single dose of TAK-755 intravenous (IV) infusions at a dose of 40 international units per kilogram (IU/kg) once every 1 week (Q1W) or once every 2 weeks (Q2W) for approximately 3 years, or participants enrolling from an expanded access program will continue same dose of TAK-755 but not exceeding 40 IU/kg Q1W and not less than 40 IU/kg Q2W or participants who participated in study 281102 (NCT03393975) and had an allergic response to standard-of-care treatment will receive TAK-755 at a starting dose of 40 IU/kg Q2W. Participants who are TAK-755 naïve will receive initial prophylactic PK dose of 40 IU/kg followed by prophylactic treatment Q1W or once Q2W for approximately 3 years, or until commercial availability of investigational product (IP) in the country, or decision not to launch in the country whichever occurs first.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>On-Demand Cohort: TAK-755</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All the participants will receive an initial single dose of 40 IU/kg TAK-755 on Day 1 followed by subsequent tapering dose of 20 IU/kg on Day 2 then an additional daily dose of 15 IU/kg TAK-755 starting at Day 3 until 2 days after the acute event is resolved with an approximate treatment duration of one month. Upon resolution of the acute event, participants may choose to move to the prophylactic cohort of the study or discontinue entirely from the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TAK-755</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants in prophylaxis cohort will receive IV infusions of 40 IU/kg TAK-755 during Q1W or Q2W up to 3 years. On-demand cohort participants will receive an initial IV infusion of 40 IU/kg followed by 20 IU/kg on Day 2 and 15 IU/kg daily until 2 days after the acute event has resolved (approximately one month).</description>
    <arm_group_label>On-Demand Cohort: TAK-755</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prophylactic Cohort: TAK-755</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>rADAMTS13; SHP-655; recombinant ADAMTS13; BAX 930</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants who have completed TAK-755 Phase 3 pivotal Study 281102 (NCT03393975)&#xD;
        (includes prophylactic cohort) and who meet all of the following criteria are eligible for&#xD;
        this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants or legally authorized representative has provided signed informed consent&#xD;
             &gt;=18 years of age and/or assent form &lt;18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant 0 to 70 years of age at the time of screening of the 281102 (NCT03393975)&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has been diagnosed with severe congenital ADAMTS-13 deficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant does not display any severe thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura (TTP)&#xD;
             signs (platelet count &lt;100,000/ microliter (mcL) and elevation of lactate&#xD;
             dehydrogenase (LDH) greater than (&gt;) 2 *ULN at screening (prophylactic cohort only).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants &gt;=16 years of age must have a Karnofsky score &gt;= 70% and participants &lt;16&#xD;
             years of age must have a Lansky score &gt;=80%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If female of childbearing potential, participant presents with a negative serum or&#xD;
             urine pregnancy test confirmed not more than 7 days before the first IP administration&#xD;
             and agrees to employ adequate birth control measures for the duration of the study and&#xD;
             to undergo quarterly pregnancy testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexually active males must use an accepted and effective method of contraception&#xD;
             during the treatment and until a minimum of 16 days after the last dose administered.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is willing and able to comply with the requirements of the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        TAK-755 naïve participants and non-naïve on-demand cohort participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
        TAK-755 naïve participants can only be enrolled in this continuation after enrollment of&#xD;
        the adult participants in the prophylactic arm of TAK-755 Phase 3 pivotal study 281102&#xD;
        (NCT03393975) has been completed. TAK-755 naive pediatric participants can be enrolled&#xD;
        after enrollment of the respective age cohort into the pivotal Phase 3 study 281102&#xD;
        (NCT03393975) has been completed.TAK-755 naïve participants and participants who were&#xD;
        enrolled into the on-demand cohort of theTAK-755 Phase 3 pivotal study 281102 (NCT03393975)&#xD;
        who meet ALL of the following criteria are eligible for this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is naïve to TAK-755 or was enrolled into the on-demand cohort of the&#xD;
             TAK-755 Phase 3 pivotal study 281102 (NCT03393975) for treatment of an acute event but&#xD;
             did not receive prophylactic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant or legally authorized representative has provided signed informed consent&#xD;
             (&gt;=18 years of age) and/or assent form (&lt;18 years of age).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is 0 to 70 years of age at the time of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has been diagnosed with severe congenital ADAMTS-13 deficiency defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Confirmed by molecular genetic testing, documented in participant history or at&#xD;
                  screening, and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ADAMTS-13 activity &lt;10% as measured by the fluorescence resonance energy transfer&#xD;
                  (FRETS)-VWF73 assay, documented in participant history or at screening.&#xD;
                  Participants currently receiving standard of care prophylactic therapy may exceed&#xD;
                  10% ADAMTS-13 activity at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants currently receiving prophylactic therapy will be screened immediately&#xD;
             prior to their usual prophylactic infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant does not display any severe TTP signs (platelet count &lt;100,000/microliter&#xD;
             (mcL) and elevation of LDH &gt;2*ULN) at screening (prophylactic cohort only).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants &gt;=16 years of age must have a Karnofsky score &gt;=70% and participants &lt;16&#xD;
             years of age must have a Lansky score &gt;=80%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants is hepatitis C virus negative (HCV-) as confirmed by antibody or&#xD;
             polymerase chain reaction testing OR HCV positive (HCV+) if their disease is chronic&#xD;
             but stable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If female of childbearing potential, participant presents with a negative serum or&#xD;
             urine pregnancy test confirmed not more than 7 days before the first IP administration&#xD;
             and agrees to employ adequate birth control measures for the duration of the study and&#xD;
             to undergo quarterly pregnancy testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexually active males must use an accepted and effective method of contraception&#xD;
             during treatment and until a minimum of 16 days after the last dose administered.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is willing and able to comply with the requirements of the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants from an Expanded Access Program or participants in Study 281102 (NCT03393975)&#xD;
        who had an allergic reaction to standard of care prophylactic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants from an expanded access program as well as participants who participated in&#xD;
        Study 281102(NCT03393975) who had an allergic reaction to standard-of-care prophylactic&#xD;
        treatment are eligible for enrollment in the continuation study if they meet ALL of the&#xD;
        following criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants or legally authorized representative has provided signed informed consent&#xD;
             (&gt;=18 years of age) and/or assent (&lt;18 years of age).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants is 0 to 70 years of age at the time of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants has been diagnosed with severe congenital ADAMTS-13 deficiency defined&#xD;
             as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Confirmed by molecular genetic testing, documented in participant history or at&#xD;
                  screening, and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ADAMTS-13 activity &lt;10% as measured by the fluorescence resonance energy transfer&#xD;
                  (FRETS)- VWF 73 assay, documented in participant history or at screening.&#xD;
                  Participants currently receiving standard of care prophylactic therapy may exceed&#xD;
                  10% ADAMTS 13 activity at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant does not display any severe TTP signs (platelet count &lt;100,000/mcL and&#xD;
             elevation of LDH &gt;2*ULN) at screening (prophylactic cohort only).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants &gt;=16 years of age must have a Karnofsky score &gt;=70% and participants &lt;16&#xD;
             years of age must have a Lansky score &gt;=80%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If female of childbearing potential, participant presents with a negative serum or&#xD;
             urine pregnancy test confirmed not more than 7 days before the first IP administration&#xD;
             and agrees to employ highly effective birth control measures for the duration of the&#xD;
             study and to undergo quarterly pregnancy testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexually active males must use an accepted and effective method of contraception&#xD;
             during treatment and until a minimum of 16 days after the last dose administered.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is willing and able to comply with the requirements of the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants who have completed TAK-755 Phase 3 pivotal study (281102) (NCT03393975) and&#xD;
        TAK 755 naïve participants and non-naïve on-demand cohort participants and participants&#xD;
        from an Expanded Access Program or participants in Study 281102 (NCT03393975) who had an&#xD;
        allergic reaction to standard-of-care prophylactic treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has been diagnosed with any other TTP-like disorder (microangiopathic&#xD;
             hemolytic anemia), including immune-mediated TTP.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known life-threatening hypersensitivity reaction, including anaphylaxis, to the parent&#xD;
             molecule ADAMTS-13, hamster protein, or other constituents of TAK-755.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a presence of a functional ADAMTS-13 inhibitor at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a medical history of a genetic or acquired immune deficiency that&#xD;
             would interfere with the assessment of product immunogenicity, including participants&#xD;
             who are human immunodeficiency virus-positive with an absolute cluster of&#xD;
             differentiation 4 (CD4) count &lt; 200/ cubic millimeter (mm^3) or who are receiving&#xD;
             chronic immunosuppressive drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of significant neurological events, such as major stroke,&#xD;
             indicating that a relapse might have severe consequences, as judged by the&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has been diagnosed with severe cardiovascular disease (New York Heart&#xD;
             Association classes 3 to 4).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant with end stage renal disease requiring chronic dialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has been diagnosed with hepatic dysfunction, as evidenced by, but not&#xD;
             limited to, any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum alanine aminotransferase &gt;= 2*ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Severe hypoalbuminemia &lt;24 gram per liter (g/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Portal vein hypertension (e.g., presence of otherwise unexplained splenomegaly,&#xD;
                  history of esophageal varices).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the opinion of the investigator, the participant has another clinically significant&#xD;
             concomitant disease that may pose additional risks for the participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has been treated with an immunomodulatory drug, excluding topical&#xD;
             treatment (e.g., ointments, nasal sprays), within 30 days prior to enrollment. Use of&#xD;
             corticosteroids in conjunction with administration of fresh frozen plasma to prevent&#xD;
             allergic manifestations is permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has an acute illness (e.g., influenza, flu-like syndrome, allergic&#xD;
             rhinitis/conjunctivitis, bronchial asthma) at the time of screening (prophylactic&#xD;
             cohort only).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is receiving or anticipates receiving another investigational drug and/or&#xD;
             interventional drug within 30 days before enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of drug and/or alcohol abuse within the last 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a progressive fatal disease and/or life expectancy of &lt;= 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is identified by the investigator as being unable or unwilling to&#xD;
             cooperate with study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant suffers from a mental condition rendering him/her unable to understand the&#xD;
             nature, scope, and possible consequences of the study and/or evidence of an&#xD;
             uncooperative attitude.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is a family member or employee of the sponsor or investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If female, participant is pregnant or lactating at the time of enrollment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Study Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Takeda</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Takeda Contact</last_name>
    <phone>+1-877-825-3327</phone>
    <email>medinfoUS@takeda.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Childrens Healthcare of Atlanta</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>404-727-1608</phone>
      <email>ana.antun@emoryhealthcare.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ana Antun</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27705</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>919-660-7050</phone>
      <email>ara.metjian@duke.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Thomas Ortel</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mid Ohio Heart Clinic Inc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dublin</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43017</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>614-293-2887</phone>
      <email>spero.cataland@osumc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Spero Cataland</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Oklahoma</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oklahoma City</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <zip>73104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>405-271-8299</phone>
      <email>sami-ibrahami@ouhsc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sami Ibrahimi</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AKH - Medizinische Universität Wien</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vienna</city>
        <zip>1090</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+4314040044100</phone>
      <email>paul.knoebl@meduniwien.ac.at</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Paul Knoebl</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Saint Etienne - Hôpital Nord</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint-Priest-en-Jarez cedex</city>
        <state>Loire</state>
        <zip>42270</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+33477828038</phone>
      <email>claire.berger@chu-st-etienne.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Claire Berger</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Necker - Enfants Malades</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris cedex 15</city>
        <state>Paris</state>
        <zip>75015</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+33144497210</phone>
      <email>nathalie.biebuyck@aphp.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nathalie Biebuyck</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hopital Claude Huriez - CHU Lille</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lille</city>
        <zip>59037</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+33320444371</phone>
      <email>francois.provot@chru-lille.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Francois Provot</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Saint-Antoine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75012</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+33149282162</phone>
      <email>paul.coppo@aphp.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Paul Coppo</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Robert Debré- Paris</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75935</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+33140032467</phone>
      <email>georges.deschenes@rdb.aphp.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Claire Dossier</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitaetsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>20246</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+4940741053796</phone>
      <email>hassenpflug@uke.de</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Wolf-Achim Hassenpflug</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitaetsklinikum Jena, Klinik fuerKinder-und Jugendmedizin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jena</city>
        <zip>07747</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+493641938426</phone>
      <email>karim.kentouche@med.uni-jena.de</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Karim Kentouche</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fondazione Policlinico Universitario Agostino Gemelli IRCCS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roma</city>
        <zip>168</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+39630156329</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Raimondo De Cristofaro</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kyushu University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fukuoka-shi</city>
        <state>Fukuoka-Ken</state>
        <zip>812-8582</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+81926411151</phone>
      <email>ischii@pediatr.med.kyushu-u.ac.jp</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Masataka Ishimura</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hyogo College of Medicine Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nishinomiya</city>
        <state>Hyogo</state>
        <zip>663-8501</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+81798456111</phone>
      <email>parasol@mua.biglobe.ne.jp</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Satoshi Higasa</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical Hospital,Tokyo Medical and Dental University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bunkyo City</city>
        <state>Tokyo</state>
        <zip>113-8519</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+81358035646</phone>
      <email>mkajiwara.bldt@tmd.ac.jp</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michiko Kajiwara</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Samodzielny Publiczny Dzieciecy Szpital Kliniczny</name>
      <address>
        <city>Warszawa</city>
        <zip>02-091</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+48223179614</phone>
      <email>Anna.klukowska@litewska.edu.pl</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anna Klukowska</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Instytut Hematologii i Transfuzjologii</name>
      <address>
        <city>Warszawa</city>
        <zip>02-776</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+482234961581</phone>
      <email>jwindyga@ihit.waw.pl</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jerzy Windyga</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital de Cruces</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barakaldo</city>
        <state>Vizcaya</state>
        <zip>48903</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+34946006089</phone>
      <email>delorbebarreto2@osakidetza.eus</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rafael Andres Del Ombre Barreto</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Inselspital -Universitaetsspital Bern</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bern</city>
        <zip>3010</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+41316329022</phone>
      <email>johanna.kremer@insel.ch</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Johanna Kremer Hovinga</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University College London Hospitals</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Greater London</state>
        <zip>NW12PG</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>+442034479984</phone>
      <email>marie.scully@uclh.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marie Ann Scully</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Japan</country>
    <country>Poland</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 10, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Purpura</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Purpura, Thrombocytopenic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Purpura, Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Takeda provides access to the de-identified individual participant data (IPD) for eligible studies to aid qualified researchers in addressing legitimate scientific objectives (Takeda's data sharing commitment is available on https://clinicaltrials.takeda.com/takedas-commitment?commitment=5). These IPDs will be provided in a secure research environment following approval of a data sharing request, and under the terms of a data sharing agreement.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_access_criteria>IPD from eligible studies will be shared with qualified researchers according to the criteria and process described on https://vivli.org/ourmember/takeda/. For approved requests, the researchers will be provided access to anonymized data (to respect patient privacy in line with applicable laws and regulations) and with information necessary to address the research objectives under the terms of a data sharing agreement.</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>https://vivli.org/ourmember/takeda/</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

