<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04681144</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21517</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04681144</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Learn More About How Radium-223 Affects the Quality of Life of Colombian Patients With Prostate Cancer That Has Not Responded to Testosterone Lowering Treatment and Has Spread to the Bones, and to Better Understand Its Safety</brief_title>
  <acronym>QOLRAD</acronym>
  <official_title>Describing the Quality Of Life in Colombian Patients mCRPC Under Treatment With RADium-223.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bayer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bayer</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study drug, radium-223, gives off radiation that helps to kill cancer cells in the&#xD;
      prostate. It is already available for patients to receive as a treatment for prostate cancer&#xD;
      that has not responded to testosterone lowering treatment and has spread to the bones. This&#xD;
      type of cancer is called metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer, also called mCRPC.&#xD;
      Sometimes, researchers continue studying an available treatment to learn more about how it&#xD;
      affects patients' daily lives.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, the researchers want to learn more about how radium-223 affects the patients'&#xD;
      ability to do their daily tasks. The patients in this study will already be receiving&#xD;
      treatment with radium-223 as part of their routine care. The tests and measurements in this&#xD;
      study will be done by the patients' own doctors. The researchers will collect information&#xD;
      about the patients' treatment and results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will include patients with mCRPC who have at least 2 tumors in their bones. These&#xD;
      patients will have recently started treatment with radium-223. The patients will have also&#xD;
      had surgery or treatment to lower their testosterone levels. But, the treatment did not help&#xD;
      their cancer. The study will include about 105 men in Colombia who are at least 18 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All of the patients will receive radium-223 through a needle put into the vein, also called&#xD;
      an intravenous injection. They will visit their doctor's office up to 8 times during 28&#xD;
      weeks. At these visits, their doctors will ask how they are feeling and what medications they&#xD;
      are taking, and will take blood samples. The doctors will also give the patients surveys&#xD;
      about their physical, social, and emotional health and about the symptoms of their prostate&#xD;
      cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 16, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 15, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 15, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for FACT-P</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-Prostate (FACT-P): It is a multidimension, selfreport QoL instrument specifically designed for patients with prostate cancer. It consists of 39 questions items, made up by 2 parts: the 27 questions for functional assessment of cancer therapy general (FACT-G) and 12 prostate cancer subscale questions. It assesses 4 main domains which are: physical (n=7), social/family (n=7), emotional (n=6) and functional wellbeing (n=7).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for FACT-P</measure>
    <time_frame>At week 12</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for FACT-P</measure>
    <time_frame>At week 16</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for FACT-P</measure>
    <time_frame>At week 24</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for FACT-P</measure>
    <time_frame>At week 28</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for EORTC QLQ-PR25</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline</time_frame>
    <description>European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer Quality of Life Questionnaire Prostate Specific module (EORTC QLQ-PR25): It is a questionnaire with score calculation is by subscales: urinary symptoms, bother due to use of incontinence aid, bowel symptoms, hormonal treatment-related symptoms, sexual activity and sexual functioning. Absolute score [scores are linearly transformed to a 0-100 scale, with higher scores reflecting either more symptoms (urinary, bowel, hormonal treatment-related symptoms) or higher levels of activity or functioning (sexual).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for EORTC QLQ-PR25</measure>
    <time_frame>At week 12</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for EORTC QLQ-PR25</measure>
    <time_frame>At week 16</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for EORTC QLQ-PR25</measure>
    <time_frame>At week 24</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for EORTC QLQ-PR25</measure>
    <time_frame>At week 28</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for Physical Well Being, Social/Family Well Being, Emotional Well Functional Well Being, in the FACT-P</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for urinary and bowel symptoms, sexual activity and function, and adverse effects to treatments in the EORTC QLQ-PR25</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for FACT-P; according to number of Radium-223 cycles</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
    <description>Number of cycles of Radium-223 will be measured as total number of doses received.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for EORTC QLQ-PR25; according to number of Radium-223 cycles</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
    <description>Number of cycles of Radium-223 will be measured as total number of doses received.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for FACT-P; according line of treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
    <description>Line of treatment is classified as first , second or third line agent according to formulation scheme.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for EORTC QLQ-PR25; according line of treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
    <description>Line of treatment is classified as first , second or third line agent according to formulation scheme.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for FACT-P; according to prior use or chemotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
    <description>Patients will be classified as prior chemotherapy or chemotherapy naïve</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for EORTC QLQ-PR25; according to prior use or chemotherapy.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
    <description>Patients will be classified as prior chemotherapy or chemotherapy naïve</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for FACT-P; according to clinical characteristics.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical characteristics: Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) 0-1, more than 2 bone metastasis, no visceral metastasis, Neutrophils: &gt; 1.500 L (&gt;1.5 x10exp9/L, Hemoglobin: &gt; a 10 g/dL, Platelets: &gt; a 100.000 (&gt;100x10exp9/L).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for EORTC QLQ-PR25; according to clinical characteristics.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical characteristics: ECOG 0-1, more than 2 bone metastasis, no visceral metastasis, Neutrophils: &gt; 1.500 L (&gt;1.5 x10exp9/L, Hemoglobin: &gt; a 10 g/dL, Platelets: &gt; a 100.000 (&gt;100x10exp9/L).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for FACT-P; according to changes in PSA.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
    <description>Prostate specific antigen (PSA) level will be measured in subject's blood from baseline and every 2 months after that in accordance with the San Gallen protocol(3) stablish in the routine clinical practice as guidelines for management. The percent change from the baseline value will be calculated as followed: (PSA level at week n - PSA level from baseline)/(PSA level from baseline)*100</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for EORTC QLQ-PR25; according to changes in PSA</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
    <description>PSA level will be measured in subject's blood from baseline and every 2 months after that in accordance with the San Gallen protocol(3) stablish in the routine clinical practice as guidelines for management. The percent change from the baseline value will be calculated as followed: (PSA level at week n - PSA level from baseline)/(PSA level from baseline)*100</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for FACT-P; according to changes in ALP level</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
    <description>Alkaline phosphatase (ALP) level will be measured in subject's blood from baseline and every 2 months after that in accordance with the San Gallen protocol(3) stablish in the routine clinical practice as guidelines for management. The percent change from the baseline value will be calculated as followed: (ALP level at week n - ALP level from baseline)/(ALP level from baseline)*100</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute scores for EORTC QLQ-PR25; according to changes in ALP level</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12, 16, 24- and 28-weeks and follow up visit week 28; 4 weeks post last injection</time_frame>
    <description>ALP level will be measured in subject's blood from baseline and every 2 months after that in accordance with the San Gallen protocol(3) stablish in the routine clinical practice as guidelines for management. The percent change from the baseline value will be calculated as followed: (ALP level at week n - ALP level from baseline)/(ALP level from baseline)*100</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">105</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Radium-223-dichloride (Xofigo, BAY88-8223)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Radium-223-dichloride (Xofigo, BAY88-8223)</intervention_name>
    <description>Decision to initiate treatment with Radium-223 made as per investigator's routine treatment practice</description>
    <arm_group_label>Radium-223-dichloride (Xofigo, BAY88-8223)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Colombian patients diagnosed with metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male adult patients (&gt; 18 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Label Xofigo&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No participation in an investigational program with interventions outside of routine&#xD;
             clinical practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Decision to initiate treatment with Radium-223 made as per investigator's routine&#xD;
             treatment practice, as treatment option for mCRPC either as first line (naïve), second&#xD;
             line (after progression during treatment with enzalutamide or abiraterone) or third&#xD;
             line (post-Docetaxel).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with contraindications to the use of Radium-223 according to the local label.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients and who refused to sign the informed consent form.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bayer Clinical Trials Contact</last_name>
    <phone>(+)1-888-84 22937</phone>
    <email>clinical-trials-contact@bayer.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Many Locations</name>
      <address>
        <city>Multiple Locations</city>
        <country>Colombia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Colombia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 23, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Bone metastatic castration resistant prostate cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Radium-223</keyword>
  <keyword>mCRPC</keyword>
  <keyword>Phase IV</keyword>
  <keyword>Advance prostate cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
  <keyword>Bone Cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Radium Ra 223 dichloride</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Availability of this study's data will later be determined according to Bayer's commitment to the EFPIA/PhRMA &quot;Principles for responsible clinical trial data sharing&quot;. This pertains to scope, timepoint and process of data access. As such, Bayer commits to sharing upon request from qualified researchers patient-level clinical trial data, study-level clinical trial data, and protocols from clinical trials in patients for medicines and indications approved in the US and EU as necessary for conducting legitimate research. This applies to data on new medicines and indications that have been approved by the EU and US regulatory agencies on or after January 01, 2014. Interested researchers can use www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com to request access to anonymized patient-level data and supporting documents from clinical studies to conduct research. Information on the Bayer criteria for listing studies and other relevant information is provided in the Study sponsors section of the portal.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

