<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04687735</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-2357-3002-5</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04687735</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Frozen Shoulder Single Arm Prospective Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Minimally Invasive Technique to Increase the Range of Motion of the Shoulder Joint in Frozen Shoulder: Single Arm Prospective Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Allevio Pain Management Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Allevio Pain Management Clinic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effect of combination of brachial plexus block&#xD;
      plus physical therapy on quality of life improvement in patients with frozen shoulder&#xD;
      condition via standard questionnaires.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      STUDY OBJECTIVES The primary objective is to evaluate the effect of combination of regional&#xD;
      anesthesia and physical therapy measured as an improvement in pain related disability scores&#xD;
      of the impaired shoulder using the Shoulder Disability Questionnaire (SDQ), Shoulder Pain and&#xD;
      Disability Index (SPADI), and improvement in pain score measured by Brief Pain Inventory&#xD;
      (BPI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives are to evaluate the effect of treatment on the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Anxiety, measured by General Anxiety Disorder Questionnaire (GAD-7)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Depression, measured by Beck's Depression Inventory (BDI)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Satisfaction, measured by Global Improvement and Satisfaction Score (GISS) STUDY DESIGN&#xD;
           This is as a single-center, prospective cohort study. The study does not imply any new&#xD;
           intervention; all decisions regarding the treatment will be made at the sole discretion&#xD;
           of the treating physician as part of clinical care. The study will be conducted over a&#xD;
           period of 14 months, including approximately 1-2 months of enrolment, 4-6 weeks of&#xD;
           treatment and follow-up at 3, 6, 12 months after the initiation of treatment for frozen&#xD;
           shoulder. Treatment 1 can be scheduled along with baseline consult and screening (Day&#xD;
           0), three to five more treatment visits (Treatment 2 to Treatment 6) will be scheduled&#xD;
           weekly (4-6 treatments in total), and follow up visits on 3, 6, and 12 months (with&#xD;
           ±1week window). If patient has achieved any early full ROM, treatment will be stopped&#xD;
           according to the physicians' decision. The study will be conducted at the Allevio Pain&#xD;
           Clinic, Toronto, Canada. Research Ethics approvals will be sought.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY POPULATION Patients with unilateral or bilateral frozen shoulder in any stage will be&#xD;
      screened for study eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY INTERVENTION&#xD;
&#xD;
      1st part of treatment: (by Anesthesiologist) Treatment will be provided to all eligible&#xD;
      patients at baseline visit (Day 0). In the procedure room, after exposing the affected&#xD;
      shoulder, the skin of the shoulder and neck on the affected area will be be prepared with the&#xD;
      mixture of chlorhexidine and alcohol. The position of the patient will be decided based on&#xD;
      the preference of the practitioner for performing brachial plexus block. Some of our&#xD;
      practitioners prefer to perform the procedure on supine position and some prefer lateral&#xD;
      position. Any difference in performing the brachial plexus block on supine or lateral&#xD;
      position is not expected. Furthermore, using a familiar position for the anesthesiologist&#xD;
      performing the brachial plexus block only adds to the safety of the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The anesthesiologist will use ultrasound and a sterile technique to perform two procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In the first step, with the guidance of ultrasound, brachial plexus block (inter scalene&#xD;
           approach) will be provided. In total, 10 mL of a very dilute local anesthetic, marcaine&#xD;
           0.08 %, would be injected. The real-time guidance of ultrasound will be used to monitor&#xD;
           the whole procedure. By using an ultrasound guidance, the practitioner wiill make sure&#xD;
           that the local anesthetic has reached to all three nerve roots in inter scalene space.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In the second step of the procedure, the patient will be asked to sit up. In this step,&#xD;
           normal saline will be injected into the shoulder joint. The posterior approach will be&#xD;
           used with the real-time guidance of ultrasound. Depending on the compliance of the&#xD;
           shoulder joint, between 10-40 mL of normal saline will be injected. The target area for&#xD;
           normal saline is between the shoulder capsule and the head of the humorous. The goal is&#xD;
           to use the hydrostatic pressure to lift the capsule and separate the layers of adhesion&#xD;
           from the cartilage of the head of humorous.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patient will stay in the recovery area for 15 minutes after both interventions are&#xD;
      performed. For the entire duration of both procedures, pulse rate, blood pressure, and oxygen&#xD;
      saturation in the room air will continuously be monitored every 5 minutes. Then the patient&#xD;
      will be moved to another area of the clinic to start physical therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical therapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the consult plus treatment day, assessment of the shoulder will begin in the seated&#xD;
      position. The range of passive external rotation will be measured with the elbow held tight&#xD;
      to the torso and bent at 90 degrees. Care will be taken to ensure that the patient does not&#xD;
      rotate at the trunk during external rotation of the shoulder. Manual palpation of the&#xD;
      coracoid process and deltoid insertion will be performed to check for pain and/or point&#xD;
      sensitivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patient then will be placed in the supine position to check passive flexion and abduction&#xD;
      of the shoulder. Care will be taken to ensure the patient does not hike the shoulder towards&#xD;
      the ear during the passive abduction or arch the back during passive flexion, thereby&#xD;
      allowing evaluation solely of the rotator cuff. Due to the relatively small sample size and&#xD;
      working within a very active clinic environment, a visual estimation of the passive ROM will&#xD;
      be recorded in 20-degree increments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After physical assessment and suitability confirmation, patients will be scheduled for 4-6&#xD;
      treatment appointments where they will undergo brachial plexus block and shoulder joint&#xD;
      injection by the anesthesiologist before passive mobilization performed by the chiropractor.&#xD;
      Each passive mobilization treatment will be generally 20 minutes in duration. Care will be&#xD;
      directed solely at the affected shoulder, and no other passive modalities will be applied&#xD;
      other than manual mobilization. The patient will be given three home based exercises to&#xD;
      perform. These exercises are pendulums, passive external rotation against a door frame, and&#xD;
      active wall walks within the patient's pain tolerance. The patient will be asked to perform 2&#xD;
      sets of exercises once a day, at 10 repetitions per set.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY VISITS AND PROCEDURES Study visits and related procedures are displayed in Table 1.&#xD;
      During the screening visit the study coordinator will obtain informed consent and perform&#xD;
      eligibility check, (which has been explained in recruitment section). Additional visits may&#xD;
      be required to address patient questions and to sign informed consent, collect demographics&#xD;
      (age, gender, race), medical history, clinical data. Qualified participants will be scheduled&#xD;
      for their combined appointment with anesthesiologist and chiropractor at the same time&#xD;
      (Baseline visit), and thereafter every week for 4-6 weeks depend on ROM achievement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the baseline visit, after routine documentation of the blood pressure, heart rate and&#xD;
      saturation of oxygen in room air and completion of baseline questionnaires, the patient would&#xD;
      move to the procedure room to receive the intervention that is described above.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Questionnaires will also be collected at each follow-up visits. Furthermore, the investigator&#xD;
      will perform the following procedures at all visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  perform clinical examination,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  report adverse events (AE) and/or serious adverse events (SAE), and&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  complete relevant section of case report form (CRF)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>single-center, prospective cohort study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>changes in disability score</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>measured by Shoulder Disability Questionnaire (descriptive format No= no disability, Yes= disable)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>changes in disability score</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>measured by Shoulder Pain and Disability Index, min 0, max 10, 0 means no pain and disability and 10 means the worst pain and disability</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in pain score (If there is any pain)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>measured by short form of Brief Pain Inventory Questionnaire min 0, max 10, 0 means no pain and disability and 10 means the worst pain and disability</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in anxiety score</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>measured by General Anxiety Disorder Questionnaire min 0, max 21, 0 means no anxiety and 21 means the maximum anxiety</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in depression score</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>measured by Beck's Depression Inventory min 0, max 40, 0 means no depression and 40 means the sever depression</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in treatment satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>using the Global Improvement and Satisfaction Score, between 1 to 5, 1 very dissatisfied, and 5 very satisfied</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency and duration of treatment related side</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">34</enrollment>
  <condition>Frozen Shoulder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with frozen shoulders at any stage</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intervention after nerve block</intervention_name>
    <description>Brachial plexus block + Physical therapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of unilateral or bilateral frozen shoulder, defined as greater than 50%&#xD;
             limitation of passive ROM relative to the non affected side in one or more of three&#xD;
             movement directions (i.e., abduction in the frontal plane, forward flexion in the&#xD;
             sagittal plane, or external rotation in 0° of abduction) with a hard end feel&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptoms of frozen shoulder that had lasted for at least 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to provide informed consent and perform home-based exercises as&#xD;
             instructed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to complete study questionnaires&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous manipulation of the affected shoulder under anesthesia in the last year;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other rheumatic conditions involving the shoulder (e.g., rheumatoid arthritis,&#xD;
             ankylosing Spondylitis,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fracture or dislocation of the affected shoulder;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous shoulder surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hill-Sachs lesion, severe osteoporosis, or malignancies in the shoulder region);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurologic deficits affecting shoulder function;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergy to lidocaine;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Corticosteroid injection in the affected shoulder during the receding 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-English speakers;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active non- controlled mental disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Multiple complete tear in ligaments of rotator cuff&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any infection including COVID-19&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ramin Safakish, MD, FRCPC</last_name>
    <phone>6474788462</phone>
    <email>Ramin.Safakish@AllevioClinic.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Michael Lehr, D.C</last_name>
    <phone>6474788462</phone>
    <email>Michael.Lehr@AllevioClinic.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Allevio Pain Management</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M3B 3S6</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ramin Safakish, MD, FRCPC</last_name>
      <phone>6474788462</phone>
      <email>Ramin.Safakish@Allevioclinic.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Michael Lehr, D.C., Dip.Ac., Hons.BSc</last_name>
      <phone>6474788462</phone>
      <email>Michael.Lehr@Allevioclinic.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Pal B, Anderson J, Dick WC, Griffiths ID. Limitation of joint mobility and shoulder capsulitis in insulin- and non-insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus. Br J Rheumatol. 1986 May;25(2):147-51.</citation>
    <PMID>3708230</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Uppal HS, Evans JP, Smith C. Frozen shoulder: A systematic review of therapeutic options. World J Orthop. 2015 Mar 18;6(2):263-8. doi: 10.5312/wjo.v6.i2.263. eCollection 2015 Mar 18. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25793166</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hand GC, Athanasou NA, Matthews T, Carr AJ. The pathology of frozen shoulder. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2007 Jul;89(7):928-32.</citation>
    <PMID>17673588</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Rodeo SA, Hannafin JA, Tom J, Warren RF, Wickiewicz TL. Immunolocalization of cytokines and their receptors in adhesive capsulitis of the shoulder. J Orthop Res. 1997 May;15(3):427-36.</citation>
    <PMID>9246090</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tamai K, Akutsu M, Yano Y. Primary frozen shoulder: brief review of pathology and imaging abnormalities. J Orthop Sci. 2014 Jan;19(1):1-5. doi: 10.1007/s00776-013-0495-x. Epub 2013 Dec 4. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24306579</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Riddle DL, Rothstein JM, Lamb RL. Goniometric reliability in a clinical setting. Shoulder measurements. Phys Ther. 1987 May;67(5):668-73.</citation>
    <PMID>3575423</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Neviaser AS, Hannafin JA. Adhesive capsulitis: a review of current treatment. Am J Sports Med. 2010 Nov;38(11):2346-56. doi: 10.1177/0363546509348048. Epub 2010 Jan 28. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20110457</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Homsi C, Bordalo-Rodrigues M, da Silva JJ, Stump XM. Ultrasound in adhesive capsulitis of the shoulder: is assessment of the coracohumeral ligament a valuable diagnostic tool? Skeletal Radiol. 2006 Sep;35(9):673-8. Epub 2006 May 25.</citation>
    <PMID>16724200</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ando A, Hamada J, Hagiwara Y, Sekiguchi T, Koide M, Itoi E. Short-term Clinical Results of Manipulation Under Ultrasound-Guided Brachial Plexus Block in Patients with Idiopathic Frozen Shoulder and Diabetic Secondary Frozen Shoulder. Open Orthop J. 2018 Mar 16;12:99-104. doi: 10.2174/1874325001812010099. eCollection 2018.</citation>
    <PMID>29619123</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>YAMSHON LJ. Frozen shoulder: methods for bringing about early mobilization. Calif Med. 1958 Nov;89(5):333-4.</citation>
    <PMID>13585158</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hsu WC, Wang TL, Lin YJ, Hsieh LF, Tsai CM, Huang KH. Addition of lidocaine injection immediately before physiotherapy for frozen shoulder: a randomized controlled trial. PLoS One. 2015 Feb 25;10(2):e0118217. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0118217. eCollection 2015. Erratum in: PLoS One. 2015;10(4):e0125289.</citation>
    <PMID>25714415</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kanbe K. Clinical outcome of arthroscopic capsular release for frozen shoulder: essential technical points in 255 patients. J Orthop Surg Res. 2018 Mar 16;13(1):56. doi: 10.1186/s13018-018-0758-5.</citation>
    <PMID>29548325</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Paul A, Rajkumar JS, Peter S, Lambert L. Effectiveness of sustained stretching of the inferior capsule in the management of a frozen shoulder. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2014 Jul;472(7):2262-8. doi: 10.1007/s11999-014-3581-2. Epub 2014 Mar 25.</citation>
    <PMID>24664198</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Rymaruk S, Peach C. Indications for hydrodilatation for frozen shoulder. EFORT Open Rev. 2017 Nov 22;2(11):462-468. doi: 10.1302/2058-5241.2.160061. eCollection 2017 Nov.</citation>
    <PMID>29218231</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Maund E, Craig D, Suekarran S, Neilson A, Wright K, Brealey S, Dennis L, Goodchild L, Hanchard N, Rangan A, Richardson G, Robertson J, McDaid C. Management of frozen shoulder: a systematic review and cost-effectiveness analysis. Health Technol Assess. 2012;16(11):1-264. doi: 10.3310/hta16110. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22405512</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Lewis J. Frozen shoulder contracture syndrome - Aetiology, diagnosis and management. Man Ther. 2015 Feb;20(1):2-9. doi: 10.1016/j.math.2014.07.006. Epub 2014 Jul 18. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25107826</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Rookmoneea M, Dennis L, Brealey S, Rangan A, White B, McDaid C, Harden M. The effectiveness of interventions in the management of patients with primary frozen shoulder. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2010 Sep;92(9):1267-72. doi: 10.1302/0301-620X.92B9.24282. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20798446</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vastamäki H, Varjonen L, Vastamäki M. Optimal time for manipulation of frozen shoulder may be between 6 and 9 months. Scand J Surg. 2015 Dec;104(4):260-6. doi: 10.1177/1457496914566637. Epub 2015 Jan 26.</citation>
    <PMID>25623916</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JB, Löwe B. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Arch Intern Med. 2006 May 22;166(10):1092-7.</citation>
    <PMID>16717171</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 3, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Brachial Plexus Block</keyword>
  <keyword>Physical Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bursitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

