<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04683185</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>E6742-J081-005</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>jRCT2031200316</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04683185</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Assess the Safety and Tolerability of E6742 in Japanese Healthy Adult Participants</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Multiple Ascending Dose Study to Assess the Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetics of E6742 in Japanese Healthy Adult Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Eisai Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Eisai Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary purpose of the study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability and pharmacokinetics&#xD;
      (PK) of multiple ascending oral doses of E6742 in Japanese healthy adult participants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 28, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 21, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 21, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Treatment-emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs) and Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 28 days after the last dose of study drug (approximately Day 35)</time_frame>
    <description>Safety assessments will consist of monitoring and recording all adverse events (AEs) and SAEs; laboratory evaluation for hematology, blood chemistry, and urine values; periodic measurement of vital signs and electrocardiograms (ECGs); and the performance of physical examinations.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax: Maximum Observed Plasma Concentration for E6742 and its Metabolite (ER-001132963) on Day 1</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1: 0-12 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>tmax: Time at Which the Highest Drug Plasma Concentration Occurs for E6742 and its Metabolite (ER-001132963) on Day 1</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1: 0-12 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC(0-12h): Area Under the Plasma Concentration-time Curve From Zero Time to 12 Hours Postdose for E6742 and its Metabolite (ER-001132963) on Day 1</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1: 0-12 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC Metabolite to E6742 Ratio Following Molecular Weight Correction to E6742 Equivalents on Day 1</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1: 0-12 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Css,max: Maximum Observed Plasma Concentration at Steady State for E6742 and its Metabolite (ER-001132963) on Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7: 0-168 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>tss,max: Time at Which the Highest Drug Plasma Concentration Occurs at Steady State for E6742 and its Metabolite (ER-001132963) on Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7: 0-168 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Css,av: Average Steady State Plasma Concentration for E6742 and its Metabolite (ER-001132963) on Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7: 0-168 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC(0-t): Area Under the Plasma Concentration-time Curve From Zero Time to Time of Last Quantifiable Concentration for E6742 and its Metabolite (ER-001132963) on Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7: 0-168 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC(0-12hr): Area Under the Plasma Concentration-time Curve Within a Dosing Interval at Steady State for E6742 and its Metabolite (ER-001132963) on Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7: 0-12 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>t1/2: Terminal Elimination Phase Half-life for E6742 and its Metabolite (ER-001132963) on Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7: 0-168 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CLss/F: Apparent Total Clearance at Steady State for E6742 on Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7: 0-168 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Vss/F: Apparent Volume of Distribution at Steady State for E6742 on Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7: 0-168 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PTF: Peak-trough Fluctuation for E6742 and its Metabolite (ER-001132963) on Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7: 0-168 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Accumulation Ratio for Cmax and AUC for E6742 and its Metabolite (ER-001132963) on Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7: 0-168 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Metabolite to E6742 AUC Ratio Following Molecular Weight Correction to E6742 Equivalents on Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7: 0-168 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC(0-12hr)ss: Area Under the Plasma Concentration-time Curve Within a Dosing Interval at Steady State for E6742 and its Metabolite (ER-001132963) on Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7: 0-12 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Corrected QT Interval (QTc) for E6742</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 and 7: 0-12 hours</time_frame>
    <description>High precision method QT analysis (HPQT) will be performed using data extracted from the 12-hour holter recording obtained from the morning of day 1 (predose) through 12 hours after dosing, the morning of day 7 (predose) through 12 hours after dosing.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Volunteers</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2: E6742 200 mg or Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive E6742 200 mg or E6742-matched placebo, tablets, orally, twice daily for 6 days under fasted conditions and once on Day 7 in the morning.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 3: E6742 400 mg or Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive E6742 400 mg or E6742-matched placebo, tablets, orally, twice daily for 6 days under fasted conditions and once on Day 7 in the morning.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1: E6742 100 milligram (mg) or Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive E6742 100 mg or E6742-matched placebo, tablets, orally, twice daily for 6 days under fasted conditions and once on Day 7 in the morning.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>E6742</intervention_name>
    <description>E6742 tablets.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1: E6742 100 milligram (mg) or Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2: E6742 200 mg or Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 3: E6742 400 mg or Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>E6742-matched placebo tablets.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1: E6742 100 milligram (mg) or Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2: E6742 200 mg or Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 3: E6742 400 mg or Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Non-smoking, male or female Japanese, greater than or equal to (&gt;=) age 20 years and&#xD;
             less than or equal to (&lt;=) 55 years old at the time of informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Body mass index (BMI) &gt;=18.5 and less than (&lt;) 25.0 kilogram per meter square (kg/m^2)&#xD;
             at Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Females who are breastfeeding or pregnant at Screening or Baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Females of childbearing potential who:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Within 28 days before study entry, did not use a highly effective method of&#xD;
                  contraception, which includes any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Total abstinence&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  An intrauterine device (IUD) or intrauterine hormone-releasing system (IUS)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  A contraceptive implant&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  An oral contraceptive&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Have a vasectomized partner with confirmed azoospermia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Do not agree to use a highly effective method of contraception (as described&#xD;
                  above) throughout the entire study period and for 28 days after study drug&#xD;
                  discontinuation&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Males who have not had a successful vasectomy (confirmed azoospermia) or they and&#xD;
             their female partners do not meet the criteria above (that is, not of childbearing&#xD;
             potential or practicing highly effective contraception throughout the study period and&#xD;
             for 5 times the half-life of the study drug plus 90 days after study drug&#xD;
             discontinuation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Clinically significant illness that requires medical treatment within 8 weeks or a&#xD;
             clinically significant infection within 4 weeks before dosing&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any history of gastrointestinal surgery that may affect PK profiles of E6742 at&#xD;
             Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any clinically abnormal symptom or organ impairment found by medical history,&#xD;
             ophthalmic examination or chest X ray test at Screening, or founded by physical&#xD;
             examinations, vital signs, ECG finding, or laboratory test results at Screening or&#xD;
             Baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. A prolonged QTc corrected using Fridericia's method (QTcF) interval (QTcF greater than&#xD;
             [&gt;] 450 millisecond [ms]) demonstrated on ECG at Screening or Baseline. A history of&#xD;
             risk factors for torsade de pointes or the use of concomitant medications that&#xD;
             prolonged the QT/QTc interval&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Persistent systolic blood pressure &gt;130 millimeter of mercury (mmHg) or diastolic&#xD;
             blood pressure &gt;85 mmHg diastolic at Screening or Baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Heart rate less than 45 or more than 100 beats per min at Screening or Baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Any lifetime history of suicidal ideation or any lifetime history of suicidal behavior&#xD;
             as indicated by the Suicidal Ideation section of the Columbia Suicide Severity Rating&#xD;
             Scale (C-SSRS)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Any lifetime history of psychiatric disease&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Any current psychiatric symptoms as indicated by a standard screening tool (Patient&#xD;
             Health Questionnaire 9 [PHQ 9])&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Any suicidal ideation with intent with or without a plan within Screening or 6 months&#xD;
             before Screening (that is, answering &quot;Yes&quot; to questions 4 or 5 on the C-SSRS)&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. History of autoimmune disease or immunodeficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Known to be positive for tuberculosis test (T-spot. TB Test) at Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Received immunoglobulin or blood preparation within 6 months before the study&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Received inoculation within 4 weeks before the study treatment (8 weeks before in case&#xD;
             of live or attenuated vaccine)&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Family living together or cohabitant of a patient with an influenza virus infection&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. In contact with Coronavirus disease (COVID 19) patient within 4 weeks before study&#xD;
             drug administration&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Known to be other than negative for Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2&#xD;
             (SARS Cov 2) antibody test at Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Known to be other than negative for SARS Cov 2 polymerase chain reaction (PCR) test at&#xD;
             Screening or Baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. History of retinopathy, maculopathy or macular degeneration&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Eisai Trial Site #1</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bunkyō-Ku</city>
        <state>Tokyo</state>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://jrct.niph.go.jp/en-latest-detail/jRCT2031200316</url>
    <description>Study results will be disclosed on the jRCT registry record.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>E6742</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy participants</keyword>
  <keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Eisai's data sharing commitment and further information on how to request data can be found on our website http://eisaiclinicaltrials.com/.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

