<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04682392</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PAR20-0625-ACL-bonehealth</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04682392</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>ACL Bone Health and Loading Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>ACLBONE</acronym>
  <official_title>The Effects of Bone Health on Landing Mechanics on Patients Post ACL Reconstruction.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bryan Bourcier</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Parkview Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Parkview Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to look at the effects of bone density on lower extremity&#xD;
      loading mechanics using Blood Flow Restriction (BFR) to provide the control group for bone&#xD;
      health.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: The BFR group will have decreased bone mineral loss and improved functional&#xD;
      performance compared to control group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Group 1 - ACL without BFR : 30 athletes with ACL tears and will NOT do blood flow restriction&#xD;
      (BFR). Random group allocation will be determined using envelopes for allocation concealment.&#xD;
      The control group will be tested with a Dexascan immediately post appointment confirming MRI&#xD;
      findings of ACL tear and scheduling surgery. They will be then Scanned again at first therapy&#xD;
      appointment within 24-48 hours of surgery. Then Dexascans will be done every 4 weeks until 28&#xD;
      weeks with a maximum of 9 scans. The scans will be completed on a normally scheduled&#xD;
      rehabilitation session at the convenience of the radiology techs availability. The&#xD;
      investigators will collect force plate measurements for squat symmetry at first 4-week&#xD;
      assessment period, and then for landing symmetry every 4 weeks after that until 28 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 2 - ACL with BFR: 30 athletes with ACL tear that will receive BFR. This group will be&#xD;
      selected in the same manner as the control group. They will be tested with a dexasan&#xD;
      immediately post appointment confirming MRI findings of ACL tear and scheduling surgery. At&#xD;
      the initial dexascan they will also be instructed in Blood flow restriction and do exercises&#xD;
      with blood flow restriction to prepare for initial post-surgical visit. They will be then&#xD;
      scanned again at first therapy appointment within 24-48 hours of surgery. Then Dexascans will&#xD;
      be done every 4 weeks until 28 weeks with a maximum of 9 scans. The investigators will&#xD;
      collect force plate measurements for squat symmetry at first 4-week assessment and then for&#xD;
      landing symmetry every 4 weeks after that until 28 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The standard of care following ACL tear does not include Dexascan, force plate measurements,&#xD;
      or blood flow restriction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Independent Variable&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. Blood Flow Restrictions (BFR) Dependent Variable&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Landing mechanics / force distribution&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Bone Mineral Density /Bone mass&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Lean Muscle Mass (LM)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Pain via Visual Analogue Scale (VAS)&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Quad Strength using microFET®2 Digital Handheld Dynamometer&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Hamstring strength using microFET®2 Digital Handheld Dynamometer&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. SL Hop Distance&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Triple Hop Distance&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Crossover hop Distance&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Keiser leg press max power at 5 reps at body weight&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures: Once a participant has been identified as meeting the inclusion criteria with a&#xD;
      positive MRI finding and have agreed to schedule surgery, they will be allocated to either&#xD;
      the control or experimental group. Random group allocation will be determined using envelopes&#xD;
      for allocation concealment. Prior to initiation of the study, a research assistant not&#xD;
      involved in data collection will use a random number generator to create the randomization&#xD;
      sequence allocating an equal number of participants to each of the 2 groups, the control non&#xD;
      BFR group and the experimental BFR group. The randomization will be concealed by having the&#xD;
      group assignment placed inside a sealed opaque envelope within potential participant folders.&#xD;
      This process will be documented and signed by the randomizer. Once selected and enrolled, the&#xD;
      group assignment will be revealed and will not be blinded to either the participant or the&#xD;
      researchers. The pre-op therapy session will be completed 48-72 hours following MRI&#xD;
      confirmation of ACL tear if they have opted for surgical intervention. The initial post-op&#xD;
      therapy session will be completed within 24-48 hours of surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will undergo bone mineral density (BMD), bone mass, and lean muscle mass&#xD;
      (LM) measurements using Dexascan at pre-op visit, and again at initial post op visit ad then&#xD;
      every 4 weeks from week 4-16.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will also complete a total of 9 landing/jumping trials as part of testing, with&#xD;
      rest as needed. Following the warm-up, subjects will complete 3 drop landings, 3 drop&#xD;
      vertical jumps, and 3 countermovement jumps. The participant must demonstrate safe landing&#xD;
      mechanics on the drop landings as determined by testing PT in order to attempt the drop&#xD;
      vertical jumps and the countermovement jumps.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Landing assessment will be collected at initial landing session at weeks 8, 12,16,20, 24, and&#xD;
      28 weeks post op.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The exercises selection and progression will be standardized for BFR intervention across all&#xD;
      subjects. The BFR group will exercise with 80% arterial limb occlusion using the Delphi&#xD;
      automated tourniquet around the proximal thigh outfitted with Doppler (Delfi®). If 80%&#xD;
      arterial limb occlusion is not tolerated by the participant, the pressure will be decreased&#xD;
      to tolerance. However, the pressure will not be lowered below 60% as there is a floor effect&#xD;
      at 60% LOP where BFR is no longer beneficial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exercises will be performed for 4 sets of 30-15-15-15 repetitions separated by 30s of rest&#xD;
      and 1 BFR exercise will be performed. SL hop, Triple hop, Crossover hop, and Keiser leg press&#xD;
      power will be measured at 12, 16, 20 and 24 weeks. Strength testing will be done with&#xD;
      microFET®2 Digital Handheld Dynamometer every 2 weeks of the rehab process in accordance with&#xD;
      standard rehab protocol.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 17, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>2 groups with Randomized group assignments</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Leg Weight distribution landing on force plates</measure>
    <time_frame>week 28 post surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Athlete landing on force plates from and 18 inch height to compare loading / weight symmetry</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bone mineral density</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 28 post surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Bone mineral density of distal femur and proximal tibia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>ACL Tear</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Delfi's PTS Personalized Tourniquet System for Blood Flow Restriction Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group will use Delfi's PTS Personalized Tourniquet System for Blood Flow Restriction for rehab.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non Delfi PTS Personalized Tourniquet System for Blood Flow Restriction Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard post operative ACL rehab without Blood flow restriction</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Delfi's PTS Personalized Tourniquet System for Blood Flow Restriction Group</intervention_name>
    <description>A Delphi Personal Tourniquet system for blood flow restriction (BFR) therapy will be applied to each treatment session for this group. They will do 3-5 exercises with the BFR system on the surgical or both lower extremities for bilateral or unilateral movements.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Delfi's PTS Personalized Tourniquet System for Blood Flow Restriction Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>A Dephi Personal Tourniquet System will be utilized for the experimental group.</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard ACL rehab</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard accelerated ACL protocol</description>
    <arm_group_label>Delfi's PTS Personalized Tourniquet System for Blood Flow Restriction Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Non Delfi PTS Personalized Tourniquet System for Blood Flow Restriction Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Athletes undergoing ACL reconstruction with or without meniscal pathology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  MRI confirming ACL tear&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Athletes ages 16-22&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any Cognitively impaired athletes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Athletes not in age range of 16-22&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Athletes who have additional ligament repair or chondral repair.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Athletes with any weight bearing restrictions greater than 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Athletes with re-tears or history of contralateral ACL tears&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Athletes with any systemic neuromuscular or balance disorders will not be allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Athletes who do not or are unable to provide consent or assent (with Parental&#xD;
             consent).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Athlete who has previously used Blood Flow Restriction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Athletes who are unable or unwilling to complete all rehabilitation with Parkview&#xD;
             Athletic Rehab at SportONE Parkview Fieldhouse&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>22 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bryan T Bourcier, DPT</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Parkview Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bryan T Bourcier, DPT</last_name>
    <phone>2607402518</phone>
    <email>bryan.bourcier@parkview.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Thomas M Ruediger, DPT</last_name>
    <phone>8106181897</phone>
    <email>thomas.ruediger@parkview.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Parkview Athletic Rehab</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Wayne</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46805</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Bryan T Bourcier, DPT</last_name>
      <phone>260-740-2518</phone>
      <email>bryan.bourcier@parkview.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Ryan Nelson, DPT</last_name>
      <phone>7657497019</phone>
      <email>ryan.nelson@parkview.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jonathan Dettmer, DPT</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Thomas Ruediger, DPT</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nyland J, Fisher B, Brand E, Krupp R, Caborn DN. Osseous deficits after anterior cruciate ligament injury and reconstruction: a systematic literature review with suggestions to improve osseous homeostasis. Arthroscopy. 2010 Sep;26(9):1248-57. doi: 10.1016/j.arthro.2010.03.017. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20810081</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thomas AC, Wojtys EM, Brandon C, Palmieri-Smith RM. Muscle atrophy contributes to quadriceps weakness after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Sci Med Sport. 2016 Jan;19(1):7-11. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2014.12.009. Epub 2015 Jan 13.</citation>
    <PMID>25683732</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lepley AS, Grooms DR, Burland JP, Davi SM, Kinsella-Shaw JM, Lepley LK. Quadriceps muscle function following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: systemic differences in neural and morphological characteristics. Exp Brain Res. 2019 May;237(5):1267-1278. doi: 10.1007/s00221-019-05499-x. Epub 2019 Mar 9.</citation>
    <PMID>30852644</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kuenze CM, Foot N, Saliba SA, Hart JM. Drop-Landing Performance and Knee-Extension Strength After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction. J Athl Train. 2015 Jun;50(6):596-602. doi: 10.4085/1062-6050-50.2.11. Epub 2015 May 15.</citation>
    <PMID>25978101</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lu Y, Patel BH, Kym C, Nwachukwu BU, Beletksy A, Forsythe B, Chahla J. Perioperative Blood Flow Restriction Rehabilitation in Patients Undergoing ACL Reconstruction: A Systematic Review. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020 Mar 25;8(3):2325967120906822. doi: 10.1177/2325967120906822. eCollection 2020 Mar. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32232065</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Centner C, Ritzmann R, Schur S, Gollhofer A, König D. Blood flow restriction increases myoelectric activity and metabolic accumulation during whole-body vibration. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019 Jun;119(6):1439-1449. doi: 10.1007/s00421-019-04134-5. Epub 2019 Apr 4.</citation>
    <PMID>30949807</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lauver JD, Cayot TE, Rotarius T, Scheuermann BW. The effect of eccentric exercise with blood flow restriction on neuromuscular activation, microvascular oxygenation, and the repeated bout effect. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017 May;117(5):1005-1015. doi: 10.1007/s00421-017-3589-x. Epub 2017 Mar 21.</citation>
    <PMID>28324168</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lauver JD, Cayot TE, Rotarius TR, Scheuermann BW. Acute Neuromuscular and Microvascular Responses to Concentric and Eccentric Exercises With Blood Flow Restriction. J Strength Cond Res. 2020 Oct;34(10):2725-2733. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003372.</citation>
    <PMID>31524780</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>9. Lambert B, Hedt CA, Jack RA, et al. Blood Flow Restriction Therapy Preserves Whole Limb Bone and Muscle Following ACL Reconstruction. Orthop J Sport Med. 2019;7(3_suppl2):2325967119S0019. doi:10.1177/2325967119S00196</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>10. Brandner CR, May AK, Clarkson MJ, Warmington SA. Reported side-effects and safety considerations for the use of blood flow restriction during exercise in practice and research. Tech Orthop. 2018;33(2):114-121. doi:10.1097/BTO.0000000000000259</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>11. Patterson SD, Hughes L, Warmington S, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise position stand: Considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Front Physiol. 2019;10(MAY):1-15. doi:10.3389/fphys.2019.00533</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Loenneke JP, Wilson JM, Wilson GJ, Pujol TJ, Bemben MG. Potential safety issues with blood flow restriction training. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011 Aug;21(4):510-8. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01290.x. Epub 2011 Mar 16. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21410544</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ladlow P, Coppack RJ, Dharm-Datta S, Conway D, Sellon E, Patterson SD, Bennett AN. Low-Load Resistance Training With Blood Flow Restriction Improves Clinical Outcomes in Musculoskeletal Rehabilitation: A Single-Blind Randomized Controlled Trial. Front Physiol. 2018 Sep 10;9:1269. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2018.01269. eCollection 2018.</citation>
    <PMID>30246795</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tennent DJ, Hylden CM, Johnson AE, Burns TC, Wilken JM, Owens JG. Blood Flow Restriction Training After Knee Arthroscopy: A Randomized Controlled Pilot Study. Clin J Sport Med. 2017 May;27(3):245-252. doi: 10.1097/JSM.0000000000000377.</citation>
    <PMID>27749358</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>15. Curran M, Bedi A, Mendias C, Wojtys EM, Kujawa M, Palmieri-Smith R. Blood Flow Restriction Training Does Not Improve Quadriceps Strength After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction. Orthop J Sport Med. 2019;7(7_suppl5):2325967119S0029. doi:10.1177/2325967119s00293</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baim S, Wilson CR, Lewiecki EM, Luckey MM, Downs RW Jr, Lentle BC. Precision assessment and radiation safety for dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry: position paper of the International Society for Clinical Densitometry. J Clin Densitom. 2005 Winter;8(4):371-8. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16311420</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Blake GM, Naeem M, Boutros M. Comparison of effective dose to children and adults from dual X-ray absorptiometry examinations. Bone. 2006 Jun;38(6):935-42. Epub 2005 Dec 22.</citation>
    <PMID>16376161</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 8, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 23, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Parkview Health</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Bryan Bourcier</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Outpatient Rehab manager</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

