<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04684563</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UPCC15420</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04684563</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>huCART19-IL18 in NHL/CLL Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I Trial of huCART19-IL18 Cells in Patients With Relapsed or Refractory CD19+ Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma (NHL) and Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pennsylvania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to find the maximum dose of huCART19-IL18 cells that is safe for&#xD;
      use in humans with Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma (NHL) and Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase I dose finding study to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and assess&#xD;
      the safety, tolerability, manufacturing feasibility, pharmacokinetics, and preliminary&#xD;
      efficacy of huCART19-IL18 cells in patients with Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma (NHL) and Chronic&#xD;
      Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL). This trial will evaluate up to 7 dose levels using the Bayesian&#xD;
      Optimal Interval (BOIN) design with accelerated titration to determine the maximum tolerated&#xD;
      dose (MTD) of huCART19-IL18 cells. Subjects will be assigned to a dose level prior to study&#xD;
      treatment based on available safety experience at the current and prior dose levels.&#xD;
      huCART19-IL18 cells will be administered to all subjects as a single intravenous (IV)&#xD;
      infusion or slow IV push, depending on the assigned dose level. For consistency, the&#xD;
      huCART19-IL18 infusions will be identified as IV infusions throughout the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 6, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2036</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2036</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This trial will evaluate up to 7 dose levels using the Bayesian Optimal Interval (BOIN) design with accelerated titration to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of huCART19-IL18 cells. Subjects will be assigned to a dose level prior to study treatment based on available safety experience at the current and prior dose levels.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Treatment-Emergent Adverse Events as assessed by CTCAE v5.0.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of manufacturing products that meet release criteria.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects who have a response</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Best Overall Response (BOR)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Response (DOR)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterize low level disease and B cell assessment in response to huCART19-IL18 cells</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Polychromatic flow cytometry-based assessment of leukemia and B cells, extent and duration of leukemic response</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterize low level disease and B cell assessment in response to huCART19-IL18 cells</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Presence or absence of malignant B cells by Next-Generation Immunoglobulin heavy chain Sequencing (NGIS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>7</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia</condition>
  <condition>Non-hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level 1a (DL1a)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>3x10^6 huCART19-IL18 cells administered as a single intravenous (IV) infusion or slow IV push</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level -1 (DL-1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>7x10^5 huCART19-IL18 cells administered as a single intravenous (IV) infusion or slow IV push; This dose level will only be explored if at least one DLT is observed at Dose Level 1a.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level 1b (DL1b)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>3x10^6 huCART19-IL18 cells following lymphodepleting chemotherapy administered as a single intravenous (IV) infusion or slow IV push</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level 2 (DL2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>7x10^6 huCART19-IL18 cells following lymphodepleting chemotherapy administered as a single intravenous (IV) infusion or slow IV push</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level 3 (DL3)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>3x10^7 huCART19-IL18 cells following lymphodepleting chemotherapy administered as a single intravenous (IV) infusion or slow IV push</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level 4 (DL4)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>7x10^7 huCART19-IL18 cells following lymphodepleting chemotherapy administered as a single intravenous (IV) infusion or slow IV push</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level 5 (DL5)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>3x10^8 huCART19-IL18 cells following lymphodepleting chemotherapy administered as a single intravenous (IV) infusion or slow IV push</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>huCART19-IL18</intervention_name>
    <description>autologous Chimeric Antigen Receptor (CAR) T cells directed against the human CD19 antigen that also express human Interleukin 18 (IL-18)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level -1 (DL-1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level 1a (DL1a)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level 1b (DL1b)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level 2 (DL2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level 3 (DL3)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level 4 (DL4)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Level 5 (DL5)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Signed informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Documentation of CD19 expression on malignant cells&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. CLL: At time of most recent relapse&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. NHL: Within 6 months of physician-investigator confirmation of eligibility as&#xD;
                  long as there has been no intervening CD19 directed therapy since expression&#xD;
                  confirmed. Results outside of this window may be used, if there is no accessible&#xD;
                  tumor site and the subject did not receive intervening CD19 directed therapy&#xD;
                  since CD19 expression was confirmed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with relapsed disease after prior allogeneic SCT must meet the following&#xD;
             criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Have no active GVHD and require no immunosuppression&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Are more than 6 months from transplant at the time of physician-investigator&#xD;
                  confirmation of eligibility&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Adequate organ function defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Creatinine ≤ 1.6 mg/dl b. ALT/AST ≤ 3x upper limit of normal range c. Direct&#xD;
             bilirubin ≤ 2.0 mg/dl, unless the subject has Gilbert's syndrome (≤3.0 mg/dl) d. Must&#xD;
             have a minimum level of pulmonary reserve defined as ≤ Grade 1 dyspnea and pulse&#xD;
             oxygen &gt; 92% on room air e. Left Ventricle Ejection Fraction (LVEF) ≥ 40% confirmed by&#xD;
             ECHO/MUGA&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Evidence of active disease. This could include circulating disease in the blood,&#xD;
             disease in the bone marrow by standard morphology, or in NHL patients, measurable&#xD;
             disease per Lugano criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Male or female age ≥ 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. ECOG Performance Status that is either 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects of reproductive potential must agree to use acceptable birth control methods,&#xD;
             as described in protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Disease-specific criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL): i. Patients with relapsed/refractory disease&#xD;
             after at least 2 prior lines of appropriate therapy; and ii. Patients must have&#xD;
             previously received, or be intolerant to an approved BTK inhibitor and venetoclax,&#xD;
             unless a BTK inhibitor or venetoclax is contraindicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
             b. Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma (NHL): i. Patients with any of the following diagnoses:&#xD;
             Diffuse Large B-cell Lymphoma not otherwise specified (DLBCL NOS), germinal center or&#xD;
             activated B-cell types; Primary Cutaneous DLBCL; Primary Mediastinal (thymic) Large&#xD;
             B-cell Lymphoma; ALK+ Anaplastic Large B-cell Lymphoma; High-Grade B-cell Lymphoma&#xD;
             with MYC and BCL2 and/or BCL6 rearrangements (i.e. &quot;Double or Triple Hit&quot;); High-grade&#xD;
             B-cell Lymphoma, NOS; T-cell Rich B-cell Lymphoma; Transformed Follicular Lymphoma; or&#xD;
             any aggressive B-cell lymphoma arising from indolent lymphoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patients must have either relapsed after, or be ineligible for, prior CAR T cell&#xD;
        therapy, and meet one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Relapsed/refractory disease after at least 2 prior lines of appropriate therapy and&#xD;
             are ineligible for autologous stem cell transplant or commercial CAR T cell therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Relapsed/refractory disease after autologous SCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Relapsed/refractory disease after allogeneic SCT. ii. Follicular lymphoma 1. Patients&#xD;
             who have received at least 2 prior lines of appropriate therapy (not including single&#xD;
             agent monoclonal antibody therapy) and progressed within 2 years after second or&#xD;
             higher line of therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        iii. Mantle cell lymphoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients must have either failed or be ineligible for standard of care Tecartus™&#xD;
             (brexucabtagene autoleucel) or other investigational CAR T cell product; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients must also meet one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Relapsed/refractory disease after at least 2 prior lines of appropriate therapy,&#xD;
                  including a BTK inhibitor. Single-agent monoclonal antibody therapy does not&#xD;
                  count towards prior lines of therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Relapsed/refractory disease after prior autologous SCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Relapsed/refractory disease after prior allogeneic SCT. iv. Large cell&#xD;
                  transformation of CLL (Richter's Transformation)&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patients must be primary refractory or received at least 1 prior line of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Active hepatitis B, active hepatitis C, or other active, uncontrolled infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Class III/IV cardiovascular disability according to the New York Heart Association&#xD;
             Classification&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Clinically apparent arrhythmia or arrhythmias that are not stable on medical&#xD;
             management within two weeks of physician-investigator confirmation of eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Active acute or chronic GVHD requiring systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Dependence on systemic steroids or immunosuppressant medications. For additional&#xD;
             details regarding use of steroid and immunosuppressant medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Receipt of immune checkpoint inhibitors within 4 months prior to&#xD;
             physician-investigator confirmation of eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Receipt of prior huCART19 therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Active CNS disease. Note: Patients with a history of CNS involvement that was&#xD;
             successfully treated are eligible. A CNS evaluation is only required for eligibility&#xD;
             if a subject is experiencing signs/symptoms of CNS involvement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with a known history or prior diagnosis of optic neuritis or other&#xD;
             immunologic or inflammatory disease affecting the central nervous system, and&#xD;
             unrelated to their cancer or previous cancer treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Active autoimmune disease requiring systemic immunosuppressive treatment equivalent to&#xD;
             ≥ 10mg of prednisone. Patients with autoimmune neurologic diseases (such as MS) will&#xD;
             be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jakub Svoboda, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Pennsylvania</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Abramson Cancer Center Clinical Trials Service</last_name>
    <phone>855-216-0098</phone>
    <email>PennCancerTrials@emergingmed.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pennsylvania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Abramson Cancer Center Clinical Trials Service</last_name>
      <phone>855-216-0098</phone>
      <email>PennCancerTrials@emergingmed.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CLL</keyword>
  <keyword>NHL</keyword>
  <keyword>CAR-T cells</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

