<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04681482</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>B0661162</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04681482</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness And Safety Of Oral Anticoagulants Among Obese Patients With Non-Valvular A-Fib In VA Patients With Medicare</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effectiveness and Safety of Oral Anticoagulants Among Obese Patients With Non-Valvular Atrial Fibrillation in the Veterans Affairs Population With Medicare</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pfizer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pfizer</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The overall objective of this analysis is to understand patient characteristics, the use of&#xD;
      treatment, and clinical outcomes among obese (overweight) and severely obese patients with&#xD;
      non-valvular atrial fibrillation (NVAF) who initiate therapy with OACs (oral&#xD;
      anti-coagulants). The aim of this study is to compare all DOACs (direct oral anti-coagulants)&#xD;
      to warfarin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, the primary analysis will be conducted among apixaban vs warfarin patients only. If&#xD;
      sample size permits, we will also conduct other DOAC vs warfarin and DOAC vs DOAC analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 2, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 3, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 3, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of Stroke/Systemic Embolism (SE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Between January 1, 2013 and December 31, 2017</time_frame>
    <description>Stroke/SE will be identified using hospital claims which had a stroke/SE diagnosis code as the primary diagnosis code and occurring anytime during the period of drug use or within 30 days from the last day of supply of treatment prescription.&#xD;
Stroke/SE will be a dichotomous variable that equals 1 if there is ≥1 stroke event during the follow-up period. Time to the first stroke/SE event will be calculated. The first stroke/SE event will be stratified by ischemic stroke, hemorrhagic stroke, and SE.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of Major Bleeding (MB)</measure>
    <time_frame>Between January 1, 2013 and December 31, 2017</time_frame>
    <description>Major bleeding event(s) observed during follow-up will be identified using hospital claims which had a MB diagnosis as the primary diagnosis code and occurring anytime during the follow-up period of drug use or within 30 days from the last day of supply of treatment prescription. A major bleeding event will be a dichotomous variable that equals 1 if there is ≥1 bleeding event during the follow-up period. Time to the first major bleeding event will be calculated. The first major bleeding event will be stratified by gastrointestinal (GI), intracranial hemorrhage (ICH), and other MB.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Net Clinical Benefit</measure>
    <time_frame>Between January 1, 2013 and December 31, 2017</time_frame>
    <description>Medicare For patients with stroke/SE or MB event, net clinical benefit will be assessed by evaluating the first hospital claim for a stroke/SE or MB event. The hospital claim can occur anytime during the period of drug use or within 30 days from the last day of supply of treatment prescription.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time in Therapeutic Range</measure>
    <time_frame>Between January 1, 2013 and December 31, 2017</time_frame>
    <description>Time in therapeutic range (TTR) will be calculated using the Rosendaal method26 and will be computed using INR values among warfarin patients during the follow-up. This method calculates international normalized ratio (INR)-specific person-time by incorporating the frequency of INR measurements and their actual values, and assuming that changes between consecutive INR measurements are linear over time. TTR will be calculated based on the percentage of time a patient remained in therapeutic range evaluated during the entire follow-up period.Flags will be created for TTR ≥65% [good] and TTR &lt;65% [poor].</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1</enrollment>
  <condition>Atrial Fibrillation</condition>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <condition>Anticoagulants</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Apixaban Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>The cohort prescribed apixaban and diagnosed with Atrial Fibrillation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Warfarin Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>patients prescribed warfarin only diagnosed with Atrial Fibrillation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Apixaban</intervention_name>
    <description>Anticoagulant medication used to treat and prevent blood clots and to prevent stroke in people with nonvalvular atrial fibrillation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Apixaban Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Eliquis</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Obese or severely obese AF patients in the CMS Medicare and Veterans' Health Affairs (VHA)&#xD;
        databases who were newly prescribed OACs between January 1, 2013 and December 31, 2017.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Obese or severely obese.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Initiated an OAC from July 1, 2013 - December 31, 2017; the first DOAC pharmacy claim&#xD;
             date during the identification period will be designated as the index date. The first&#xD;
             warfarin prescription date will be designated as the index date for patients without&#xD;
             any DOAC claim.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals ≥18 years old as of the index date.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had 6 months continuous health plan enrollment with medical benefits (Parts A &amp; B) for&#xD;
             at least 6 months pre-index date (baseline period).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 1 diagnosis of AF prior to or on index date, identified by any medical claim&#xD;
             associated with an International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision, Clinical&#xD;
             Modification (ICD-9-CM) code of 427.31 or International Classification of Diseases,&#xD;
             Tenth Revision, Clinical Modification (ICD-10-CM) code of I480-I482, and I4891.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had body weight or BMI value reported within ±6 months of the index date.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had medical claims indicating a diagnosis or procedure of rheumatic mitral valvular&#xD;
             heart disease, heart valve replacement/transplant, venous thromboembolism, or&#xD;
             transient AF 6 months prior to or on the index date.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had hip/knee replacement surgery within 6 weeks prior to or on the index date.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Were pregnant during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had an OAC prescription during the 6 months pre-index date.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had follow-up time equal to 0 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had more than one OAC on the index date.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pfizer CT.gov Call Center</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Pfizer</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pfizer</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10012</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://pmiform.com/clinical-trial-info-request?StudyID=B0661162</url>
    <description>To obtain contact information for a study center near you, click here.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 23, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Medicare</keyword>
  <keyword>Veterans Affairs</keyword>
  <keyword>Major Bleeding</keyword>
  <keyword>Stroke</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Apixaban</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Pfizer will provide access to individual de-identified participant data and related study documents (e.g. protocol, Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP), Clinical Study Report (CSR)) upon request from qualified researchers, and subject to certain criteria, conditions, and exceptions. Further details on Pfizer's data sharing criteria and process for requesting access can be found at: https://www.pfizer.com/science/clinical_trials/trial_data_and_results/data_requests.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <pending_results>
    <submitted>October 28, 2021</submitted>
  </pending_results>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

