<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03842228</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCI-2019-00601</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2019-00601</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI10217</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>10217</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>10217</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>UM1CA186688</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03842228</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Testing the Combination of the Anti-cancer Drugs Copanlisib, Olaparib, and MEDI4736 (Durvalumab) in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors With Selected Mutations</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1b Biomarker-Driven Combination Trial of Copanlisib, Olaparib, and MEDI4736 (Durvalumab) in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase Ib trial studies side effects and best dose of copanlisib and olaparib when given&#xD;
      together with durvalumab, and how well they work in treating patients with solid tumors that&#xD;
      have spread to other places in the body (metastatic) or cannot be removed by surgery&#xD;
      (unresectable). Copanlisib may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes&#xD;
      needed for cell growth. PARPs are proteins that help repair DNA mutations. PARP inhibitors,&#xD;
      such as olaparib, can keep PARP from working, so tumor cells can't repair themselves, and&#xD;
      they may stop growing. Immunotherapy with monoclonal antibodies, such as durvalumab, may help&#xD;
      the body's immune system attack the cancer, and may interfere with the ability of tumor cells&#xD;
      to grow and spread. Giving combinations of copanlisib and olaparib or copanlisib, olaparib,&#xD;
      and durvalumab may work better in treating patients with solid tumors compared to usual&#xD;
      treatments such as surgery, radiation, or other chemotherapy drugs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate the safety and establish the recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) of the doublet&#xD;
      combination of copanlisib and olaparib and of the triplet combination of copanlisib, olaparib&#xD;
      and MEDI4736 (durvalumab) in patients with molecularly-selected solid tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To observe and record anti-tumor activity of the doublet combination of copanlisib and&#xD;
      olaparib, and of the triplet combination of copanlisib, olaparib and MEDI4736 (durvalumab) in&#xD;
      patients with molecularly-selected advanced solid tumors, as measured by objective response&#xD;
      rate (ORR) (complete response [CR] + partial response [PR]). Although the clinical benefit of&#xD;
      the doublet and triplet combination of these drugs has not yet been established, the intent&#xD;
      of offering this treatment is to provide a possible therapeutic benefit, and thus the patient&#xD;
      will be carefully monitored for tumor response and symptom relief in addition to safety and&#xD;
      tolerability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To assess overall duration of response (DoR), progression free survival (PFS) and overall&#xD;
      survival (OS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To assess the pharmacokinetic (PK) profiles of these combinations, and explore&#xD;
      exposure-response relationships.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To correlate molecular alterations with OR (CR+PR).&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study of copanlisib and olaparib.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive copanlisib hydrochloride intravenously (IV) over 1 hour on days 1, 8, and 15&#xD;
      and olaparib orally (PO) twice daily (BID). Beginning cycle 2, patients receive durvalumab IV&#xD;
      over 1 hour on day 1. Cycles repeat every 28 days for 24 months in the absence of disease&#xD;
      progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 30 days and then every 3-6&#xD;
      months for up to 2 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 12, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum-tolerated dose (MTD) of copanlisib and olaparib</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Will employ the Bayesian optimal interval (BOIN) design (Liu and Yuan, 2015; Yuan et al., 2016) to determine the MTD.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR = complete response [CR] + partial [PR])</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Anti-tumor activity of the combination of copanlisib and olaparib, and of the triplet combination of copanlisib, olaparib, and durvalumab will be measured by ORR. Will estimate ORR with 95% confidence intervals (CI).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response</measure>
    <time_frame>From time measurement criteria are met for CR or PR until the first date that recurrent or progressive disease is objectively documented, assessed up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will use the Kaplan-Meier method to estimate this distribution.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment to time of progression or death, whichever occurs first, assessed up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will use the Kaplan-Meier method to estimate this distribution.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will use the Kaplan-Meier method to estimate this distribution.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immune-modulatory changes</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will assess immuno-modulatory changes of copanlisib and olaparib, and of the triplet combination of copanlisib, olaparib and durvalumab using paired t-tests or Wilcoxon signed rank tests.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PI3K pathway signaling marker levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will assess associations between marker levels (e.g. phosphorylated Akt [pAkt], pS6, p4EBP1) and response using receiver operating characteristic curve analysis, graphical analysis, and logistic regression analysis as appropriate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Single nucleotide variation profile</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will assess associations between marker levels and response using receiver operating characteristic curve analysis, graphical analysis, and logistic regression analysis as appropriate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Copy number variation profile</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will assess associations between marker levels and response using receiver operating characteristic curve analysis, graphical analysis, and logistic regression analysis as appropriate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Copanlisib pharmacokinetics</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, day 1 and 15: baseline, 30 minutes 1 hour (h), 2h, 3h, and 5h after completion of copanlisib infusion</time_frame>
    <description>Will assess associations between marker levels and response using receiver operating characteristic curve analysis, graphical analysis, and logistic regression analysis as appropriate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">102</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Unresectable Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (copanlisib hydrochloride, olaparib, and durvalumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive copanlisib hydrochloride IV over 1 hour on days 1, 8, and 15 and olaparib PO BID. Beginning cycle 2, patients receive durvalumab IV over 1 hour on day 1. Cycles repeat every 28 days for 24 months in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Copanlisib Hydrochloride</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (copanlisib hydrochloride, olaparib, and durvalumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>5-Pyrimidinecarboxamide, 2-Amino-N-(2,3-dihydro-7-methoxy-8-(3-(4-morpholinyl)propoxy)imidazo(1,2-C)quinazolin-5-yl)-, Hydrochloride (1:2)</other_name>
    <other_name>Aliqopa</other_name>
    <other_name>BAY 80-6946 Dihydrochloride</other_name>
    <other_name>BAY-80-6946 Dihydrochloride</other_name>
    <other_name>Copanlisib Dihydrochloride</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Durvalumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (copanlisib hydrochloride, olaparib, and durvalumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Imfinzi</other_name>
    <other_name>Immunoglobulin G1, Anti-(Human Protein B7-H1) (Human Monoclonal MEDI4736 Heavy Chain), Disulfide with Human Monoclonal MEDI4736 Kappa-chain, Dimer</other_name>
    <other_name>MEDI-4736</other_name>
    <other_name>MEDI4736</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Olaparib</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (copanlisib hydrochloride, olaparib, and durvalumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>AZD 2281</other_name>
    <other_name>AZD-2281</other_name>
    <other_name>AZD2281</other_name>
    <other_name>KU-0059436</other_name>
    <other_name>Lynparza</other_name>
    <other_name>PARP Inhibitor AZD2281</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA FOR ENROLLMENT INTO STEPS 1, 2, AND 3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have germline or somatic mutations in DDR genes: ARID1A, ATM, ATRX,&#xD;
             BARD1, BRCA1, BRCA2, BRIP1, CDK12, CHEK1, CHEK2, FANCA, FANCL, MRE11A, MSH2, PALB2,&#xD;
             PARP1, POLD1, PP2R2A, RAD51B, RAD51C, RAD51D, RAD54L, XRCC2; or actionable mutations&#xD;
             in the PTEN gene, or hotspot mutations in the PIK3CA gene (E542, E545 or H1047 are&#xD;
             accepted). Local testing in Clinical Laboratory Improvement Act (CLIA)-certified&#xD;
             laboratory will be accepted. Only mutations that have been recognized as actionable by&#xD;
             the MD Anderson Precision Oncology Decision Support (PODS) team will be accepted&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have histologically confirmed malignancy that is metastatic or&#xD;
             unresectable and for which standard curative or palliative measures do not exist or&#xD;
             are no longer effective&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have measurable disease by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors&#xD;
             (RECIST) 1.1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be &gt;= 4 weeks beyond treatment with any chemotherapy or other&#xD;
             investigational therapy to include hormonal, biological, or targeted agents; or at&#xD;
             least 5 half-lives from hormonal, biological, or targeted agents, whichever is shorter&#xD;
             at the time of treatment initiation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;= 18 years. Because no dosing or adverse event (AE) data are currently available&#xD;
             on the use of copanlisib in combination with olaparib +/- durvalumab (MEDI4736) in&#xD;
             patients &lt; 18 years of age, children are excluded from this study, but will be&#xD;
             eligible for future pediatric trials&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a mutation within both the DDR and PTEN/PIK3CA pathways will be assessed&#xD;
             by the genomics Precision Oncology Decision Support group at MD Anderson, and the&#xD;
             patient will be allocated to the PI3K or DDR expansion group deemed to be the main&#xD;
             driver. If the actionability between the groups is deemed to be equivocal, then the&#xD;
             patient will be allocated to the expansion cohort with fewer patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) =&lt; 1 (Karnofsky &gt;=&#xD;
             60%)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 10 g/dL with no blood transfusion in the past 28 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Leukocytes &gt;= 3,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lipase =&lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,500/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &gt;= 100,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase&#xD;
             [SGOT])/alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase [SGPT])&#xD;
             =&lt; 2.5 x institutional ULN, unless liver metastases are present in which case they&#xD;
             must be =&lt; 5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Activated partial thrombin time =&lt; 1.5 x ULN unless subject is receiving anticoagulant&#xD;
             therapy as long as prothrombin time (PT) or partial thromboplastin time (PTT) is&#xD;
             within the therapeutic range of intended use of anticoagulants&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  International normalized ratio =&lt; 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &gt;= 51 mL/min, based on a 24-hour urine test for&#xD;
             creatinine clearance or estimated using the Cockcroft-Gault equation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &gt;= 50%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are therapeutically treated with an agent such as warfarin or heparin&#xD;
             will be allowed to participate provided that their medication dose and international&#xD;
             normalized ratio (INR)/PTT is stable&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prophylactic antiemetics may be administered according to standard practice. The&#xD;
             routine use of standard antiemetics, including 5-hydroxytryptamine type 3 (5-HT3)&#xD;
             blockers, such as granisetron, ondansetron, or an equivalent agent, is allowed as&#xD;
             needed. The use of corticosteroids as antiemetics prior to copanlisib administration&#xD;
             will not be allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Postmenopausal or evidence of non-childbearing status, a negative urine or serum&#xD;
             pregnancy test within 28 days of study treatment and confirmed prior to treatment on&#xD;
             day 1. Postmenopausal is defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Amenorrheic for 1 year or more following cessation of exogenous hormonal&#xD;
                  treatments&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Luteinizing hormone (LH) and follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) levels in the&#xD;
                  postmenopausal range for women under 50&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Radiation-induced oophorectomy with last menses &gt; 1 year ago&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chemotherapy-induced menopause with &gt; 1 year interval since last menses&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Surgical sterilization (bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child-bearing potential MUST have a negative serum or urine human chorionic&#xD;
             gonadotropin (HCG) test unless prior tubal ligation (&gt;= 1 year before screening),&#xD;
             total hysterectomy or menopause (defined as 12 consecutive months of amenorrhea).&#xD;
             Patients should not become pregnant or breastfeed while on this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients and their partners, if sexually active and of childbearing potential, must&#xD;
             agree to the use of two highly effective forms of contraception in combination&#xD;
             throughout the period of taking study treatment and for 6 months after last dose of&#xD;
             study drug(s) to prevent pregnancy in the study patient or partner. Male patients&#xD;
             should avoid donating sperm for 3 months following the last dose of olaparib&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-infected (HIV 1/2 antibody-positive; HIV testing&#xD;
             pre-study not required) patients may participate IF they meet all the following&#xD;
             eligibility requirements:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  They must be on an anti-retroviral regimen with evidence of at least two&#xD;
                  undetectable viral loads within the past 6 months on this same regimen; the most&#xD;
                  recent undetectable viral load must be within the past 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  They must have a CD4 count &gt;= 250 cells/mcL over the past 6 months on this same&#xD;
                  anti-retroviral regimen and must not have had a CD4 count &lt; 200 cells/ mcL over&#xD;
                  the past 2 years, unless it was deemed related to the cancer and/or&#xD;
                  chemotherapy-induced bone marrow suppression&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  For patients who have received chemotherapy in the past 6 months, a CD4&#xD;
                       count &lt; 250 cells/mcL during chemotherapy is permitted as long as viral&#xD;
                       loads were undetectable during this same chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  They must have an undetectable viral load and a CD4 count &gt;= 250 cells/mcL within&#xD;
                  7 days of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  They must not be currently receiving prophylactic therapy for an opportunistic&#xD;
                  infection and must not have had an opportunistic infection within the past 6&#xD;
                  months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Glycosylated hemoglobin (HbA1C) of =&lt; 8.5% at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
             Patients with impaired decision-making capacity (IDMC) must have a legally authorized&#xD;
             representative or caregiver who gives such consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is willing and able to comply with the protocol for the duration of the study,&#xD;
             including undergoing treatment and scheduled visits and examinations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a tumor that is readily accessible for biopsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA FOR ENROLLMENT INTO STEP 2 AND 3 ONLY&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight &gt; 30 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy &gt;= 16 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  EXCLUSION CRITERIA FOR STEPS 1, 2, AND 3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are receiving any other investigational agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other malignancy unless curatively treated with no evidence of disease for &gt;= 5 years&#xD;
             except: adequately treated non-melanoma skin cancer, curatively treated in situ cancer&#xD;
             of the cervix, ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS), or stage 1, grade 1 endometrial&#xD;
             carcinoma. A patient with a history of localized triple negative breast cancer may be&#xD;
             eligible, provided the patient completed the adjuvant chemotherapy &gt; 3 years prior to&#xD;
             registration, and the patient remains free of recurrent or metastatic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with myelodysplastic syndrome/acute myeloid leukemia (MDS/AML) or with bone&#xD;
             marrow findings consistent with MDS/AML&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to olaparib, copanlisib, PI3K inhibitors or MEDI4736 (durvalumab) or any&#xD;
             of the excipients of any study products&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant use of strong CYP3A inhibitors and inducers&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Olaparib: concomitant use of known strong CYP3A inhibitors (e.g., itraconazole,&#xD;
                  telithromycin, clarithromycin, protease inhibitors boosted with ritonavir or&#xD;
                  cobicistat, indinavir, saquinavir, nelfinavir, boceprevir, telaprevir) or&#xD;
                  moderate CYP3A inhibitors (e.g., ciprofloxacin, erythromycin, diltiazem,&#xD;
                  fluconazole, verapamil). The required washout period for strong or moderate CYP3A&#xD;
                  inhibitors prior to starting olaparib is 2 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Because the lists of these agents are constantly changing, it is important to&#xD;
                  regularly consult a frequently-updated medical reference. As part of the&#xD;
                  enrollment/informed consent procedures, the patient will be counseled on the risk&#xD;
                  of interactions with other agents, and what to do if new medications need to be&#xD;
                  prescribed or if the patient is considering a new over-the-counter medicine or&#xD;
                  herbal product&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Concomitant use of known strong CYP3A inducers (e.g., phenobarbital,&#xD;
                  enzalutamide, phenytoin, rifampicin, rifabutin, rifapentine, carbamazepine,&#xD;
                  nevirapine and St John's Wort) or moderate CYP3A inducers (e.g., bosentan,&#xD;
                  efavirenz, modafinil). The required washout period for strong or moderate CYP3A&#xD;
                  inducers prior to starting olaparib is 5 weeks for enzalutamide or phenobarbital&#xD;
                  and 3 weeks for other agents&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Copanlisib: copanlisib is primarily metabolized by CYP3A4. Therefore, the&#xD;
                  concomitant use of strong inhibitors of CYP3A4 (e.g., ketoconazole, itraconazole,&#xD;
                  clarithromycin, ritonavir, indinavir, nelfinavir and saquinavir), and strong&#xD;
                  inducers of CYP3A4 (e.g. rifampin, phenytoin, carbamazepine, phenobarbital, St.&#xD;
                  John's Wort) are not permitted from 14 days prior to enrollment until the end of&#xD;
                  the study&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Other medications that are prohibited while on copanlisib treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Herbal medications/preparations (except for vitamins)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Anti-arrhythmic therapy other than beta blockers or digoxin&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Because the lists of these agents are constantly changing, it is important to&#xD;
                  regularly consult a frequently-updated medical reference for a list of drugs to&#xD;
                  avoid or minimize use of. As part of the enrollment/informed consent procedures,&#xD;
                  the patient will be counseled on the risk of interactions with other agents, and&#xD;
                  what to do if new medications need to be prescribed or if the patient is&#xD;
                  considering a new over-the-counter medicine or herbal product&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, uncontrolled major seizure disorder, unstable spinal cord compression,&#xD;
             superior vena cava syndrome, extensive interstitial bilateral lung disease on high&#xD;
             resolution computed tomography (HRCT) scan, symptomatic congestive heart failure,&#xD;
             cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit&#xD;
             compliance with study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Resting electrocardiogram (ECG) indicating uncontrolled, potentially reversible&#xD;
             cardiac conditions, as judged by the investigator (e.g., unstable ischemia,&#xD;
             uncontrolled symptomatic arrhythmia, congestive heart failure, QT corrected by the&#xD;
             Fridericia formula [QTcF] prolongation of &gt; 500 msec, electrolyte disturbances), or&#xD;
             patients with congenital long QT syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are breast feeding or pregnant are excluded from this study because olaparib&#xD;
             is a poly (adenosine diphosphate-ribose) polymerase (PARP) inhibitor with the&#xD;
             potential for teratogenic or abortifacient effects. Because there is an unknown but&#xD;
             potential risk for adverse events in nursing infants secondary to treatment of the&#xD;
             mother with olaparib, breastfeeding should be discontinued if the mother is treated&#xD;
             with olaparib and copanlisib +/- MEDI4736 (durvalumab)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous allogenic bone marrow transplant or double umbilical cord blood&#xD;
             transplantation (dUCBT)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Packed red blood cell or platelet transfusion in the last 28 days prior to study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Whole blood transfusions in the last 120 days prior to study entry. Whole blood&#xD;
             transfusions performed within 120 days of study entry may interfere with blood samples&#xD;
             taken for exploratory analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should be excluded if they have a condition requiring systemic treatment with&#xD;
             either corticosteroids (&gt; 10 mg daily prednisone equivalents) or other&#xD;
             immunosuppressive medications within 14 days of study drug administration. However,&#xD;
             systemic corticosteroids may be indicated after starting the study drugs to treat&#xD;
             immune-related adverse reactions. Inhaled or topical steroids and adrenal replacement&#xD;
             doses =&lt; 10 mg daily prednisone equivalents are permitted in the absence of active&#xD;
             autoimmune disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with non-healing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with HbA1c &gt; 8.5%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Note: for patients with newly diagnosed diabetes mellitus that cannot meet&#xD;
                  protocol requirements, a single re-screening (which includes all screening&#xD;
                  procedures) should be performed when then patient's diabetes is controlled and&#xD;
                  can meet protocol eligibility requirement for HbA1c&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arterial or venous thrombotic or embolic events such as cerebrovascular accident&#xD;
             (including transient ischemic attacks), deep vein thrombosis or pulmonary embolism&#xD;
             within 6 months before the start of study medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active, clinically serious infections &gt; grade 2 (Common Terminology&#xD;
             Criteria for Adverse Events [CTCAE] version [v] 5.0). Active infection including&#xD;
             tuberculosis (clinical evaluation that includes clinical history, physical examination&#xD;
             and radiographic findings, and tuberculosis [TB] testing in line with local practice),&#xD;
             hepatitis B (known positive hepatitis B virus [HBV] surface antigen [HBsAg] result),&#xD;
             or hepatitis C. Patients with a past or resolved HBV infection (defined as the&#xD;
             presence of hepatitis B core antibody [anti-HBc] and absence of HBsAg) are eligible.&#xD;
             Patients positive for hepatitis C (HCV) antibody are eligible only if polymerase chain&#xD;
             reaction is negative for HCV ribonucleic acid (RNA). HBV/HCV screening is required 28&#xD;
             days prior to starting the study drug using a routine hepatitis virus lab panel&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection requiring IV antibiotics or other uncontrolled intercurrent illness&#xD;
             requiring hospitalization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unable to swallow orally administered medication and any medical condition or&#xD;
             diagnosis that would likely impair absorption of an orally administered drug (e.g.&#xD;
             gastrectomy, ileal bypass, chronic diarrhea, gastroparesis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known psychiatric or substance abuse disorders that would interfere with cooperation&#xD;
             with the requirements of the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known active central nervous system (CNS) metastases and/or carcinomatous meningitis.&#xD;
             Subjects with previously treated brain metastases may participate provided they are&#xD;
             stable (without evidence of progression by imaging for at least four weeks prior to&#xD;
             the first dose of trial treatment and any neurologic symptoms have returned to&#xD;
             baseline), have no evidence of new or enlarging brain metastases, and are not using&#xD;
             steroids for at least 7 days prior to trial treatment. This exception does not include&#xD;
             carcinomatous meningitis which is excluded regardless of clinical stability&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New York Heart Association class III or IV heart disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Timothy A Yap</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center LAO</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Colorado Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aurora</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80045</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Suspended</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brigham and Women's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Public Contact</last_name>
      <phone>617-724-5200</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Geoffrey I. Shapiro</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Public Contact</last_name>
      <phone>617-667-9925</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gerburg M. Wulf</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Public Contact</last_name>
      <phone>877-442-3324</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Geoffrey I. Shapiro</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas at Austin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78712</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Public Contact</last_name>
      <phone>512-232-1543</phone>
      <email>irb@austin.utexas.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kyaw L. Aung</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas Medical Branch</name>
      <address>
        <city>Galveston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77555-0565</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Public Contact</last_name>
      <phone>409-772-1950</phone>
      <email>clinical.research@utmb.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bagi R. Jana</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M D Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Public Contact</last_name>
      <phone>877-632-6789</phone>
      <email>askmdanderson@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Timothy A. Yap</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas Health Science Center at San Antonio</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Public Contact</last_name>
      <phone>210-450-3800</phone>
      <email>phoresearchoffice@uthscsa.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>John Sarantopoulos</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 7, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 13, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 15, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Durvalumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Olaparib</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Poly(ADP-ribose) Polymerase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulin G</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>NCI is committed to sharing data in accordance with NIH policy. For more details on how clinical trial data is shared, access the link to the NIH data sharing policy page</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://grants.nih.gov/policy/sharing.htm</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

