<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04027608</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00000042</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01DK106265</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04027608</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Nutrition and Activity in Kids</brief_title>
  <acronym>SNAK</acronym>
  <official_title>Sensitization of the Reinforcing Value of Food as a Predictor of Weight Change in Adolescents</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>State University of New York at Buffalo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>State University of New York at Buffalo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      While a substantial body of research suggests that RRV is related to obesity, there is very&#xD;
      little research on factors that contribute to the RRV of food, particularly how patterns of&#xD;
      eating can increase or decrease the motivation to eat specific foods. Previous work has&#xD;
      demonstrated that a subset of individuals with obesity show increases in RRV of food after&#xD;
      repeated consumption of large portions of high energy density (HED) snack foods, which has&#xD;
      been conceptualized as sensitization. Preliminary data suggest that sensitization of the RRV&#xD;
      of HED food is a predictor of weight gain over time. However, more work needs to be done to&#xD;
      address this relationship using a planned, prospective study design, using adolescent&#xD;
      research subjects, and examining potential moderators of this relationship.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to identify risk and protective factors to excess zBMI change in&#xD;
      adolescents over time. Aim 1 was to measure the relative reinforcing value (RRV) of a&#xD;
      preferred HED and low energy density (LED) snack food before and after 2-weeks of daily&#xD;
      exposure. Aim 2 was to assess the RRV of exercise and sedentary activity. Hypotheses include&#xD;
      1) sensitization to HED food will be associated with greater zBMI at the time of testing as&#xD;
      well as greater zBMI change over time 2) sensitization to LED food will be associated with&#xD;
      lower zBMI at the time of testing in adolescents and less zBMI change over time. 3) Greater&#xD;
      RRV of exercise will be protective against zBMI increases over time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 29, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 28, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Weight Change</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 15, and 24 months from baseline.</time_frame>
    <description>BMI z-score change over time</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">273</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity, Adolescent</condition>
  <condition>Adolescent Behavior</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Reinforcing value of HED and LED foods in response to snack food monotony</intervention_name>
    <description>Each child will be asked to eat two different snack foods over the course of two weeks each. The RRV of that food (vs alternative reinforcer) will be tested and baseline and post exposure. Increases in RRv for food after monotony will be considered sensitization to that food. All children will be followed to observe weight change over time for 2 years each.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adolescents living in the Western New York area, aged 12-14 years at the time of&#xD;
        enrollment. Flyers were posted in the community within a 30 min drive of UB South Campus.&#xD;
        Additionally, flyers were sent to list serves, posted on facebook, and distributed to both&#xD;
        private and public schools within a 40 min drive of the university campus.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  between 12-14yoa (male and female)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  zBMI: -1.5 to +2.0 (*determined by Height/weight measurement at Visit 1)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  neutral or higher liking of the study foods&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to complete 9 study visits over 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  -metabolic or endocrine disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  use of medications known to effect appetite (Ritalin, Adderall, Concerta, Wellbutrin,&#xD;
             Prednisone, etc)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to complete the study visits&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  allergy to study foods&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  dislike of study foods (*determined via Preference for Study foods forms at Visit 1)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  parent report that child reads below 4th grade reading level&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  parent report that child cannot complete light physical activity without assistance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No English Speaking parent or legal guardian (therefore cannot provide consent in&#xD;
             English nor answer questionnaires for this study) * all other exclusion criteria are&#xD;
             assessed from Survey monkey screening in advance of the first appointment vis parental&#xD;
             report. At the first appointment the child is directly asses for height, weight, and&#xD;
             The linking of study foods.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>14 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 18, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 19, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 22, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>State University of New York at Buffalo</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jennifer Temple</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>adolescent</keyword>
  <keyword>obesity</keyword>
  <keyword>relative reinforcing value</keyword>
  <keyword>physical activity</keyword>
  <keyword>weight change</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

