<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04026542</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RECHMPL19_0330</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04026542</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Factors Associated With Normal Exercise Capacity in Patients With Single Ventricle</brief_title>
  <acronym>SV</acronym>
  <official_title>Factors Associated With Normal Exercise Capacity in Patients With Single Ventricle: the Multicenter Cross-sectional Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Montpellier</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>M3C (complex congenital heart disease) French Network</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Montpellier</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The congenital heart disease (CHD) is the firts cause of congenital birth defects. Medical&#xD;
      and surgical advances completely changed the epidemiology of CHD. Among these CHD, the&#xD;
      univentricular heart, or single ventricle (SV), is a disease whose medical-surgical progress&#xD;
      has completely changed the epidemiology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The SV at birth receives systemic and pulmonary venous returns in the single functional&#xD;
      cavity and provides systemic and pulmonary flow. The SV undergoes a severe volumetric&#xD;
      overload and considerably increases its work, which is not viable for the long time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In 1968, Professor Francis Fontan created the palliative surgery of the univentricular heart.&#xD;
      It consists in establishing a derivation of the systemic venous blood from the two vena cava&#xD;
      veins directly to the pulmonary arteries, without a sub-pulmonary ventricle. So, the VU no&#xD;
      longer undergoes volumetric overload, and eliminates cyanosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this &quot;Fontan circulation&quot;, there is no pump to push the blood in the pulmonary arteries,&#xD;
      only the remaining systemic post-capillary energy (reflection of the central venous pressure)&#xD;
      allows to drive the blood through the lungs with a risk of stasis upstream (right overload)&#xD;
      and a limited pre-charge downstream, which can lead to severe consequences: limited exercise&#xD;
      capacity, systolic and diastolic dysfunction of the SV, arrhythmia, cyanosis, cirrhosis and&#xD;
      hepatic carcinoma, exudative enteropathy , plastic bronchitis, venous thromboses, deaths.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is a great heterogeneity within this family of SV with extremely varied evolutionary&#xD;
      profiles. The cardiorespiratory exercise test, which has become a &quot;gold standard&quot;, makes it&#xD;
      possible to assess the severity of CHD. In our study on the aerobic fitness of children with&#xD;
      CHD, the investigators found that 44% of children with SV had normal aerobic fitness (&gt; 80%&#xD;
      of the theoretical VO2max)1. Some good prognostic criteria are already described: left SV,&#xD;
      good VU function, total cavopulmonary shunt in young age, etc. But the investigators know&#xD;
      that these elements are not enough to explain why some SV, which the investigators will call&#xD;
      the &quot;great-SV&quot;, have a better aerobic fitness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective of our study is to describe the population of &quot;great SV&quot; (VO2max ≥ 80%)&#xD;
      within the general population of SV. The investigators thus wish to determine the prognostic&#xD;
      criteria favorable to a good aerobic fitness in univenticular heart disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is cross-sectionnal, multicentric national (M3C network), descriptive,&#xD;
      observational.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Children ≥ 6 years old and adults with a single ventricle according to the international&#xD;
      classification ACC-CHD and who had a cardiopulmonary exercise test in the year during usual&#xD;
      follow-up will be included. Patients refuse the use of medical data will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective of our study is to describe the rate of &quot;great SV&quot; (VO2max ≥ 80%) within&#xD;
      the general population of SV. The secondary objectives are to compare the two groups: group&#xD;
      &quot;great SV&quot; with VO2max ≥ 80% versus group SV with VO2max &lt; 80%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following criteria will be collected&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anatomical : left SV, right SV, undetermined SV, total cavopulmoary shunt, partial&#xD;
      cavopulmonary shunt&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinic: NYHA status, saturation, medical treatment, number of surgery procedure, number of&#xD;
      catheterization procedure, presence of pacemaker or implantable defibrillator, presence of&#xD;
      arrythmia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Morbidity: number oh hospitalization during the year, presence of arrhythmia, cirrhosis and&#xD;
      hepatic carcinoma, exudative enteropathy , plastic bronchitis, venous thromboses, stroke.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Echocardiography: ejection fraction of SV, 2D Strain of SV, atrioventricular valve&#xD;
      regurgitation, aortic stenosis, aspect of the flow in the cavopulmonary shunt.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiac MRI: ejection fraction of SV&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiac catheterization: mean pulmonary arterial pressure, pulmonary arterial wedge pressure,&#xD;
      presence of fistulae.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiopulmonary exercise test : VO2max, anaerobic threesold, VE/VCO2 slope, oxygen uptake&#xD;
      efficiciency slope, maximal heart rate, oxygene pulse and saturation at exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pulmonary functional test : forced expiratory volume in 1 seconde (FEV1), the forced vital&#xD;
      capacity (FVC), the FEV1/FVC ratio (FEV1/FVC%), DLCO and residual volume.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>rate of &quot;great SV&quot; (VO2max ≥ 80%) within the general population of SV</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>measurement of the VO2max at the annual cardiopulmonary exercise test.&#xD;
rate of patient who have a VO2max ≥ 80% in this population of SV recruited.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the 2 groups: &quot;great SV&quot; versus others SV.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Multivariate analysis with the following data to define parameters associated with &quot;great SV&quot;: Anatomical, Clinic, Morbidity, Echocardiography, Cardiac MRI, Cardiac catheterization, Cardiopulmonary exercise test, Pulmonary functional test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>Univentricular Heart</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with a single ventricle according to the international classification ACC-CHD who&#xD;
        had a cardiopulmonary exercise test in the year during usual follow-up.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Children ≥ 6 years old and adults with a single ventricle according to the international&#xD;
        classification ACC-CHD and who had a cardiopulmonary exercise test in the year during usual&#xD;
        follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Patients refuse the use of medical data will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Arthur GAVOTTO, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Montpellier</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pascal AMEDRO, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Montpellier</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Uh Montpellier</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montpellier</city>
        <zip>34295</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 17, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 17, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 19, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>VO2max</keyword>
  <keyword>Fontan</keyword>
  <keyword>Congenital heart disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Single ventricle</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Univentricular Heart</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>NC</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

