<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04025775</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AP-Renal</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04025775</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Closed-loop in Adults With T2D Requiring Dialysis</brief_title>
  <acronym>AP-Renal</acronym>
  <official_title>An Open-label, Two-centre, Randomised, 2-period Cross-over Study to Assess the Efficacy, Safety and Utility of Fully Closed-loop Insulin Delivery in Comparison With Standard Care, in Adults With Type 2 Diabetes Requiring Maintenance Dialysis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Cambridge</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital Inselspital, Berne</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Cambridge</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main objective of this study is to determine the efficacy, safety and utility of fully&#xD;
      automated closed-loop glucose control in the home setting over a 20 day period in adults with&#xD;
      type 2 diabetes (T2D) requiring maintenance dialysis. This study builds on previous and&#xD;
      on-going studies of closed-loop systems that have been performed in Cambridge in adults with&#xD;
      type 1 diabetes in the home setting, and in adults with type 2 diabetes in the inpatient&#xD;
      setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is an open-label, two-centre, randomised, cross-over study, involving two home study&#xD;
      periods during which glucose levels will be controlled either by a fully automated&#xD;
      closed-loop system or by participants' usual insulin therapy in random order. Each treatment&#xD;
      arm is 20 days long with a 2-4 week washout period between treatments. A total of up to 40&#xD;
      adults with T2D requiring maintenance dialysis will be recruited through outpatient clinics&#xD;
      or the dialysis unit, to allow for 32 completed participants available for assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will receive appropriate training by the research team on the safe use of the&#xD;
      study devices (insulin pump and continuous glucose monitoring (CGM) and closed-loop insulin&#xD;
      delivery system). Participants in the control arm will continue with standard therapy and&#xD;
      will wear a blinded CGM system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome is time spent with glucose levels in the target range between 5.6 and&#xD;
      10.0 mmol/L as recorded by CGM. Secondary outcomes are the time spent with glucose levels&#xD;
      above and below target, as recorded by CGM, and other CGM-based metrics in addition to&#xD;
      insulin requirements. Safety evaluation comprises the tabulation of severe hypoglycaemic&#xD;
      episodes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Purpose of clinical trial To determine the efficacy, safety and utility of fully automated&#xD;
      closed-loop insulin delivery in the home setting in adults with type 2 diabetes requiring&#xD;
      maintenance dialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study objectives The study objective is to compare fully automated closed-loop insulin&#xD;
      delivery with usual care in adults with type 2 diabetes requiring maintenance dialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. EFFICACY: The objective is to assess the ability of fully-automated closed-loop insulin&#xD;
           delivery in maintaining CGM glucose levels within the target range from 5.6 to 10.0&#xD;
           mmol/l as compared to usual care in adults with type 2 diabetes requiring maintenance&#xD;
           dialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. SAFETY: The objective is to evaluate the safety of fully automated closed-loop insulin&#xD;
           delivery in terms of episodes and severity of hypoglycaemia, and nature and severity of&#xD;
           other adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. UTILITY: The objective is to determine the acceptability and duration of use of the&#xD;
           closed-loop system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design An open-label, two-centre, randomised, two-period crossover study comparing&#xD;
      fully automated closed-loop insulin delivery with usual care in adults with type 2 diabetes&#xD;
      requiring dialysis. Two intervention periods in the home setting will last 20 days each with&#xD;
      a 2-4 week washout period. The order of the two interventions will be random.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study endpoints The primary endpoint is the time spent in the target glucose range from 5.6&#xD;
      to 10.0 mmol/l based on CGM glucose levels during the 20 day home stay.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other key endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Time spent with sensor glucose above target (10.0 mmol/l)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Time spent with sensor glucose &lt;3.9 mmol/l&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Average of sensor glucose levels&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoints include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Time spent with sensor glucose below target (5.6 mmol/l)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Time spent with sensor glucose &lt;3.0 mmol/l)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Time spent with sensor glucose levels in significant hyperglycaemia (glucose levels &gt; 20&#xD;
           mmol/l)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Standard deviation and coefficient of variation of sensor glucose levels&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  AUC of glucose below 3.5 mmol/l (63 mg/dl)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Total daily insulin requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Average inter-dialytic weight gain&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety evaluation Assessment of frequency and severity of hypoglycaemic episodes and nature&#xD;
      and severity of other adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Utility evaluation Assessment of the acceptability and duration of use of the closed-loop&#xD;
      system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participating clinical centres&#xD;
&#xD;
      UK 1. Addenbrooke's Hospital, Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Cambridge,&#xD;
&#xD;
      Switzerland&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. Bern University Hospital, Bern&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size 32 adults completing the study. Recruitment will target up to 40 adults to allow&#xD;
      for drop-outs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Maximum duration of study for a participant 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment Participants will be recruited through the adult diabetes outpatient clinics or&#xD;
      dialysis units at participating centres.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consent Written informed consent will be obtained from participants according to Research&#xD;
      Ethics Committee (REC) requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Screening and baseline assessment Eligible participants will undergo a baseline evaluation&#xD;
      including medical (diabetes) history and current therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomisation Eligible participants will be randomised in a 1:1 ratio using randomisation&#xD;
      software to the use of fully automated closed-loop insulin delivery or to usual care for 20&#xD;
      days, with a 2-4 week washout period between the two interventions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Closed loop arm Following randomisation, participants in the closed-loop group will&#xD;
           receive training to cover key aspects of insulin pump use and CGM. Competency on the use&#xD;
           of study devices will be evaluated Once competent in the use of the study pump and CGM,&#xD;
           participants will receive training required for safe and effective use of the&#xD;
           closed-loop system. During a 2-4 hour session participants will operate the system under&#xD;
           the supervision of the clinical team. Competency on the use of closed-loop system will&#xD;
           be evaluated. Thereafter, participants are expected to use closed-loop for 20 days&#xD;
           without supervision or remote monitoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
           All participants will be provided with 24 hour telephone helpline and will also be given&#xD;
           written instructions about when to contact clinical team.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Standard therapy (control arm) Participants in the control group will continue with&#xD;
           standard insulin therapy with blinded CGM for 20 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study contacts Follow up contacts will be conducted within 24 hours of starting each&#xD;
      treatment arm and then at weekly intervals thereafter.&#xD;
&#xD;
      End of study assessments Validated questionnaires evaluating the impact of the technology on&#xD;
      diabetes management and quality of life will be completed. Participants will resume usual&#xD;
      care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures for safety monitoring during trial Standard operating procedures for monitoring&#xD;
      and reporting of all adverse events (AE) will be in place, including serious adverse events&#xD;
      (SAE), serious adverse device effects (SADE).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A data safety and monitoring board (DSMB) will be informed of all serious adverse events and&#xD;
      any unanticipated serious adverse device effects that occur during the study and will review&#xD;
      compiled adverse event data at periodic intervals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Criteria for withdrawal of patients on safety grounds&#xD;
&#xD;
      A participant may terminate participation in the study at any time without necessarily giving&#xD;
      a reason and without any personal disadvantage. An investigator can stop the participation of&#xD;
      a subject after consideration of the benefit/risk ratio. Possible reasons are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Serious adverse events&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Significant protocol violation or non-compliance&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Failure to satisfy competency assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Decision by the investigator, or the Sponsor, that termination is in the participant's&#xD;
           best medical interest&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Pregnancy, planned pregnancy, or breast feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Allergic reaction to insulin&#xD;
&#xD;
      Efforts will be made to retain participants in follow up for the final primary outcome&#xD;
      assessment even if the intervention is discontinued, unless the investigator believes that it&#xD;
      will be harmful for the participant to continue in the trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time in the target glucose range (5.6 to 10.0 mmol/l)</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of time spent with sensor glucose readings in the target range from 5.6 to 10.0</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent above target glucose (10.0 mmol/l)</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Both armsPercentage of time spent with sensor glucose readings above target glucose (10.0 mmol/l)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Mean sensor glucose level</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent in hypoglycaemia (&lt;3.9 mmol/l)</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of time spent with sensor glucose readings &lt;3.9 mmol/l</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent below target glucose (5.6 mmol/l)</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of time spent with sensor glucose readings below target glucose (5.6 mmol/l)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Standard deviation of glucose levels</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Standard deviation of glucose levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Coefficient of variation of glucose levels</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Coefficient of variation of glucose levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent below &lt;3.0 mmol/l</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of time spent with sensor glucose readings &lt;3.0 mmol/l</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time in significant hyperglycaemia (&gt; 20 mmol/l)</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of time with glucose levels in significant hyperglycaemia (&gt; 20 mmol/l)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total, basal and bolus insulin dose</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Average daily total, basal and bolus insulin requirements</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC of glucose below 3.5 mmol/l</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the curve of sensor glucose readings below 3.5mmol/l</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of episodes of severe hypoglycaemia</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Safety evaluation</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects experiencing severe hypoglycaemia</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Safety evaluation</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency and nature of other adverse events or serious adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Safety evaluation</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of time of closed-loop operation</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Utility evaluation</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of time of CGM availability</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Utility evaluation</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Average inter-dialytic weight gain</measure>
    <time_frame>20 day intervention period</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 2 Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>End Stage Renal Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Closed loop insulin delivery</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Unsupervised home use of day and night fully automated closed loop insulin delivery system (CamAPS HX) for 20 days&#xD;
The CamAPS HX closed-loop system comprises&#xD;
Dana insulin pump (Diabecare, Sooil, Seoul, South Korea)&#xD;
Dexcom G6 real-time CGM sensor (Dexcom, Northridge, CA, USA)&#xD;
An Android smartphone hosting CamAPS HX Application with the Cambridge model predictive control algorithm and communicating wirelessly with the insulin pump&#xD;
Glooko/Diasend cloud upload system to monitor CGM/insulin data.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the control arm will continue to follow their current diabetes management plan for the 20 day study period.Participants will be wear a masked continuous glucose monitoring (CGM) system during the 20 day study period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CamAPS HX Closed-loop</intervention_name>
    <description>The CamAPS HX closed-loop system comprises&#xD;
Dana insulin pump (Diabecare, Sooil, Seoul, South Korea)&#xD;
Dexcom G6 real-time CGM sensor (Dexcom, Northridge, CA, USA)&#xD;
An Android smartphone hosting CamAPS HX Application with the Cambridge model predictive control algorithm and communicating wirelessly with the insulin pump&#xD;
Glooko/Diasend cloud upload system to monitor CGM/insulin data.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Closed loop insulin delivery</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Multiple Daily Insulin Injections (Control)</intervention_name>
    <description>Multiple Daily Insulin Injections with masked Dexcom G6 CGM sensor (Dexcom, Northridge, CA, USA)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject is age 18 years or over&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of type 2 diabetes using standard diagnostic practice&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject requires maintenance dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject requires current treatment with subcutaneous insulin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Screening HbA1c ≤ 11% (97mmol/mol) on analysis from local laboratory&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is willing to perform regular finger-prick blood glucose monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject is literate in English (UK) or German (Switzerland)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject is willing to wear study devices 24/7 during intervention arm and follow&#xD;
             study specific instructions&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physical or psychological condition likely to interfere with the normal conduct of the&#xD;
             study and interpretation of the study results as judged by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected allergy to insulin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of reliable telephone facility for contact&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, planned pregnancy, or breast feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe visual impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe hearing impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medically documented allergy towards the adhesive (glue) of plasters or unable to&#xD;
             tolerate tape adhesive in the area of sensor placement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious skin diseases located at places of the body, which potentially are possible to&#xD;
             be used for localisation of the glucose sensor&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Illicit drugs abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prescription drugs abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alcohol abuse&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Roman Hovorka, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University of Cambridge</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Inselspital, Bern University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bern</city>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cambridge</city>
        <zip>CB2 0QQ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 16, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 18, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 19, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Cambridge</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr Roman Hovorka</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Metabolic Technology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Fully anonymised data may be shared with third parties (EU or non-EU based) for the purposes of advancing management and treatment of diabetes.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

