<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03095976</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1608175133</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03095976</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Amnion-Chorion Allograft Barrier Used for Root Surface and Guided Tissue Regeneration</brief_title>
  <official_title>Amnion-Chorion Allograft Barrier Used for Root Surface and Guided Tissue Regeneration for Periodontal Intrabony Defects and Grade II Furcation Defects.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Indiana University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Indiana University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this pilot project is to evaluate the efficacy of application of&#xD;
      Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane on the root surface of periodontally diseased teeth in&#xD;
      conjunction with bone substitute covered by Amnion-Chorion allograft in a combination Guided&#xD;
      Tissue Regeneration (GTR) treatment of periodontal intrabony and furcation defects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients who are referred to the Graduate Periodontics Clinic at Indiana University School of&#xD;
      Dentistry for the treatment of severe chronic/aggressive periodontitis will be screened for&#xD;
      possible participation in this study. Up to 20 subjects will be accepted into this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Written informed consent and authorization will be obtained from all participants and they&#xD;
      will be given a copy of the signed informed consent documents.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The procedures listed below are all within standard care for a regenerative therapy around&#xD;
      the teeth except the application of the membrane on the root surface prior to the bone&#xD;
      grafting. No data collected for this study will be taken from sources outside of that already&#xD;
      recorded for standard of care procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical Measurements A single calibrated examiner will perform clinical baseline and 6-month&#xD;
      follow up measurements. O'Leary plaque score will be assessed. Six sites of each tooth of&#xD;
      probing depth (PD), recession (REC) and clinical attachment level (CAL) will be recorded to&#xD;
      the nearest millimeter with a University of North Carolina Probe (UNC Probe). For Glickman&#xD;
      grade II furcation defects, in addition to the previous measurements, vertical probing pocket&#xD;
      depth (VPD) and horizontal probing depth (HPD) will be measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Radiographic assessment will be performed with vertical bite-wing radiographs at baseline and&#xD;
      6-month post-surgical treatment. In order to maximize the standardization of the angulation&#xD;
      of radiographs, bite registration will be taken prior to the first radiograph and utilized&#xD;
      with beam-guiding device. It will be stored to be used post operatively. Sirona Dental&#xD;
      Systems© with 7mA 60kV with 0.16s exposure time will be utilized for all radiographs. Digital&#xD;
      #2 films manufactured by Air Techniques Inc. will be used for radiographic assessment. Bony&#xD;
      defect (BD) will be defined as the most coronal point where the periodontal ligament space&#xD;
      showed a continuous width. If several bony contours could be identified, the most apical one&#xD;
      that crossed the root will be defined as the boney defect and the most coronal one as&#xD;
      alveolar crest. If the cemento-enamel junction (CEJ) was destroyed by the restorative&#xD;
      treatment, the margin of the restoration will be taken as a landmark. Beam guided device will&#xD;
      be used as a calibration of measurements. The change of bone fill and angulation will be&#xD;
      recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All surgery will be rendered at the Graduate Periodontics Clinic at Indiana University School&#xD;
      of Dentistry. All the patients will be treated under local anesthesia (2% lidocaine with&#xD;
      1/100,000epi or 4% articaine with 1/100,000epi). If the patient is willing to receive the&#xD;
      surgery under intravenous or oral sedation, those services will be provided based on the&#xD;
      necessity. After local anesthesia, intracrevicular incisions will be made and full-thickness&#xD;
      mucoperiosteal flaps will be raised both buccally and lingually; the surgeon will try to&#xD;
      preserve the maximum extent of the marginal and interdental gingival tissue to obtain primary&#xD;
      closure and membrane coverage. Vertical releasing incisions will only be used if necessary to&#xD;
      gain access for defect debridement. The alveolar bone will be exposed at least 3 mm beyond&#xD;
      the edges of the defect, and periosteal releasing incisions will be made to ensure complete&#xD;
      membrane coverage at the time of suturing if necessary. All granulation tissue will be&#xD;
      removed, the defects will be debrided, and the roots will be thoroughly scaled and root&#xD;
      planed by hand instruments and ultrasonic devices. Following debridement, 17%&#xD;
      Ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid (EDTA) solution with cotton pellet will be applied on the&#xD;
      root surface for 2 minutes. After thorough irrigation with saline, BioXclude® (Amnion-Chorion&#xD;
      Membrane: Food and Drug Administration (FDA) Approved materials for intrabony defects) will&#xD;
      be cut into two pieces. The amnion-chorion BioXclude membrane is regulated by the FDA under&#xD;
      section 361 of the Public Health Service Act as a &quot;Human cells, tissues, and cellular or&#xD;
      tissue-based product&quot; (HCT/P). The FDA does not require pre-market approval for these&#xD;
      products like it would with drugs, biologics or devices. Therefore, this product will have no&#xD;
      associated &quot;investigational device exemption&quot; (IDE) number. The FDA views using amnion&#xD;
      chorion as a wound covering to aid in the healing of tissues throughout the body to be a&#xD;
      &quot;homologous use&quot;. One goes to the root surface, and coronal portion of the membrane has to be&#xD;
      &gt;3mm coronal of CEJ. Once applied the membrane, one drop of saline will be applied to obtain&#xD;
      better adaptation of membrane on the root surface. Bone substitutes 0.5cc (Particle size of&#xD;
      0.25-0.5mm of Corticocancellous, Maxxeus®) will be hydrated for at least 10min prior to&#xD;
      application, and applied into the defects. The bone particles will not exceed the edge of&#xD;
      defects in order to avoid over fill. Following the bone graft will be delivered to the&#xD;
      defect. The coronal portion of excessive membrane will be just folded over the graft&#xD;
      materials. The other BioXclude membrane will be utilized over the grafts, and will always be&#xD;
      placed coronal to the interproximal bone crest so that it completely covers the defect and&#xD;
      extends 2 to 3 mm beyond the residual bone. No sutures, pins, or tacks will be used for&#xD;
      membrane fixation or stabilization. The orientation of the membrane will not matter. Vertical&#xD;
      or horizontal mattress sutures with 5-0 Proline (Monofilament/Nylon) will be placed in the&#xD;
      interproximal tissues to obtain primary closure as much as possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intra-surgical Clinical Measurements. Intrabony defects: defect morphology will be measured&#xD;
      (1 wall, 2 walls and/or those combinations) from the deepest aspect of the defect from the&#xD;
      most coronal side of edge of the defects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Furcation defects: 1) Cementoenamel junction to roof of furcation (CEJ-ROF); 2) roof of&#xD;
      furcation to base of defect (ROF-BOD); 3) roof of furcation to crest of bone at furcation&#xD;
      entrance (ROF-COB); 4) crest of bone to base of defect (COB-BOD); 5) root divergence at crest&#xD;
      of bone (RDCB); 6) horizontal extent (base) of defect at level of furcation entrance (HBODF);&#xD;
      7) horizontal extent (base) of defect at level of crest of bone (HBOD-C); and 8)&#xD;
      cemento-enamel junction to interproximal crest of bone (CEJ-INTPRX)&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will receive antibiotics (875mg amoxicillin twice /day) for one week. If&#xD;
      participants are allergic to amoxicillin, clindamycin (150mg twice/day) for one week will be&#xD;
      prescribed. Analgesics (600mg ibuprofen three times/day) will be prescribed as needed for&#xD;
      discomfort. Pt will be seen one, two and four weeks as a post-operative follow up. Patients&#xD;
      will be advised to rinse twice daily with 0.12% chlorhexidine for 2 weeks after surgery.&#xD;
      Patients will be instructed to refrain from brushing the teeth in the surgical area for 2&#xD;
      weeks. After that, they will be instructed to initiate brushing with an extra-soft&#xD;
      toothbrush. Subjects will be recalled at 4-week intervals after 4weeks from surgical&#xD;
      procedure for a period of 6 months for plaque scoring, oral hygiene instruction, and&#xD;
      professional prophylaxis as needed. No subgingival probing or instrumentation will be&#xD;
      performed at the experimental sites until the 6-month follow-up appointment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 14, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 10, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 10, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective Case Series</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Probing Depth Change</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Probing depth was measured at intrabony defect following surgical procedure.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Attachment Change</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Attachment is defined as the sum of probing depth and gingival recession. The amount of gain of attachment level will be measured.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">4</enrollment>
  <condition>Periodontal Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Test group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Application of Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane (ACM) on the root surface of periodontally diseased teeth in conjunction with corticocancellous allograft bone substitute covered by ACM in a combination GTR treatment of periodontal intrabony and furcation defects.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane on the root surface of periodontally diseased site.</intervention_name>
    <description>Application of Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane (ACM) on the root surface of periodontally diseased teeth in conjunction with corticocancellous allograft bone substitute covered by ACM in a combination GTR treatment of periodontal intrabony and furcation defects</description>
    <arm_group_label>Test group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. ASA class I or II;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. age &gt;18 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Non-smoker;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. diagnosis of chronic or aggressive periodontitis previously treated with nonsurgical&#xD;
             mechanical debridement; 5) patients have at least one two-wall intrabony defect in&#xD;
             interproximal areas with radiographic evidence of an intrabony component of ≥ 4 mm,&#xD;
             PPD ≥ 6 mm with 1-wall or 2-wall or combination of those defects;&#xD;
&#xD;
        6) Glickman Grade II furcation involvement on buccal of mandibular or maxillary first or&#xD;
        second molars without soft tissue exposure of furcation entrance; 7) tooth mobility Miller&#xD;
        Grade &lt;1; 8) more than 2mm of keratinized tissue with those selected teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. did not meet all inclusion criteria;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. pregnancy or nursing woman;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. subjects with active systemic or localized infection (exclude chronic periodontitis);&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. poor compliance or failure to maintain good oral hygiene as ascertained by the&#xD;
             presence of full-mouth plaque score ≥ 20%;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. restorations or caries on root surfaces or untreated endodontic infections;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. participants received periodontal surgical treatment on the same site of this study&#xD;
             within 2 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. use of systemic or local antibiotics on the anticipated surgical sites during the past&#xD;
             3 months.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Indiana University School of Dentistry</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eke PI, Dye BA, Wei L, Thornton-Evans GO, Genco RJ; CDC Periodontal Disease Surveillance workgroup: James Beck (University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, USA), Gordon Douglass (Past President, American Academy of Periodontology), Roy Page (University of Washin. Prevalence of periodontitis in adults in the United States: 2009 and 2010. J Dent Res. 2012 Oct;91(10):914-20. Epub 2012 Aug 30.</citation>
    <PMID>22935673</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bowers GM, Schallhorn RG, McClain PK, Morrison GM, Morgan R, Reynolds MA. Factors influencing the outcome of regenerative therapy in mandibular Class II furcations: Part I. J Periodontol. 2003 Sep;74(9):1255-68.</citation>
    <PMID>14584858</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eickholz P, Hörr T, Klein F, Hassfeld S, Kim TS. Radiographic parameters for prognosis of periodontal healing of infrabony defects: two different definitions of defect depth. J Periodontol. 2004 Mar;75(3):399-407.</citation>
    <PMID>15088878</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Crea A, Deli G, Littarru C, Lajolo C, Orgeas GV, Tatakis DN. Intrabony defects, open-flap debridement, and decortication: a randomized clinical trial. J Periodontol. 2014 Jan;85(1):34-42. doi: 10.1902/jop.2013.120753. Epub 2013 Mar 28.</citation>
    <PMID>23537123</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kiany F, Moloudi F. Amnion membrane as a novel barrier in the treatment of intrabony defects: a controlled clinical trial. Int J Oral Maxillofac Implants. 2015 May-Jun;30(3):639-47. doi: 10.11607/jomi.3590.</citation>
    <PMID>26009915</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Koob TJ, Rennert R, Zabek N, Massee M, Lim JJ, Temenoff JS, Li WW, Gurtner G. Biological properties of dehydrated human amnion/chorion composite graft: implications for chronic wound healing. Int Wound J. 2013 Oct;10(5):493-500. doi: 10.1111/iwj.12140. Epub 2013 Aug 1.</citation>
    <PMID>23902526</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Koob TJ, Lim JJ, Massee M, Zabek N, Rennert R, Gurtner G, Li WW. Angiogenic properties of dehydrated human amnion/chorion allografts: therapeutic potential for soft tissue repair and regeneration. Vasc Cell. 2014 May 1;6:10. doi: 10.1186/2045-824X-6-10. eCollection 2014.</citation>
    <PMID>24817999</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chakraborthy S, Sambashivaiah S, Kulal R, Bilchodmath S. Amnion and Chorion Allografts in Combination with Coronally Advanced Flap in the Treatment of Gingival Recession: A Clinical Study. J Clin Diagn Res. 2015 Sep;9(9):ZC98-ZC101. doi: 10.7860/JCDR/2015/12971.6572. Epub 2015 Sep 1.</citation>
    <PMID>26501023</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Avila-Ortiz G, De Buitrago JG, Reddy MS. Periodontal regeneration - furcation defects: a systematic review from the AAP Regeneration Workshop. J Periodontol. 2015 Feb;86(2 Suppl):S108-30. doi: 10.1902/jop.2015.130677. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25644295</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Albandar JM, Brown LJ, Löe H. Clinical features of early-onset periodontitis. J Am Dent Assoc. 1997 Oct;128(10):1393-9.</citation>
    <PMID>9332140</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Genco RJ, Borgnakke WS. Risk factors for periodontal disease. Periodontol 2000. 2013 Jun;62(1):59-94. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0757.2012.00457.x. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23574464</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Preshaw PM. Host response modulation in periodontics. Periodontol 2000. 2008;48:92-110. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0757.2008.00252.x. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18715360</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Waerhaug J. The infrabony pocket and its relationship to trauma from occlusion and subgingival plaque. J Periodontol. 1979 Jul;50(7):355-65.</citation>
    <PMID>381633</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Laurell L, Gottlow J, Zybutz M, Persson R. Treatment of intrabony defects by different surgical procedures. A literature review. J Periodontol. 1998 Mar;69(3):303-13.</citation>
    <PMID>9579616</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ivanovic A, Nikou G, Miron RJ, Nikolidakis D, Sculean A. Which biomaterials may promote periodontal regeneration in intrabony periodontal defects? A systematic review of preclinical studies. Quintessence Int. 2014 May;45(5):385-95. doi: 10.3290/j.qi.a31538. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24634903</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Claffey N, Egelberg J. Clinical characteristics of periodontal sites with probing attachment loss following initial periodontal treatment. J Clin Periodontol. 1994 Nov;21(10):670-9.</citation>
    <PMID>7852611</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 24, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 24, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>February 27, 2021</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>March 22, 2021</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2021</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Indiana University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Yusuke Hamada</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Guided Tissue Regeneration,</keyword>
  <keyword>Amnion-Chorion,</keyword>
  <keyword>Intrabony defects,</keyword>
  <keyword>furcation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Periodontal Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol, Statistical Analysis Plan, and Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>September 10, 2019</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/76/NCT03095976/Prot_SAP_ICF_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Test Group</title>
          <description>Application of Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane (ACM) on the root surface of periodontally diseased teeth in conjunction with corticocancellous allograft bone substitute covered by ACM in a combination GTR treatment of periodontal intrabony and furcation defects.&#xD;
Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane on the root surface of periodontally diseased site.: Application of Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane (ACM) on the root surface of periodontally diseased teeth in conjunction with corticocancellous allograft bone substitute covered by ACM in a combination GTR treatment of periodontal intrabony and furcation defects</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="4"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="4"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Test Group</title>
          <description>Application of Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane (ACM) on the root surface of periodontally diseased teeth in conjunction with corticocancellous allograft bone substitute covered by ACM in a combination GTR treatment of periodontal intrabony and furcation defects.&#xD;
Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane on the root surface of periodontally diseased site.: Application of Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane (ACM) on the root surface of periodontally diseased teeth in conjunction with corticocancellous allograft bone substitute covered by ACM in a combination GTR treatment of periodontal intrabony and furcation defects</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="4"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>&lt;=18 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Between 18 and 65 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="3"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>&gt;=65 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>years</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="53.53" spread="15.41"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="3"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Race (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>American Indian or Alaska Native</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Asian</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Black or African American</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="2"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>White</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="2"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>More than one race</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Region of Enrollment</title>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>United States</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Iniital Probing Depth</title>
          <units>millimeter</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="7.67" spread="1.12"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Gingival Recession</title>
          <units>millimeter</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0.44" spread="1.01"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Clinical Attachement Level</title>
          <units>millimeter</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="8.11" spread="1.62"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Probing Depth Change</title>
        <description>Probing depth was measured at intrabony defect following surgical procedure.</description>
        <time_frame>Baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Test Group</title>
            <description>Application of Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane (ACM) on the root surface of periodontally diseased teeth in conjunction with corticocancellous allograft bone substitute covered by ACM in a combination GTR treatment of periodontal intrabony and furcation defects.&#xD;
Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane on the root surface of periodontally diseased site.: Application of Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane (ACM) on the root surface of periodontally diseased teeth in conjunction with corticocancellous allograft bone substitute covered by ACM in a combination GTR treatment of periodontal intrabony and furcation defects</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Probing Depth Change</title>
          <description>Probing depth was measured at intrabony defect following surgical procedure.</description>
          <units>millimeter</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="4"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="4.22" spread="0.73"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Clinical Attachment Change</title>
        <description>Clinical Attachment is defined as the sum of probing depth and gingival recession. The amount of gain of attachment level will be measured.</description>
        <time_frame>Baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Test Group</title>
            <description>Application of Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane (ACM) on the root surface of periodontally diseased teeth in conjunction with corticocancellous allograft bone substitute covered by ACM in a combination GTR treatment of periodontal intrabony and furcation defects.&#xD;
Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane on the root surface of periodontally diseased site.: Application of Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane (ACM) on the root surface of periodontally diseased teeth in conjunction with corticocancellous allograft bone substitute covered by ACM in a combination GTR treatment of periodontal intrabony and furcation defects</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Clinical Attachment Change</title>
          <description>Clinical Attachment is defined as the sum of probing depth and gingival recession. The amount of gain of attachment level will be measured.</description>
          <units>mm</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="4"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="2.44" spread="2.24"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>up to 6 months</time_frame>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Test Group</title>
          <description>Application of Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane (ACM) on the root surface of periodontally diseased teeth in conjunction with corticocancellous allograft bone substitute covered by ACM in a combination GTR treatment of periodontal intrabony and furcation defects.&#xD;
Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane on the root surface of periodontally diseased site.: Application of Amnion-Chorion allograft membrane (ACM) on the root surface of periodontally diseased teeth in conjunction with corticocancellous allograft bone substitute covered by ACM in a combination GTR treatment of periodontal intrabony and furcation defects</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="4"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="4"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>5</frequency_threshold>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="4"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>Principal Investigators are NOT employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Dr. Yusuke Hamada</name_or_title>
      <organization>Indiana University School of Dentistry</organization>
      <phone>317-274-5121</phone>
      <email>yuhamada@iupui.edu</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

