<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03097601</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2016/09</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03097601</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>ELR+CXCL Cytokines in Metastatic Kidney Cancers: Predictive Markers of Resistance to Sunitinib</brief_title>
  <acronym>SUNITRES</acronym>
  <official_title>ELR+CXCL Cytokines in Metastatic Kidney Cancers: Predictive Markers of Resistance to Sunitinib and New Relevant Therapeutic Targets in Refractory Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Antoine Lacassagne</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut National de la Santé Et de la Recherche Médicale, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Antoine Lacassagne</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Metastatic renal cell carcinomas (mRCC) are highly angiogenic tumors because of mutation of&#xD;
      the pVHL gene leading to over-expression of VEGF. Therefore, mRCC represent a paradigm for&#xD;
      the use of anti-angiogenic treatments targeting the VEGF/VEGFR pathway. Despite an increase&#xD;
      of the time to progression these treatments, taken alone, are not curative with ineluctable&#xD;
      progression especially for the reference treatment sunitinib a multi kinase inhibitors of&#xD;
      VEGF, PDGF, CSF1 receptors and c-kit, FLT3 and RET. At progression on sunitinib, patients&#xD;
      received mTOR inhibitors which is responsible, at least, of HIF1A mRNA translation, then on a&#xD;
      third line sorafenib that inhibits VEGFR2, 3 PDGFR, c-KIT and B-RAF. The access to these&#xD;
      different lines of treatment has finally prolonged survival but this situation is not&#xD;
      satisfactory. Unexpected aspect associated with the use of anti-angiogenesis treatments was&#xD;
      the diversity of the patients' response. Some patients are right away refractory and die&#xD;
      rapidly, but the majority of patient has a transient response then progress and a few&#xD;
      percentages of them are responder for a very long period of time. By only targeting normal&#xD;
      endothelial cells and tumor neo-vascularization, the response should have been more&#xD;
      homogenous, thus highlighting that the treatment induced a &quot;Darwinian&quot; adaptation of tumor&#xD;
      cells and cells of the microenvironment. Two conclusions follow from these observations: 1-&#xD;
      The need to identify predictive markers of efficacy; 2-The identification of druggable&#xD;
      targets participating in progression on anti-angiogenic treatments. Our results have&#xD;
      highlighted the ELR+CXCL cytokines, pro-inflammatory and pro-angiogenic cytokines as&#xD;
      prognosis markers of survival of mRCC patients and relevant therapeutic targets on&#xD;
      experimental tumors in mice. As VEGF/VEGFR, these cytokines are produced by tumor,&#xD;
      endothelial and inflammatory cells. Their receptors (CXCR1, 2) are expressed physiologically&#xD;
      by immune and endothelial cells and aberrantly by tumor cells generating at the same time&#xD;
      autocrine proliferation loops, chronic angiogenesis and inflammation. Therefore, the&#xD;
      CXCL/CXCR1,2 axis constitutes an independent axis of cancer development and propagation.&#xD;
      However, the current standard of care is to administer anti-angiogenic therapies as the first&#xD;
      line treatment. The objective of this project is linked to the identification of potent&#xD;
      predictive markers of efficacy, easily measured in plasma samples. Deciphering the molecular&#xD;
      mechanisms associated with the production of such cytokines by tumor cells and by cells of&#xD;
      the microenvironment represents an interesting intellectual challenge and a relevant way to&#xD;
      improve the current treatments by targeting, at progression on the current standard of care,&#xD;
      other pathways than the VEGF/VEGFR axis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Metastatic renal cell carcinomas (mRCC) are highly angiogenic tumors because of mutation of&#xD;
      the pVHL gene leading to over-expression of VEGF. Therefore, mRCC represents a paradigm for&#xD;
      the use of anti-angiogenic treatments targeting the VEGF/VEGFR pathway. Despite an increase&#xD;
      of the time to progression these treatments, administered alone, are not curative with&#xD;
      ineluctable progression especially for the reference treatment sunitinib a multi kinase&#xD;
      inhibitors of VEGF, PDGF, CSF1 receptors and c-kit, FLT3. At progression with sunitinib&#xD;
      treatment, patients received mTOR inhibitors which is responsible, at least, of HIF1A mRNA&#xD;
      translation, then through a third line sorafenib that inhibits VEGFR2, 3 PDGFR, c-KIT and&#xD;
      B-RAF. The access to these different lines of treatment has finally prolonged survival but&#xD;
      this situation is not satisfactory. New way of thinking and new therapeutic targets are&#xD;
      necessary to &quot;chronisize&quot; the pathology or even to cure it. The current therapeutic practises&#xD;
      are based on the statement that the treatments must destroy blood vessels to asphyxiate the&#xD;
      tumors and that endothelial cells are normal cells that cannot adapt to the selection&#xD;
      pressure exerted by the treatments. These statements arewrong since tumor cells aberrantly&#xD;
      express the receptors targeted by anti-angiogenic drugs leading to cell adaptation and tumor&#xD;
      recurrence. Another unexpected aspect associated with the use of anti-angiogenesis treatments&#xD;
      was the diversity of the patients'response. Some patients are right away refractory and die&#xD;
      rapidly, but the majority of patients has a transient response then progress and a few&#xD;
      percentages of them are responders for a very long period. By only targeting normal&#xD;
      endothelial cells and tumor neo-vascularization, the response should have been more&#xD;
      homogenous. 3 conclusions follow from these observations: 1- The need to identify predictive&#xD;
      markers of efficacy; 2-The identification of druggable targets participating in progression&#xD;
      on anti-angiogenic treatments; 3- These targets should be independent of the VEGF/VEGFR axis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results have highlighted the ELR+CXCL cytokines, pro-inflammatory and pro-angiogenic&#xD;
      cytokines as prognosis markers of survival of mRCC patients and relevant therapeutic targets&#xD;
      on experimental tumors in mice. As VEGF/VEGFR, these cytokines are produced by tumor,&#xD;
      endothelial and inflammatory cells. Their receptors (CXCR1, 2) are expressed physiologically&#xD;
      by immune and endothelial cells and aberrantly by tumor cells generating at the same time&#xD;
      autocrine proliferation loops, chronic angiogenesis and inflammation. Therefore, the&#xD;
      CXCL/CXCR1,2 axis constitutes an independent axis of cancer development and propagation.&#xD;
      However, the current standard of care is to administer anti-angiogenic therapies as the first&#xD;
      line treatment. Hence, what is the relevance of CXCL cytokines as predictive markers of&#xD;
      sunitinib efficacy, and what are the mechanisms linked to the production of CXCL cytokines by&#xD;
      mRCC or in response to treatments?. Deciphering the molecular mechanisms associated with the&#xD;
      production of such cytokines by tumor cells and by cells of the microenvironment represents&#xD;
      an interesting intellectual challenge and a relevant way to improve the current treatments by&#xD;
      targeting, at progression on the current standard of care, other pathways than the VEGF/VEGFR&#xD;
      axis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This project aimed at the improvement of current clinical practises for mRCC. Numerous&#xD;
      efforts have been given to the determination of prognosis markers for different tumors&#xD;
      including mRCC. However, for clinical practises, physicians are more interested to predictive&#xD;
      markers of success/failure of a treatment that to biological prognosis markers that are most&#xD;
      of the time as indicative as classical clinical parameters (TNM for example). The recent&#xD;
      experiments have highlighted relevant cytokines (ELR+CXCL) participating in the&#xD;
      aggressiveness of mRCC. Indeed, the intra-tumor amounts of the ELR+CXCL cytokine CXCL7 was a&#xD;
      potent prognosis marker of survival independent of any clinical parameters. Therefore it was&#xD;
      indicative of poor prognosis for patients who were a priori of good prognosis according to&#xD;
      the TNM or the Fuhrman grade (consideration of nuclear and nucleolus size). We have also&#xD;
      demonstrated the prognosis value of two other ELR+CXCL cytokine CXCL1, CXCL5 and CXCL8. Both&#xD;
      of them are not independent of clinical parameters. However, their role as predictive markers&#xD;
      of resistance to anti-angiogenic drugs, the current standard of care, is still unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For a medical point of view, a rapid identification of responders and no-responders is of&#xD;
      first importance. It will avoid undesired toxic events for unresponsive patients and a rapid&#xD;
      adaptation of the treatment considering that different lines of therapies are currently&#xD;
      available for mRCC patients. The determination of a threshold value for the most relevant&#xD;
      cytokines is needed and this threshold must be determined of independent cohort of patients&#xD;
      for a better reliability. Such test should not be invasive for the patients and as simple as&#xD;
      possible in order to introduce in clinical practises for a low price that can be reimburse by&#xD;
      the social security. It is compatible with what we propose to do by measuring ELR+CXCL levels&#xD;
      on blood samples with classical ELISA tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Deciphering the mechanisms at the origin of the de novo synthesis of redundant&#xD;
      pro-angiogenic/pro-inflammatory cytokines under the selection pressure of treatment targeting&#xD;
      the VEGF/VEGFR pathway is intellectually challenging and may identify unknown parameters&#xD;
      implicated in Darwinian adaptation of tumor cells among a very heterogeneous environment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objectives are :&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Research helping to the understanding of biological mechanisms from clinical&#xD;
           observations (Bed to Bench) and the transfer of knowledge from the clinic to the&#xD;
           laboratories (bed to bench).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Research helping to the prognosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Research helping to the therapeutic decision and treatment monitoring.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 2, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 30, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 30, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ELR+CXCL cytokines</measure>
    <time_frame>December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>To determine of a threshold level of one or multiple ELR+CXCL cytokines indicative of progression for routine clinical practises</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>molecular mechanisms</measure>
    <time_frame>December 2020</time_frame>
    <description>To decipher the molecular mechanisms implicated in ELR+CXCL cytokines expression at the basal level and at progression on sunitinib. Expression of these cytokines by tumor cells and cells from the microenvironment (especially the Macrophages M1/Macrophages M2 ratio).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Kidney Cancers</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>sunitinib cohort</arm_group_label>
    <description>independent cohorts of patients who received sunitinib for metastic kidney cancer, on who we intend to demonstrate that ELR+CXCL cytokines levels are of sunitinib response</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ELR+CXCL cytokines levels are of sunitinib response</intervention_name>
    <description>Demonstrate on independent cohorts of patients that ELR+CXCL cytokines levels are of sunitinib response</description>
    <arm_group_label>sunitinib cohort</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Experiment on cell lines, on human samples and animal models. CXCL cytokines as predictive&#xD;
      markers of sunitinib efficacy in order to demonstrate the mechanisms linked to the production&#xD;
      of CXCL cytokines by mRCC or in response to treatments&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        patients with mRCC and treated by sunitinib after radical nephrectomy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with mRCC and treated by sunitinib after radical nephrectomy included in&#xD;
             SUVEGIL 8 Clinical Trial (Sponsor : Centre Antoine Lacassagne)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non applicable&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christine LOVERA</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Centre Antoine Lacassagne</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Antoine LACASSAGNE</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nice</city>
        <zip>06189</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 27, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 27, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 20, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 20, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 21, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sunitinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

