<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00536146</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999907216</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>07-DK-N216</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00536146</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Stress-Hormone System in Alcohol-Dependent Subjects</brief_title>
  <official_title>Trauma, Stress and Persistence of HPA Dysregulation in Alcoholism</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study, conducted at the University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center and the Parkland&#xD;
      Hospital in Dallas, will examine the stress hormone system of alcohol-dependent people. This&#xD;
      system is weakened in alcohol-addicted people. This study will determine how long it is&#xD;
      weakened, whether other hormone systems are also weakened and whether changes in the hormone&#xD;
      system are associated with previous trauma or stress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy normal men and men who are alcohol-dependent may be eligible for this study.&#xD;
      Candidates must be between 21 and 60 years of age and have at least a 5-year history of&#xD;
      active alcohol dependence. They are screened with a medical history, blood and urine tests&#xD;
      and questions about alcohol and drug use, psychiatric problems, history of trauma and recent&#xD;
      stress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants undergo the following procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Day 1 - Public Speaking Task&#xD;
&#xD;
      At 6:00 PM subjects have an I.V. line (needle attached to a small plastic tube) inserted into&#xD;
      a vein in each arm to draw blood samples and give medication. They are then given a light&#xD;
      dinner and then lie down and rest. They rinse their mouth out with water and a drop of lemon&#xD;
      juice is placed on their tongue. In 30 to 40 seconds they spit into a funnel attached to a&#xD;
      collecting tube. A blood sample is collected to measure levels of cortisol (a stress hormone)&#xD;
      ACTH (a hormone responsible for the release of cortisol) and neurosteroids (hormones that&#xD;
      affect the brain). Subjects then give a 5-minute speech (telling an ending to a story) and&#xD;
      solve a math problem in front of a small group of people. They are then asked how they are&#xD;
      feeling. Saliva and blood samples are then collected every 10 minutes for the next 60&#xD;
      minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Day 2 - Cosyntropin Study&#xD;
&#xD;
      At 6:30 p.m. subjects have an I.V. line inserted into a vein in each arm. At 7:45 PM and 8:30&#xD;
      PM saliva is collected as described above. Starting at 7:30 PM, blood samples are collected&#xD;
      every 10 minutes until 9:00 PM and then every 20 minutes until 10:00 PM. At 8:00 PM&#xD;
      cosyntropin (a medicine that stimulates production of cortisol) is given through the I.V.&#xD;
      over 1 minute.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Day 3 - oCRH Study&#xD;
&#xD;
      At 6:30 p.m. subjects have an I.V. line inserted into a vein in each arm. At 7:45 PM and 8:30&#xD;
      PM saliva is collected as described above. Starting at 7:30 PM, blood samples are collected&#xD;
      every 10 minutes until 9:00 PM and then every 20 minutes until 10:00 PM. At 8:00 PM ovine CRH&#xD;
      (a medicine that stimulates production of cortisol) is given through the I.V. over 1 minute.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may be asked to repeat these studies 3 months later.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) axis provides a key biologic link between the brain&#xD;
      and the body's behavioral and physiologic responses to stress, recovery, and adaptation. Both&#xD;
      mental trauma and chronic alcohol use may produce disturbances in the HPA response to stress.&#xD;
      Thus, changes in this system during a period when there is no alcohol intake may impair the&#xD;
      body's ability to mount an appropriate response to environmental stressors, heightening the&#xD;
      probability of additional alcohol intake. However, the relationship between trauma, stress,&#xD;
      and HPA axis disturbances requires further study. In this study, the NIH investigators will&#xD;
      attempt to determine if the sensitivity of glucocorticoid gene induction varies with stress.&#xD;
      Blood samples will be obtained at The University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center (TSMC)&#xD;
      in collaboration with the Veteran's Affairs Medical Center (VA) at Dallas, Texas under a&#xD;
      protocol and consent forms approved by TSMC IRB. Only samples collected as described in the&#xD;
      TSMC protocol will be studied at NIH.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 24, 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date>January 29, 2009</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment>70</enrollment>
  <condition>Alcoholism</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Alcohol-Dependent Subjects:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Male, 21-60 yrs, DSM-IV diagnosis of alcohol dependence, 4-6 weeks abstinence; Alcohol&#xD;
        intake of at least 80 grams of absolute alcohol (approximately one six-pack of beer or&#xD;
        one-half pint of 100% proof distilled spirits) on a daily basis for at least two weeks&#xD;
        prior to the cessation of drinking. Years drinking: at least 5 yr history of active alcohol&#xD;
        dependence; Lifetime drug of choice is alcohol; requesting treatment in long-term&#xD;
        residential program.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Healthy Controls:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Thirty men age-matched (plus or minus 5 years) with the patients will be studied. Previous&#xD;
        studies have typically used the presence or absence of trauma to define trauma groups.&#xD;
        However, these studies have focused on specific types of trauma (i.e. childhood, combat)&#xD;
        rather than trauma as a cumulative experience. It is unlikely that we will be able to find&#xD;
        subjects who have never experienced any trauma, including the death of loved ones, parental&#xD;
        separation, natural disaster, crime, etc. Therefore, we will initially recruit controls&#xD;
        without regard to trauma level. Following the recruitment of the first ten subjects, trauma&#xD;
        scores will be reviewed. If our control group endorses low levels of trauma, we will direct&#xD;
        further recruitment towards a group with at least one self-report of significant lifetime&#xD;
        trauma such that at 50 percent of the control population has a least one significant&#xD;
        lifetime traumatic event.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Only English-speaking subjects will be included. Several of the study questionnaires are&#xD;
        only available in English. In addition, these studies are exploratory and require the&#xD;
        induction of anxiety. The investigators at TSMC believe it prudent to assure that all&#xD;
        subjects are able to communicate easily with all staff during the fMRI and stress&#xD;
        induction. Subjects will be recruited from subjects requesting treatment for alcohol&#xD;
        dependence at the Dallas VA but no subjects will be seen at NIH.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Alcohol-Dependent Subjects:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary psychoactive dependence disorder other than alcohol, except nicotine and&#xD;
             caffeine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active diagnosis of Axis I Schizophrenia, Mood, or Anxiety Disorders (except PTSD).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of medications known to significantly affect HPA axis functioning or neural&#xD;
             activity, including all psychotropics with the previous two weeks (or four weeks for&#xD;
             fluoxetine).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of medications known to significantly affect HPA axis functioning or neural&#xD;
             activity, including all psychotropics with the previous two weeks (or four weeks for&#xD;
             fluoxetine). Patients concomitantly using anxiolytics, antidepressants, opioids,&#xD;
             lithium, anticonvulsants, sedative/hypnotics, buspirone, beta blockers, alpha&#xD;
             adrenergic drugs, steroids, beta agonists, clonidine, dopamine agonists, naltrexone,&#xD;
             acamprosate, or disulfiram will be excluded from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any medical conditions that might affect HPA axis functioning or possibly endanger the&#xD;
             patient's health or behavioral stability. Medical conditions that might limit&#xD;
             cooperation (e.g. dementia) or put the patient at medical risk (i.e. significant&#xD;
             hematologic, hepatic, renal, or cardiovascular pathology) will be excluded. Patients&#xD;
             with past or present neurologic disorders (i.e. head trauma with loss of consciousness&#xD;
             requiring hospitalization, transient ischemic attacks, stroke, tumor, etc.) will be&#xD;
             excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Healthy Controls:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lifetime history of DSM IV Substance Use Disorder (except Nicotine or Caffeine&#xD;
             Dependence) or other Axis I disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  One first-degree family member with a substance use disorder (other than nicotine).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical, psychiatric, and medication exclusions will be the same as those described&#xD;
             for the alcohol dependent patients.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75390</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Veterans Affairs Medical Center at Dallas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 29, 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 26, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 26, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 27, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Glucocorticoid</keyword>
  <keyword>Steroids</keyword>
  <keyword>Dose-Responsive Curve</keyword>
  <keyword>EC50</keyword>
  <keyword>Stress Response</keyword>
  <keyword>Alcoholism</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

