<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00534170</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>YH-001 NICED 010</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00534170</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Randomized Controlled Field Trial of a Probiotics to Assess Its Role in Preventig Diarrhoea</brief_title>
  <acronym>Yakult</acronym>
  <official_title>Randomized Controlled Field Trial of a Probiotics to Assess Its Role in The Prevention of Acute Diarrhoeal Diseases in Children</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Indian Council of Medical Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Yakult Honsha Co., LTD</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Indian Council of Medical Research</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A therapeutic as well as preventive role of probiotics has been suggested from results of&#xD;
      different studies using different probiotics that have been tested, usually lactic acid&#xD;
      producing bacteria such as lactobacillus, bifidobacterium and streptococcus species. The&#xD;
      supplementation of probiotics to infants may also have a prophylactic effect against acute&#xD;
      diarrhoeal diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the present proposal, we plan to examine if daily intake of a probiotic beverage, which&#xD;
      includes 15 billion probiotic Lactobacilli, has a beneficial role in protecting children from&#xD;
      infectious diarrhea in Kolkata.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To assess the impact of probiotics in the prevention of acute diarrhoeal diseases in&#xD;
           children&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To assess the impact of probiotics on nutrition and growth of the children&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Reduction in duration, frequency of diarrhoea&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Identification of pathogens causing diarrhoea&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Examination of faecal microflora&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY DESIGN&#xD;
&#xD;
      It will be a double blind randomized controlled field trial involving 4000 children aged&#xD;
      between 1 and 5 years in an urban slum of Kolkata, India. The 4000 children will be&#xD;
      identified through demographic survey. The study will be double blinded where the study arm&#xD;
      will receive Probiotic drink, which includes 15 billion probiotic Lactobacilli, one bottle&#xD;
      (65ml) daily (under supervision of a Health Worker) for 12 weeks and the control arm will&#xD;
      receive a similar drink without the lactobacilli (Nutrient drink) daily for 12 weeks.&#xD;
      Randomization will be done in a ratio of 1:1, i.e., the study arm and control arm will&#xD;
      include 2000 children each. All the children under the study will be visited daily by a&#xD;
      health worker who will supervise intake of Probiotic drink or Nutrient drink by the children.&#xD;
      All the children will be followed up daily for 24weeks for identification of acute diarrhoea&#xD;
      cases.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A therapeutic as well as preventive role of probiotics has been suggested from results of&#xD;
      different studies using different probiotics that have been tested, usually lactic acid&#xD;
      producing bacteria such as lactobacillus, bifidobacterium and streptococcus species. The&#xD;
      supplementation of probiotics to infants may also have a prophylactic effect against acute&#xD;
      diarrhoeal diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the present proposal, we plan to examine if daily intake of a probiotic beverage, which&#xD;
      includes 15 billion probiotic Lactobacilli, has a beneficial role in protecting children from&#xD;
      infectious diarrhea in Kolkata.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To assess the impact of probiotics in the prevention of acute diarrhoeal diseases in&#xD;
           children&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To assess the impact of probiotics on nutrition and growth of the children&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Reduction in duration, frequency of diarrhoea&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Identification of pathogens causing diarrhoea&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Examination of faecal microflora&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY DESIGN&#xD;
&#xD;
      It will be a double blind randomized controlled field trial involving 4000 children aged&#xD;
      between 1 and 5 years in an urban slum of Kolkata, India. The 4000 children will be&#xD;
      identified through demographic survey. The study will be double blinded where the study arm&#xD;
      will receive Probiotic drink, which includes 15 billion probiotic Lactobacilli, one bottle&#xD;
      (65ml) daily (under supervision of a Health Worker) for 12 weeks and the control arm will&#xD;
      receive a similar drink without the lactobacilli (Nutrient drink) daily for 12 weeks.&#xD;
      Randomization will be done in a ratio of 1:1, i.e., the study arm and control arm will&#xD;
      include 2000 children each. All the children under the study will be visited daily by a&#xD;
      health worker who will supervise intake of Probiotic drink or Nutrient drink by the children.&#xD;
      All the children will be followed up daily for 24weeks for identification of acute diarrhoea&#xD;
      cases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODOLOGY&#xD;
&#xD;
      Slum areas in Kolkata Municipal Corporation with approximately 60,000 populations&#xD;
      (approximate 15,000 families) will be selected from ward 66 to reach a sample size of minimum&#xD;
      4,000 children (1-5 year age).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline anthropometric measurements will be taken. The diarrhoeal surveillance will be&#xD;
      through regular household visit by CHW and stool container will be kept at each child's house&#xD;
      to collect stool sample if diarrhoea occurs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      INCLUSION/ EXCLUSION CRITERION FOR RECRUITMENT OF PARTICIPANTS Children of either sex aged&#xD;
      1-5 years will be eligible for screening and parents will give and a written, informed&#xD;
      consent form (Appendix 7) will be required from either of the parents/ guardians of each&#xD;
      participating child. Participating children should be free from any chronic illness and also&#xD;
      any recent illness that may compromise the immune system. In general they will have good&#xD;
      health without known underlying illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Children with history of diarrhoea in the preceding 2 weeks will not be eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ADMINISTRATION OF STUDY AGENTS&#xD;
&#xD;
      There will be a setup of 5 health outposts and 20 clusters (each cluster with 40 children)&#xD;
      will be approximately of 800 children will be assigned for each health outpost. There will be&#xD;
      20 Community Health Workers (CHW), allocated in each health outpost will be responsible for&#xD;
      administer of one agent code for 40 children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SAFETY EVALUATION&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical monitor will evaluate adverse events due to intake of the drink.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DATA MANAGEMENT PROCEDURES&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data obtained from demographic survey (Appendix 4), daily reports and other proforma will be&#xD;
      entered in a PC using suitable software. Data will be scrutinized for accuracy and&#xD;
      consistency before it is entered into the PC. Data will be entered into computers in a&#xD;
      dedicated area located at NICED, using data entry programs specially created for the project&#xD;
      by programmer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STATISTICAL CONSIDERATIONS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endpoints&#xD;
&#xD;
      Efficacy will be assessed by comparing the following between the probiotic and nutrient&#xD;
      groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
      i) Average duration of diarrhoea ii) Severity of the disease iii) Incidence of diarrhoeal&#xD;
      disease iv) Nutritional gain v) Analysis of fecal microflora&#xD;
&#xD;
      ETHICAL ASSURANCE FOR PROTECTION OF HUMAN RIGHTS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Written informed consent will be obtained from the parent/guardian of each participating&#xD;
      child for the Probiotic and Nutrition studies and for the safety and for permission to&#xD;
      collect feces. The probiotic or nutritional drink is safe and has been administered to infant&#xD;
      children, adults and the elderly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Storage conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
      The probiotic and nutrient will be stored at 4 to 10C. Bottles taken to the field will be&#xD;
      carried in carrying bags. Each box will have a single ice pack, and care will be taken not to&#xD;
      freeze the contents of the bottle.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MONITORING, AUDITING, INSPECTION&#xD;
&#xD;
      Responsibilities of the investigator(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
      The principal and co-investigators at NICED will be responsible for overall supervision and&#xD;
      management of the project. Field investigators and other co-investigators will support the&#xD;
      PI. The PI and co-investigators will supervise all activities at health facilities and in the&#xD;
      sites (demographic surveillance, data collection, and samples collection and transportation).&#xD;
      They will also visit the study sites regularly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ETHICAL AND REGULATORY STANDARDS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethical principle&#xD;
&#xD;
      The justification for using a nutrient in this study is that: 1) no probiotic is currently&#xD;
      recommended for use for prevention of diarrhoeal diseases in public health programs in India&#xD;
      and 2) a valid assessment of probiotic efficacy in Kolkata, which is endemic for diarrhoea,&#xD;
      can only be obtained with use of a nutrient. The nutrient will consist of nutrient without&#xD;
      lactobacillus, which will help for nutritional growth of the children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential benefits&#xD;
&#xD;
      During both phases of the project, the potential benefits to participants include proper&#xD;
      treatment and referral when needed, as well as free and accurate diagnosis of the causative&#xD;
      agent of diarrhoeal disease. During the trial phase, the probiotic recipients are expected to&#xD;
      benefit from the protection offered by the probiotic against diarrhoea.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential risks&#xD;
&#xD;
      The potential risk to the participants will be minimal, since there is extensive&#xD;
      documentation for the safety of the probiotic to be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Risk/benefit ratio&#xD;
&#xD;
      The direct benefit the participants may expect from participating in this study will be free&#xD;
      laboratory examination and treatment for diarrhoea diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main benefit of obtaining data on the efficacy of the probiotic in Kolkata will be that&#xD;
      these data will be crucial in guiding the decision of the Indian, and perhaps other&#xD;
      developing country governments as to whether this probiotic will be alternative approach for&#xD;
      growth of the children as well as prevention of diarrhoeal diseases. All recipients of the&#xD;
      probiotic will potentially benefit from the probable protective effects against diarrhoea.&#xD;
      The risks associated with the use of the probiotic or the nutrient and various other study&#xD;
      procedures proposed to be used in this trial are expected to be minimal to nonexistent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laws and regulations&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be performed in accordance with the principles that govern biomedical research&#xD;
      involving human subjects, specifically the ICMR Ethical Guidelines, the Declaration of&#xD;
      Helsinki, and the International Conference on Harmonization's Good Clinical Practice&#xD;
      Guidelines to provide assurance that the rights, integrity, and confidentiality of trial&#xD;
      subjects are protected and that reported results are credible and accurate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
      Individual informed consents from parents of eligible children between 1-5 years old will be&#xD;
      obtained. Consent will be documented by signature or thumbprint of the parents/guardian on&#xD;
      separate sheet. The privacy and confidentiality of all data and information collected from&#xD;
      trial participants will be ensured both during and after the conduct of the trial.&#xD;
      Individuals will not be identified in any reports and publications based on the trial data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Institutional review committee&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before initiation of the study, the final protocol and the informed consent will require&#xD;
      clearance Scientific Advisory Committee of NICED, Institutional Ethics Committee of NICED,&#xD;
      Health Ministry Screening Committee of the Government of India.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ADMINISTRATIVE ASPECTS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Record retention&#xD;
&#xD;
      The principal investigator and NICED will keep all trial documents for at least 5 years after&#xD;
      the completion or discontinuation of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      KEY PERSONNEL Name Professional Discipline/ Specialty Role in the Project&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. 1. Dipika Sur Epidemiology PI in India&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. 2. S.K. Bhattacharya Cholera and enteric disease Co-PI in India&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. 4. Byomkesh Manna Epidemiology Co-I in India&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. 5. S.K. Niyogi Microbiology Co-I in India&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. 6 Anup Palit Microbiology Co-I in India&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. 7. S.P. Mukhopadhyay Public health Controller&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. 8. Ashok Chowdhury Clinician Clinical Monitor&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>June 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2008</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Diarrhoeal episodes in children</measure>
    <time_frame>10 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>nutritional status in children</measure>
    <time_frame>10 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">4000</enrollment>
  <condition>Diarrhea</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>A,F,T,K</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Two arms are for intervention and two are for control or placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Probiotic (Yakult)</intervention_name>
    <description>It is a dietary supplement ,65 ml containing 15 billion lactobacillus</description>
    <arm_group_label>A,F,T,K</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Yakult</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children of either sex aged 1-5 years will be eligible for screening and parents will&#xD;
             give and a written, informed consent form will be required from either of the parents/&#xD;
             guardians of each participating child.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participating children should be free from any chronic illness and also any recent&#xD;
             illness that may compromise the immune system. In general they will have good health&#xD;
             without known underlying illness&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children below -2SD of the National Center for Health Statistics (NCHS) reference&#xD;
             median in the nutritional parameters will not be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children with history of diarrhoea in the preceding 2 weeks will not be eligible.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>59 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr.Dipika Sur, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Cholera and Enteric Diseases, India</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institute of Cholera and Enteric Disease</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kolkata</city>
        <state>West Bengal</state>
        <zip>7000010</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2007</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 21, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 21, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 24, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 21, 2007</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 21, 2007</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">September 24, 2007</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Probiotic</keyword>
  <keyword>Prevention of diarrhoea</keyword>
  <keyword>Nutritional status</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diarrhea</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

