<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00534066</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2002H0262</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00534066</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Utility of Serial BNP Levels in Emergency Department CHF</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Utility of Serial BNP Levels as a Predictor of Adverse Outcomes in Emergency Department CHF</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ohio State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ohio State University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of the study is to determine if a series of BNP blood tests performed on patients&#xD;
      who present to the Emergency Department with congestive heart failure (CHF) can predict which&#xD;
      patients may have adverse outcomes. If the BNP is shown to be predictive of bad outcomes in&#xD;
      certain patients, those patients might receive more intensive therapy early to prevent such&#xD;
      outcomes. This was a prospective trial enrolling patients who presented to the ED and were&#xD;
      diagnosed with heart failure. Subjects had a blood test for BNP, which is elevated in the&#xD;
      presence of heart failure, collected twelve hours after their initial clinical BNP was&#xD;
      obtained in the ED. Demographics, history, length of hospital stay, and other approved data&#xD;
      were collected. At 30 days and 6 months after discharge, a follow up call was made to&#xD;
      determine if the subject had required additional emergency care, had been admitted to a&#xD;
      hospital, or had died during that period of time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BNP is a 32-amino acid peptide secreted almost exclusively by the ventricles under conditions&#xD;
      of ventricular wall strain.Multiple studies have examined the utility of BNP as a marker of&#xD;
      decompensated heart failure, both in the inpatient and outpatient settings. Several studies&#xD;
      have examined the use of a single BNP measure to predict adverse outcomes in CHF patients.&#xD;
      Typical study designs have utilized CHF specialty clinics or patients admitted for congestive&#xD;
      heart failure (CHF) exacerbation as the study population. Very few studies have utilized BNP&#xD;
      in the acute care setting; these studies have also used BNP as a single measure. As the serum&#xD;
      half-life of BNP is approximately 22 minutes,BNP levels will respond to measures decreasing&#xD;
      ventricular wall strain, such that a decreasing BNP level should be diagnostic of improved&#xD;
      CHF. It is our hypothesis that Emergency Department patients with acute CHF exacerbation and&#xD;
      a decreasing serum BNP level after 12 hours of therapy will demonstrate an improved outcome&#xD;
      when compared to patients whose BNP does not decrease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our goal is to establish the utility of serial BNP levels during the intensive initial&#xD;
      management of acute CHF. One and six month follow-up patient outcomes will be collected and&#xD;
      compared against the serial BNP measurements while the patient was in the acute phase of&#xD;
      treatment. It is our hypothesis that serial brain natriuretic peptide (BNP) levels compared&#xD;
      at 0 and 12 hours for research purposes will be predictive of a combined endpoint of death,&#xD;
      readmission, or repeat Emergency Department visit for recurrent CHF in patients presenting to&#xD;
      the Emergency Department with an acute exacerbation of CHF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date, no data has been published regarding the utility of serial BNP measurements in the&#xD;
      observation unit management of CHF. Our study proposes to compare outcomes in patients&#xD;
      managed in the Clinical Decision Unit (CDU), a six bed observation unit in our Emergency&#xD;
      Department, against patients admitted for CHF exacerbation. The primary outcome of the study&#xD;
      will be the combined endpoint of death, readmission, or repeat Emergency Department visit for&#xD;
      recurrent CHF at 30 days and 6 months. For inpatients, and those patients admitted from the&#xD;
      CDU to the inpatient service, additional outcome measures will be adverse outcomes&#xD;
      (intubation, balloon pump, death, etc) during the index hospitalization. As the clinicians&#xD;
      managing the patient will not have access to the 12 hour BNP level, the measurement of BNP&#xD;
      itself will not be a source of bias. Our secondary hypothesis is that the occurrence of the&#xD;
      combined endpoint will be independent of treatment location (CDU vs inpatient) as opposed to&#xD;
      responder vs. non-responder status.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2006</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Defined Population</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">52</enrollment>
  <condition>Congestive Heart Failure</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Admitted</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients presenting to the ED with acute exacerbation of CHF who require admission to the hospital directly from the ED</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Observational</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients who present to the ED for acute exacerbation of CHF who are transferred to the Observation Unit from the ED for up to 24 hours.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age18 or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  primary diagnosis of CHF in the Emergency Department&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  admission to the hospital or transfer to the Observation Unit&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  minors, prisoners,pregnant women,unable to provide consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unstable angina or acute myocardial infarction in the ED&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  dialysis dependent patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  use of nesiritide as a therapy in the ED&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Brian C Hiestand, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ohio State University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Ohio State University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2007</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 21, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 21, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 24, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 21, 2007</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 21, 2007</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">September 24, 2007</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Natriuretic Peptide, Brain</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

