<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03049020</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1760/14S-IV</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03049020</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Efficacy of Laparoscopic Sacrocolpopexy in the Treatment of Pelvic Organ Prolapse in Women With or Without Avulsion of the Levator Ani Muscle</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Efficacy of Laparoscopic Sacrocolpopexy in the Treatment of Pelvic Organ Prolapse in Women With or Without Avulsion of the Levator Ani Muscle</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Charles University, Czech Republic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Charles University, Czech Republic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Based on a prospective study, to evaluate how pre-operative pelvic floor status - the&#xD;
      presence of injury to the musculus levator ani - may influence the results of laparoscopic&#xD;
      sacrocolpopexy. The investigators hope to confirm or disprove the hypothesis that the&#xD;
      presence of such injury increases the risk of post-operative prolapse recurrence&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction Pelvic organ prolapse (POP), is a common health problem affecting up to 40% of&#xD;
      women. The life time risk for undergoing at least one session of pelvic organ prolapse&#xD;
      surgery has been estimated at approximately 13%. The prevalence of reoperation after primary&#xD;
      pelvic reconstructive surgery is high, around 30%, while some articles report the figure as&#xD;
      up to 58%. From the beginning of the 1990s the view of pelvic floor defects and urinary&#xD;
      incontinence in women started to change significantly. The diagnostics and management of&#xD;
      these defects became an independent uro-gynecological sub-specialization within gynecology&#xD;
      and obstetrics, and it has been included among 4 basic sub-specializations recognized by the&#xD;
      European Board and College of Obstetrics and Gynecology. Surgical treatment is indicated in&#xD;
      women with symptomatic POP when conservative management has failed or has been declined.&#xD;
      There is no indication for repair of asymptomatic POP as an isolated procedure where surgical&#xD;
      correction is of uncertain benefit and adds peri- and post-operative risks. The objective of&#xD;
      our treatment should always aim to restore quality of life and comfort. Very little is known&#xD;
      of the factors associated with surgical failure. Studies have identified a variety of risk&#xD;
      factors: younger age, high body mass index and advanced preoperative prolapse (grade III-IV)&#xD;
      were associated with an increased risk of reoperation in some studies, while other studies&#xD;
      did not prove these hypotheses. One factor which significantly influences the result of the&#xD;
      pelvic organ surgery is the presence of pelvic floor injury. Injury of the levator ani muscle&#xD;
      mainly affects the results of traditional vaginal wall repair, with 60% risk of recurrence.&#xD;
      In the last few years, in an attempt to reduce recurrence and improve the outcome of&#xD;
      reconstructive surgery in the treatment of pelvic organ prolapse, surgeons have started to&#xD;
      use transvaginally introduced prosthetic material (mesh). This type of surgery significantly&#xD;
      increases the efficacy of the procedure (anatomic cure rate over 90%), but its use is&#xD;
      associated with a risk of some complications (vaginal erosions and potential consecutive&#xD;
      infections, granulomas, dyspareunia, vesico-vaginal fistulas, chronic pain) thereby&#xD;
      potentially reducing the patients' quality of life and leading to additional surgery. If the&#xD;
      mesh is introduced during the sacrocolpopexy and the vaginal wall is not open, there is a&#xD;
      significant decrease of mesh-related complications. Laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy is considered&#xD;
      the gold standard for the management of apical prolapse with high long-term efficacy. Based&#xD;
      on the retrospective data available, it seems that the status of the pelvic floor may also&#xD;
      influence the results of this procedure, but at present investigators have no data to confirm&#xD;
      this hypothesis. Therefore investigators plan to obtain these data from a prospective&#xD;
      analysis of the results of laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the prospective longitudinal study, the investigators plan to include all patients for&#xD;
      whom surgical treatment of pelvic organ prolapse and laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy are&#xD;
      indicated. Based on pre-study power analysis enrollment of 120 patients is planned (after&#xD;
      preliminary evaluation of the results this could be increased to 160 patients), which is the&#xD;
      minimal number to prove or disprove the null hypothesis: The pelvic floor does not influence&#xD;
      the result of laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy in women with symptomatic pelvic organ prolapse&#xD;
      stage II or higher. Based on previous studies it can be anticipated that the failure rate in&#xD;
      patients with a defect of the pelvic floor will be higher. To enroll an adequate number of&#xD;
      patients the study will be conducted in two university centers with long experience of this&#xD;
      type of surgery (the number of enrolled patients in each workplace should be identical).&#xD;
      Based on pre-study statistical calculations (power analysis) it is indicated that the&#xD;
      required sample size for final statistical analysis in each group is 54 patients (allocation&#xD;
      ratio 1:1). Investigators estimate a drop-out rate of 10%, therefore it is planned to enroll&#xD;
      60 patients into each group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim of the study Based on a prospective study, to evaluate how pre-operative pelvic floor&#xD;
      status - the presence of injury to the musculus levator ani - may influence the results of&#xD;
      laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy. The investigators hope to confirm or disprove the hypothesis&#xD;
      that the presence of such injury increases the risk of post-operative prolapse recurrence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria are:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age over 18, signed informed consent, symptomatic pelvic organ prolapse stage II or higher&#xD;
      (according to the International Continence Society Pelvic Organ Prolapse quantification&#xD;
      system - POPQ) in anterior and apical (central) compartment, and agreement with postoperative&#xD;
      follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria are:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous pelvic reconstructive surgery with mesh, isolated posterior compartment prolapse,&#xD;
      previous radiotherapy in lesser pelvis, contraindication for laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pre-operative assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will undergo complete urogynecological investigation before the procedure:&#xD;
      history, clinical examination, assessment of pelvic organ prolapse using the POPQ system,&#xD;
      examination of the levator resting tone and contraction (Oxford scale),where appropriate&#xD;
      urodynamics according to International Continence Society recommendation and ultrasound&#xD;
      examination. They will also complete standardized international questionnaires (ICIQ-UI SF,&#xD;
      PISQ 12, POPDI). Ultrasound examinations will be performed as a combined examination using a&#xD;
      convex probe, from abdominal and perineal approaches, and sectoral vaginal probe from the&#xD;
      introital approach. The study will be recorded mainly in digital form. Acquired data from 4D&#xD;
      imagery will be preserved in form of data set and processed with the appropriate proper&#xD;
      software. The ultrasound examination will include an assessment of standard parameters&#xD;
      describing position of urethrovesical junction, bladder descent, uterus descent, posterior&#xD;
      vaginal wall descent (rectocele, enterocele). Using 3D/4D ultrasound examination the status&#xD;
      of pelvic floor will be evaluated (presence of avulsion of puborectalis muscle, abnormal&#xD;
      genital hiatus distension). Based on pre-operative ultrasound examination, the women will be&#xD;
      divided into two groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Group - women without defect of pelvic floor with urogenital hiatus size up to 30 cm2&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Group - women with pelvic floor trauma with urogenital hiatus size over 30 cm2&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgery and peri-operative monitoring All surgical procedures will be provided under general&#xD;
      anesthesia, and antibiotic prophylaxis will be used. Surgery will be provided in standardized&#xD;
      steps: identification of the promontory, dissection of the peritoneum above the promontory&#xD;
      and preparation of the ligamentum longitudinale anterior, peritoneum dissection, dissection&#xD;
      of the vesicovaginal septum up to bladder neck, dissection of the rectovaginal septum towards&#xD;
      the perineum, application of Y mesh, fixation to the vaginal apex using the non-absorbable&#xD;
      sutures, and for anterior and posterior vaginal wall absorbable sutures fixation of the upper&#xD;
      mesh arm to the ligamentum longitudinale anterior using non-absorbable suture, following by&#xD;
      complete peritoneum closure above the mesh. The procedure could include&#xD;
      salpingo-oophorectomy, supracervical hysterectomy or total hysterectomy (concomitant&#xD;
      procedures are not exclusion criteria).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any peri-operative complications will be monitored. Surgical evaluation will include&#xD;
      operating time (from incision to last suture), estimated intraoperative blood loss (vacuum&#xD;
      aspiration), and perioperative complications (bladder perforation, vagina perforation, bowel&#xD;
      injury, ureter injury and vascular injury). Postoperative data will be analyzed, including&#xD;
      early postoperative complications (hematoma, spontaneous voiding recovery, urinary tract&#xD;
      infection, ileus, constipation) and late postoperative complications (procedure failure, mesh&#xD;
      erosion, de novo voiding difficulty, de novo stress urinary incontinence, further surgical&#xD;
      procedures).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post-operative follow-up The first post-operative complete examination is planned for 3&#xD;
      months after surgery (the same examination as before the procedure). The next check-up will&#xD;
      be provided one year and two years after surgery, and the procedure will be the same as at&#xD;
      the 3-month check-up. In addition to pre-operative ultrasound examination, the position of&#xD;
      the mesh will be monitored. We plan to have a minimum one year follow-up for all patients in&#xD;
      this study, and also after two years when possible. Postoperative follow-up will be&#xD;
      terminated if the result of surgery is evaluated as a failure, and in these cases reoperation&#xD;
      will be offered. We also plan further post-operative follow-up up to five years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Criteria for evaluation of the cure and failure:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcome: the objective cure will be defined as absence of pelvic organ prolapse&#xD;
      (using the POPQ system - maximal I. stage prolapse).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Number of failures in each group: failure is defined as pelvic organ prolapse stage II or&#xD;
      higher using the POPQ system during the clinical examination, or as a descent 1 cm below the&#xD;
      lower edge of the pubic bone based on ultrasound examination .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary outcome:&#xD;
&#xD;
      These include change of the genital hiatus size, distance of mesh from the bladder neck&#xD;
      urethrovesical junction), lowest position of the mesh, evaluation of the subjective&#xD;
      parameters, quality of life based on evaluation of questionnaires ICIQ-SF, PISQ 12, POPDI,&#xD;
      occurrence of de novo stress urinary incontinence, number of re-operations for pelvic organ&#xD;
      prolapse, occurrence de novo symptoms of overactive bladder, in sexually active patients&#xD;
      occurrence of de novo dyspareunia&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our project completely fulfills the primary aims in conception of health research till the&#xD;
      year 2022, in the subfield &quot;Innovative surgical procedure&quot;. Basic aims and priorities of the&#xD;
      project are: implementation of the surgical procedures with lower invasivity to the treatment&#xD;
      of pelvic organ prolapse and predict its efficacy on pre-operative pelvic floor status,&#xD;
      minimizing unfavorable impact of the surgical procedure on the patient. Basis for the&#xD;
      evaluation of the socio-economic contribution of the project solution will be high-quality&#xD;
      evaluation of modern surgical procedures. Implementation of the new effective procedures for&#xD;
      the pelvic organ prolapse shall significantly decrease total treatment cost, and&#xD;
      significantly improve the long term quality of life of the patient. Thus is necessary to&#xD;
      conduct such type of study, in order to use only those procedures which improve or maintain&#xD;
      treatment effectiveness, do not increase the complication rate, and decrease the recovery&#xD;
      time - thus having a fundamental impact on the amount of money invested from the public&#xD;
      budget.&#xD;
&#xD;
      d) Methods promotion For a comparison of two groups of patient, with or without pelvic floor&#xD;
      injury is estimated range selections in particular groups. If we mark p1 percentage of&#xD;
      success rate procedure in patient with pelvic floor injury, p2 percentage of success rate&#xD;
      procedure in the group without pelvic floor injury, for a 5% significance level we will prove&#xD;
      zero hypothesis (that the percentage success rate is in all groups same) or the alternative&#xD;
      hypothesis (that the percentage success rate differ). We require the ranges of selection to&#xD;
      be the same in all groups same, and for percent values p1=85%, P2=60% a we require power test&#xD;
      80%. Under these conditions statistical calculations indicate that the required sample size&#xD;
      in each group is 54 patients, and so as a whole we will analyze the data of almost 108&#xD;
      patients. We estimate a drop-out rate of 10%, so it is planned to enrolled 60 patients into&#xD;
      each group- total 120 patients. The success rate used to calculate the size of the group has&#xD;
      been estimated from previous studies; the estimated success rate of 60% for the patient with&#xD;
      pelvic floor defect, and higher efficacy in patient with normal pelvic floor (85%). After&#xD;
      evaluation of one year result of 60 women we plan to provide interim analysis and&#xD;
      re-calculated the numbers of women which should be enrolled to the study to reach the&#xD;
      statistical significance, and we are able to increase the number of enrolled women up to 20&#xD;
      in each center to total number of 160 included patients. Based on a statistical model,&#xD;
      special software for data input will be prepared. The values to be monitored will be exactly&#xD;
      specified in the model to allow for subsequent statistical processing. In our study we will&#xD;
      use several types of statistical evaluation. In the tables summarizing general&#xD;
      characteristics, data will be evaluated by means of data average and median, significant&#xD;
      deviation. Furthermore, we will establish floor and cap of 95% confidence interval to arrive&#xD;
      at an average. Zero or alternative hypotheses will be established and their validity&#xD;
      determined. Where numbers are compared, chi square will be applied, while in cases where the&#xD;
      number of observations is small, Fischer exact test will be used. We will be used&#xD;
      non-parametric Kruskal-Wallis one-way analysis of variance for quantitative features and&#xD;
      Fisher exact test for contingency tables. We used Bonferroni inequality to correct p value in&#xD;
      case of multiple comparisons.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>October 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective cure rate</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>The objective cure will be defined as absence of pelvic organ prolapse. Number of failures in each group: failure is defined as pelvic organ prolapse stage II or higher using the POPQ system during the clinical examination, or as a descent 1 cm below the lower edge of the pubic bone based on ultrasound examination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Genital hiatus size</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluated on Valsalva in 4D transperineal ultrasound rendered volumes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Distance of mesh from the bladder neck</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>measured in sagittal plane on transperineal ultrasound.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lowest position of the mesh</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>measured in sagittal plane on transperineal ultrasound.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ICIQ-UI SF</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>International Consultation on Incontinence Questionnaire - Urinary Incontinence , short form.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PISQ 12</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>Pelvic Organ Prolapse/ Incontinence Sexual Questionnaire - validated measure for evaluation of sexuality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PFDI</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>Pelvic Floor Distress Inventory - validated measure for assessment of pelvic floor function</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>de novo stress urinary incontinence</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>complaints of the patient</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>de novo symptoms of overactive bladder</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>complaints of the patient</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>number of re-operations</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>for any reason</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>de novo dyspareunia</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>in previously sexually active women</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Pelvic Organ Prolapse Recurrence</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>With levator ani avulsion</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients indicated for sacrocolpopexy for pelvic organ prolapse and suffering with levator ani avulsion</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Without levator ani avulsion</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients indicated for sacrocolpopexy for pelvic organ prolapse and without levator ani avulsion</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy</intervention_name>
    <description>standard laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy for prolapse treatment</description>
    <arm_group_label>With levator ani avulsion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Without levator ani avulsion</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Age over 18, symptomatic pelvic organ prolapse stage II or higher (according to the&#xD;
        International Continence Society Pelvic Organ Prolapse quantification system - POPQ) in&#xD;
        anterior and apical (central) compartment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age over 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  symptomatic pelvic organ prolapse stage II or higher (according to the International&#xD;
             Continence Society Pelvic Organ Prolapse quantification system - POPQ) in anterior and&#xD;
             apical (central) compartment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  agreement with postoperative follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous pelvic reconstructive mesh surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Isolated posterior compartment prolapse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous radiotherapy in lesser pelvis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication of laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jaromir Masata, MD, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Charles University, Czech Republic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jaromir Masata, MD, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>224967009</phone>
    <email>masata@volny.cz</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vladimir Kalis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Plzen</city>
        <country>Czech Republic</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Vladimir Kalis</last_name>
      <phone>377617213</phone>
      <email>kalisv@fnplzen.cz</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>General University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Prague</city>
        <zip>12800</zip>
        <country>Czech Republic</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jaromir Masata</last_name>
      <phone>224967009</phone>
      <email>masata@volny.cz</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Czech Republic</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 10, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 8, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 9, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 8, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 8, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 9, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Charles University, Czech Republic</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kamil Svabik</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Kamil Svabik, MD, Ph.D.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>pelvic organ prolapse</keyword>
  <keyword>sacrocolpopexy</keyword>
  <keyword>pelvic floor ultrasound</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prolapse</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pelvic Organ Prolapse</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

