<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03766126</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>831619 (UPCC 35418)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03766126</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lentivirally Redirected CD123 Autologous T Cells in AML</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I Study of Lentivirally Transduced T Cells Engineered to Contain Anti-CD123 Linked to TCRζ and 4-1BB Signaling Domains in Subjects With Refractory Acute Myeloid Leukemia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pennsylvania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Phase 1 open-label study to estimate the safety, manufacturing feasibility, and efficacy of&#xD;
      intravenously administered, lentivirally transduced T cells expressing anti-CD123 chimeric&#xD;
      antigen receptors expressing tandem TCRζ and 4-1BB (TCRζ /4-1BB) costimulatory domains in&#xD;
      Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML) subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 1 study to determine the safety, feasibility, and efficacy of CART123 cells&#xD;
      following lymphodepleting chemotherapy in patients with relapsed/refractory AML. Subjects&#xD;
      will be treated with a split dosing approach of CART123 cells (10% Day 0; 30% Day 1; 60% Day&#xD;
      2) for Cohort 1a/1b or a single IV administration of CART123 cells for Cohort 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The total dose administered to each subject will be based on body weight obtained at the time&#xD;
      of apheresis. Thus, the target total transduced dose, preceded by lymphodepleting&#xD;
      chemotherapy, is 1-2x10^6 CART123 cells/kg for Cohort 1a, 5x10^6 CART123 cells/kg for Cohort&#xD;
      1b, or 2x10^6 CART-123 cells/kg for Cohort 2. The protocol-specified minimum acceptable dose&#xD;
      for infusion is 1x10^5 CART123 cells/kg for all cohorts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is recommended per routine clinical care, that all subjects with marrow aplasia at Day&#xD;
      28+/-5 undergo allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplantation (alloHCT) as a rescue strategy.&#xD;
      If required, this procedure will be performed as part of routine care, outside of the scope&#xD;
      of this research study, however subjects will continue to be followed on study. All subjects&#xD;
      should therefore have a previously identified stem cell donor in order to participate in this&#xD;
      study. Please see Section 6.8 for additional details.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All subjects will be followed monthly for up to 6 months post the first CART123 cell infusion&#xD;
      (Day 0). Thereafter subjects will be transitioned into LTFU for up to 15 years post infusion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 6, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 3, 2033</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 3, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety profile of CART123 cells by monitoring the frequency and severity of adverse events assessed by the National Cancer Institute (NCI) - Common Toxicity Criteria (v5.0)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the safety of CART123 cells in AML subjects following lymphodepletion with cyclophosphamide + fludarabine.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the percentage of manufacturing products that do not meet release criteria for vector transduction efficiency, T cell product purity, viability, sterility.</measure>
    <time_frame>5 year</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate the percentage of manufacturing products that do not meet release criteria for vector transduction efficiency, T cell product purity, viability, sterility.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Estimation of CART123 efficacy by evaluation of OS and PFS of subjects at protocol defined intervals which receive at least one infusion of CART123 cells</measure>
    <time_frame>15 years</time_frame>
    <description>Estimate the efficacy of at least 1 dose of CART123 cells in AML subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS) as percent of subjects surviving at protocol defined time points.</measure>
    <time_frame>15 years</time_frame>
    <description>Overall survival (OS) and progression-free survival (PFS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS) as percent of subjects surviving without disease progression at protocol defined time points</measure>
    <time_frame>15 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response (DOR)</measure>
    <time_frame>15 years</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of response (DOR)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Necessity of rescue bone marrow transplant</measure>
    <time_frame>15 years</time_frame>
    <description>Need for rescue allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplantation (alloHCT)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Myeloid Leukemia, in Relapse</condition>
  <condition>Acute Myeloid Leukemia, Adult</condition>
  <condition>Acute Myeloid Leukemia, Refractory</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>CART123 cells; cyclophosphamide; fludarabine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CART123 cells; cyclophosphamide; fludarabine</intervention_name>
    <description>CART123 cells following lymphodepleting chemotherapy in patients with relapsed/refractory AML. Subjects will be treated with a split dosing approach of CART123 cells (10% Day 0; 30% Day 1; 60% Day 2) for Cohort 1a/1b or a single IV administration of CART123 cells for Cohort 2.&#xD;
The total dose administered to each subject will be based on body weight obtained at the time of apheresis. Thus, the target total transduced dose, preceded by lymphodepleting chemotherapy, is 1-2x10^6 CART123 cells/kg for Cohort 1a, 5x10^6 CART123 cells/kg for Cohort 1b, or 2x10^6 CART-123 cells/kg for Cohort 2. The protocol-specified minimum acceptable dose for infusion is 1x10^5 CART123 cells/kg.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>T Cells Containing Anti-CD123 Signaling Domains</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female subjects 18 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects with active acute myeloid leukemia (AML) with no available curative treatment&#xD;
             options using currently available therapies. Specifically:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. AML that has not achieved a complete remission or morphologic leukemia free state&#xD;
                  by ELN criteria (Döhner et al., 2017 Blood, 129(4):424-447); partial remission or&#xD;
                  refractory disease (including primary refractory) are eligible. Or:&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. AML relapsed following allogeneic stem cell transplantation (including MDS&#xD;
                  evolved to AML post-allogeneic stem cell transplantation). Note: morphologic&#xD;
                  relapse is not required; persistent/recurrent disease-associated molecular,&#xD;
                  phenotypic or cytogenetic abnormalities (measurable residual disease, MRD) at any&#xD;
                  time after allogeneic HCT is eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects with relapsed disease after prior transplant must meet one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Subjects with relapsed disease after prior allogeneic HCT (myeloablative or&#xD;
             non-myeloablative) will be eligible if they meet all other inclusion criteria and i.&#xD;
             Have no residual donor cells (by STR analysis on 2 occasions separated by at least 1&#xD;
             month), OR: ii. Donor cells are present but there is no active GVHD (&gt;Gr II), subject&#xD;
             does not require systemic immunosuppression and is more than 3 months from transplant,&#xD;
             and at least 1 month off GVHD prophylaxis.&#xD;
&#xD;
             b. Subjects with relapsed disease after prior autologous or syngeneic HCT will be&#xD;
             eligible if they meet all other inclusion criteria and it has been more than 3 months&#xD;
             from transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects must have a suitable stem cell donor available who may donate cells in the&#xD;
             event the subject needs to undergo an allogeneic HCT. Donor may be matched or&#xD;
             mismatched and must be found to be suitable according to the institution's standard&#xD;
             criteria; donors must be fully cleared to proceed as the donor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Satisfactory organ functions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Creatinine ≤ 1.6 mg/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. ALT/AST must be ≤5 x upper limit of normal unless related to disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Direct bilirubin or total bilirubin &lt; 2.0mg/dl, unless subject has Gilbert's&#xD;
                  syndrome (≤3.0 mg/dL);&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Left ventricular ejection fraction &gt; 40% as confirmed by ECHO/MUGA&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. ECOG Performance status 0-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Written informed consent is given.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. No contraindications for leukapheresis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects of reproductive potential must agree to use acceptable birth control methods&#xD;
             (as described in protocol Section 4.3).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnant or lactating (nursing women) women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with relapsed AML with t(15:17).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. HIV infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Active hepatitis B or hepatitis C infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Concurrent use of systemic steroids or immunosuppressant medications. Recent or&#xD;
             current use of inhaled steroids or physiologic replacement with hydrocortisone is not&#xD;
             exclusionary. For additional details regarding use of steroids while on study, please&#xD;
             see Section 5.5.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any uncontrolled active medical disorder that would preclude participation as&#xD;
             outlined.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects with signs or symptoms indicative of CNS involvement. A CNS evaluation should&#xD;
             be performed as clinically appropriate to rule out CNS involvement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Known history of allergy or hypersensitivity to study product excipients (human serum&#xD;
             albumin, DMSO, and Dextran 40).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Class III/IV cardiovascular disability according to the New York Heart Association&#xD;
             Classification (see Appendix 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with a known history or prior diagnosis of optic neuritis or other&#xD;
             immunologic or inflammatory disease affecting the central nervous system, and&#xD;
             unrelated to leukemia or previous leukemia treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects with clinically apparent arrhythmia, or arrhythmias that are not stable on&#xD;
             medical management, within 2 weeks of the Screening/Enrollment visit.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pennsylvania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 3, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 4, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 6, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 16, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 16, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>refractory</keyword>
  <keyword>relapsed</keyword>
  <keyword>Acute</keyword>
  <keyword>Myeloid</keyword>
  <keyword>leukemia</keyword>
  <keyword>AML</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fludarabine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

