<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00937131</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BRD/05/011</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00937131</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Use of Rituximab in Acute Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic Purpura (TTP)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Study to Assess the Safety, Efficacy and Tolerability of Rituximab (Mabthera) in Combination With Plasma Exchange (PEX) in Patients With Acute Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic Purpura (TTP)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University College, London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University College, London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      TTP is a rare and serious blood disorder, characterized by the formation of small clots&#xD;
      (micro thrombi) within the circulation and can be fatal. The formation of blood clots occurs&#xD;
      primarily in the smaller blood vessels, the arterioles and capillaries, associated with&#xD;
      multisystem organ involvement, especially the brain and kidneys. TTP has an incidence of&#xD;
      approximately 1-3 people/million of the population/year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TTP is due to a decrease in an enzyme, ADAMTS 13 that is released by cells lining blood&#xD;
      vessels (endothelial cells). ADAMTS 13 'cleaves' or breaks down very large von Willebrand&#xD;
      Factor (vWF) strands. vWF is used in blood clotting. Deficiency or inhibition of the enzyme,&#xD;
      results in release of the ultra large vWF into the circulation. Platelets bind to these ultra&#xD;
      large vWF multimers, promoting blood clot formation and platelet consumption&#xD;
      (thrombocytopenia). In more then 70% of TTP cases no precipitating cause can be found and the&#xD;
      majority of these patients have antibodies against ADAMTS 13. Plasma Exchange (PEX) was&#xD;
      introduced in the management of TTP in 1977 and the mortality of TTP patients has since&#xD;
      decreased from approximately 90% to 15-20%. PEX is essential in TTP treatment as plasma&#xD;
      contains the missing enzyme ADAMTS 13.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rituximab (licensed and internationally used monoclonal antibody) selectively acts on white&#xD;
      blood cells known as B-lymphocytes or B cells that produce the antibody to ADAMTS 13. By&#xD;
      inhibiting ADAMTS 13 antibody production, ADAMTS 13 activity increases, resulting in&#xD;
      remission. Rituximab has been used in our institutions in patients with acute TTP that are&#xD;
      refractory to standard treatment - PEX. The resulting remission has been dramatic, with a&#xD;
      non-toxic side effect profile and no patients to date has relapsed (longest follow-up 19&#xD;
      months) following Rituximab therapy. Therefore, we plan to use Rituximab with PEX in patients&#xD;
      who present with acute TTP.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is multi-centre study within the South East England (SEE) Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic&#xD;
      Purpura (TTP) study group, primarily involving tertiary centres with expertise in treating&#xD;
      TTP, apheresis units and specialist medical professionals. Feedback and discussions with TTP&#xD;
      patients during treatment and discussion with those attending out-patient clinics have been&#xD;
      incorporated into the development of this study. We have reviewed treatment protocols for TTP&#xD;
      patients published in peer reviewed journals and consulted SEE TTP study groups on the study&#xD;
      design. Medical professionals with expertise in TTP treatment and management have also been&#xD;
      consulted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a non-randomised Phase ll feasibility study to assess (i) whether Rituximab with PEX&#xD;
      decreases the time to remission of patients with acute TTP, (ii) the mortality of TTP&#xD;
      patients (assessed at 3 months from presentation), (iii) the safety and toxicity of Rituximab&#xD;
      in conjunction with standard therapy for acute TTP, (iv) the effect of Rituximab on B cell&#xD;
      function, (v) the effect of Rituximab on ADAMTS 13 activity and antibody production and time&#xD;
      to relapse. The study design and methodology has been devised to specifically address&#xD;
      questions regarding the use of Rituximab with PEX to further improve the treatment of TTP&#xD;
      patients with the least disruption and inconvenience to their standard and local treatment&#xD;
      and care to decrease TTP patient mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adult patients (across up to 8 participating UK sites) presenting with acute TTP and who fall&#xD;
      within the study protocol inclusion criteria, as determined by the Lead Consultant&#xD;
      Haematologist per institution, will be offered entry into the study. We wish to recruit 40&#xD;
      patients to this study and although the incidence of TTP is low, it is generally considered&#xD;
      to be under diagnosed and therefore, underestimated. Recruiting 40 patients is achievable&#xD;
      considering the number of patients presenting with acute TTP within the SEE TTP study group&#xD;
      over the past 18 months. Some TTP patients may be unconscious or may have a neurological&#xD;
      dysfunction associated with acute TTP, such as personality or memory symptoms. In these&#xD;
      cases, consent will be requested from the patient's legal representative in compliance with&#xD;
      the International Conference on Harmonisation (ICH) guidance for Good Clinical Practice&#xD;
      (GCP).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given the significant benefit in terms of remission, the increased level of ADAMTS 13 level&#xD;
      in patients with acute refractory TTP and documented benefit of patients with other antibody&#xD;
      driven disorders with Rituximab therapy, Rituximab in conjunction with standard therapy -&#xD;
      PEX, is to be investigated. This is to reduce mortality further that the 15-20%, reducing the&#xD;
      number of PEXs and therefore decreasing the exposure to blood component products that may&#xD;
      contain fatal proteins such as variant Creutzfeldt-Jakob Disease (vCJD). As between 30-60%&#xD;
      relapse with a further episode of TTP, follow up to determine time to relapse will be&#xD;
      observed and compared to historical controls. During this period, blood counts and ADAMTS 13&#xD;
      levels will be assessed. We have a specific assay to determine the benefit following&#xD;
      treatments and historical data to compare previous patient admission that can be matched.&#xD;
      Researcher bias will be reduced as the time taken for a specific platelet level count (150 x&#xD;
      10 to the power of 9/L) must be determined and recorded within the routine laboratory in each&#xD;
      institution, the number of PEX will be recorded by the patient's nurse, continuing until the&#xD;
      platelet count is maintained above 150 x 10 to the power of 9/L. In addition, there will be a&#xD;
      clear audit trail, which will allow data and records to be cross checked.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators know from the literature and data collected as part of the SEE TTP study&#xD;
      group, the epidemiology of TTP and mortality rate. With the improvement in laboratory&#xD;
      techniques, there is improved detection of antibodies against ADAMTS 13. As antibodies to&#xD;
      ADAMTS 13 can be detected in up to 90% of cases, having excluded specific precipitating&#xD;
      causes, monitoring of ADAMTS 13 levels and the ADAMTS 13 antibody can be made regularly in&#xD;
      our research facility. As per the patient's local treatment protocol for TTP i.e. PEX and&#xD;
      steroid treatment, all patients will have a daily PEX until their platelet level count is &gt;&#xD;
      150 X 10 to the power of 9/L. Patients will receive pre-Rituximab medication (Hydrocortison,&#xD;
      Piriton, and Paracetamol, as per local protocol), 30 minutes prior to Rituximab infusion to&#xD;
      reduce any potential side effects. Rituximab will be administered intravenously, immediately&#xD;
      following PEX. PEX should be withheld for 24 hours following Rituximab therapy, if&#xD;
      appropriate to the patient's clinical condition. Rituximab will be given once a week for 4&#xD;
      weeks in the first instance. The first treatment will be given within the first 3 days of&#xD;
      admission, as there is a need to administer Rituximab in working office hours and allows&#xD;
      participating sites to obtain the test results to ascertain whether the patient meets the&#xD;
      study's inclusion criteria. If patients are well enough to be discharged before their 4th&#xD;
      treatment, treatment will be continued in their local haematology day unit. If there is still&#xD;
      evidence of antibodies to ADAMTS 13 and the ADAMTS 13 level has not been&#xD;
      corrected/normalised, up to a maximum 4 additional Rituximab infusion will be given weekly.&#xD;
      Nurses will monitor the patient's blood pressure, pulse, breathing rate, temperature and&#xD;
      oxygen saturation level every 15 min for the first hour of Rituximab infusion and then hourly&#xD;
      until infusion is complete. The patient will continue to be monitored as per the local&#xD;
      protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The side effects of Rituximab are generally mild such as flu-like symptoms, low blood&#xD;
      pressure, nausea, flushing and rigor, and if experienced, usually occur during the first&#xD;
      infusion. Pre-medication as noted above will be given prior to Rituximab infusion. If any&#xD;
      side effects are experienced the rate of the infusion will be reviewed, slowed or suspended&#xD;
      if necessary and intervention appropriate to the side effect will be given. Anaphylaxis is a&#xD;
      potential risk with the first dose, but all patients will receive appropriate pre-medication.&#xD;
      Very rare side effects are more likely to be associated with people who have extensive&#xD;
      lymphoma disease and/or as a result of several years use of Rituximab in clinical trials,&#xD;
      primarily for malignant disease, often with other chemotherapeutic agents as well as post&#xD;
      marketing surveillance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will have standard haematological and biochemical blood tests as well having&#xD;
      their ADAMTS 13 levels assessed. Regular blood tests will be arranged for patients discharged&#xD;
      from hospital, to check their full blood count, electrolytes and liver function results and&#xD;
      ADAMDTS 13 level. TTP patients will be reviewed initially weekly at their local out-patients&#xD;
      clinic following discharge and as time passes and if their results are stable the period&#xD;
      between appointments will be lengthened.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study has been designed to cause the least disruption and inconvenience to patients and&#xD;
      their standard and treatment/care. It is imperative that patients are continuously assessed&#xD;
      and monitored during and post study treatment. Any potential risk is offset by (i) improving&#xD;
      time to remission, associated with a decreased time of active TTP and organ damage, (ii)&#xD;
      reduced exposure to plasma products and thus the risk of vCJD and (iii) improved management&#xD;
      of acute TTP and mortality of these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will be reviewed in local haematology clinics or the TTP clinic at UCLH.&#xD;
      Patients or their legal representatives will be informed or any update of TTP information in&#xD;
      general or if new information becomes available about the treatment/drug during the study or&#xD;
      during regular outpatient consultations. Review of ongoing data will be presented at the SEE&#xD;
      TTP study group as well as national and international meetings. The final report will be&#xD;
      presented in peer reviewed journals. Patient will also be kept informed of any publications&#xD;
      arising from the study and hardcopies will be made available to all patients or their next of&#xD;
      kin/legal representative.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>March 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary objective of this study is to investigate whether Rituximab and PEX decreases the time to remission of TTP patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Improved mortality ot TTP patients</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and toxicity of Rituximab in conjunction with standard therapy for acute TTP</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of Rituximab on B lymphocyte function</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of Rituximab on ADAMTS 13 activity and antibody production and time to relapse</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic Purpura (TTP)</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rituximab</intervention_name>
    <description>Concentrate for solution for infusion, Intravenous use, 375mg/m2, Maximum 8 weekly infusions</description>
    <other_name>Rituximab (MabThera)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients &gt; 18 years and &lt; 65 years who present with an acute episode of TTP&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of microangiopathic haemolytic anaemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thrombocytopenia with a normal clotting screen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Raised Lactate Dehydrogenase (one and a half time above upper normal)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients without neurological dysfunction able to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients of reproductive age (must avoid pregnancy for 12 months and/or normalised B&#xD;
             cell function after receiving Rituximab. Oestrogen containing oral contraceptive pills&#xD;
             and the morning after pills should be avoided in female TTP patients)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with an acute deterioration in neurological function which may include&#xD;
             encephalopathy, such as altered personality, problems with short term memory and coma&#xD;
             can be included when consent has been given by next of kin or from the appropriate&#xD;
             legal representative.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All female subjects who are knowingly pregnant or breast feeding or do not use an&#xD;
             adequate form of contraception (the effect on the foetus and newborn have not yet been&#xD;
             fully established so Rituximab should be avoided in these groups. Male patients&#xD;
             receiving Rituximab should ensure adequate contraception for 12 months following&#xD;
             treatment).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are HIV positive (which does not appear to be antibody mediated, would be&#xD;
             unlikely to benefit from Rituximab)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with childhood TTP&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have Haemolytic Uraemic Syndrome (HUS) (which is not associated with&#xD;
             reduced ADAMTS 13 levels)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are post bone marrow transplant - either autologous or allogeneic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients wiht a medical or long term psychiatric condition which, in the opinion of&#xD;
             the investigator, contraindicates the patients' participation into the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous or concurrent malignancies at other sites, with exception of appropriately&#xD;
             treated localized epithelial or cervical cancer. Patients with a history of cured&#xD;
             tumours may be entered (&gt; 5 years).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marie A Scully, MBBS, BSc, MRCPath</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University College London, University College London Hosptials NHS Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St Bartholomew's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>EC1A 7BE</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St Thomas Hosptial</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SE1 7EH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University College London Hospitals</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>W1</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 9, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 9, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 10, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 9, 2009</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 9, 2009</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">July 10, 2009</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Nadeem Khan</name_title>
    <organization>University College London</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Purpura</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Purpura, Thrombocytopenic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Purpura, Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

