<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00039559</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CDR0000069397</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>MGH-000084</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00039559</nct_id>
    <nct_alias>NCT00301743</nct_alias>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Trial to Screen Participants Who Are at High Genetic Risk for Ovarian Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Ovarian Cancer Screening Pilot Trial in High Risk Women</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Massachusetts General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      RATIONALE: Screening tests may help doctors detect cancer cells early and plan more effective&#xD;
      treatment for ovarian cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PURPOSE: Screening trial to determine the significance of cancer antigen 125 (CA125) levels&#xD;
      in detecting ovarian cancer in participants who have a high genetic risk of developing&#xD;
      ovarian cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine the feasibility of prospective ovarian cancer screening studies within the&#xD;
           Cancer Genetics Network and other NCI ovarian programs for participants who are at high&#xD;
           genetic risk for developing ovarian cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Identify the logistical issues of screening these participants and their solutions&#xD;
           within this framework.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Establish normal ranges and distributions of CA125 values over time within and between&#xD;
           high-risk participants, with subclassification by pre- or post-menopausal status,&#xD;
           estrogen-replacement therapy usage, and prior prophylactic oophorectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Estimate the specificity and positive predictive value of the &quot;risk of ovarian cancer&#xD;
           algorithm&quot; (ROCA) suitable for designing a definitive trial of screening for ovarian&#xD;
           cancer in high-risk participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Establish a longitudinal serum and plasma biorepository for retrospective evaluation of&#xD;
           other promising biomarkers with special relevance to inherited ovarian and breast cancer&#xD;
           risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Participants with 1 or 2 ovaries are assigned to group&#xD;
      A, whereas participants with prior prophylactic bilateral oophorectomy are assigned to group&#xD;
      B (closed to accrual as of 10/18/04).&#xD;
&#xD;
      At baseline, participants who are not eligible by breast cancer susceptibility gene (BRCA)&#xD;
      mutation criteria or family history criteria undergo a probability of having a BRCA mutation&#xD;
      given family history of cancer (BRCAPRO) evaluation. Participants in both groups complete a&#xD;
      questionnaire requesting demographic information and a personal and family health history at&#xD;
      baseline and a questionnaire requesting hospitalization or cancer diagnosis information after&#xD;
      each blood test. Participants in both groups also complete health status questionnaires once&#xD;
      every 3 months for 6 months-7 years. Participants undergo blood draws for measurement of&#xD;
      CA125 levels once every 3 months for 6 months-7 years. For each CA125 measurement, the risk&#xD;
      of ovarian cancer algorithm (ROCA) is calculated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group A (1 or 2 ovaries at baseline):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants are assigned to 1 of 2 subgroups based on ROCA.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Subgroup A1: Participants with normal-risk for ovarian cancer (ROCA less than 1%)&#xD;
                continue CA125 screening as above.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Subgroup A2: Participants with intermediate-risk for ovarian cancer (ROCA more than&#xD;
                1% but less than 10%) or elevated-risk for ovarian cancer (ROCA more than 10%)&#xD;
                undergo transvaginal sonography (TVS). Participants with elevated-risk undergo an&#xD;
                additional blood draw for a confirmatory CA125 level prior to TVS. Participants&#xD;
                with normal TVS continue CA125 screening as above. Participants with abnormal TVS&#xD;
                are referred to a gynecologic oncologist who decides whether standard clinical&#xD;
                intervention for potential ovarian cancer is needed. Participants who are not&#xD;
                referred for standard clinical intervention continue CA125 screening as above.&#xD;
                Participants who are referred for standard clinical intervention, have at least 1&#xD;
                ovary remaining, and are found to have no malignancy continue CA125 screening as&#xD;
                above. Participants who are referred for standard clinical intervention, are found&#xD;
                to have no malignancy, and then undergo prophylactic bilateral oophorectomy proceed&#xD;
                to CA125 screening as in group B below. Participants who are referred for standard&#xD;
                clinical intervention and are found to have malignancy are taken off study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group B (no ovaries at baseline) (closed to accrual as of 10/18/04):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants are assigned to 1 of 2 subgroups based on ROCA.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Subgroup B1: Participants with normal-risk for ovarian cancer (ROCA less than 5%)&#xD;
                continue CA 125 screening as above.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Subgroup B2: Participants with elevated-risk for ovarian cancer (ROCA more than 5%)&#xD;
                undergo an additional blood draw for a confirmatory CA125 level and are then&#xD;
                referred to a gynecologic oncologist who decides whether standard clinical&#xD;
                intervention for potential ovarian cancer is needed. Participants who are not&#xD;
                referred for standard clinical intervention continue CA125 screening as above.&#xD;
                Participants who are referred for standard clinical intervention and are not found&#xD;
                to have malignancy continue CA125 screening as above. Participants who are referred&#xD;
                for standard clinical intervention and are found to have malignancy are taken off&#xD;
                study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients are followed for clinical diagnosis for 1 additional year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PROJECTED ACCRUAL: Approximately 2,430 participants will be accrued for this study within 12&#xD;
      months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>May 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity of early detection for ovarian cancer</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to one year since last blood test</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Specificity of early detection</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to one year from last blood test</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2430</enrollment>
  <condition>Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Early detection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Early detection</intervention_name>
    <description>CA125 is measured in blood and the longitudinal results interpreted with a statistical algorithm to determine if there has been a significant increase from baseline.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Early detection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant meet the criteria for one of the following conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participant has tested positive for a mutation in the breast cancer&#xD;
                  susceptibility gene 1 (BRCA1) or breast cancer susceptibility gene 2 (BRCA2) or&#xD;
                  has a first- or second-degree relative with a BRCA1 or BRCA2 mutation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  At least 2 ovarian or breast cancers (including ductal carcinoma in situ) have&#xD;
                  occurred among the participant and her first- and second-degree relatives within&#xD;
                  the same lineage&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Condition may be satisfied by multiple primary cancers in the same person&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Where breast cancer is required to meet this criterion, at least 1 breast&#xD;
                       cancer patient must have been pre-menopausal (age 50 and under at diagnosis&#xD;
                       if age at menopause unknown)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participant is of Ashkenazi Jewish ethnicity and either has had breast cancer or&#xD;
                  has 1 first-degree or 2 second-degree relatives with breast cancer (including&#xD;
                  ductal carcinoma in situ) or ovarian cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Where breast cancer is required to meet this criterion, at least 1 breast&#xD;
                       cancer patient must have been pre-menopausal (age 50 and under at diagnosis&#xD;
                       if age at menopause unknown)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Probability of carrying a BRCA1 or BRCA2 mutation exceeds 20% as calculated by&#xD;
                  BRCAPRO, given family pedigree of breast cancer (including ductal carcinoma in&#xD;
                  situ) and ovarian cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must have no prior or concurrent ovarian cancer (including low malignant&#xD;
             potential (LMP) cancers) or primary papillary serous carcinoma of the peritoneum&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must not be negative for the same BRCA1 or BRCA2 mutation for which a&#xD;
             first- or second-degree relative has tested positive&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who test negative for BRCA1 or BRCA2 mutation are still eligible if the&#xD;
             pedigree or BRCAPRO criteria are satisfied, including Ashkenazi women who test&#xD;
             negative for the three founder mutations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documentation of family history is by participant's self-report&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In relatives, ovarian cancer is defined as invasive ovarian epithelial cancers,&#xD;
             fallopian tube cancers, or primary papillary serous carcinoma of the peritoneum&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Germ cell or granulosa tumors or LMP ovarian cancers do not qualify&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  First- and second-degree relatives include half siblings of the participant or her&#xD;
             first-degree relative&#xD;
&#xD;
        PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Age:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  30 and over&#xD;
&#xD;
        Performance status:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not specified&#xD;
&#xD;
        Life expectancy:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not specified&#xD;
&#xD;
        Hematopoietic:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No hemophilia or other bleeding disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No serious anemia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Hepatic:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not specified&#xD;
&#xD;
        Renal:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not specified&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pulmonary:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No emphysema&#xD;
&#xD;
        Other:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fertile patients must use effective contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No psychiatric, psychological, or other conditions that would preclude informed&#xD;
             consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No concurrent untreated malignancy except nonmelanoma skin cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No medical conditions that would preclude blood draws during study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No chronic infectious disease&#xD;
&#xD;
        PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Biologic therapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not specified&#xD;
&#xD;
        Chemotherapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 3 months since prior adjuvant anticancer chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Endocrine therapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior or concurrent adjuvant hormonal therapies (e.g., tamoxifen, leuprolide, or&#xD;
             goserelin) allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent hormonal therapies (e.g., tamoxifen) for prevention allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
        Radiotherapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 3 months since prior adjuvant anticancer radiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Surgery:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 3 months since prior intraperitoneal surgery (laparoscopy or laparotomy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No prior prophylactic oophorectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Other:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 5 years since prior non-hormonal treatment for metastatic malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No concurrent participation in other ovarian cancer early detection trials&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Steven J. Skates, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M. D. Anderson Cancer Center at University of Texas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030-4009</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 6, 2002</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 26, 2003</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 27, 2003</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 7, 2013</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 7, 2013</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">June 10, 2013</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Steven Skates</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Steven Skates PhD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ovarian epithelial cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Ovarian Epithelial</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

