<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00034021</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R01AT000224-01A2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00034021</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ginkgo Biloba: Antidepressant-Induced Sexual Dysfunction</brief_title>
  <official_title>Ginkgo Biloba: Antidepressant-Induced Sexual Dysfunction</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health (NCCIH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health (NCCIH)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to provide the first empirical examination of the effects of&#xD;
      Ginkgo biloba (GBE), sex therapy, and a combination of the two on subjective and&#xD;
      physiological measures of sexual function in women who are experiencing sexual disorders&#xD;
      secondary to antidepressants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Virtually all antidepressant medications are associated with a high incidence of adverse&#xD;
      sexual side effects. In women, the side effects most commonly reported include decreased&#xD;
      sexual arousal with decreased lubrication, delayed or inhibited orgasm, and decreased sexual&#xD;
      desire. To date, there are no effective pharmacological antidotes for treating these sexual&#xD;
      side effects. Ginkgo biloba extract (GBE), a naturally occurring substance from the ancient&#xD;
      Chinese Ginkgo tree, has properties proven to increase peripheral blood flow and to&#xD;
      facilitate the relaxation of smooth muscle tissue. Its effectiveness in this regard has been&#xD;
      demonstrated in numerous clinical trials that show gingko biloba to be highly efficient in&#xD;
      treating peripheral vascular disorders. Female sexual arousal involves a complex interplay of&#xD;
      these very actions - the relaxation of smooth muscle tissue and the inflow of blood to the&#xD;
      genital region. Hence, pharmacologically, it is feasible that GBE may be effective in&#xD;
      enhancing female sexual arousal. Moreover, given that the mechanisms hypothesized to&#xD;
      facilitate female sexual function are operative at a peripheral rather than a central (i.e.,&#xD;
      neurotransmitter) level, it is unlikely that GBE would adversely impact the mood-alleviating&#xD;
      therapeutic effects of antidepressant medications that are believed to be centrally mediated.&#xD;
      Limited, uncontrolled studies lend support to this hypothesis. The purpose of the present&#xD;
      study is to provide the first empirical examination of the effects of both acute and chronic&#xD;
      GBE on subjective and physiological measures of sexual function in women who are experiencing&#xD;
      clinically diagnosable hypoactive sexual desire disorder, female sexual arousal disorder,&#xD;
      and/or inhibited female orgasm secondary to either to fluoxetine, sertraline, or paroxetine&#xD;
      use. Women (N = 110) stabilized on antidepressant medication and free of a current Axis I&#xD;
      disorder will be randomized to 8 weeks of daily treatment with either GBE (200 mg) or&#xD;
      placebo. Sexual functioning will be assessed through (a) daily patient diary recordings, (b)&#xD;
      patient-rating scales completed each week, and (c) blind independent evaluator ratings. The&#xD;
      acute effects of GBE will also be assessed using vaginal photoplethysmograph techniques to&#xD;
      assess genital blood flow, both prior to and following chronic GBE treatment. The findings&#xD;
      from the present study will (a) help determine whether chronic and/or acute GBE facilitates&#xD;
      sexual function in women with antidepressant-induced sexual dysfunction and, (b) examine&#xD;
      whether acute GBE influences vaginal measures of sexual arousal. If effective, GBE could play&#xD;
      a significant adjunctive role in the treatment of clinical depression and other psychological&#xD;
      disorders commonly treated with antidepressant medications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date>September 2004</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <condition>Hypoactive Sexual Desire Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Sexual Dysfunctions, Psychological</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ginkgo Biloba</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sex Therapy (genital focus)</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Proficient in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be currently involved in a heterosexual relationship in which they are&#xD;
             willing to engage in at least two sexual encounters (with intent to attain orgasm) per&#xD;
             week during the course of the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who report an onset of Hypoactive Sexual Desire Disorder, Female Sexual&#xD;
             Arousal Disorder, or Female Orgasmic Disorder no less than one week and no more than 3&#xD;
             months after beginning treatment with either fluoxetine, sertraline, or paroxetine;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have been receiving treatment with either fluoxetine, sertraline, or&#xD;
             paroxetine for a minimum of 10 weeks (and are currently receiving fluoxetine,&#xD;
             sertraline, or paroxetine treatment);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must describe the sexual dysfunction as following the otherwise successful&#xD;
             treatment with the antidepressant, and as being distinctly different from any sexual&#xD;
             dysfunction they may have noticed prior to starting antidepressant treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must agree to not use aspirin during the course of the study, and agree to&#xD;
             use a medically accepted form of birth control for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must agree to not supplement their diet with GBE throughout the duration of&#xD;
             the study (outside of that which they receive as part of the study medication).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must live in Austin Texas&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Under the age of 18 or over the age of 65&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with amenorrhea for &gt; 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant (as determined by a pregnancy test) or are intending to become&#xD;
             pregnant during the course of the study, and subjects who are lactating or are &lt;1 year&#xD;
             post-partum.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of bleeding disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of HIV infection or active, untreated pelvic or urinary tract infection&#xD;
             including, sexually transmitted diseases such as chlamydia, genital herpes, gonorrhea,&#xD;
             or syphilis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major pelvic surgery that may have caused nerve damage, including: vulvectomy,&#xD;
             circumcision, colostomy, cystostomy, or serious bladder, rectal, or abdominal surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurological impairment due to diabetes, stroke, pelvic nerve damage secondary to&#xD;
             trauma, cancer treatments, myasthenia gravis, multiple sclerosis or spinal cord&#xD;
             damage.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant untreated renal or endocrine disease. Uncontrolled hypotension&#xD;
             or hypertension manifested by systolic blood pressure &gt;170 or &lt;90 mm Hg or diastolic&#xD;
             blood pressure &gt;100 or &lt;50 mm Hg (if stress is suspected, participants will be&#xD;
             retested under basal conditions).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any supraventricular arrhythmia with an uncontrolled ventricular&#xD;
             response (mean heart rate &gt;100 bpm) at rest despite medical or device therapy, or any&#xD;
             history of spontaneous or induced sustained ventricular tachycardia (heart rate &gt;100&#xD;
             bpm for &gt;30 sec) despite medical or device therapy, or the presence of an automatic&#xD;
             internal cardioverter defibrillator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of sudden cardiac arrest despite medical or device therapy, or any evidence&#xD;
             of congestive heart failure within 6 months prior to the first visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hamilton Depression Rating Scale (HAM-D) score greater than or equal to 15.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of drug, alcohol, or substance abuse within the past 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of an untreated Axis I psychiatric disorder, including schizophrenia,&#xD;
             manic-depressive disorder, delusional disorder, or psychotic disorders not classified&#xD;
             elsewhere.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are not currently involved in a heterosexual relationship in which they&#xD;
             are willing to engage in at least two sexual encounters per week.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with a history of sexual trauma (defined as serious distress caused by&#xD;
             unwanted or coercive sexual activity), including sexual abuse, molestation, rape, and&#xD;
             sexual phobias.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who report experiencing clinically significant sexual difficulties, including&#xD;
             hypoactive sexual desire disorder, sexual arousal disorder, or inhibited orgasm prior&#xD;
             to antidepressant treatment, or who report an onset of sexual dysfunction less than&#xD;
             one week or more than 3 months after beginning antidepressant treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with Vaginismus, Sexual Aversion Disorder, or Dyspareunia (unless the&#xD;
             Dyspareunia is secondary to Female Sexual Arousal Disorder and is reversed with the&#xD;
             use of a sexual lubricant).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are currently receiving psychological intervention that specifically&#xD;
             focuses on sexuality issues.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who pose a current, serious suicidal or homicidal risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition, which in the opinion of the investigator, would put the&#xD;
             participant at risk and warrant precluding from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving any of the following medications will be precluded from the study.&#xD;
             If any of the medications listed below become necessary during the course of the&#xD;
             study, the participant will be discontinued from the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Anticoagulant medications (e.g., warfarin, heparin).&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Chronic, daily use of dehydroepiandrosterone (DHEA), testosterone and other&#xD;
                  androgens, estrogen (in hormone replacement therapy), tamoxifen, raloxifene, and&#xD;
                  other SERMs.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Nitrates.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Any current use of GBE.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Chemotherapy agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Antipsychotic, antianxiety, or sedative/hypnotic agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Antidepressants other than fluoxetine, sertraline, or paroxetine.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Agents that may affect the sexual response including cyprotrone acetate,&#xD;
                  antihistamines, decongestants containing pseudoephedrine or ephedrine, beta&#xD;
                  adrenergic blocking agents (beta blockers), clonidine, or sildenafil (Viagra).&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Any approved or experimental medications or treatments used to enhance the sexual&#xD;
                  response.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Cindy Meston, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Texas at Austin</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas, Austin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78757</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mestonlab.com</url>
    <description>Click here to learn more about the Female Sexual Psychophysiology Laboratory at the University of Texas at Austin.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>July 2006</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 19, 2002</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 19, 2002</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 22, 2002</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 17, 2006</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 17, 2006</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">August 18, 2006</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Female Sexual Arousal Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Female Orgasmic Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>ginkgo biloba</keyword>
  <keyword>human therapy evaluation</keyword>
  <keyword>sex behavior</keyword>
  <keyword>antidepressant</keyword>
  <keyword>blood flow</keyword>
  <keyword>clinical trial</keyword>
  <keyword>drug adverse effect</keyword>
  <keyword>mental disorder chemotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>relaxation</keyword>
  <keyword>smooth muscle</keyword>
  <keyword>alternative medicine</keyword>
  <keyword>blood flow measurement</keyword>
  <keyword>female</keyword>
  <keyword>placebo</keyword>
  <keyword>women's health</keyword>
  <keyword>Secondary to either to fluoxetine, sertraline, or paroxetine use.</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sexual Dysfunctions, Psychological</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

