<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00033956</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>U10-01-12-002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00033956</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of M40403 for the Prevention of Dose Limiting Toxicities of High Dose IL-2</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I/II Open Label Dose Escalation and Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Evaluation of M40403, for the Prevention of the Dose Limiting Toxicities of High Dose IV Bolus IL-2 Treatment of Metastatic Melanoma or Renal Cell Carcinoma.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>MetaPhore Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>MetaPhore Pharmaceuticals</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The clinical use of IL-2 is currently limited by development of dose-dependent hypotension&#xD;
      (systolic blood pressure (SBP) &lt; 90 mm Hg). The overall outcome is constant across sites with&#xD;
      20-50% of the patients requiring ICU management because of unresponsive hypotension and&#xD;
      hyporeactivity (loss of response to vasoconstrictors). Because of the dose-limiting side&#xD;
      effects, the duration of IL-2 dosing is frequently curtailed. Thus, hemodynamic toxicities&#xD;
      have limited the usefulness of IL-2 therapy. M40403 has prevented both the hypotension and&#xD;
      hyporeactivity associated with IL-2 treatment in preclinical studies. This trial will study&#xD;
      the safety and efficacy of M40403 in the prevention or reduction of hypotension in patients&#xD;
      receiving IL-2 therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      High-dose interleukin-2 (IL-2) therapy is currently indicated for treatment of metastatic&#xD;
      renal cell carcinoma and metastatic malignant melanoma, and has been associated with a 5-15%&#xD;
      long-term clinical response. In addition, IL-2 therapy is showing promise in treatment of&#xD;
      acute myelogenous leukemia, non-Hodgkin's lymphoma, and breast cancer, and in improving&#xD;
      immunologic function in patients with AIDS. However, the major dose-limiting toxicity of&#xD;
      IL-2, hypotension, severely limits the usefulness of IL-2 therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Because of the unresponsive hypotension and loss of response to exogenously administered&#xD;
      vasopressors, 20-50% of the patients receiving high dose IL-2 therapy require ICU management.&#xD;
      These dose-limiting side effects frequently necessitate curtailing the full period of IL-2&#xD;
      dosing in order to reverse the hypotension and prevent subsequent renal dysfunction. Thus,&#xD;
      hemodynamic toxicities have limited the usefulness of IL-2 therapy. A course of IL-2 therapy&#xD;
      requires long hospitalization and intense patient monitoring during administration. As a&#xD;
      consequence, despite favorable long-term response, few sites offer this treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The availability of an agent that prevents IL-2-induced hypotension without adversely&#xD;
      affecting the therapeutic mechanism of IL-2, would markedly facilitate IL-2 administration&#xD;
      and at a minimum, would maximize the number of patients who could receive the full regimen of&#xD;
      IL-2. The reduction in IL-2 toxicity may also enable higher doses and/or more frequent dosing&#xD;
      of IL-2 to be used, with the potential of higher success of tumor response. Because M40403&#xD;
      may decrease the toxicity of IL-2, co-administration of M40403 may make it possible to&#xD;
      broaden the clinical use of IL-2 to conditions where it is not currently indicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The indication to be studied is for use in the prevention or reduction of hypotension&#xD;
      associated with interleukin-2 (IL-2) therapy in patients with metastatic melanoma and renal&#xD;
      cell carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is divided into a sequential dose escalation phase followed by the expansion of the&#xD;
      selected dose in a double-blind, placebo-controlled, evaluation phase. Patients with&#xD;
      metastatic or inoperable melanoma and renal cell carcinoma will be receiving high dose IL-2&#xD;
      per approved labeling as two 5-day sequences. M40403 will be administered by intravenous&#xD;
      infusion over 30 minutes prior to each intravenous administration of high dose IL-2.&#xD;
      Sequential panels of patients will receive increasing doses of M40403 along with IL-2 until&#xD;
      an active dose is determined and an MTD is reached. Patients will be followed to determine&#xD;
      the effects of M40403 on development of markers of IL-2 dose-limiting toxicity including&#xD;
      hypotension, tachycardia, index of renal perfusion, cumulative dose of pressor required and&#xD;
      cumulative dose of IL-2 administered. Approximately 48 patients will be studied.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Suspended</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2001</start_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment>48</enrollment>
  <condition>IL-2 Induced Hypotension</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>M40403</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has given signed informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has documented histologically confirmed malignant melanoma or renal cell&#xD;
             carcinoma which is metastatic.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is eligible for high dose IV IL-2 therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tumor dimension of at least one lesion is measurable in two dimensions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is at least 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is ambulatory with good performance status (ECOG PS 0,1; Karnofsky 100-70%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If the patient is a woman of child bearing potential, patient is not lactating and ahs&#xD;
             a negative pregnancy test (beta-HCG test obtained within 72 hours of enrollment) and&#xD;
             agrees to use an adequate method of contraception for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has adequate organ function as defined by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  WBC count &gt;3,500 per cubic millimeter; platelet count&gt; 100,000 per cubic&#xD;
                  millimeter;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilirubin within institutional normal range; creatinine less than or equal to 2.0&#xD;
                  mg/dl or creatinine clearance &gt; 50 ml/min;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No evidence of congestive heart failure, symptoms of coronary artery disease,&#xD;
                  serious cardiac arrhythmias or evidence of prior myocardial infarction. A&#xD;
                  pretreatment cardiac stress test must be performed within 42 days of IL-2&#xD;
                  treatment. Patients with documented ischemia on the pretreatment cardiac stress&#xD;
                  test will be excluded from the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adequate pulmonary reserve. Pulmonary function tests (PFTs) must be performed&#xD;
                  within 42 days of IL-2 treatment and an FEV1 &gt; 2.0 liters or 75% of predicted for&#xD;
                  height and age is the minimum acceptable criteria for patient entry. PAtients&#xD;
                  unable to perform PFTs will be excluded from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has recovered from all toxic effects of prior therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a life expectancy, in the opinion of the investigator, of at least 4&#xD;
             months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has an organ allograft.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has brain metastases. A Brain CT or MRI scan should be performed within 42&#xD;
             days of IL-2 treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is know to be HIV antibody positive. HIV testing is not required for&#xD;
             enrollment into this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has evidence of active infection which requires antibiotic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has received systemic corticosteroids in the four weeks prior to the first&#xD;
             dose of study drug, or requires or is anticipated to require corticosteroids for&#xD;
             intercurrent disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has received radiotherapy, chemotherapy, or immunotherapy in the four weeks&#xD;
             prior to the first dose of study drug, or is scheduled to receive concurrent&#xD;
             radiotherapy, chemotherapy, or immunotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has contraindication to treatment with pressor agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient currently receives chronic medication for asthma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a history of another malignancy other than basal cell skin cancer within 5&#xD;
             years prior to the first dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has any significant medical disease other than the malignancy which, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the investigator, may interfere with completion of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has previously received any IL-2 therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has received another investigational medication within 4 weeks prior to M40403&#xD;
             administration or is scheduled to receive an investigational drug other than M40403&#xD;
             during the course of the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Northwestern University Medical School</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60611-2927</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Providence Portland Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97213-3635</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Huntsman Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84112</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2002</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 17, 2002</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 17, 2002</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 18, 2002</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 23, 2005</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 23, 2005</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">June 24, 2005</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Metastatic Melanoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Renal Cell Carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>IL-2</keyword>
  <keyword>Interleukin-2</keyword>
  <keyword>Hypotension</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypotension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

