<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00039845</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>020223</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>02-N-0223</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00039845</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>MRI Language Studies in Young Children</brief_title>
  <official_title>fMRI Languages Studies In Young Children</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will use magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) to investigate language function in&#xD;
      children-that is, how language skills such as naming objects, understanding spoken language&#xD;
      and reading are organized in the brain. The study focuses on children between 4 and 7 years&#xD;
      old. Children 8 to 12 years old and adults will be studied before the younger children to&#xD;
      test study paradigms appropriate for pre-literate children. The results of this study will&#xD;
      help evaluate the usefulness of MRI in identifying language function and location and may&#xD;
      improve the treatment of children with seizures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Right-handed, native English-speaking adults and children between 4 and 12 years of age may&#xD;
      be eligible for this study. Candidates will be screened with a routine neurological&#xD;
      examination. Children will also undergo neuropsychological testing (standard tests of&#xD;
      language, memory, perception and attention) either at the screening visit or at a later time.&#xD;
      Parents will fill out a form to identify children with attention deficit and hyperactivity&#xD;
      disorders. These children will be excluded form the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will undergo MRI scanning of the brain while performing a task designed to&#xD;
      test a language skill, such as identifying a picture or listening to or reading a word. The&#xD;
      MRI detects changes in blood properties in the areas of the brain that perform each task.&#xD;
      Before the MRI, children will be rehearsed for the tests and will have a session in the&#xD;
      scanner to know what to expect and feel more at ease during the actual test. The time in the&#xD;
      MRI machine is usually between 15 and 20 minutes, but will be no more than 40 minutes for&#xD;
      children 8 to 12 years old, and not more than 20 minutes for younger children. Children may&#xD;
      be requested to have up to five MRI sessions to test different brain functions or confirm&#xD;
      findings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ...&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This protocol aims to develop paradigms to identify the neural networks that underlie&#xD;
      language processing in pre/early literate children. These studies are designed to test the&#xD;
      hypothesis that language networks are strongly lateralized and regionally specific in&#xD;
      children younger than eight. The study extends our investigations of paradigm development and&#xD;
      language network organization in adults and older children (8-12) to the 4-7 year age group.&#xD;
      Word reading, object naming, and auditory comprehension paradigms will be adapted for&#xD;
      children 4-7 years old. Paradigm stimuli will be devised from pilot data obtained under&#xD;
      protocol 01-N-181. Paradigms will be piloted in adults and older children (8-12 years) before&#xD;
      young child studies (4-7 years) and will employ the 1.5 and 3T scanners. Paradigms will be&#xD;
      designed to overcome limitations in previous studies: monitoring performance in the scanner,&#xD;
      using 3T and event related designs to improve signal to noise and allow data analysis in&#xD;
      relation to task item response, and improve motion correction, using language neutral control&#xD;
      conditions, and using paradigms appropriate for pre-literate children. Data will be analyzed&#xD;
      on an individual basis with AFNI and group analysis with SPM 99 using random effect analysis&#xD;
      to identify brain regions associated with task performance. These paradigms will be used as&#xD;
      language probes for other protocols designed to study the effect of acute and chronic disease&#xD;
      states (e.g. stroke and epilepsy) on the plasticity of neuronal organization in language&#xD;
      networks. In order to compare two non-invasive language mapping modes, we will perform&#xD;
      magnetoencephalography with auditory category and description decision tasks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 7, 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date>April 20, 2009</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <enrollment>180</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Right handed (Edinburgh Handedness Inventory).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Native English speaker.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adults and older children (8-12 years) will be recruited to pilot paradigms. Younger&#xD;
        children, aged 4-7 years, are the principal subject of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Medical contraindications to MRI procedures (e.g. pacemakers, cochlear devices, surgical&#xD;
        clips, etc).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Technical contraindications to MRI procedures (e.g. no braces (distort image data)).&#xD;
&#xD;
        History of neurologic or psychiatric disease or a learning or attentional disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
        School performance one year below grade level.&#xD;
&#xD;
        CNS active medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Claustrophobia.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inability to comply with the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Volunteers will also be asked if they have a history of dry or irritated eyes and informed&#xD;
        this may increase the risk of eye irritation and discomfort in the 3T scanner.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Barnes PD. Imaging of the central nervous system in pediatrics and adolescence. Pediatr Clin North Am. 1992 Aug;39(4):743-76. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>1635805</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Benson RR, FitzGerald DB, LeSueur LL, Kennedy DN, Kwong KK, Buchbinder BR, Davis TL, Weisskoff RM, Talavage TM, Logan WJ, Cosgrove GR, Belliveau JW, Rosen BR. Language dominance determined by whole brain functional MRI in patients with brain lesions. Neurology. 1999 Mar 10;52(4):798-809.</citation>
    <PMID>10078731</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Binder JR, Rao SM, Hammeke TA, Frost JA, Bandettini PA, Jesmanowicz A, Hyde JS. Lateralized human brain language systems demonstrated by task subtraction functional magnetic resonance imaging. Arch Neurol. 1995 Jun;52(6):593-601.</citation>
    <PMID>7763208</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 20, 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 12, 2002</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 12, 2002</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 13, 2002</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Brain</keyword>
  <keyword>Imaging</keyword>
  <keyword>Pediatrics</keyword>
  <keyword>Mapping</keyword>
  <keyword>Development</keyword>
  <keyword>fMRI</keyword>
  <keyword>Children</keyword>
  <keyword>Language</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteer</keyword>
  <keyword>HV</keyword>
  <keyword>Normal Control</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

