<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00039689</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>020202</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>02-I-0202</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00039689</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Leukapheresis Procedures to Obtain Plasma and Lymphocytes for Research Studies on Primary and Chronic HIV-Infected Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Leukapheresis Procedures to Obtain Plasma and Lymphocytes for Research Studies on Antiretroviral Naive HIV-Infected Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There is evidence that early and aggressive treatment with antiretroviral drugs can prevent&#xD;
      the loss of immune cell function that accompanies HIV infection. This study will use&#xD;
      leukapheresis (drawing blood, separating out the white cells and returning the blood to the&#xD;
      patient) to obtain blood cells from HIV-infected patients in either the acute or chronic&#xD;
      stage of infection who are being treated with early highly active antiretroviral therapy&#xD;
      (HAART). Leukapheresis is necessary to obtain enough cells to delineate the response of B&#xD;
      cells to CD4+ T cell help, the CD8 factors associated with suppression of viral replication&#xD;
      and normalization of immune function, and natural killer function relative to HIV disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study participants will be adult (older than 18 years) HIV primary or acutely affected&#xD;
      patients (those with a history of exposure to HIV but not yet showing chronic symptoms of HIV&#xD;
      disease) and HIV chronically infected patients (those infected with HIV for longer than 12&#xD;
      months or showing other symptoms of HIV disease) who are not receiving HAART at the beginning&#xD;
      of the study. The study seeks to enroll 30 primary and 30 chronic patients. Pregnant women&#xD;
      will not be enrolled in the study; women who become pregnant will be dropped from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Leukapheresis will be performed on each patient before HAART therapy begins and then three&#xD;
      times a year. Each session will take between 1 and 3 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This longitudinal study will enable researchers to examine the function of certain B cells,&#xD;
      natural killer cells, and CD8+ T cells in people who do not have chronic HIV disease and in&#xD;
      those who do have the disease and are treated with HAART.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      HIV infection is known to cause profound and irreversible dysfunction of both innate and&#xD;
      adaptive arms of the immune system. However, there is mounting evidence that early and&#xD;
      aggressive treatment with antiretroviral drugs can prevent loss of immune cell function. In&#xD;
      an attempt to further delineate the effect of early antiretroviral therapy (ART) on&#xD;
      maintenance of immune cell function, we wish to recruit drug-naive HIV-infected patients who&#xD;
      are either in early or chronic stage of infection. The study will require that patients&#xD;
      undergo leukapheresis or research blood draw once before and several times after enrollment.&#xD;
      Leukapheresis will be used in order to obtain sufficient cells to pursue the following&#xD;
      objectives: delineating B cell response to CD4+T cell help, delineating the effect of ART on&#xD;
      persistent HIV reservoirs in CD4+T cells of infected individuals, and delineating CD8+T&#xD;
      cell-mediated suppression of viral replication and normalization of immune function, and&#xD;
      characterizing natural killer (NK) function relative to HIV disease. The required number of&#xD;
      mononuclear cells needed to perform these experiments can be easily and safely obtained using&#xD;
      leukapheresis procedures in the Clinical Center Apheresis Unit. This protocol is specifically&#xD;
      designed to conform to the requirements of the Apheresis Unit for donors to have&#xD;
      leukapheresis procedures, but the protocol, by itself, is not an independent research study.&#xD;
      Alternatively, whole blood draws may be used in cases where patients are unable to undergo&#xD;
      leukapheresis. While this approach will limit extensive functional analyses, informative&#xD;
      phenotypic and limited functional analyses can nonetheless be performed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 12, 2002</start_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To further investigate differences in the immunologic function of various lymphocyte subsets in HIV-infected patients</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study</time_frame>
    <description>To further investigate differences in the immunologic function of various lymphocyte subsets in HIV-infected patients who are treated early in their infection and during the chronic phase of the infection. Studies will also be done to further delineate the various antigen-specific and innate immune responses including characterization of soluble factors associated with early HIV infection.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">750</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HIV chronic infection</arm_group_label>
    <description>For example, an individual infected with HIV-1 for an indeterminate amount of time.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HIV early infection</arm_group_label>
    <description>For example, a negative HIV antibody immunoassay within 6 months of a positive HIV antibody assay and confirmatory test (as defined by current CDC criteria).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Subjects will be recruited from existing cohorts of individuals participating in National&#xD;
        Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID) who meet the Inclusion/Exclusion&#xD;
        Criteria. Additional local and regional recruitment may be done using direct mailing to&#xD;
        infectious disease physicians, internet ad campaigns, social media outlets, print ads, and&#xD;
        from local clinics via the NIAID patient recruitment contract with Matthews Media Group.@@@&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adult (18 years old or older) HIV-1-infected patient&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adequate venous access for apheresis or sufficient research blood collection&#xD;
&#xD;
        Positive HIV antibody immunoassay and a positive confirmatory HIV test (as defined by&#xD;
        current CDC criteria). Tests may be done in our clinic or by an outside provider. For&#xD;
        individuals with suspected early infection; the following additional criteria may be used:&#xD;
        HIV RNA levels of &gt;2,000 copies/ml with a negative result from an HIV antibody immunoassay.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Willingness to be able to make follow up visits at least once in the next 4 months and&#xD;
        prior to the initiation of antiretroviral therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Blood pressure less than 180/100; pulse rate between 50-100 unless a lower pulse reat is&#xD;
        considered normal for the volunteer&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adequate blood counts (hemoglobin greater than or equal to 9.0 g/dL, hematocrit greater&#xD;
        than or equal to 28 percent, platelets greaterhan or equal to 50,000).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Willingness to give informed consent including consent for the storage of blood samples and&#xD;
        genetic testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Antiretroviral naive or no antiretroviral use in the last six months, or previously&#xD;
        enrolled 02-I-0202 subjects on whom there are samples stored in the repository. Subjects&#xD;
        who become HIV- infected&#xD;
&#xD;
        while taking antiretroviral therapy for pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) will be eligible&#xD;
        for enrollment as long as them meet diagnostic criteria for HIV positivity. Subjects who&#xD;
        enroll under another LIR apheresis protocol within the past three months and complete&#xD;
&#xD;
        the apheresis prior to starting antiretroviral therapy will also be&#xD;
&#xD;
        eligible for enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pregnant and/or breastfeeding women.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Be currently acusing alcohol or other drugs that potentially could interfere with patient&#xD;
        compliance or safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Have a condition in the opinion of the investigators would make the patient ineligible for&#xD;
        the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Susan Moir, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kathleen R Gittens</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 435-8003</phone>
    <email>gittenskr@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Susan Moir, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 402-4559</phone>
    <email>sm221a@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2002-I-0202.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dubruille J, Meng B, Lerondeau MT. [Fractures to bonded metal ceramics]. Actual Odontostomatol (Paris). 1971 Mar;25(93):59-79. French.</citation>
    <PMID>4936645</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kanter PM, Schwartz HS. A fluorescence enhancement assay for cellular DNA damage. Mol Pharmacol. 1982 Jul;22(1):145-51.</citation>
    <PMID>6289069</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Holt JH Jr, Barnard AC, Lynn MS. A study of the human heart as a multiple dipole electrical source. II. Diagnosis and quantitation of left ventricular hypertrophy. Circulation. 1969 Nov;40(5):697-710.</citation>
    <PMID>4246957</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 7, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 6, 2002</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 6, 2002</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 7, 2002</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cellular Immunity</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic HIV Infection</keyword>
  <keyword>Antiretroviral Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Primary HIV Infection</keyword>
  <keyword>Humoral Immunity</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV Infection</keyword>
  <keyword>Acute Infection</keyword>
  <keyword>Treatment Naive</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

