<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04065009</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20190729</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04065009</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The IPLA-OVCA Trial, Intra-Peritoneal Local Anaesthetics in Ovarian Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>IPLA-OVCA</acronym>
  <official_title>A Randomized Double Blind, Multicenter Trial to Assess Time-interval Between Cytoreductive Surgery and Adjuvant Chemotherapy After Administration of Local Anesthetic Intraperitoneally/Perioperatively in Advanced Epithelial Ovarian Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Karolinska Institutet</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Skane University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Karolinska Institutet</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Surgery and chemotherapy combined constitute first line treatment in women with advanced&#xD;
      ovarian cancer. The aim of surgery apart from staging is cytoreduction, i.e. surgical&#xD;
      resection of tumour. Radical resection of all tumour visible by the naked eye followed by&#xD;
      adjuvant chemotherapy is associated with best chance of prolonged survival. However, because&#xD;
      of tumour dissemination in the peritoneal cavity, radical surgery is often very extensive&#xD;
      with surgery in all quadrants of the abdomen and multi-organ resection with substantial risk&#xD;
      of postoperative severe complications and subsequent delay in administration of adjuvant&#xD;
      chemotherapy. Longer time-interval between surgery to start of adjuvant chemotherapy has been&#xD;
      associated with decrease in survival.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgery presents opportunities not only for eradicating tumours but, paradoxically, also for&#xD;
      proliferation and invasion of residual cancer cells. It increases the shedding of malignant&#xD;
      cells into the blood and lymphatic circulations, inhibits their apoptosis and potentiates&#xD;
      their invasion capacity. Additionally, the immune system, the inflammatory system and the&#xD;
      neuroendocrine system react to surgery with important changes, which have been proven to&#xD;
      promote progression of cancer. Several anaesthesia-related factors play an important role in&#xD;
      perioperative tumorigenesis such as inhalational anaesthetics, opiate analgesics, local&#xD;
      anaesthetics and regional anaesthesia, all of which may impact short-term morbidity and&#xD;
      long-term mortality. A previous randomized placebo-controlled pilot study suggests that women&#xD;
      who receive local anesthetics intraperitoneally preoperatively have a significantly decreased&#xD;
      time-interval to initiation of adjuvant chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a prospective, randomised, multi-centre study, we plan to further assess if&#xD;
      intraperitoneal local anaesthetics administered perioperatively during 72 h leads to early&#xD;
      start of chemotherapy compared to placebo in patients undergoing cytoreductive surgery for&#xD;
      FIGO stage III-IV ovarian cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Epithelial ovarian cancer (EOC) is the common term for cancer that originate from the surface&#xD;
      of the ovary, lining of the fallopian tube and the peritoneum. There are different&#xD;
      histopathological subtypes with high grade serous adenocarcinomas being the most prevalent&#xD;
      (70%) followed by endometrioid (10%), clear cell (10%), low-grade serous (5%) and mucinous&#xD;
      adenocarcinomas (3%).The pattern of dissemination is foremost through early exfoliation or&#xD;
      seeding of tumour-cells in the peritoneum (carcinomatosis) and the majority of women have&#xD;
      advanced stage disease at presentation, why ovarian cancer is the gynecologic malignancy with&#xD;
      highest mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ovarian cancer affects 295 000 women every year globally and causes 185 000 cancer-related&#xD;
      deaths annually . The highest incidence is seen in Northern Europe and North America and the&#xD;
      lowest in South East Asia and parts of Africa. In the Nordic countries 2300 women are&#xD;
      diagnosed annually and the corresponding number in Sweden is 700. Ovarian cancer constitutes&#xD;
      3% of all female cancers in Sweden and the risk of developing disease before the age of 75 is&#xD;
      1.1%. A decline in incidence is evident since the 1970s most probably due to increase in use&#xD;
      of contraceptive pills but also change in criteria for diagnosis (an adnexal biopsy is&#xD;
      mandatory for diagnosis today). The median age at diagnosis is 63 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Risk-factors include genetic mutations, family history, hormone replacement therapy and&#xD;
      endometriosis. Pregnancy, lactation, contraceptive pills, sterilization, salpingectomy,&#xD;
      hysterectomy and salpingoophorectomy are all factors associated with decreased risk of&#xD;
      developing EOC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Staging of ovarian cancer is surgical and according to the International Federation of&#xD;
      Gynecology and Obstetrics (FIGO), latest revised in 2014 (7). In stage III and IV, advanced&#xD;
      ovarian cancer, extra-pelvic dissemination is evident. Stage of disease is a strong&#xD;
      prognostic factor for survival. The total 5-year relative survival in Sweden is 50% but&#xD;
      ranges from 90% for stage I to 20% for stage IV. However, treatment is also an important&#xD;
      prognostic factor and may increase survival even in advanced stage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgical treatment of advanced EOC is often accompanied by a severe inflammatory and&#xD;
      immuno-compromised perioperative course associated with early morbidity, delayed&#xD;
      rehabilitation and, sometimes, delayed start of chemotherapy. Early start of chemotherapy has&#xD;
      been repeatedly associated with improved survival. For this reason, perioperative factors&#xD;
      such as choice of anaesthesia and analgesia and fluid replacement may be important.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tumorigenesis and the perioperative environment Surgery, perioperative stress and anaesthesia&#xD;
      may all modulate the immuno-surveillance mechanisms and compromise host defences that&#xD;
      normally maintain a balance between immunity &amp; tumorigenesis. There is increasing evidence&#xD;
      that surgery itself may promote the recurrence and metastases of cancer, which depends&#xD;
      largely on the tumour's ability to metastasise, combined with the host immunity and&#xD;
      inflammatory response. Natural killer (NK) cells act as a primary defence against&#xD;
      perioperative cancer metastases. Negative effects of anaesthetics and analgesics on NK-cell&#xD;
      activity may promote pro-inflammatory effects and may also activate cancer cell survival&#xD;
      pathways. Additionally, concentrations of tumour-related anti-angiogenic factors are&#xD;
      decreased while angiogenic factors such as vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) are&#xD;
      increased. Hypoxia inducing factor (HIF-1) is a transcriptional factor that has also been&#xD;
      shown to play an important role for tumour survival. Hypoxia in solid tumours leads to&#xD;
      activation of HIF-1, which in turn increases cancer cell survival . Similarly, hyperoxia may,&#xD;
      paradoxically, lead to activation of HIF-1 and potentially worsen long-term survival.&#xD;
      Inhalational anaesthetics but not propofol have been shown to affect VEGF as well as&#xD;
      transforming growth factor-beta (TGF-β) in patients undergoing breast surgery that may affect&#xD;
      long-term survival. VEGF and TGF-β play a significant role in establishing tumour blood&#xD;
      supply and cell proliferation. Other factors such as surgical stress, blood transfusions,&#xD;
      hypothermia, hyperglycaemia, and postoperative pain may also affect immunity and the tumour&#xD;
      microenvironment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Role of anaesthetics and analgesics in cancer metastases Preventing a major systemic&#xD;
      inflammatory response and preserving immuno-surveillance in the perioperative period are&#xD;
      fundamental in promoting improved postoperative outcome in cancer surgery. The severity of&#xD;
      injury correlates with the magnitude of inflammation. In vitro studies have shown that amide&#xD;
      local anaesthetics have cytotoxic activity, which could prove to be beneficial in preventing&#xD;
      cancer recurrence. These potential cytotoxic effects of LA may effectively reduce&#xD;
      postoperative morbidity and promote early start of chemotherapy. Anaesthetic drugs,&#xD;
      specifically inhalation anaesthetics, impair numerous immune functions, including those of&#xD;
      neutrophils, macrophages, dendritic cells, T-cell, and natural killer (NK) cells.&#xD;
      Upregulation of hypoxia-inducible-factors (HIF) in tumour cells by volatile anaesthetics may&#xD;
      contribute to a tumour's recurrence by stimulating cytoprotective or pro-tumorigenic&#xD;
      behaviour in residual cells. However, propofol may not depress the immune function and does&#xD;
      not upregulate synthesis of HIF. Opioid analgesics inhibit both cellular and humoral immune&#xD;
      function, increase angiogenesis, and promote breast tumour growth in rodents. Opioids&#xD;
      interfere with immune function by depressing NK cell activity . The use of epidural&#xD;
      anaesthesia and analgesia thus prevents the stress response to surgery, reduces the need for&#xD;
      opiates and may prolong survival.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fluid dynamics and early recovery Fluid optimization remains a challenge because of several&#xD;
      factors: preoperative fluid shifts and accumulation of ascitic fluid, low preoperative&#xD;
      albumin from malnutrition, as well as perioperative fluid and blood loss. Both hypo- and&#xD;
      hypervolemia have been shown to have adverse effects and may delay recovery and start of&#xD;
      chemotherapy and a large prospective, randomised study concluded that hypovolemia may even&#xD;
      lead to renal insufficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective of this Phase 3 double blind placebo controlled trial is to investigate&#xD;
      if local anesthetics administered intraperitoneally perioperatively at time of upfront&#xD;
      surgery for advanced ovarian cancer reduces the time-interval between surgery and adjuvant&#xD;
      chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives are to investigate, postoperative morbidity, complications and long term&#xD;
      survival.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial entails a translational part with the following specific aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To examine if surgical peritoneal stress evolves during the course of surgery, as measured&#xD;
      by pro-inflammatory cytokines and biomarkers in the mesothelium, tumour tissues and blood,&#xD;
      coupled to analysis of the circulating tumour DNA II. To test if intraperitoneally&#xD;
      administered anti-inflammatory analgesics may reduce the (mesothelial) inflammation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To use functional ex vivo assays for exploring how the above identified surgical tissue&#xD;
      responses and induced or inhibited pathways affect the aggressive EOC cell functions and&#xD;
      properties including tumour invasion and chemo-resistance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 26, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 26, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 26, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomised, double blind, prospective, multicenter</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Study drugs are blinded and administered perioperatively. Fully blinded for all (participants, assessors etc)</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time-interval from upfront surgery to adjuvant chemotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Number of days to start of adjuvant chemotherapy (0 - 60 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Days from surgery to first infusion of adjuvant chemotherapy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative complications</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed according to the Clavien-Dindo Nomenclature</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 5 years after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Death of any reason</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative quality of recovery</measure>
    <time_frame>Perioperatively</time_frame>
    <description>As measured by validated instruments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative morbidity</measure>
    <time_frame>Perioperatively</time_frame>
    <description>As measured by validated instruments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">220</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Normal saline administered intraperitoneally at defined times during upfront surgery and intermittently postoperatively for 72 hours</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Local anesthetic (ropivacaine) administered intraperitoneally at defined times during upfront surgery and intermittently postoperatively for 72 hours</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ropivacaine</intervention_name>
    <description>Experimental drug will be administered intraperitoneally</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Narop</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Saline Solution</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo will be administered intraperitoneally</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Normal saline</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA I-III&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Scheduled for upfront cytoreductive surgery for presumed stage III or IV epithelial&#xD;
             ovarian cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to epidural anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to any component drugs used during epidural or intraperitoneal anesthesia&#xD;
             (Ropivacaine, Sufentanil)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled renal, liver, heart failure or ischemic heart disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Speech, language or cognitive difficulties&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women in whom cytoreductive surgery is not attempted at time of upfront laparotomy due&#xD;
             to extent of disease&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sahar Salehi, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Karolinska Institute and Karolinska University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sahar Salehi, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>08-51770000</phone>
    <email>sahar.salehi@sll.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Emma Hasselgren, MD</last_name>
    <phone>08-51770000</phone>
    <email>emma.hasselgren@sll.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Karolinska Hospital, Solna</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stockholm</city>
        <zip>17176</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Katja Tobin Klinisk prövningsledare/Clinical Research Manager</last_name>
      <phone>+46 8 517 745 15</phone>
      <email>katja.tobin@sll.se</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Katja Wiklund Clinical Research Manager/Quality coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+46 8 517 725 84</phone>
      <email>katja.wiklund@sll.se</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hayden JM, Oras J, Block L, Thörn SE, Palmqvist C, Salehi S, Nordstrom JL, Gupta A. Intraperitoneal ropivacaine reduces time interval to initiation of chemotherapy after surgery for advanced ovarian cancer: randomised controlled double-blind pilot study. Br J Anaesth. 2020 May;124(5):562-570. doi: 10.1016/j.bja.2020.01.026. Epub 2020 Mar 13.</citation>
    <PMID>32172954</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 19, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 20, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 22, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Karolinska Institutet</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sahar Salehi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Senior Consultant, Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Local Anesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>Time-interval from surgery to adjuvant chemotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>advanced ovarian cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Ovarian Epithelial</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ropivacaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All study data will be retained at site of patient recruitment. Primary investigator and statistician will only have access to coded patient identity</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

