<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04063761</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AMEVAB2019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04063761</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating Active Esophageal Cooling During Cardiac Ablation Procedures</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluating Active Esophageal Cooling During Cardiac Ablation Procedures</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Advanced Cooling Therapy, Inc., d/b/a Attune Medical</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Iowa</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Advanced Cooling Therapy, Inc., d/b/a Attune Medical</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Left atrial catheter ablation including pulmonary vein isolation is a standard therapy in the&#xD;
      management of symptomatic atrial fibrillation; however thermal esophageal injury is a known&#xD;
      potential consequence of this procedure. Delivery of radiofrequency (RF) energy necessary to&#xD;
      perform left atrial ablation has the potential to cause injury to the nearby esophagus&#xD;
      including ulceration, hematoma, spasm, esophageal motility disorders, and, in the most&#xD;
      extreme case, atrial-esophageal fistula (AEF). Esophageal mucosal lesions are the likely&#xD;
      precursor to AEF, and esophageal mucosal lesions have been detected on post-ablation&#xD;
      endoscopy after pulmonary vein isolation with an incidence ranging from 3% to 60%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Active esophageal cooling during RF ablation as a means of esophageal injury prevention has&#xD;
      been investigated through mathematical models, pre-clinical studies, and in clinical trials.&#xD;
      Existing data support the efficacy of this approach, but the practice has not been widely&#xD;
      adopted due to lack of a commercially available device.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim or purpose of this study is to evaluate the impact on procedural efficiency of&#xD;
      ablation procedures performed using esophageal heat transfer to cool the esophagus during&#xD;
      left atrial RF ablation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is a prospective, pilot study using the Attune Medical esophageal heat transfer&#xD;
      device to actively cool the esophagus during RF ablation procedures. This design is&#xD;
      appropriate to gather the data needed regarding overall procedural time, compare this to&#xD;
      historical controls, and estimate a sample size for a larger study powered for statistical&#xD;
      significance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The subjects will undergo preparation and anesthesia procedures following standard practice.&#xD;
      Once the patient is intubated, the esophageal heat transfer device will be placed into the&#xD;
      esophagus according to the Instructions for Use (IFU). The device will remain in place until&#xD;
      the ablation procedure is completed and will be removed before extubation. Posterior left&#xD;
      atrial wall ablation using standard parameters will only be performed when the esophageal&#xD;
      heat transfer device has reached a temperature of 4-6 degrees C for at least 2 minutes. The&#xD;
      device will be set to neutral or warming temperature (37-42 degrees C) during other aspects&#xD;
      of the procedure (such as mapping and anterior wall ablations).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will be followed up in total for 6 weeks (Long Term Follow-up visit) after the&#xD;
      procedure to document any clinical complication related to thermal esophageal injuries if&#xD;
      applicable.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 20, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 20, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Total time of active ablation procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>Study Day 1 for all patients enrolled, during left atrial ablation procedures using radiofrequency energy</time_frame>
    <description>Total time of active ablation procedure measured from trans-septal puncture to achievement of Pulmonary Vein Isolation (PVI)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total procedure time</measure>
    <time_frame>Study Day 1 for all patients enrolled from patient entry to Electrophysiology (EP) lab until post procedure discharge to Post-Anesthesia Care Unit (PACU)</time_frame>
    <description>Total procedure time from patient entry to Electrophysiology (EP) lab until discharge to Post-Anesthesia Care Unit (PACU)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of procedural pauses during left atrial instrumentation</measure>
    <time_frame>Study Day 1 for all patients, during left atrial ablation procedures using radiofrequency energy</time_frame>
    <description>Number of procedural pauses during left atrial instrumentation measured from trans-septal puncture to achievement of Pulmonary Vein Isolation (PVI)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Atrial Fibrillation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Esophageal Cooling</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single arm study: Patients receive the Attune Medical Esophageal Heat Transfer Device</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>esophageal cooling device (Attune Medical, Chicago, IL)</intervention_name>
    <description>Prospective, single center pilot study</description>
    <arm_group_label>Esophageal Cooling</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients (age over 18 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing first left atrial ablation for the treatment of atrial fibrillation (AF)&#xD;
             including pulmonary vein isolation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing catheter-based ablation procedure using radiofrequency energy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be able to understand and critically review the informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must understand and agree to study requirements and sign a written informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are unable to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of prior atrial fibrillation (AF) ablation procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant co-morbidities that preclude standard ablation procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with &lt;40 kg of body mass&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with relevant esophageal pathology (e.g. esophageal cancer)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alexander Mazur, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Iowa</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Iowa</name>
      <address>
        <city>Iowa City</city>
        <state>Iowa</state>
        <zip>52242</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 19, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 20, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 21, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

