<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04066738</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>12193</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04066738</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Scar Location and Acute Haemodynamic Response to MultiPoint Pacing Study in Patients With Ischemic Cardiomyopathy</brief_title>
  <official_title>SCar Location and Acute Haemodynamic Response to MultiPoint Pacing in Patients With Ischemic Cardiomyopathy (SCAR MPP Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute for Health Research, United Kingdom</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cardiac Resynchronization Therapy (CRT) is a proven treatment for heart failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CRT consists of a special pacemaker with two/three leads (insulated wires which take the&#xD;
      electrical impulses from the device to the heart), one in the right ventricle, one in a vein&#xD;
      on the outer surface of the left ventricle (in a vessel called coronary sinus or CS) and&#xD;
      sometimes one in the right atrium (right top chamber of the heart). Tiny electrical impulses&#xD;
      are simultaneously sent to the ventricles to make them beating together again in a more&#xD;
      synchronised pattern. This leads to a coordinated, synchronous pumping action that, in most&#xD;
      patients, translates into improved heart failure symptoms and improved quality and quantity&#xD;
      of life, reducing the chance of being admitted to hospital with worsening heart failure.&#xD;
      Unfortunately up to one third of the patients do not benefit from CRT therapy and to date&#xD;
      there are no useful criteria to predict the response to CRT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In an effort to improve the response rate to CRT, alternative methods have been developed. In&#xD;
      particular, a new technology called MultiPoint Pacing (MPP) (St. Jude Medical, Sylmar, CA)&#xD;
      has recently become available. It allows simultaneous stimulation of 2 different points in&#xD;
      the left ventricle by using a single lead with four electrodes. This strategy should improve&#xD;
      the pumping function of the heart by recruiting a larger mass of muscle. Although MPP is as&#xD;
      safe and as effective as standard CRT pacing, the improvements to date in the heart pump&#xD;
      function it gives over standard CRT pacing are variable and small.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent evidence suggests that MPP pacing could be particularly beneficial in some subgroups&#xD;
      of patients, in particular patients with a previous history of heart attack resulting in scar&#xD;
      formation in the left ventricle.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that MPP works better when the lead is closer to the scar&#xD;
      because this allows recruitment of areas with slow conduction, thus increasing&#xD;
      synchronization further.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To this aim, they plan to compare, in each patient, the acute response produced by MPP on the&#xD;
      cardiac function when the CS lead is placed close to myocardial scar and when it is placed&#xD;
      far from scar respectively.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A prospective single-centre pilot study will be conducted to investigate this topic. Fifteen&#xD;
      patients, with a history of previous ST Elevation Myocardial Infarction (STEMI) resulting in&#xD;
      myocardial scar and elected to CRT implant at the OUH, will be enrolled in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Compared to standard practice, additional research investigations will be a baseline visit&#xD;
      for eligibility assessment, informed consent and pre-CRT implant cardiac MRI, a&#xD;
      three-dimensional electroanatomical map reconstruction of the CS venous system during the&#xD;
      standard CRT implant and the evaluation of the acute haemodynamic response (AHR, percentage&#xD;
      increase of LV-dP/dT max) of MPP over conventional single-site LV pacing during the CRT&#xD;
      implant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The cardiac Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) will be performed in each patient 1-2 weeks&#xD;
      before the CRT implant during the baseline visit. It will provide information regarding&#xD;
      presence and location of myocardial scar and anatomy of the CS venous system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A de-novo CRT implant will be performed under fluoroscopic guidance as per standard care. All&#xD;
      subjects will be implanted with a regulatory approved St. Jude Medical CRT device compatible&#xD;
      with MPP feature (models n° CD3271-40(Q), CD3371-40(Q), CD3371-40C(QC) or newer) and St. Jude&#xD;
      Medical quadripolar left ventricular lead (Quartet 1458Q or newer). The choice of the right&#xD;
      ventricular and right atrial leads will be left to the operator. After implant of the right&#xD;
      ventricular and right atrial leads, a CS venogram will be then performed as per standard&#xD;
      practice (see intervention section for more details).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A three-dimensional electroanatomical map of the CS venous system will be constructed with&#xD;
      Precision mapping system and a Biotronik Vision wire (Biotronik Se &amp; Co. KG, Berlin, Germany)&#xD;
      by using the CS venogram as a guide. The map will be merged with the correspondent cardiac&#xD;
      MRI images in order to locate the myocardial scar in respect to the CS branches. This will&#xD;
      allow the identification of two target CS branches for the study measurements, one located in&#xD;
      the peri-infarct region and one located in the remote myocardium.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Certus PressureWire will be then introduced into the LV. A PhysioMon software (Radi Medical&#xD;
      Systems, Uppsala, Sweden) will be used for electronic calculation of the LV-dP/dTmax from&#xD;
      every heartbeat for a period of at least thirty seconds to ensure steady-state conditions.&#xD;
      The baseline LV-dP/dTmax will be measured during ventricular spontaneous rhythm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A St. Jude Medical quadripolar left ventricular lead will be sequentially placed in the&#xD;
      &quot;peri-infarct&quot; CS branch and in the &quot;remote myocardium&quot; CS branch. In each site the&#xD;
      percentage increase in LV-dP/dTmax (Acute Haemodynamic Response, AHR) produced by both&#xD;
      conventional single-site and MPP LV pacing to will be measured. All 4 poles of the&#xD;
      quadripolar lead will be used in turn for conventional single-site LV pacing, 3 different&#xD;
      configurations will be used in turn for MPP. The LV-dP/dTmax will be recorded for each pacing&#xD;
      configuration in order to identify the MPP and the single-site LV pacing configurations&#xD;
      producing the best AHR (best percentage increase of LV-dP/dTmax).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The AHR produced by the best MPP configuration in peri-infarct region will be compared with&#xD;
      the AHR produced by the best MPP configuration in the remote myocardium. Moreover, the&#xD;
      percentage increase of LV-dP/dTmax produced by the best MPP configuration over the best&#xD;
      conventional single-site LV pacing in the peri-infarct region will be compared with the same&#xD;
      measurement obtained in the remote myocardium.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The decision about the final position of the LV lead and the activation of MPP feature after&#xD;
      the CRT implant will be left to operator preference.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Unable to recruit&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 27, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 30, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 23, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of acute haemodynamic response produced by MPP in peri-infarct region and in remote myocardium respectively</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage change of LV-dP/dTmax produced by MPP over spontaneous ventricular activation in the peri-infarct region and in the remote myocardium</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison between MPP and standard pacing in terms of acute haemodynamic response</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage change of LV dP/dT max produced by MPP over conventional single-site LV pacing, both in the peri-infarct region and in the remote myocardium</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">2</enrollment>
  <condition>Heart Failure</condition>
  <condition>Ischemic Cardiomyopathy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with myocardial scar</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient with previous STEMI resulting in myocardial scar, elected to CRT implant</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cardiac MRI with gadolinium contrast</intervention_name>
    <description>Imaging of left ventricular scar and coronary sinus venous system</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with myocardial scar</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>3D reconstruction and location of coronary sinus venous system relative to myocardial scar</intervention_name>
    <description>Three dimensional mapping of coronary sinus venous system with Abbott Precision mapping system and Biotronik Vision wire Merge with MRI images of CS and myocardial scar</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with myocardial scar</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acute haemodynamic measurements during CRT implant</intervention_name>
    <description>Advancement of pressure wire to LV cavity via femoral/radial arterial access. Real time measurement of LV-dP/dTmax during conventional CRT and MPP after consecutive placement of LV lead in two different CS branches (peri-infarct region and remote myocardium)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with myocardial scar</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age of 18 years or over&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous STEMI (&gt; 3 months before enrolment) and consequent LV scar;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Standard indication to CRT-D (NYHA functional class III-IV despite optimal medical&#xD;
             therapy, LV ejection fraction (LVEF) ≤35 %, QRS duration ≥120 msec, LBBB);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sinus rhythm;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Will and ability to give informed consent for participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, trying for a baby or breast feeding;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other significant disease or disorder which, in the opinion of the investigator,&#xD;
             may either put the participants at risk because of participation in the study, or may&#xD;
             influence the result of the study, or the participant's ability to participate in the&#xD;
             study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to tolerate MRI scanning (e.g. claustrophobia, unable to lie flat)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindications to MRI scanning (e.g. implantable devices, cranial aneurysm clips,&#xD;
             metallic ocular foreign bodies, hypersensitivity to gadolinium);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significantly impaired renal function (eGFR &lt; 30ml/min);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergy to cardiac MRI contrast media;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe claustrophobia.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>John Radcliffe Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <zip>OX3 9DU</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 17, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 22, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 26, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Trust</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Tim Betts MD MBChB FRCP</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principle Investigator, Consultant Cardiologist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>MultiPoint Pacing</keyword>
  <keyword>Acute Haemodynamic Response</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cardiomyopathies</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <pending_results>
    <submitted>September 12, 2021</submitted>
    <returned>October 7, 2021</returned>
  </pending_results>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

