<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04069052</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DMED-2274-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04069052</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Inhaled Nitric Oxide on Deadspace in COPD</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Inhaled Nitric Oxide (iNO) on Physiologic Dead Space in Patients With Mild Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Queen's University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Queen's University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) is a progressive disease of the respiratory&#xD;
      system that generally develops as a result of smoking. Most people with COPD are classified&#xD;
      as having &quot;mild&quot; disease severity and may not have significantly impaired lung function (e.g.&#xD;
      flow) as measured by traditional lung function tests. However, multiple studies have shown&#xD;
      that patients with mild disease already have significant damage to the small airways and&#xD;
      blood vessels of the pulmonary system. This results in a considerable portion of the lung&#xD;
      that does not participate in gas exchange, a phenomenon called physiologic dead space. Mild&#xD;
      COPD patients develop symptoms of intolerable breathlessness early in exercise compared with&#xD;
      healthy individuals. Previous studies have shown that pulmonary vasodilators, which locally&#xD;
      increase blood vessel radius, may improve gas exchange and reduce symptoms of breathlessness&#xD;
      in patients with mild COPD. Therefore, the objective of this study is to determine the effect&#xD;
      of reducing dead space with a pulmonary vasodilator on the intensity of breathlessness during&#xD;
      exercise in patients with mild COPD. This five visit, double-blinded, placebo-controlled&#xD;
      crossover study will test the impact of inhaled nitric oxide, a direct vasodilator, during&#xD;
      cardiopulmonary exercise on dead space and breathlessness intensity. Use of an esophageal&#xD;
      catheter during testing will additionally permit measurement of neural drive to breathe and&#xD;
      pulmonary mechanics throughout the protocol. Though patients with mild COPD represent the&#xD;
      majority of the COPD population, their symptoms remain poorly managed by current, inefficient&#xD;
      standard of care. The proposed study will examine dead space reduction as a novel therapeutic&#xD;
      target for improving breathlessness and exercise tolerance in patients with mild COPD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will recruit 20 current or ex-smokers who meet the criteria for mild chronic&#xD;
      obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), measured by lung function tests. Participation is&#xD;
      voluntary and participants may withdraw from the study at any time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      General Medical Examination: All participants will undergo a physical examination conducted&#xD;
      by a physician. Concomitant medications will be recorded as well as body height and weight;&#xD;
      blood pressure; heart rate rhythm using a 12-lead electrocardiogram (ECG); and blood oxygen&#xD;
      saturation. The physician will identify any contraindications to exercise testing that would&#xD;
      prevent safe participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pulmonary Function Tests: Standard lung function tests include: spirometry (measuring&#xD;
      respiratory flow during a maximal breath outward); body plethysmography (measuring lung&#xD;
      volumes); diffusing capacity for carbon monoxide (DLCO; measuring gas exchange across the&#xD;
      lung); maximal inspiratory pressure (MIP) and maximal expiratory pressure (MEP) maneuvers&#xD;
      (evaluating respiratory muscle strength); and impulse oscillometry (IOS; measuring lung&#xD;
      mechanics). Each test will be performed at least 2-3 times to ensure the results are&#xD;
      consistent. For all tests, the participant will breathe through a rubber mouthpiece with nose&#xD;
      clips on to occlude the nasal passage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiopulmonary Exercise Tests: The participants will perform exercise on a stationary&#xD;
      bicycle at each visit. While exercising, they will breathe through a mouthpiece with nose&#xD;
      clips on, which allows for the breath-by-breath recording of physiologic variables throughout&#xD;
      exercise. For each test, the participant will begin by sitting on the bike at rest (no&#xD;
      pedaling) for approximately 6 minutes to establish a consistent measure of their baseline&#xD;
      breathing. They will then begin pedaling for 1 minute against no resistance to warm-up. The&#xD;
      load will then increase either by 10 Watts every minute (Visit 1) or to a constant work rate&#xD;
      that will be maintained for 4 minutes (Visits 2-5). Every 2 minutes, the participant will be&#xD;
      asked to take a full breath all the way in (an inspiratory capacity (IC) maneuver). The&#xD;
      participant will also be asked to rate their breathing discomfort, their leg discomfort, how&#xD;
      unpleasant their breathing feels, and how difficult it is to breathe in and out, using a&#xD;
      10-point Borg Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Diaphragm EMG and Respiratory Pressure Measurements: Before exercise, a topical anaesthetic&#xD;
      spray will be applied to the nasal passages and throat and a thin catheter (diameter 2 mm)&#xD;
      will be inserted by experienced personnel through the nose down the throat and into the&#xD;
      esophagus (&quot;food tube&quot;) and top part of stomach. This catheter measures the electric activity&#xD;
      (EMG) of the diaphragm, which provides useful information about the inspiratory drive to&#xD;
      breathe. It also measures pressures in the esophagus within the chest as well as in the&#xD;
      stomach, which gives useful information about the work of breathing and breathing mechanics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood Sampling: Small samples of blood will be taken from the earlobe before exercise, at&#xD;
      2-minute intervals during exercise, and after exercise. The participant's earlobe will be&#xD;
      warmed using a warm, damp cloth (ensuring adequate blood flow to the skin surface) throughout&#xD;
      the baseline rest period and exercise. A very small puncture will be made using a lancet&#xD;
      (similar to a very fine needle-tip), and blood will be collected in small glass tubes &lt; 1mm&#xD;
      in size. These samples will be analysed for their blood gas content (oxygen and carbon&#xD;
      dioxide), variables needed to calculate dead space (the proportion of the lung unable to&#xD;
      adequately participate in gas exchange).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: This will be a single-centre, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled&#xD;
      crossover study evaluating the effects of inhaled nitric oxide on the intensity of&#xD;
      breathlessness and the physiological responses to a standardized exercise task. After giving&#xD;
      written informed consent, participants will complete 5 visits, each conducted in the morning&#xD;
      2-7 days apart.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 1 (Screening): The participants will have a detailed medical history taken and physical&#xD;
      examination conducted by a study physician. The participants will also have their symptoms of&#xD;
      COPD evaluated by standard written questionnaires [modified Medical Research Council (mMRC)&#xD;
      dyspnea scale, Baseline Dyspnea Index (BDI), and COPD Assessment Test (CAT)]. These&#xD;
      questionnaires will be explained to the participant by the study personnel and will be used&#xD;
      to determine if the participants meet the criteria of having moderate-to-severe&#xD;
      activity-related breathlessness. The participants will then undergo a series of pulmonary&#xD;
      (lung) function tests at rest to determine lung function. Participants will complete a&#xD;
      symptom-limited, incremental workload, cardiopulmonary exercise test on a stationary bicycle&#xD;
      to determine their maximal work rate (Wmax). The participant will exercise on the bike for as&#xD;
      long as they can, with the resistance increasing by 10 Watts every 1 min (see description&#xD;
      above). Cardiac status will be monitored by 12-lead ECG. Heart rate, oxygen saturation&#xD;
      (SpO2), and blood pressure will be monitored throughout exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visits 2 &amp; 3 (Run-In): The participants will be familiarized with the 4-min standardized&#xD;
      cycle exercise test and breathing apparatus that will be completed for the remaining visits.&#xD;
      This cycle exercise test will be performed at a constant load. The initial resistance&#xD;
      selected will be 75% of their maximum workload (Wmax; determined from exercise test in Visit&#xD;
      1) with adjustments to the load made as needed. The goal of the resulting 4-min exercise test&#xD;
      is to have a standardized protocol that allows the participants to become sufficiently&#xD;
      breathless to assess the potential therapeutic effect of nitric oxide while not being so&#xD;
      intense as to prevent them from completing the test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visits 4 and 5 (Treatment): The participants will complete the 4-min cycle exercise test at&#xD;
      the work rate established in Visits 2 and 3 while breathing from a gas mixture consisting of&#xD;
      either 1) inhaled nitric oxide (800 ppm) or 2) placebo (room air), each on a background of&#xD;
      room air (21% oxygen; remainder nitrogen). Tests at Visits 4 and 5 will include detailed&#xD;
      measurements of diaphragm electric activity (EMG) and respiratory mechanical measurements.&#xD;
      Blood samples will be collected as described above: before exercise, at 2-minute intervals&#xD;
      throughout exercise, and at the end of exercise.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Single-centre, double-blinded, crossover study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dyspnea Intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>At 4 minutes from start of exercise</time_frame>
    <description>Primary objective is to measure perceptual (e.g. intensity of dyspnea and leg discomfort) responses at isotime (maximum exercise time achieved by all participants) during a standardized cardiopulmonary exercise testing (cycle ergometer).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Inspiratory neural drive</measure>
    <time_frame>At 4 minutes from start of exercise</time_frame>
    <description>Primary objective is to measure inspiratory neural drive (IND) by diaphragm activation (EMGdi/EMGdi max) at isotime (maximum exercise time achieved by all participants) during cardiopulmonary exercise testing (cycle ergometer).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lung volumes</measure>
    <time_frame>At 4 minutes from start of exercise</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary objective is to measure lung volumes at isotime (maximum exercise time achieved by all participants) during cardiopulmonary exercise testing (cycle ergometer).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Trans-diaphragmatic Pressure (Pdi)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 4 minutes from start of exercise</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary objective is to measure trans-diaphragmatic pressure (Pdi) at isotime (maximum exercise time achieved by all participants) during cardiopulmonary exercise testing (cycle ergometer).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gastric Pressure (Pga)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 4 minutes from start of exercise</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary objective is to measure gastric pressure (Pga) at isotime (maximum exercise time achieved by all participants) during cardiopulmonary exercise testing (cycle ergometer).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Esophageal Pressure (Pes)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 4 minutes from start of exercise</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary objective is to measure esophageal pressure (Pes) at isotime (maximum exercise time achieved by all participants) during cardiopulmonary exercise testing (cycle ergometer).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Metabolic and gas exchange</measure>
    <time_frame>At 4 minutes from start of exercise</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary objective is to measure metabolic and gas exchage (earlobe blood samples analyzed for blood gas content) at isotime (maximum exercise time achieved by all participants) during cardiopulmonary exercise testing (cycle ergometer).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Inhaled Nitric Oxide</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Inhaled nitric oxide administered throughout 4 min exercise protocol at 800 ppm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Inhaled room air administered throughout 4 min exercise protocol at FiO2 = 0.21.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nitric Oxide</intervention_name>
    <description>Gaseous pulmonary vasodilator, SoKinox (nitric oxide) flowed into a mask and breathed in.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Inhaled Nitric Oxide</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SoKinox</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Room air (placebo) flowed into a mask and breathed in.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Room air</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. clinically stable as defined by stable hemodynamic status, optimized medical&#xD;
             treatment, no changes in medication dosage or frequency of administration with no&#xD;
             hospital admission in the preceeding 6 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. current or ex-smokers (&gt;=20 pack-years)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. male or female &gt;45 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. mild COPD as defined by Medical Research Council dyspnea scale &gt;=3 and&#xD;
             post-bronchodilator FEV1 &gt;=80% predicted and FEV1/FVC &lt;0.7 and &lt;LLN&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. ability to perform all study procedures and provide/sign informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. women of childbearing age who are pregnant or trying to become pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. active cardiopulmonary disease or other comorbidities that could contribute to dyspnea&#xD;
             and exercise limitation&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. important contraindications to clinical exercise testing, including inability to&#xD;
             exercise because of neuromuscular or musculoskeletal disease(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. use of daytime oxygen, or exercise-induced O2 desaturation to &lt;80% on room air&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. body mass index (BMI) &lt;18.5 or =&gt;35.0 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. echocardiographic evidence of pulmonary hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. prior history of pulmonary thromboembolism or systemic vasculopathy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Denis E O'Donnell, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Queen's University, Respiratory Investigation Unit</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Matthew D James, BScH</last_name>
    <phone>6135496666</phone>
    <phone_ext>4910</phone_ext>
    <email>RIU@queensu.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sandra G Vincent, BScH</last_name>
    <phone>6135496666</phone>
    <phone_ext>4890</phone_ext>
    <email>RIU@queensu.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Respiratory Investigation Unit, Kingston General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kingston</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>K7L 2V7</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Matthew D James, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>6135496666</phone>
      <phone_ext>4910</phone_ext>
      <email>RIU@queensu.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Sandra G Vincent, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>6135496666</phone>
      <phone_ext>4890</phone_ext>
      <email>RIU@queensu.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 11, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 23, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 28, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Queen's University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Denis O'Donnell</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Dyspnea</keyword>
  <keyword>Exertional Dyspnea</keyword>
  <keyword>Dead Space</keyword>
  <keyword>Exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>Inspiratory Neural Drive</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nitric Oxide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

