<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00059579</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>030149</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>03-M-0149</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00059579</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Brain Regulation of Emotions in People With Depression and Anhedonia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Functional MRI Study of Brain Mechanism Mediating Anhedonia in Major Depression</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will use magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) to examine how the brain regulates&#xD;
      emotions in healthy people and in patients who have major depression and anhedonia (loss of&#xD;
      feeling of pleasure in things that normally give pleasure).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy normal volunteers and patients between 18 and 50 years of age with major depression,&#xD;
      with or without significant anhedonia, are eligible for this study. Candidates will be&#xD;
      screened with a psychiatric interview, a physical examination that will include blood and&#xD;
      urine samples, and an electrocardiogram, and a questionnaire about their emotions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will perform a monetary reward task while lying in an MRI scanner. The task is&#xD;
      similar to playing a computer video game with the possibility of winning cash. The amount of&#xD;
      cash is largely dependent on the subject's performance. The accumulated amount of cash earned&#xD;
      in a session will fluctuate depending on the subject's continuing performance level. That is,&#xD;
      during a single session, a subject could lose money earned early in the session if his or her&#xD;
      performance later in the session is not as good as earlier.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MRI pictures will be taken during performance of the task. MRI uses a magnetic field and&#xD;
      radio waves to produce images of body tissues and organs. The patient lies on a table that is&#xD;
      moved into the scanner (a narrow cylinder) and wears earplugs to muffle loud knocking and&#xD;
      thumping sounds that occur during the scanning process. The procedure will last about 1 to&#xD;
      1-1/2 hours.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Anhedonia has been one of the two key diagnostic criteria for major depressive disorder (MDD)&#xD;
      since the publication of The Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, Third&#xD;
      Edition, yet little is known about its neural substrates. Neuroimaging studies have&#xD;
      identified numerous brain regions that are thought to be involved with MDD. Most studies&#xD;
      dealt with MDD as a syndromal entity, and not surprisingly, yielded quite variable results&#xD;
      with respect to the areas of the brain identified, the nature of the functional changes&#xD;
      (i.e., decrease or increase in activities), lateralization, and correlation with clinical&#xD;
      symptoms. Clinical heterogeneity and lack of symptom-specific targets are presumably among&#xD;
      the factors contributing to the variability. The hypothesis that a functionally impaired&#xD;
      mesolimbic dopaminergic pathway may comprise a part of neural substrate underlying core MDD&#xD;
      symptoms of anhedonia and loss of motivation has been proposed. Nevertheless, the roles of&#xD;
      brain reward mechanisms in mediating anhedonia in MDD remain unclear. Availability of&#xD;
      appropriate experimental paradigms that can be used empirically to measure anhedonia is a&#xD;
      prerequisite to test such a hypothesis. Recent studies using monetary incentive paradigms&#xD;
      coupled with neuroimaging techniques have identified hemodynamic responses in structures that&#xD;
      serve as part of the mesolimbic dopaminergic pathway during processing rewards in healthy&#xD;
      humans.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We hypothesize that anhedonia in MDD is associated with impairment of brain reward mechanisms&#xD;
      such that dysfunction of the orbital and ventromedial frontal cortices involved in the&#xD;
      impaired hedonic attribution capacity, while dysfunction of the ventral striatum area that&#xD;
      contains the nucleus accumbens is involved with the reduced or lack of reactivity to&#xD;
      rewarding environmental stimuli in patients with MDD. Our hypothesis is to link specific&#xD;
      neural substrates to the two psychiatric components of anhedonia, i.e., loss of interest and&#xD;
      lack of reactivity, as defined in the diagnostic criteria for MDD. We plan to operationally&#xD;
      test our hypothesis by using empirical measurement of reward responses in MDD patients with&#xD;
      and without significant anhedonia using a conditioning task assessing appetitive and aversive&#xD;
      learning without any performance aspects and spatial delayed response task assessing the&#xD;
      relationship between reward, performance and mood with the event-related functional magnetic&#xD;
      resonance imaging method. We expect to find reduced activation of the ventral striatum,&#xD;
      orbital and ventromedial frontal cortices in response to monetary incentive stimuli in MDD&#xD;
      patients with significant anhedonia relative to MDD patients without anhedonia and healthy&#xD;
      control.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to assess the role of dopamine in anhedonia and in reward processing, we propose to&#xD;
      assess the effect of dietary tyrosine plus phenylalanine depletion on the neural and&#xD;
      behavioral responses associated with the performing of the monetary reward tasks investigated&#xD;
      herein in an additional sample of subjects. Dietary depletion of tyrosine and phenylalanine,&#xD;
      two DA precursors, is a validated method to induce significant reduction of the brain DA&#xD;
      concentration as shown in two previous [11C]Raclopride PET studies. We hypothesize that&#xD;
      depressed patients will show less activation than controls in brain regions associated with&#xD;
      the mesolimbic DA system, such as striatum, amygdala, anterior cingulate gyrus and&#xD;
      orbitofrontal cortex in response to reward in the placebo condition. We expect tyrosine and&#xD;
      phenylalanine depletion to induce a similar neural impairment to reward in healthy subjects,&#xD;
      including a reduction of the neural activation in the striatum, amygdala, anterior cingulate&#xD;
      gyrus and orbitofrontal cortex in response to reward. The reduction of the neural activation&#xD;
      in those regions will be stronger in healthy controls than in depressed patients. Finally, we&#xD;
      hypothesize that tyrosine depletion will influence negatively the valence ratings of&#xD;
      rewarding stimuli in healthy subjects. In depressed patients, anhedonia scores will correlate&#xD;
      negatively with the valence ratings of rewarding stimuli in the placebo condition already.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The outcome of the proposed work may provide clues for diagnosis, classification, and&#xD;
      treatment of MDD, and may also yield leads for identifying the fundamental neural mechanisms&#xD;
      underlying anhedonia in other disabling psychiatric conditions such as schizophrenia and&#xD;
      addiction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 24, 2003</start_date>
  <completion_date>November 12, 2010</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <enrollment type="Actual">163</enrollment>
  <condition>Major Depressive Disorder</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
        For both patient and control groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Age 18 to 50 of any ethnicity without other significant medical conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
        Not in active use of illicit drugs and heavy consumption of alcohol&#xD;
&#xD;
        No metallic implants or onplants that are ferromagnetic&#xD;
&#xD;
        Competent to sign consent forms to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For patient groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For the group with significant anhedonia, current MDD, as defined by DSM-IV criteria, with&#xD;
        significant anhedonia defined as having PAS and/or SAS scores at or above one standard&#xD;
        deviation of appropriate norm. For the group without significant anhedonia, current MDD, as&#xD;
        defined by DSM-IV criteria, without significant anhedonia defined as having PAS and/or SAS&#xD;
        scores within or below one standard deviation of appropriate norm. The BPD subjects will&#xD;
        meet DSM-IV criteria for bipolar I or II disorder, most recent episode depressed and will&#xD;
        currently be in a major depressive episode. We will use the Young Mania Rating Scale to&#xD;
        assess the severity of the disorder Subjects may be enrolled as either inpatients or&#xD;
        outpatients at their entrance to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For control group:&#xD;
&#xD;
        No prior history of any psychiatric conditions including substance dependence&#xD;
&#xD;
        No family history of MDD, bipolar disorder, or psychosis&#xD;
&#xD;
        PAS and/or SAS scores within or below one standard deviation of appropriate norm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Medical conditions or concomitant medications that are likely to influence cerebral blood&#xD;
        flow or neurological function including cardiovascular, respiratory, endocrine and&#xD;
        neurological diseases;&#xD;
&#xD;
        History of psychosis, current mania and substance dependence;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exposure to psychiatric medications in the past 4 weeks;&#xD;
&#xD;
        History of repeated self-mutilation or homicidal attempts, current active suicidal /&#xD;
        homicidal ideations;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Current or recent (within past six weeks) illicit drug use or heavy alcohol consumption&#xD;
        (more than 2 six-packs of beer or equivalent alcoholic beverages per week);&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pathological gamblers as defined by DSM-IV.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Blanchard JJ, Horan WP, Brown SA. Diagnostic differences in social anhedonia: a longitudinal study of schizophrenia and major depressive disorder. J Abnorm Psychol. 2001 Aug;110(3):363-71.</citation>
    <PMID>11502079</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Boyer P, Tassin JP, Falissart B, Troy S. Sequential improvement of anxiety, depression and anhedonia with sertraline treatment in patients with major depression. J Clin Pharm Ther. 2000 Oct;25(5):363-71.</citation>
    <PMID>11123488</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Barbier EL, Silva AC, Kim SG, Koretsky AP. Perfusion imaging using dynamic arterial spin labeling (DASL). Magn Reson Med. 2001 Jun;45(6):1021-9.</citation>
    <PMID>11378880</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 12, 2010</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 29, 2003</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 28, 2003</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 29, 2003</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Reward</keyword>
  <keyword>Cortex</keyword>
  <keyword>Dopamine</keyword>
  <keyword>Neuroimaging</keyword>
  <keyword>Strirtum</keyword>
  <keyword>Major Depressive Disorder (MDD)</keyword>
  <keyword>Melancholic Features</keyword>
  <keyword>Brain Imaging</keyword>
  <keyword>Functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging (fMRI)</keyword>
  <keyword>Dopaminergic Mechanisms</keyword>
  <keyword>Anhedonia</keyword>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Major Depressive Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>MDD</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteer</keyword>
  <keyword>HV</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anhedonia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

