<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00050245</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>030057</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>03-N-0057</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00050245</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Rituximab to Treat Neuropathy With Anti-MAG Antibodies</brief_title>
  <official_title>Safety, Tolerability, and Efficacy of Rituximab in Patients With Anti-Glycoconjugate Antibody-Mediated Demyelinating Neuropathy: A Double-Blind Placebo-Controlled Randomized Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will test the safety and effectiveness of the drug Rituximab in treating a nerve&#xD;
      disease called MGUS (also known as neuropathy with anti-MAG antibodies). Patients with MGUS&#xD;
      have an abnormal protein called monoclonal IgM immunoglobulin that attacks the myelin sheath&#xD;
      (protective coating) of nerves, causing them to not function properly. The disease affects&#xD;
      the nerves in the legs or arms, and patients have numbness, tingling, muscle weakness, and&#xD;
      unsteady gait. There are no adequate treatments. Immunosuppressive drugs or human&#xD;
      immunoglobulin infusions can produce mild and transient improvement, but the benefits of&#xD;
      these therapies are not significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The abnormal immunoglobulin protein in MGUS is produced by white cells called B lymphocytes.&#xD;
      Rituximab is approved to treat B cell lymphomas. Also, the drug showed promise in a recent&#xD;
      study of patients with demyelinating neuropathy associated with production of antibodies from&#xD;
      B lymphocytes directed against certain nerve proteins. Although the number of patients&#xD;
      treated with Rituximab was small, the drug was well tolerated and caused significant&#xD;
      improvement in several of the patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients 25 years of age and older with MGUS may be eligible for this 2-year study.&#xD;
      Candidates will be screened with a medical history, physical and neurological examinations,&#xD;
      and blood tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be randomly assigned to receive intravenous (through a vein) infusions of&#xD;
      either Rituximab or placebo (a solution that looks like Rituximab but has no active&#xD;
      ingredient) once a week for 4 consecutive weeks. In addition, they will undergo the following&#xD;
      tests and procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Monthly follow-up visits following Rituximab treatment for repeat physical and&#xD;
           neurological examinations, blood tests, muscle strength measurements, and review of&#xD;
           signs and symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Two sessions of lymphapheresis, one at the beginning of the study and one a year&#xD;
           later-to collect lymphocytes. For this procedure, whole blood is drawn through a needle&#xD;
           in an arm vein, much like donating a unit of blood. The blood then flows through a&#xD;
           catheter (plastic tube) into a cell separating machine, where the white blood cells are&#xD;
           extracted and removed. The red cells and plasma are then returned to the body through a&#xD;
           needle in the other arm. The procedure takes about 60 to 90 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Electrophysiologic studies (electromyography and nerve conduction testing) are done once&#xD;
           at the beginning of the study and again one year later. For electromyography, a small&#xD;
           needle is inserted into a few muscles and the patient is asked to relax or to contract&#xD;
           the muscles. The electrical activity of the muscle cells is recorded and analyzed by a&#xD;
           computer. For nerve conduction testing, nerves are stimulated through small wire&#xD;
           electrodes attached to the skin and the response is recorded and analyzed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If this study indicates that Rituximab is beneficial against MGUS, patients who were assigned&#xD;
      to receive placebo during the trial will be offered treatment with Rituximab (four weekly&#xD;
      infusions) at the end of the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will examine the safety, tolerability, and efficacy of the humanized monoclonal&#xD;
      antibody Rituximab to induce a clinical and serological remission in patients with&#xD;
      IgM-anti-glycoconjugate antibody-mediated demyelinating neuropathy. Rituximab is a monoclonal&#xD;
      antibody specific for the common B cell antigen CD20. Its administration depletes pre-B and&#xD;
      mature B lymphocytes without altering neutrophils or hematopoietic stem cells. In humans with&#xD;
      indolent B cell lymphomas, Rituximab can be safely administered, is well tolerated, promotes&#xD;
      selective B cell depletion and lowers the serum IgM levels. Preliminary experience in some&#xD;
      patients with demyelinating polyneuropathy and IgM-anti-glycolipid antibodies has shown that&#xD;
      Rituximab was beneficial in improving the patient's symptoms and reducing the anti IgM&#xD;
      antibody levels. In the present study we will examine in a placebo randomized trial the&#xD;
      efficacy of Rituximab in patients with polyneuropathy related to IgM-anti-glycolipid&#xD;
      antibodies. Twenty-six patients will be randomized to receive placebo or Rituximab given at&#xD;
      four weekly intravenous infusions of 375 mg/M(2). The primary outcome will be based on&#xD;
      changes in the monthly measurements of the neuropathy scores. The fine specificities of the&#xD;
      IgM antibodies to various glycoconjugates or differences in the affinity binding to various&#xD;
      antigens in neural membranes will be explored before and after treatment. It is anticipated&#xD;
      that the study will: a) provide a new, immune-based and target-oriented therapy for patients&#xD;
      with this neuropathy and b) examine the pathogenic role of these antibodies in the cause of&#xD;
      the disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 27, 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date>October 17, 2007</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in neurological performance using the INCAT scales.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment>30</enrollment>
  <condition>Polyneuropathies</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rituximab</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Research subjects will have documented disability of IgM anti-glycoconjugate&#xD;
        antibody-mediated demyelinating neuropathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Neuropathy associated with IgM monoclonal immunoglobulins reactivate to MAG or other&#xD;
        glycoconjugates.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Willingness and legal ability to give and sign informed study consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Willingness to travel to NIH for scheduled protocol studies and treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Men and women of reproductive potential must agree to use an acceptable method of birth&#xD;
        control during treatment and for six months after completion of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adequate bone marrow, renal, and liver function: ANC greater than 1000/mm3, BUN/Cr with&#xD;
        normal range for age, AST or ALT less than 2 x of upper limit of normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Immunosuppressive drug therapy at the time of or 6 months prior to enrollment.&#xD;
        Specifically, candidates may not be taking prednisone, cyclosporine, tacrolimus,&#xD;
        azathioprine, mycophenolate mofetil, anti-lymphocyte agents, cyclophosphamide,&#xD;
        methotrexate, or other agents whose therapeutic effect is immunosuppressive or could&#xD;
        provoke neuropathy as undesirable secondary effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any medical or social condition that precludes follow-up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any active malignancy or any history of a hematogenous malignancy or lymphoma. Patients&#xD;
        with melanoma will be excluded. Patients with primary, cutaneous basal cell or squamous&#xD;
        cell cancers may be enrolled providing the lesions are treated prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Coagulopathy or requirement for anticoagulation therapy that would contraindicate protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Platelet count less than 100,000/mm(3).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Hemoglobin less than 7.0 mg/dl.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any known immunodeficiency syndrome included HIV infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any history of cardiac insufficiency, major vascular disease, or symptomatic coronary&#xD;
        artery disease. Patients with cardiomyopathy grade III or IV by the New York Heart&#xD;
        Classification will be excluded from this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Systemic edema or pulmonary edema.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Chronic hypotension (SBP less than 100 mm Hg).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any condition that would likely increase the risk of protocol participation or confound the&#xD;
        interpretation of the data including active infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pregnancy. Serum pregnancy test will be performed and must be negative in all women of&#xD;
        childbearing potential enrolled in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        History of active psychiatric disorder that may interfere with participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients below the age of 25 because this neuropathy does not occur in such age groups.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dalakas MC, Quarles RH. Autoimmune ataxic neuropathies (sensory ganglionopathies): are glycolipids the responsible autoantigens? Ann Neurol. 1996 Apr;39(4):419-22.</citation>
    <PMID>8619518</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 17, 2007</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 2, 2002</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 2, 2002</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 3, 2002</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Neuropathy</keyword>
  <keyword>B Cells</keyword>
  <keyword>Anti-MAG</keyword>
  <keyword>Demyelination</keyword>
  <keyword>MAG</keyword>
  <keyword>RITUXAN</keyword>
  <keyword>Monoclonal Antibodies</keyword>
  <keyword>Retuximab</keyword>
  <keyword>Demyelinating Neuropathy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Polyneuropathies</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

