<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00056602</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>030133</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>03-AR-0133</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00056602</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinically Important Changes in Rheumatoid Arthritis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinically Important Changes in Rheumatoid Arthritis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases (NIAMS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will explore how patients with rheumatoid arthritis evaluate, or rate, symptom&#xD;
      improvements. Physicians generally evaluate patients health and treatment benefits based on&#xD;
      laboratory measures, such as the number of tender or swollen joints, duration of morning&#xD;
      stiffness, grip strength, pain severity and others. Less attention is given to whether these&#xD;
      treatment results are meaningful to patients. This study will examine how much of an&#xD;
      improvement in pain, stiffness, function, and other symptoms is needed before patients&#xD;
      consider the change an important improvement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients 18 years of age or older who were diagnosed with rheumatoid arthritis after age 16&#xD;
      and who have active arthritis (6 or more tender joints) may be eligible for this study. Of&#xD;
      particular interest are patients beginning treatment with prednisone, methotrexate,&#xD;
      leflunomide, infliximab, or etanercept, although patients receiving any type of treatment may&#xD;
      be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be evaluated twice at the NIH Clinical Center, once at the start of the&#xD;
      study and again at either 1 month or 4 months later, depending on the individual s treatment&#xD;
      regimen. Permission will also be requested to review patients medical records for results of&#xD;
      previous blood tests and x-rays. At each NIH visit, patients will undergo the following tests&#xD;
      and procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Medical history and physical examination, including evaluation of joint swelling and&#xD;
           tenderness;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Questionnaires about rheumatoid arthritis symptoms;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Computer-based exercise to assess preferences for various state-of-health choices;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Grip strength test;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Walking test on level ground, with or without the use of a cane or walker;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood test to measure inflammation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the second visit, in addition to the above procedures, participants will complete a&#xD;
      questionnaire to rate the importance of changes, if any, in pain, morning stiffness, fatigue,&#xD;
      joint swelling, functioning, worry, depression, and overall impressions, since the first&#xD;
      visit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Proper interpretation of the results of clinical trials requires an assessment of not only&#xD;
      the statistical significance of treatment differences but also the clinical importance of&#xD;
      such differences. Efforts to define criteria for important improvement in rheumatoid&#xD;
      arthritis (RA) activity have thus far not considered the patient's perspective. The aim of&#xD;
      this project is to determine if criteria for important improvement in arthritis activity&#xD;
      measures can be defined. This will be done by assessing the agreement among patients of&#xD;
      judgments of important changes in arthritis activity. We will also determine if preference&#xD;
      measures, which are a group of measures of the desirability of a particular state of health,&#xD;
      can be used to assess when patients experience an important change in their arthritis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This prospective longitudinal observational study will measure changes in 12 arthritis&#xD;
      activity measures, changes in preference measures, and judgments of the importance of changes&#xD;
      in arthritis activity over one to four months in 300 patients with active RA. Consensus among&#xD;
      patients regarding the degree of change considered important would allow group criteria for&#xD;
      important improvement to be defined that were based on patients' evaluations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 18, 2003</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 23, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 1, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <enrollment type="Actual">192</enrollment>
  <condition>Rheumatoid Arthritis</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants will be recruited by physician referral and self-referral.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria will be:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. A diagnosis of RA;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age 18 years or older;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Onset of arthritis after the age of 16 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Active arthritis, as evidenced by six or more tender joints&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria will be:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Inability to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Children will necessarily be excluded from this protocol.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael M Ward, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases (NIAMS)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?B_2003-AR-0133.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Paulus HE, Egger MJ, Ward JR, Williams HJ. Analysis of improvement in individual rheumatoid arthritis patients treated with disease-modifying antirheumatic drugs, based on the findings in patients treated with placebo. The Cooperative Systematic Studies of Rheumatic Diseases Group. Arthritis Rheum. 1990 Apr;33(4):477-84.</citation>
    <PMID>2109613</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>van Gestel AM, Prevoo ML, van 't Hof MA, van Rijswijk MH, van de Putte LB, van Riel PL. Development and validation of the European League Against Rheumatism response criteria for rheumatoid arthritis. Comparison with the preliminary American College of Rheumatology and the World Health Organization/International League Against Rheumatism Criteria. Arthritis Rheum. 1996 Jan;39(1):34-40.</citation>
    <PMID>8546736</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ward MM. Response criteria and criteria for clinically important improvement: separate and equal? Arthritis Rheum. 2001 Aug;44(8):1728-9.</citation>
    <PMID>11508421</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 19, 2003</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 18, 2003</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 19, 2003</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 3, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 3, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 6, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Utility</keyword>
  <keyword>Health Status</keyword>
  <keyword>Preferences</keyword>
  <keyword>Response Criteria</keyword>
  <keyword>Treatment</keyword>
  <keyword>Rheumatoid Arthritis</keyword>
  <keyword>RA</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

