<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03877653</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>30-00946</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>Freedom-1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03877653</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Freedom-1 Study for Chronic Knee Pain</brief_title>
  <official_title>Double-Blinded Randomized Control Trial of Knee Pain Utilizing Sub-Threshold Peripheral Nerve Stimulation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Stimwave Technologies</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Texas Institute for Pain and spine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Western Clinical Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Stimwave Technologies</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To demonstrate the potential benefits and risk of active sub-threshold stimulation in the&#xD;
      treatment of chronic knee pain as compared to subjects that did not have active stimulation.&#xD;
      Improvement will be assessed in relation to the clinical outcome measures of pain, with&#xD;
      primary endpoint; Pain relief rate as measured by the number of subjects with greater or&#xD;
      equal to a 50% decrease in pain on the visual analog scale, comparing baseline to the 1-month&#xD;
      follow-up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This will be a multi-center, prospective, sham-controlled, double blinded, randomized&#xD;
      clinical study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of eighty evaluable (80) subjects with unilateral arthritic knee pain will be&#xD;
      recruited into this clinical trial from multiple sites. Enrollment will continue until 80&#xD;
      subjects have evaluable primary endpoints. Some subjects will not pass the 1-week trial&#xD;
      period, and others may be lost to follow-up. The Principal Investigator (PI) will screen all&#xD;
      of the subjects for appropriateness for the procedure. The degree of neuropathic pain will be&#xD;
      assessed using the DN4 standard questionnaire. 29 A diagnostic injection of the IPS under&#xD;
      ultrasound, fluoroscopy or landmark guided in the clinic will be performed, and only those&#xD;
      subjects with significant temporary pain relief (&gt; 75%) for at least 2 hours will be allowed&#xD;
      to continue with the study. All subjects will be brought to the procedure room or operating&#xD;
      room (OR) for the trial implant procedure under local anesthetic. An introducer will be&#xD;
      placed under ultrasound or fluoroscopic guidance at the target nerve and the electrodes&#xD;
      percutaneously advanced towards the IPS. After insertion of the receiver and then&#xD;
      confirmation of stimulation, the trial stimulator will be secured to the skin. The stimulator&#xD;
      tail will be outside the body and attached to the skin. All subjects will undergo an active&#xD;
      7-day provisional test period. Only those subjects reporting &gt; 50% pain relief at the end of&#xD;
      the 7-day provisional test period as compared to baseline will be allowed to continue with&#xD;
      the study. The trial leads will be removed at the end of 7 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All subjects responding to therapy with &gt; 50% pain relief at 7 days will, at a later date, be&#xD;
      brought to the operating room (OR) and given a sedative and local anesthetic. An introducer&#xD;
      will be placed under ultrasound or fluoroscopic guidance onto the target nerve and the&#xD;
      electrode array advanced towards the nerve. The receiver will be mated with the electrode&#xD;
      array, and, after confirmation of stimulation, the permanent stimulator will be tunneled and&#xD;
      secured. The subject will then be randomized to either active sub-threshold (high frequency)&#xD;
      stimulation or no stimulation (sham). All subjects and assessors will be blinded to the group&#xD;
      assignment for up to three months follow-upFollow-up visits will be conducted at 1 week, 1&#xD;
      month, 3 months, and 6 months post-implantation. Follow up phone calls at 12 months, 18&#xD;
      months, and 24 months post-implantation will be performed to confirm durability of pain&#xD;
      relief with a verbal rating scale (VRS; 0-100) and global perceived effects scale (GPES) and&#xD;
      to capture any subject-reported adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Initial and follow-up evaluations will consist of physical exams, visual analog scales (VRS&#xD;
      at 12, 18, 24 months), Western Ontario and McMasters University Arthritis Score (WOMAC),&#xD;
      range of motion (flexion and extension measured by goniometer, work status and medication&#xD;
      intake evaluation. At 1-month post-permanent implant, if there is not &gt;50% relief, the&#xD;
      subject will be unblinded. If sham was confirmed, the stimulator will then be reprogrammed to&#xD;
      receive active treatment, and the trial continued. If the active arm was confirmed, the&#xD;
      stimulator will be reprogrammed, and the trial continued. All subjects will be unblinded at&#xD;
      the 3-month visit regardless of randomization and outcome. If sham was confirmed, the&#xD;
      stimulator will then be reprogrammed to receive active treatment Available stimulation&#xD;
      programs include tonic (on table testing), burst, 1000 Hz 1499 Hz frequency stimulation, all&#xD;
      of which may be utilized via the same subject.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>placebo-controlled double blinded randomized clinical trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>A sponsor representative will open the sealed envelopes and assign groups. Investigators and research staff will be blinded to assignment of high frequency or sham. Randomization assignment will be documented post-implant but will be filed separately in a document locker, which will only be available to a sponsor representative until the time of unblinding.&#xD;
When receiving active stimulation, devices will be programmed to deliver electrical stimulation below perception threshold. Stimulation waveforms delivered above perception threshold have the potential to unblind subjects to their assignments.&#xD;
When receiving sham stimulation, devices will be programmed to not actively deliver electrical stimulation but still deplete battery life to maintain blinding. Subjects will have to recharge batteries similar to receiving active stimulation.&#xD;
Sites will not have access to the programmer. Study devices can only be programmed by Stimwave representatives.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Responder rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>A. Percentage of patients with at least 50% improvement in the knee pain identified at baseline compared to 3 months post full implant of the StimQ PNS System pain identified at baseline compared to 6 months post full implant of the Freedom PNS system with the VAS</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual analog scale (VAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of pain relief experienced in the area of pain identified at baseline compared to 6 months post full implant of the Freedom PNS system as described on a 100 mm line scale (with 0= no pain; 100: worst pain imaginable)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Western Ontario and McMasters University Arthritis Score (WOMAC)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The WOMAC is a patient self-reported disability questionnaire consists of 5 questions measuring pain, 2 measuring joint stiffness, and 17 measuring functional limitation, with all questions scored on a scale of 0 to 4 to assess the consequence of impairment in terms of functional impairment and will be completed at screening/baseline and at all follow up evaluations.compared to baseline. Answers on a scale of 0 (no disability) to 10 (worst disability)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Global Perceived Effect scales (GPES)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Patient satisfaction with the implant will be measured by assessing global perceived effects (GPES) on a 7-point scale (1 = worst and 7 = best) Scale from 1 (no change) to 7 (a great deal better) describing improvement with therapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>McGill Short Form (SF-MPQ-2)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The SF-MPQ-2 is a patient self-reported depression and pain quality questionnaire consisting of 22 questions, with all questions scored on a scale of 0 to 10. Answers on a scale of 0 (none) to 10 (worst possible)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neuropathic pain questionnaire (DN4)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The DN4 is a patient self-reported questionnaire designed to evaluate to degree of neuropathic pain. There are 10 questions on a scale of 0 (No) to 1 (Yes). Scores equal or higher than 4 out of 10 are an indication for the presence of neuropathic pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Work status (if working);</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Work history and status will be evaluated based on a patient's self-reported questionnaire(s) completed at screening/baseline and all follow up visits.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage Increase in Ability to do Knee Bends and Walking Tolerance</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The patients will be evaluated for knee bends and walking tolerance before and after the treatment, using a treadmill for distance. Scale in degrees and (k)meters</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Range of Motion</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The passive and active range of motion will be measures with a goniometer.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Timed Up &amp; Go (TUG)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>This test assesses mobility. The patient sits back in a standard armchair, and identifies a line on the floor 3 meters (10 feet) away. When the examiner says &quot;go&quot;, the patient is timed to see how long it takes to get up out of the chair, walk to the line, turn around, come back to the chair and sit down</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Medication: Change in concomitant pain medication usage</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Measure a change in concomitant pain medication usage.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Treadmill</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Pain-free walking time and distance on the treadmill</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Osteoarthritic Knee Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Interventional</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single arm, active stimulation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>When receiving sham stimulation, devices will be programmed to not actively deliver electrical stimulation but still deplete battery life to maintain blinding. Subjects will have to recharge batteries similar to receiving active stimulation.&#xD;
Sites will not have access to WaveCrest programmer. Study devices can only be programmed by Stimwave representatives.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Wireless neuromodulation</intervention_name>
    <description>A needle and catheter are carefully inserted near the enervated nerve. The stimulator is then placed through the catheter close to the nerve. The proximal end of the stimulator is then sutured underneath the skin to prevent migration.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Interventional</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is over 18 years of age;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with a history of chronic, function-limiting (VAS &gt;5/10) knee pain from&#xD;
             osteoarthritis of at least three months in duration with or without prior surgeries;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has been diagnosed with Kellgren-Lawrence Grade II or III knee osteoarthritis,&#xD;
             confirmed by X-ray studies conducted in the last year;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has been examined and has been deemed to be an appropriate candidate for the&#xD;
             procedure;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are able to give voluntary, written informed consent to participate in&#xD;
             this investigation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who, in the opinion of the Investigator, are able to understand this&#xD;
             investigation, are able to co-operate with the study procedures and are willing to&#xD;
             return to the center for all the required post-operative follow-ups;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented failure of at least two less invasive treatment modalities and medications&#xD;
             including physical therapy, intra-articular steroids and/or oral NSAIDS;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has not had recent surgical procedures of the knee within the last three&#xD;
             months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject noted good (&gt; 75%) but only temporary relief for at least 2 hours from an&#xD;
             infrapatellar saphenous nerve injection with local anesthetic;-&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is deemed to be neuro-psycho-socially appropriate for implantation therapies&#xD;
             based of assessment of a Clinical Psychologist, using face-to-face encounters and&#xD;
             psychological testing measures;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject should be able to provide follow up for a 2-year period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant contralateral knee pain that would influence their level of activity&#xD;
             greater to two on a scale to ten;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hip or foot pain greater than knee pain;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurogenic or vascular claudication;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has been diagnosed with Kellgren-Lawrence Grade IV knee osteoarthritis,&#xD;
             confirmed by X-ray studies conducted in the last year;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled major depression or uncontrolled psychiatric disorders;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled or acute medical illnesses including coagulopathy, renal insufficiency,&#xD;
             chronic liver dysfunction, progressive neurological deficit, infection, unstable&#xD;
             angina, and severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic severe conditions that could interfere with the interpretations of the outcome&#xD;
             assessments for pain and bodily function (eg. Rheumatoid arthritis, severe spinal&#xD;
             stenosis, activity-limiting cardiac disease);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant or planning to become pregnant, lactating;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI) greater than 40 (morbid obesity);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with multiple complaints involving concomitant knee, foot, or ankle pathology&#xD;
             or radiculopathy, that will not be amenable to study due to the overlap of pain&#xD;
             complaints;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has been examined and has been deemed to be inappropriate for the procedure&#xD;
             based on anatomical restrictions;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lymphedema or stasis ulcers or other conditions that would compromise the surgical&#xD;
             site;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to understand informed consent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to comply with all protocol requirements (including attending all follow-up&#xD;
             visits);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of adverse reaction to local anesthetic drugs;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Worker's compensation claimants;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Incarcerated or has an ankle position locator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject noted no relief from a local anesthetic injection of infrapatellar saphenous&#xD;
             nerve;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented allergy to device material components;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected substance abuse within the last 2 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pacemaker or implanted defibrillator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Co-existing pain condition or participation in another clinical study that could&#xD;
             confound the results of this study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Based on the opinion of the investigator any legal concerns that would preclude&#xD;
             his/her enrollment in the study or potentially confound the results;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other implanted active medical devices in the same site.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Niek Vanquathem, BA</last_name>
    <phone>0032 492 69 22 23</phone>
    <email>niekv@stimwavefreedom.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Western Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Placentia</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92870</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jessica Lynch</last_name>
      <phone>714-223-7000</phone>
      <phone_ext>124</phone_ext>
      <email>research@ocpain.net</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Albert Lai, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Institute of Pain and Spine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pearland</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77584</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christie Kent</last_name>
      <phone>832-509-2154</phone>
      <email>CKent@txpainandspine.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jay LaFleur, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 11, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 13, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 18, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>PNS</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic</keyword>
  <keyword>Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Wireless</keyword>
  <keyword>Neuromodulation</keyword>
  <keyword>knee</keyword>
  <keyword>osteoarthritic</keyword>
  <keyword>peripheral nerve stimulation</keyword>
  <keyword>infra patellar saphenous</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

