<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03876457</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>G180275, Pro00056862</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03876457</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SELECT2: A Randomized Controlled Trial to Optimize Patient's Selection for Endovascular Treatment in Acute Ischemic Stroke</brief_title>
  <acronym>SELECT2</acronym>
  <official_title>SELECT2: A Randomized Controlled Trial to Optimize Patient's Selection for Endovascular Treatment in Acute Ischemic Stroke</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospitals Cleveland Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Stryker Neurovascular</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospitals Cleveland Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      SELECT 2 evaluates the efficacy and safety of endovascular thrombectomy compared to medical&#xD;
      management alone in acute ischemic stroke patients due to a large vessel occlusion in the&#xD;
      distal ICA and MCA M1 who have large core on either CT (ASPECTS: 3-5) or advanced perfusion&#xD;
      imaging ([rCBF&lt;30%] on CTP or [ADC&lt;620] on MRI: ≥50cc) or both and are treated within 0-24&#xD;
      hours from last known well.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The second aim is to look at the correlation of imaging profiles with thrombectomy clinical&#xD;
      outcomes and treatment effect. This will be evaluated by comparing the outcomes in patients&#xD;
      with discordant imaging profile and assessing if thrombectomy outcome rates and treatment&#xD;
      effect will differ in patients with discordant imaging profiles (favorable CT/unfavorable&#xD;
      perfusion imaging and unfavorable CT/favorable perfusion imaging).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      SELECT 2 is a prospective, randomized, international, multicenter, assessor-blinded&#xD;
      controlled trial evaluating the efficacy and safety of thrombectomy in patients with large&#xD;
      core on either CT or advanced perfusion imaging treated within 0-24 hours from last known&#xD;
      well. The secondary aim is to look at the correlation of imaging profiles with thrombectomy&#xD;
      clinical outcomes and treatment effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with the final diagnosis of an acute ischemic stroke due to a large vessel occlusion&#xD;
      in the distal ICA and MCA M1 who have large core on either CT (ASPECTS: 3-5) or advanced&#xD;
      perfusion imaging ([rCBF&lt;30%] on CTP or [ADC&lt;620] on MRI: ≥50cc) or both within 0-24 hrs from&#xD;
      last known well will be randomized in a 1:1 ratio into thrombectomy plus medical management&#xD;
      vs medical management alone. Patient outcomes will be measured at baseline, 24 hours post,&#xD;
      discharge, 30 days and 90 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint is the Modified Rankin Scale (mRS) at 90 (+/- 15) days. The primary&#xD;
      outcome is a shift on 90-day mRS. The 2nd primary outcome is favorable clinical outcomes: mRS&#xD;
      score of 0-2. Secondary outcomes are safety outcomes such the incidence of symptomatic&#xD;
      intracranial hemorrhage (sICH per SITS-MOST) and Imaging endpoints such as infarct volume on&#xD;
      MRI diffusion-weighted imaging (DWI) sequence (or CT if MRI not feasible) 24 to 72 hours&#xD;
      after randomization. CT images will be read by iSchemaView automated ASPECTS as well as by a&#xD;
      physician. In cases where there is disagreement, the physician reading will override the&#xD;
      automated software reading. CT/MR perfusion images with mismatch determination will be read&#xD;
      by iSchemaView automated RAPID software. All the images will be adjudicated by a blinded core&#xD;
      lab at the University of Texas-Medical School at Houston.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A maximum of 560 patients will be randomized across the study sites. Covariate adaptive&#xD;
      randomization will be used to balance the distribution of important variables. Interim&#xD;
      analyses will be conducted at 200 and 380 patients, at which time the study may stop for&#xD;
      efficacy or futility.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 11, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Modified Rankin Scale (mRS) score</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>The modified Rankin Scale (mRS) is a commonly used scale for measuring the degree of disability or dependence in the daily activities of people who have suffered a stroke or other causes of neurological disability. The scale runs from 0-6 with &quot;0&quot; being perfect health without symptoms to &quot;6&quot; being death.&#xD;
Score 0: No symptoms Score 1: No significant disability. Able to carry out all usual activities, despite some symptoms.&#xD;
Score 2: Slight disability. Able to look after own affairs without assistance, but unable to carry out all previous activities.&#xD;
Score 3: Moderate disability. Requires some help, but able to walk unassisted. Score 4: Moderately severe disability. Unable to attend to own bodily needs without assistance, and unable to walk unassisted.&#xD;
Score 5: Severe disability. Requires constant nursing care and attention, bedridden, incontinent.&#xD;
Score 6: Dead</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with favorable clinical outcomes defined as mRS scores of 0-2.</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>The modified Rankin Scale (mRS) is a commonly used scale for measuring the degree of disability or dependence in the daily activities of people who have suffered a stroke or other causes of neurological disability. The scale runs from 0-6 with &quot;0&quot; being perfect health without symptoms to &quot;6&quot; being death.&#xD;
Score 0: No symptoms Score 1: No significant disability. Able to carry out all usual activities, despite some symptoms.&#xD;
Score 2: Slight disability. Able to look after own affairs without assistance, but unable to carry out all previous activities.&#xD;
Score 3: Moderate disability. Requires some help, but able to walk unassisted. Score 4: Moderately severe disability. Unable to attend to own bodily needs without assistance, and unable to walk unassisted.&#xD;
Score 5: Severe disability. Requires constant nursing care and attention, bedridden, incontinent.&#xD;
Score 6: Dead</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with symptomatic intracranial hemorrhage (sICH) per SITS-MOST</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 hours after randomization</time_frame>
    <description>NIHSS worsening of 4 or more points associated with sICH per Safe Implementation of Thrombolysis in Stroke-Monitoring Study (SITS-MOST) definition assessed within 24 hours after randomization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>deaths occurring within 90-day follow-up</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with groin hematomas, infections or any vascular injury cause by the endovascular procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 72 hours after procedure</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>From admission date to discharge date (about 1 week)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Discharge location</measure>
    <time_frame>discharge (about 1 week after randomization)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>NIH Stroke Scale score at 24 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours after randomization</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>NIH Stroke Scale score at discharge or day 5-7 (whichever comes earlier)</measure>
    <time_frame>at discharge (which is about 1 week after randomization) or Day 5-7, whichever comes earlier</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neuro-QoL score</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Infarct volume</measure>
    <time_frame>24 to 72 hours after randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Infarct volume on MRI diffusion-weighted imaging (DWI) sequence (or CT if MRI not feasible) 24 to 72 hours after randomization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lesion growth</measure>
    <time_frame>24 to 72 hours after randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Lesion growth between the RAPID identified ischemic core on baseline imaging and the infarct volume</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with successful reperfusion</measure>
    <time_frame>24 to 72 hours after randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Successful reperfusion defined as DWI lesion volume minus Tmax&gt;6 seconds greater than 50%</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with recanalization of the primary arterial occlusive lesion</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours after randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Recanalization of the primary arterial occlusive lesion, assessed by a modified Thrombolysis in Cerebral Infarction scores of 2b (50% to 75% reperfusion), 2c (&gt;75% to 99% reperfusion) or 3 (complete reperfusion)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">560</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Ischemic Stroke</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Endovascular Thrombectomy plus Medical Management</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Medical Management</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Endovascular Thrombectomy</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients randomized to endovascular thrombectomy arm will receive thrombectomy plus medical management. They will be treated with thrombectomy devices (stent-retrievers or aspiration devices) currently cleared by the FDA for thrombus removal in patients experiencing an acute stroke within 24 hours of symptom onset. The devices which will be used are FDA-approved stent retrievers: the Trevo Retriever, the Solitaire Revascularization Device, EmboTrap Revascularization Device and Tigertriever Revascularization Device; and/or the aspiration devices approved by the FDA (e.g. MicroVention SOFIA Catheter, and the Penumbra thrombectomy system). The choice of thrombectomy method, primary approach/technique, whether primary aspiration or primary stent-retriever with or without aspiration, will be left up to the interventionalist, with any of the FDA-approved devices approved in the study protocol or a combination of them.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Endovascular Thrombectomy plus Medical Management</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Medical Management</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive standard AHA guideline-directed medical therapy, which will include IV thrombolytic therapy available for use according to practice guidelines in patients presenting within the first 3 hours from last-seen-normal and meeting other FDA label criteria, or up to 4.5 hours from last-seen-normal and meeting other AHA guidelines. For non-thrombolysis treated patients, this will include aspirin 325 mg on day 1 followed by aspirin 81 mg or 325 mg thereafter, which will be determined by treating physician and standard deep venous thrombosis prevention therapy. Intravenous anticoagulation and dual anti-platelet therapy will be discouraged without clear documented reasoning. Post-thrombolysis patients will be treated based on standard study site protocols for these patients.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Endovascular Thrombectomy plus Medical Management</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Medical Management</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adults (18-85 years) with the final diagnosis of an acute ischemic stroke&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. NIH Stroke Scale Score (NIHSS) ≥ 6&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Last known well to groin puncture or medical management between 0 to 24 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pre-stroke modified Rankin Scale score (mRS) of 0-1&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Eligible for thrombectomy or medical management&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Signed Informed Consent obtained&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject willing to comply with the protocol follow-up requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Anticipated life expectancy of at least 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        Specific Neuroimaging Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Proven large vessel occlusion in ICA or MCA-M1 occlusion (carotid occlusions can be&#xD;
             cervical or intracranial, with or without tandem MCA lesions) determined by MRA or CTA&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Large infarct-core lesion on at least one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  2.1. Non-Contrast CT (ASPECTS of 3-5),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  2.2. CT perfusion (rCBF&lt;30% ≥50cc),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  2.3. MRI-DWI (ADC&lt;620 ≥50cc)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Inability to undergo CT angiography and/or CT perfusion imaging (e.g., renal&#xD;
             insufficiency, iodine/contrast allergy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Co-morbid psychiatric or medical illnesses that would confound the neurological&#xD;
             assessments&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Treatment with thrombolytic agent beyond 4.5 hours from last known well&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Treated with thrombolytic agent 3-4.5 hours after last known well AND any of the&#xD;
             following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  1) age &gt;80,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  2) current anticoagulant use,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  3) history of diabetes AND prior stroke,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  4) NIHSS &gt;25,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  5) ischemic involvement of &gt; 1/3 MCA territory&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Current participation in another investigational drug or device study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Neuroimaging Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who have both ASPECTS of 6-10 on non-contrast CT AND core volume &lt;50 cc on&#xD;
             perfusion imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with very large core on non-contrast CT i.e. ASPECTS ≤ 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Evidence of intracranial tumor (except small meningioma), acute intracranial&#xD;
             hemorrhage, neoplasm, or arteriovenous malformation&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. A significant mass effect with midline shift&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Evidence of internal carotid artery dissection that is flow limiting or aortic&#xD;
             dissection&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Intracranial stent implanted in the same vascular territory that precludes the safe&#xD;
             deployment/removal of the neurothrombectomy device&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Acute symptomatic arterial occlusions in more than one vascular territory confirmed on&#xD;
             CTA/MRA (e.g., bilateral MCA occlusions, or an MCA and a basilar artery occlusion).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Signs of established infarct and large area of cerebral edema on non-contrast CT&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Amrou Sarraj, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Case Western Reserve University - University Hospitals Cleveland Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amrou Sarraj, MD</last_name>
    <phone>216-844-9999</phone>
    <email>Amrou.Sarraj@UHhospitals.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kaiser Permanente</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90027</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Navdeep X. Sangha, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baptist Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jacksonville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32207</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ricardo A. Hanel, MD. PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rush University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael Chen, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascension St. Vincent Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46260</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Daniel Sahlein, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Iowa Hospitals and Clinics</name>
      <address>
        <city>Iowa City</city>
        <state>Iowa</state>
        <zip>52242</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Santiago Ortega-Gutierrez, MD, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66160</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael G. Abraham, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Spectrum Health Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Grand Rapids</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>49503</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jenny P. Tsai, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospitals Cleveland Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Amrou Sarraj, MD</last_name>
      <phone>216-844-1110</phone>
      <email>Amrou.Sarraj@UHhospitals.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Deep Pujara, MBBS</last_name>
      <email>Deep.Pujara@UHhospitals.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sophia Sundararajan, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Yin Hu, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cleveland Clinic Foundation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Hussain M. Shazam, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Riverside Methodist Hospital - OhioHealth</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43214</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>William Hicks, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ronald F. Budzik, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Abington Jefferson Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Abington</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19001</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Osman Kozak, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael T. Mullen, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Thomas Jefferson University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19107</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Pascal Jabbour, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nabeel A. Herial, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Semmes Murphey Clinic - University of Tennessee Health Science Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Memphis</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>38163</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lucas Elijovich, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dell Seton Medical Center at the University of Texas at Austin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78712</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Steven Warach, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Valley Baptist Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Harlingen</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78550</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ameer E. Hassan, DO</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Faris Shaker, MbChB</last_name>
      <phone>713-500-7194</phone>
      <email>faris.shaker@uth.tmc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Spiros L Blackburn, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Andrew D Barreto, MD MSc</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascension Wisconsin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milwaukee</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Daniel Gibson, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Liverpool Hospital - South Western Sydney Clinical School</name>
      <address>
        <city>Liverpool</city>
        <state>New South Wales</state>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Dennis Cordato, MBBS, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nathan Manning, G180275</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Royal Adelaide Hospital (RAH)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Adelaide</city>
        <state>South Australia</state>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Timothy J. Kleinig, MBBS, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Melbourne Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Melbourne</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bruce Campbell, MBBS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bernard Yan, MBBS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Health Network - Toronto Western Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joanna Schaafsma, MD, MSc, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Christchurch Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Christchurch</city>
        <state>Canterbury</state>
        <country>New Zealand</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Teddy Wu, MBChB, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Germans Trias i Pujol</name>
      <address>
        <city>Badalona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Natalia Pérez de la Ossa, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clínic i Provincial de Barcelona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jordi Blasco, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitari de Bellvitge</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Pere Cardona Portela</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitari Vall d'Hebron</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marc Ribo, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clínico Universitario de Valladolid</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valladolid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Juan F. Arenallis, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>New Zealand</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 8, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 12, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 15, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Case Western Reserve University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Amrou Sarraj</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ischemic stroke</keyword>
  <keyword>Large vessel occlusion</keyword>
  <keyword>Endovascular thrombectomy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ischemic Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cerebral Infarction</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

