<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00079768</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>040133</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>04-N-0133</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00079768</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Alemtuzumab to Treat Sporadic Inclusion Body Myositis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of a T Cell-Depleting Monoclonal Antibody, Alemtuzumab, in Patients With Inclusion Body Myositis: A Pilot Clinicopathological Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will examine the safety and effectiveness of alemtuzumab (Campath® (Registered&#xD;
      Trademark)) for improving muscle strength in patients with sporadic inclusion body myositis&#xD;
      (s-IBM). The most common inflammatory muscle disease in people over the age of 50, s-IBM&#xD;
      progresses steadily, leading to severe weakness and wasting of the muscles in the arms and&#xD;
      legs. The cause of s-IBM is not known, but it may be an autoimmune disease, in which the&#xD;
      body's immune cells (white blood cells) attack and destroy parts of muscle. Alemtuzumab is a&#xD;
      laboratory-made antibody currently approved to treat certain leukemias. It has also been used&#xD;
      to treat patients with autoimmune conditions such as rheumatoid arthritis, vasculitis,&#xD;
      multiple sclerosis, and tissue rejection associated with transplantation. Alemtuzumab&#xD;
      destroys white blood cells that have a protein called CD52 on their surface and that might be&#xD;
      among the cells attacking muscle.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with s-IBM are eligible for this study. Candidates are screened with physical and&#xD;
      neurological examinations, blood tests, and an electrocardiogram. Participants undergo the&#xD;
      following tests and procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Campath administration: Patients are admitted to the NIH Clinical Center for 1 to 1-1/2&#xD;
           weeks for intravenous infusions of Campath, given every other day for a total of 4&#xD;
           infusions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Follow-up visits after infusions: Patients are monitored for up to 1 year with periodic&#xD;
           blood tests, physical and neurological examinations, medical history, muscle strength&#xD;
           measurements, and a review of symptoms, including the ability to perform daily living&#xD;
           activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Lymphapheresis: Patients undergo this procedure for collecting large numbers of white&#xD;
           blood cells twice - once at the beginning of the study and again after 6 months. Blood&#xD;
           is removed through a needle in an arm vein and flows through a machine that separates it&#xD;
           into its components by centrifugation (spinning). The white cells and plasma are removed&#xD;
           and the red cells and platelets are returned to the patients through the same needle or&#xD;
           through another needle in the other arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Muscle biopsy: Muscle biopsies are done in the operating room under local anesthetic. A&#xD;
           small incision is made in the thigh or upper arm and a small piece of muscle is removed.&#xD;
           Biopsies are done at the beginning of the study and again after 6 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Sporadic Inclusion-Body Myositis (s-IBM) is the most common muscle disease in patients above&#xD;
      the age of 50 years. It is an inflammatory myopathy mediated by sensitized, cytotoxic CD8+ T&#xD;
      cells that clonally expand in situ and invade MHC-I-expressing muscle fibers. The antigen&#xD;
      recognized by the T cells is unknown. The disease is progressive, resists the currently&#xD;
      available immunotherapies and leads to wheelchair confinement. Applying therapeutic&#xD;
      strategies with agents that deplete T cells clones and investigating the antigenic&#xD;
      specificity of the endomysial T cells is expected to enhance our understanding of the cause&#xD;
      of s-IBM and lead to clinical improvement. The present study is designed to: a) test in a&#xD;
      pilot study the safety, T cell depletion of the endomysial T cells and clinical efficacy of&#xD;
      the monoclonal antibody Alemtuzumab in 20 patients with s-IBM followed for 12 months by&#xD;
      serial quantitative assessment of muscle strength; b) explore the spectrum of the antigens&#xD;
      recognized by the T cells extracted from the muscle biopsy specimens by searching for immune&#xD;
      dominant peptides using positional scanning synthetic combinational peptide libraries, before&#xD;
      and after therapy; and c) determine the reciprocal relationship between clinical response and&#xD;
      endomysial inflammatory mediators before and after treatment. It is anticipated that the&#xD;
      study may lead to identification of putative antigens that trigger the disease, clarify the&#xD;
      significance of the inflammation and amyloid deposits in muscle fiber injury and provide a&#xD;
      novel therapy for s-IBM patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2004</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 2007</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2007</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the muscle strength at 6 months by 15%.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment>20</enrollment>
  <condition>Myositis, Inclusion Body</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Alemtuzumab (Campath)</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  Only patients who are currently enrolled in protocol 02-N-0121 Study of Immune&#xD;
             Dysregulation in Patients with Sporadic Inclusion Body Myositis (s-IBM) will be&#xD;
             considered for enrollment in protocol 04-N-0133.&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients with confirmed diagnosis of s-IBM willing to undergo therapy with Alemtuzumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Willingness and legal ability to give and sign informed study consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Willingness to travel to the Clinical Center for planned studies and treatment as required&#xD;
        by protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Men and women of reproductive potential must agree to use an acceptable method of birth&#xD;
        control during and for six months after completion of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Availability of tissue for testing. This will include muscle and peripheral blood&#xD;
        lymphocytes isolated through routine lymphocytapheresis or phlebotomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Immunosuppressive drug therapy at the time of or 6 months prior to enrollment.&#xD;
        Specifically, candidates may not be taking Prednisone, cyclosporine, tacrolimus,&#xD;
        azathioprine, mycophenolate mofetil, anti-lymphocyte agents, cyclophosphamide methotrexate,&#xD;
        or other agents whose concomitant use may enhance the toxicity of Alemtuzumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any medical or personal difficulties that precludes serial follow-up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any active malignancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Significant coagulopathy or requirement for anticoagulation therapy that would&#xD;
        contraindicate protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Platelet count less than 100,000/mm(3).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Hemoglobin less than 9.0 mg/dl.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any known immunodeficiency syndrome included HIV infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any history of cardiac insufficiency, major vascular disease, or unstable coronary artery&#xD;
        disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any history of systemic or pulmonary edema.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any history of previous treatment with monoclonal antibodies or sensitivity to the study&#xD;
        drug (Alemtuzumab), pre-medication regimen, or prophylactic agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
        History of chronic hypotension (SBP less than 100 mmHg).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any medical condition that would likely increase the risk of side effects of the study drug&#xD;
        or confound the interpretation of the data including active infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pregnancy and active nursing (breast feeding).&#xD;
&#xD;
        History of uncontrolled thyroid disease or a history of autoimmune thyroiditis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dalakas MC. Polymyositis, dermatomyositis and inclusion-body myositis. N Engl J Med. 1991 Nov 21;325(21):1487-98. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>1658649</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dalakas MC, Sonies B, Dambrosia J, Sekul E, Cupler E, Sivakumar K. Treatment of inclusion-body myositis with IVIg: a double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Neurology. 1997 Mar;48(3):712-6.</citation>
    <PMID>9065553</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dalakas MC, Koffman B, Fujii M, Spector S, Sivakumar K, Cupler E. A controlled study of intravenous immunoglobulin combined with prednisone in the treatment of IBM. Neurology. 2001 Feb 13;56(3):323-7.</citation>
    <PMID>11171896</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 12, 2004</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 11, 2004</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 12, 2004</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 16, 2010</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 16, 2010</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">June 17, 2010</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Marinos C. Dalakas, M.D./National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke</name_title>
    <organization>National Institutes of Health</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Inflammation</keyword>
  <keyword>Myositis</keyword>
  <keyword>Humanized Monoclonal Antibody</keyword>
  <keyword>Cytotoxic T Cells</keyword>
  <keyword>Endomysial T Cells</keyword>
  <keyword>Alemtuzumab</keyword>
  <keyword>Monoclonal Antibodies</keyword>
  <keyword>IBM</keyword>
  <keyword>Anti-CD 52</keyword>
  <keyword>Inclusion Body Myositis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Myositis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myositis, Inclusion Body</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alemtuzumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

