<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00072592</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>040022</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>04-I-0022</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00072592</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Open Label Pilot Study Examining the Use of Rituximab in Patients With Wegener's Granulomatosis Who Have Experienced Disease Relapse on Standard Therapies</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open Label Pilot Study Examining the Use of Rituximab in Patients With Wegener's Granulomatosis Who Have Experienced Disease Relapse on Standard Therapies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will examine the use of rituximab in patients with Wegener's granulomatosis (WG)&#xD;
      who have experienced a relapse of the disease through standard therapies. Rituximab is an&#xD;
      antibody directed against the human protein called CD20, found on the surface of normal and&#xD;
      abnormal B lymphocytes. Rituximab decreases the number of B lymphocytes. This study will&#xD;
      examine the safety of rituximab in WG and rituximab's ability to reduce the level of&#xD;
      circulating antineutrophil cytoplasmic antibodies (ANCA), which are antibodies that react to&#xD;
      substances found in white blood cells. ANCA have been found to be strongly associated with&#xD;
      WG. The study will also explore whether rituximab can reduce the occurrence of disease&#xD;
      relapse. WG is a disease marked by inflammation of blood vessels. It can involve many&#xD;
      different parts of the body, including the sinuses, lungs, kidneys, brain, nerves, eyes,&#xD;
      intestinal tract, skin, joint, heart, and others. Before the use of cytotoxic drug therapy,&#xD;
      WG was almost always fatal if untreated, with a mortality rate of 93% within 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients 18 to 75 years of age who have a history of at least one relapse of the disease&#xD;
      despite standard treatments, who have had active WG within the previous 12 months and are in&#xD;
      remission, who are receiving either methotrexate or azathioprine for remission maintenance,&#xD;
      and who have circulating ANCA, may be eligible for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A minimum of 22 visits to the clinic will be required to complete the entire study. Patients&#xD;
      will undergo a comprehensive medical evaluation, with laboratory studies and x-rays. There&#xD;
      may also be consultations and possible biopsies of affected organs only if medically&#xD;
      indicated for diagnosis and treatment of the disease. In the 4-week period that patients will&#xD;
      receive rituximab infusions, the methotrexate or azathioprine will be continued at the same&#xD;
      dosage unless there are side effects that requite the medication to be temporarily stopped or&#xD;
      the dosage reduced. Patients will receive four doses of rituximab, at 375 mg per meter&#xD;
      squared of body surface area, once a week. It will be infused into a vein, through an&#xD;
      intravenous catheter. For the first dose, patients will be admitted as inpatients for at&#xD;
      least 24 hours, for monitoring during the infusion and for any reactions associated with it.&#xD;
      The second, third, and fourth rituximab infusions may be given either on an inpatient or&#xD;
      outpatient basis to be decided on how the patient tolerates the first infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following the four infusions, there will be blood tests to monitor the safety of the&#xD;
      medication and the status of the disease, to be done at home every week for 4 weeks. Results&#xD;
      will be sent to the researchers by fax. Patients will be asked to return to the clinic 1&#xD;
      month after the fourth infusion and every 1 to 3 months afterward. If there are no side&#xD;
      effects or a relapse of the disease, the methotrexate or azathioprine will be continued for 2&#xD;
      years past remission. If by then the disease then remains in remission, the dose of either&#xD;
      medication will be gradually decreased and eventually stopped. The usual schedule is to&#xD;
      reduce methotrexate by 2.5 mg per month and to reduce azathioprine by 25 mg per month. If at&#xD;
      that point there are no signs of active disease, the patients' illness will be considered to&#xD;
      be in continued remission and no further treatment will be necessary. If relapse does occur,&#xD;
      treatment would be different than previously. In most cases, treatment would involve&#xD;
      prednisone and cyclophosphamide or methotrexate If the ANCA finding is negative after&#xD;
      rituximab treatment and again becomes positive, and there is evidence of a return of B&#xD;
      lymphocytes, patients may receive a second course of four rituximab infusions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This pilot study will seek to investigate the use of rituximab in patients with Wegener's&#xD;
      granulomatosis who have experienced disease relapse through standard therapies. Rituximab is&#xD;
      a chimeric monoclonal antibody directed against CD20, which induces B cell death and results&#xD;
      in rapid and sustained depletion of circulating and tissue-based B cells. The objectives of&#xD;
      this protocol will be to establish the safety of rituximab in Wegener's granulomatosis, to&#xD;
      examine the ability of rituximab to reduce the level of circulating antineutrophil&#xD;
      cytoplasmic antibodies (ANCA), and to preliminarily explore whether rituximab is able to&#xD;
      prevent disease relapse. This prospective standardized open label trial will enroll 10&#xD;
      patients who have a well-documented history of disease relapse while receiving&#xD;
      immunosuppressive therapy given according to published regimens and who are ANCA positive&#xD;
      after remission induction. Patients will be enrolled once they have achieved remission from a&#xD;
      recent relapse and are receiving either methotrexate or azathioprine for remission&#xD;
      maintenance. All patients will receive rituximab 375 mg/M(2) once a week for 4 weeks. During&#xD;
      and following the rituximab treatment period, patients will remain on their remission&#xD;
      maintenance agent of methotrexate or azathioprine. Patients who are enrolled while on&#xD;
      prednisone will continue to taper the dosage to discontinuation as medically permitted.&#xD;
      Following the 4 weekly infusions of rituximab, patients will be followed prospectively for&#xD;
      evidence of effective B cell depletion, features of drug toxicity, level of circulating ANCA,&#xD;
      and clinical disease status. Patients whose ANCA levels become undetectable following the&#xD;
      infusion of rituximab may be retreated with a second 4 week course of rituximab should their&#xD;
      ANCA titer become positive (greater than or equal to 1:40) and there has been a return of B&#xD;
      cells in the peripheral blood. Methotrexate or azathioprine will be continued for two years&#xD;
      past remission, after which time, this will be tapered and discontinued. Patients will&#xD;
      continue to be monitored for two years off all immunosuppressive therapy or if a disease&#xD;
      relapse should occur, for a minimum of 12 months after the last rituximab infusion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2003</start_date>
  <completion_date>August 2005</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment>10</enrollment>
  <condition>Wegener's Granulomatosis</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rituximab</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Documentation of WG based on clinical characteristics and histopathologic and/or&#xD;
        angiographic evidence of vasculitis. In the absence of histopathologic and/or angiographic&#xD;
        evidence of vasculitis, patients who meet one of the following criteria and in whom&#xD;
        infectious and autoimmune diseases that may mimic WG have been excluded will also be&#xD;
        eligible:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A positive assay for anti-PR-3 or anti-MPO autoantibodies (ANCA) and the presence of&#xD;
        glomerulonephritis defined by red blood cell casts and proteinuria or renal biopsy showing&#xD;
        necrotizing glomerulonephritis in the absence of immune deposits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        A positive assay for anti-PR-3 or anti-MPO autoantibodies and at least 2 of the following:&#xD;
        the presence of granulomatous inflammation on biopsy; abnormal chest radiograph (defined as&#xD;
        the presence of nodules, fixed infiltrates, or cavities); nasal/oral inflammation on&#xD;
        clinical examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Age 18-75 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Previous history of greater than or equal to 1 disease relapse as defined in Appendix I in&#xD;
        patients fitting one of the below categories:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Disease relapse occurred while receiving MTX or AZA for remission maintenance following&#xD;
        remission induction with daily CYC according to standard regimens on which there has been&#xD;
        published data&#xD;
&#xD;
        Disease relapse occurred while on MTX following MTX induction according to the standard&#xD;
        regimen on which there has been published data (98) in a patient who is unable to receive&#xD;
        or is intolerant to daily CYC.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Active WG within the past 12 months for which the patient received induction therapy with&#xD;
        glucocorticoids combined with daily CYC or MTX according to standard regimens&#xD;
&#xD;
        Evidence of current disease remission as defined in Appendix I and is currently receiving&#xD;
        remission maintenance therapy consisting of MTX or AZA according to standard regimens.&#xD;
        Patients may concurrently be receiving prednisone that is being tapered. Patients who&#xD;
        completed their prednisone taper and are no longer receiving systemic glucocorticoids will&#xD;
        be eligible if they are within 6 months of the time of prednisone discontinuation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Circulating ANCA as defined by the presence of antibodies detectable by indirect&#xD;
        immunofluorescence performed by the NIH Clinical Immunology laboratory at a titer of&#xD;
        greater than or equal to 1:40 on two determinations done at least 4 weeks apart. Patients&#xD;
        who are historically ANCA positive and become ANCA negative during remission induction will&#xD;
        be eligible if they again become positive to a level of greater than or equal to 1:40 on&#xD;
        two determinations done at least 4 weeks apart at a prednisone dose of less than or equal&#xD;
        to 50mg QOD or within 6 months following the discontinuation of prednisone.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Willingness to travel to the NIH&#xD;
&#xD;
        Willingness of both women and men to use an effective means of birth control while&#xD;
        receiving treatment through this study. Effective contraception methods include abstinence,&#xD;
        surgical sterilization of either partner, barrier methods such as diaphragm, condom, cap or&#xD;
        sponge, or hormonal contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Evidence of active infection, which, in the judgment of the investigator, is of greater&#xD;
        danger to the patient than the underlying vasculitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients who are pregnant or who are nursing infants will not be eligible. Women of&#xD;
        childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test within one week prior to study&#xD;
        entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Serological evidence of infection with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis C, or&#xD;
        a positive hepatitis B surface antigen. A serological determination will be performed&#xD;
        within two weeks of beginning study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inability to comply with study guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Hemocytopenia: platelet count greater than 80,000/mm(3), absolute neutrophil count less&#xD;
        than 1500/mm(3), hematocrit less than 20% (in the absence of gastrointestinal bleeding or&#xD;
        hemolytic anemia).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Known allergy to murine proteins&#xD;
&#xD;
        Use of illegal drugs or alcohol abuse (alcohol use that would prevent a patient from&#xD;
        fulfilling the study requirements or that would increase the risk of study procedures.)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hoffman GS, Kerr GS, Leavitt RY, Hallahan CW, Lebovics RS, Travis WD, Rottem M, Fauci AS. Wegener granulomatosis: an analysis of 158 patients. Ann Intern Med. 1992 Mar 15;116(6):488-98.</citation>
    <PMID>1739240</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reinhold-Keller E, Beuge N, Latza U, de Groot K, Rudert H, Nölle B, Heller M, Gross WL. An interdisciplinary approach to the care of patients with Wegener's granulomatosis: long-term outcome in 155 patients. Arthritis Rheum. 2000 May;43(5):1021-32. Erratum in: Arthritis Rheum. 2000 Oct;43(10):2379.</citation>
    <PMID>10817555</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Talar-Williams C, Hijazi YM, Walther MM, Linehan WM, Hallahan CW, Lubensky I, Kerr GS, Hoffman GS, Fauci AS, Sneller MC. Cyclophosphamide-induced cystitis and bladder cancer in patients with Wegener granulomatosis. Ann Intern Med. 1996 Mar 1;124(5):477-84.</citation>
    <PMID>8602705</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2005</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 4, 2003</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2003</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 5, 2003</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 3, 2008</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 3, 2008</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 4, 2008</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>ANCA</keyword>
  <keyword>B Lymphocyte</keyword>
  <keyword>Vasculitis</keyword>
  <keyword>Treatment</keyword>
  <keyword>Remission</keyword>
  <keyword>Wegener Granulomatosis</keyword>
  <keyword>WG</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Granulomatosis with Polyangiitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

