<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01386866</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20080639</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01386866</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Single Dose Study of [14C]-Labelled AMG 706 in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-label, Single Dose Study of the Mass Balance and Metabolic Disposition of Orally Administered [14C]-Labelled AMG 706 (Motesanib) Followed by Extended Treatment With Motesanib in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Amgen</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Amgen</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In order for a tumour to grow and spread to other parts of the body, it needs to have a blood&#xD;
      supply. Certain proteins in the body, called cytokines or growth factors, have been shown to&#xD;
      cause the growth of new blood vessels that supply tumours and therefore help the tumour to&#xD;
      grow and spread. Motesanib (AMG 706) prevents these proteins from working, and may help to&#xD;
      prevent the growth of tumours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the first part of this study, we will look at the way your body absorbs this drug into&#xD;
      your blood, how your body changes and breaks down the drug, and then how the drug leaves your&#xD;
      body in your urine and faeces.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to provide potential treatment benefit for the subjects who participated in the&#xD;
      first part of the study, the second part of the study will allow subjects to continue on&#xD;
      motesanib (AMG 706) treatment. The estimated length of this part of the study is unknown, and&#xD;
      dependent on how subjects respond to motesanib (AMG 706).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Profile and identification of metabolites of [14C]-AMG 706 in plasma, urine, and faeces</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics of total radioactivity in plasma and whole blood</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The mass balance of [14C]-AMG 706 (as the percentage of the dose administered) in urine and faeces</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>• Measure the area under the plasma concentration curve versus time of AMG 706, as well as determine half-life and time of maximum concentration of AMG 706.</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The subject incidences of serious adverse events, adverse events, and clinically significant changes in vital signs and clinical laboratory tests</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">4</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Solid Tumors</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AMG 706</intervention_name>
    <description>Single oral dose of 125 mg AMG 706 (motesanib) containing 100 μCi of [14C]-AMG 706 followed by option to continue onto a treatment extension phase for potential treatment benefit. Subjects will be administered motesanib 125 mg (5 x 25 mg tablets) on a daily basis until subjects experience a dose-limiting toxicity (DLT), an unacceptable AE, disease progression, or voluntary withdrawal.</description>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with a pathologically documented and definitively diagnosed advanced solid&#xD;
             tumor(excluding tumors that may significantly interfere with the absorption,&#xD;
             metabolism, or excretion of the test article, such as primary or metastatic liver&#xD;
             tumor with approximately &gt;50% of liver tissue involvement) that is refractory to&#xD;
             standard treatment or for which no curative therapy is available&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status of 0-1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Man or woman (male or female), age &gt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and sign an Independent Ethics Committee (IEC) Approved informed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must also fulfil Haematological, Renal, Hepatic and Coagulation criteria (not&#xD;
             listed)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute disease state (e.g. nausea, vomiting, fever, diarrhea) within 7 days of Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of documented arterial or venous thrombosis within 1 year of Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of bleeding diathesis or bleeding within 14 days of Day 1, or&#xD;
             hypercoagulopathy syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of life-threatening ventricular arrhythmia (e.g. sustained ventricular&#xD;
             tachycardia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of pulmonary hemorrhage or gross hemoptysis (1/2 teaspoon of bright red blood&#xD;
             or more) within 6 months of Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Central nervous system metastases (exception: subjects with treated, asymptomatic&#xD;
             central nervous system metastases, those who have been clinically stable in the&#xD;
             judgment of the investigator and off steroids for at least 30 days before Day 1 are&#xD;
             eligible)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with head and neck cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with ovarian cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with large central (located adjacent to or within the hilum or mediastinum)&#xD;
             tumor lesions ≥ 3 cm, regardless of histology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled hypertension: average systolic blood pressure &gt; 150 mm Hg or average&#xD;
             diastolic blood pressure &gt; 90 mm Hg (average blood pressure of the three separate&#xD;
             blood pressure values measured within 10 minutes during screening)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic chemotherapy within 28 days of Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiotherapy within 28 days of Day 1 or within 14 days of Day 1 for peripheral lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Experimental or approved antibody therapy within 6 weeks before Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent or prior (within 4 weeks prior to Day 1 of 5 half-lives of the medication&#xD;
             which ever is longer) treatment with potent CYP3A inducers, including but not limited&#xD;
             to : phenytoin, carbamazepine, rifampicin, phenobarbital and St John's Wort&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent or prior (within 2 weeks prior to Day 1 or 5 half-lives of the medication&#xD;
             which ever is longer) treatment with potent CYP3A inhibitors, including but not&#xD;
             limited to: ketoconazole, itraconazole, fluconazole, clarithromycin, erythromycin,&#xD;
             cyclosporine, tacrolimus, nefazodone and/or HIV protease inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent or prior (within 2 weeks prior to Day 1) consumption of grapefruit (i.e.&#xD;
             whole fruit or fruit juice)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who as a result of gastrointestinal surgeries (including cholecystectomy) or&#xD;
             a medical condition (e.g. constipation, cholecystitis / cholelithiasis) that will&#xD;
             significantly alter the absorption, metabolism or excretion of motesanib.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with irregular bowel habits (more than 3/day or less than 1 every 2 days).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who will not refrain from taking herbal/ complementary therapies (which have&#xD;
             the potential to alter the absorption, metabolism, or excretion of the [14C]-AMG 706)&#xD;
             for 7 days before first dosing, and for the duration of the ADME part of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent immune modulators such as cyclosporine and tacrolimus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any anti-coagulation therapy within 7 days prior to Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects whose occupation requires exposure to radiation or monitoring for radiation&#xD;
             exposure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant cardiac disease within 12 months of study Day 1, including&#xD;
             myocardial infarction, unstable angina, Grade 2 or greater peripheral vascular&#xD;
             disease, cerebrovascular accident, transient ischemic attack, congestive heart&#xD;
             failure, or ongoing arrhythmias requiring medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery (that which requires general anesthesia) within 28 days or minor surgery&#xD;
             within 14 days of Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any kind of disorder that compromises the ability of the subject to give written&#xD;
             informed consent and/or comply with the study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of any medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory abnormality that in the&#xD;
             opinion of the investigator may increase the risks associated with study participation&#xD;
             or investigational product administration or may interfere with the interpretation of&#xD;
             the study results&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known positive test for human immunodeficiency virus infection, hepatitis C virus,&#xD;
             chronic active hepatitis B infection or any co-morbid disease that would increase risk&#xD;
             of toxicity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any subject not consenting to use adequate contraceptive precautions (eg, hormonal,&#xD;
             barrier or abstinence) during the course of the study and for 6 months after the last&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects who have a positive pregnancy test at screening or on Day-1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects who are breastfeeding or plan to breastfeed during the study or within&#xD;
             6 months after the last administration of the investigational product&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in a therapeutic clinical trial within 30 days of Day1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is unwilling or unable to comply with the study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has a known sensitivity to any of the products to be administered over the&#xD;
             course of the study (e.g. known hypersensitivity to study medication motesanib)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with a history of gall bladder and bile duct disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with Gilberts syndrome&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Amgen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.amgentrials.com</url>
    <description>AmgenTrials clinical trials website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 14, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 30, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 1, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 14, 2011</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 14, 2011</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">July 15, 2011</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Global Development Leader</name_title>
    <organization>Amgen Inc.</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>AMG 706</keyword>
  <keyword>Motesanib</keyword>
  <keyword>Amgen</keyword>
  <keyword>Phase 1</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Motesanib diphosphate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

