<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01386203</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SHEBA-11-8663-NP-CTIL</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01386203</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Exhaled Breath Biomarkers in Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Early Detection of Lung Cancer - Exhaled Breath Nano-Analysis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sheba Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sheba Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Analysis of volatile organic compounds (VOCs) is a new attractive non-invasive field in&#xD;
      medical diagnostics. These VOCs can be detected via the exhaled breath.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Together with Prof Haick group at the Technion Inst (Israel), the investigators data shows&#xD;
      that there is a relation between the VOCs patterns of NSCLC and control cell lines and&#xD;
      equivalent states in exhaled breath. The investigators demonstrated that there is a clear&#xD;
      discrimination between the lung cancer and the healthy clusters . The investigators also&#xD;
      analyzed the headspace of NSCLC and SCLC cell lines and the investigators could discriminate&#xD;
      significantly between SCLC versus NSCLC based on their VOCs patterns. This analysis allowed&#xD;
      us to identify the specific VOCs consumed or omitted by cancerous cells. Therefore, a&#xD;
      non-invasive and highly sensitive test would be extremely valuable for the classification and&#xD;
      early screening of lung cancer and for targeted therapy. In this study, the investigators&#xD;
      will monitor the VOC pattern of patients with lung cancer as well as high risk cohort and&#xD;
      patients under risk/evaluation for lung cancer. Likewise the investigators will monitor pts&#xD;
      under and after therapy. In addition, the investigators will compare teh breath signature to&#xD;
      other biomarkers of lung cancer, like circulating tumor cells and others.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Scientific background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lung cancer is the most lethal cancer, responsible for 28% of cancer deaths and killing ~1.3&#xD;
      million people worldwide every year. Diagnosis and treatment of lung cancer in its early&#xD;
      stages could increase the 5-year-survival rate 3-4 fold with a potential for cure4, 7.&#xD;
      Therefore, the main goal of this study is early detection of lung cancer, and specifically&#xD;
      focusing on the volatile biomarkers of lung cancer that will assist in easy, inexpensive&#xD;
      diagnosis based on our previous findings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Currently available diagnostic tests of lung cancer are not suitable for screening, are&#xD;
      extremely costly and involve invasive procedures (e.g. bronchoscopy), that are not free of&#xD;
      complications. The goal of cancer screening is to detect tumors at an early stage in order to&#xD;
      give treatment a better chance of success. Recently, the biggest lung cancer screening trial&#xD;
      (NLST) has shown a mortality benefit of 21% per 5 years study favor low dose CT screening&#xD;
      protocol compare to chest X-rays1. Therefore, there is an urgent requirement for a tool to&#xD;
      allow a better definition of the high-risk cohort. Such a tool might be a panel of&#xD;
      biomarkers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Focusing on the volatile biomarkers of lung cancer, our group has recently defined a volatile&#xD;
      VOCs signature that can distinguish the breath of lung cancer patients from the breath of&#xD;
      healthy individuals and from cancerous cells 2, 9. These significant findings have led us to&#xD;
      the understanding that volatile biomarkers would fit for early detection of lung cancer and&#xD;
      for discrimination between subtypes of lung cancer. Such discrimination will have significant&#xD;
      implications on clinical decisions and on patients' benefits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exhaled Breath Analysis as a Diagnostic Tool and Preliminary results:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analysis of volatile organic compounds (VOCs) is a new attractive non-invasive field in&#xD;
      medical diagnostics. The principle behind this approach is based on the fact that cancers&#xD;
      cells are distinguished from normal cell in their metabolism rate, cell apoptosis pathways&#xD;
      and protein expression patterns and thus emit and or consume various VOCs. These VOCs can be&#xD;
      detected either directly from the headspace of the cancer cells or via the exhaled breath.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Together with Prof Haick group at the Technion Inst (Israel), our data shows that there is a&#xD;
      relation between the VOCs patterns of NSCLC and control cell lines and equivalent states in&#xD;
      exhaled breath. We demonstrated that there is a clear discrimination between the lung cancer&#xD;
      and the healthy clusters. We also analyzed the headspace of NSCLC and SCLC cell lines and we&#xD;
      could discriminate significantly between SCLC versus NSCLC based on their VOCs patterns. This&#xD;
      analysis allowed us to identify the specific VOCs consumed or omitted by cancerous cells.&#xD;
      This finding has clinical applications since SCLC is distinguished from NSCLC by its&#xD;
      sensitivity to chemotherapy and radiotherapy and other characteristics. Therefore, a&#xD;
      non-invasive and highly sensitive test would be extremely valuable for the classification and&#xD;
      early screening of lung cancer and for targeted therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Breath Collection and the Artificial NOSE&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a typical collection, after normal exhalation, the subject will breath through a&#xD;
      mouthpiece a filtered air to remove all VOCs of any ambient contaminants. Individuals will&#xD;
      exhale in a constant flow rate. The exhaled air will be contained through the mouthpiece by&#xD;
      Mayler bags and/or will be passed through a container. The collected air breath samples will&#xD;
      be analysed for VOC by gas-chromatography mass spectrometry (GC-MS), highly-sensitive&#xD;
      nano-sensors (Nanomaterial-Based Devices, Technion - Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa,&#xD;
      Israel) or as online mass spectrometry (Ionimed, Austria). Further, the signals will be&#xD;
      analyzed by a pattern recognition algorithms, such as principal component analysis (PCA),&#xD;
      supported vector machines (SVM), or neuronal network analysis can then be applied on the&#xD;
      entire set of signals to acquire information on the identity, properties and chemical&#xD;
      composition of the vapor exposed to the sensors array 5, 10.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our goal is to isolate and define a volatile signature, which allows discrimination between&#xD;
      lung cancer from a normal state. That will potential serve as a unique biomarker for lung&#xD;
      cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our Objectives are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To test the feasibility for detecting early stage lung cancer via analysis of exhaled&#xD;
           breath irrespective of the sub-histology.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To test the feasibility of the breath biomarkers for monitoring the response to lung&#xD;
           cancer treatment (surgery, chemotherapy or other cancer treatments)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare sensitivity and selectivity of the breath analysis to conventional cancer&#xD;
           markers and/or diagnostics (CT, PET, circulating tumor cells, blood markers etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Correlation of histology and/or other clinical measures to the breath signature.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the clinical setup, we will sample three populations:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group A - patients with lung cancer (NSCLC and SCLC), any stage; this group will be divided&#xD;
      later as for:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. SCLC (before and after therapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. NSCLC:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Surgically treated (Before and after therapy 3 years follow up).&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Advanced disease (Before and after therapy, 3 years follow up). Group B - high risk&#xD;
                patients who are undergoing investigation related to Lung cancer or pulmonary&#xD;
                nodule.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group C - age and co-morbidity matched controls without proof of cancer/pre-cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All collections will follow local IRB guidelines. Information will be collected from all&#xD;
      subjects, including epidemiologic data, histologic characteristics, tumor's metabolic&#xD;
      activity (SUV avidity through PET scan). The clinical information will include health status,&#xD;
      lung cancer subtype, pathology sub-classification and differentiation, advanced analysis and&#xD;
      staining if available, imaging results (including CT, PET scan and its SUV avidity), location&#xD;
      of the cancer, total volume of the tumor, stage of disease, genetic classification of the&#xD;
      tumor and epidemiological data, e.g. age, gender, smoking and family history, family history,&#xD;
      respiratory disease, exposure to asbestos etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If cancer, the selection for therapy are as per the standards of care and the routine&#xD;
      established care provided by the staff at the local institute. This protocol is not intended&#xD;
      to interfere with or dictate this process.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Examination procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
      The total duration of the study for each subject takes 10-20 minutes while subjects will stay&#xD;
      on followup for up to 3 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will continue for 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Newly diagnosed patients with non small cell lung cancer:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Breath tests:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Two tests immediately prior to any therapy (surgery/other; One week apart to test&#xD;
           reproducibility).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. If was operated for cure, then at 3,6,12,18,24,36 months later.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. If was radiated, then at mid &amp; end of radiation and at 3,6,12,18,24,36 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. If chemotherapy, then every 3 months, between cycles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow up phase:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Every three months to coincide with patients regular follow up their treating physicians. As&#xD;
      per the standards of care, at this point every patient will be monitored with a CT scan of&#xD;
      chest and abdomen at regular intervals. This CT will be used for determination of disease&#xD;
      recurrence or to document remission.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Correlative studies&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Sputum Cytology (Induced Sputum will be collected for cytologic examination).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Blood samples will be taken for Circulating tumor cells analysis and other systemic&#xD;
           markers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Collection of the Breath Samples&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a typical collection, after normal exhalation, the subject will breath through a&#xD;
      mouthpiece a filtered air to remove all VOCs of any ambient contaminants. Individuals will&#xD;
      exhale in a constant flow rate. The exhaled air will be contained through the mouthpiece by&#xD;
      Mayler bags and/or will be passed through a container. The collected air breath samples will&#xD;
      be analysed for VOC by gas-chromatography mass spectrometry (GC-MS), highly-sensitive&#xD;
      nano-sensors (Nanomaterial-Based Devices, Technion - Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa,&#xD;
      Israel) or as online mass spectrometry (Ionimed, Austria). Further, the signals will be&#xD;
      analyzed by a pattern recognition algorithms, such as principal component analysis (PCA),&#xD;
      supported vector machines (SVM), or neuronal network analysis can then be applied on the&#xD;
      entire set of signals to acquire information on the identity, properties and chemical&#xD;
      composition of the vapor exposed to the sensors array 5, 10.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>June 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lung Cancer</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lung Cancer after therapy</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COPD controls</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      exhaled breath and CTC and biomarkers&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Lung cancer patients vs. post therapy vs. COPD controls&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A diagnosis of lung cancer, regardless of histology.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A suspicious for lung cancer under investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to participate in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Availability of a signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to comply with study and/or follow up procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inclusion of Women and Minorities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both men and women and members of all races and ethnic groups are eligible for this&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Criteria for discontinuation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects may be discontinued from study treatment and assessments at any time.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>95 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nir Peled, MD PhD FCCP</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Sheba Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nir Peled, MD PhD</last_name>
    <email>peled.nir@sheba.health.gov.il</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sheba Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tel Hashomer</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nir Peled</last_name>
      <email>peled.nir@sheba.health.gov.il</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 3, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 29, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 30, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 28, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 28, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 29, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>biomarkers</keyword>
  <keyword>breath</keyword>
  <keyword>early detection</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

