<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01389726</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R01NR012256</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01NR012256</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01389726</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparing Interventions To Improve The Well-Being Of Custodial Grandfamilies</brief_title>
  <acronym>COPE</acronym>
  <official_title>Comparing Interventions To Improve The Well-Being Of Custodial Grandfamilies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kent State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Nursing Research (NINR)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kent State University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a multi-site, four-year long clinical trial study in which several mental&#xD;
      health interventions will be delivered to custodial grandmothers and then compared. The study&#xD;
      will examine effects on the mental health of these grandmothers and the grandchildren they&#xD;
      provide full-time care to in complete absence of the grandchild's birth parents. Grandparents&#xD;
      from diverse racial, ethnic, and socio-economic backgrounds will be recruited to test for&#xD;
      cultural differences in response to these interventions. This study is important because&#xD;
      there is growing evidence that custodial grandchildren are at-risk for psychological&#xD;
      difficulties due to neglect and abuse by birth parents, challenges to parenting faced by&#xD;
      custodial grandparents, and limited access to needed services. This study is funded by the&#xD;
      National Institute of Nursing Research, a division of the National Institutes of Health, and&#xD;
      it is anticipated that more than 500 custodial grandfamilies in four sites across the United&#xD;
      States will partake.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Although prior studies reveal that custodial grandmothers (CGM) and grandchildren (CGC) face&#xD;
      high risk for psychological difficulties, virtually no rigorous studies of psychosocial&#xD;
      interventions based on solid conceptual frameworks have been conducted with these vulnerable&#xD;
      families. In view of preliminary findings that disrupted parenting mediates the relationship&#xD;
      between CGM's psychological distress in the caregiver role and CGC's emotional and behavioral&#xD;
      problems, this project involves a randomized clinical trial (RCT) of the comparative&#xD;
      feasibility and efficacy of two evidenced-based psychoeducational interventions widely used&#xD;
      with other caregiver populations. Grandmothers (N = 504) of CGC (age 5 - 12) will be randomly&#xD;
      assigned to one of three conditions: Behavioral Parent Training (BPT; derived from Project&#xD;
      KEEP for foster parents; Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (CBT; derived from Coping with&#xD;
      Caregiving for caregivers of frail elders); Minimal Support Condition (to control for&#xD;
      non-specific treatment factors). The proposed universal interventions include prevention and&#xD;
      remediation objectives and involve a group format approach with mental health professionals&#xD;
      and grandparent peers serving as co-leaders. The RCT will occur in multiple locations across&#xD;
      the US to ensure that findings generalize beyond a single area and that equal numbers of&#xD;
      Black (n = 168), Hispanic (n = 168), and White (n = 168) families participate. Prior to the&#xD;
      RCT, focus groups will be held separately with CGMs of each race (n = 10 apiece) and&#xD;
      experienced practitioners (n = 10) with the aim of assessing the perceived importance and&#xD;
      acceptability of recruitment methods, treatment goals, and procedures, including possible&#xD;
      differences by race/ethnicity. Multiple-informant and multiple-method assessments during the&#xD;
      RCT at pretest, posttest and 6, 12, 18, and 24 month follow-ups will include indicators of&#xD;
      CGM psychological distress (anxiety, depression); CGC adjustment (internalizing and&#xD;
      externalizing problems); and disrupted parenting (use of ineffective discipline and low&#xD;
      nurturance). Based on the conceptual framework of the prominent Family Stress Model,&#xD;
      multi-group structural equation modeling analyses will be used to achieve four aims: (a) To&#xD;
      compare the short and long-term effectiveness of CBT and BPT; (b) to examine longitudinally&#xD;
      the dynamic linkages between CGM parenting practices, CGM' psychological distress, and CGC&#xD;
      adjustment as modified by BPT and CBT; (c) to determine if key moderating variables&#xD;
      (race/ethnicity, CGC, initial psychological difficulties in CGC and CGM influence RCT&#xD;
      outcomes; and (d) to examine key factors related to acceptability and adherence to the&#xD;
      proposed interventions. The findings will inform future clinical practice with custodial&#xD;
      grandfamilies by identifying which of the proposed interventions are most effective and most&#xD;
      acceptable among specific sub-groups (e.g., race/ethnicity; initial risk) and by unraveling&#xD;
      the specific antecedent-consequent relations among CGM distress, dysfunctional parenting, and&#xD;
      CGC adjustment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Parenting Quality after intervention up to two years</measure>
    <time_frame>post-test (2 to 6 weeks following intervention), 6 mos, 12 mos, 18 mos, 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Parenting quality will be measured in terms of the degree to which grandparents employ positive discipline strategies and engage in warm or nurturing parenting styles. Measured both using self-report and observer ratings.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Grandchild Internalizing and Externalizing Symptoms after intervention up to two years</measure>
    <time_frame>post-test (2 to 6 weeks following intervention), 6 mos, 12 mos, 18 mos, 24 mos</time_frame>
    <description>Measured through grandmother report, grandchild report, and observer ratings</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in GM Psychological Distress after intervention up to two years</measure>
    <time_frame>post-test (2 to 6 weeks following intervention), 6mos, 12 mos, 18 mos, 24 mos</time_frame>
    <description>Grandmother's psychological distressed as defined by anxiety and depression levels (measured both through self report and clinical ratings)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention efficacy</measure>
    <time_frame>2 to 6 weeks following intervention</time_frame>
    <description>GM satisfaction with intervention, and comparative impact of interventions vs. control. These variables will be measured at the post-test which will take place between two and 6 weeks following the completion of the intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">343</enrollment>
  <condition>Custodial Grandparents</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Behavioral Parenting Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Triple-P Parenting Training Program (group level)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>CBT group-level intervention (Designed by Larry Thompson &amp; Dolores Gallagher Thompson)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Psychosocial-Informational Support</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard of Care informational support group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Behavioral Parent Training</intervention_name>
    <description>Triple-P program involves 11 weeks of ongoing group support with contact one time per week with trained group leaders</description>
    <arm_group_label>Behavioral Parenting Training</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Triple-P</other_name>
    <other_name>BPT</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Support group based intervention involving sessions one time per week for 11 weeks with 9-12 grandmothers, 1 trained professional group leader, and 1 trained peer leader</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CBT</other_name>
    <other_name>Cognitive therapy</other_name>
    <other_name>Larry Thompson</other_name>
    <other_name>Dolores Gallagher-Thompson</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Psychosocial-Informational support</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard of care normally provided to custodial grandparents. Involves providing information and support in the context of a weekly group meeting with 9-12 grandparents, 1 professional group leader &amp; 1 peer leader over the course of 11 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Psychosocial-Informational Support</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Support group</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grandmother raising grandchildren&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No biological resides in grandmother's home&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one grandchild between ages 4 and 12&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grandchild has lived with grandmother for minimum of 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grandchild is expected to stay with grandmother&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biological parent is directly involved in raising child&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grandmother is unable to leave the home to attend weekly meetings&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grandmother is unable to speak English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grandmother is unable to answer simple questions&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gregory Smith, Ed.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Kent State University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bert Hayslip, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of North Texas Health Science Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Karie Feldman, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Kent State University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California, San Bernardino</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Bernardino</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92407</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Maryland Baltimore County</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kent State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kent</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44242</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of North Texas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Denton</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>76203</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 5, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 6, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 8, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Gregory Smith, Ed.D.; Professor</name_title>
    <organization>Kent State University</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>custodial grandparents</keyword>
  <keyword>kinship caregivers</keyword>
  <keyword>grandparents raising grandchildren</keyword>
  <keyword>grandmothers</keyword>
  <keyword>grandchildren</keyword>
  <keyword>psychological well-being</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

