<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02501434</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10550</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02501434</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Aneurysmal Subarachnoid Hemorrhage Trial RandOmizing Heparin</brief_title>
  <acronym>ASTROH</acronym>
  <official_title>A Blind-adjudication Multi-center Phase II Randomized Clinical Trial of Continuous Low-dose Intravenous Heparin Therapy in Coiled Low-grade Aneurysmal Subarachnoid Hemorrhage Patients With Significant Hemorrhage Burden</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Robert F. James</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Indiana University School of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Indiana University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A Blind-adjudication Multi-center Phase II Randomized Clinical Trial of Continuous Low-dose&#xD;
      Intravenous Heparin Therapy in Coiled Low-grade Aneurysmal Subarachnoid Hemorrhage Patients&#xD;
      with Significant Hemorrhage Burden.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this study is to investigate the safety and clinical effect of a&#xD;
      continuous low-dose intravenous unfractionated heparin (LDIVH) infusion for the prevention of&#xD;
      aneurysmal subarachnoid hemorrhage (aSAH) induced neurocognitive dysfunction and other&#xD;
      delayed neurological deficits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additionally, increased blood and CSF levels of certain inflammatory biomarkers (IL-6, hsCRP,&#xD;
      etc) have been correlated to aSAH patients with poor clinical outcomes. Unfractionated&#xD;
      heparin (UFH) has known anti-inflammatory actions. As a result, a secondary objective of this&#xD;
      study will be to evaluate whether LDIVH can reduce blood and CSF inflammatory biomarkers&#xD;
      levels compared to controls and whether there is any association between inflammatory&#xD;
      biomarker levels and cognitive outcomes in aSAH.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA)</measure>
    <time_frame>90-day follow-up visit</time_frame>
    <description>Primary Clinical Outcome Measure- mean score compared between groups</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of &quot;Major Bleeding&quot; or &quot;Clinically Relevant Non-Major Bleeding&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>Patients will be followed for the duration of the hospital stay; an expected average of 3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>As defined by the International Society of Thrombosis and Heamostasis (ISTH) Primary Safety Outcome Measure-</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of &quot;Major Bleeding&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be followed for the duration of the hospital stay, an expected average of 3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>As defined by the International Society of Thrombosis and Haemostasis (ISTH)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of Type II Heparin Induced Thrombocytopenia (HIT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Enrollment through 90-day follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of Deep Venous Thrombosis (DVT) or Pulmonary Embolism (PE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Enrollment through 90-day follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All Cause - Mortality Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Enrollment through 90-day follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Any Fever (&gt; 38.3 degrees C; &gt; or = 101.0 degrees F)</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be followed for the duration of the hospital stay, an expected average of 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of multiple fevers (&gt; 2 episodes)</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be followed for the duration of the hospital stay, an expected average of 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean daily fever burden</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be followed for the duration of the hospital stay, an expected average of 3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Daily fever burden = Sum of hourly fever burden over 24 hours; Hourly fever burden = Any hourly temperature recording &gt; 37 degrees C - (minus) 37 degrees C; if temperature is less than or equal to 37 degrees C then the hourly fever burden would be zero.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Glasgow Coma Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Enrollment, post-enrollment days #6, 10, discharge, and 90-day follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>National Institutes of Health Stroke Scale (NIHSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Enrollment, post-enrollment days #6, 10, upon discharge from hospital stay an expected average of about 3 weeks after admission, 90-day follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Enrollment, post-enrollment days #6, 10, 1 year follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Mean between groups and rate of MoCA score of 20 or less between groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Center for Epidemiologic Studies Depression Scale (CES-D)</measure>
    <time_frame>90-day follow-up visit and 1-year follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Trail Making Test Parts A&amp;B</measure>
    <time_frame>90-day follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cerebral Vasospasm</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be followed for the duration of the hospital stay, an expected average of 3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of moderate and severe radiographic cerebral vasospasm (catheter angiogram, CTA, MRA) or incidence OR moderate and severe vasospasm by transcranial doppler (TCD) criteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of clinical cerebral vasospasm requiring rescue therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be followed for the duration of the hospital stay, an expected average of 3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Rescue therapy = vasopressors or endovascular therapy for the purposes of reversing clinical vasospasm; it does not include Triple H (Hyperdynamic Therapy)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of CT or MRI imaging demonstrating cerebral vasospasm related cerebral infarction</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be followed for the duration of the hospital stay, an expected average of 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ordinal Regression Analysis of the modified Rankin Scale score (mRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>90-day follow-up visit and 1 year follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Relative frequency of &quot;good outcome&quot; as defined by dichotomized mRS score 0-2</measure>
    <time_frame>90-day follow-up visit and 1 year follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Barthel Index</measure>
    <time_frame>90-day follow-up visit and 1 year follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Return to work status</measure>
    <time_frame>90-day follow-up and 1 year follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lawton instrumental activities of daily living (IADL)</measure>
    <time_frame>90-day follow-up visit and 1 year follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life in Brain Injury - Overall Scale (QOLIBRI-OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>90-day follow-up visit and 1 year follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Checklist Individual Strength- Subscale Fatigue (CIS-F)</measure>
    <time_frame>90-day follow-up visit and 1 year follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma biomarker level (hsCRP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Enrollment, post-enrollment days #2,4,6,10</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cerebrospinal Fluid (CSF) biomarker level (hsCRP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Enrollment, post-enrollment days #2,4,6,10</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through 90-Day follow-up visit</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary Safety Outcome Measure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Subgroup analysis for the following subgroups: (Clinical Site, Gender, Admission CT Hijdra Sum Score &lt;23, WFNS grade, aneurysm location, anterior circulation aneurysm vs posterior circulation aneurysm location, infection requiring antibiotic treatment,</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be followed for the duration of the hospital stay, an expected average of 3 weeks, 90-day follow-visit and 1 year follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">88</enrollment>
  <condition>Aneurysmal Subarachnoid Hemorrhage</condition>
  <condition>Neurobehavioral Manifestations</condition>
  <condition>Vasospasm, Intracranial</condition>
  <condition>Intracranial Aneurysm</condition>
  <condition>Heparin-induced Thrombocytopenia Type II</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard of Care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LDIVH (Unfractionated Heparin)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Continuous Low-Dose IV Unfractionated Heparin Infusion</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Continuous Low-Dose IV Unfractionated Heparin Infusion</intervention_name>
    <description>Continuous intravenous infusion of a low-dose unfractionated heparin drip</description>
    <arm_group_label>LDIVH (Unfractionated Heparin)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Heparin</other_name>
    <other_name>Unfractionated Heparin</other_name>
    <other_name>Heparin drip</other_name>
    <other_name>IV Heparin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 18 and ≤ 70 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Historical modified Rankin Scale Score 0-1&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Aneurysmal subarachnoid hemorrhage caused by a ruptured saccular aneurysm confirmed by&#xD;
             catheter angiography that is repaired by endovascular coil embolization. Initiation of&#xD;
             the coil embolization procedure should occur within 48 hours from the time of the&#xD;
             aneurysm rupture (ictus). In patients where the exact time of the ictus is uncertain,&#xD;
             a reasonable estimate of the time of ictus may be assigned. This reasonable time&#xD;
             estimate should be considered likely accurate to within hours of the true unknown&#xD;
             time.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Quality of aneurysm embolization is interpreted to be Raymond-Roy Score of 1&#xD;
             (Complete) or 2 (Residual Neck) indicating that the aneurysm is adequately secured. A&#xD;
             tiny amount of contrast in the body of the aneurysm is acceptable as long as the&#xD;
             physician considers the aneurysm secured and to NOT represent a Raymond-Roy Score of 3&#xD;
             (Residual Aneurysm).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. WFNS grade 1 or 2 as assessed after repair of the aneurysm during screening but prior&#xD;
             to randomization. A patient who presents with a WFNS greater than 2 who then improves&#xD;
             with resuscitation, ventriculostomy, or time is acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The pre-repair, admission head CT demonstrates an aSAH bleed pattern of &quot;thick and&#xD;
             diffuse&quot; or &quot;thick and focal&quot; hemorrhage within the subarachnoid basal cisterns&#xD;
             measuring ≥ 4 mm in the short axis and ≥ 20 mm in the long axis which is consistent&#xD;
             with a modified Fisher grade 3 or 4. Intraventricular hemorrhage is acceptable.&#xD;
             Enrollable patients must NOT have a parenchymal hemorrhage greater than 10 cc. Please&#xD;
             refer to diagram below for examples. The hemorrhage location should be substantially&#xD;
             within the supratentorial space and not isolated to the infratentorial space.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The location of the aneurysm should be the anterior circulation, posterior&#xD;
             communicating, OR a basilar terminus (apex). Angiographic location of the aneurysm&#xD;
             should be confirmed by catheter digital subtraction angiography (DSA) usually obtained&#xD;
             during the coil embolization procedure. Patients with PICA or other posterior&#xD;
             circulation aneurysms as the cause of the SAH should not be included because they&#xD;
             typically cause primarily infratentorial bleed patterns.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Ability to screen the patient and obtain a head CT 2-12 hours after the completion of&#xD;
             the coiling procedure and the ability to initiate the study drug 12 ± 8 hours after&#xD;
             the completion of aneurysm coiling procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. After recovering from anesthesia following the aneurysm coiling procedure, the patient&#xD;
             must remain a WFNS SAH grade ≤ 2 without evidence of a significant new focal&#xD;
             neurological deficit including monoparesis / monoplegia, hemiparesis / hemiplegia, or&#xD;
             receptive, expressive or global aphasia. New minor cranial nerve defect without any&#xD;
             other new findings is permissible. If an NIHSS score was obtained prior to the&#xD;
             aneurysm coiling procedure, a post-coiling (pre-enrollment) NIHSS score must not have&#xD;
             increased by ≥ 4 points and GCS score must not be decreased by ≥ 2 points. The&#xD;
             clinician at the local site should use their best clinical judgment as to whether a&#xD;
             significant neurological decline has occurred due to the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patient is willing and able to return for study follow-up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patient or their Legally Authorized Representative (LAR) has provided written informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Angio-negative SAH.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History or imaging suggesting that the current hemorrhage presentation is a recent&#xD;
             re-rupture of the aneurysm. Prior sentinel headache with negative CT or prior sentinel&#xD;
             headache where the patient did not seek medical attention does not exclude the&#xD;
             patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Surgical Clipping (or plan for clipping) of the ruptured aneurysm or any non- ruptured&#xD;
             aneurysm on the same admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Aneurysm is identified to be traumatic, mycotic, blister or fusiform type by catheter&#xD;
             DSA.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any intracranial stent placement or non-coil intra-aneurysmal device where dual-&#xD;
             antiplatelet therapy is needed during admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patient has additional aneurysm(s) that are untreated and could reasonably be&#xD;
             considered a possible alternate cause of the aSAH based on the observed bleeding&#xD;
             pattern. Adequate treatment of these aneurysms by coiling embolization would result in&#xD;
             the aneurysms no longer causing an exclusion. MRI may be used in some situations to&#xD;
             determine that the associated aneurysms did not rupture based on lack of blood seen&#xD;
             adjacent to the additional aneurysms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patient received heparin in any form within the last 100 days prior to current&#xD;
             presentation / admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Thrombocytopenia (platelet count less than 100,000 - assuming clumping has been ruled&#xD;
             out as a cause).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. New intraparenchymal hemorrhage or new infarction larger the 15cc in volume, or&#xD;
             significant increased mass effect as seen on the post-coiling, pre-enrollment head CT&#xD;
             when compared to baseline admission head CT. New hyperdensity on CT scan related to&#xD;
             contrast staining is not an exclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patient has a documented history of heparin induced thrombocytopenia (HIT).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patient developed SAH-induced cardiac stunning prior to enrollment, with an ejection&#xD;
             fraction &lt;30%, or requiring IV medications for blood pressure maintenance.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Concurrent significant intracranial pathology identified prior to enrollment,&#xD;
             including but not limited to, Moyamoya disease, high suspicion or documented CNS&#xD;
             vasculitis, severe fibromuscular dysplasia, arteriovenous malformation, arteriovenous&#xD;
             fistula, or malignant brain tumor.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Thrombolytic therapy within 24 hours prior to enrollment (rtPA, urokinase, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Plan for antiplatelet or oral anticoagulation therapy from the time of the coil&#xD;
             embolization procedure until 14 full days after enrollment. Antiplatelet therapy may&#xD;
             be resumed after the 14-day window. A single 325 mg Aspirin (or lower dose) given&#xD;
             during the coil embolization peri-procedural period is acceptable if this is the local&#xD;
             standard of care but should be documented.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Concomitant serious or uncontrolled disease such as severe infection, active (non-&#xD;
             remission) cancer, severe organ dysfunction (severe heart failure, severe chronic&#xD;
             kidney impairment requiring dialysis or severe chronic liver disease) or any&#xD;
             coagulopathy (including DIC or bleeding diathesis).&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Uncontrollable hypertension (&gt;180 systolic and/or &gt;110 diastolic) that is not&#xD;
             correctable prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Prior neurological disease/deficit or psychiatric disease that may continue to alter&#xD;
             the results of neuropsychological evaluation, such as dementia, Multiple sclerosis,&#xD;
             seizure disorder, severe traumatic brain injury, previous ruptured cerebral aneurysm&#xD;
             or active major depression. Childhood seizures that have resolved and no longer&#xD;
             require treatment are not part of this exclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Active Immunosuppression therapy including chronic corticosteroid usage.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. History of gastrointestinal hemorrhage or major systemic hemorrhage within 30 days&#xD;
             (including large flank or large retroperitoneal hematoma due to current admission&#xD;
             coiling procedure requiring treatment), hemoglobin less than 6 g/dL, INR ≥1.5 after&#xD;
             reversal of anticoagulants.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Major surgery (including open femoral, aortic, or carotid surgery) within previous 30&#xD;
             days.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Currently pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Enrollment in another research study that prescribes a therapeutic treatment that&#xD;
             differs from the local standard of care, or that would conflict with this study in&#xD;
             some other significant fashion. Registries or coil comparison studies are appropriate.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Robert F James, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Indiana University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>J Marc Simard, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Maryland, College Park</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>J Mocco, MD, MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kevin N Sheth, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Carolyn O'Neil</last_name>
    <phone>317-963-7293</phone>
    <email>caoneil@iu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale University</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Florida</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Terminated</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tallahassee Neurological Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tallahassee</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rush University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Terminated</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Indiana University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carolyn O'Neil, RN</last_name>
      <email>caoneil@iu.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bradley Bohnstedt, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Louisville</name>
      <address>
        <city>Louisville</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jerrad R Businger, MD</last_name>
      <phone>419-957-7202</phone>
      <email>j0busi01@exchange.louisville.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Ann Jerde, RN</last_name>
      <phone>502-438-8787</phone>
      <email>ann.jerde@louisville.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Michigan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Terminated</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mount Sinai Ichan School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical University of South Carolina</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charleston</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas Southwestern</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Simard JM, Schreibman D, Aldrich EF, Stallmeyer B, Le B, James RF, Beaty N. Unfractionated heparin: multitargeted therapy for delayed neurological deficits induced by subarachnoid hemorrhage. Neurocrit Care. 2010 Dec;13(3):439-49. doi: 10.1007/s12028-010-9435-1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20809188</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Al-Khindi T, Macdonald RL, Schweizer TA. Cognitive and functional outcome after aneurysmal subarachnoid hemorrhage. Stroke. 2010 Aug;41(8):e519-36. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.110.581975. Epub 2010 Jul 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20595669</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schweizer TA, Al-Khindi T, Macdonald RL. Mini-Mental State Examination versus Montreal Cognitive Assessment: rapid assessment tools for cognitive and functional outcome after aneurysmal subarachnoid hemorrhage. J Neurol Sci. 2012 May 15;316(1-2):137-40. doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2012.01.003. Epub 2012 Jan 26.</citation>
    <PMID>22280947</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wong GK, Lam SW, Ngai K, Wong A, Mok V, Poon WS. Quality of Life after Brain Injury (QOLIBRI) Overall Scale for patients after aneurysmal subarachnoid hemorrhage. J Clin Neurosci. 2014 Jun;21(6):954-6. doi: 10.1016/j.jocn.2013.09.010. Epub 2013 Nov 9.</citation>
    <PMID>24373816</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hong CM, Tosun C, Kurland DB, Gerzanich V, Schreibman D, Simard JM. Biomarkers as outcome predictors in subarachnoid hemorrhage--a systematic review. Biomarkers. 2014 Mar;19(2):95-108. doi: 10.3109/1354750X.2014.881418. Epub 2014 Feb 5. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24499240</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Romero FR, Bertolini Ede F, Figueiredo EG, Teixeira MJ. Serum C-reactive protein levels predict neurological outcome after aneurysmal subarachnoid hemorrhage. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2012 Mar;70(3):202-5.</citation>
    <PMID>22392113</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fountas KN, Tasiou A, Kapsalaki EZ, Paterakis KN, Grigorian AA, Lee GP, Robinson JS Jr. Serum and cerebrospinal fluid C-reactive protein levels as predictors of vasospasm in aneurysmal subarachnoid hemorrhage. Clinical article. Neurosurg Focus. 2009 May;26(5):E22. doi: 10.3171/2009.2.FOCUS08311.</citation>
    <PMID>19409001</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tosun C, Kurland DB, Mehta R, Castellani RJ, deJong JL, Kwon MS, Woo SK, Gerzanich V, Simard JM. Inhibition of the Sur1-Trpm4 channel reduces neuroinflammation and cognitive impairment in subarachnoid hemorrhage. Stroke. 2013 Dec;44(12):3522-8. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.113.002904. Epub 2013 Oct 10.</citation>
    <PMID>24114458</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Simard JM, Aldrich EF, Schreibman D, James RF, Polifka A, Beaty N. Low-dose intravenous heparin infusion in patients with aneurysmal subarachnoid hemorrhage: a preliminary assessment. J Neurosurg. 2013 Dec;119(6):1611-9. doi: 10.3171/2013.8.JNS1337. Epub 2013 Sep 13.</citation>
    <PMID>24032706</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>James RF, Shao EY, Page PS, Nazar RG, Martin LB, Dvorak J, Kanaan HK, Daniels MJ, Craycroft J, Rai SN, Everhart DE, Simard JM. Low-dose IV heparin preserves cognitive function in aneurysmal subarachnoid hemorrhage patients. [Unpublished Data]. Presented at AANS 82nd Annual Scientific Meeting. April 5-9, 2014. San Francisco, CA; Abstract #16572.</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 13, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 15, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 17, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Indiana University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Robert F. James</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Neurosurgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>aneurysmal subarachnoid hemorrhage</keyword>
  <keyword>unfractionated heparin</keyword>
  <keyword>neurobehavioral manifestations</keyword>
  <keyword>delayed ischemic neurological deficits</keyword>
  <keyword>cerebral aneurysm</keyword>
  <keyword>coil embolization</keyword>
  <keyword>Montreal Cognitive Assessment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Subarachnoid Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Intracranial Aneurysm</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neurobehavioral Manifestations</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vasospasm, Intracranial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Aneurysm</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thrombocytopenia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heparin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Calcium heparin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>There is no plan to share data other than through publication or requests to Robert James by other investigators.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

