<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02509416</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>14-0604-2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02509416</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Rapid Assessment of Trainee Endoscopy Skills (RATES) Study Two</brief_title>
  <acronym>RATES 2</acronym>
  <official_title>Rapid Assessment of Trainee Endoscopy Skills (RATES) Study Two: A Prospective Multicenter Study Evaluating Competence in Endoscopic Ultrasound and Endoscopic Retrograde Cholangiopancreatogram Among Advanced Endoscopy Trainees</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Colorado, Denver</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Columbia University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Carolinas Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Cleveland Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Duke University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Emory University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Geisinger Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>St. Luke's Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Feinberg School of Medicine, Northwestern University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Stanford University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Stony Brook University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospitals Cleveland Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Alberta</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of California, Los Angeles</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Florida</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Massachusetts, Worcester</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Michigan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The University of Texas Health Science Center at San Antonio</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Texas</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Virginia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Brigham and Women's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Virginia Mason Hospital/Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Henry Ford Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Mayo Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of California, Davis</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Indiana University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Kansas</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Wisconsin, Madison</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Washington University School of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of North Carolina</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Colorado, Denver</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The establishment of a number of training programs in therapeutic endoscopy, standardization&#xD;
      of the performance of endoscopic ultrasound (EUS) and endoscopy retrograde&#xD;
      cholangiopancreatography (ERCP) and definition of competence is of paramount importance. The&#xD;
      length of training and minimum number of procedures, requisite theoretical learning and&#xD;
      methodology to define competence in EUS and ERCP are not well defined. The investigators&#xD;
      research has demonstrated that individuals in training acquire skills at different rates and&#xD;
      the number of procedures completed alone is a suboptimal marker for competency in a given&#xD;
      procedure. Hence, emphasis needs to be shifted away from the number of procedures performed&#xD;
      to performance metrics with well-defined and validated thresholds of performance. Multicenter&#xD;
      prospective data are needed to help guide development of competency based medical education&#xD;
      that define learning curves in EUS and ERCP and set evidence-based benchmarks required to&#xD;
      achieve competence using a validated competency assessment tool.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: The central hypothesis is that a validated EUS and ERCP competency assessment&#xD;
      tool will allow for reliable and generalizable standardized learning curves, competency&#xD;
      benchmarks and creation of a centralized national database that compares a trainee's&#xD;
      performance amongst peers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Competency-based medical education and milestones: Given the increasing emphasis on quality&#xD;
      metrics and competency in health care, the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical&#xD;
      Education (ACGME) recently announced plans to replace their current reporting system in 2014&#xD;
      with the Next Accreditation System (NAS). This reporting system focused on: 1) ensuring that&#xD;
      milestones are reached at various points in training, 2) ensuring that competence is achieved&#xD;
      by all trainees, and 3) making certain that these assessments are documented by their&#xD;
      programs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Learning curves and competence in EUS: EUS is a vital tool in the diagnosis and staging of&#xD;
      gastrointestinal and certain non-gastrointestinal malignancies and diseases. EUS is operator&#xD;
      dependent and training in EUS requires the development of technical and cognitive skills&#xD;
      beyond that required for standard endoscopic procedures. It is intuitive that the quality of&#xD;
      EUS in provision of patient care is directly proportional to the training, skill and&#xD;
      experience of the endosonographer. Unfortunately, the intensity and length of training and&#xD;
      minimum number of procedures required, requisite curriculum and extent of theoretical&#xD;
      learning, and methodology to define competence are not well defined. There are limited data&#xD;
      on learning curves in EUS imaging.Based on expert opinion, the American Society of&#xD;
      Gastrointestinal Endoscopy (ASGE) recommends a minimum of 150 total supervised procedures, 75&#xD;
      of which have a pancreatobiliary indication and 50 cases of fine needle aspiration (FNA) (25&#xD;
      of which are pancreatic FNA) before competency can be determined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Similar guidelines were recently proposed by the British Society of Gastroenterology (BSG)13&#xD;
      and the European Society of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy. However, these guidelines have not&#xD;
      been validated. This does not account for the different rates at which people learn and in&#xD;
      fact, many experts believe that the majority of trainees will require double the number of&#xD;
      proposed procedures to achieve competency in EUS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Learning curves and competence in ERCP: ERCP is an effective modality in the evaluation and&#xD;
      management of pancreatobiliary diseases. This procedure can be technically demanding and&#xD;
      associated with a wide range of adverse events. Technically failed ERCP may result in&#xD;
      complications, need for additional procedures and their associated costs. Similar to EUS,&#xD;
      ERCP is operator dependent and requires acquisition of certain technical and cognitive&#xD;
      skills. There are limited data on learning curves and competence in ERCP, a cannulation rate&#xD;
      of &gt;80% (with some suggesting &gt;90%) has been considered a surrogate for trainee competency.&#xD;
      The ASGE recommends a minimum of 180 total procedures, the majority of which are therapeutic&#xD;
      before competency can be achieved. However, this threshold is based predominantly on biliary&#xD;
      cannulation success rate and does not take into account procedure complexity and the&#xD;
      different rates at which people learn. It is also important to note that none of the previous&#xD;
      studies have evaluated learning curves and competency in other quality indicators such as&#xD;
      successful stone extraction, traversing and dilating a stricture, stent placement to name a&#xD;
      few.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Competency assessment tools: Previous competency assessment tools have focused primarily on a&#xD;
      limited number of motor skills involved in EUS and ERCP with no procedure-related cognitive&#xD;
      skill assessment. The investigators have designed a prospective comprehensive competency&#xD;
      assessment tool using validated benchmarks to define competency thresholds. The EUS and ERCP&#xD;
      Skills Assessment Tool (TEESAT) can be used in a continuous fashion throughout the duration&#xD;
      of training to grade technical and cognitive skills in EUS and ERCP in a balanced manner.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Significance, Innovation and Impact on Training and Education with the launch of the ACGME's&#xD;
      NAS, advanced endoscopy training programs should utilize competency based medical education&#xD;
      and demonstrate that advanced endoscopy trainees (AETs) have attained the technical and&#xD;
      cognitive skills required for safe and effective unsupervised practice in advanced endoscopy.&#xD;
      Based on the investigators research, the investigators can draw two conclusions: a)&#xD;
      individuals in training in any technical procedure acquire skills at different rates and&#xD;
      emphasis needs to be shifted away from the number of procedures performed to performance&#xD;
      metrics with defined and validated competency thresholds of performance and b) current&#xD;
      guidelines of performing 150 EUS and 180 ERCPs are inadequate to achieve competence in EUS&#xD;
      and ERCP, respectively. With the expanding indications and applications of EUS and ERCP and&#xD;
      establishment of a number of &quot;third tier&quot; training programs in advanced endoscopy,&#xD;
      standardization of the performance of EUS and ERCP and definition of competence and training&#xD;
      among AETs is of paramount importance. The potential impacts of this study's results are&#xD;
      multifold: i) facilitate the ability of training programs to evolve with the new ACGME/NAS&#xD;
      reporting requirements, (ii) help program directors/trainers and trainees identify specific&#xD;
      skill deficiencies in training and allowing for tailored, individualized remediation, (iii)&#xD;
      create a centralized national database that would allow generation of &quot;on-demand&quot; detailed&#xD;
      reports on how individual trainees are progressing compared with their peers across the&#xD;
      nation, (iv) establish reliable and generalizable standardized learning curves (milestones)&#xD;
      and competency benchmarks that national GI societies and training programs can use to develop&#xD;
      credentialing guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      APPROACH AND RESEARCH STRATEGY Setting and Subject Recruitment: Program directors and AETs at&#xD;
      all advanced endoscopy programs registered with the ASGE will be invited to participate in&#xD;
      this study and will be considered as study participants. AETs will complete a questionnaire&#xD;
      to determine baseline characteristics and prior experience with EUS and ERCP. AETs' prior&#xD;
      experience with EUS and ERCP will not be an exclusion criterion for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Competency assessment tools: Previous competency assessment tools have focused primarily on a&#xD;
      limited number of motor skills involved in EUS and ERCP with no procedure-related cognitive&#xD;
      skill assessment. The investigators have designed a prospective comprehensive competency&#xD;
      assessment tool using validated benchmarks to define competency thresholds. The EUS and ERCP&#xD;
      Skills Assessment Tool (TEESAT) can be used in a continuous fashion throughout the duration&#xD;
      of training to grade technical and cognitive skills in EUS and ERCP in a balanced manner.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Learning curves during independent practice and Quality Indicators in EUS and ERCP: The ASGE&#xD;
      and ACG Task Force on Quality in Endoscopy recently published documents highlighting quality&#xD;
      indicators in EUS and ERCP. Impact of structured feedback on learning curves, specifically&#xD;
      related to quality metrics, during the first year of independent practice for AETs has not&#xD;
      been evaluated. This is an important component of construct validity for the proposed&#xD;
      assessment tool and novel web-based comprehensive data collection and reporting, was&#xD;
      identified as a priority research question by the Task Force. The defined performance targets&#xD;
      and quality metrics will serve as benchmarks for analysis during training and first year of&#xD;
      independent practice.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 15, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 15, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall competency</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of advanced endoscopy trainees (AETs) that achieve overall competency in EUS and ERCP using a standardized competency assessment tool with a comprehensive data collection and reporting system.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of advanced endoscopy fellows that reach competency</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Creation of a nationalized database utilizing the comprehensive assessment tool as to have advanced endoscopy fellows compare themselves to the national average in EUS and ERCP exams.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">37</enrollment>
  <condition>Competency Based Education</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Program directors and AETs at all advanced endoscopy programs registered with the ASGE will&#xD;
        be invited to participate in this study and will be considered as study participants.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Program directors and AETs at all advanced endoscopy programs registered with the ASGE&#xD;
             will be invited to participate in this study and will be considered as study&#xD;
             participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  N/A&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sachin Wani, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Colorado, Denver</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 1, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 24, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 28, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>endoscopic ultrasound</keyword>
  <keyword>endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography</keyword>
  <keyword>competency</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

