<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04127110</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EORTC-1825</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2019-003862-41</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04127110</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Activity of Lorlatinib Based on ALK Resistance Mutations Detected on Blood in ALK Positive NSCLC Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>ALKALINE</acronym>
  <official_title>Activity of Lorlatinib Based on ALK Resistance Mutations on Blood in ALK Positive NSCLC Patients Previously Treated With 2nd Generation ALK Inhibitor</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>European Organisation for Research and Treatment of Cancer - EORTC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>European Organisation for Research and Treatment of Cancer - EORTC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study includes patients diagnosed with a metastatic non small cell lung cancer (NSCLC)&#xD;
      with anaplastic lymphoma kinase (ALK) translocation. The standard treatment for patients with&#xD;
      metastatic non small cell lung cancer with ALK translocation is represented by personalized&#xD;
      treatment with drugs called ALK inhibitors. During the treatment with an ALK inhibitor, the&#xD;
      tumour can start to grow again, because the tumour adapts to the drug and develops escape&#xD;
      mechanisms, becoming resistant. At the tumour cells level, the mechanisms underlying&#xD;
      resistance can include the development of other alterations, mainly mutations, including in&#xD;
      the ALK gene. The alterations that developed depend on the drug the tumour has been exposed&#xD;
      to.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The alterations can be identified by analysing tumour tissue obtained through a biopsy,&#xD;
      however, repeating a tumour biopsy is difficult and risky and might not be able to provide&#xD;
      sufficient tissue for the test. Therefore in the last years, new tests have been developed to&#xD;
      identify the mutations in the blood.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lorlatinib is a drug that inhibits ALK and has already been identified to be able to control&#xD;
      the tumour growth when ALK mutations are identified and is already approved as standard&#xD;
      treatment after progression to a previous treatment with ALK inhibitors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to identify which patient populations may benefit most from&#xD;
      treatment with lorlatinib, based on the alterations found in their genes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 17, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months after enrolment of last patient</time_frame>
    <description>Progression Free Survival Rate at 12 months (PFSR-12) is defined as the proportion of patients at 12 months who are alive and non-progressing.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months after enrolment of last patient</time_frame>
    <description>OS is defined as the time interval between the date of enrolment and the date of death from any cause. If no event has been observed, then the patient is censored at the last date known to be alive.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months after enrolment of last patient</time_frame>
    <description>Overall Response Rate (ORR) is an overall rate including patients with documented complete response (CR) or partial response (PR)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Response (DOR)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months after enrolment of last patient</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of Response will only be reported for patients who achieved either CR or PR. The duration of response is measured from the time measurement criteria are met for CR/PR (whichever is first recorded) until the first date that recurrent or progressive disease is objectively documented. If progression has not been observed, the patient will be censored at the date of the last follow up examination. In the event of death without progression competing risk method will be used.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CNS Overall Response Rate (CNS-ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months after enrolment of last patient</time_frame>
    <description>CNS Overall Response Rate (CNS ORR) is an overall rate including patients with documented complete response (CNS-CR) or partial response (CNS-PR)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety profile according to NCI CTCAE v.5</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after last dose</time_frame>
    <description>Safety profile according to NCI CTCAE v.5</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Non Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lorlatinib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Lorlatinib is administered orally at the daily dose of 100 mg (four tablets of 25 mg).&#xD;
Lorlatinib will be taken continuously on a daily basis until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, occurrence of any withdrawal criterion, whichever comes first.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lorlatinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Lorlatinib is administered orally at the daily dose of 100 mg (four tablets of 25 mg).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lorlatinib</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        A) Enrolment in optional prospective sub-study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The patient could be enrolled during the ongoing response to second-generation anaplastic&#xD;
        lymphoma kinase (ALK) inhibitor if the following conditions are fulfilled:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has received at least 6 months of second generation anaplastic lymphoma&#xD;
             kinase - tyrosine kinase inhibitor (ALK-TKI) therapy (if crizotinib-pretreated) OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has received at least 12 months of second generation ALK-TKI therapy (if&#xD;
             crizotinib-naïve)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is willing and able to comply with the protocol for the duration of the study&#xD;
             including scheduled visits and examinations including follow up&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Before patient registration, written informed consent must be given according to the&#xD;
             International Conference on Harmonisation-Good Clinical Practice (ICH/GCP), and&#xD;
             national/local regulations&#xD;
&#xD;
        B) Enrolment in ALKALINE phase II study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of NSCLC with ALK rearrangement,&#xD;
             assessed by fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) assay (Abbott Molecular Inc) or&#xD;
             by Immunohistochemistry (IHC) (Ventana Inc) approved by food and drug administration&#xD;
             (FDA)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stage IIIB (not eligible for local therapy) or stage IV (according to Union for&#xD;
             International Cancer Control (UICC) tumor lymph node metastasis (TNM) staging v8.0)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  World health organization (WHO) performance status (WHO PS) of 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous treatment with at least one 2nd-generation ALK inhibitor. The 2nd-generation&#xD;
             ALK TKI (ceritinib, alectinib, brigatinib) should be the latest therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progressive disease during treatment with 2nd-generation ALK inhibitor prior to the&#xD;
             administration of lorlatinib&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease according to Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors (RECIST)&#xD;
             version 1.1 by computed tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of&#xD;
             Chest/Abdomen/Pelvis and brain MRI performed within 28 days prior to study enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Note: At least one measurable extracranial lesion is required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Archival tissue from primary tumour or metastatic site, if available, and blood&#xD;
             samples&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Note: if blood samples cannot be collected (patient's refusal or any other&#xD;
                  reason), patient will not be eligible for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treated and/or untreated brain or leptomeningeal metastases will be allowed if&#xD;
             asymptomatic and/or controlled (stable dose of steroids 7 days before the beginning of&#xD;
             lorlatinib treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate bone marrow and organ function defined as following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute Neutrophil Count (ANC) ≥ 1.5 x 10E9/L;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥ 100 x 10E9/L;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dL;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum total amylase ≤1.5 Upper Limit Normal (ULN);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum lipase ≤1.5 ULN;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine ≤1.5 x ULN or estimated creatinine clearance &gt; 30 mL/min - Total&#xD;
                  serum bilirubin ≤1.5 x ULN or direct bilirubin ≤ ULN for patients with total&#xD;
                  bilirubin levels &gt; 1.5 x ULN; for patients with Gilbert's disease total bilirubin&#xD;
                  may be &gt; 1.5 x ULN, however direct bilirubin must be normal;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate Aminotransferase (AST) and Alanine Aminotransferase (ALT) ≤2.5 x ULN&#xD;
                  (≤5.0 x ULN if there is liver metastases involvement);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child bearing potential (WOCBP) must have a negative serum pregnancy test&#xD;
             within 3 days prior to the first dose of lorlatinib.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Note: women of childbearing potential are defined as premenopausal females&#xD;
                  capable of becoming pregnant (i.e. females who have had any evidence of menses in&#xD;
                  the past 12 months, with the exception of those who had prior hysterectomy).&#xD;
                  However, women who have been amenorrheic for 12 or more months are still&#xD;
                  considered to be of childbearing potential if the amenorrhea is possibly due to&#xD;
                  prior chemotherapy, antioestrogens, low body weight, ovarian suppression or other&#xD;
                  reasons.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients of childbearing / reproductive potential should use highly effective birth&#xD;
             control measures, as defined by the investigator, during the study treatment period&#xD;
             and for at least 5 weeks after the last dose of lorlatinib for female patients and for&#xD;
             at least 14 weeks after the last dose of lorlatinib for male patients. A highly&#xD;
             effective method of birth control is defined as a method, which results in a low&#xD;
             failure rate (i.e. less than 1% per year) when used consistently and correctly. Such&#xD;
             methods include:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Combined (oestrogen and progestogen containing) hormonal contraception associated&#xD;
                  with inhibition of ovulation (oral, intravaginal, transdermal)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Progestogen-only hormonal contraception associated with inhibition of ovulation&#xD;
                  (oral, injectable, implantable)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intrauterine device (IUD)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intrauterine hormone-releasing system (IUS)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilateral tubal occlusion&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Vasectomized partner&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Sexual abstinence (the reliability of sexual abstinence needs to be evaluated in&#xD;
                  relation to the duration of the clinical trial and the preferred and usual&#xD;
                  lifestyle of the patient)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Note: Lorlatinib can induce Cytochrome P450 3A4/5 (CYP3A4/5) both in vitro and in&#xD;
                  vivo. Most hormonal contraceptives are CYP3A substrates, therefore, if this&#xD;
                  method of contraception is chosen it must be used along with condom (male or&#xD;
                  female condom) due to the risk of contraception failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects who are breast feeding should discontinue nursing prior to the first&#xD;
             dose of study treatment and until 7 days after the last dose of lorlatinib.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is willing and able to comply with the protocol for the duration of the study&#xD;
             including undergoing treatment and scheduled visits and examinations including follow&#xD;
             up.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Before patient registration, written informed consent must be given according to&#xD;
             ICH/GCP, and national/local regulations.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Spinal cord compression. Patients who received adequate treatment (surgery or&#xD;
             radiotherapy) and has adequate control of the pain and stabilization and/or recovery&#xD;
             of neurological symptoms/function for the 3 weeks prior to study entry are allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery within 4 weeks prior to study enrolment. Complete wound healing from&#xD;
             major surgery must have occurred 3 weeks before the first dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minor surgical procedures (including port insertion, uncomplicated tooth extractions)&#xD;
             without complete wound healing at the latest 1 week before the first dose of study&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiation therapy within 2 weeks of study entry. Exception are:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Palliative radiation (≤10 fractions) is allowed if completed at least 48 hours&#xD;
                  prior to study enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stereotactic or small field brain irradiation is allowed if completed at least 2&#xD;
                  weeks prior to study enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Whole brain radiation is allowed if completed at least 4 weeks prior to study&#xD;
                  enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any systemic anti-cancer therapy or an investigational drug treatment completed within&#xD;
             5 half-lives prior to start lorlatinib (in case of clinically meaningful risk of&#xD;
             tumour flare according to investigator's assessment, discussion with EORTC is required&#xD;
             before enrolment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any unresolved toxicities from prior systemic therapy, including haematological&#xD;
             toxicities, greater than International Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events&#xD;
             (CTCAE) v5.0 grade 2 at the time of study enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection requiring therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known active hepatitis B (HBV) or hepatitis C (HCV). Active HBV is defined as a known&#xD;
             positive hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) result. Active HCV is defined by a known&#xD;
             positive Hep C antibody (Ab) result and known quantitative HCV ribonucleic acid (RNA)&#xD;
             result greater than the lower limits of detection of the assay&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), or acquired immunodeficiency syndrome&#xD;
             (AIDS)-related illness Note: Testing for HIV must be performed at sites where mandated&#xD;
             locally&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following cardiac criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clinically significant cardiovascular disease (that is active or occurred &lt;3&#xD;
                  months prior to enrolment): cerebral vascular accident/stroke, myocardial&#xD;
                  infarction, unstable angina, congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association&#xD;
                  Classification Class ≥ II), second-degree or third-degree atrioventricular (AV)&#xD;
                  block (unless paced) or any AV block with PR &gt;220 msec&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ongoing cardiac dysrhythmias of National Cancer Institute (NCI) CTCAE Grade ≥2,&#xD;
                  uncontrolled atrial fibrillation of any grade, bradycardia defined as &lt;50 bpm&#xD;
                  (unless patient is otherwise healthy such as long-distance runners, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Abnormal Left Ventricular Ejection Fraction (LVEF): LVEF &lt;50% (assessed by&#xD;
                  multigated acquisition (MUGA) scan or echocardiogram (ECHO))&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of interstitial lung disease (ILD) or history of (non-infectious) pneumonitis&#xD;
             that required oral or intravenous (IV) steroids (other than Chronic obstructive&#xD;
             pulmonary disease (COPD) exacerbation) or current pneumonitis or current evidence of&#xD;
             interstitial lung disease. Patients with history of prior radiation pneumonitis are&#xD;
             not excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any serious or uncontrolled acute or chronic medical or psychiatric condition,&#xD;
             including recent (within the past year) or active suicidal ideation or behaviour,&#xD;
             chronic alcoholism, drug addiction, or laboratory abnormality that may increase the&#xD;
             risk associated with study participation or investigational product administration or&#xD;
             may interfere with the interpretation of study results and, in the judgment of the&#xD;
             investigator, would make the patient not eligible for this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hereditary problems of galactose intolerance, total lactase deficiency, or&#xD;
             glucose-galactose malabsorption&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to swallow and/or retain oral tablets or impaired gastrointestinal function&#xD;
             or disease that may significantly alter the absorption of lorlatinib (e.g., ulcerative&#xD;
             diseases, uncontrolled vomiting, malabsorption syndrome, small bowel resection with&#xD;
             decreased intestinal absorption)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of active hematologic or primary solid tumour malignancy (other than&#xD;
             completely resected non-melanoma skin cancer, successfully treated in situ carcinoma&#xD;
             for example in situ cervical cancer, completely resected and successfully treated&#xD;
             papillary thyroid cancer, or localized and presumed cured prostate cancer) within the&#xD;
             last 3 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hypersensitivity to excipients of Lorlatinib (please refer to Summary of&#xD;
             Product Characteristics - SmPC)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients currently receiving (or unable to stop use at least 3 plasma half-lives of&#xD;
             the strong CYP3A4/5 inducer before lorlatinib treatment is started) medications or&#xD;
             herbal supplements known ti be strong inducers of the cytochrome P450 (CYP) 3A4/5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition potentially&#xD;
             hampering compliance with the study protocol and follow-up schedule; those conditions&#xD;
             should be discussed with the patient before registration in the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
        Important note: All eligibility criteria must be adhered to, in case of deviation a&#xD;
        discussion with Headquarters and study coordinator is mandatory.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anne-Marie Dingemans, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Erasmus MC, Rotterdam, Netherlands</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Laura Mezquita, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hospital Clinic Universitari de Barcelona, Spain</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>EORTC HQ</last_name>
    <phone>+32 2 774 1611</phone>
    <email>1825@eortc.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut Jules Bordet-Hopital Universitaire ULB</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brussels</city>
        <zip>1000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Thierry Berghmans, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cliniques Universitaires Saint-Luc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brussels</city>
        <zip>BE 1200</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Thierry Pieters, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitair Ziekenhuis Antwerpen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edegem</city>
        <zip>BE 2650</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jo Raskin, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU-UCL Namur - CHU Mont Godinne - UCL Namur</name>
      <address>
        <city>Yvoir</city>
        <zip>5530</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sebahat Ocak, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Avignon</name>
      <address>
        <city>Avignon</city>
        <zip>84902</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nicolas Cloarec, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU de Brest</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brest</city>
        <zip>29200</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Renaud Descourt, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hopitalier Intercommunal De Creteil</name>
      <address>
        <city>Créteil</city>
        <zip>94010</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gaelle Rousseau-Bussac, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>King Hussein Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Amman</city>
        <country>Jordan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kamal Al-Rabi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Netherlands Cancer Institute-Antoni Van Leeuwenhoekziekenhuis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Amsterdam</city>
        <zip>1066 CX</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joop de Langen, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Erasmus MC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rotterdam</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anne-Marie Dingemans, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oslo University Hospital - Radiumhospitalet</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oslo</city>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Aslaug Helland, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut Catala d'Oncologia - ICO L'Hospitalet - Hospital Duran i Reynals</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hospitalet De Llobregat</city>
        <state>Barcelona</state>
        <zip>08908</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Samuel Ernest Nadal Alforja, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clinic Universitari de Barcelona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Laura Mezquita, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital De La Santa Creu I Sant Pau</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gabriela Sullivan Ivana, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut Catala d'Oncologia - ICO Badalona - Hospital Germans Trias i Pujol</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Enric Carcereny, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital General Universitario Gregorio Maranon</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28007</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Antonio Calles, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinica Universidad de Navarra - Clinica Universitaria De Navarra</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ignacio Gil-Bazo, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario 12 De Octubre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Santiago, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Santiago Ponce Aix, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Ramon y Cajal</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Pilar Garrido Lopez, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinica Universidad de Navarra - Clinica Universitaria De Navarra</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pamplona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ignacio Gil-Bazo, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Jordan</country>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
    <country>Norway</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 14, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 14, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 15, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Anaplastic lymphoma kinase (ALK) positive non small cell lung cancer (NSCLC)</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

