<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04111965</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SOPH176-1218/I-II</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04111965</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Trial to Compare the Safety and Efficacy of Nanodrop®</brief_title>
  <acronym>PRO-176/I</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase I-II Clinical Trial to Compare the Safety and Efficacy of Nanodrop® Against Systane® Balance in the Treatment of Dry Eye Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Laboratorios Sophia S.A de C.V.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Laboratorios Sophia S.A de C.V.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Study design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase I-II clinical trial, comparative, non-inferiority with active control, parallel groups,&#xD;
      double blind with randomisation. Safety analysis when completing the visits of the first 12&#xD;
      subjects of the Nanodrop® group, if there are less than 20% of unexpected Events (EA),&#xD;
      related to the research product, recruitment is continued until the sample is completed for&#xD;
      efficacy analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      objectives Security: Evaluate the safety of the ophthalmic application of Nanodrop® by&#xD;
      quantifying the incidence of unexpected Adverse Events (EA) related to the research product&#xD;
      (PI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Effectiveness: Demonstrate the non-inferiority of Nanodrop® compared to Systane® Balance, in&#xD;
      the efficacy of the treatment of patients with dry eye, by means of the Ocular Surface&#xD;
      Disease Index (OSDI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Security:&#xD;
&#xD;
      H0 = Nanodrop® is safe in its ophthalmic application as it presents an incidence of&#xD;
      unexpected adverse events related to the research drug, less than 20% of the population of&#xD;
      Nanodrop® safety group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      H1 = Nanodrop® is not safe in its ophthalmic application, as it presents an incidence of&#xD;
      unexpected adverse events related to the research drug, exceeding 20% of the population of&#xD;
      Nanodrop® safety group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Effectiveness:&#xD;
&#xD;
      H0 = Nanodrop® is lower than Systane® Balance by more than 5 points in the OSDI test score.&#xD;
&#xD;
      H1 = Nanodrop® is lower than Systane® Balance by 5 points or less in the OSDI test score.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Number of subjects: n = 126 evaluable subjects 63 evaluable subjects per group (both eyes).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main inclusion criteria: Dry eye diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Duration of intervention treatment: 28 days Approximate duration of the subject in the study:&#xD;
      35 days&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Phase I-II clinical trial, comparative, non-inferiority with active control, double blind with randomisation. Safety analysis when completing the visits of the first 12 subjects</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Masking will be done through the primary and secondary packaging.&#xD;
They will be identified by means of identical tags. Which, in compliance with current and applicable regulations, must contain at least:&#xD;
Name, address and telephone number of the sponsor.&#xD;
Pharmaceutical form and route of administration.&#xD;
Lot Number.&#xD;
Legend &quot;Exclusively for clinical studies&quot;&#xD;
Date of Expiry.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ocular Surface Disease Index (OSDI)</measure>
    <time_frame>will be evaluated at the end of the treatment (day 29, final visit)</time_frame>
    <description>OSDI is a questionnaire designed to measure eye surface irritation with Rasch analysis to produce estimates on a linear interval scale (ratings: 0-100). Similar to the index for ocular surface diseases, the ocular comfort index (OCI) evaluates symptoms. It contains items that focus on the discomfort associated with alterations of the ocular surface. Each of these questions has two parts, which concern separately the frequency and severity of symptoms.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of unexpected events related to the research product</measure>
    <time_frame>during the 29 days of evaluation, including the safety call</time_frame>
    <description>the adverse events will be evaluated with a scale of Present / Absent, it is a nominal variable, the normal value is absent</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>visual acuity (VA)</measure>
    <time_frame>will be evaluated at the end of the treatment (day 29, final visit)</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity (VA) is a test of visual function. It will be evaluated at baseline, without refractive correction with the Snellen chart.Which will be located in a place with adequate lighting, natural or artificial and at a distance of 3meters from the subject to be evaluated. The snellen chart consists of a booklet with 11 lines composed of letters, each line has a different size and a different weighting. the subject is placed at a safe distance and the contralateral eye to which it will be evaluated is covered, then the examiner detects until the line can clearly see the letters given he or she a score, the normal score for a VA is 20/20.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Epithelial Defects (ED) Fluorescein stain</measure>
    <time_frame>will be evaluated at the end of the treatment (day 29, final visit)</time_frame>
    <description>The epithelial defects will be evaluated by fluorescein, it is a discrete variable that will be realized by direct observation, It will be qualified according to the Eye Staining Rating (CTO) of the International Alliance of Clinical Collaboration of Sjögren (SICCA).According to the CTO, grade 0 corresponds to the absence of dotted epithelial erosions (EEP); Grade 1 is defined as the presence of 1-5 EEP; Grade 2 corresponds to 6-30 EEP; and&gt; 30 EEP will be classified as grade 3. Additionally a qualification point will be added if: 1) EEP is presented in the central portion of the cornea with a diameter of 4mm; 2) filaments are observed and 3) confluent staining patches are observed, including linear stains</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>epithelial Defects (ED) Green lissamine</measure>
    <time_frame>will be evaluated at the end of the treatment (day 29, final visit)</time_frame>
    <description>The epithelial defects will be evaluated by green lissamine, it is a discrete variable that will be realized by direct observation, It will be qualified according to the Eye Staining Rating (CTO) of the International Alliance of Clinical Collaboration of Sjögren (SICCA). In the CTO, grade 0 is defined as the presence of 0 to 9 lissamine green staining points in the interpalpebral bulbar conjunctiva (qualifying the temporal and nasal portion separately); grade 1 is defined by the presence of 10 to 32 points; grade 2 by 33 to 100; and grade 3 for&gt; 100 points. Due to the difficulty of counting individual points in a moving eye, any area ≥ 4mm2 of confluent points is considered&gt; 100 points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of expected adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>will be evaluated at the end of the treatment (day 29, final visit)</time_frame>
    <description>the adverse events will be evaluated with a scale of Present / Absent, it is a nominal variable, the normal value is absent</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tear breakup time (TBUT)</measure>
    <time_frame>will be evaluated at the end of the treatment (day 29, final visit)</time_frame>
    <description>brake up time of the tear film One of the first aspects of the tear film that changes when there is an alteration to the ocular surface is its stability. In general, if the corneal or conjunctival surface is damaged, it is unlikely that a stable tear film can be maintained.&#xD;
The most common method to evaluate tear film stability is the evaluation of TBUT with fluorescein. Once the fluorescein is instilled, with the cobalt blue filter the patient is asked not to blink after having blinked 1 to 2 times. The colored precorneal fluorescein layer will change to less fluorescent or non-fluorescent regions. The time that elapses from the last blink to the appearance of these regions is the TBUT. It will be reported in seconds.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">126</enrollment>
  <condition>Dry Eye</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Nanodrop® (PRO-176)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>- Nanodrop®. 0.6% propylene glycol. Ophthalmic emulsion Laboratorios Sophia, S.A. from C.V. Route of administration: Ophthalmic.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Systane® Balance</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Systane® Balance. 0.6% propylene glycol. Ophthalmic emulsion Alcon Laboratories, Inc.&#xD;
Route of administration: Ophthalmic.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nanodrop®</intervention_name>
    <description>minimum to meet 1 drop 4 times a day, both eyes</description>
    <arm_group_label>Nanodrop® (PRO-176)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PRO-176</other_name>
    <other_name>Propylene glycol 0.6%</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Systane Balance</intervention_name>
    <description>minimum to meet 1 drop 4 times a day, both eyes</description>
    <arm_group_label>Systane® Balance</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Propylene glycol 0.6%</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have the ability to voluntarily grant your signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Power and willingness to comply with scheduled visits treatment plan and other study&#xD;
             procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be willing to modify the activities of your lifestyle.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be of legal age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of reproductive age should ensure continuation (initiated ≥ 30 days prior to the&#xD;
             signing of the Informed Consent Form or ICF) of using a hormonal contraceptive method&#xD;
             or intrauterine device (IUD) during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Present a dry eye diagnosis, defined by:&#xD;
&#xD;
        OSDI ≥ 13 points plus one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Corneal staining with more than 5 sites&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Conjunctival staining with more than 9 sites&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breakup Time of lacrimal film (BUT) &lt;10 seconds:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the case of women: being pregnant, breastfeeding or planning to get pregnant within&#xD;
             the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have participated in another clinical research study ≤ 30 days before the scrutiny&#xD;
             visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having previously participated in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Present a Better Corrected Visual Acuity (MAVC) of 20/200 or worse in one of the eyes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Present an added ophthalmological diagnosis of:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Allergic, viral or bacterial conjunctivitis. Anterior blepharitis. Demodex. Eye parasitic&#xD;
        infections. Unresolved eye trauma. Healing diseases of the ocular surface. Corneal or&#xD;
        conjunctival ulcers. Filamentous keratitis. Neurotrophic keratitis. Bullous keratopathy.&#xD;
        Neoplastic diseases on the ocular surface or annexes. Diseases with fibrovascular&#xD;
        proliferations on the conjunctival and / or corneal surface.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Diseases in the retina and / or posterior segment that require treatment or threaten the&#xD;
        visual prognosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Glaucoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a management of your dry eye that requires the implementation of stage 2&#xD;
             treatments of the recommendations in the treatment and management by stages for the&#xD;
             dry eye disease from the Dry Eye Workshop II of The Tear Film and Ocular Surface&#xD;
             Society (DEWS II, TFOS).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a history of drug addiction or current drug dependence or within the last two&#xD;
             years prior to the signing of the Informed Consent Form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a history of ocular surgical procedure within the last 3 months prior to the&#xD;
             signing of the Informed Consent Form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be a user of soft or hard contact lenses. You can enter if you can suspend your use&#xD;
             during the study, you must turn 15 days without using the contact lens before&#xD;
             inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having another medical condition, acute or chronic, that at the discretion of the&#xD;
             researcher could increase the risk associated with participation in the study or&#xD;
             administration of the product under investigation, or that could interfere with the&#xD;
             interpretation of the results of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Present known hypersensitivity to the components of the products under investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be or have an immediate family member (for example: spouse, parent / legal guardian,&#xD;
             brother or child) who is an employee of the research site or the sponsor, and who&#xD;
             participates directly in this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Leopoldo Baiza Durán, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Laboratorios Sophia S.A de C.V.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ricardo Llamas, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+52 (33) 3001 4200</phone>
    <phone_ext>1259</phone_ext>
    <email>ricardo.llamas@sophia.com.mx</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Oscar M. Olvera, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+52 (33) 3001 4200</phone>
    <phone_ext>1074</phone_ext>
    <email>oscar.olvera@sophia.com.mx</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Health Pharma Professional Research S.A. de C.V.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ciudad de mexico</city>
        <state>Ciudad De México</state>
        <zip>03100</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Diego Romero-Cano, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+525575864856</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Diego Romero-Cano, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Asociación para Evitar la Ceguera en México, I.A.P.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ciudad de mexico</city>
        <state>Ciudad De México</state>
        <zip>04030</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Everardo Hernandez-Quintela, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+525520841400</phone>
      <phone_ext>1043</phone_ext>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Everardo Hernandez-Quintela, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Catarata y Glaucoma de Occidente</name>
      <address>
        <city>Guadalajara</city>
        <state>Jalisco</state>
        <zip>44160</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Abraham Soto, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+52133 3611 1939</phone>
      <email>dr_sotogomez@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Pamela Ghavez, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+52133 3611 1939</phone>
      <email>dra.pchavez@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clínica de Investigación en Reumatología y Obesidad S.C.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Guadalajara</city>
        <state>Jalisco</state>
        <zip>44650</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lilia M Gomez-Valdez, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+5231200700</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lilia M Gomez-Valdez, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jose Navarro Partida</name>
      <address>
        <city>Guadalajara</city>
        <state>Jalisco</state>
        <zip>45160</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jose Navarro, PHD</last_name>
      <phone>+5213315208841</phone>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Daniel rodriguez-carrizalez, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+5213313710056</phone>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centro Potosino de Investigación Médica SC</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Luis Potosí</city>
        <zip>78250</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Juan E Almendarez-Reyna, DM</last_name>
      <phone>+524444752715</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Juan E Almendarez-Reyna, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Mexico</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 30, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 30, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 2, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Dry eye</keyword>
  <keyword>propylene glycol</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dry Eye Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Keratoconjunctivitis Sicca</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

