<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04115956</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>OP201</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04115956</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Clinical Study of Melphalan Flufenamide (Melflufen) and Dexamethasone for Patients With Immunoglobulin Light Chain (AL) Amyloidosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-Label, Phase 1/2 Study of Melflufen and Dexamethasone for Patients With AL Amyloidosis Following at Least One Prior Line of Therapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Oncopeptides AB</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>PRA Health Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Oncopeptides AB</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase 1/2 open label study of melphalan flufenamide (melflufen) in combination with&#xD;
      dexamethasone for participants with Al amyloidosis following at least one prior line of&#xD;
      therapy. Melflufen will be administered on Day 1 of each 28-day cycle in combination with&#xD;
      dexamethasone on days 1 and 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In both phases, treatment of each individual participant will continue for up to 8 cycles or&#xD;
      until any stopping events occur.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 46 participants will be enrolled.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a clinical trial of melphalan flufenamide (melflufen), a peptide-conjugated alkylator&#xD;
      which belongs to an novel class of drugs called peptidase-enhanced compounds, and targets the&#xD;
      transformation process of tumor cells with a unique mechanism of action, as potential&#xD;
      treatment option of AL amyloidosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      AL amyloidosis is a rare progressive disease caused by proteotoxic light chain protein&#xD;
      produced by small plasma cell clone. This plasma cell dyscrasia is characterized by&#xD;
      monoclonal plasma cell's excessive production of monoclonal immunoglobulin light-chains that&#xD;
      tends to misfold and subsequently deposit as amyloid fibrils in visceral organs. The plasma&#xD;
      cell dyscrasia in AL amyloidosis is similar to that in multiple myeloma (MM) and therapies&#xD;
      that are effective in MM are often used to treat AL amyloidosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Melphalan flufenamide is currently been evaluated in several ongoing clinical trials in&#xD;
      patients with multiple myeloma, with observed efficacy. There are currently no therapies&#xD;
      approved for treatment of AL amyloidosis and based on the efficacy of melphalan flufenamide&#xD;
      and the demonstrated efficacy of melphalan (and other alkylators), it is anticipated that&#xD;
      patients with AL amyloidosis may receive benefit from treatment with melphalan flufenamide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study consist of a screening period (up to 28 days), a treatment period (up to 8 cycles)&#xD;
      and a follow-up period (up to 24 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 1: Approximately 8-30 participants will be screened to achieve 7-23 enrolled&#xD;
      participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 2: Approximately 30 participants will be screened to achieve 23 enrolled participants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 6, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Melflufen + Dexamethasone</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary objective in Phase 1 is to explore safety and tolerability of melflufen</measure>
    <time_frame>During phase 1 for up to 8 cycles of treatment of 28 days each (approx. up to 8 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Endpoints:&#xD;
Frequency and grade of Adverse Events. The maximum grade for each type of AE will be recorded for each participant and frequency tables will be presented and reviewed to determine patterns&#xD;
Laboratory values (laboratory abnormalities) for hematology, coagulation, blood chemistry, urinalysis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary objective in Phase 1 is to identify recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D)</measure>
    <time_frame>During phase 1 for up to 8 cycles of 28 days each (approx. up to 8 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Endpoint: Dose-Limiting Toxicity (DLT) during Cycle 1 up to maximum dose of melflufen of 40 mg. A DLT event is defined as thrombocytopenia, neutropenia, non-hematologic toxicity and/or inability to receive Cycle 2 Day 1 dose within 14 days from planned Cycle 2 Day 2 due to continued melflufen-related toxicity from Cycle 1.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary endpoint in Phase 2 is to evaluate the hematologic overall response rate (ORR) after 4 cycles at the RP2D determined in Phase 1</measure>
    <time_frame>During phase 2 after 4 cycles of treatment ( approx. 4 months)</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of participants who achieve a hematologic Complete Response (CR), Very Good Partial Response (VGPR) or Partial Response (PR)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess pharmacokinetic profile of melflufen in this patient population</measure>
    <time_frame>At Cycle 1 Day 1 and Cycle 2 Day 1 at time points 5-10 minutes, 1-2 hours and 3-8 hours after end of infusion. Each cycle length is 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>Melphalan plasma concentration post melflufen administration at 3 time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess best hematologic response</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study treatment of up to 8 cycles of 28 days each (approx. 8 months) per patient</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with each outcome (Complete Response (CR), Very Good Partial Response (VGPR), Partial Response (PR), No Response (NR) or Progressive Disease (PD))</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the duration of hematologic response</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study treatment period of up to 8 cycles of 28 days each (approx 8 months) per patient</time_frame>
    <description>Median time (Complete Response (CR), Very Good Partial Response (VGPR), Partial Response (PR), No Response (NR) or Progressive Disease (PD))</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the proportion of organ system responses</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study treatment period of up to 8 cycles of 28 days each (approx 8 months) per patient</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants with kidney, cardiac or liver response, respectively</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess duration of organ system responses</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study treatment period of up to 8 cycles (approx 8 months) per patient</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of organ responses separately for each organ</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess hematologic ORR (overall response rate)</measure>
    <time_frame>During phase 1 for up to 8 cycles of treatment of 28 days each (approx. up to 8 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants who achieve a hematologic CR, VGPR or PR</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess time to next AL amyloidosis treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study, covering up to 8 cycles (approx. 8 months) of treatment and 24 months of follow up</time_frame>
    <description>Time to next AL amyloidosis treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study, covering up to 8 cycles (approx. 8 months) of treatment and up to 24 months of follow up</time_frame>
    <description>Overall survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">46</enrollment>
  <condition>AL Amyloidosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Melflufen and dexamethasone in combination</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intravenous infusion of melflufen Day 1 of 28 day cycles, in combination of dexamethasone on Days 1 and 2 of each 28-day cycle.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Melphalan-Flufenamide (Melflufen)</intervention_name>
    <description>Treatment consist of i.v. melflufen on Day 1 of each 28-day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Melflufen and dexamethasone in combination</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexamethasone</intervention_name>
    <description>Dexamethasone 40 mg (20 mg at investigator's discretion) administered on Days 1 and 2 of each 28-day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Melflufen and dexamethasone in combination</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Dexamethason JENAPHARM</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: (For full list of inclusion criteria, see study protocol)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female, age 18 years or older at the time of signing the informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Proven histochemical diagnosis of AL amyloidosis based on tissue specimens with Congo&#xD;
             red staining&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one prior line of therapy, defined as either one non-transplant regimen, one&#xD;
             ASCT (autologous stem cell transplantation), or one regimen of induction therapy&#xD;
             followed by a single ASCT. No more that 4 cycles of melphalan containing chemotherapy&#xD;
             is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable hematologic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Objectively measurable organ amyloid involvment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG performance status ≤ 2 (ECOG = Eastern cooperative oncology group)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child bearing potential must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than 30% plasma cells in bone marrow aspirate or biopsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acceptable laboratory results met (absolute neutrophil count (ANC), platelet count,&#xD;
             hemoglobin, total bilirubin,alkaline phosphatase, AST (aspartate aminotransferase) and&#xD;
             ALT (alanine aminotransferase), renal function)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male participant agrees to use contraception during treatment and 90 days after last&#xD;
             dose of melflufen&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: (For full list of exclusion criteria, see study protocol)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Amyloidosis due to known mutations of the transthyretin gene or presence of another&#xD;
             non-AL amyloidosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of gastro-intestinal bleeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiac risk stage 3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Low platelets value with evidence of mucosal or internal bleeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical documented cardiac syncope, NYHA Class 3 or 4 congestive heart failure,&#xD;
             myocardial infarction, unstable angina pectoris, clinically significant ventricular&#xD;
             arrhythmias (NYHA=New York Heart Association Functional Classification)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant finding on 24 h Holter recording&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe orthostatic hypotension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant factor X deficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant autonomic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any medical condition that would impose excessive risk to the patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious psychiatric illness, active alcoholism or drug addiction that may hinder or&#xD;
             confuse compliance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known HIV or active hepatitis B or C viral infections&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous cytotoxic therapies, including cytotoxic investigational agents within 3&#xD;
             weeks prior to start of study treatment. Monoclonal antibodies within 4 weeks.&#xD;
             Concomitant immunotherapy, investigational therapy and anticoagulation therapy are not&#xD;
             permitted&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior autologous or allogenic stem cell transplant within 12 weeks of initiation of&#xD;
             therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior allogeneic stem cell transplant with active graft-host-disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior major surgical procedure or radiation therapy within 4 weeks of the first dose&#xD;
             of study treatment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Giovanni Palladini, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital San Matteo in Pavia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Boston University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02111</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fakultní Nemocnice Ostrava</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ostrava - Poruba</city>
        <zip>70852</zip>
        <country>Czechia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Limoges</name>
      <address>
        <city>Limoges</city>
        <zip>87000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Heidelberg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Heidelberg</city>
        <zip>69120</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alexandra General Hospital of Athens</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athen</city>
        <zip>11528</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hadassah University Hospital Ein Kerem</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jerusalem</city>
        <zip>9112001</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fondazione IRCCS Policlinico San Matteo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pavia</city>
        <zip>27100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oslo University Hospital - Rikshospitalet</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oslo</city>
        <zip>0372</zip>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Instytut Hematologii i Transfuzjologii</name>
      <address>
        <city>Warszawa</city>
        <zip>00791</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clinic de Barcelona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08036</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University College London Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>NW1 2BU</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Czechia</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Greece</country>
    <country>Israel</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Norway</country>
    <country>Poland</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 29, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 2, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulin Light-chain Amyloidosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Amyloidosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Melphalan</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

