<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03927846</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00056912</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03927846</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Implementation of Nurse-guided Web-based Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Pain Management</brief_title>
  <official_title>Web-based Pain Self-Management: Nurse-Guided</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Wake Forest University Health Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Wake Forest University Health Sciences</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To see if nurse guided web based cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) will show pain&#xD;
      improvement in patients with all types of pain complaints.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this application is to test the feasibility of a care model where&#xD;
      clinic nurses play a vital role in promoting the adoption of web-based CBT in the ambulatory&#xD;
      medical setting. Participants (n=60) in the primary care and rheumatology clinics will be&#xD;
      randomized to one of 2 arms: (1) 6 regular telephone contacts, vs. (2) 6 computer generated&#xD;
      email reminders (control arm) over an 8-week period. To enhance participants' motivation to&#xD;
      engage in the web-based CBT, nurses will use motivational interviewing technique. The&#xD;
      investigators will use outcome measures including the number of completed web-based learning&#xD;
      modules, amount of time spent by the nurses on study-related and non-study related phone&#xD;
      calls, health care use, and clinical variables. Our proposed line of research is significant&#xD;
      because it will potentially make CBT, a significantly underutilized treatment modality,&#xD;
      potentially more affordable and accessible. If nurse guided web-based CBT can be shown to be&#xD;
      effective and implementable, Wake Baptist Health System can potentially leverage web-based&#xD;
      CBT as one component in a multidisciplinary pain management program to prospective employers&#xD;
      in North Carolina. Wake Baptist may also develop its own web-based CBT for commercial use.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 17, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 18, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 18, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants (n=60) in the primary care and rheumatology clinics will be randomized to one of 2 arms: (1) 6 regular telephone contacts, vs. (2) 6 computer generated email reminders (control arm) over an 8-week period. To enhance participants' motivation to engage in the web-based CBT, nurses will use motivational interviewing technique.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Study coordinator will be blinded to randomization</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS (Patient Reported-outcomes Measurement Information System) Pain Intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>Questionnaire that measures subject pain intensity. The possible score range is 3-15, 3 being the best outcome and 15 being the worst outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS Pain Interference</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>PROMIS pain interference is a questionnaire that measures interference of pain on subject's life. The possible raw score range is 6-30. The raw score has been converted into a T score. The T score range is from 41.6 to 75.6. A t-score indicates the number of standard deviations away from the mean. A t-score of 50 is equal to the mean of a reference population. Values below 50 indicate pain interference better than the reference population and values above 50 indicate pain interference worse than the reference population.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Completed Phone Calls</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>The number of completed phone calls by the nurse will be recorded.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Completed Learning Modules Per Treatment Arm</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>The number of completed learning modules per treatment arm will be recorded.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of Subjects With Interest in Pain Self-management</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to the acceptability a subject has to pain self management. This would be determined by the number of subjects who answer &quot;yes&quot; to the question &quot;Have you ever wondered if there is something that you could do on your own to better manage your pain?&quot; divided by the number of patients who answered &quot;yes&quot; to the question &quot;Over the last 6 months, do you have daily or almost daily pain that interfered with your general activity or enjoyment of life?&quot;</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of Patients Who Viewed Educational Video</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to the acceptability a subject has to watching the educational video on web-based CBT. This would be determined by the number of patients who watched the video from Expectation Management and Medical Information (EMMI) divided by the number of patients who received the video from EMMI.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of Subjects Who Called the Research Coordinator to Participate in the Study.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to the acceptability a subject has to participating in the study. This would be determined by the number of patients who made a phone call to the research team after watching the video divided by the number of patients who watched the video.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Ratings of Perceived Disruption</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to whether health care personnel perceives a disruption in the clinic standard operating procedures</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Uptake Rates</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to the adoption or extent of participants' motivation to engage in the web-based CBT program. For the uptake rate, the number of times participants log in to web-based CBT will be recorded.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Self-report Frequency of Practicing Pain Coping Skills</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to the adoption or extent of participants' motivation to engage in the web-based CBT program. Self-report frequency of practicing pain coping skills will be measured by a question scale 0-5. Higher scores denote better outcomes.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Participant Overall Satisfaction on Web-based CBT Program</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to the adoption or extent of participants' motivation to engage in the web-based CBT program. Recorded in a question - scale 0-5. Higher scores denote better outcomes.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Nurse's Time</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to the feasibility of the web-based CBT program. The number of minutes a nurse spends on study-related phone calls and the time a nurse spends during the initial and ongoing MI training will be recorded.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived Work Rating</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to the feasibility of the web-based CBT program. Nurses will rate perceived additional work load. Recorded using sing a scale 1-5, higher scores denotes worse outcomes.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Motivational Interviewing Treatment Integrity (MITI) Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to the feasibility of the web-based CBT program. This scale is used to assess treatment fidelity to the principles of MI.Scale range from 5 to 25, where a score of 25 represents 100% adherence to the principles of motivational interviewing (MI).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Opioid Daily Dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to the burden or utilization of health care in relation to the web-based CBT program. The mean daily dose of opioids will be recorded for all participants.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Non-study Phone Calls</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to the burden or utilization of health care in relation to the web-based CBT program. The number of pain relevant phone calls will be recorded.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>New Referrals to Other Musculoskeletal-related Specialties</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to the burden or utilization of health care in relation to the web-based CBT program. The number of new referrals to other musculoskeletal-related specialties will be recorded.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Emergency Room Visits Related to Pain</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This refers to the burden or utilization of health care in relation to the web-based CBT program. The number of ER visits per subject related to pain will be recorded.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS Physical Health -Fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This is a questionnaire that pertains to subject physical health. Raw summed score from 4 to 20, where 20 represents severe fatigue.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS Physical Health - Physical Function</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This is a questionnaire that pertains to subject physical health. Raw summed score from 4 to 20, where 20 represents severe physical impairment.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS Physical Health - Sleep-related Impairment</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This is a questionnaire that pertains to subject physical health.Raw summed score from 4 to 20, where 20 represents severe sleep impairment.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS Physical Health- Pain Behavior</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This is a questionnaire that pertains to subject physical health. Raw summed score from 20 to 100, where 100 represents severely maladaptive pain behavior.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS Social Health</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This is a questionnaire that pertains to subject social health. Raw summed score range from 4 to 20, where 20 represents complete inability to participate in various social functions.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) Pain Severity</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This is a pain severity questionnaire. BPI consists of four items that are scored from 0 (no pain) to 10 (worst possible pain); the mean of this four areas is reported as the score.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>BPI Pain Interference</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This is a questionnaire that shows a subject's perceived interference of pain in his/her daily life. The BPI pain interference section consists of seven items that are scored from 0 (no interference) to 10 (complete interference).A pain interference score is calculated from the mean of the seven pain interference items.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Catastrophizing Score (PCS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This questionnaire shows the subject's perceived pain. The score is from 0-52 with 0 being the best outcome and 52 being the worst outcome.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Global Rating of Change (GRoC)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>This questionnaire shows how the subject rates his/her overall condition of pain from the beginning of treatment to when the questionnaire is completed. The score ranges from -5 to 5, with -5 being the worst outcome and 5 being the best outcome.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Health Questionnaire Depression Scale (PHQ-8)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>A questionnaire that shows patient's level of depression. Scores can be 0-24, with 0 being the best outcome and 24 being the worst. A score of 10 or greater is considered major depression. A score of 20 or more is severe major depression.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Generalized Anxiety Disorder (GAD-7)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>A questionnaire that shows how much anxiety a subject has. Scores can be 0-18. A score of 5-9 means mild anxiety. A score of 10-14 means moderate anxiety. A score of 15-18 means severe anxiety.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Musculoskeletal Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Telephone Contact (Nurse)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>6 regular telephone contacts by nurses who will use a motivational interviewing technique</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>E-mail contact</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>6 computer generated email reminders (control arm) over an 8-week period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nurse-guided Web-based Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>nurse contact is to support and enhance participants' motivation to engage in the web-based CBT program.</description>
    <arm_group_label>E-mail contact</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Telephone Contact (Nurse)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: -&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. patients at the primary care or rheumatology clinic with daily pain for 6 months or&#xD;
             longer affecting the low back, neck, hip, knee or widespread pain;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. at least moderate in average pain severity, defined as a weekly average pain severity&#xD;
             score of 5 or greater 24;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. at least 18 years of age;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. reliable phone (landline or cell), and&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. have home computer with reliable internet access.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. planned elective surgery during the study period;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. very severe symptoms of depression (i.e., The eight-item Patient Health Questionnaire&#xD;
             depression scale (PHQ8) score of ≥ 20);&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. ongoing unresolved disability claims;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. inflammatory arthritis (e.g., lupus, rheumatoid arthritis, ankylosing spondylitis,&#xD;
             etc.);&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. cancer-related musculoskeletal pain;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. history of bipolar disorder or schizophrenia; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. takes daily opioid for more than one year.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dennis Ang, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Wake Forest University Health Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wake Forest Baptist Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winston-Salem</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 23, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 23, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 25, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>May 5, 2021</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>June 24, 2021</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Actual">July 15, 2021</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>If nurse guided web-based CBT can be shown to be effective and implementable, Wake Baptist can potentially leverage web-based CBT as one component in a multidisciplinary pain management program to prospective employers in North Carolina. With assistance from Wake Forest Innovation, Wake Baptist may also develop its own web-based CBT that can be commercialize in the future.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>April 7, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/46/NCT03927846/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>May 5, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/46/NCT03927846/SAP_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>February 20, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/46/NCT03927846/ICF_002.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Nurse Support</title>
          <description>Participants received phone-based coaching</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P2">
          <title>Control</title>
          <description>No contact with the research team</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="30"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="30"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="20"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="19"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="10"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="11"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
          <drop_withdraw_reason_list>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Lost to Follow-up</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="10"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="11"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
          </drop_withdraw_reason_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Nurse Support</title>
          <description>Participants received phone-based coaching</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B2">
          <title>Control</title>
          <description>No contact with the research team</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B3">
          <title>Total</title>
          <description>Total of all reporting groups</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="30"/>
            <count group_id="B2" value="30"/>
            <count group_id="B3" value="60"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>years</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="52.3" spread="14.9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="51.8" spread="20.5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="52.1" spread="17.8"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="26"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="23"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="49"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="7"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="11"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Ethnicity (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="2"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Not Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="29"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="29"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="58"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>PROMIS pain intensity</title>
          <description>Questionnaire that measures subject pain intensity. The possible score range is 3-15, 3 being the best outcome and 15 being the worst outcome</description>
          <units>units on a scale</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="5.8" spread="1.6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="6.0" spread="1.9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="5.9" spread="1.7"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>PROMIS pain interference</title>
          <description>PROMIS pain interference is a questionnaire that measures interference of pain on subject's life. The possible raw score range is 6-30. The raw score has been converted into a T score. The T score range is from 41.6 to 75.6. A t-score indicates the number of standard deviations away from the mean. A t-score of 50 is equal to the mean of a reference population. Values below 50 indicate pain interference better than the reference population and values above 50 indicate pain interference worse than the reference population.</description>
          <units>T-Score</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="61.2" spread="7.4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="62.9" spread="6.5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="62.1" spread="7.0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>PROMIS (Patient Reported-outcomes Measurement Information System) Pain Intensity</title>
        <description>Questionnaire that measures subject pain intensity. The possible score range is 3-15, 3 being the best outcome and 15 being the worst outcome</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Nurse Support</title>
            <description>Participants received phone-based coaching</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Control</title>
            <description>No contact with the research team</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>PROMIS (Patient Reported-outcomes Measurement Information System) Pain Intensity</title>
          <description>Questionnaire that measures subject pain intensity. The possible score range is 3-15, 3 being the best outcome and 15 being the worst outcome</description>
          <units>score on a scale</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Error</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="20"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="19"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="4.4" spread="0.3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="4.7" spread="0.2"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>PROMIS Pain Interference</title>
        <description>PROMIS pain interference is a questionnaire that measures interference of pain on subject's life. The possible raw score range is 6-30. The raw score has been converted into a T score. The T score range is from 41.6 to 75.6. A t-score indicates the number of standard deviations away from the mean. A t-score of 50 is equal to the mean of a reference population. Values below 50 indicate pain interference better than the reference population and values above 50 indicate pain interference worse than the reference population.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Nurse Support</title>
            <description>Participants received phone-based coaching</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Control</title>
            <description>No contact with the research team</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>PROMIS Pain Interference</title>
          <description>PROMIS pain interference is a questionnaire that measures interference of pain on subject's life. The possible raw score range is 6-30. The raw score has been converted into a T score. The T score range is from 41.6 to 75.6. A t-score indicates the number of standard deviations away from the mean. A t-score of 50 is equal to the mean of a reference population. Values below 50 indicate pain interference better than the reference population and values above 50 indicate pain interference worse than the reference population.</description>
          <units>T-score</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Error</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="20"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="19"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="57.4" spread="0.9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="57.3" spread="0.9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Completed Phone Calls</title>
        <description>The number of completed phone calls by the nurse will be recorded.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Nurse Support</title>
            <description>Participants received phone-based coaching</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Control</title>
            <description>No contact with the research team</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Completed Phone Calls</title>
          <description>The number of completed phone calls by the nurse will be recorded.</description>
          <units>number of phone calls</units>
          <param>Median</param>
          <dispersion>Inter-Quartile Range</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="20"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="19"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="3.5" lower_limit="2" upper_limit="5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="0" lower_limit="0" upper_limit="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Completed Learning Modules Per Treatment Arm</title>
        <description>The number of completed learning modules per treatment arm will be recorded.</description>
        <time_frame>Week 16</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Nurse Support</title>
            <description>Participants received phone-based coaching</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Control</title>
            <description>No contact with the research team</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Completed Learning Modules Per Treatment Arm</title>
          <description>The number of completed learning modules per treatment arm will be recorded.</description>
          <units>number of learning modules</units>
          <param>Median</param>
          <dispersion>Inter-Quartile Range</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="30"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="30"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="7" lower_limit="1" upper_limit="8"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="8" lower_limit="1" upper_limit="8"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Proportion of Subjects With Interest in Pain Self-management</title>
        <description>This refers to the acceptability a subject has to pain self management. This would be determined by the number of subjects who answer &quot;yes&quot; to the question &quot;Have you ever wondered if there is something that you could do on your own to better manage your pain?&quot; divided by the number of patients who answered &quot;yes&quot; to the question &quot;Over the last 6 months, do you have daily or almost daily pain that interfered with your general activity or enjoyment of life?&quot;</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Proportion of Patients Who Viewed Educational Video</title>
        <description>This refers to the acceptability a subject has to watching the educational video on web-based CBT. This would be determined by the number of patients who watched the video from Expectation Management and Medical Information (EMMI) divided by the number of patients who received the video from EMMI.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Proportion of Subjects Who Called the Research Coordinator to Participate in the Study.</title>
        <description>This refers to the acceptability a subject has to participating in the study. This would be determined by the number of patients who made a phone call to the research team after watching the video divided by the number of patients who watched the video.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Ratings of Perceived Disruption</title>
        <description>This refers to whether health care personnel perceives a disruption in the clinic standard operating procedures</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Uptake Rates</title>
        <description>This refers to the adoption or extent of participants' motivation to engage in the web-based CBT program. For the uptake rate, the number of times participants log in to web-based CBT will be recorded.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Self-report Frequency of Practicing Pain Coping Skills</title>
        <description>This refers to the adoption or extent of participants' motivation to engage in the web-based CBT program. Self-report frequency of practicing pain coping skills will be measured by a question scale 0-5. Higher scores denote better outcomes.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Participant Overall Satisfaction on Web-based CBT Program</title>
        <description>This refers to the adoption or extent of participants' motivation to engage in the web-based CBT program. Recorded in a question - scale 0-5. Higher scores denote better outcomes.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Nurse's Time</title>
        <description>This refers to the feasibility of the web-based CBT program. The number of minutes a nurse spends on study-related phone calls and the time a nurse spends during the initial and ongoing MI training will be recorded.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Perceived Work Rating</title>
        <description>This refers to the feasibility of the web-based CBT program. Nurses will rate perceived additional work load. Recorded using sing a scale 1-5, higher scores denotes worse outcomes.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Motivational Interviewing Treatment Integrity (MITI) Scale</title>
        <description>This refers to the feasibility of the web-based CBT program. This scale is used to assess treatment fidelity to the principles of MI.Scale range from 5 to 25, where a score of 25 represents 100% adherence to the principles of motivational interviewing (MI).</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Mean Opioid Daily Dose</title>
        <description>This refers to the burden or utilization of health care in relation to the web-based CBT program. The mean daily dose of opioids will be recorded for all participants.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Non-study Phone Calls</title>
        <description>This refers to the burden or utilization of health care in relation to the web-based CBT program. The number of pain relevant phone calls will be recorded.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>New Referrals to Other Musculoskeletal-related Specialties</title>
        <description>This refers to the burden or utilization of health care in relation to the web-based CBT program. The number of new referrals to other musculoskeletal-related specialties will be recorded.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Number of Emergency Room Visits Related to Pain</title>
        <description>This refers to the burden or utilization of health care in relation to the web-based CBT program. The number of ER visits per subject related to pain will be recorded.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>PROMIS Physical Health -Fatigue</title>
        <description>This is a questionnaire that pertains to subject physical health. Raw summed score from 4 to 20, where 20 represents severe fatigue.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>PROMIS Physical Health - Physical Function</title>
        <description>This is a questionnaire that pertains to subject physical health. Raw summed score from 4 to 20, where 20 represents severe physical impairment.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>PROMIS Physical Health - Sleep-related Impairment</title>
        <description>This is a questionnaire that pertains to subject physical health.Raw summed score from 4 to 20, where 20 represents severe sleep impairment.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>PROMIS Physical Health- Pain Behavior</title>
        <description>This is a questionnaire that pertains to subject physical health. Raw summed score from 20 to 100, where 100 represents severely maladaptive pain behavior.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>PROMIS Social Health</title>
        <description>This is a questionnaire that pertains to subject social health. Raw summed score range from 4 to 20, where 20 represents complete inability to participate in various social functions.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) Pain Severity</title>
        <description>This is a pain severity questionnaire. BPI consists of four items that are scored from 0 (no pain) to 10 (worst possible pain); the mean of this four areas is reported as the score.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>BPI Pain Interference</title>
        <description>This is a questionnaire that shows a subject's perceived interference of pain in his/her daily life. The BPI pain interference section consists of seven items that are scored from 0 (no interference) to 10 (complete interference).A pain interference score is calculated from the mean of the seven pain interference items.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Nurse Support</title>
            <description>Participants received phone-based coaching</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Control</title>
            <description>No contact with the research team</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>BPI Pain Interference</title>
          <description>This is a questionnaire that shows a subject's perceived interference of pain in his/her daily life. The BPI pain interference section consists of seven items that are scored from 0 (no interference) to 10 (complete interference).A pain interference score is calculated from the mean of the seven pain interference items.</description>
          <units>score on a scale</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Error</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="20"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="19"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="3.5" spread="0.3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="3.5" spread="0.3"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Pain Catastrophizing Score (PCS)</title>
        <description>This questionnaire shows the subject's perceived pain. The score is from 0-52 with 0 being the best outcome and 52 being the worst outcome.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Global Rating of Change (GRoC)</title>
        <description>This questionnaire shows how the subject rates his/her overall condition of pain from the beginning of treatment to when the questionnaire is completed. The score ranges from -5 to 5, with -5 being the worst outcome and 5 being the best outcome.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Patient Health Questionnaire Depression Scale (PHQ-8)</title>
        <description>A questionnaire that shows patient's level of depression. Scores can be 0-24, with 0 being the best outcome and 24 being the worst. A score of 10 or greater is considered major depression. A score of 20 or more is severe major depression.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Generalized Anxiety Disorder (GAD-7)</title>
        <description>A questionnaire that shows how much anxiety a subject has. Scores can be 0-18. A score of 5-9 means mild anxiety. A score of 10-14 means moderate anxiety. A score of 15-18 means severe anxiety.</description>
        <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Nurse Support</title>
          <description>Participants received phone-based coaching</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E2">
          <title>Control</title>
          <description>No contact with the research team</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="30"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="30"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="30"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="30"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>0</frequency_threshold>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="30"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="30"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>All Principal Investigators ARE employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Dennis Ang, Primary Investigator</name_or_title>
      <organization>Wake Forest Health Sciences</organization>
      <phone>336-705-8701</phone>
      <email>dang@wakehealth.edu</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

