<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03151681</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PRPL-006</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03151681</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Trauma of Betrayal: Treating Adjustment Disorder With Reconsolidation Blockade Under Propranolol</brief_title>
  <official_title>Treating Adjustment Disorders Stemming From Romantic Betrayals: An Open-label Trial of Impairing Memory Reconsolidation Using Propranolol</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Douglas Mental Health University Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Douglas Mental Health University Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Attachment injuries are events occurring within couple relationships that involve betrayal or&#xD;
      abandonment by a significant other during times of need (e.g., infidelity). They can be&#xD;
      understood as relationship traumas, which can lead to debilitating symptoms consistent with&#xD;
      posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD), depression, and generalized anxiety for the injured&#xD;
      partner. Research has demonstrated that the presence of an attachment injury represents a&#xD;
      barrier to empirically effective couple's therapy. However, disrupting memory reconsolidation&#xD;
      with the beta-blocker propranolol has been shown to alleviate PTSD symptoms by attenuating&#xD;
      the salience of the emotional trauma memory, representing an interesting avenue for the&#xD;
      treatment of adjustment disorders stemming from attachment injuries. Moreover, evidence&#xD;
      suggests that a certain degree of mismatch, or an error between what is expected/predicted to&#xD;
      occur and what actually occurs, must be present in order for a memory to destabilize and&#xD;
      enter the reconsolidation phase following retrieval. Here, the investigators aim to extend&#xD;
      the conditions under which reconsolidation therapy with propranolol can be used in a clinical&#xD;
      setting, as well as assess whether incorporating mismatch enhances treatment effects. The&#xD;
      investigators hypothesize that, compared to a wait-list control, 4-6 sessions of memory&#xD;
      reactivation under propranolol will significantly reduce trauma-related and general&#xD;
      anxio-depressive symptoms, associated with an attachment injury. Moreover, the investigators&#xD;
      hypothesize that participants randomized to the mismatch group will improve significantly&#xD;
      more than the standard treatment group on all variables of interest.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Experiment 1: Repeated measures open-label clinical trial with time-series analysis.&#xD;
Experiment 2: Randomized clinical trial (mismatch vs. no mismatch) with within-group wait-list.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Randomization to 'mismatch group' or 'no-mismatch group' will be done prior to the first treatment session by a third party unrelated to the study, and blind to participant outcome. Participants will also be blind to which group they are randomized to. The randomization scheme will use the permuted-block method with a block size of four, stratified by gender (male and female) and event type (infidelity and other), and a group allocation probability of 50% (Fleiss, 1986).</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Within-group difference: Wait-list vs. Treatment; Between-group difference: Mismatch vs. No Mismatch on Impact of Events Scale-Revised</measure>
    <time_frame>Administered at baseline (Week 0), Post-Wait-list (Week 4), at each subsequent weekly visit, at the one-week post-treatment follow-up, and at the three-month follow up.</time_frame>
    <description>Severity of Trauma and Stressor-related symptoms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Within-group difference: Wait-list vs. Treatment; Between-group difference: Mismatch vs. No Mismatch on Hopkins Symptom Checklist-25</measure>
    <time_frame>Administered at baseline (Week 0), Post-Wait-list (Week 4), at each subsequent weekly visit, at the one-week post-treatment follow-up, and at the three-month follow up.</time_frame>
    <description>General Psychological Distress (Depression and Anxiety)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Within-group difference: Wait-list vs. Treatment; Between-group difference: Mismatch vs. No Mismatch on World Health Organization - Quality of Life BREF</measure>
    <time_frame>Administered at baseline (Week 0), Post-Wait-list (Week 4), at the one-week post-treatment follow-up, and at the three-month follow up.</time_frame>
    <description>Perceived Quality of Life in 4 Domains, Psychological, Physical, Environmental, Social</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Adjustment Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Posttraumatic Stress Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Trauma and Stressor Related Disorders</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Propranolol pill + mismatch memory reactivation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Prediction-error will be incorporated into each treatment sessions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Propranolol pill + standard memory reactivation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Waitlist</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Propranolol Pill</intervention_name>
    <description>1mg/kg of propranolol 60 minutes prior to memory reactivation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Propranolol pill + mismatch memory reactivation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Propranolol pill + standard memory reactivation</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Inderal</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of an adjustment disorder or chronic adjustment disorder, as defined by the&#xD;
             Diagnostic and Statistical Manual for Mental Disorders, as a result of an attachment&#xD;
             injury, defined as an event involving the perceived betrayal, violation of trust, or&#xD;
             abandonment by a significant other.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently experiencing clinically important psychological distress as a result of the&#xD;
             event, as defined by a score of at least 22 on the IES-R, and a score of at least&#xD;
             &quot;moderately ill&quot; on the Clinical Global Impressions - Severity of Illness Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have been in the romantic relationship for at least 6 months prior to the event.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must not take psychotropic medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fluency in English or French&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systolic blood pressure &lt;100 mm Hg;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiac rhythm below 55 beats per minute;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A medical condition that contraindicates the administration of propranolol, e.g.,&#xD;
             Asthma, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, cardiac insufficiency, cardiac choc,&#xD;
             Second- or third-degree atrioventricular block, diabetes, spastic angina, auricular&#xD;
             sinus illness, bradycardia, Raynaud's disease, severe peripheral vascular disease,&#xD;
             untreated Pheochromocytoma, arterial hypotension, previous anaphylactic allergic&#xD;
             shock;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous adverse reaction to, or non-compliance with, beta-blocker;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of a substance that may involve potentially dangerous interactions with&#xD;
             propranolol, including P450 2D6 inhibitors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant or breast feeding;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals currently participating in any other form of psychotherapy (other than&#xD;
             strictly supportive).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of substance dependence disorder, bipolar disorder, or psychotic disorder;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants judged (based on history, mental status exam, clinical impression, or the&#xD;
             Suicidal Behaviors Questionnaire as being at significant risk of suicidal behavior.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in another drug trial within 30 days prior to the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of any clinical condition that might interfere with the interpretation of the&#xD;
             efficacy and safety results.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Alain Brunet, PhD.</last_name>
    <phone>5147616131</phone>
    <phone_ext>4348</phone_ext>
    <email>alain.brunet@mcgill.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Douglas Mental Health University Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montréal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H4H1R3</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alain Brunet, PhD.</last_name>
      <phone>5147616131</phone>
      <phone_ext>4348</phone_ext>
      <email>alain.brunet@mcgill.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Michelle Lonergan, MSc.</last_name>
      <phone>514-761-6131</phone>
      <phone_ext>3491</phone_ext>
      <email>michelle.lonergan@mail.mcgill.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jacques Tremblay, MD., MSc.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 29, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 11, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 12, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Douglas Mental Health University Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Alain Brunet, Ph.D.</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Primary Investigator and Full Professor, Department of Psychiatry, McGill University.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Reconsolidation</keyword>
  <keyword>Propranolol</keyword>
  <keyword>Infidelity</keyword>
  <keyword>Attachment injury</keyword>
  <keyword>Romantic relationships</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adjustment Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Trauma and Stressor Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Propranolol</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

