<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03158064</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>17-160</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03158064</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating Immune Therapy, Duravalumab (MEDI4736) With Tremelimumab for Relapsed/Refractory Germ Cell Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Single-arm, Phase II Study of Durvalumab (MEDI4736) and Tremelimumab for Relapsed/Refractory Germ Cell Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to test the safety and effectiveness of durvalumab with&#xD;
      tremelimumab in patients with relapsed or refractory germ cell tumors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 15, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>overall response rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>by RECIST v1.1</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">31</enrollment>
  <condition>Germ Cell Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Nonseminomatous Germ Cell Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Seminoma</condition>
  <condition>Germinomatous Germ Cell Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Dysgerminoma</condition>
  <condition>Pineal Germ Cell Tumor</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Duravalumab + Tremelimumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Duravalumab/Tremelimumab: Durvalumab and Tremelimumab will be administered by IV every 4 weeks for up to 4 doses/cycles, then Durvalumab by IV every 4 weeks starting at Week 16 for 9 doses (total treatment duration of 12 months).&#xD;
Participants enrolled now will receive tremelimumab *300mg with durvalumab 1500mg for 1 cycle followed by 12 cycles of durvalumab 1500mg every 4 weeks or until lack of clinical benefit or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Durvalumab</intervention_name>
    <description>1500 mg by IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Duravalumab + Tremelimumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MEDI4736</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tremelimumab</intervention_name>
    <description>75 mg by IV&#xD;
*300mg</description>
    <arm_group_label>Duravalumab + Tremelimumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years at time of informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight &gt; 30 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed diagnosis of GCT (nonseminoma or seminoma in men;&#xD;
             non-dysgerminomas, dysgerminomas, or germinomas in women or patients with pineal gland&#xD;
             GCT) at MSKCC of any primary site (includes female GCT and intracranial GCT).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of measurable disease either by RECIST 1.1 or elevation of serum tumor&#xD;
             markers (AFP &gt; 15 ng/mL or HCG &gt;2.2 mIU/ml).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have progressed after at least one prior systemic therapy for GCT and&#xD;
             meet one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Patients with evidence of progressive or recurrent GCT after progression prior high&#xD;
             dose chemotherapy (HDCT) treatment, defined as meeting at least on of the following&#xD;
             criteria: i. Tumor biopsy of new or growing or unresectable lesions demonstrating&#xD;
             viable GCT. In the event of an incomplete gross resection where viable GCT is found,&#xD;
             patients will be considered eligible for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        ii. Consecutive elevated serum tumor markers (HCG or AFP) that are increasing. Increase of&#xD;
        an elevated LDH alone does not constitute progressive disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        iii. Development of new or enlarging lesions in the the setting of persistently elevated&#xD;
        HCG or AFP, even if the HCG and AFP are not continuing to rise.&#xD;
&#xD;
        b. Patients deemed not to be a candidate for or benefit from potentially curative HDCT or&#xD;
        other curative treatment options defined as follows: i. Patients with inadequate renal&#xD;
        function for HDCT. ii. Patients who have had 3 or more lines of prior chemotherapy as this&#xD;
        patient population has historically not benefitted from HDCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
        iii. Patients with late relapse (relapse &gt; 2 years after last therapy) as this patient&#xD;
        population has historically not benefitted from HDCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
        iv. Patient with inadequate stem cell collection to move forward with HDCT. v. Patients&#xD;
        with significant medical or psychosocial comorbidities that are felt to be a&#xD;
        contraindication to HDCT by the treating investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: There is no maximum number of prior treatments allowed &quot;Progression&quot; after prior&#xD;
        therapy is defined as any one of the following: NOTE: Patients with clinically growing&#xD;
        &quot;teratoma&quot; (normal declining tumor markers and radiographic or clinical progression) should&#xD;
        be considered for surgery. In patients with rising tumor markers as their only evidence of&#xD;
        disease progression where AFP is &lt;30 or HCG is &lt;15, alternate causes of increased levels of&#xD;
        these markers should be ruled out. (e.g., hypogonadism by testosterone suppression of LH,&#xD;
        hepatitis, use of marijuana).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with brain metastases are allowed onto the study as long as patients have&#xD;
             completed their treatment for brain metastasis, no longer require corticosteroids, and&#xD;
             are asymptomatic. Subjects with neurological symptoms should undergo a head CT scan or&#xD;
             brain MRI to exclude brain metastasis, at the discretion of the treating physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate normal organ and marrow function as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.0 x 109/L (&gt; 1000 per mm3)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count ≥ 100 x 109/L (&gt;100,000 per mm3)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) (≤ 3 x&#xD;
                  institutional ULN in patient's with Gilbert's syndrome)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST (SGOT)/ALT (SGPT) ≤ 2.5 x institutional ULN unless liver metastases are&#xD;
                  present, in which case it must be ≤ 5x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Calculated creatinine clearance &gt;30 mL/min by the Cockcroft-Gault formula&#xD;
                  (Cockcroft and Gault 1976) or by 24-hour urine collection for determination of&#xD;
                  creatinine clearance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of post-menopausal status or negative urinary or serum pregnancy test for&#xD;
             female pre-menopausal patients. Women will be considered post-menopausal if they have&#xD;
             been amenorrheic for 12 months without an alternative medical cause. The following&#xD;
             age-specific requirements apply.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women &lt; 50 years of age would be considered post-menopausal if they have been&#xD;
                  amenorrheic for 12 months or more following cessation of exogenous hormonal&#xD;
                  treatment and if they have luteinizing hormone and follicle-stimulating hormone&#xD;
                  levels in the post-menopausal range for the institution or underwent surgical&#xD;
                  sterilization (bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women &gt;/= 50 years of age would be considered post-menopausal if they have been&#xD;
                  amenorrheic for 12 months or more following cessation of all exogenous hormonal&#xD;
                  treatments, had radiation-induced menopause with last menses &gt; 1 year ago, had&#xD;
                  chemotherapy-induced menopause with last menses &gt;1 year ago, or underwent&#xD;
                  surgical sterilization (bilateral oophorectomy, bilateral salpingectomy or&#xD;
                  hysterectomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A positive serum pregnancy test must be confirmed by a pelvic US since some NSGCT may&#xD;
             secrete beta-hCG and cause a false positive pregnancy. A pelvic US does not need to be&#xD;
             repeated with each cycle unless the treating physician thinks it is necessary to do&#xD;
             so.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients of reproductive potential, defined as not surgical sterile (i.e.,&#xD;
             bilateral tubal ligation, bilateral oophorectomy, or complete hysterectomy) or&#xD;
             post-menopausal (see above for definition) and non-sterilized males who are sexually&#xD;
             active with a female partner of reproductive potential must be willing to adhere to&#xD;
             the following restrictions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Females of childbearing potential who are sexually active with a non-sterilized&#xD;
                  male partner must agree to use at least 1 highly effective method of&#xD;
                  contraception from the time of screening until 180 days after the last dose of&#xD;
                  durvalumab + tremelimumab combination therapy or 90 days after the last dose of&#xD;
                  durvalumab monotherapy. Cessation of birth control after this point should be&#xD;
                  discussed with a responsible physician. Periodic abstinence, the rhythm method,&#xD;
                  and the withdrawal method are not acceptable methods of birth control. It is&#xD;
                  strongly recommended that non-sterilized male partners of a female patient must&#xD;
                  use male condom plus spermicide throughout this period Not engaging in sexual&#xD;
                  activity for the total duration of the drug treatment and the drug washout period&#xD;
                  is an acceptable practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Non-sterilized males who are sexually active with a female partner of&#xD;
                  childbearing potential must use a male condom plus spermicide from screening&#xD;
                  through 180 days after receipt of the final dose of durvalumab + tremelimumab&#xD;
                  combination therapy or 90 days after receipt of the final dose of durvalumab&#xD;
                  monotherapy. Periodic abstinence, the rhythm method, and the withdrawal method&#xD;
                  are not acceptable methods of birth control. Not engaging in sexual activity is&#xD;
                  an acceptable practice. Male patients should refrain from sperm donation&#xD;
                  throughout this period. It is strongly recommended that female partners (of&#xD;
                  childbearing potential) of male patients to also use a highly effective method of&#xD;
                  contraception throughout this period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is willing and able to comply with the protocol for the duration of the study&#xD;
             including undergoing treatment and scheduled visits and examinations including follow&#xD;
             up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Involvement in the planning and/or conduct of the study (applies to both AstraZeneca&#xD;
             staff and/or staff at the study site)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous enrolment in the present study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in another clinical study with an investigational product during the&#xD;
             last 14 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mean QT interval corrected for heart rate (QTc) ≥ 470 ms calculated from 3&#xD;
             electrocardiograms (ECGs) using Fredericia's Correction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any previous treatment with a PD-1 or PD-L1 inhibitor, including durvalumab or an&#xD;
             anti-CTLA-4, including tremelimumab&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of the last dose of anti-cancer therapy (chemotherapy, immunotherapy,&#xD;
             endocrine therapy, targeted therapy, biologic therapy, tumor embolization, monoclonal&#xD;
             antibodies, other investigational agent) ≤ 14 days prior to the first dose of study&#xD;
             drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery within 28 days of starting study treatment. There is no minimum time&#xD;
             requirement for minor procedures such as biopsy or vascular access placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiation within 14 days of starting study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or prior use of immunosuppressive medication within 28 days before the first&#xD;
             dose of durvalumab or tremelimumab. The following are exceptions to this criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intranasal, inhaled, topical steroids, or local steroid injections (e.g., intra&#xD;
                  articular injection)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Systemic corticosteroids at physiologic doses not to exceed10 mg/day of&#xD;
                  prednisone or its equivalent&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Steroids as premedication for hypersensitivity reactions (e.g., CT scan&#xD;
                  premedication)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A temporary period of steroids for different indications, at the discretion of&#xD;
                  the principal investigator (e.g., chronic obstructive pulmonary disease,&#xD;
                  radiation, nausea, etc)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any unresolved toxicity (&gt;CTCAE grade 2) from previous anti-cancer therapy. Subjects&#xD;
             with irreversible toxicity that is not reasonably expected to be exacerbated by the&#xD;
             investigational product may be included (e.g., alopecia, hearing loss, peripheral&#xD;
             neuropathy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of pulmonary fibrosis by imaging or biopsy (including secondary to bleomycin),&#xD;
             pneumonitis (including drug induced) requiring steroids ≥ 3 weeks, organizing&#xD;
             pneumonia (i.e., bronchiolitis obliterans, cryptogenic organizing pneumonia, etc.), or&#xD;
             evidence of active pneumonitis on screening chest computed tomography (CT) scan with&#xD;
             associated symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active or prior documented autoimmune or inflammatory disorders (including&#xD;
             inflammatory bowel disease [e.g., colitis or Crohn's disease], diverticulitis, celiac&#xD;
             disease, systemic lupus erythematosus, Sarcoidosis syndrome, or Wegener syndrome&#xD;
             (granulomatosis with polyangiitis, Graves' disease, rheumatoid arthritis,&#xD;
             hypophysitis, uveitis, etc)). The following are exceptions to this criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with vitiligo or alopecia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with hypothyroidism (eg, following Hashimoto syndrome) stable on hormone&#xD;
                  replacement&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any chronic skin condition that does not require systemic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients without active autoimmune disease in the last 5 years may be included&#xD;
                  but only after consultation with the study physician&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with diverticulosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with celiac disease controlled by diet alone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of primary immunodeficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allogeneic organ transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hypersensitivity to durvalumab, tremelimumab or any excipient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, on-going or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, uncontrolled hypertension, unstable&#xD;
             angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, active peptic ulcer disease or gastritis, active&#xD;
             bleeding diatheses, evidence of acute or chronic hepatitis B, hepatitis C or human&#xD;
             immunodeficiency virus (HIV), or psychiatric illness/social situations that would&#xD;
             limit compliance with study requirements or compromise the ability of the subject to&#xD;
             give written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection including tuberculosis (clinical evaluation that includes clinical&#xD;
             history, physical examination and radiographic findings, and TB testing in line with&#xD;
             local practice), hepatitis B (known positive HBV surface antigen (HBsAg) result),&#xD;
             hepatitis C, or human immunodeficiency virus (positive HIV 1/2 antibodies). Patients&#xD;
             with a past or resolved HBV infection (defined as the presence of hepatitis B core&#xD;
             antibody [anti-HBc] and absence of HBsAg) are eligible. Patients positive for&#xD;
             hepatitis C (HCV) antibody are eligible only if polymerase chain reaction is negative&#xD;
             for HCV RNA.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of previous clinical diagnosis of tuberculosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of leptomeningeal carcinomatosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of live attenuated vaccination within 30 days prior to study entry or within&#xD;
             30 days of receiving durvalumab or tremelimumab. Inactivated vaccines, such as the&#xD;
             injectable influenza vaccine, are permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would interfere with&#xD;
             evaluation of study treatment or interpretation of patient safety or study results&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Malignancies other than the disease under study within 5 years prior to Cycle 1, Day&#xD;
             1, with the exception of those with a negligible risk of metastasis or death and with&#xD;
             expected curative outcome (such as adequately treated carcinoma in situ of the cervix,&#xD;
             basal or squamous cell skin cancer, localized prostate cancer treated surgically with&#xD;
             curative intent, or ductal carcinoma in situ treated surgically with curative intent)&#xD;
             or undergoing active surveillance per standard-of-care management (e.g. prostate&#xD;
             cancer with Gleason score 6, and prostate-specific antigen (PSA) 10 mg/mL, etc).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should agree to not donate blood while participating in this study or for at&#xD;
             least 90 days following the last infusion of durvalumab or tremelimumab&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Samuel Funt, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Samuel Funt, MD</last_name>
    <phone>646-888-4770</phone>
    <email>funts@mskcc.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Darren Feldman, MD</last_name>
    <phone>646-422-4491</phone>
    <email>feldmand@mskcc.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memoral Sloan Kettering Basking Ridge</name>
      <address>
        <city>Basking Ridge</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07920</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Samuel Funt, MD</last_name>
      <phone>646-888-4770</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Monmouth</name>
      <address>
        <city>Middletown</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07748</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Samuel Funt, MD</last_name>
      <phone>646-888-4770</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Bergen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montvale</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07645</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Samuel Funt, MD</last_name>
      <phone>646-888-4770</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Commack</name>
      <address>
        <city>Commack</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11725</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Samuel Funt, MD</last_name>
      <phone>646-888-4770</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memoral Sloan Kettering Westchester</name>
      <address>
        <city>Harrison</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10604</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Samuel Funt, MD</last_name>
      <phone>646-888-4770</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Samuel Funt, MD</last_name>
      <phone>646-888-4770</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Nassau</name>
      <address>
        <city>Uniondale</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11553</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Samuel Funt, MD</last_name>
      <phone>646-888-4770</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mskcc.org</url>
    <description>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 16, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 16, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 17, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>17-160</keyword>
  <keyword>durvalumab</keyword>
  <keyword>tremelimumab</keyword>
  <keyword>MEDI4736</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Germ Cell and Embryonal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Seminoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dysgerminoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Durvalumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tremelimumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

