<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03157388</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1-10-72-1-15</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03157388</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Gut Sterilisation on Macrophage Activation in Patients With Alcoholic Hepatitis.</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Gut Sterilisation on Macrophage Activation in Patients With Alcoholic Hepatitis.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Aarhus</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Aarhus</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Alcoholic hepatitis (AH) is a severe alcohol induced hepatic inflammation that leads to&#xD;
      jaundice and liver failure. Gut derived bacterial translocation to the liver is currently&#xD;
      thought to be one of the main inflammatory drivers of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This project investigates the effects of gut sterilisation with broad spectrum antibiotics in&#xD;
      patients with AH&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Alcoholic hepatitis (AH) is a severe alcohol induced hepatic inflammation that leads to&#xD;
      jaundice and liver failure. The incidence of AH is increasing and the disease is associated&#xD;
      with a high mortality. In spite of numerous clinical trials both treatment and prognosis have&#xD;
      remained essentially unchanged for decades, emphasizing the need to improve our understanding&#xD;
      of the disease mechanisms behind AH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current perception of the pathogenesis of alcohol-induced liver injury mainly derives&#xD;
      from animal models, and the resident hepatic macrophages, the Kupffer cells, seem to play an&#xD;
      important role. Activation of these cells may give rise to most of the hallmark clinical&#xD;
      findings of AH: The cytokines released initiate hepatic inflammation and an acute phase&#xD;
      response, recruit neutrophils, and activate stellate cells, contributing to the acute portal&#xD;
      hypertension. Jaundice is due to intrahepatic cholestasis caused by down regulation of the&#xD;
      bilirubin transporters on the basolateral hepatocyte membrane. Hepatic macrophages are&#xD;
      thought to be activated by the bacterial derived endotoxins/lipopolysaccharides (LPS) present&#xD;
      in the portal blood because of an alcohol-induced increase in gut-blood permeability with&#xD;
      translocation of bacteria, as found in patients with alcoholic liver injury. LPS is&#xD;
      recognized by the hepatic macrophages via a membrane complex including the pathogen&#xD;
      recognition receptor molecule Toll-like receptor 4 (TLR-4). LPS Binding Proteins (LBP)&#xD;
      produced by hepatocytes then bind and present LPS to the membrane glycoprotein CD14 that in&#xD;
      turn activates TLR-4. In support of these mechanisms, alcohol-induced liver injury is reduced&#xD;
      in knockout mice missing LBP, CD14, and TLR-4. Likewise, chemical destruction of hepatic&#xD;
      macrophages in rats prevents alcohol-induced liver injury, as does cleansing the gut flora&#xD;
      with antibiotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Human hepatic macrophages when activated, express their surface receptor CD163. We and others&#xD;
      have previously shown that sCD163 is released from the liver in alcoholic liver disease, that&#xD;
      its plasma concentration predicts mortality in patients with acute liver failure and is as a&#xD;
      marker of portal hypertension and a predictor of clinical decompensation in patients with&#xD;
      liver cirrhosis. Very recently we have directly demonstrated hepatic macrophage activation in&#xD;
      human AH paralleling the disease severity, and to suggest this to be elicited by LPS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The line of evidence presented above provides rationale for testing whether intervention&#xD;
      toward bacterial translocation may result in a diminished immune response in human AH.&#xD;
      Consequently, in this study the investigators seek to perform total gut microbiota&#xD;
      eradication by combining 3 different orally administered antibiotics. The investigators have&#xD;
      chosen antibiotics that are not absorbed into the systemic circulation, because the&#xD;
      investigators want to limit the effects to the gastrointestinal tract.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 1, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 1, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>15 patients with alcoholic hepatitis will be consecutively included and compared to a historical cohort of AH patients</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Macrophage activation cd163</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in serum levels of macrophage activation markers sCD163</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>LBP</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>serum levels of Lipopolysaccaride binding protein</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>TNF alfa</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>serum levels of, Tumor Necrosis Factor-alfa</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Interleukin-1b</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>serum levels of, Interleukin-1b</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Alcoholic Hepatitis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Combined Vancomycin and Gentamycin and Meropenem</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Combined Vancomycin and Gentamycin and Meropenem</intervention_name>
    <description>The following combined antibiotic regime will be administered for eradication of gut bacteria.&#xD;
7 days combined antibiotic treatment, per oral route, once daily: vancomycin 500 mg (Vancomycin &quot;Hospira&quot;), powder for concentrate and gentamycin 40 mg (&quot;Hexamycin®&quot;), solution and meropenem 500 mg (Meropenem &quot;Hospira&quot;), powder for concentrate; The three drugs are dissolved and combined in approximately 100 ml of apple juice.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A first time diagnose of AH by a combination of physical and laboratory criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. A history of excessive alcohol ingestion (10 units or more per day) until at least&#xD;
             three weeks before admission&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Acute jaundice (developed over at most 2 weeks, serum bilirubin &gt; 80 μmol/l).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. liverbiopsy will be performed in case of doubt regarding the diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Non-native speaking Danish&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Viral hepatitis,&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Autoimmune liver disease,&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Bile duct obstruction,&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Liver tumours or any other cancer,&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Presence of an infectious focus (either clinically assessed or based on chest x-ray,&#xD;
             urine samples or ascites puncture),&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. On-going gastrointestinal bleeding or bleeding within the previous three months&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any prior immune-modulating therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Any known gastrointestinal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Contraindications against/allergy towards the used antibiotics&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hendrik D Vilstrup, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Aarhus University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aarhus University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aarhus</city>
        <zip>8000</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 15, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 16, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 17, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 22, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 22, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 23, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>inflammation</keyword>
  <keyword>Macrophages</keyword>
  <keyword>CD163</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis, Alcoholic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vancomycin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gentamicins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Meropenem</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

