<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00863408</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999909093</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>09-I-N093</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00863408</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Estivation of Malaria Vector Mosquitoes in the Sahelian Region of Mali</brief_title>
  <official_title>Estivation of Malaria Vector Mosquitoes in the Sahelian Region of Mali (Village of Thierola in the District of Banamba)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  P. falciparum, one of the most virulent forms of malaria, causes more than 300 million&#xD;
           episodes of malaria and 1 million deaths each year. The spread of drug-resistant&#xD;
           parasites, insecticide-resistant mosquitoes, and persistent socioeconomic conditions of&#xD;
           poverty compound the difficulties of malaria as a major global health problem. New means&#xD;
           of disease and vector control are vitally needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Several promising strategies rely on targeting mosquito populations when they are most&#xD;
           vulnerable, such as during the dry season when mosquitoes find it difficult to&#xD;
           reproduce. Large regions of the West African country of Mali have prolonged dry seasons&#xD;
           (up to 8 months), during which mosquito populations dramatically decline within a month&#xD;
           after the rainfall ceases. Clearly, mosquitoes can survive the dry season (as evident&#xD;
           from their robust numbers during the wet season) but the process that enables them to do&#xD;
           so remains unknown. Targeting the small and fragile mosquito population at the end of&#xD;
           the dry season could reduce or eliminate the numbers of mosquitoes in certain regions,&#xD;
           providing great benefits for communities in dry regions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine if common malaria-carrying mosquitoes survive the dry season in the Mali&#xD;
           village of Thierola by estivation (going dormant, or hibernating, during dry periods).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To identify and examine mosquitoes that were marked with special paint during a previous&#xD;
           protocol, if these marked mosquitoes are captured during the investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  All activities in this protocol will take place in Thierola village, Banamba district,&#xD;
           Koulikoro region, Mall, West Africa. The village was chosen because it is isolated from&#xD;
           other communities by at least 6 km and is a small community of less than 300 inhabitants&#xD;
           living in 90 houses.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be healthy adult men between 18 and 65 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Thirty adult men who live in Thierola will be recruited to participate as mosquito&#xD;
           collectors for the human-baited trapping method and will work in teams of two.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The first collector will expose his lower legs to attract human-seeking mosquitoes.&#xD;
           Using a mouth aspirator, the second collector will collect the mosquitoes as they land&#xD;
           on the first collector's legs.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The collections will be conducted both indoors and outdoors from 6 p.m. to 6 a.m. the&#xD;
           following morning for 14 consecutive days.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  All study volunteers will be trained in proper collection technique and supervised&#xD;
           throughout the study by a mobile team led by the study investigators. Volunteers will be&#xD;
           monitored for signs of malaria and treated accordingly if they develop symptoms of the&#xD;
           disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Researchers will collect mosquito samples at the end of the dry season (April-May) and&#xD;
           at the start of the rainy season (May-June).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Mosquitoes collected in the study will be analyzed by NIH researchers to learn more&#xD;
           about how they survive during the dry season.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Malaria causes over one million deaths annually. A promising control strategy relies on&#xD;
      targeting mosquito populations when they are vulnerable, such as during the dry season.&#xD;
      Prolonged dry season during which larval sites are scarce and mosquito populations decline&#xD;
      prevail in the Sahel which covers a large part of Mali. How mosquitoes withstand the dry&#xD;
      season remains unknown. Some evidence supports the adult estivation hypothesis whereby&#xD;
      mosquitoes remain in protected sites, except for sporadic journeys to obtain blood-meals to&#xD;
      sustain themselves rather than to produce eggs. Alternatively, mosquitoes do not survive the&#xD;
      dry season locally; rather, they migrate from areas where reproduction continues at permanent&#xD;
      water bodies. We aim to determine if An. Gambiae estivate during the dry season in the Sahel;&#xD;
      and if so, identify their hidden resting sites. As mosquito populations decline, standard&#xD;
      sampling techniques yield zero mosquitoes. Because estivating females take blood meals&#xD;
      intermittently, the most promising sampling technique is by human landing catch (HLC).&#xD;
      Finding a few mosquitoes during the dry season have been reported, but it could not be&#xD;
      determined if they were estivating or were migrants from villages, where larval sites&#xD;
      persist. This study can resolve this because we captured marked and released over 5000&#xD;
      mosquitoes just before the dry season (November 2008). We aim to collect mosquitoes during&#xD;
      the end of the dry season (April 2009) and the onset of the rainy season (June 2009) and find&#xD;
      out if they bear marks from the previous wet season. Finding a single marked specimen will be&#xD;
      the ultimate proof for the estivation hypothesis. Experiments will take place in the Sahelian&#xD;
      village Thierola, Koulikoro Region, Mali, where the dry season exceeds 7 months. The village&#xD;
      was chosen because it has no permanent larval sites and is a small community (&lt; 300&#xD;
      inhabitants) living in 90 houses, allowing collection in all houses in a single day. Thirty&#xD;
      adult male residing in Thierola will be recruited as collectors for the HLC. A collector will&#xD;
      expose his lower legs to attract mosquitoes. Using a mouth aspirator, mosquitoes will be&#xD;
      collected as they land on the collector's legs, ideally, before a blood meal is taken.&#xD;
      Collection will be conducted 6pm to 6am for 14 consecutive days in April 2009 and again after&#xD;
      the rains begin in June 2009. Collectors will be informed of the proper collecting procedures&#xD;
      during the consenting procedure. During the time of year we propose to conduct this work,&#xD;
      mosquito populations will be at their minima and any surviving mosquitoes will take blood&#xD;
      meals infrequently. Therefore, the HLCs will be conducted when malaria transmission is&#xD;
      extremely low and the risk to volunteers essentially nil. In summary, knowledge of how&#xD;
      mosquitoes survive the dry season would open novel ways for vector and malaria control.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 3, 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date>March 10, 2010</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <condition>Malaria</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18-65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Only healthy male adults who are free of acute and chronic illnesses will participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Permanent residency in Thierola&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to collect mosquitoes after being trained&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Beier JC, Killeen GF, Githure JI. Short report: entomologic inoculation rates and Plasmodium falciparum malaria prevalence in Africa. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 1999 Jul;61(1):109-13.</citation>
    <PMID>10432066</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hay SI, Rogers DJ, Toomer JF, Snow RW. Annual Plasmodium falciparum entomological inoculation rates (EIR) across Africa: literature survey, Internet access and review. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg. 2000 Mar-Apr;94(2):113-27. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>10897348</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Simard F, Lehmann T, Lemasson JJ, Diatta M, Fontenille D. Persistence of Anopheles arabiensis during the severe dry season conditions in Senegal: an indirect approach using microsatellite loci. Insect Mol Biol. 2000 Oct;9(5):467-79.</citation>
    <PMID>11029665</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 10, 2010</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 17, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 17, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 18, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Mosquito</keyword>
  <keyword>Human Landing Collection</keyword>
  <keyword>Malaria</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

