<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04725058</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1443169</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04725058</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Obesity Group Visits. A Novel Way to Approach the Obesity Epidemic in an Inner-City Setting</brief_title>
  <official_title>Obesity Group Visits. A Novel Way to Approach the Obesity Epidemic in an Inner-City Setting</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Charles Drew University of Medicine and Science</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Charles Drew University of Medicine and Science</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study has two aims: Aim 1: To compare a medical group visit model versus&#xD;
      a dietitian-let model (shared composite group visit approach vs individualized dietitian-led&#xD;
      approach) to provide obesity care in a real-world diverse inner city population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2. To use both perivascular fat attenuation and coronary artery calcium (CAC) scores in&#xD;
      those receiving composite group intervention vs. dietitian-led intervention to see if&#xD;
      lifestyle intervention can reduce plaque progression and improve perivascular fat&#xD;
      attenuation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      After being informed about the study and potential risks, all study participants giving&#xD;
      written informed consent will be screened to determine eligibility for study entry. At week&#xD;
      0, study participants who meet the eligibility requirements will be randomized in a blind&#xD;
      manner (participant only) in a 3:1 block ratio. The study will randomize 750 subjects to the&#xD;
      composite group visit and 250 subjects to the dietitian-led group into a 12-months duration&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For Aim 2: A subset of 200 participants who identify as female and over 50 years old and&#xD;
      males over 40 years old randomized to either the composite group arm or the dietitian-led arm&#xD;
      will have the option to take part in a sub-study that involves getting a Coronary Artery&#xD;
      Calcium (CAC) scan done at the Lundquist Institute. The first 125 subjects in the composite&#xD;
      group arm and the first 75 subjects in the dietitian-led arm that express interest and want&#xD;
      to undergo CAC scanning and perivascular fat measurements at baseline and at 12-months of&#xD;
      intervention will need to sign a separate consent for these procedures. CAC scan readers will&#xD;
      be blind to the assigned group. A group of 100 subjects not participating in the aim 1&#xD;
      intervention will be able to join the study under the control group. These participants will&#xD;
      not be randomly assigned.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 3, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Weight</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, months 3, 6 and 12.</time_frame>
    <description>Weight will be measured at baseline and at 3,6, and 12 months.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, months 3, 6 and 12.</time_frame>
    <description>Hemoglobin A1c will be measured at baseline, and at moths 0, 3, 6 and 12 to determine the effect of the intervention arm.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Healthy Eating Index-2015 Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, months 3, 6 and 12.</time_frame>
    <description>Diet quality will be assessed by the healthy eating Index-2015 score calculated from the food frequency questionnaire using the diet history questionnaire tool (DHQ) version III software. The minimum and maximum scores ranges fron 0 to 100. Higher scores greater than 60 indicate better diet quality.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Physical Activity Measures</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, months 3, 6 and 12.</time_frame>
    <description>The IPAQ short form is a seven-item instrument evaluation tool of physical activity among the adults that measures a range of physical activity from vigorous to sedentary over the last 7 days. The specific type of activities assessed are walking, moderate intensity activities and vigorous intensity activities. All continuous scores are expressed in metabolic equivalent minutes(MET-minutes) per week with walking =3.3 METs, Moderate PA=4.0 METs and Vigorous PA = 8.0 METs. An overall total physical activity score can be computed as the sum of the total MET-minutes/week scores where more MET-minutes per week indicate more physical activity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in General Health Questionnaire (GHQ-12) Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, months 3, 6 and 12.</time_frame>
    <description>The General Health Questionnaire (GHQ-12) consists of 12-item rating scale for assessing psychological distress over the past few weeks. Scale score ranges from 0-12, with a higher score indicating a higher level of psychological distress.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Social Determinants of Health Factors (SDOH, PRAPARE (Protocol for Responding to and Addressing Patient Assets, Risks, and Experiences) tool.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and at month-12.</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline to 12-month follow-up PRAPARE score. The PRAPARE assessment tool will be used to calculate a tally risk score indicating the cumulative number of SDOH risks a patient faces (including 15 SDOH domains).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Coronary Artery Calcification (CAC) score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 12 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Coronary Artery Scanning will be measured at baseline and at month 12 to determine calcium scores.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Medical Group Visit</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive obesity management in a group setting let by endocrinologist and nutritionist.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dietitian-Led Visit</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participant receives obesity management in an individual setting lead by registered dietitian.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Medical Group Visit</intervention_name>
    <description>A group of 20 or more participants will receive obesity management through endocrinologist and registered dietitian in a group seetting.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Medical Group Visit</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Medical Group</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dietitian Individual Visit</intervention_name>
    <description>Participant receives obesity management individually from a registered dietitian.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dietitian-Led Visit</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  Inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Age ≥ 18&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  BMI ≥ 30 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Male, Female, LGBT&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any ethnicity&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Interested in weight loss and be open to being randomized in either a medical&#xD;
                  group visit arm or dietitian-led arm (willingly agree to sign consent form)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Currently within or be eligible to receive care at LAC-DHS and be empaneled to&#xD;
                  have a primary care provider (PCP) who can adjust their medicines including&#xD;
                  anti-hypertensive and diabetic medications if needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If had stopped taking weight loss medication (orlistat, lorcaserin, and&#xD;
                  phentermine/topiramate-ER, phenetermine, diethylpropion, phendimetrazine and&#xD;
                  benzphetamine) for at least 2 months prior enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If had stopped taking supplements advertised to increase weight loss at least 3&#xD;
                  months prior enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Females &gt;50 years of age and Males &gt;40 years of age meet inclusion criteria to participate&#xD;
        in the sub-study that involves getting a Coronary Artery Calcium (CAC) scan done at the&#xD;
        Lundquist Institute.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt;18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI&lt; 30 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to sing consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently participating in another obesity treatment program&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently on a weight loss medication (orlistat, lorcaserin, and&#xD;
             phentermine/topiramate-ER, phenetermine, diethylpropion, phendimetrazine and&#xD;
             benzphetamine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently on metformin or topiramate primarily prescribed for weight loss&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ineligible to receive care at LAC-DHS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with mental illness, substance abuse issues as well as other illnesses who are&#xD;
             unable to follow directions related to the study or becomes disruptive to the overall&#xD;
             group&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had bariatric surgery less than a year from time of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Females &lt;50 years of age and Males &lt;40 years of age are not eligible to participate in the&#xD;
        sub-study that involves getting a Coronary Artery Calcium (CAC) scan done at the Lundquist&#xD;
        Institute.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Theodore Friedman, MD. PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Charles Drew University of Medicine and Science</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Petra Duran</last_name>
    <phone>3233573428</phone>
    <email>petraduran@cdrewu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Chrsitina Moldovan, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>5627742264</phone>
    <email>cristinamoldovan@cdrewu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Charles R. Drew University of Medicine and Science</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90059</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Petra Duran</last_name>
      <phone>323-357-3428</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ogden CL, Carroll MD, Kit BK, Flegal KM. Prevalence of childhood and adult obesity in the United States, 2011-2012. JAMA. 2014 Feb 26;311(8):806-14. doi: 10.1001/jama.2014.732.</citation>
    <PMID>24570244</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Knowler WC, Barrett-Connor E, Fowler SE, Hamman RF, Lachin JM, Walker EA, Nathan DM; Diabetes Prevention Program Research Group. Reduction in the incidence of type 2 diabetes with lifestyle intervention or metformin. N Engl J Med. 2002 Feb 7;346(6):393-403.</citation>
    <PMID>11832527</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ryan DH, Bray GA. Pharmacologic treatment options for obesity: what is old is new again. Curr Hypertens Rep. 2013 Jun;15(3):182-9. doi: 10.1007/s11906-013-0343-6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23625271</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Carvajal R, Wadden TA, Tsai AG, Peck K, Moran CH. Managing obesity in primary care practice: a narrative review. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2013 Apr;1281:191-206. doi: 10.1111/nyas.12004. Epub 2013 Jan 16. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23323827</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vadheim LM, Brewer KA, Kassner DR, Vanderwood KK, Hall TO, Butcher MK, Helgerson SD, Harwell TS. Effectiveness of a lifestyle intervention program among persons at high risk for cardiovascular disease and diabetes in a rural community. J Rural Health. 2010 Summer;26(3):266-72. doi: 10.1111/j.1748-0361.2010.00288.x.</citation>
    <PMID>20633095</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 21, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Charles Drew University of Medicine and Science</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Theodore Friedman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All IPD that underlie results in a publication.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>starting 6 months after publication.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Contact Petra Duran and PI directly.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

