<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04724447</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04724447</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>ANTIVIRAL TREATMENT OF CYTOMEGALOVIRUS IN DEPRESSION</brief_title>
  <official_title>EXPERIMENTAL ANTIVIRAL TREATMENT OF CYTOMEGALOVIRUS IN DEPRESSION: AFFECTIVE, NEURAL, AND INFLAMMATORY MECHANISMS</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Laureate Institute for Brain Research, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Laureate Institute for Brain Research, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to determine whether treatment of CMV positive (CMV+) individuals with major&#xD;
      depressive disorder (MDD) with valganciclovir (VGCV) alters neural circuitry, reduces&#xD;
      inflammation, and improves depressive behavior and symptoms to a greater extent than placebo.&#xD;
      In this double-blind, randomized placebo-controlled, parallel group trial, 24 individuals&#xD;
      with a Quick Inventory of Depressive Symptomatology-Self Report (QIDS-SR) scale score ≥ 14&#xD;
      will be enrolled to participate in an 8-week treatment study. Participants will be randomized&#xD;
      with a 1-1 ratio to receive 900 milligrams (mg) VGCV or placebo to be taken orally once per&#xD;
      day. Participants will complete a 2-hour pre-screen, a baseline blood-draw, clinical&#xD;
      evaluation, and MRI scan (visit 2), a clinical evaluation, blood draw, and MRI scan at week 4&#xD;
      (visit 6), and a clinical evaluation, blood draw, and MRI scan at week 8 (visit 10). Weekly&#xD;
      telephonic visits to assess depressive symptoms and side effects will held between the&#xD;
      in-person assessments.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>White matter integrity of the inferior fronto-occipital fasciculus (IFOF)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Mean fractional anisotropy of the IFOF measured with diffusion tensor imaging</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Volume of the medial temporal gyrus (MTG)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Mean gray matter volume of the MTG measured with structural MRI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Volume of the orbitofrontal cortex (OFC)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Mean gray matter volume of the OFC measured with structural MRI</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Inflammatory mediators</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Serum concentration of inflammatory mediators: CXCL10, sCD14, and TNF measured with ELISA or the Mesoscale Discovery Platform</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>CD8+ cells</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of terminally differentiated CD8+ cells (TEMRA cells) measured with flow cytometry</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Anhedonia</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Symptoms of anhedonia measured with the Snaith-Hamilton Pleasure Scale (SHAPS). Higher scores are indicative of greater anhedonia.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Depression</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Symptoms of depression measured with the Montgomery-Asberg Depression Rating Scale (MADRS). Higher scores are indicative of more severe depression.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Major Depressive Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Valganciclovir</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>900 milligrams (mg) valganciclovir (VGCV) to be taken orally once per day for 8 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo equivalent of 900 milligrams (mg) VGCV to be taken orally once per day for 8 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Valganciclovir</intervention_name>
    <description>2 x 450mg VGCV tablets</description>
    <arm_group_label>Valganciclovir</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo equivalent of 900mg/day VGCV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Provision of signed and dated informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Stated willingness to comply with all study procedures and availability for the&#xD;
             duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Male or female, aged 18-65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Diagnosis with major depressive disorder (MDD)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Current symptoms of depression, that is, a QIDS-SR score ≥14.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Unmedicated for at least 4 weeks (8 weeks for fluoxetine).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. In good general health as evidenced by medical history, physical exam, and safety labs&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Ability to take oral medication and be willing to adhere to the VGCV regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. For females of reproductive potential: use of highly effective contraception for at&#xD;
             least 1 month prior to screening and agreement to use such a method during study&#xD;
             participation and for an additional 4 weeks after the end of VGCV administration&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. For males of reproductive potential: use of condoms or other methods to ensure&#xD;
             effective contraception with partner during the study and for at least 90 days after&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Agreement to adhere to Lifestyle Considerations (see section 5.3) throughout study&#xD;
             duration&#xD;
&#xD;
             Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
             General Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Breast-feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unwillingness to avoid pregnancy during the study due to the possible teratogenic&#xD;
                  effects of valganciclovir&#xD;
&#xD;
             Medical Conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Moderate to severe traumatic brain injury (&gt;30 min. loss of consciousness or &gt;24&#xD;
                  hours posttraumatic amnesia) or other neurocognitive disorder with evidence of&#xD;
                  neurological deficits.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of co-morbid medical conditions not limited to but including&#xD;
                  cardiovascular (e.g., history of acute coronary event, stroke) and neurological&#xD;
                  diseases (e.g., Parkinson's disease), as well as pain disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of co-morbid inflammatory disorders such as rheumatoid arthritis or&#xD;
                  other autoimmune disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of an uncontrolled medical condition that is deemed by the investigators&#xD;
                  to interfere with the proposed study procedures, or to put the study participant&#xD;
                  at undue risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of a chronic infection (e.g. HIV) that may elevate pro-inflammatory&#xD;
                  cytokines.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of an acute infectious illness (e.g. SARS CoV-2) or receipt of a&#xD;
                  vaccination in the week prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Psychiatric Disorders:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current significant suicidal ideation (intent to commit suicide or making&#xD;
                  specific plans for suicide)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Suicide attempt within the last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Lifetime history of schizophrenia, schizophreniform, schizoaffective disorder,&#xD;
                  delusional disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of a manic or hypomanic episode not better accounted for by substance use&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Moderate to severe substance use disorder within the last year, excluding&#xD;
                  cannabis or nicotine use disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Moderate or severe alcohol use disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Positive urine toxicology (except cannabis)&#xD;
&#xD;
             Contraindications to Valganciclovir:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Myelosuppressive chemotherapy or radiation therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count &lt; 500/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count &lt; 25,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin &lt; 8g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Impaired renal function (estimated glomerular filtration rate&#xD;
                  &lt;60mL/minute/1.73m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Sensitivity to VGCV, ganciclovir or other nucleoside analogues&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Medications that could interact with VGCV (see below):&#xD;
&#xD;
             Prohibited Medications Abacavir Lamivudine, 3TC Amikacin Aminoglycosides Amphotericin&#xD;
             B cholesteryl sulfate complex (ABCD) Amphotericin B lipid complex (ABLC) Amphotericin&#xD;
             B liposomal (LAmB) Amphotericin B Aprotinin Bacitracin Bictegravir; Emtricitabine;&#xD;
             Tenofovir Alafenamide Cisplatin Colchicine; Probenecid Cyclosporine Dapsone Darunavir;&#xD;
             Cobicistat; Emtricitabine; Tenofovir alafenamide&#xD;
&#xD;
             Didanosine, ddI:&#xD;
&#xD;
             Doravirine; Lamivudine; Tenofovir disoproxil fumarate Doxorubicin Efavirenz;&#xD;
             Emtricitabine; Tenofovir Efavirenz; Lamivudine; Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate&#xD;
             Elvitegravir; Cobicistat; Emtricitabine; Tenofovir Alafenamide Elvitegravir;&#xD;
             Cobicistat; Emtricitabine; Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate Emtricitabine Emtricitabine;&#xD;
             Rilpivirine; Tenofovir alafenamide Emtricitabine; Rilpivirine; Tenofovir disoproxil&#xD;
             fumarate Emtricitabine; Tenofovir alafenamide Emtricitabine; Tenofovir disoproxil&#xD;
             fumarate Entecavir Flucytosine Gentamicin Hyaluronidase, Recombinant; Immune Globulin&#xD;
             Hydroxyurea Imipenem; Cilastatin Immune Globulin IV, IVIG, IGIV Kanamycin Lamivudine;&#xD;
             Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate Mycophenolate Paromomycin Pentamidine Plazomicin&#xD;
             Polymyxin B Streptomycin Sulfamethoxazole; Trimethoprim, SMX-TMP, Cotrimoxazole&#xD;
             Tacrolimus Talimogene Laherparepvec Telbivudine Tenofovir Alafenamide Tenofovir, PMPA&#xD;
             Tobramycin Trimethoprim Vancomycin Vinblastine Vinca alkaloids Vincristine Liposomal&#xD;
             Vincristine Vinorelbine Zidovudine&#xD;
&#xD;
             Other Medications:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current and/or past regular use of hormone-containing medications (excluding&#xD;
                  contraceptives)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current use of non-steroid anti-inflammatory drugs that is deemed by the&#xD;
                  investigators to potentially confound the results of the study or the increase&#xD;
                  risk of renal impairment (e.g. more than 3 days/week).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current and/or past regular use of immune modifying drugs that target specific&#xD;
                  immune responses such as TNF antagonists&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chronic use of antibiotics such as isotretinoin or minocycline because of their&#xD;
                  potential effects on the microbiome and immune function.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current and/or past regular use of antiarrhythmic, anti-anginal, and&#xD;
                  anticoagulant drugs (does not apply where medications are taken for different&#xD;
                  purpose).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Inclusion of individuals reporting other types of medications or supplements not&#xD;
                  listed or considered thus far will be at the discretion of the PI based on their&#xD;
                  potential to affect immune function, brain function or brain blood flow.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Contraindications to MRI:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cardiac pacemaker, metal fragments in eyes/skin/body (shrapnel), aortic/aneurysm&#xD;
                  clips, prosthesis, by-pass surgery/coronary artery clips, hearing aid, heart&#xD;
                  valve replacement, shunt (ventricular or spinal), electrodes, metal&#xD;
                  plates/pins/screws/wires, or neuro/bio-stimulators (TENS unit), persons who have&#xD;
                  ever been a professional metal worker/welder, history of eye surgery/eyes washed&#xD;
                  out because of metal, vision problems uncorrectable with lenses, inability to lie&#xD;
                  still on one's back for 60 minutes; prior neurosurgery; tattoos or cosmetic&#xD;
                  makeup with metal dyes, unwillingness to remove body piercings, and pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Claustrophobia severe enough to prevent scanning&#xD;
&#xD;
             Health Factors:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  BMI &gt; 38 because of the effects of obesity on pro-inflammatory cytokine activity&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clinically significant abnormalities on screening laboratory tests&#xD;
&#xD;
             Non-English speaking participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
             • The majority of the assessments proposed for this study have not been translated&#xD;
             from English, thus, non-English speaking volunteers will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jonathan Savitz, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>918 502 5104</phone>
    <email>jsavitz@laureateinstitute.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Laureate Institute for Brain Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tulsa</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <zip>74136</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Valganciclovir</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

