<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04723004</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>JS001-035-III-HCC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04723004</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of Toripalimab Combined With Bevacizumab Versus Sorafenib Therapy for HCC</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Open-label, Multi-center Phase III Clinical Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of Toripalimab (JS001) Combined With Bevacizumab Versus Sorafenib as First-line Therapy for Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Shanghai Junshi Bioscience Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Shanghai Junshi Bioscience Co., Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, randomized, open-label, parallel-group, active controlled,&#xD;
      multi-center phase III registration clinical study to observe, compare and evaluate the&#xD;
      efficacy and safety of Toripalimab (hereafter referred to as JS001) combined with Bevacizumab&#xD;
      versus Sorafenib as the first-line therapy for advanced HCC This study will enroll the&#xD;
      patients with locally advanced or metastatic hepatocellular carcinoma who could not be&#xD;
      radically cured and not receive any prior systemic therapy. The study will use PFS and OS as&#xD;
      the co-primary endpoints, with approximately 280 patients planned to be enrolled.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>A duration from the date of initial treatment with Toripalimab Plus Bevacizumab or Sorafenib to disease progression (defined by RECIST 1.1) or death of any cause, whichever comes first.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Duration from the date of initial treatment with Toripalimab Plus Bevacizumab or Sorafenib monotherapy to the date of death due to any cause.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ORR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The rate of participants that achieve either a complete response (CR) or a partial response (PR).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>DoR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Duration from the first time reported partial response or complete response to the first time of disease progression or death.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Control Rate (DCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with reduction and non-change in tumor burden of a predefined amount, including complete remission, partial remission and stable disease</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>TTP</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Define as the time from randomization to the first documented disease progression</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of AEs/SAEs as Assessed by CTCAE v5.0</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of consent informed until 60 days after the last investigational product administration. Up to 2 approximately years.</time_frame>
    <description>Analysis of adverse events (AEs) are based on treatment-related AEs (trAEs) and immune-related AEs (irAEs), and all-grade AEs and grade 3-4 AEs. AEs are evaluated by investigators according to the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events, version 5.0</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>TMB</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 years</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between tumor mutation burden (TMB) and the efficacy of Toripalimab combined with Bevacizumab</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ADA</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 years</time_frame>
    <description>Serum levels and incidence of Anti-drug antibody of Toripalimab combined with Bevacizumab treatment group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">280</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma (HCC)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Toripalimab combined with Bevacizumab</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Sorafenib</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Toripalimab combined with Bevacizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Experimental group:&#xD;
Toripalimab, 240mg, IV infusion, every 3 weeks (q3w). combined with Bevacizumab 15mg/kg, IV infusion, every 3 weeks (q3w), Continuous infusion, in a cycle of 3 weeks (21 days), until occurrence of termination event specified in the protocol.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sorafenib</intervention_name>
    <description>Control group:&#xD;
Sorafenib 400mg, po, Bid, continuous administration, until occurrence of termination event specified in the protocol.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Patients meeting all the following inclusion criteria can be enrolled in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age of 18-75 years (inclusive), male or female.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Histological or cytological diagnosis of HCC or clinical diagnosis of HCC in cirrhotic&#xD;
             patients per the American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases (AASLD)&#xD;
             guideline.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Barcelona Clinic Liver Cancer (BCLC) stage Category B or C , and unsuitable for radical&#xD;
        surgical and/or local therapy, or has progressed following surgical and/or local therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. No previous systemic therapy for HCC, mainly including systemic chemotherapy,&#xD;
        anti-angiogenic drugs or other molecular targeted therapy, immunotherapy containing CTLA-4,&#xD;
        PD-1/PD-L1 monoclonal antibody) for HCC.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Having ≥ 1 measurable lesion per RECISTv1.1. Requirement: the selected target lesion has&#xD;
        not been treated locally before, or is located in the area of previous local therapy, but&#xD;
        determined as PD through radiological examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Child-Pugh class A, with no history of hepatic encephalopathy. 6. Eastern Cooperative&#xD;
        Oncology Group Performance Status (ECOG PS) status of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Predicted life expectancy ≥12 weeks. 8. Adequate hematologic and end-organ function 9.&#xD;
        In case of HBsAg (+) and/or HBcAb (+), HBV DNA is required to be &lt; 500 IU/mL, and it is&#xD;
        required to continue the effective anti-HBV therapy that has been adopted in the full&#xD;
        course, or start to use entecavir or tenofovir after screening in the full course during&#xD;
        the study; Patients with anti-HCV antibody positive and HCV-RNA&gt;103 copies/mL will be&#xD;
        excluded; HBV/HCV co-infected patients, i.e., positive for both HbsAg and HCV-RNA, will be&#xD;
        excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
        10. Female subjects of childbearing potential must receive serum pregnancy test within 7&#xD;
        days before randomization and the result should be negative, and should be willing to adopt&#xD;
        reliable and effective contraceptive methods during the trial and within 60 days after the&#xD;
        last dose of study drug. The male patients whose partners are women of childbearing&#xD;
        potential must agree to use reliable and effective contraceptive methods during the trial&#xD;
        and within 60 days after the last dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
        11. Being voluntary to participate in the study, sufficiently informed consent and&#xD;
        signature of written informed consent form, with good compliance.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients can not be enrolled in the study if any one of the following criteria is&#xD;
        fulfilled:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Known cholangiocellular carcinoma (ICC) or mixed cell carcinoma, sarcomatoid HCC and&#xD;
             hepatic fibrolamellar carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of malignancy other than HCC within 5 years prior to screening, with the&#xD;
             exception of cured localized malignancies including cervical carcinoma in situ, skin&#xD;
             basal cell carcinoma and carcinoma in situ of prostate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Hepatic surgery and/or local therapy or investigational treatment with for HCC within&#xD;
             4 weeks prior to randomization, or palliative radiotherapy for bone metastatic lesion&#xD;
             within 2 weeks prior to randomization, or Chinese medicine preparation with anti-liver&#xD;
             cancer effect within 2 weeks prior to randomization, and non-recovery (not recovered&#xD;
             to ≤ NCI-CTCAE v5.0 grade 1) from side effects of any such treatment (except&#xD;
             alopecia).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prior other anti-PD-1 antibody therapy or other immunotherapy against PD-1 / PD-L1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Uncontrolled pericardial effusion, uncontrolled pleural effusion or clinically obvious&#xD;
             moderate/severe pleural effusion at screening, defined as reaching the following&#xD;
             criteria: having clinical symptoms and physical examination identifies pleural&#xD;
             effusion; Paracentesis and/or intracavitary administration are required for pleural&#xD;
             effusion during screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of gastrointestinal hemorrhage within 6 months prior to randomization; the&#xD;
             patients with portal hypertension need to receive gastroscopy to exclude the patients&#xD;
             with &quot;red sign&quot;, if they are considered by investigators to have high risk for&#xD;
             hemorrhage (including moderate-to-severe esophageal and/or gastric varices with&#xD;
             hemorrhagic risk, locally active peptic ulcer and persistent fecal occult blood (+)).&#xD;
             The patient needs to be excluded if there is a history of &quot;red sign&quot; in gastroscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Having ≥ grade 3 (NCI-CTC AE v5.0) gastrointestinal or non-gastrointestinal fistula at&#xD;
             present.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Cancer thrombus in the main trunk of portal vein involving contralateral portal vein&#xD;
             branch, or involving superior mesenteric vein. Cancer thrombus in inferior vena cava&#xD;
             should be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Serious cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases:&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Having major bleeding and coagulation disorders or other obvious evidence on&#xD;
             hemorrhagic tendency:&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Medium to large surgical treatment within 4 weeks prior to randomization (except&#xD;
             diagnostic biopsy).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Central nervous system metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Serious, non-healing or dehiscing wound, active ulcer or untreated bone fracture.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Vaccination of live vaccine within 30 days prior to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Active autoimmune diseases requiring systemic treatment (i.e., immunomodulatory drug,&#xD;
             corticosteroid or immunosuppressant) in the past 2 years; however, replacement therapy&#xD;
             (e.g., thyroxine, insulin or physiological corticosteroid replacement therapy for&#xD;
             renal or pituitary insufficiency), inhaled or topical corticosteroids will not be&#xD;
             excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. History of clear interstitial lung disease or non-infectious pneumonia, unless induced&#xD;
             by local radiotherapy, or history of active tuberculosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Any serious acute and chronic infection requiring systemic antibacterial, antifungal&#xD;
             or antiviral therapy at screening, not including viral hepatitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Previously receiving allogeneic stem cell or solid organ transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Inability to swallow tablets, malabsorption syndrome or any condition that affects&#xD;
             gastrointestinal absorption.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Known history of serious allergy to any monoclonal antibody, targeted anti-angiogenic&#xD;
             drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Other unsuitable subjects as per the investigators.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bifeng Liu</last_name>
    <phone>18967116090</phone>
    <email>bifeng_liu@junshipharma.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jia Fan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Shanghai</city>
        <zip>130061</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jia Fan</last_name>
      <phone>86 21 31587871</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 21, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 21, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

