<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04728893</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1026-003</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-002324-36</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>MK-1026-003</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04728893</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Nemtabrutinib (MK-1026) in Participants With Hematologic Malignancies (MK-1026-003)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2 Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of MK-1026 in Participants With Hematologic Malignancies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of nemtabrutinib (formerly&#xD;
      ARQ 531) in participants with hematologic malignancies of chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL)/&#xD;
      small lymphocytic lymphoma (SLL), Richter's transformation, marginal zone lymphoma (MZL),&#xD;
      mantle cell lymphoma (MCL), follicular lymphoma (FL), and Waldenström's macroglobulinemia&#xD;
      (WM).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will be performed in 2 parts: Dose Escalation and Confirmation (Part 1) and Cohort&#xD;
      Expansion (Part 2). Following determination of a recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) in Part 1,&#xD;
      the study plans to proceed with Part 2 using 8 disease-specific expansion cohorts (Cohorts A&#xD;
      to H).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 5, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 19, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 19, 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1: Number of participants experiencing dose-limiting toxicities (DLTs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~56 days (Cycles 1-2, cycle = 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>DLTs will be defined as toxicities observed during the first 2 cycles (8 weeks) of Part 1 and include: Grade ≥3 nonhematologic toxicity (except Grade 3 nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, rash, fatigue, and uncontrolled hypertension which will not be considered a DLT unless lasting ≥72 hours despite optimal supportive care); Grade 4 hematologic toxicity lasting &gt;7 days (except Grade 3 lymphocytosis, Grade 4 platelet count decreased of any duration, or Grade 3 platelet count decreased if associated with bleeding); any Grade 3 or Grade 4 nonhematologic laboratory abnormality if values result in drug-induced liver injury, or medical intervention is required, or the abnormality leads to hospitalization, or the abnormality persists for &gt;1 week (with exceptions); missing &gt;25% of nemtabrutinib doses as a result of drug-related adverse events (AEs) during the first 2 cycles (8 weeks); Grade 5 toxicity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1: Number of participants experiencing adverse events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~78 months</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant, temporally associated with the use of study treatment, whether or not considered related to the study treatment. The number of participants experiencing AEs will be reported for Part 1.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1: Number of participants discontinuing study treatment due to AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~78 months</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant, temporally associated with the use of study treatment, whether or not considered related to the study treatment. The number of participants discontinuing study treatment due to an AE will be reported for Part 1.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Objective Response Rate (ORR) per International Workshop on Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (iwCLL) criteria 2018 as assessed by independent central review (ICR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~78 months</time_frame>
    <description>ORR per iwCLL 2018 criteria is defined as the percentage of participants achieving a complete response (CR), complete response with incomplete bone marrow recovery (CRi), nodular partial response (nPR), or partial response (PR). CR is defined as meeting the following criteria: no lymph nodes &gt;1.5 cm, spleen size &lt;13 cm, liver normal; no constitutional symptoms, normal lymphocyte count, platelets ≥100 x 10^9/L; hemoglobin ≥11 g/dL; and normocellular marrow (no CLL cells or B lymphoid nodules). CRi is defined as meeting CR criteria but with hypocellular bone marrow. nPR is defined as having features of CR but with lymphoid nodules in the marrow. PR is defined as ≥50% decrease in ≥2 of the following: lymph nodes, liver and/or spleen size, lymphocytes PLUS ≥1 of the following met: platelets ≥100 x 10^9/L or ≥50% increase from screening, hemoglobin &gt;11 g/dL or ≥50% increase from screening, CLL cells or B lymphoid nodules in marrow.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: ORR per Lugano criteria 2014 as assessed by ICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~78 months</time_frame>
    <description>ORR per Lugano criteria 2014 is defined as the percentage of participants achieving a CR or PR. CR defined as EITHER CR by imaging (computed tomography [CT]): all lymph nodes normal (none ≥15 mm) and normal liver and spleen OR complete metabolic response (CMR): score of 1, 2 or 3 on the 5-point scale assessing fluorodeoxyglucose (FDG) metabolic activity in lymphomatous lesions (ranging from 1=no uptake above background to 5=uptake markedly higher than liver) AND bone marrow (BM) normal by morphology. PR defined as EITHER PR by imaging (CT) with ≥50% decrease in the sum of the product of diameters [SPD] of target lesions, no worsening of nontarget lesions, no new lesions and ≥50% spleen abnormal portion OR Partial Metabolic Response (PMR) with score of 4 or 5 on the FDG 5-point scale (with no new lesions) and decreased overall uptake AND residual BM abnormalities; OR CR by imaging with residual BM abnormalities; OR PR by imaging without residual BM abnormalities.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: ORR per International Workshop on Waldenström's Macroglobulinemia (IWWM) criteria 2014 as assessed by ICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~78 months</time_frame>
    <description>ORR per IWWM criteria 2014 is defined as the percentage of participants achieving a CR, very good partial response (VGPR), or PR. CR is defined as all lymph nodes are normal in size (none ≥15 mm), liver and spleen normal in size, serum immunoglobulin M (IgM) values in the normal range, disappearance of monoclonal protein by immunofixation (confirmation needed with a second immunofixation at any subsequent timepoint), and no histological evidence of BM involvement. VGPR is defined as ≥50% decrease from baseline in SPD of lymph nodes (if abnormal at baseline), ≥50% decrease from baseline in the abnormal portion of the spleen (if previously abnormal), and ≥90% decrease from baseline in serum IgM, or serum IgM values in normal range. PR is defined as ≥50% decrease from baseline in SPD of lymph nodes (if abnormal at baseline), ≥50% decrease from baseline in serum IgM, and ≥50% decrease from baseline in the abnormal portion of the spleen (if previously abnormal).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1: Area Under the Curve (AUC) of Nemtabrutinib</measure>
    <time_frame>At designated time points (up to ~57 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be obtained at designated time points during Part 1 for the assessment of nemtabrutinib AUC (Day 1 of Cycles 1 and 2: Pre-dose, 2, 4, 6, 8, and 24 hours post-dose; Day 1 of Cycle 3: pre-dose and 2, 4, and 6 hours post-dose [up to ~57 days]). Each cycle is 28 days.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1: Minimum Concentration (Cmin) of Nemtabrutinib</measure>
    <time_frame>At designated time points (up to ~57 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be obtained at designated time points during Part 1 for the assessment of nemtabrutinib Cmin (Day 1 of Cycles 1 and 2: Pre-dose, 2, 4, 6, 8, and 24 hours post-dose; Day 1 of Cycle 3: pre-dose and 2, 4, and 6 hours post-dose [up to ~57 days]). Each cycle is 28 days.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1: Maximum Concentration (Cmax) of Nemtabrutinib</measure>
    <time_frame>At designated time points (up to ~57 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be obtained at designated time points during Part 1 for the assessment of nemtabrutinib Cmax (Day 1 of Cycles 1 and 2: Pre-dose, 2, 4, 6, 8, and 24 hours post-dose; Day 1 of Cycle 3: pre-dose and 2, 4, and 6 hours post-dose [up to ~57 days]). Each cycle is 28 days.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1: ORR per iwCLL criteria 2018 as assessed by ICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~78 months</time_frame>
    <description>ORR per iwCLL 2018 criteria is defined as the percentage of participants achieving a CR, CRi, nPR, or PR. CR is defined as meeting the following criteria: no lymph nodes &gt;1.5 cm, spleen size &lt;13 cm, liver normal; no constitutional symptoms, normal lymphocyte count, platelets ≥100 x 10^9/L; hemoglobin ≥11 g/dL; and normocellular marrow (no CLL cells or B lymphoid nodules). CRi is defined as meeting CR criteria but with hypocellular bone marrow. nPR is defined as having features of CR but with lymphoid nodules in the marrow. PR is defined as ≥50% decrease in ≥2 of the following: lymph nodes, liver and/or spleen size, lymphocytes PLUS ≥1 of the following met: platelets ≥100 x 10^9/L or ≥50% increase from screening, hemoglobin &gt;11 g/dL or ≥50% increase from screening, CLL cells or B lymphoid nodules in marrow.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1: Duration of Response (DOR) per iwCLL criteria 2018 as assessed by ICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~78 months</time_frame>
    <description>For participants with CR, CRi, nPR, or PR per iwCLL 2018 criteria, DOR is defined as the time from the first documented evidence of objective response until PD or death due to any cause, whichever occurs first. CR is defined as meeting the following criteria: no lymph nodes &gt;1.5 cm, spleen size &lt;13 cm, liver normal; no constitutional symptoms, normal lymphocyte count, platelets ≥100 x 10^9/L; hemoglobin ≥11 g/dL; and normocellular marrow (no CLL cells or B lymphoid nodules). CRi is defined as meeting CR criteria but with hypocellular bone marrow. nPR is defined as having features of CR but with lymphoid nodules in the marrow. PR is defined as ≥50% decrease in ≥2 of the following: lymph nodes, liver and/or spleen size, lymphocytes PLUS ≥1 of the following met: platelets ≥100 x 10^9/L or ≥50% increase from screening, hemoglobin &gt;11 g/dL or ≥50% increase from screening, CLL cells or B lymphoid nodules in marrow.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Number of participants experiencing AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~78 months</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant, temporally associated with the use of study treatment, whether or not considered related to the study treatment. The number of participants experiencing AEs will be reported for Part 2.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Number of participants discontinuing study treatment due to AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~78 months</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant, temporally associated with the use of study treatment, whether or not considered related to the study treatment. The number of participants discontinuing study treatment due to an AE will be reported for Part 2.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: AUC of Nemtabrutinib</measure>
    <time_frame>At designated time points (up to ~57 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be obtained at designated time points during Part 2 for the assessment of nemtabrutinib AUC (Day 1 of Cycles 1, 2, and 3: Pre-dose, 2, 4, 6, hours post-dose [up to ~57 days]). Each cycle is 28 days.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Cmin of Nemtabrutinib</measure>
    <time_frame>At designated time points (up to ~57 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be obtained at designated time points during Part 2 for the assessment of nemtabrutinib Cmin (Day 1 of Cycles 1, 2, and 3: Pre-dose, 2, 4, 6, hours post-dose [up to ~57 days]). Each cycle is 28 days.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: Cmax of Nemtabrutinib</measure>
    <time_frame>At designated time points (up to ~57 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be obtained at designated time points during Part 2 for the assessment of nemtabrutinib Cmax (Day 1 of Cycles 1, 2, and 3: Pre-dose, 2, 4, 6, hours post-dose [up to ~57 days]). Each cycle is 28 days.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: DOR per iwCLL criteria 2018 as assessed by ICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~78 months</time_frame>
    <description>For participants with CR, CRi, nPR, or PR per iwCLL 2018 criteria, DOR is defined as the time from the first documented evidence of objective response until disease progression or death due to any cause, whichever occurs first. CR is defined as meeting the following criteria: no lymph nodes &gt;1.5 cm, spleen size &lt;13 cm, liver normal; no constitutional symptoms, normal lymphocyte count, platelets ≥100 x 10^9/L; hemoglobin ≥11 g/dL; and normocellular marrow (no CLL cells or B lymphoid nodules). CRi is defined as meeting CR criteria but with hypocellular bone marrow. nPR is defined as having features of CR but with lymphoid nodules in the marrow. PR is defined as ≥50% decrease in ≥2 of the following: lymph nodes, liver and/or spleen size, lymphocytes PLUS ≥1 of the following met: platelets ≥100 x 10^9/L or ≥50% increase from screening, hemoglobin &gt;11 g/dL or ≥50% increase from screening, CLL cells or B lymphoid nodules in marrow.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: DOR per Lugano criteria 2014 as assessed by ICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~78 months</time_frame>
    <description>For participants with CR or PR per Lugano criteria 2014, DOR is defined as the time from the first documented evidence of objective response until PD or death due to any cause, whichever occurs first. CR defined as EITHER CR by imaging (CT): all lymph nodes normal (none ≥15 mm) and normal liver and spleen OR CMR: score of 1, 2 or 3 on the 5-point scale assessing FDG metabolic activity in lymphomatous lesions (ranging from 1=no uptake above background to 5=uptake markedly higher than liver and/or new lesions) AND BM normal by morphology. PR defined as EITHER PR by imaging (CT) with ≥50% decrease in the SPD of target lesions, no worsening of nontarget lesions, no new lesions and ≥50% spleen abnormal portion OR PMR with score of 4 or 5 on the FDG 5-point scale (with no new lesions) and decreased overall uptake AND residual BM abnormalities; OR CR by imaging with residual BM abnormalities; OR PR by imaging without residual BM abnormalities.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 2: DOR per IWWM criteria 2014 as assessed by ICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~78 months</time_frame>
    <description>For participants with CR, VGPR, or PR per IWWM criteria 2014, DOR defined as the time from first documented evidence of objective response until PD or death due to any cause, whichever occurs first. CR defined as all lymph nodes normal in size (none ≥15 mm), liver and spleen normal in size, serum IgM values in normal range, disappearance of monoclonal protein by immunofixation (confirmation needed with second immunofixation at any subsequent timepoint), and no histological evidence of BM involvement. VGPR defined as ≥50% decrease from baseline in SPD of lymph nodes (if abnormal at baseline), ≥50% decrease from baseline in abnormal portion of the spleen (if previously abnormal), and ≥90% decrease from baseline in serum IgM, or serum IgM values in normal range. PR is defined as ≥50% decrease from baseline in SPD of lymph nodes (if abnormal at baseline), ≥50% decrease from baseline in serum IgM, and ≥50% decrease from baseline in abnormal portion of the spleen (if previously abnormal).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Hematologic Malignancies</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Nemtabrutinib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive nemtabrutinib orally once daily (QD) until progressive disease (PD) or discontinuation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nemtabrutinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Nemtabrutinib tablets administered PO QD.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Nemtabrutinib</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ARQ 531</other_name>
    <other_name>MK-1026</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 to 2 within 7&#xD;
             days prior to allocation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a life expectancy of at least 3 months, based on the investigator assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has the ability to swallow and retain oral medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who are Hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg)-positive are eligible if they&#xD;
             have received Hepatitis B virus (HBV) antiviral therapy for at least 4 weeks and have&#xD;
             undetectable HBV viral load prior to randomization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with history of Hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection are eligible if HCV&#xD;
             viral load is undetectable at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has adequate organ function&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male participants agree to refrain from donating sperm and agree to either remain&#xD;
             abstinent from heterosexual intercourse as their preferred and usual lifestyle OR&#xD;
             agree to use contraception, during the intervention period and for 12 days after last&#xD;
             dose of study intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participants not pregnant or breastfeeding are eligible to participate if not a&#xD;
             woman of childbearing potential (WOCBP), or if a WOCBP they either use a contraceptive&#xD;
             method that is highly effective OR remain abstinent from heterosexual intercourse as&#xD;
             their preferred and usual lifestyle during the intervention period and for at least 30&#xD;
             days after the last dose of study intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
        Part 1 and Part 2 (Cohorts A to C)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a confirmed diagnosis of CLL/SLL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Has active disease for CLL/SLL clearly documented to initiate therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Has evaluable core or excisional lymph node biopsy for biomarker analysis from an&#xD;
                  archival or newly obtained biopsy at Screening (optional for participants&#xD;
                  enrolling in Part 1)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Part 2 (Cohorts D to G)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a confirmed diagnosis of and response to previous treatment of one of the&#xD;
             following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants with Richter's transformation who are relapsed or refractory&#xD;
                  following at least 1 line of prior therapy (Cohort D)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants with pathologically confirmed MCL, documented by either&#xD;
                  overexpression of cyclin D1 or t(11;14), who are relapsed or are refractory to&#xD;
                  chemoimmunotherapy and a covalent irreversible BTK inhibitor (BTKi) (Cohort E)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants with MZL (including splenic, nodal, and extra nodal MZL) who are&#xD;
                  relapsed or refractory to chemoimmunotherapy and a covalent irreversible BTKi&#xD;
                  (Cohort F)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants with FL who are relapsed or refractory to chemoimmunotherapy,&#xD;
                  immunomodulatory agents (i.e. lenalidomide plus rituximab), and a&#xD;
                  phosphoinositide 3-kinase inhibitor (PI3Ki) (Cohort G)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have measurable disease defined as at least 1 lesion that can be accurately measured&#xD;
             in at least 2 dimensions with spiral CT scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an evaluable core or excisional lymph node biopsy for biomarker analysis from an&#xD;
             archival or newly obtained biopsy at Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
        Part 2 (Cohort H): confirmed diagnosis of WM; participants who are relapsed or refractory&#xD;
        to chemoimmunotherapy and a covalent irreversible BTKi&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has active disease defined as1 of the following: systemic symptoms, physical findings,&#xD;
             laboratory abnormalities, coexisting disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has measurable disease, satisfying any of the following: at least 1 lesion that can be&#xD;
             accurately measured in at least 2 dimensions with spiral CT scan (minimum measurement&#xD;
             must be &gt;15 mm in the longest diameter or &gt;10 mm in the short axis); IgM ≥4500 g/dL;&#xD;
             or bone marrow infiltration of 70%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an evaluable core or excisional lymph node biopsy for biomarker analysis from an&#xD;
             archival or newly obtained biopsy at Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has active HBV/HCV infection (Part 1 and Part 2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of malignancy ≤3 years prior to signing informed consent except for&#xD;
             adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer or in situ cervical cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has active central nervous system (CNS) disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an active infection requiring systemic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received prior systemic anti-cancer therapy within 4 weeks prior to allocation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently participating in or has participated in a study of an investigational&#xD;
             agent or has used an investigational device within 4 weeks prior to the first dose of&#xD;
             study intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has any clinically significant gastrointestinal abnormalities that might alter&#xD;
             absorption&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Toll Free Number</last_name>
    <phone>1-888-577-8839</phone>
    <email>Trialsites@merck.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>John Theurer Cancer Center at Hackensack University Medical Center ( Site 2704)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hackensack</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07601</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>551-996-3003</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical Oncology Associates (Summit Cancer Centers) ( Site 2710)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Spokane</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>99208</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>509-462-2273</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tom Baker Cancer Centre ( Site 0401)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Calgary</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T4N 4N2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>4035213723</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jewish General Hospital ( Site 0400)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montreal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H3T 1E2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>5143408222 x 24572</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Lyon-Sud ( Site 0804)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pierre Benite</city>
        <state>Rhone-Alpes</state>
        <zip>69495</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+33478864348</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rambam Medical Center ( Site 1301)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Haifa</city>
        <zip>3109601</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+97247772547</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hadassah Ein Karem Jerusalem ( Site 1300)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jerusalem</city>
        <zip>9112001</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+97226778180</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chaim Sheba Medical Center ( Site 1302)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ramat Gan</city>
        <zip>5262001</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+972526669155</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sourasky Medical Center ( Site 1303)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tel Aviv</city>
        <zip>6423906</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+97236973782</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>A.O. Universitaria Policlinico S. Orsola-Malpighi ( Site 1400)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bologna</city>
        <zip>40138</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+390516363680</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IRCCS Ospedale San Raffaele ( Site 1402)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milano</city>
        <zip>20132</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>00390226434797</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Instituto Catalan de Oncologia ICO - Hospital Duran i Reynals ( Site 2000)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hospitalet de Llobregat</city>
        <state>Barcelona</state>
        <zip>08908</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+34932607750</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitari Vall d'Hebron ( Site 2001)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08035</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+34934893806</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario 12 de Octubre ( Site 2003)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28041</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+34917792809</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario de Salamanca ( Site 2002)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salamanca</city>
        <zip>37007</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+34 923 29 11 00 Ext. 55974</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Israel</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hematologic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>http://engagezone.msd.com/doc/ProcedureAccessClinicalTrialData.pdf</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>http://engagezone.msd.com/ds_documentation.php</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

