<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04720092</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19365</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2017-000648-16</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04720092</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Trial to Learn How a New Liquid Form of Rivaroxaban Behaves and How Safe it is Compared to the Current Tablet Form of Rivaroxaban in Healthy Male Participants</brief_title>
  <official_title>Single-dose, Open-label, Randomized, 2-way Crossover Bioequivalence Study of 10 mg Granules for Oral Suspension Rivaroxaban Versus 10 mg Tablets Rivaroxaban Under Fasted Condition in Healthy Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bayer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bayer</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Researchers were looking for another way to treat people with a blood clot in their veins.&#xD;
      Before a treatment can be approved for people to take, researchers do clinical trials to&#xD;
      better understand its safety and how it behaves.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this trial, the researchers learned how a new liquid form of rivaroxaban behaved compared&#xD;
      to the tablet form in a small number of healthy participants. They also wanted to find out&#xD;
      how safe it was. The trial included about 30 white men who were between the ages of 18 and&#xD;
      55. The participants also had a body mass index (BMI) between 18 and 29.9 kilograms per&#xD;
      square meter (kg/m^2). BMI is a measurement that uses a person's height and weight to learn&#xD;
      how much body fat they have.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All the participants in this trial took 10 milliliter of the new form of rivaroxaban&#xD;
      (containing 1 milligram [mg] of rivaroxaban per milliliter). Later they also took 10 mg of&#xD;
      the current tablet form of rivaroxaban. They took each form 1 time by mouth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This trial was a &quot;crossover&quot; trial. In a crossover trial, all the participants take all of&#xD;
      the treatments, but in a different order. In between the 2 treatments, there was a &quot;washout&#xD;
      period&quot; of at least 7 days. This was done so that the first treatment could leave each&#xD;
      participant's body before they took their next treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While taking each treatment, the participants stayed at the trial site for 5 days. During&#xD;
      this time, they did not eat food for at least 10 hours before and at least 4 hours after&#xD;
      taking each treatment. After taking the last treatment, the participants had a final visit&#xD;
      about 7 to 14 days later.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the trial, the doctors took blood and urine samples. They also did physical&#xD;
      examinations and checked the participants' heart health using an electrocardiogram (ECG).&#xD;
      They asked the participants questions about how they were feeling and if they had any medical&#xD;
      problems.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 5, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 27, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 28, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the concentration versus time curve from zero to infinity (AUC) of rivaroxaban in plasma after single dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose up to 72 hours post-dose</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC from time zero to the last data point greater than (&gt;) lower limit of quantification (LLOQ) (AUC[0-tlast]) of rivaroxaban in plasma after single dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose up to 72 hours post-dose</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the concentration versus time curve from zero to infinity (AUC)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum observed drug concentration (Cmax) of rivaroxaban in plasma after single dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose up to 72 hours post-dose</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects with treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of study drug administration up to 30 days after last study drug administration</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Thromboembolic Disorders</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment A-B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects received a single oral dose of 10 mg rivaroxaban tablet in the fasted state on Day 1 (Treatment A) during intervention period 1; and then a single oral dose of 10 mg rivaroxaban oral suspension in the fasted state on Day 1 (Treatment B) during intervention period 2. A wash-out of at least 7 days was maintained between the treatments.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment B-A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects received a single oral dose of 10 mg rivaroxaban oral suspension in the fasted state on Day 1 (Treatment B) during intervention period 1; and then a single oral dose of 10 mg rivaroxaban tablet in the fasted state on Day 1 (Treatment A) during intervention period 2. A wash-out of at least 7 days was maintained between the treatments.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rivaroxaban (Xarelto, BAY59-7939)</intervention_name>
    <description>Granules for oral suspension, 10 mg, oral, single dose</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment A-B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment B-A</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rivaroxaban (Xarelto, BAY59-7939)</intervention_name>
    <description>Tablet, 10 mg, oral, single dose</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment A-B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment B-A</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The informed consent had to be signed before any study specific tests or procedures&#xD;
             were done&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy male subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age: 18 to 55 years (inclusive) at the screening examination/visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Race: White&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI): above/equal 18 and below/equal 29.9 kg/m^2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and follow instructions&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existing diseases for which it can be assumed that the absorption, distribution,&#xD;
             metabolism, elimination and effects of the study drugs will not be normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected liver disorders and bile secretion/flow&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with thyroid disorders as evidenced by assessment of thyroid stimulating&#xD;
             hormone (TSH) levels outside the normal reference range at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Personal or familial history of genetically muscular diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to the study drugs (active substances or excipients of the&#xD;
             preparations)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known severe allergies e.g. allergies to more than 3 allergens, allergies affecting&#xD;
             the lower respiratory tract- allergic asthma, allergies requiring therapy with&#xD;
             corticosteroids, urticaria) or significant non-allergic drug reactions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known disorders with increased bleeding risk (e.g., periodontosis, hemorrhoids, acute&#xD;
             gastritis, peptic ulcer)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known sensitivity to common causes of bleeding (e.g. nasal)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically relevant findings in the electrocardiogram (ECG) such as a second- or&#xD;
             third-degree atrioventricular (AV) block, prolongation of the QRS (QRS interval in&#xD;
             ECG) complex over 120 msec or of the QTc-interval over 450 msec at the first screening&#xD;
             visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence or history of arrhythmic disturbances; or known congenital QT (QT interval in&#xD;
             ECG) prolongation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systolic blood pressure below 100 or above 140 mmHg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diastolic blood pressure below 50 or above 90 mmHg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Heart rate below 50 or above 90 beats/ min&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CRS Clinical-Research-Services Mönchengladbach GmbH</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mönchengladbach</city>
        <state>Nordrhein-Westfalen</state>
        <zip>41061</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.bayer.com/</url>
    <description>Click here to find results for studies related to Bayer products</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Thromboembolism</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rivaroxaban</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Availability of this study's data will be determined according to Bayer's commitment to the EFPIA/PhRMA &quot;Principles for responsible clinical trial data sharing&quot;. This pertains to scope, timepoint and process of data access.&#xD;
As such, Bayer commits to sharing upon request from qualified researchers patient-level clinical trial data, study-level clinical trial data, and protocols from clinical trials in patients for medicines and indications approved in the US and EU as necessary for conducting legitimate research. This applies to data on new medicines and indications that have been approved by the EU and US regulatory agencies on or after January 01, 2014.&#xD;
Interested researchers can use www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com to request access to anonymized patient-level data and supporting documents from clinical studies to conduct research. Information on the Bayer criteria for listing studies and other relevant information is provided in the Study sponsors section of the portal.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

