<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04721613</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BASEC_01_2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04721613</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Circadian Melatonin Rhythms in Critically Ill Patients With Delirium</brief_title>
  <official_title>Circadian Melatonin Rhythms in Critically Ill Patients With Delirium - A Prospective Single-centre Observational Proof-of-concept Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Basel, Switzerland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centre for Chronobiology, Transfaculty Research Platform Molecular and Cognitive Neurosciences (MCN), Psychiatric Hospital of the University of Basel (UPK)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Basel, Switzerland</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Delirious patients often suffer from sleep disturbances such as insomnia, sleep&#xD;
      fragmentation, daytime somnolence, and reversal of sleep-wake rhythms. There is evidence,&#xD;
      that patients suffering from hyperactive, as well as hypoactive and mixed delirium suffer&#xD;
      from disturbed circadian rhythm. The investigators hypothesize that the circadian melatonin&#xD;
      profile in critically ill delirious patients measured at two-hourly intervals deviates&#xD;
      significantly in terms of phase, width and amplitude from non-delirious critically ill&#xD;
      patients with similar age and SOFA (Sequential Organ Failure Assessment) score.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Delirium is a highly prevalent neuropsychological condition in patients admitted to the ICU.&#xD;
      Occurrence of a delirium in critically ill patients is associated with prolonged ICU stay and&#xD;
      longer hospitalization, reduced quality of life and increased mortality. Furthermore, it is&#xD;
      accompanied by a higher risk of cognitive disorder after ICU discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Delirium is defined as an acute, usually reversible state of disturbance of consciousness&#xD;
      with a change of perception and cognition. Its fluctuating course leads to a division in&#xD;
      three subgroups: hyperactive, hypoactive and mixed delirium. Hyperactive delirious patients&#xD;
      present agitated and anxious behaviour, hypoactive delirium however is characterised by&#xD;
      withdrawal, somnolence and reduced responsiveness to stimuli. The mixed subtype shows&#xD;
      alternating characteristics from both hyperactive and hypoactive delirium.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ICU patients especially in the post-operative setting frequently show several risk factors&#xD;
      for delirium, including environmental changes, advanced age, alcohol abuse, dementia, demand&#xD;
      for vasopressors, increased doses of opioids or metabolic disturbances.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sleep and many symptoms that occur in delirium are influenced by the circadian timing system&#xD;
      and therefore are thought to be closely related. The neurohormone melatonin plays a major&#xD;
      role in regulating circadian rhythms. It is produced in the pineal gland and its diurnal&#xD;
      secretion pattern is under the control of the central circadian pacemaker located in the&#xD;
      suprachiasmatic nuclei of the anterior hypothalamus. Under normal entrained condition&#xD;
      melatonin starts to increase one to three hours prior habitual bedtime, which often coincides&#xD;
      with the onset of darkness outside. Thus, melatonin is often referred to as the hormone of&#xD;
      darkness. Peak melatonin levels occur approximately two hours prior usual rise time (usually&#xD;
      between 2 and 5 A.M.). Melatonin levels are lower during daytime independent of experienced&#xD;
      light levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Delirious patients often suffer from sleep disturbances such as insomnia, sleep&#xD;
      fragmentation, daytime somnolence, and reversal of sleep-wake rhythms. There is evidence that&#xD;
      hyperactive as well as hypoactive and mixed delirium is connected to disturbed circadian&#xD;
      rhythm. This leads to the question whether there is a link between delirium syndromes as well&#xD;
      as different delirium subtypes and potential alterations in circadian melatonin plasma levels&#xD;
      compared to non-delirious patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Plasma melatonin levels can be assessed in saliva, blood and urine. Due to its rapid&#xD;
      metabolisation plasma melatonin levels represent a precise proxy of the current pineal&#xD;
      secretion. It therefore is reasonable to collect plasma samples for melatonin assessments&#xD;
      frequently throughout the study period to obtain an accurate time course of the circadian&#xD;
      melatonin rhythm profile.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is suggestive evidence that regulating melatonin levels during delirium lowers the&#xD;
      incidence of delirium and leads to a reduction of duration and severity of the disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that the circadian melatonin profile in critically ill&#xD;
      delirious patients measured in two-hourly intervals across 24 hours deviates significantly&#xD;
      from non-delirious critically ill patients with similar age and SOFA (Sequential Organ&#xD;
      Failure Assessment) score in terms of phase, width and amplitude.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 31, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Melatonin profile</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in melatonin profile in ICU patients with delirium compared to non-delirious patients</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>ICU Delirium</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hypoactive ICU delirium</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hyperactive or mixed ICU delirium</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Critically ill patients not suffering form ICU delirium</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Assessment of Melatonin level</intervention_name>
    <description>Measuring the plasma or serum melatonin in pg/ml during the first 24 hours after delirium diagnosis in two-hour intervals.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Critically ill patients not suffering form ICU delirium</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Hyperactive or mixed ICU delirium</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Hypoactive ICU delirium</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The investigators will include 20 patients that fulfil inclusion criteria and do not&#xD;
        complete any of the exclusion criteria. Half of the patients should suffer from a&#xD;
        hyperactive/mixed delirium with a RASS score ≥2, the other half from a hypoactive delirium.&#xD;
        For the control group of 10 patients, the investigators will select age-matched patients&#xD;
        grouped in a range of ten years with a minimum of 55 years (55-64 years, 65-74 years, 75-84&#xD;
        years, 85-94 years and higher). The patients of both groups will be hospitalized in the ICU&#xD;
        also meeting a similar SOFA score (difference +/- one point). Five patients of the control&#xD;
        group will be matched with hyperactively/mixed delirious patients, the other five patients&#xD;
        with hypoactively delirious patients.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adult patients (aged 55 years or older)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Admission to the ICU&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current delirium (ICDSC ≥4)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Functioning venous or arterial line for blood sample collection&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Delirium prior to ICU admission&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Intake of beta blockers within 48 hours before study inclusion and during study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Premenopausal women&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Terminal state&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Dementia&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Substance abuse including alcohol in current medical history&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Martin Siegemund, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+41613286414</phone>
    <email>martin.siegemund@usb.ch</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Basel</name>
      <address>
        <city>Basel</city>
        <zip>4031</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Martin Siegemund, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+41613286414</phone>
      <email>martin.siegemund@usb.ch</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Alexa Hollinger, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+41615565895</phone>
      <email>alexa.hollinger@usb.ch</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tatjana Zehnder, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Delirium</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Melatonin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

