<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04723147</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00000361</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1R61MH121625-01A1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04723147</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>DTA (Dopaminergic Therapy for Anhedonia) Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Dopaminergic Therapy for Inflammation-Related Anhedonia in Depression</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Emory University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Emory University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this 6-week, double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover study is to explore&#xD;
      new treatment options for people with depression who have high inflammation and anhedonia.&#xD;
      Thirty-five male and female participants with depression, between the ages of 25-55 years of&#xD;
      age, will be randomized to two study tracks (A and B) to receive both placebo and three doses&#xD;
      of L-DOPA, given in different orders. Increases or decreases in each dose will occur&#xD;
      gradually over 6 weeks of the study. Participants will complete lab tests, medical and&#xD;
      psychiatric assessments, neurocognitive testing and functional MRI (fMRI) scans as part of&#xD;
      the study. The total length of participation is about 2 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Depression is a widespread disorder (lifetime prevalence &gt;20%). Current antidepressant&#xD;
      medications are effective for many patients; however, more than 30% fail to respond. Of the&#xD;
      patients that do respond to treatment, some continue to suffer with primary symptoms of&#xD;
      depression like an inability to experience pleasure, called anhedonia. In this regard, one&#xD;
      biological pathway that may contribute to symptoms of depression and particularly anhedonia&#xD;
      is inflammation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this 6-week, double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover study is to explore&#xD;
      new treatment options for people with depression who have high inflammation and anhedonia.&#xD;
      Despite evidence of low dopamine function in patients with depression, the ability of&#xD;
      existing dopaminergic therapies, like L-DOPA, to affect brain circuits in depression has yet&#xD;
      to be explored. This study will help determine the best dose of an FDA-approved medication,&#xD;
      Sinemet (L-DOPA) that might be used in the future to treat sub-groups of depressed&#xD;
      individuals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Forty male and female participants with depression, between the ages of 25-55 years of age,&#xD;
      will be randomized to two study tracks (A and B) to receive both placebo and three doses of&#xD;
      L-DOPA, given in different orders. Increases or decreases in each dose will occur gradually&#xD;
      over 6 weeks of the study. Participants will complete lab tests, medical and psychiatric&#xD;
      assessments, neurocognitive testing and functional MRI (fMRI) scans as part of the study. The&#xD;
      total length of participation is about 2 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 29, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in targeted ventral striatum to ventromedial prefrontal cortex (VS-vmPFC) connectivity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1-week of placebo, and 1-week at each dose of L-DOPA</time_frame>
    <description>Patients will undergo resting-state and task-based functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) to calculate functional connectivity (FC) between the ventral striatum (VS) and ventromedial prefrontal cortex (vmPFC). FC is measured as continuous Z scores reflecting the correlation of activity between the brain regions. Higher FC Z scores reflect stronger connectivity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Effort-Expenditure for Rewards Task (EEfRT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1-week of placebo, and 1-week at each dose of L-DOPA</time_frame>
    <description>The EEfRT is a widely used, multi-trial task in which participants are given an opportunity on each trial to choose between two different task difficulty levels in order to obtain monetary rewards. EEfRT will be used as an objective measure of motivation and will be administered following MRI scans during the study. The EEfRT is reported as the percent of high effort trials selected. A higher percentage reflects higher motivation for effort expenditure.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Inventory of Depressive Symptomatology- Self-Report (IDS-SR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1-week of placebo, and 1-week at each dose of L-DOPA</time_frame>
    <description>Anhedonia will be assessed from a subscale of the Inventory of Depressive Symptomatology- Self-Report (IDS-SR). Scores on this 3-question scale range from 0-9 with higher scores reflecting greater anhedonia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Snaith-Hamilton Pleasure Scale-Clinician (SHAPS-C )</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1-week of placebo, and 1-week at each dose of L-DOPA</time_frame>
    <description>The Snaith-Hamilton Pleasure Scale-Clinician (SHAPS-C) is a clinician administered tool to assess symptoms of anhedonia. The SHAPS-C uses 14 question each rated on a Likert scale of 1-4, with higher scores reflecting greater pathology.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Motivation and Pleasure-Self-Report (MAP-SR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1-week of placebo, and 1-week at each dose of L-DOPA</time_frame>
    <description>The Motivation and Pleasure-Self-Report (MAP-SR) will be used to capture self-reported aspects of anhedonia and reduced motivation. The scale uses 18 question each rated on a Likert scale of 0-4, with higher scores reflecting greater pathology.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Hamilton Depression Rating Scale (HAM-D)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1-week of placebo, and 1-week at each dose of L-DOPA</time_frame>
    <description>The anhedonia and motivation-related item from the clinician administered Hamilton Depression Rating Scale (HAM-D) (item #7: work and activities) will be used to measure anhedonia. This item is rated on a scale of 0-4 with higher scores reflecting greater pathology</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">35</enrollment>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <condition>Anhedonia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Carbidopa Levodopa followed by Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive first Carbidopa Levodopa at doses ranging from 150 to 450 mg administered at a ratio of 1 mg carbidopa for every 4 mg L-DOPA with a starting dose of 150 mg/day with dose escalation 150 mg/day per week to a final dose of 450 mg/day; and then placebo.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo followed by Carbidopa Levodopa</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive first placebo, and then Carbidopa Levodopa (L-DOPA) at doses ranging from 150 to 450 mg administered at a ratio of 1 mg carbidopa for every 4 mg L-DOPA with a starting dose of 150 mg/day with dose escalation 150 mg/day per week to a final dose of 450 mg/day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Carbidopa Levodopa</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive L-DOPA at doses ranging from 150 to 450 mg administered at a ratio of 1 mg carbidopa for every 4 mg L-DOPA. Starting dose is 150 mg/day with dose escalation 150 mg/day per week to a final dose of 450 mg/day</description>
    <arm_group_label>Carbidopa Levodopa followed by Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo followed by Carbidopa Levodopa</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Sinemet, L-DOPA</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>A placebo is a sugar pill that has no therapeutic effect and will be administered orally. Participants will receive 1 placebo tablet matching the Carbidopa Levodopa tablet.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Carbidopa Levodopa followed by Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo followed by Carbidopa Levodopa</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Placebo tablet</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  willing and able to give written informed consent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  men or women, 25-55 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a primary diagnosis of DSM-V MD, current, as diagnosed by the SCID-I;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  score &gt;10 on the Patient Health Questionnaire [PHQ]-9&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  off all antidepressant or other psychotropic therapy (e.g. mood stabilizers,&#xD;
             antipsychotics, anxiolytics, and sedative hypnotics) for at least 4 weeks prior to&#xD;
             baseline visit (8 weeks for fluoxetine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CRP ≥2 mg/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Score &gt;/=2 on the anhedonia question of Patient Health Questionnaire [PHQ]-9&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history or evidence (clinical or laboratory) of an autoimmune disorder ;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history or evidence (clinical or laboratory) of hepatitis B or C infection or human&#xD;
             immunodeficiency virus infection; - history of any type of cancer requiring treatment&#xD;
             with more than minor surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unstable cardiovascular, endocrinologic, hematologic, hepatic, renal, or neurologic&#xD;
             disease (as determined by physical examination, EKG and laboratory testing);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of any (non-mood-related) psychotic disorder; active psychotic symptoms of any&#xD;
             type; history or current bipolar disorder; history or current gambling disorder;&#xD;
             substance abuse/dependence within 6 months of study entry (as determined by SCID);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  active suicidal plan as determined by a score &gt;3 on item #3 on the HAM-D; g. an active&#xD;
             eating disorder (except for patients with binge eating disorder in whom binging is&#xD;
             clearly associated with worsening of mood symptoms) ;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a history of a cognitive disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy or lactation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic use of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory agents (NSAIDS) (excluding 81mg of&#xD;
             aspirin), glucocorticoid containing medications or statins;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  use of NSAIDS, glucocorticoids, or statins at any time during the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  urine toxicology screen is positive for drugs of abuse,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any contraindication for MRI scanning; n. intolerance, sensitivity or contraindication&#xD;
             to carbidopa-levodopa (including history of narrow-angle glaucoma, melanoma, gastric&#xD;
             and/or duodenal ulcers, bleeding disorders, or frequent migraines).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jennifer Felger, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Emory University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jennifer Felger, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>404-727-3987</phone>
    <email>jfelger@emory.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Bobbi Woolwine, CCRC</last_name>
    <phone>4047129620</phone>
    <email>bwoolwi@emory.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Bobbi Woolwine</last_name>
      <phone>404-712-9620</phone>
      <email>bwoolwi@emory.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 21, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Emory University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jennifer Felger</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Anhedonia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anhedonia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Levodopa</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carbidopa</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carbidopa, levodopa drug combination</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Only the data - raw and analyzed, or both, depending on the items. Statistical plans an additional information may be shared within the data base but it is not required as the data will be linked to the publications.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>After publication, within one year of the end of the project.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Must be NIH investigators and they have to submit an application, including analysis plan, in order to be granted access.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

