<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04721509</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>4-2020-0880</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04721509</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Smartphone Based Telemedicine and Education in Patients With Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Smartphone Based Telemedicine and Education in Patients With Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yonsei University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yonsei University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Objective: evaluation of effect of smartphone based telemedicine and education in patients&#xD;
      with type 1 diabetes mellitus Outline: Among the patients with type 1 diabetes, the group&#xD;
      with telemedicine and education using smartphone set as a experimental group and the group&#xD;
      without those set as a control group, respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size: experimental group (n=50), control group (n=50) Inclusion criteria: patients&#xD;
      with type 1 diabetes with A1c&gt;8.0% Exclusion criteria: chronic disease, psychological&#xD;
      disease, children aged under 12 with parents with psychological disease, athletics Method: We&#xD;
      divide subjects as an experimental group and a control group by randomization, and they visit&#xD;
      outpatient clinic every 12 weeks. We perform telemedicine and education with smartphone&#xD;
      application to the experimental group every 2 weeks. We evaluate the effect of smartphone&#xD;
      based telemedicine and education in patients with type 1 diabetes mellitus with checking A1c&#xD;
      and checklist at baseline, 12 weeks and 24 weeks after starting of the research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Variables: A1c, satisfaction, knowledge, self-confidence, willing to continuing, quality of&#xD;
      life, physical activity, drinking, smoking Primary endpoint: Improvement in HbA1c of&#xD;
      experimental group Secondary endpoint: No improvement in HbA1c of control group&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Inclusion criteria: patients with type 1 diabetes with A1c&gt;8.0% Exclusion criteria: chronic disease, psychological disease, children aged under 12 with parents with psychological disease, athletics Method: We divide subjects as an experimental group and a control group by randomization, and they visit outpatient clinic every 12 weeks. We perform telemedicine and education with smartphone application to the experimental group every 2 weeks. We evaluate the effect of smartphone based telemedicine and education in patients with type 1 diabetes mellitus with checking A1c and checklist at baseline, 12 weeks and 24 weeks after starting of the research.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Open label</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change in HbA1c of experimental group</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>No change in HbA1c of control group</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months later</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Smartphone-based telemedicine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Conventional management without telemedicine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Experimental : Smartphone-based telemedicine with the app 'Songaree diabetes'</intervention_name>
    <description>Experimental group: outpatient clinic and offline education every 12 weeks plus telemedicine and education with smartphone app 'Songaree diabetes' every 2 weeks for 24 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Smartphone-based telemedicine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        a. patients aged under 30 with type 1 diabetes b. patients who control glucose level with&#xD;
        multiple daily injection of insulin pump c. Patients who agree the task to check glucose&#xD;
        level during the experiment d. patients who has been diagnosed as type 1 diabetes more than&#xD;
        3 months e. patients whose A1c more than 8.0% within 6 months f. Patients who can use&#xD;
        smartphone all day 2) exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. chronic disease (except thyroid disorders with euthyroidism), psychological disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients aged under 12 whose parents have psychological disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients who cannot use smartphone app properly&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. athletics&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients who use continuous glucose monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ho-Seong Kim</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Severance Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ho-Seong Kim</last_name>
    <phone>82-2-2228-2050</phone>
    <email>kimho@yuhs.ac</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yonsei University College of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ho-Seong Kim</last_name>
      <phone>82-2-2228-2050</phone>
      <email>kimho@yuhs.ac</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Maahs DM, West NA, Lawrence JM, Mayer-Davis EJ. Epidemiology of type 1 diabetes. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am. 2010 Sep;39(3):481-97. doi: 10.1016/j.ecl.2010.05.011. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20723815</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Song SO, Song YD, Nam JY, Park KH, Yoon JH, Son KM, Ko Y, Lim DH. Epidemiology of Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus in Korea through an Investigation of the National Registration Project of Type 1 Diabetes for the Reimbursement of Glucometer Strips with Additional Analyses Using Claims Data. Diabetes Metab J. 2016 Feb;40(1):35-45. doi: 10.4093/dmj.2016.40.1.35.</citation>
    <PMID>26912154</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>American Diabetes Association. 11. Microvascular Complications and Foot Care: Standards of Medical Care in Diabetes-2020. Diabetes Care. 2020 Jan;43(Suppl 1):S135-S151. doi: 10.2337/dc20-S011. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31862754</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>American Diabetes Association. 6. Glycemic Targets: Standards of Medical Care in Diabetes-2020. Diabetes Care. 2020 Jan;43(Suppl 1):S66-S76. doi: 10.2337/dc20-S006. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31862749</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Phelan H, Lange K, Cengiz E, Gallego P, Majaliwa E, Pelicand J, Smart C, Hofer SE. ISPAD Clinical Practice Consensus Guidelines 2018: Diabetes education in children and adolescents. Pediatr Diabetes. 2018 Oct;19 Suppl 27:75-83. doi: 10.1111/pedi.12762.</citation>
    <PMID>30175451</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Viana LV, Gomes MB, Zajdenverg L, Pavin EJ, Azevedo MJ; Brazilian Type 1 Diabetes Study Group. Interventions to improve patients' compliance with therapies aimed at lowering glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c) in type 1 diabetes: systematic review and meta-analyses of randomized controlled clinical trials of psychological, telecare, and educational interventions. Trials. 2016 Feb 17;17:94. doi: 10.1186/s13063-016-1207-6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26888087</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sun C, Malcolm JC, Wong B, Shorr R, Doyle MA. Improving Glycemic Control in Adults and Children With Type 1 Diabetes With the Use of Smartphone-Based Mobile Applications: A Systematic Review. Can J Diabetes. 2019 Feb;43(1):51-58.e3. doi: 10.1016/j.jcjd.2018.03.010. Epub 2018 Mar 27.</citation>
    <PMID>30026048</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 21, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 21, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diabetes Mellitus, Telemedicine, Smartphone, Type 1, Child, Adolescent, Young Adult</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

