<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04722029</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00001291</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04722029</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pilot Study of Haploidentical Donor Adenovirus Specific T-lymphocytes to Treat Refractory Adenovirus Infections</brief_title>
  <acronym>ADV-VSTS</acronym>
  <official_title>Open-Label Pilot Study of Haploidentical Donor Adenovirus Specific T Lymphocytes (ADV-VSTS) for the Treatment of Refractory Adenovirus Infection and/or Disease in Hospitalized Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nationwide Children's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Nationwide Children's Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This open-label, single-arm, phase I/II clinical trial will assess the safety and efficacy of&#xD;
      related donor adenovirus-specific T lymphocytes isolated from whole blood or leukapheresis&#xD;
      products. The adenovirus-specific T lymphocytes will be generated automatically by the&#xD;
      CliniMACS Prodigy using the CliniMACS Cytokine Capture System (IFN-γ) after incubation with&#xD;
      MACS GMP PepTivator Peptide Pools of Hexon 5 for enrichment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety by measuring unacceptable toxicities</measure>
    <time_frame>7-28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Safety will be assess at 28 days post ADV-VSTS infusion. Safety is defined as presentation of unacceptable toxicities, measured by grade III-IV acute GVHD within 28 days, solid organ rejection/ graft failure within 28 days, grade &gt;4 infusional toxicity within 7 days of infusion, and grade 4-5 adverse events within 28 days per CTCAE 5.0.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy by measuring viral load</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of patients with ≥1 log decrease in ADV viral load. ADV viral load will be monitored by quantitative ADV PCR weekly until negative PCR. Response will be assess on day 28 post ADV-VSTS infusion defined as complete response, partial response, stable disease or progressive disease</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Adenovirus Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Donor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Donors will be evaluated to determine suitability to undergo apheresis collection and their infectious disease status. Donor evaluation will include history and physical examination, laboratory tests, FDA- approved donor testing of communicable diseases (HIV, HVB, HCV, HTLV-I, II, WNV, T. pallidum, T. cruzi, and Zika virus), ABO and Rh typing, pregnancy tests, and donor serology for ADV.&#xD;
Qualified donors will undergo leukapheresis. Collection will proceed for 2 hours or 2 blood volumes, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Recipient</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Recipient will undergo a screening period that will include history and physical examination, laboratory tests, performance status, HLA typing and pregnancy test (if needed).&#xD;
Qualified patients will receive ADV-VSTS infusion from haploidentical donors up to a maximum of 5.0 x 104 interferon gamma-negative cells/kg. All patients will be followed for laboratory and clinical response, safety, efficacy and tolerance.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Adenovirus Specific T lymphocytes</intervention_name>
    <description>ADV-VSTs is being proposed for the treatment of refractory ADV infection and/or disease in these populations using haploidentical donors for ease of donor selection, antiviral immunity, coupled with a high-throughput antigen stimulation/IFN-γ capture system (Miltenyi Biotec, CliniMACS Prodigy® System) for rapid and less costly isolation of ADV-VSTs.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Recipient</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 0 days to 60 years with one of the following conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients who are solid organ transplantation recipients (renal, heart, lung,&#xD;
                  liver, pancreas, small bowel, multi-visceral) and are &gt; 28 days post-transplant&#xD;
                  at the time of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patients with underlying malignancy who are receiving or have received&#xD;
                  chemotherapy within 6 months of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Patients with known autoimmune or autoinflammatory conditions, not associated&#xD;
                  with a known underlying primary immunodeficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Patients who are receiving or have received systemic immunosuppressive therapies&#xD;
                  in the 30 days prior to screening including: biologic agents, calcineurin&#xD;
                  inhibitors, mTOR inhibitors, or corticosteroid&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Patients without known immunocompromised conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  And must meet at least 1 of the following criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Documented ADV refractory infection (i.e., DNAemia detected by qualitative or&#xD;
                  quantitative PCR in the peripheral blood &gt; 14 days or rising viral load in blood&#xD;
                  despite antiviral therapy &gt;14 days).&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Evidence of refractory ADV end organ disease (proven or probable as previously&#xD;
                  defined46, including pneumonitis, colitis, hepatitis, hemorrhagic cystitis etc.)&#xD;
                  despite antiviral therapy &gt;14 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Medical intolerance to anti-viral therapies including renal toxicity (Cr &gt;2)&#xD;
                  and/or bone marrow suppression (ANC &lt;1500, Hb &lt;10 and/or Plt &lt;50) or&#xD;
                  gastrointestinal manifestation (grade ≥2 diarrhea), or other related organ&#xD;
                  injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. At high risk for antiviral failure due to history of recurrent ADV reactivations,&#xD;
                  or recently started on increased immunosuppressants.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative pregnancy test in female patients if applicable (childbearing potential)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent and/or signed assent line from patient, parent or legal&#xD;
             guardian prior to any study-related procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of anti-thymocyte globulin (ATG), alemtuzumab, cytoxan, or other T-cell&#xD;
             depleting drugs or monoclonal antibodies within 28 days from enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving corticosteroid (prednisone equivalent) ≥ 0.5mg/kg/day or ≥ 20mg/day at the&#xD;
             time of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipients of allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplant (bone marrow, peripheral&#xD;
             blood or umbilical cord blood)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of uncontrolled infection (except ADV) as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Bacterial infections - patients must be receiving definitive therapy and have no&#xD;
                  signs of progressing infection for 72 hours prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Fungal infections - patients must be receiving definitive systemic anti-fungal&#xD;
                  therapy and evidence of response/stabilization on therapy for 1 week prior to&#xD;
                  enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Progressing infection is defined as hemodynamic instability attributable to&#xD;
                  sepsis, or new symptoms, worsening physical signs or radiographic findings&#xD;
                  attributable to infection. Persisting fever without other signs or symptoms will&#xD;
                  not be interpreted as progressing infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with poor performance status determined by Karnofsky (patients &gt;16 years) or&#xD;
             Lansky (patients ≤16 years) score ≤30% (Table 5)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant enrollment in another experimental clinical trial investigating the&#xD;
             treatment of refractory adenovirus infection(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  During the study, treatment with other investigational anti-adenoviral agents is&#xD;
             prohibited until Week 12.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If patient has been treated with CMX001 (brincidofovir, BCV) prior to ADV-VST&#xD;
             enrollment, BCV must be discontinued for at least 72 hours prior to ADV-VSTs infusion&#xD;
             for washout based on known geometric mean elimination half-life of BCV (8 to 12&#xD;
             hours). Any medical condition which could compromise participation in the study&#xD;
             according to the investigator's assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known HIV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patient of childbearing age who is pregnant or breast-feeding or not willing to&#xD;
             use an effective method of birth control during study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to iron dextran&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unwilling or unable to comply with the protocol or unable to give informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known human anti-mouse antibodies&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eunkyung Song, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Nationwide Children's Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Melinda Triplet</last_name>
    <phone>6147226039</phone>
    <email>Melinda.Triplet@nationwidechildrens.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adenoviridae Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

