<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04830670</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>WIDE&amp;NARROW</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04830670</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Bone Formation Maxillary Sinus Width</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison of Bone Formation According to Different Maxillary Sinus Width: a Multicenter Prospective Study.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>International Piezosurgery Academy</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>International Piezosurgery Academy</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      According to previous scientific evidence lining on biological concept of bone regeneration&#xD;
      into the maxillary sinus, an observational study was set up to record possible (hypothesized)&#xD;
      difference in bone formation between different width of the maxillary sinus itself.&#xD;
      Therefore, a multicenter study was set up that foresaw a surgical intervention of sinus lift&#xD;
      with lateral approach, the 6 months healing phase, the implant insertion in two sites with&#xD;
      the implant site preparation made by a trephine bur to retrieve a bone specimen for&#xD;
      histomorphometric examination without any additive invasively for the patient.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Material and Methods Study protocol This study was designed as a multicenter prospective&#xD;
      study following STROBE (STrengthening the Reporting of Observational studies in Epidemiology)&#xD;
      guidelines. All procedures were performed in strict accordance with the recommendations of&#xD;
      the Declaration of Helsinki as revised in Fortaleza for investigations with human subjects.&#xD;
      The study protocol had been approved by the relevant ethical committee (Comitato Etico&#xD;
      Calabria-Sezione Area Nord n. 55/2016). Patients, after being thoroughly informed about the&#xD;
      study protocol, the treatment, its alternatives and any potential risk, signed a written&#xD;
      informed consent for the participation in the study and authorized the use of their data for&#xD;
      research purposes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any patient with Kennedy class II partial edentulism requiring unilateral sinus floor&#xD;
      elevation for the placement of two not adjacent dental implants supporting a fixed partial&#xD;
      prosthesis was eligible for entering this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pre-surgical phase Patients recruited in the present study underwent a careful clinical&#xD;
      examination, including assessment of periodontal conditions (probing and periapical&#xD;
      radiographs), evaluation of available bone volume in the edentulous areas on cone beam&#xD;
      computed tomography and analysis of occlusal relationships (diagnostic wax-up). A surgical&#xD;
      resin guide was manufactured by duplicating the diagnostic wax-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients received professional mechanical tooth cleaning and periodontal debridement one&#xD;
      week prior to surgery and were prescribed with chlorhexidine digluconate 0.2% mouthwash twice&#xD;
      a day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgical procedure All patients underwent antibiotic prophylaxis (2 g single-dose amoxicillin&#xD;
      one hour before surgery). After performing local anaesthesia (articaine 4% with epinephrine&#xD;
      1:100.000) and elevating a full-thickness flap, the surgical guide was placed in position and&#xD;
      an antrostomy was created by consuming the lateral wall of the maxillary sinus with&#xD;
      ultrasonic instrumentation in the area between the two planned implant sites. The sinus&#xD;
      membrane was then carefully elevated and, after checking its integrity with visual inspection&#xD;
      and Valsalva maneuver, the subantral space was filled with a composite graft in granules [50%&#xD;
      cortico-cancellous porcine graft (Gen-Os, Tecnoss, Pianezza, Italy) - 50% synthetic&#xD;
      nano-hydroxyapatite (Fisiograft Bone, Ghimas, Casalecchio di Reno, Italy)]. A resorbable&#xD;
      bovine collagen membrane (Bio-Gide, Geistlich, Wolhusen, Switzerland) fixed with two pins was&#xD;
      placed to cover the lateral antrostomy and flaps were sutured with Sentineri sutures and&#xD;
      single stitches using synthetic monofilament. Patients were prescribed with antibiotics for 4&#xD;
      days (amoxicillin 1 g three times a day) and NSAID (ibuprofen 600 mg), when needed. Sutures&#xD;
      were removed after 10 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After 6 months of healing, a cone beam tc scan was performed to evaluate the radiographic&#xD;
      outcome of the regenerative procedure and to plan implant insertion. With the assistance of&#xD;
      the surgical template, two bone-core biopsy biopsies were harvested in the planned implant&#xD;
      sites by using 3-mm diameter trephine drills (2982.Y0.30, DenTag, Maniago, Italy) (Fig. 3-4).&#xD;
      Dental implants were then inserted in the biopsy sites: after 5 months of submerged healing,&#xD;
      they were restored with screwed ceramic crowns.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Radiographic measurements Radiographic measurements were taken from the three cone beam CT&#xD;
      cross-sectional slices (step 1 mm; width 1 mm) corresponding to the position where the biopsy&#xD;
      was retrieved. Two independent calibrated examiners (A.R. and Fe.Be.) measured residual bone&#xD;
      height (RBH) between the alveolar ridge and the sinus floor; sinus width (SW) (distance&#xD;
      between buccal and palatal walls at 10-mm level, comprising the residual alveolar crest.&#xD;
      Distances were measured by using the specific tool of an imaging software (OsiriX MD, Pixmeo&#xD;
      SARL, Bernex, Switzerland) and were expressed in millimeters. Intra-examiner reliability was&#xD;
      assessed with Cohen's K test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample processing for histological analysis Histologic and histomorphometric analyses of all&#xD;
      specimens were performed by one of the authors (VN), blinded to the study design and to&#xD;
      biopsy origin. Immediately after harvesting, biopsies were carefully rinsed with cold 5%&#xD;
      glucose solution to remove blood remnants maintaining the correct osmolarity (278&#xD;
      milliosmole/L).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specimens were subsequently fixed for three days in 10% buffered formalin solution at pH 7.2,&#xD;
      and then dehydrated in an ascending series of alcohol rinses and embedded in a methacrylate&#xD;
      resin (Technovit 7200 VLC, Kulzer, Wehrheim, Germany). After 12 days of polymerization,&#xD;
      biopsies were cut along their longitudinal axis with a high-precision carborundum disk at 50&#xD;
      µm and then ground down under running water with a series of polishing discs to about 30 ± 10&#xD;
      µm. The slides were then mounted and stained with acid fuchsine-toluidine blue and von Kossa&#xD;
      staining.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Histomorphometry The following variables were measured for each biopsy: total area of the&#xD;
      biopsy (in mm2), percentage of newly-formed bone (NFB),percentage of connective tissue/marrow&#xD;
      spaces (MS), and percentage of residual graft particles (RG). The analysis was performed&#xD;
      using transmitted brightfield light microscope (Biostar B3; Exacta Optech, San Prospero,&#xD;
      Italy), connected to high resolution digital camera (Moticam 5.0; Motic Microscopy, Kowloon,&#xD;
      China). A software with image capturing capabilities (Image-Pro Plus 6.0; Media Cybernetics&#xD;
      Inc., Bethesda, MD, U.S.A.) was used to analyze images. Software calibration was performed&#xD;
      for each image analysis by using the &quot;Calibration Wizard&quot; tool, which reports the number of&#xD;
      pixels between two selected points. Linear remapping of the pixel numbers was used to&#xD;
      calibrate the distance in µm or in mm according to the magnification degree.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Predictor and outcome variables This prospective study tested the null hypothesis of no&#xD;
      differences in new bone formation among areas of different width in the same sinus against&#xD;
      the alternative hypothesis of a difference.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary predictor variables were sinus width (SW) and residual bone height (RBH).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcome measure:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • new bone formation (NFB) after six months of healing&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary outcome measures:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  residual graft (RG): after six months of healing&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  any complications or adverse events&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size calculation and statistical power A statistical software (Statistica per&#xD;
      Discipline Biomediche, Version 6.0, Mc Graw-Hill, New York, NY, U.S.A.) was used to determine&#xD;
      the sample size of this prospective study, basing on data of a previous publication. Expected&#xD;
      difference in NFB (as mean percentage) between narrow and wide part of the sinus was&#xD;
      13.8±18.25% (using sinus width=13 mm as a cut-off). A sample of 16 histological specimens for&#xD;
      each group was required to detect significant differences between the two groups (confidence&#xD;
      level 5% with statistical power of 80%).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis An independent investigator (A.R.) analyzed all datasets with&#xD;
      statistical software (IBM SPSS Statistics for Windows, Version 25.0, IBM Corp., Armonk, NY,&#xD;
      USA). Data normality was assessed with Shapiro-Wilk test: all datasets met the required&#xD;
      assumptions for using parametric methods. Descriptive statistics included mean and standard&#xD;
      deviation. The value of α was set to 0.05.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Differences in NFB between mesial and distal sites were evaluated by means of paired samples&#xD;
      t-test. The potential influence of sinus width and RBH on NFB and RG percentage was evaluated&#xD;
      by using Pearson correlation coefficient.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 15, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 15, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>quantity (%) of newly formed bone</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>quantity (%) of newly formed bone (NFB) in histomorphometric analysis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>quantity (%) of graft</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>quantity (%) of residual graft (RG) in histomorphometric analysis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>quantity of complications</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>quantity of any complications or adverse events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">16</enrollment>
  <condition>Alveolar Bone Resorption</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Large sinus</arm_group_label>
    <description>same patient, sinus width &gt; 12mm measured at 10mm from the alveolar crest at the planned implant site</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>narrow sinus</arm_group_label>
    <description>same patient, sinus width &lt; 12mm measured at 10mm from the alveolar crest at the planned implant site</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>sinus floor elevation with lateral approach</intervention_name>
    <description>sinus floor elevation with lateral approach. 6 months healing phase. implant site preparation with trephine bur and bone specimen retrieval.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Large sinus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>narrow sinus</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      alveolar bone specimen containing native bone, regenerated bone (with residual graft&#xD;
      particles); the specimens were retrieved with a trephine bur that prepared the same time the&#xD;
      implant site.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Any patient with Kennedy class II partial edentulism (Kennedy 1928) requiring unilateral&#xD;
        sinus floor elevation for the placement of two not adjacent dental implants supporting a&#xD;
        fixed partial prosthesis was eligible for entering this study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  height of the residual bone crest &lt;5 mm in both sites where implant placement was&#xD;
             planned;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age &gt;18 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  written informed consent given.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  general contraindications to implant surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  smokers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  uncontrolled diabetes (HBA1c &gt; 7.5%)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  treated or under treatment with intravenous antiresorptive drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  allergy to bovine collagen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  immunosuppressed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  irradiated in the head and neck area&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  substance abusers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  psychiatric problems or unrealistic expectations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patient not fully able to comply with the study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  maxillary sinus conditions contraindicating sinus floor elevation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  poor oral hygiene and motivation (FMPS &gt;25 and or FMBS&gt;20)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Schneiderian membrane perforation during surgery&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Claudio Stacchi, Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Piezoelectricsurgery Academy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hesire</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cassano allo Ionio</city>
        <state>CS</state>
        <zip>87011</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Studio</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gorizia</city>
        <state>GO</state>
        <zip>34170</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Studio B</name>
      <address>
        <city>Verona</city>
        <state>VR</state>
        <zip>37045</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Stacchi C, Spinato S, Lombardi T, Bernardello F, Bertoldi C, Zaffe D, Nevins M. Minimally Invasive Management of Implant-Supported Rehabilitation in the Posterior Maxilla, Part I. Sinus Floor Elevation: Biologic Principles and Materials. Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 2020 May/Jun;40(3):e85-e93. doi: 10.11607/prd.4497.</citation>
    <PMID>32233183</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Stacchi C, Spinato S, Lombardi T, Bernardello F, Bertoldi C, Zaffe D, Nevins M. Minimally Invasive Management of Implant-Supported Rehabilitation in the Posterior Maxilla, Part II. Surgical Techniques and Decision Tree. Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 2020 May/Jun;40(3):e95-e102. doi: 10.11607/prd.4498.</citation>
    <PMID>32233185</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Stacchi C, Vercellotti T, Toschetti A, Speroni S, Salgarello S, Di Lenarda R. Intraoperative complications during sinus floor elevation using two different ultrasonic approaches: a two-center, randomized, controlled clinical trial. Clin Implant Dent Relat Res. 2015 Jan;17 Suppl 1:e117-25. doi: 10.1111/cid.12136. Epub 2013 Aug 22.</citation>
    <PMID>23968289</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Avila G, Wang HL, Galindo-Moreno P, Misch CE, Bagramian RA, Rudek I, Benavides E, Moreno-Riestra I, Braun T, Neiva R. The influence of the bucco-palatal distance on sinus augmentation outcomes. J Periodontol. 2010 Jul;81(7):1041-50. doi: 10.1902/jop.2010.090686.</citation>
    <PMID>20450402</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Sinus lift;</keyword>
  <keyword>sinus elevation;</keyword>
  <keyword>sinus width;</keyword>
  <keyword>bone graft</keyword>
  <keyword>histomorphometry</keyword>
  <keyword>alveolar bone atrophy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bone Resorption</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>data will be shared after data managing and statistics</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

