<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04839770</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MIECH-2020-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04839770</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>MIECH: The Minimally Invasive Endoscopic Surgery With the Axonpen System for Spontaneous Intracerebral Hemorrhage</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Minimally Invasive Endoscopic Surgery With the Axonpen System for Spontaneous Intracerebral Hemorrhage (MIECH): An Open-label, Non-randomized, Single-arm Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Clearmind Biomedical Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Chang Gung Memorial Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Clearmind Biomedical Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this trial is to provide preliminary safety data of the minimally&#xD;
      invasive endoscopic surgery using the Axonpen™ system for spontaneous intracerebral&#xD;
      hemorrhage (ICH). The effectiveness of the Axonpen™ system in early hematoma removal and the&#xD;
      surgical impact on subject's functional recovery will also be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Axonpen™ system, consisting of a neuroendoscope (Axonpen) and a monitor (Axonmonitor), is&#xD;
      cleared by FDA and indicated for the illumination and visualization of intracranial tissue&#xD;
      and fluids and the controlled aspiration of tissue and/or fluid during surgery of the&#xD;
      ventricular system or cerebrum.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In the present trial, the FDA-cleared Axonpen™ system will be applied on the ICH surgery. The&#xD;
      Axonpen™ System is a neuroendoscope combined with the functions of hematoma aspiration and&#xD;
      irrigation, aiming to minimize surgical brain injury, optimize surgical procedure, and be&#xD;
      available for early hematoma evacuation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The technique of minimally invasive endoscopic neurosurgery for ICH is still considered in&#xD;
      development; however, a retrospective study [Kuo et al.] has shown that early and complete&#xD;
      evacuation of ICH may lead to improved outcomes in selected patients, where the surgery&#xD;
      utilized combination of the existing instruments, such as a rod-lens endoscope with&#xD;
      irrigation system and a suction coagulator, to enable visualization, aspiration, and&#xD;
      irrigation of the hematoma to be worked simultaneously. The technology employed and the&#xD;
      results revealed in this study provide a proof of concept for the Axonpen™ system, and also&#xD;
      imply that the current device could be safe and effective in the management of ICH.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 7, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Safety will be assessed by determining mortality within 30 days post-operation for all subjects</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Adverse events (AEs), Serious Adverse Events (SAEs), and Unanticipated Device Effects (UDEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days</time_frame>
    <description>AEs, SAEs, and UDEs will be observed from the beginning of the surgery until the last follow-up visit (Day 180) for safety monitoring, and their relation to the study device will be analyzed</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hemorrhage volume</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Residual hematoma will be measured via 6 &amp; 72 hours post-operation CT. Reduction (%) of hemorrhage volume will be assessed by comparing with pre-operation CT</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Glasgow Coma Scale (GCS)</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical assessment for level of consciousness and responsiveness before and after surgery (Assessed by the sum of E/V/M scores. E: Eye opening, 1 = None - 4 = Spontaneous. V: Verbal response, 1 = None - 5 = Normal conversation. M: Motor response, 1 = None - 6 = Normal)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>modified Rankin Scale (mRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Functional outcomes will be measured via mRS at 72 hours and 7 days post-operation, hospital discharge, and 40, 90, 180 days follow-up visits (Scale ranges from 1 to 7, 1 = No symptoms - 7 = Dead)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Glasgow Outcome Scale Extended (GOSE)</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Functional outcomes will be measured via GOSE at 72 hours and 7 days post-operation, hospital discharge, and 40, 90, 180 days follow-up visits (Scale ranges from 1 to 8, 1 = Death - 8 = Upper good recovery)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of ICU</measure>
    <time_frame>Number of days from admission, up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of stay in the ICU</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>Number of days from admission to discharge, up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of stay in the hospital</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Intracerebral Hemorrhage</condition>
  <condition>Cerebral Hemorrhage</condition>
  <condition>Intracranial Hemorrhage</condition>
  <condition>Basal Ganglia Hemorrhage</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Axonpen</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive minimally invasive endoscopic surgery using the Axonpen™ system for early hematoma evacuation (within 48 hours post-ictus).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Axonpen system</intervention_name>
    <description>The Axonpen™ system, containing the Axonpen and the Axonmonitor, has been cleared for the illumination and visualization of intracranial tissue and fluids and the controlled aspiration of tissue and/or fluid during surgery of the ventricular system or cerebrum.&#xD;
The Axonpen is a neuroendoscope integrated with suction (sourced from hospital vacuum) and irrigation (sourced from third-party saline infusion bag) functions. The Axonmonitor is used for view and storage of the endoscopic image. The Axonpen™ system is intended to optimize the procedure of minimally invasive neurosurgery for early ICH evacuation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Axonpen</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients who fulfill ALL the inclusion criteria will be enrolled:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 20-80 years, all genders/sexes are inclusive;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Evidence of a spontaneous basal ganglia ICH on CT scan;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient, or a family member with legally authorized responsibility, has given informed&#xD;
             consent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. GCS of 6-14;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Volume of hematoma in range of 30-80 ml as measured by the ABC/2 method;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Can receive surgical treatment within 48 hours after ictus.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients who fulfill ANY ONE of the exclusion criteria should not be enrolled:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. CT angiography (CTA) spot sign positive or CT blend sign positive;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Previous symptomatic stroke with neurological sequelae (per history or as seen on&#xD;
             initial CT scan);&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. ICH known or suspected by study investigator to be secondary to aneurysm, vascular&#xD;
             malformation, hemorrhagic transformation of ischemic stroke, cerebral venous&#xD;
             thrombosis, thrombolytic therapy, tumor, or infection;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Acute or active infection signs requiring treatment at the time of admission;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Significant ventricular extension of the hemorrhage; more than 30 mL of&#xD;
             intraventricular hemorrhage;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Refractory elevated ICP after placement of an EVD (external ventricular drain);&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Severe pre-existing physical or mental disability or severe co-morbidity which might&#xD;
             interfere with assessment of outcome;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Minimally invasive neurosurgery could not be commenced within 48 hours of onset. The&#xD;
             case shall be excluded when the time of onset cannot be estimated and is judged with&#xD;
             controversy by the investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The hematological effects of any previous anticoagulants are not completely reversed&#xD;
             (prothrombin time &gt; 12.2 seconds, partial thromboplastin time &gt; 35.5 seconds, platelet&#xD;
             count &lt; 100 × 10^3/μL);&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Hereditary or acquired hemorrhagic diathesis or coagulation factor deficiency;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Any condition that could impose hazards to the patient with the MIN or affect the&#xD;
             participation of the patient in the study. The judgment is left to the discretion of&#xD;
             the investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Major surgery within the preceding 14 days which poses risk in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Any history or current evidence suggestive of venous or arterial thrombotic events&#xD;
             within the previous 12 months, including clinical, ECG, laboratory, or imaging&#xD;
             findings;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Use of heparin, low-molecular weight heparin, GPIIb/IIIa antagonist, antiplatelet&#xD;
             agents, or oral anticoagulation (e.g., warfarin, factor Xa inhibitor, thrombin&#xD;
             inhibitor) within the previous 14 days, irrespective of laboratory values;&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Pregnancy, breast-feeding, or positive pregnancy test (either serum or urine) (Woman&#xD;
             of child-bearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test prior to the study&#xD;
             procedure.);&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Participation in any investigational study in the last 30 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Known terminal illness or planned withdrawal of care or comfort care measures.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hsiu-Jen Lin, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+886-2-22697417</phone>
    <phone_ext>108</phone_ext>
    <email>shaun@theclearmindgroup.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Chun-Wei Yang</last_name>
    <phone>+886-2-22697417</phone>
    <phone_ext>107</phone_ext>
    <email>carrey@theclearmindgroup.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chang Gung Memorial Hospital (Linkou Branch)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taoyuan</city>
        <zip>333423</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <phone>+886-3-3281200</phone>
      <phone_ext>2412</phone_ext>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Chi-Cheng Chuang, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kuo LT, Chen CM, Li CH, Tsai JC, Chiu HC, Liu LC, Tu YK, Huang AP. Early endoscope-assisted hematoma evacuation in patients with supratentorial intracerebral hemorrhage: case selection, surgical technique, and long-term results. Neurosurg Focus. 2011 Apr;30(4):E9. doi: 10.3171/2011.2.FOCUS10313.</citation>
    <PMID>21456936</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 31, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Intracerebral Hemorrhage</keyword>
  <keyword>Cerebral Hemorrhage</keyword>
  <keyword>Intracranial Hemorrhage</keyword>
  <keyword>ICH</keyword>
  <keyword>Stroke</keyword>
  <keyword>Endoscopic Hematoma Evacuation</keyword>
  <keyword>Minimally Invasive Surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Endoscopic Neurosurgery</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cerebral Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Intracranial Hemorrhages</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Basal Ganglia Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

