<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04830527</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>030-2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04830527</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>EMA Baseline Screening System for Therapists Who Treat Youths With Depressive Symptoms</brief_title>
  <official_title>Development and Evaluation of an Ecological Momentary Assessment (EMA) Baseline Screening System for Therapists Who Treat Youths With Depressive Symptoms</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vania Martínez-Nahuel</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>ANID - Millennium Science Initiative Program - NCS17_03 Millennium Nucleus to Improve the Mental Health of Adolescents and Youths (Imhay), Santiago, Chile</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>ANID - Millennium Science Initiative Program - ICS13_005 Millennium Institute for Research in Depression and Personality (MIDAP), Santiago, Chile</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Center for Psychotherapy Research, University Hospital Heidelberg, Heidelberg, Germany</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Chile</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Youth depression is a matter of concern worldwide. It affects an important part of the young&#xD;
      population around the world and its consequences both physically and mentally make this issue&#xD;
      an important research field for psychologists and other health related professionals&#xD;
      (Zuckerbrot, Cheung, Jensen, Stein &amp; Laraque, 2018). Two of the biggest challenges that&#xD;
      clinicians and researchers face when dealing with youth depression are adherence and the&#xD;
      establishment of a therapeutic alliance (TA; Nock &amp; Ferriter, 2005). While several treatments&#xD;
      are available to relief depressive symptomatology in youths, a significant number do not&#xD;
      access them for a variety of reasons (DiMatteo, Lepper &amp; Corgan, 2000). In the last decades,&#xD;
      substantial research has been conducted on how youths and the general population perceive&#xD;
      therapy, and different methods have been developed to assess clients and therapists in order&#xD;
      to improve outcomes and other aspects of the psychotherapy process, such as feedback tools&#xD;
      and real-time measurements like Ecological Momentary Assessment (EMA) (Shiffman, et al.,&#xD;
      2008). With the aid of Information Communication Technologies (ICTs) and eMental Health&#xD;
      strategies, feedback and assessment tools can be presented in a friendly manner, providing a&#xD;
      novel way to possibly improving adherence rates and TA scores. This study aims to develop and&#xD;
      test the effectiveness of an Ecological Momentary Assessment mobile application to improve&#xD;
      initial adherence and TA in psychotherapy for youths with depression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypotheses for this trial are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Applying an EMA baseline screening application one week before the beginning of&#xD;
           treatment for youth depression will significantly improve the TA.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Applying an EMA baseline screening application one week before the beginning of&#xD;
           treatment for youth depression will significantly improve initial adherence.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 24, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Working Alliance Inventory, Patient Form (WAI-P)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the end of first three psychotherapy sessions.</time_frame>
    <description>Likert scale with answers that range from 1 to 7. Higher scores suggest a better perception of the Therapeutic Alliance.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Working Alliance Inventory, Therapist Form (WAI-T)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the end of first three psychotherapy sessions.</time_frame>
    <description>Likert scale with answers that range from 1 to 7. Higher scores suggest a better perception of the Therapeutic Alliance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assistance to sessions</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the end of first three psychotherapy sessions.</time_frame>
    <description>Assistance to sessions will be registered by therapists as a measurement of initial adherence.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">160</enrollment>
  <condition>Depressive Symptoms</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in experimental group will receive EMA prompts. Therapists in this group will receive a summarized PDF report before the beginning of the first psychotherapy session. The report will include graphic summarized data from the EMA prompts.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in control group will receive the EMA prompts in the same manner as patients in the experimental group.&#xD;
Therapists in this group will not receive the PDF reports, and instead will get raw scores from a screening evaluation conducted with patients in the recruitment phase of the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>EMA prompting for patients</intervention_name>
    <description>EMA prompting will consist of the delivery of the PHQ-4 and PANAS questionnaires, as well as basic identification, therapy motivations and expectations, location, current activity and social interactions.&#xD;
These prompts will be presented to patients during a 7 day period, 5 times per day.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PDF Reports for therapists</intervention_name>
    <description>After the patients' EMA data is collected, a previously designed R script will summarize and transform the data into a brief and graphic report for therapists in the experimental arm of the study. These reports are intended to provide detailed information about the patients' mood, anxiety levels, positive and negative affects, as well as crossed data such as mood according to location, anxiety according to activity, etc.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria for Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Owning a mobile phone with permanent access to the internet,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Scoring from eleven to nineteen points in the PHQ-9 questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having completed the eighth grade of basic education.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria for Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being diagnosed with Depression with psychotic symptoms,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having a depressive episode as part of a bipolar disorder diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having suicidal thoughts and/or behaviour as measured by the PHQ-9 and evaluated by&#xD;
             the physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alcohol and/or substance abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria for Therapists:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Having 1 or more years of clinical experience.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria for Therapists:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having less than 1 year of clinical experience.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having participated in the design of PDF reports.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>24 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CEMERA, Faculty of Medicine, Universidad de Chile</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santiago</city>
        <state>Region Metropolitana</state>
        <zip>8380455</zip>
        <country>Chile</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Chile</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Abras, C., Maloney-Krichmar, D., Preece, J. (2004) User-Centered Design. In Bainbridge, W. Encyclopedia of Human-Computer Interaction. Thousand Oaks: Sage Publications.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Borghero F, Martínez V, Zitko P, Vöhringer PA, Cavada G, Rojas G. [Screening depressive episodes in adolescents. Validation of the Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9)]. Rev Med Chil. 2018 Apr;146(4):479-486. doi: 10.4067/s0034-98872018000400479. Spanish.</citation>
    <PMID>29999123</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cipriani A, Zhou X, Del Giovane C, Hetrick SE, Qin B, Whittington C, Coghill D, Zhang Y, Hazell P, Leucht S, Cuijpers P, Pu J, Cohen D, Ravindran AV, Liu Y, Michael KD, Yang L, Liu L, Xie P. Comparative efficacy and tolerability of antidepressants for major depressive disorder in children and adolescents: a network meta-analysis. Lancet. 2016 Aug 27;388(10047):881-90. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(16)30385-3. Epub 2016 Jun 8.</citation>
    <PMID>27289172</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Clark MS, Jansen KL, Cloy JA. Treatment of childhood and adolescent depression. Am Fam Physician. 2012 Sep 1;86(5):442-8. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22963063</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cox GR, Callahan P, Churchill R, Hunot V, Merry SN, Parker AG, Hetrick SE. Psychological therapies versus antidepressant medication, alone and in combination for depression in children and adolescents. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014 Nov 30;(11):CD008324. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD008324.pub3. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25433518</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>David-Ferdon C, Kaslow NJ. Evidence-based psychosocial treatments for child and adolescent depression. J Clin Child Adolesc Psychol. 2008 Jan;37(1):62-104. doi: 10.1080/15374410701817865. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18444054</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eapen V, Črnčec R. Strategies and challenges in the management of adolescent depression. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2012 Jan;25(1):7-13. doi: 10.1097/YCO.0b013e32834de3bd. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22156932</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fernández, O., Pérez, C., Gloger, S., Krause, M., (2015) Importancia de los cambios iniciales en psicoterapia con jovenes, Terapia Psicológica, (33)3, pp. 247 - 255.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fernández, O. M., Herrera-Salinas, P. &amp; Escobar-Martínez, M. J. (2016). youthes en Psicoterapia: Su Representación de la Relación Terapéutica. Revista Latinoamericana de Ciencias Sociales, Niñez y Juventud, 14 (1), pp. 559-575.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fernandez, O.M., Krause, M., &amp; Pérez, J.C. (2016). Therapeutic alliance in the initial phase of psychotherapy with ado- lescents: different perspectives and their association with therapeutic outcomes. Research in Psychotherapy: Psychopathology, Process and Outcome, 19(1), 1-9. doi: 10.4081/ripppo.2016.180</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Goodyer IM, Reynolds S, Barrett B, Byford S, Dubicka B, Hill J, Holland F, Kelvin R, Midgley N, Roberts C, Senior R, Target M, Widmer B, Wilkinson P, Fonagy P. Cognitive-behavioural therapy and short-term psychoanalytic psychotherapy versus brief psychosocial intervention in adolescents with unipolar major depression (IMPACT): a multicentre, pragmatic, observer-blind, randomised controlled trial. Health Technol Assess. 2017 Mar;21(12):1-94. doi: 10.3310/hta21120.</citation>
    <PMID>28394249</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hatcher, R., &amp; Gillaspy, J., (2006) Development and validation of a revised short version of the working alliance inventory, Psychotherapy Research, 16:1, 12-25, DOI: 10.1080/10503300500352500</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB. The Patient Health Questionnaire-2: validity of a two-item depression screener. Med Care. 2003 Nov;41(11):1284-92.</citation>
    <PMID>14583691</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB, Monahan PO, Löwe B. Anxiety disorders in primary care: prevalence, impairment, comorbidity, and detection. Ann Intern Med. 2007 Mar 6;146(5):317-25.</citation>
    <PMID>17339617</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kelders SM, Kok RN, Ossebaard HC, Van Gemert-Pijnen JE. Persuasive system design does matter: a systematic review of adherence to web-based interventions. J Med Internet Res. 2012 Nov 14;14(6):e152. doi: 10.2196/jmir.2104. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23151820</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lal S, Adair CE. E-mental health: a rapid review of the literature. Psychiatr Serv. 2014 Jan 1;65(1):24-32. doi: 10.1176/appi.ps.201300009. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24081188</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lambert MJ, Whipple JL, Smart DW, Vermeersch DA, Nielsen SL, Hawkins EJ. The effects of providing therapists with feedback on patient progress during psychotherapy: are outcomes enhanced? Psychother Res. 2001 Mar;11(1):49-68. doi: 10.1080/713663852.</citation>
    <PMID>25849877</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lambert MJ. Maximizing Psychotherapy Outcome beyond Evidence-Based Medicine. Psychother Psychosom. 2017;86(2):80-89. doi: 10.1159/000455170. Epub 2017 Feb 10. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28183083</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Luciano JV, Bertsch J, Salvador-Carulla L, Tomás JM, Fernández A, Pinto-Meza A, Haro JM, Palao DJ, Serrano-Blanco A. Factor structure, internal consistency and construct validity of the Sheehan Disability Scale in a Spanish primary care sample. J Eval Clin Pract. 2010 Oct;16(5):895-901. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2753.2009.01211.x.</citation>
    <PMID>20626541</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lewinsohn PM, Clarke GN. Psychosocial treatments for adolescent depression. Clin Psychol Rev. 1999 Apr;19(3):329-42.</citation>
    <PMID>10097874</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Michael KD, Crowley SL. How effective are treatments for child and adolescent depression? A meta-analytic review. Clin Psychol Rev. 2002 Mar;22(2):247-69. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11806021</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nock MK, Ferriter C. Parent management of attendance and adherence in child and adolescent therapy: a conceptual and empirical review. Clin Child Fam Psychol Rev. 2005 Jun;8(2):149-66. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15984084</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>O'Dea B, Calear AL, Perry Y. Is e-health the answer to gaps in adolescent mental health service provision? Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2015 Jul;28(4):336-42. doi: 10.1097/YCO.0000000000000170.</citation>
    <PMID>26001926</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pacheco, B. &amp; Aránguiz, C., (2011) Factores relacionados a la adherencia a tratamiento en youthes con depresión, Revista Chilena de Neuro-Psiquiatría, 49(1), pp. 69-78.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Riper H, Andersson G, Christensen H, Cuijpers P, Lange A, Eysenbach G. Theme issue on e-mental health: a growing field in internet research. J Med Internet Res. 2010 Dec 19;12(5):e74. doi: 10.2196/jmir.1713.</citation>
    <PMID>21169177</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sheehan DV, Lecrubier Y, Sheehan KH, Amorim P, Janavs J, Weiller E, Hergueta T, Baker R, Dunbar GC. The Mini-International Neuropsychiatric Interview (M.I.N.I.): the development and validation of a structured diagnostic psychiatric interview for DSM-IV and ICD-10. J Clin Psychiatry. 1998;59 Suppl 20:22-33;quiz 34-57. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>9881538</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shimokawa K, Lambert MJ, Smart DW. Enhancing treatment outcome of patients at risk of treatment failure: meta-analytic and mega-analytic review of a psychotherapy quality assurance system. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2010 Jun;78(3):298-311. doi: 10.1037/a0019247.</citation>
    <PMID>20515206</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shiffman S, Stone AA, Hufford MR. Ecological momentary assessment. Annu Rev Clin Psychol. 2008;4:1-32. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18509902</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shirk SR, Karver M. Prediction of treatment outcome from relationship variables in child and adolescent therapy: a meta-analytic review. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2003 Jun;71(3):452-64. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>12795570</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Silk JS, Forbes EE, Whalen DJ, Jakubcak JL, Thompson WK, Ryan ND, Axelson DA, Birmaher B, Dahl RE. Daily emotional dynamics in depressed youth: a cell phone ecological momentary assessment study. J Exp Child Psychol. 2011 Oct;110(2):241-57. doi: 10.1016/j.jecp.2010.10.007. Epub 2010 Nov 26.</citation>
    <PMID>21112595</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weersing VR, Brent DA, Rozenman MS, Gonzalez A, Jeffreys M, Dickerson JF, Lynch FL, Porta G, Iyengar S. Brief Behavioral Therapy for Pediatric Anxiety and Depression in Primary Care: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Psychiatry. 2017 Jun 1;74(6):571-578. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.0429.</citation>
    <PMID>28423145</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weisz JR, Kuppens S, Ng MY, Eckshtain D, Ugueto AM, Vaughn-Coaxum R, Jensen-Doss A, Hawley KM, Krumholz Marchette LS, Chu BC, Weersing VR, Fordwood SR. What five decades of research tells us about the effects of youth psychological therapy: A multilevel meta-analysis and implications for science and practice. Am Psychol. 2017 Feb-Mar;72(2):79-117. doi: 10.1037/a0040360.</citation>
    <PMID>28221063</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 30, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Chile</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Vania Martínez-Nahuel</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>depression</keyword>
  <keyword>therapeutic alliance</keyword>
  <keyword>youth</keyword>
  <keyword>Ecological Momentary Assessment</keyword>
  <keyword>e-mental Health</keyword>
  <keyword>e-Health</keyword>
  <keyword>adherence</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

