<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04830085</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017/22</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04830085</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Factors Associated With Adenomyosis and a Clinical Scoring System for the Diagnosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Factors Associated With Adenomyosis and a Clinical Scoring System for the Diagnosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mersin University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mersin University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Adenomyosis is a relatively common benign disorder in which endometrial gland and stroma are&#xD;
      located within the myometrium resulting angiogenesis of the spiral vessel, hypertrophy of the&#xD;
      surrounding smooth muscles and enlargement of the uterus. So far the definitive diagnosis&#xD;
      still requires histologic analysis of the hysterectomy specimens or hysteroscopic or&#xD;
      laparoscopic biopsy. There is no specific laboratory tests and reliable clinical standards&#xD;
      for the diagnosis. The preoperative diagnosis of adenomyosis, would prevent unnecessary&#xD;
      therapies, loss of time and use of resources in vain. Therefore precise prediction of this&#xD;
      disease without surgery gains importance. Developing a scoring system with clinical&#xD;
      evaluation for this purpose will be very helpful in solving this problem. From this point,&#xD;
      the investigators aimed to develop a scoring system that will predict presence of adenomyosis&#xD;
      wİth high sensitivity using clinical evaluation methods such as history, physical&#xD;
      examination, ultrasonography and laboratory tests. A prospective cohort study was conducted&#xD;
      with 221 patients. In the study, the investigators have created a clinical scoring system for&#xD;
      this purpose for the first time in the literature. In this scoring system, there are simple&#xD;
      parameters that can be easily used by the clinician, have a low cost and are repeatable. The&#xD;
      effect of each parameter on predicting adenomyosis is different, and the total effect can be&#xD;
      calculated according to the answer to be given to all questions. In this simple scoring&#xD;
      system, parity, menarche, VAS scores of dysmenorrhea and dyspareunia, myometrial&#xD;
      heterogeneity in ultrasonography and presence of tenderness during pelvic examination were&#xD;
      found to be useful parameters in predicting the diagnosis of adenomyosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A prospective cohort study was conducted in Mersin University Faculty of Medicine Department&#xD;
      of Obstetrics and Gynecology between 10.02.2017 and 10.08.2017 with 221 patients who had&#xD;
      undergone hysterectomy for benign disorders. The patients who were admitted to the hospital&#xD;
      with the hysterectomy indications for benign pathologies were visited before the operation&#xD;
      and a detailed anamnesis was obtained. Physical and pelvic examinations with transvaginal&#xD;
      ultrasound examinations were performed by the same investigator. Demographic characteristics,&#xD;
      obstetric and gynecologic histories were noted. The amount of percieved pain was measured&#xD;
      with Visual Analog Scale (VAS). Observing myometrial cysts, enlarged uterus, heterogeneous&#xD;
      myometrium and or focal nodular areas during transvaginal sonography was considered to&#xD;
      suggest adenomyosis. The hysterectomy specimes were evaluated by department of pathology. The&#xD;
      diagnosis of adenomyosis was based on the presence of glandular extension ≥2.5 mm below the&#xD;
      endometrial myometrial interface.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to develop a scoring system a regression analysis was carried out to find the&#xD;
      parameters that were associated with the presence of adenomyosis. Number of parities,&#xD;
      dyspareunia and dysmenorrhea VAS scores, age of menarche, presence of uterine tenderness and&#xD;
      detection of heterogenous myometrium and myometrial cysts during ultrasonography were found&#xD;
      to be the significant parameters.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 10, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 10, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 10, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Severity of dysmenorrhea measured with Visual Analog Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Severity of dyspareunia measured with Visual Analog Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of myometrial heterogeneity during transvaginal ultrasonographic examination</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of myometrial cysts during transvaginal ultrasonographic examination</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Presence of uterine tenderness during pelvic examination</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">221</enrollment>
  <condition>Adenomyosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with adenomyosis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Hysterectomy (abdominal or vaginal or laparoscopic) Histopathological assessment Adenomyosis was diagnosed with histopathological assessment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients without adenomyosis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Hysterectomy (abdominal or vaginal or laparoscopic) Histopathological assessment Adenomyosis was excluded with histopathological assessment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hysterectomy</intervention_name>
    <description>Hysterectomy (abdominal, vaginal or laparoscopic)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with adenomyosis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients without adenomyosis</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Histopathological evaluation</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patients who were admitted to the hospital with the hysterectomy indications for&#xD;
             benign pathologies&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with postoperative diagnosis of gynecologic malignancies and who were&#xD;
             pregnants&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>HAKAN AYTAN, Prof. MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Mersin University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mersin University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mersin</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Mersin University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Hakan Aytan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenomyosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

