<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04839328</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HM005PS3S01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04839328</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase Ⅲ Efficacy and Safety Study of Hemay005 in Subjects With Moderate to Severe Plaque Psoriasis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase Ⅲ Multicenter, Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled To Assess Efficacy and Safety Study of Hemay005 in Subjects With Moderate to Severe Plaque Psoriasis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tianjin Hemay Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tianjin Hemay Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Hemay005 is a novel phosphodiesterase type 4(PDE4) inhibitor being developed for the&#xD;
      treatment of psoriasis. After single asending dose and mutiple asending dose in health&#xD;
      subjects. phase 2 results suggest Hemay005 60 mg BID has a higher curative effect trend，and&#xD;
      adverse reactions were mild, so we choose 60 mg BID as Hemay005 phase 3 dosage And the&#xD;
      patients with moderate to severe plaque psoriasis will be randomized into 2 cohorts(60mg BID&#xD;
      and placebo) approximately 306 subjects will be enrolled (204 in 60mg BID and 102 in&#xD;
      placebo). This study includes an 16-week treatment Period, then a 36-week Treatment Period&#xD;
      without placebo.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 13, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 12, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 5, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects who have 75% or more reduction in [Psoriasis area-and-severity index score (PASI)] (PASI75).</measure>
    <time_frame>week 16</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of subjects who have a reduction of 75% or more from baseline in the psoriasis area-and-severity index score (PASI 75) at week 16.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects achieving an overall sPGA score of clear (0) or almost clear (1) with at least a 2-point reduction from baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>week 16</time_frame>
    <description>The static Physician's Global Assessment (sPGA) rated the investigator's overall clinical assessment of a participants plaque thickness, erythema, and scaling on a 6-point scale ranging from 0 (clear, except for residual discoloration) to 5 (majority of plaques have severe thickness, erythema, and scale). To assign a sPGA score, the investigator examined all psoriatic lesions and assigned a severity score ranging from 0 to 5 for thickness, erythema, and scaling. Scores for thickness, erythema, and scaling are summed and the mean of these 3 scores equals the overall sPGA score. Decreases in sPGA correspond to clinical improvement.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects who have 75% or more reduction in [Psoriasis area-and-severity index score (PASI)] (PASI75).</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects achieving an overall sPGA score of clear (0) or almost clear (1) with at least a 2-point reduction from baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects who have 90% or more reduction in [Psoriasis area-and-severity index score (PASI)] (PASI90).</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">306</enrollment>
  <condition>Psoriasis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>60mg Hemay005</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with chronic plaque psoriasis will be treated BID for 16 weeks with 60mg Hemay005 in first phase. Then will be treated BID for 36-week extension followed with 60mg of Hemay005.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with chronic plaque psoriasis will be treated BID for 16 weeks with placebo in first phase. Then will be treated BID for 36-week extension followed with 60mg of Hemay005.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>60mg Hemay005</intervention_name>
    <description>Hemay005 is a small molecule PDE4 inhibitor.</description>
    <arm_group_label>60mg Hemay005</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebos are the same as drugs, but contain no Hemay005.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. At the time of signing the informed consent, the age was more than or equal to 18&#xD;
             years old, regardless of gender；&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Stable plaque psoriasis with a history of more than 6 months (from the time of&#xD;
             randomization)；&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Screening and baseline PSAI ≥12, sPGA≥3（Moderate to Severe）,affected body surface area&#xD;
             BSA≥10%；&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. All subjects must agree and commit to the use of a reliable contraceptive regimen.&#xD;
             Women of childbearing potential must undergo monthly pregnancy testing during the&#xD;
             study and agree to use two of the following methods of contraception throughout the&#xD;
             study and for 90 days after the last dose of study drug. Reliable contraceptive&#xD;
             regimen: vasectomy, abstinence, the use of condoms, intrauterine contraceptives (IUD),&#xD;
             (Oral administration, patch, ring, injection, implantation) Barrier methods (diaphragm&#xD;
             with spermicide, condom with spermicide)；&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The subjects voluntarily participated in the study and signed the informed consent .&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Forms of psoriasis other than chronic plaque-type; (i.e., erythrodermic and guttate&#xD;
             psoriasis, palmar, plantar or nail disease) at screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Investigator diagnosed as drug-induced psoriasis (including but not limited to new&#xD;
             onset or aggravation of psoriasis caused by beta blockers, calcium channel inhibitors&#xD;
             or lithium preparations);&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Skin diseases, chronic diarrhea, serious digestive system diseases (such as active&#xD;
             gastric ulcer, gastrointestinal bleeding, etc.), or other autoimmune inflammatory&#xD;
             diseases that may interfere with clinical evaluation, according to the investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The screening period was accompanied with active infection (such as bacterial&#xD;
             infection, viral infection, fungal infection, etc., which required oral or intravenous&#xD;
             treatment), and the investigator assessed that participation in this study may&#xD;
             increase the risk of subjects;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects with a history of tuberculosis or active tuberculosis (there were signs or&#xD;
             symptoms of active tuberculosis judged by the researcher at the time of screening);&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Use of prohibited treatments of this study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of congenital or acquired immunodeficiency;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects couldn't limit their uv exposure during the study period ;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of apremilast or Hemay005 tablets;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects with conditions that may affect oral drug absorption, such as subtotal&#xD;
             gastrectomy, clinically significant diabetic gastroenteropathy, or certain types of&#xD;
             weight-loss surgery, such as gastric bypass surgery, do not include surgery that&#xD;
             simply separates the stomach into separate Chambers, such as gastric banding surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects with tumor or history of malignancy (solid organ tumor or hematological tumor&#xD;
             including myelodysplastic syndrome) in the past 5 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. History of alcohol or drug abuse or dependence in the past year;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subjects with a history of mental illness, suicidal behavior (including positive&#xD;
             attempt, interrupted attempt or attempted suicide) or suicidal thoughts in the past 6&#xD;
             months were not suitable for clinical trials after the evaluation of the investigator;&#xD;
             subjects with severe anxiety or depression during the screening period were assessed&#xD;
             as severe anxiety or depression;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. There are clinically serious, progressive or uncontrollable diseases in the screening&#xD;
             period, including but not limited to respiratory system, cardiovascular system,&#xD;
             endocrine system, blood system, musculoskeletal system and nervous system. According&#xD;
             to the assessment of investigator, participating in this study may increase the risk&#xD;
             of subjects or interfere with data interpretation;&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. In the screening period, human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) serological positive&#xD;
             (i.e., HIV antibody positive);Evidence of hepatitis B virus infection: hepatitis B&#xD;
             surface antigen (HBsAg) positive, or hepatitis B core antibody (HBcAb) positive and&#xD;
             HBV-DNA above the upper limit of the normal range, or hepatitis B E antibody (HBeAb)&#xD;
             positive and HBV-DNA above the upper limit of the normal range;Evidence of hepatitis C&#xD;
             virus (HCV) infection: HCV antibody positive;&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. During the screening period, there were any of the following laboratory abnormalities:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt; 2 times the&#xD;
                  upper limit of normal value, or total bilirubin &gt; 1.5 times the upper limit of&#xD;
                  normal value;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Serum creatinine &gt; 1.2 times the upper limit of normal value;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. The hemoglobin of male patients was less than 8.5 g / dl (85.0 g / L), and that&#xD;
                  of female patients was less than 8.0 g / dl (80.0 g / L);&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. WBC count &lt; 3.0 × 109 / L or ≥ 14 × 109 / L;&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Platelet count &lt; 100 × 109 / L&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Female who were pregnant during lactation or pregnancy, or during the planned study&#xD;
             period, or subjects who had sperm / egg donation plans during the study period;&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Know allergic to active ingredient or excipient of the investigational product;&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Participated in any other interventional clinical trial within 4 weeks or 5&#xD;
             pharmacokinetic / pharmacodynamic half lives before randomization (whichever is&#xD;
             longer);&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. The investigator considered that there are any other conditions that are not suitable&#xD;
             for participating in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Junitng Wu</last_name>
    <phone>+8615822778207</phone>
    <email>hemay1834@126.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hemay005</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

