<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04838145</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2015-003350-41</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04838145</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Diabetes Virus Detection and Intervention Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>DiViDInt</acronym>
  <official_title>The Diabetes Virus Detection and Intervention Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Oslo University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Oslo University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study in 96 children and adolescents age 6-15&#xD;
      newly diagnosed with type 1 diabetes to describe the influence of antiviral treatment&#xD;
      (Pleconaril and Ribavirin) on progression of disease and residual insulin secretion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      If antiviral treatment is efficient in halting the disease progression, it will be to great&#xD;
      benefit for the participating patients. Maintenance or even an increase in beta cell mass due&#xD;
      to regeneration will lead to improved endogenous insulin production and give a milder course&#xD;
      of the disease with improved glycemic control. This will in a substantial way improve the&#xD;
      long-term prognosis with less severe long term vascular complications.Some patients may have&#xD;
      close to complete remission and be able to stop insulin treatment. If antiviral treatment is&#xD;
      effective, it would add proof to the concept that type 1 diabetes in its origin is a viral&#xD;
      disease. This would be an important milestone in medical research and a breakthrough in the&#xD;
      understanding of the etiopathogenesis of autoimmune diseases. It may promote the development&#xD;
      of vaccines to prevent the disease. T1D seems more aggressive in children than in adults, and&#xD;
      the beta cell function decline rapidly compared to adults. As a consequence, the effect of&#xD;
      antiviral treatment will potentially be more significant in children than in adults. Children&#xD;
      have higher HbA1c which increases the risk of complications. Thus, T1D is a more aggressive&#xD;
      disease in children than in adults and hence it's important to do this study in children.&#xD;
      Pharmaceuticals are usually studied in different age intervals, commonly 1-6 years, 6-12&#xD;
      years and 12-15 years. For safety reasons and simplicity, the investigators want to start&#xD;
      with the two older groups. The investigators will treat the participants with two antiviral&#xD;
      medications (Pleconaril and ribavirin) or placebo in a double blind, randomized, placebo&#xD;
      controlled, parallel group study. Pleconaril has previously been given in doses of 5-10mg/kg&#xD;
      x 2-3 in clinical trials in children, thus achieving serum levels high enough for killing the&#xD;
      majority of the viruses. The investigators have, due to the long treatment period, reduced&#xD;
      the doses to 5 mg/kg x 2. Ribavirin will be given in dosages according to Summariy of product&#xD;
      characteristics (SmPC). The investigators have chosen to administer Investigational Medicinal&#xD;
      Product (IMPs) as an oral solution as this will make it easier to give the medication&#xD;
      according to weight.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 30, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 25, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 25, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A double-blind, placebo controlled, prospective, randomized trial examining the effect of antiviral treatment given for 6months on residual insulin secretion</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Insulin secretion</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in mean residual insulin secretion in the Insulin tolerance test (ITT)-population measured by Mixed Meal Tolerance Test (MMTT) stimulated C-peptide two-hour area under the curve profile from visit 1 to12 months after initiation of study treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insulin secretion</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in mean residual insulin secretion in the ITT-population measured by Mixed Meal Tolerance Test (MMTT) stimulated C-peptide two-hour area under the curve profile from visit 1 to 3 months after initiation of study treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insulin secretion</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in mean residual insulin secretion in the ITT-population measured by Mixed Meal Tolerance Test (MMTT) stimulated C-peptide two-hour area under the curve profile from visit 1 to 6 months after initiation of study treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insulin secretion</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in mean residual insulin secretion in the ITT-population measured by Mixed Meal Tolerance Test (MMTT) stimulated C-peptide two-hour area under the curve profile from visit 1 to 24 months after initiation of study treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insulin secretion</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in mean residual insulin secretion in the ITT-population measured by Mixed Meal Tolerance Test (MMTT) stimulated C-peptide two-hour area under the curve profile from visit 1 to 36 months after initiation of study treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stimulated c-peptide</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with peak residual insulin secretion measured by MMTT: stimulated C-peptide &gt;0.2 pmol/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>C-peptide filter paper</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Fasting and meal stimulated C-peptide from blood sampled on filter paper at home at 4 weekly intervals throughout the study period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insulin dose</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean Insulin dosage per kilo bodyweight per 24 hours</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <description>HbA1c at every control</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hypoglycemic events</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of severe hypoglycaemic events and less severe events requiring assistance from others with blood glucose values ≤ 3.9 mmol/L will be registered at each control</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insulin-dose-adjusted HbA1c (IDAA1c)</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <description>HbA1c adjusted to insulin dose</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proinsulin/c-peptide ratio in serum</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proinsulin/c-peptide ratio in serum as a measure of beta cell stress</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Presence of enterovirus</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Presence of enterovirus and rhinovirus and/or neutralizing antibodies against those viruses in nose, blood, saliva and stool</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">96</enrollment>
  <condition>Type1 Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <condition>Enterovirus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pleconaril: 5 mg/kg x2 times a day for 26 weeks up to 40 kg. Max dose 300mg x2. Ribavirin:15 (7.5) mg/kg/day divided in two doses daily for 26 weeks: Max dose 1000mg/24h if body weight&lt;75kg and 1200mg if body weight&gt;75kg.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Receives placebo, on a double blind basis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavirin + Pleconaril</intervention_name>
    <description>Randomized to treatment with study drugs (ribavirin and pleconaril)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebos</intervention_name>
    <description>Randomized to treatment with placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Diagnosed type 1 Diabetes (E10.9). First injection of insulin maximum three weeks&#xD;
             prior to inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Must be willing and capable of taking the study drugs and meet for tests and follow up&#xD;
             as described.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Signed informed consent and expected cooperation of the patients for the treatment and&#xD;
             follow up must be obtained and documented according to International Conference on&#xD;
             Harmonization Good Clinical Practice (ICH GCP), and national/local regulations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Aged 6.00-15.99 years at inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Treatment with any oral or injected anti-diabetic medications other than insulin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. A history of haemolytic anaemia or significantly abnormal haematology results at&#xD;
             screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of severe cardiac disease previous six months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Impaired renal function&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients taking ethinyl estradiol&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participation in other clinical trials with a new chemical entity within the previous&#xD;
             3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Inability or unwillingness to comply with the provisions of this protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Females who are lactating or pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Males or females (after menarche) not willing to use highly effective contraception&#xD;
             (progesterone-only hormonal anticonception with inhibition of ovulation or sexual&#xD;
             abstinence) and barrier contraception (condoms), if sexually active during the&#xD;
             treatment period and in the following 7 months&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Presence of serious disease or condition, which in the opinion of the investigator&#xD;
             makes the patient non-eligible for the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Knut Dahl-Jørgensen, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Professor</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pediatric department, Oslo University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oslo</city>
        <zip>0514</zip>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Norway</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 4, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Oslo University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lars Krogvold</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Consultant</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Type 1 diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Children</keyword>
  <keyword>Enterovirus</keyword>
  <keyword>Recent onset</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Enterovirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pleconaril</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data and material collected from the placebo-group will be shared with the &quot;Innodia&quot; consortium</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

