<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04831203</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>METC 20-092</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04831203</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>NWT-03 and Brain Function</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Egg-protein Hydrolysate (NWT-03) to Boost Brain Function - Mind Your Blood Vessels</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Maastricht University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Maastricht University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Age-related chronic diseases including dementia, type II diabetes mellitus (T2DM) and&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease (CVD) become more prevalent and of increasing societal concern. Common&#xD;
      denominators of these co-morbidities are insulin-resistance and impaired vascular function.&#xD;
      Animal and short-term human studies now suggest that NWT-03 - an egg-protein hydrolysate -&#xD;
      improves insulin-sensitivity and peripheral vascular function, which are risk markers for the&#xD;
      development of T2DM and CVD. Insulin-resistance is also associated with cognitive decline,&#xD;
      while impaired brain vascular function is an important event preceding the development of&#xD;
      impaired cognitive performance. The investigators have already shown in a shorter-term trial&#xD;
      (12 weeks) beneficial effects of a daily dose of 5.0 g of NWT-03 on cognitive performance.&#xD;
      However, underlying mechanisms have not yet been addressed, while the long-term effects&#xD;
      remain unknown. Thus, the investigators now hypothesize that NWT-03 beneficially affects&#xD;
      cognitive performance and brain vascular function following long-term daily intake.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objectives of this trial are to evaluate in overweight or obese adults (aged&#xD;
      60-75) with subjective cognitive decline (SCD) the effects of a 36-weeks NWT-03 intervention&#xD;
      on (1) cognitive performance using a neurophysiological test battery, and (2) cerebral blood&#xD;
      flow, as quantified by the current non-invasive gold standard magnetic resonance imaging&#xD;
      (MRI) perfusion method Arterial Spin Labeling (ASL). Secondary study objectives are to&#xD;
      examine effects on insulin-sensitivity and peripheral vascular function.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This intervention study will have a randomized, controlled, parallel design. The total study&#xD;
      duration will be 36 weeks. Forty-four older adults (aged 60-75 years) with a Body Mass Index&#xD;
      (BMI) between 25-35 kg/m2 (overweight or obese) and subjective cognitive decline (SCD), as&#xD;
      assessed with the cognitive failure questionnaire, will participate. These study individuals&#xD;
      are known to be at increased risk of cognitive impairment, allowing for improvement by the&#xD;
      intervention. During the study, subjects will receive daily (in the morning) 5.0 g NWT-03 or&#xD;
      placebo powders for 36 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Due to the aging population, the number of people with cognitive impairment will have doubled&#xD;
      by the year 2035. Also, the number of individuals with type-2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) and&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease (CVD) will have increased substantially. Common denominators of these&#xD;
      age-related co-morbidities in humans are insulin-resistance and an impaired vascular&#xD;
      function.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Newtricious (NWT)-03 is a novel dietary egg-protein hydrolysate that has proven benefits on&#xD;
      glucose and insulin metabolism, as the investigators have recently shown in overweight or&#xD;
      obese individuals with T2DM or impaired glucose tolerance. Furthermore, peripheral vascular&#xD;
      function was improved. The potential explanation of these effects may arise from the finding&#xD;
      that NWT-03 blocks the enzyme dipeptidyl peptidase (DPP)-IV (7) - a pharmaceutical target for&#xD;
      the treatment of T2DM and CVD - that beneficially affects insulin metabolism. Compared to the&#xD;
      wealth of knowledge about the impact of insulin-sensitivity and peripheral vascular function&#xD;
      on the risk of T2DM and CVD, emerging evidence also indicates that these risk markers affect&#xD;
      cognitive performance. This is of great interest, since the brain is an insulin sensitive&#xD;
      organ and insulin-resistance is associated with cognitive decline, while impaired brain&#xD;
      vascular function is a key pathophysiological event preceding the development of an impaired&#xD;
      cognitive performance. A study in mice also showed effects of NWT-03 on neuro-inflammation&#xD;
      and oxidative stress in the brain. In fact, a decreased expression of TNF-α and improved&#xD;
      expression of enzymes involved in anti-oxidative processes were observed. The investigators&#xD;
      have also shown in a similar - but shorter-term (12 weeks) - trial beneficial effects of&#xD;
      NWT-03 on executive function, as the latency of response was reduced (manuscripts in&#xD;
      preparation). In addition, the hen egg-white hydrolysate (i.e. LumiVida) also improved&#xD;
      reaction time in middle-aged women. Underlying mechanisms of these hydrolysates on cognitive&#xD;
      performance were however not addressed. In our review the investigators summarized the impact&#xD;
      of dietary factors and exercise on brain vascular function in adults and discussed the&#xD;
      relation between these effects with changes in cognitive performance. It was concluded that&#xD;
      studies on the longer-term effects of lifestyle factors, including diet and physical&#xD;
      exercise, can improve brain vascular function, which may contribute to the beneficial effects&#xD;
      observed on cognitive performance. In addition, longer-term effects remain unknown and only a&#xD;
      limited number of parameters related to cognitive performance were studied. Therefore, the&#xD;
      investigators propose to perform a long-term placebo-controlled double blind intervention&#xD;
      study including functional outcome parameters and study in vivo effects of NWT-03 on brain&#xD;
      vascular function, which is a potential target to prevent or slow-down cognitive impairments,&#xD;
      and improve cognitive performance. Focus will be on older adults (aged 60-75 years) with a&#xD;
      Body Mass Index (BMI) between 25-35 kg/m2 (overweight or obese) and subjective cognitive&#xD;
      decline (SCD), as assessed with the cognitive failure questionnaire. These individuals are&#xD;
      known to be at increased risk of cognitive impairment, allowing for improvement by the&#xD;
      intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary study endpoints are effects on insulin-sensitivity and peripheral vascular&#xD;
      function, which are risk markers that may affect cognitive performance. Finally, the&#xD;
      investigators will focus on other potential mechanisms underlying effects on brain function&#xD;
      (i.e. ambulatory blood pressure, structural brain status, humoral factors, and the more&#xD;
      conventional cardiometabolic risk markers) and other perceivable benefits, including general&#xD;
      well-being (quality of life, sleep characteristics and mood) and physical fitness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Effects will be investigated using innovative and emerging non-invasive brain magnetic&#xD;
      resonance imaging (MRI)-perfusion methods, while focusing on whole brain and&#xD;
      cognitive-control brain areas plus cognitive performance tests. Furthermore, the&#xD;
      investigators have reviewed that cerebral blood flow in gray matter is a sensitive and&#xD;
      straightforward marker of brain vascular function, which correlates with cognitive&#xD;
      performance. Of note, lower cerebral blood flow is associated with accelerated cognitive&#xD;
      decline and increased risk of dementia in the general population based on results of the&#xD;
      Rotterdam prospective cohort study. Cerebral blood flow changes will be quantified on a&#xD;
      Siemens 3 Tesla Magnetom Prisma Fit scanner at the Scannexus research facilities by the&#xD;
      non-invasive gold standard approach: the MRI perfusion method pseudo-continuous Arterial Spin&#xD;
      Labeling.Cognitive performance will be assessed using CANTAB (i.e. Cambridge&#xD;
      Neuropsychological Test Automated Battery). These validated assessments for state-of-the-art&#xD;
      cognitive testing focus on the main cognitive domains (i.e. executive function, attention and&#xD;
      memory). Brain vascular function will be investigated using innovative and emerging&#xD;
      non-invasive brain magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)-perfusion methods, while focusing on&#xD;
      whole brain and cognitive-control brain areas plus cognitive performance tests. Furthermore,&#xD;
      the investigators have reviewed that cerebral blood flow in gray matter is a sensitive and&#xD;
      straightforward marker of brain vascular function, which correlates with cognitive&#xD;
      performance. Of note, lower cerebral blood flow is associated with accelerated cognitive&#xD;
      decline and increased risk of dementia in the general population based on results of the&#xD;
      Rotterdam prospective cohort study. Cerebral blood flow changes will be quantified on a&#xD;
      Siemens 3 Tesla Magnetom Prisma Fit scanner at the Scannexus research facilities by the&#xD;
      non-invasive gold standard approach: the MRI perfusion method pseudo-continuous Arterial Spin&#xD;
      Labeling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Considering the background information given in the previous paragraph, the following&#xD;
      research questions are formulated:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary research question:&#xD;
&#xD;
      What are the effects in older adults with a BMI between 25-35 kg/m2 and SCD of a 36-weeks&#xD;
      NWT-03 intervention on (i) cognitive performance using a neurophysiological test battery, and&#xD;
      (ii) cerebral blood flow, as quantified by the MRI-perfusion method Arterial Spin Labelling?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Major null hypotheses, H0:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. A 36-weeks NWT-03 intervention does not significantly affect cognitive performance in&#xD;
           older adults with a BMI between 25-35 kg/m2 and SCD.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. A 36-weeks NWT-03 intervention does not significantly affect cerebral blood flow, as&#xD;
           assessed by Arterial Spin Labelling, in older adults with a BMI between 25-35 kg/m2 and&#xD;
           SCD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Major alternate hypotheses, Ha:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. A 36-weeks NWT-03 intervention significantly affects cognitive performance in older&#xD;
           adults with a BMI between 25-35 kg/m2 and SCD.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. A 36-weeks NWT-03 intervention significantly affects cerebral blood flow, as assessed by&#xD;
           Arterial Spin Labelling, in older adults with a BMI between 25-35 kg/m2 and SCD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary research question:&#xD;
&#xD;
      What are the effects in older adults with SCD of a 36-weeks NWT-03 intervention on insulin&#xD;
      sensitivity and peripheral vascular function, which are risk markers for T2DM and CVD?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory research questions:&#xD;
&#xD;
      What are the effects in older adults with subjective cognitive decline (SCD) of a 36-weeks&#xD;
      NWT-03 intervention on;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  mechanisms underlying effects on brain function, including structural brain status,&#xD;
           humoral factors, and the more conventional cardiometabolic risk markers;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  perceivable (consumer) benefits, including physical fitness and general well-being.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A randomized, placebo-controlled trial with a parallel design will be conducted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before screening, subjects will be informed about the procedures and informed consent will be&#xD;
      obtained. Following screening, study participants that fulfill all inclusion criteria and are&#xD;
      willing to participate will be asked to participate in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be informed about their screening results, including anthropometric measures&#xD;
      (weight, length, body mass index), systolic and diastolic blood pressure (SBP and DBP), serum&#xD;
      total cholesterol and triacylglycerol concentrations, and plasma glucose concentrations. When&#xD;
      treatment with drugs or lifestyle interventions is indicated according to the Standards of&#xD;
      the Dutch general practitioners' community (NHG), subjects will be advised to consult their&#xD;
      general practitioner. Study results obtained during the intervention trial (i.e. brain&#xD;
      vascular function) will be reported in a descriptive way at a group level, for example:&#xD;
      &quot;brain vascular function is improved&quot;. because no accepted normal ranges exist for these&#xD;
      measurements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the days before blood sampling, adults are asked not to perform any strenuous physical&#xD;
      exercise or to consume alcoholic beverages. On the morning of blood sampling - after a&#xD;
      12-hour overnight fast (from 8.00 PM) - study subjects are only allowed to drink a glass of&#xD;
      water. Subjects are also asked not to change their habitual diet during the study. Finally,&#xD;
      subjects are asked to come to the Metabolic Research Unit (MRUM) by public transport or car&#xD;
      (and not by foot or bike) to standardize research measurements as much as possible&#xD;
&#xD;
      At baseline and after 18 weeks, anthropometric measurements will be performed, and a fasting&#xD;
      blood sample will be drawn. At baseline and after 36 weeks, subjects have to attend two times&#xD;
      the research facilities to perform the follow-up measurements: once for the &quot;Day A&quot;&#xD;
      measurements and once for the &quot;Day B&quot; measurements. During these tests, study participants&#xD;
      have to stay at the university and are not allowed to eat. These test days will take place&#xD;
      with an interval of three days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 23, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Brain Vascular Function</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Cerebral blood flow as quantified non-invasively by the MRI perfusion method Arterial Spin Labeling (ASL)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cognitive performance</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Cambridge Neuropsychological Test Automated Battery (CANTAB)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Glucose metabolism</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Oral Glucose Tolerance Test (OGTT)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peripheral vascular function (1)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Flow-mediated vasodilation (FMD)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peripheral vascular function (2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Carotid artery reactivity (CAR)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peripheral vascular function (3)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Pulse wave analysis (PWA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peripheral vascular function (4)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Pulse wave velocity (PWV)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peripheral vascular function (5)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Retinal microvascular calibers</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Systolic and Diastolic Blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Office and 24-hour ambulatory blood pressure</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Advanced glycation endproducts</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Serum protein-bound advanced glycation endproducts (AGEs)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Blood lipids</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Lipids and Lipoproteins</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Blood glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Glucose</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Blood Insulin</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>insulin</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Blood markers for low-grade systemic inflammation</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Markers for low-grade systemic inflammation (IL-6, TNF-alpha)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Blood markers for microvascular function</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Markers for microvascular function (sCAM-1, vWf, cGMP)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Blood marker of neurogenesis</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Brain-derived neurotrophic factor</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Structural brain status</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>MRI Structural MPRAGE scan</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Other perceivable benefits: Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>The Quality of life will be assessed using a 32-item questionnaire</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Other perceivable benefits: Physical fitness (1)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Timed up-and-go test (TUGT)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Other perceivable benefits: Physical fitness (2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>The 6-minute walk test (6 MWT)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Other perceivable benefits: Physical fitness (4)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Muscle strength test, as measured using the Biodex system</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Weight</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Weight in kg</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Height</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Height in kg</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Waist circumference</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Waist circumference in centimeters</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Hip circumference</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Hip circumference in centimeters</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Indirect fat distribution</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by skinfold measurements</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Food intake</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in outcomes at the end of a 36-week protein hydrolysate intervention and 36-week control period</time_frame>
    <description>Food intake will be assessed using the Food Frequency Questionnaire</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">44</enrollment>
  <condition>Brain Vascular Function</condition>
  <condition>Cognition</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Protein-hydrolysate</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dietary supplement: an egg-protein hydrolysate (NWT-03) Study volunteers will receive a daily powder of 5 g of protein hydrolysate to mix with 200 mL of water for 36 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control: 5 g of maltodextrin powder mixed with 250 mL of water for 36 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>An egg-protein hydrolysate (NWT-03)</intervention_name>
    <description>As described in the experimental arm</description>
    <arm_group_label>Protein-hydrolysate</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>As described in the Control arm</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men and women, aged between 60-75 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjective cognitive decline (SCD)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI between 25-35 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting plasma glucose &lt; 7.0 mmol/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting serum total cholesterol &lt; 8.0 mmol/L (further testing will be performed for&#xD;
             excessive hyperlipidemia [serum total cholesterol ≥ 8.0 mmol/L] according to the&#xD;
             Standard for cardiovascular risk management of NHG)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting serum triacylglycerol &lt; 4.5 mmol/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systolic blood pressure &lt; 160 mmHg and diastolic blood pressure &lt; 100 mmHg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stable body weight (weight gain or loss &lt; 3 kg in the past three months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to give up being a blood donor from 8 weeks before the start of the study,&#xD;
             during the study and for 4 weeks after completion of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No difficult venipuncture as evidenced during the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left-handedness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current smoker, or smoking cessation &lt; 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diabetic patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Familial hypercholesterolemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abuse of drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  More than 3 alcoholic units per day&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of vitamin or mineral supplements known to interfere with the main outcomes as&#xD;
             judged by the principal investigators within the previous 1-month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of medication to treat blood pressure, lipid or glucose metabolism&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of an investigational product within another trial within the previous 1-month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe medical conditions that might interfere with the study, such as epilepsy,&#xD;
             asthma, kidney failure or renal insufficiency, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease,&#xD;
             inflammatory bowel diseases, auto inflammatory diseases and rheumatoid arthritis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active cardiovascular disease like congestive heart failure or cardiovascular event,&#xD;
             such as an acute myocardial infarction or cerebrovascular accident&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contra-indications for MRI imaging (e.g. pacemaker, surgical clips/material in body,&#xD;
             metal splinter in eye, claustrophobia)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Peter J Joris, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Maastricht University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Peter J Joris, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+31 433881311</phone>
    <email>p.joris@maastrichtuniversity.nl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Micah S Adams, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>+31 433881313</phone>
    <email>m.adams@maastrichtuniversity.nl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Maastricht University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Maastricht</city>
        <state>Limburg</state>
        <zip>6211 LK</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Micah S Adams, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>+31 433881313</phone>
      <email>m.adams@maastrichtuniversity.nl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cerebral Blood Flow</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognitive Performance</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

