<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04837963</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RECHMPL21_0225</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04837963</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Does Hirschsprung Disease Increase the Risk of Febrile Urinary Tract Infection in Children</brief_title>
  <official_title>Does Hirschsprung Disease Increase the Risk of Febrile Urinary Tract Infection in Children ? A Case-control Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Montpellier</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Montpellier</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Febrile urinary tract infection (FUTIs) are the most common bacterial infections in children&#xD;
      under the age of 2 years. They represent 7% of children presenting with fever without a&#xD;
      source. In case of recurrent or undertreated FUTIs there is a risk for kidney function with&#xD;
      the threat of chronic renal failure [7]. They are more often isolated but some FUTIs may&#xD;
      reveal an underlying and facilitating condition. Beside the well-known congenital anomalies&#xD;
      of the kidneys and urinary tract such as reflux or obstructions, others risk factors for FUTI&#xD;
      are reported. Age less than 1 year, uncircumcised males, poor fluid intake, bladder bowel&#xD;
      dysfunction (BBD) including dysfunctional voiding pattern and constipation increase the risk&#xD;
      of FUTI. The prevalence of BBD in children with FUTIs is far higher than in the general&#xD;
      population. Recommendations emphasize on an efficient treatment of BBD in the first-line&#xD;
      management of recurring FUTIs and it has been proven to be efficient (ref).&#xD;
&#xD;
      One of the BBD may include Hirschsprung's Disease (HD). HD is the first congenital&#xD;
      malformation of the enteric nervous system with a reported prevalence of 1 in 5000 live&#xD;
      birth. It's characterized by an aganglionosis and subsequent dysmotility affect by always the&#xD;
      anal canal, most commonly there is a rectosigmoid form (74-80%), and less commonly involves a&#xD;
      long segment of colon (12-22%) or a total colonic aganglionosis with ileal involvement upto&#xD;
      50 cm proximal to ileocecal junction (4-13%). The treatment is based on the resection of&#xD;
      dysfunctional segment of colon with an anastomosis between the normally innervated bowel to&#xD;
      the anus, while preserving normal sphincter function. But significant bowel dysfunction may&#xD;
      persist postoperatively. 20% of the children present a fecal incontinence, and 14% a&#xD;
      constipation in long-term studies. Bladder dysfunction and associated urological anomalies&#xD;
      are also reported in these patients. All of that may facilitate the occurrence of febrile&#xD;
      urinary tract infections (FUTI) in patients with HD. Unfortunately, few studies focused on&#xD;
      this specific population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this study was to find out whether children with HD are more prone to&#xD;
      develop FUTIs than controls and which patient with HD are more at risk to develop UTIs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 16, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the risk of febril urinary tract infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Compare the risk of febril urinary tract infection between children with Hirschsprung disease and control Febrile urinary tract infection was defined as a positive urine examination with a single bacteria with more than 10.5 cfu/mL and more than 10.4 leukocytes/ml associated with fever above 38.5°C and C-reactive protein (CRP) above 50 mg/</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the age at the time of febrile urinary tract infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Compare the age at the time of febrile urinary tract infection between children with Hirschsprung disease and control. This event could occur sooner in children with Hirschsprung disease than controls.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Febrile urinary tract infection risk factor</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Febrile urinary tract infection risk factor for children with Hirschsprung disease based upon the form of the disease, kinf of surgery, functional results For each patient treated by Hirschsprung disease, surgical technique, the level of involvement and the functional outcome will be collected.&#xD;
The functional outcome was evaluated through the number of stool per day, the presence of soiling, the need of additional antegrade or retrograde colonic enema</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">630</enrollment>
  <condition>Hirschsprung Disease</condition>
  <condition>Febrile Urinary Tract Infection (Disorder)</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Cases were patients who underwent surgical treatment of an HD confirmed on histopathologic&#xD;
        exam. Controls were children who underwent an appendicetomy for acute appendicitis without&#xD;
        history of HD, ano rectal malformation or any other colic disease.. Two controls were&#xD;
        matched for age and sex, at least included for each case&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients :&#xD;
&#xD;
        - surgical treatment of an HD confirmed on histopathologic exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Controls :&#xD;
&#xD;
        - appendicetomy for acute appendicitis without history of HD, ano rectal malformation or&#xD;
        any other colic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with HD but not yet operated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patient with a stoma at the time of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patient with chronic intestinal pseudo obstruction without HD&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nicolas KALFA</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Montpellier</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University hospital of Montpellier</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montpellier</city>
        <zip>34295</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pediatric Surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Case Control study</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Tract Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hirschsprung Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hyperthermia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fever</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>NC</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

