<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04834154</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-57111</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04834154</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mental Health Disparities in Spanish Speaking Latina Breast Cancer Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Addressing Mental Health Disparities in Spanish Speaking Latina Breast Cancer Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Stanford University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Stanford University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of the study is to:Translate a mindfulness program into Spanish for Latina&#xD;
      patients with breast cancer.Train a community health worker to facilitate the mindfulness&#xD;
      program. Determine if this program is culturally acceptable and feasible, and Obtain pilot&#xD;
      data on the program's effectiveness in reducing anxiety and depression&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Primary aims of this study are to: 1) translate a behavioral health intervention into&#xD;
      Spanish, 2) deliver it to a population of Spanish speaking Latina breast cancer patients, and&#xD;
      3) determine acceptability and feasibility. Secondary aims are to gather preliminary data on&#xD;
      anxiety, depression and sleep quality pre and post intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability change across session</measure>
    <time_frame>End of each week for 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The Acceptability scale was developed for this study and is a 5 point Likert scored scale that will be administered after end of each weeks for 6 weeks. There are two questions with scores ranging from &quot;strongly disagree&quot; (score 0), &quot;disagree&quot; (score 1), &quot;neutral&quot; (score 2), &quot;agree&quot; (score 3), and &quot;strongly agree&quot; (score 4). Scores range from 0 to 8 with the higher scores representing greater levels of acceptability. It has 2 additional open ended questions: &quot;What changes did you make in your daily routine as a result of this intervention, if none, why&quot; and &quot;Were there any barriers to making changes you listed on your action plan, if so what were they? The scale takes approximately 5 minutes to complete. Acceptability change will be measured after each session (week 1-6). The mean score with standard deviation for each 6 sessions and acceptability will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in Feasibility</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The Feasibility and Satisfaction scale was developed for this study and is a 5 point Likert scored scale that will be administered at at time of completion of intervention or at time of withdraw (if participant withdraws prior to completion of intervention.) Five questions are scored from &quot;strongly disagree&quot; (score 0), &quot;disagree&quot; (score 1), &quot;neutral&quot; (score 2), &quot;agree&quot; (score 3), and &quot;strongly agree&quot; (score 4). Scores range from 0 to 20 with higher scores representing greater levels of feasibility. Differences in Feasibility will be evaluated and reported. There is also 1 open-ended question &quot;What is the optimal number of visits&quot; with continuous numeric score (participants able to write in number of preferred visits) with higher score representing desire for greater number of visits. The scale takes approximately 5-10 minutes to complete</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences in Generalized Anxiety Disorder-7 (GAD7) between time points.</measure>
    <time_frame>Three time points (week 1 and 6 of intervention, and 3 months post intervention.)</time_frame>
    <description>The GAD7 is a well validated seven-item self-administered questionnaire used to measure anxiety. It has 7 questions with Likert scores ranging from &quot;not at all&quot; (score 0), &quot;several days&quot; (score 1), &quot;more than half the days&quot; (score 2), and &quot;nearly every day (score 3).Scores range from 0 to 21 with higher scores indicating higher levels of anxiety, and a cutoff of or above 10 representing high likelihood of generalized anxiety disorder. Difference in GAD-7 measured at three time points (week 1 and 6 of the intervention and 3 months post intervention) will be compared and reported. The scale takes approximately 5-10 minutes to complete</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences in Center for Epidemiological Studies-Depression (CES-D) between time points.</measure>
    <time_frame>Three time points (week 1 and 6 of intervention, and 3 months post intervention.)</time_frame>
    <description>The CES-D scale is a well validated self-administered questionnaire used to measure depression. The 20 item scale has Likert scores ranging from &quot;rarely or none of the time&quot; (score 0), &quot;some or little of the time&quot; (score 1), &quot;moderate or much of the time&quot; (score 2), and &quot;most or almost all the time&quot; (score 3).Scores range from 0 to 60 with higher scores indicated greater depressive symptoms. A cut off at or above 20 has sensitivity 79% and specificity of 80% for major depression. Difference in CES-D measured at three time points (week 1 and 6 of the intervention and 3 months post intervention) will be reported and compared. The scale takes approximately 5-10 minutes to complete.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences in PROMIS-SD between time points</measure>
    <time_frame>Three time points (week 1 and 6 of intervention, and 3 months post intervention.)</time_frame>
    <description>The Participant Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) Adult Short Form: Sleep Disturbance (PROMIS-SD), is an 8 item scale measuring overall sleep quality, disturbances, and satisfaction over the past 7 days on 5 point Likert scale with scores ranging from 1 to 5. Raw scores are converted into t scores ranging from 28.9 to 76.5, with higher scores indicating greater sleep disturbance. Exploratory analysis will compare scores at three time points (week 1 and 6 of the intervention and 3 months post intervention). The scale takes approximately 2 minutes to complete 26 and is available in Spanish.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Depression, Anxiety</condition>
  <condition>Mindfulness</condition>
  <condition>Sleep Disturbance</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness group visit</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will attend 6 weekly educational and mindfulness sessions</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Wait list control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be placed on a wait list</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mindfulness</intervention_name>
    <description>6 weekly 2.0 hour video-conferenced group sessions with the following components: 1) short grounding meditation, 2) check in/review of prior weeks practice and symptoms, 3) educational topic, 3) main meditation, 4) reflection on meditation, and 5) action plan formation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness group visit</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Educational video</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control group</intervention_name>
    <description>Wait list control</description>
    <arm_group_label>Wait list control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self reported diagnosis of invasive breast cancer who has currently or within last 12&#xD;
             months been in active treatment (surgery, chemotherapy, or radiation) or on endocrine&#xD;
             therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-identified anxiety (persistent worry or nervousness), depression (feeling sad,&#xD;
             little interest or pleasure in doing things or hopeless), or sleep disturbance.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breast cancer related treatment (surgery, radiation, chemotherapy) or endocrine&#xD;
             therapy within the last 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self identifies as Spanish speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self identifies as Latinx / Latina / Latino&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-Spanish speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  other diagnosis besides invasive breast cancer (ie Ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS),&#xD;
             fibroadenoma, abnormal mammogram but not yet with final diagnosis, non-breast cancer&#xD;
             patients)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  comorbid bipolar affective disorder or psychotic disorder (as self-identified by&#xD;
             patient after asking &quot;do you have any other psychiatric conditions&quot;)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inability to physically or psychologically attend group sessions, and by discretion of&#xD;
             the study coordinator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients currently participation in stress reduction or mindfulness&#xD;
             groups/interventions will be excluded from participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cancer &quot;survivors&quot; if not in active or endocrine treatment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Maria G Juarez-Reyes, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Stanford University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lisa Golman-Rosas, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Stanford University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Maria G Juarez-Reyes, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>6504989000</phone>
    <email>mjuarezreyes@stanford.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Olivia Tigre, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>650-723-9907</phone>
    <email>otige@stanford.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palo Alto</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94305</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Olivia Tigre, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>650-726-9907</phone>
      <email>otigre@stanford.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zich JM, Attkisson CC, Greenfield TK. Screening for depression in primary care clinics: the CES-D and the BDI. Int J Psychiatry Med. 1990;20(3):259-77.</citation>
    <PMID>2265888</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JB, Löwe B. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Arch Intern Med. 2006 May 22;166(10):1092-7.</citation>
    <PMID>16717171</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF 3rd, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989 May;28(2):193-213.</citation>
    <PMID>2748771</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Akman T, Yavuzsen T, Sevgen Z, Ellidokuz H, Yilmaz AU. Evaluation of sleep disorders in cancer patients based on Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index. Eur J Cancer Care (Engl). 2015 Jul;24(4):553-9. doi: 10.1111/ecc.12296. Epub 2015 Mar 1.</citation>
    <PMID>25727241</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu HS, Harden JK. Symptom burden and quality of life in survivorship: a review of the literature. Cancer Nurs. 2015 Jan-Feb;38(1):E29-54. doi: 10.1097/NCC.0000000000000135. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24831042</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chen D, Yin Z, Fang B. Measurements and status of sleep quality in patients with cancers. Support Care Cancer. 2018 Feb;26(2):405-414. doi: 10.1007/s00520-017-3927-x. Epub 2017 Oct 23. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29058128</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carlson LE. Mindfulness-based interventions for coping with cancer. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2016 Jun;1373(1):5-12. doi: 10.1111/nyas.13029. Epub 2016 Mar 9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26963792</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vøllestad J, Nielsen MB, Nielsen GH. Mindfulness- and acceptance-based interventions for anxiety disorders: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Clin Psychol. 2012 Sep;51(3):239-60. doi: 10.1111/j.2044-8260.2011.02024.x. Epub 2011 Sep 9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22803933</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hoge EA, Bui E, Marques L, Metcalf CA, Morris LK, Robinaugh DJ, Worthington JJ, Pollack MH, Simon NM. Randomized controlled trial of mindfulness meditation for generalized anxiety disorder: effects on anxiety and stress reactivity. J Clin Psychiatry. 2013 Aug;74(8):786-92. doi: 10.4088/JCP.12m08083.</citation>
    <PMID>23541163</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schell LK, Monsef I, Wöckel A, Skoetz N. Mindfulness-based stress reduction for women diagnosed with breast cancer. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019 Mar 27;3:CD011518. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD011518.pub2.</citation>
    <PMID>30916356</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>behavioral intervention</keyword>
  <keyword>Spanish speaking</keyword>
  <keyword>Latina</keyword>
  <keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Mindfulness</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dyssomnias</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

