<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03625349</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>E3207-R</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>E1697-R</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03625349</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Passive Limb Movement: A Tool to Assess Vascular Health and Guide Rehabilitation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Passive Limb Movement: A Tool to Assess Vascular Health and Guide Rehabilitation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Brief Summary:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Current U.S. Veteran demographics reveal an aging population with significant cardiovascular&#xD;
      dysfunction. This ultimately manifests as mobility limitation, inactivity, and a subsequent&#xD;
      worsening of cardiovascular disease (CVD) that often leads to death. However, despite this&#xD;
      clear negative cycle of events, there is not a single clinically accepted, and therefore&#xD;
      routinely utilized, method of assessing vascular health. As nitric oxide (NO) is&#xD;
      anti-atherogenic and cardioprotective, identifying an in vivo bioassay of NO bioavailability&#xD;
      has significant worth in this arena. Fueled predominantly by the VA Merit Award prior to this&#xD;
      renewal application, single passive leg movement (sPLM) and the subsequent blood flow&#xD;
      increase, measured non-invasively by ultrasound Doppler in the common femoral artery, is&#xD;
      emerging as a method by which vascular endothelial function and therefore NO bioavailability&#xD;
      can be determined. However, although this work has yielded an initial characterization of&#xD;
      sPLM and established this method to be a novel, valid, and a clinically relevant approach to&#xD;
      determine vascular health, further understanding of the sPLM response with advancing age and,&#xD;
      ultimately, its implementation and assessment in both rehabilitation and clinical arenas is&#xD;
      still necessary. With the growing interest in personalized medicine, the development of&#xD;
      tools, such as sPLM, that allow individualized assessments to guide the physician, the&#xD;
      patient, and the rehabilitative team, are essential. Therefore, two specific aims are&#xD;
      proposed that will address the Central Hypothesis that the sPLM paradigm provides a&#xD;
      clinically meaningful assessment of endothelial function. First, cardiac rehabilitation will&#xD;
      be assessed by sPLM in the elderly, and, coupled with studies in the young, will elucidate&#xD;
      the predominant pathways responsible for the change in endothelial function with aging and&#xD;
      rehabilitation. Second, the CVD diagnostic value of the sPLM assessment of endothelial&#xD;
      function will be evaluated relative to classic measures and markers of subclinical disease in&#xD;
      order accelerate the inclusion of endothelial dysfunction as a CVD risk factor. The proposed&#xD;
      studies aim to catalyze the transition of the assessment of endothelial function by sPLM from&#xD;
      research to clinical practice.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Importance and impact: It is becoming increasingly apparent that arterial endothelial&#xD;
      dysfunction contributes significantly to the age-related downward spiral that includes&#xD;
      mobility limitation, frailty, and ultimately cardiovascular disease (CVD). Endothelial&#xD;
      dysfunction has been documented to manifest in the coronary epicardial and resistance&#xD;
      vasculature as well as the peripheral arteries, indicating that such dysfunction is a&#xD;
      systemic condition. Indeed, there is a growing appreciation that the vast majority of CVD is,&#xD;
      in fact, associated with endothelial dysfunction. Thus, developing a better understanding of&#xD;
      the relationship between arterial aging and CVD is one of the most important clinical&#xD;
      challenges that we currently face. The vascular endothelium, a single layer of cells lining&#xD;
      the blood vessel wall, plays an essential role in maintaining both arterial function and&#xD;
      health. In either an autocrine or paracrine fashion, vascular endothelial cells synthesize&#xD;
      and release numerous biologically active molecules that modulate arterial structure as well&#xD;
      as vasodilatory, thrombolytic, and vasoprotective functions. The important role that nitric&#xD;
      oxide (NO) plays in vasodilation. The transition from normal endothelial function to the&#xD;
      phenotype of endothelial dysfunction contributes to the development of atherosclerosis and&#xD;
      increased CVD risk. Specifically, these vascular changes, catalyzed by diminished NO&#xD;
      bioavailability, lead to vasoconstriction and an endothelial state that is pro-coagulative,&#xD;
      pro-proliferative, and pro-inflammatory. The recognition that the endothelium is not simply a&#xD;
      passive interface between blood and vessel wall, but is also the site of NO production, has&#xD;
      led to great advances in the field of vascular research. Indeed, endothelial-derived NO is&#xD;
      now not only recognized as one of the most important vasodilators, particularly in the&#xD;
      muscular arteries, but it also is apparent that NO inhibits other key events associated with&#xD;
      the development of atherosclerosis, such as leukocyte adhesion and migration, platelet&#xD;
      adhesion and aggregation, and smooth muscle cell proliferation. Thus, attenuated NO&#xD;
      bioavailability is evidence of a broadly dysfunctional endothelial phenotype, and, therefore,&#xD;
      the assessment of NO-mediated vasodilatory capacity provides significant insight into the&#xD;
      integrity and function of the endothelium. Although the process of CVD can begin early in&#xD;
      life and is accelerated by the aging process, endothelial dysfunction, a recognized precursor&#xD;
      to atherosclerosis, precedes the structural changes associated with this disease and so can&#xD;
      be used as a predictor of CVD onset.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Originality: Most, if not all, CVD risk factors are associated with endothelial dysfunction,&#xD;
      and risk factor modification can lead to improved endothelial function. With the growing&#xD;
      interest in personalized medicine, the development of diagnostic tools, that allow&#xD;
      individualized assessments of endothelial function to guide the physician, the patient, and&#xD;
      the rehabilitative team, are essential. However, although, over the past 20 years, several&#xD;
      methodologies have been developed to assess endothelial function in humans, and these&#xD;
      approaches have contributed extensively to clinical research, none have been adopted into&#xD;
      clinical practice. In fact, not a single method for assessing endothelial function has been&#xD;
      recommended by clinical guidelines for the diagnosis of CVD and the guidance of prevention&#xD;
      strategies for primary or secondary CVD. From work performed in the current Merit Review&#xD;
      Award, the novel single passive leg movement (sPLM)-induced increase in leg blood flow (LBF)&#xD;
      approach to assess endothelial function appears to be the clinically relevant tool that has&#xD;
      long been missing from the healthcare provider's arsenal. However, the additional studies&#xD;
      proposed in this renewal application are needed to confirm this conclusion, especially as it&#xD;
      relates to rehabilitation. Importantly, the sPLM paradigm can guide rehabilitation in several&#xD;
      ways. First, the high diagnostic value would provide earlier detection of CVD risk,&#xD;
      particularly as endothelial dysfunction precedes many of the other risk factors, and the sPLM&#xD;
      testing can be used to recommend and motivate patients to undergo rehabilitation. Second, the&#xD;
      sPLM assessment can be used to determine the efficacy of rehabilitation in order to guide&#xD;
      program development. If rehabilitation is not improving vascular function, the program can be&#xD;
      modified to address this CVD risk factor, with the impact on other outcomes in mind. Third,&#xD;
      the sPLM paradigm can be used more acutely throughout a rehabilitation program to provide&#xD;
      &quot;real-time&quot; feedback about endothelial function, allowing practitioners to personalize the&#xD;
      program for each patient, again with other outcomes in mind.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Contribution to Veterans Health Administration (VHA): VA demographics reveal a population&#xD;
      that is significantly skewed toward the older sector and, thus, heavily burdened by&#xD;
      age-associated CVD. Even in the population at large, it is estimated that by the year 2050&#xD;
      over 21% of people will be over 60 years of age. Although these data are impressive, the&#xD;
      Veteran population is far ahead of these predictions with 51% (12.3 million) of Veterans&#xD;
      already over 60 years of age. As advancing age is the major risk factor for CVD, the risk of&#xD;
      CVD increases progressively across the lifespan and although death rates as a result of CVD&#xD;
      have fallen over the last 50 years, CVD remains the leading cause of morbidity and mortality&#xD;
      in the U.S. Given the already accelerated aged demographics in the VA Health Care System and&#xD;
      the strong link between CVD and age, there is little doubt that the burden of CVD-related&#xD;
      healthcare costs within the VA will continue to grow. Thus, it is not surprising that aging&#xD;
      and mobility limitation, both of which are linked to endothelial dysfunction, are two&#xD;
      priority areas emphasized by the VA RR&amp;D Service and are Medical Research Priorities for the&#xD;
      VHA system as a whole.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post cuff-occlusion flow-mediated vasodilation (FMD) as a test of NO bioavailability: Prior&#xD;
      to our development of the novel sPLM approach to assess endothelial function, fueled&#xD;
      predominantly by the current Merit Review Award, perhaps the most likely method to be adopted&#xD;
      for routine clinical use was the post cuff-occlusion FMD test, typically performed in the&#xD;
      brachial artery. In 1992, Celermajer et al. introduced this method of measuring the changes&#xD;
      in conduit artery diameter following a period of circulatory occlusion as a non-invasive&#xD;
      approach for in vivo determination of endothelium-dependent vasodilation in humans. In the&#xD;
      more than two decades that have followed, the application of FMD testing in clinically-based&#xD;
      research has become widespread, a progression that is exemplified by the adoption of this&#xD;
      methodology into large-scale clinical trials, including recent phases of the Framingham Heart&#xD;
      Study. The FMD test is particularly appealing due, at least in part, to a previous report&#xD;
      revealing a weak correlation between vasodilatory capacity of the peripheral and coronary&#xD;
      arteries, implicating FMD as a potential surrogate measure of coronary endothelial health.&#xD;
      Further, it has been clearly demonstrated that FMD provides independent predictive&#xD;
      information for future cardiovascular events beyond traditional risk factors. FMD testing&#xD;
      has, thus, emerged as a non-invasive approach for determining vascular function in health and&#xD;
      disease. However, predominantly due to several methodological deficiencies and significant&#xD;
      challenges in terms of implementation, FMD has never been embraced as a clinical tool.&#xD;
      Perhaps one of the most attractive aspects of FMD testing is that it has been purported to&#xD;
      provide an assay of vascular endothelial NO bioavailability. As the presence of this&#xD;
      endothelially-derived vasodilator has become synonymous with vascular health, the prospect of&#xD;
      quantifying NO in a non-invasive manner makes FMD testing particularly appealing for both&#xD;
      risk assessment and patient prognosis. The ability of NO synthase (NOS) inhibition with LNMMA&#xD;
      (NG-monomethyl-L-arginine) to completely abolish radial and brachial artery FMD provided&#xD;
      initial evidence that FMD is governed primarily through the release of NO. However, in the&#xD;
      face of significant technical and methodological refinements in the field, recent studies&#xD;
      challenge the existing dogma regarding the NO dependent nature of the FMD response. Indeed,&#xD;
      the two most recent studies in the radial artery have identified only a minimal (0-33%)&#xD;
      reduction in FMD after the administration of LNMMA, a NOS blocker, leaving considerable&#xD;
      uncertainty as to whether this test can still be relied upon to provide an assay of NO&#xD;
      bioavailability. Indeed, our group, using up-to-date measurement techniques and the typical&#xD;
      site of assessment (brachial artery), demonstrated that the majority of vasodilation provoked&#xD;
      by brachial artery FMD testing is not attributable to NO. In fact, the intra-arterial&#xD;
      delivery of L-NMMA resulted in only a modest ( 33%) reduction in FMD. Critically, L-NMMA&#xD;
      administration also reduced the post-occlusion hyperemic response, thereby diminishing the&#xD;
      shear stimulus for brachial artery vasodilation. When this effect was taken into account, FMD&#xD;
      normalized for shear rate was not different between control and L-NMMA conditions.&#xD;
      Additionally, changes in FMD are highly dependent upon assessing very small changes in artery&#xD;
      diameter. Furthermore, FMD transiently increases with exercise training over the initial 4&#xD;
      weeks, but returns to pre-training values by the 8th week due to arterial remodeling. This&#xD;
      plasticity in diameter greatly limits the use of FMD as a diagnostic assessment in clinical&#xD;
      and rehabilitation arenas. Finally, although FMD has been demonstrated to correlate with CVD&#xD;
      risk, it provides only marginal diagnostic value for CVD. These findings add to the growing&#xD;
      uncertainty surrounding the interpretation of FMD test results, the usefulness of this&#xD;
      approach clinically, and emphasize the need to develop a new and clinically relevant tool to&#xD;
      assess endothelial function and NO bioavailability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      sPLM as a test of NO bioavailability: Originally, our group and others focused on the&#xD;
      peripheral and central hemodynamic responses to sPLM, and its previous variants, as a&#xD;
      reductionist model to better understand the factors controlling movement-induced hyperemia.&#xD;
      By removing the increase in metabolism associated with active exercise, important findings&#xD;
      related to the control of skeletal muscle blood flow were revealed. Specifically, in healthy&#xD;
      humans, following the initial onset of passive movement, there is a transient, yet robust,&#xD;
      increase in LBF. Through various experimental approaches we have characterized the roles of&#xD;
      afferent feedback, the muscle pump, perfusion pressure, cardiac innervation/denervation, and&#xD;
      age in the sPLM response. However, most germane to this Merit Review renewal application,&#xD;
      funded by the current Merit Review Award, we have determined the role NO plays in the&#xD;
      sPLM-induced blood flow response in both young and old subjects. At rest, NOS inhibition has&#xD;
      consistently been documented to decrease limb blood flow and vascular conductance by 30 to&#xD;
      40%, indicating an essential role of NO in controlling basal blood flow. During active&#xD;
      exercise, the reduction in blood flow following NOS inhibition is typically less than at&#xD;
      rest, falling in the range of 5 to 25%.This implies a reduced contribution of NO to&#xD;
      exercise-induced hyperemia, an experimental paradigm characterized by increased metabolism,&#xD;
      which also likely plays a significant role in elevating blood flow during exercise. In&#xD;
      contrast, the sPLM-induced hyperemia, which does not evoke a peripheral metabolic response,&#xD;
      is intuitively more likely to be predominantly NO-mediated. Indeed, in young healthy subjects&#xD;
      the inhibition of NOS, with an intra-arterial L-NMMA infusion in the passively moved leg,&#xD;
      revealed that NO contributes to 65-80% of the hyperemia and vasodilation associated with&#xD;
      sPLM. In contrast, there was minimal effect of L-NMMA in the old. The sPLM response is also&#xD;
      markedly attenuated in old, compared to young, subjects. Substantial evidence supports NO&#xD;
      bioavailability is low in old subjects and, as sPLM is highly NO-mediated, both the&#xD;
      diminished sPLM response and diminished effect of L-NMMA are consistent with such diminished&#xD;
      NO bioavailability. This supports the sPLM as a good assessment of endothelial function&#xD;
      because it tracks physiological differences across populations. This robust and easily&#xD;
      measured reduction in NO-mediated vasodilation and subsequent hyperemia suggests that sPLM&#xD;
      induced blood flow has significant promise as a new approach to assess NO-mediated&#xD;
      endothelial function, an important predictor of CVD risk, and could be an important tool to&#xD;
      assess rehabilitation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      sPLM and FMD directly compared: Being noninvasive and with evidence of mirroring coronary&#xD;
      endothelial function to some degree, FMD is by far the most common approach to assess&#xD;
      vascular function in clinical research and has been in existence for over 20 years. However,&#xD;
      FMD testing can be a somewhat capricious endeavor exhibiting significant operator dependency,&#xD;
      difficulty with performance, a reliance upon very small vessel diameter changes (typically&#xD;
      less than 0.4 mm), uncertainty about how to account for varying shear stimuli, and concerns&#xD;
      regarding reproducibility, all of which combine to explain why FMD has yet to be adopted&#xD;
      clinically. Moreover, and of real significance, the diagnostic value of FMD for CVD is only&#xD;
      marginal and inconsistent. In a relatively recent article, highly germane to this proposal,&#xD;
      published in the Contemporary Reviews in Cardiovascular Medicine section of the journal&#xD;
      Circulation, Flammer et al. discuss many of these issues in their article entitled &quot;The&#xD;
      assessment of endothelial function: from research to clinical practice&quot;. Interestingly, they&#xD;
      conclude that a clinical tool to assess endothelial function, suitable for daily practice has&#xD;
      yet to be established. Of note, sPLM was not mentioned in this review for, at this time, this&#xD;
      novel method was truly in its infancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      sPLM, aging and NO: It is well recognized that endothelial function and, therefore NO&#xD;
      bioavailability is attenuated with age and, therefore, if sPLM is, indeed, a good indicator&#xD;
      of endothelial function, it would be anticipated that the role of NO would be diminished in&#xD;
      the elderly population. Funded by the current VA Merit Review Award, we have confirmed this&#xD;
      supposition utilizing the sPLM assessment of endothelial function. Specifically, we have&#xD;
      documented that in young healthy subjects, the inhibition of NOS by L-NMMA reduced the&#xD;
      hyperemic response to sPLM, as assessed by leg blood flow area under the curve (AUC), by&#xD;
      65-80%. In contrast, in old subjects (&gt;70 yr.), compared to their young counterparts, there&#xD;
      was a greatly attenuated sPLM-induced hyperemia in the control condition (AUC 24 vs 147 ml)&#xD;
      and a nonsignificant effect of NOS blockade, both of which are consistent with a diminished&#xD;
      NO bioavailability. These findings confirm that endothelial function is diminished with age&#xD;
      and this can be explained by a reduction in NO bioavailability, both of which can be&#xD;
      documented by the use of sPLM.&#xD;
&#xD;
      sPLM as a valid screening test for age-related endothelial dysfunction: During the current VA&#xD;
      Merit Review Award, in healthy young and old subjects, we documented that the peripheral&#xD;
      hemodynamic response to sPLM provides a highly sensitive and specific assessment of the&#xD;
      recognized age-related fall in endothelial function. Compared to young subjects, the LBF&#xD;
      response to sPLM in the old was markedly attenuated. sPLM LBF AUC revealed a clear&#xD;
      delineation between young and old, with a cut-score of 60 ml. These data document the&#xD;
      capacity for the peripheral hemodynamic responses to sPLM to provide clear and potentially&#xD;
      diagnostic information to facilitate the classification of an individual as exhibiting, or&#xD;
      not, age-related endothelial dysfunction, which is currently missing as a CVD risk factor.&#xD;
      Additionally, these findings revealed that, in young and old populations, the relatively easy&#xD;
      to assess, LBF AUC, alone, is an appropriate surrogate for the more complex leg vascular&#xD;
      conductance which requires the simultaneous assessment of beat by beat blood pressure.&#xD;
      Therefore, the hyperemic response to sPLM exhibits the prerequisite qualities of a valid&#xD;
      screening test for peripheral endothelial dysfunction, as evidenced by an sPLM assessed&#xD;
      endothelial function, CVD risk, and physical activity: There is significant evidence that&#xD;
      endothelial dysfunction is associated with CVD risk. In fact, the more risk factors that are&#xD;
      present, the worse are both the epicardial56 and peripheral endothelial function. Endothelial&#xD;
      dysfunction may, therefore, represent the effect of these risk factors on vascular health.&#xD;
      However, it is again important to recognize that impaired endothelial function precedes&#xD;
      structural changes and may therefore be considered &quot;a barometer&quot; of the total cardiovascular&#xD;
      risk burden of an individual. Thus, even a new method with limited long-term data, which&#xD;
      professes to allow the assessment of endothelial function, must demonstrate some relation to&#xD;
      CVD risk and risk factor modifications, such as increased physical activity, that can alter&#xD;
      CVD risk. Although cross-sectional, there is evidence that endothelial function assessed by&#xD;
      the blood flow response to sPLM, is, indeed, attenuated with increasing CVD risk and altered&#xD;
      by physical activity. Specifically, although there is variability within each group of&#xD;
      subjects, which would be expected and makes individual assessment so important, it is clear&#xD;
      that the young and old active subjects exhibit superior endothelial function compared to&#xD;
      their age-matched sedentary counterparts, as assessed by sPLM. Additionally, these data&#xD;
      suggest that while greater physical activity can improve endothelial function in the old, the&#xD;
      elderly subjects do not achieve the same endothelial function of the young subjects,&#xD;
      indicating age-related dysfunction. Finally, of apparently healthy subjects, the old inactive&#xD;
      subjects have the most attenuated endothelial function due to being male, inactive, and &gt;70&#xD;
      yrs. of age. Of note, in terms of endothelial function, as assessed by sPLM, this group is&#xD;
      closest to the patients with heart failure, illustrating the ultimate consequence of numerous&#xD;
      CVD risk factors and greatly attenuated endothelial function. This clear link between the&#xD;
      sPLM-induced increase in blood flow and CVD risk supports the concept that the development&#xD;
      and ultimately the adoption of sPLM as a tool to non-invasively assess endothelial function&#xD;
      could have a significant impact on both the VA Health Care System and health care in general.&#xD;
      However, currently there are no longitudinal pre- and post-rehabilitation sPLM data to&#xD;
      document the efficacy of sPLM in this arena.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In summary, from work performed in the current Merit Review Award, the novel sPLM-induced&#xD;
      increase in LBF method to assess endothelial function appears to be both valid, reliable, and&#xD;
      clinically relevant. Furthermore, sPLM surpasses previous approaches in many respects,&#xD;
      including ease of performance and analysis, is predominantly NO-mediated, and can identify&#xD;
      the typical age-related decline in endothelial function with advancing age, apparent&#xD;
      inactivity, and disease. sPLM may be the clinically relevant tool that has long been missing&#xD;
      from the healthcare provider's arsenal. However, it is now necessary to longitudinally assess&#xD;
      sPLM in the rehabilitation arena and to formally assess the diagnostic value, of the sPLM&#xD;
      paradigm, for CVD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two Specific Aims are proposed, with preliminary data supporting the approach and&#xD;
      feasibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. HOW DOES THE PASSIVE SINGLE LEG MOVEMENT (sPLM) ASSESSMENT OF ENDOTHELIAL FUNCTION&#xD;
           RESPOND TO CARDIAC REHABILITATION WITH ADVANCING AGE?&#xD;
&#xD;
           Specific Aim 1A: Determine the impact of cardiac rehabilitation on sPLM assessed&#xD;
           endothelial function in both old subjects and patients diagnosed with CVD.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Approach: sPLM assessments of endothelial function performed in both a group of&#xD;
           relatively healthy old subjects and patients diagnosed with CVD before and after a 12&#xD;
           week cardiac rehabilitation program will document the effect of cardiac rehabilitation&#xD;
           on endothelial function.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Hypothesis: The sPLM assessment of endothelial function will improve following cardiac&#xD;
           rehabilitation in both relatively healthy old subjects and patients diagnosed with CVD.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Specific Aim 1B: Determine the predominant vasodilatory pathway responsible for the&#xD;
           change in sPLM assessed endothelial function as a consequence of cardiac rehabilitation&#xD;
           in old subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Approach: The measurement of femoral artery blood flow in response to sPLM in young (no&#xD;
           rehabilitation) and old subjects (pre- and post-rehabilitation), with and without&#xD;
           intra-arterially infused NO synthase (NOS) blockade (NG-monomethyl-L-arginine (L-NMMA))&#xD;
           and in combination with prostaglandin (PG) blockade (Ketorolac) and endothelium-derived&#xD;
           hyperpolarizing factor (EDHF) blockade (Fluconazole) will document the role of these&#xD;
           dilators in the sPLM response with aging and, subsequently, with cardiac rehabilitation&#xD;
           in the old.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Hypothesis 1: Pre-rehabilitation the old subject's sPLM response will be less dependent&#xD;
           on NO and more dependent on PG- and EDHF-induced vasodilation than the young.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Hypotheses 2: Rehabilitation in the old will increase the role of NO in the sPLM-induced&#xD;
           hyperemia, as evidenced by the restoration of the impact of L-NMMA and diminution of the&#xD;
           combined effect of PG and EDHF on the sPLM response to that of the young.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. DOES THE sPLM ASSESSMENT OF ENDOTHELIAL FUNCTION PROVIDE A NOVEL, CLINICALY MEANINGFUL&#xD;
           RISK MARKER FOR CVD?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim: Determine the diagnostic value of sPLM assessed endothelial function for CVD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approach: The sPLM assessment of endothelial function and classic measures (blood pressure,&#xD;
      body mass index, fasting blood lipids, and glucose) and markers of subclinical vascular&#xD;
      disease (Framingham Risk Score, coronary artery calcium score, ankle brachial index,&#xD;
      flow-mediated dilation, carotid intima-thickness, and C-reactive protein) in healthy subjects&#xD;
      and patients with CVD will determine the diagnostic value of sPLM for CVD, demonstrating the&#xD;
      clinical utility of this measurement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: The sPLM assessment of endothelial function will have a high diagnostic accuracy&#xD;
      for CVD prevalence that is superior to classic measures and markers of subclinical vascular&#xD;
      disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood Flow Response to passive leg movement.</measure>
    <time_frame>This outcome measure will be assessed at each study visit through study completion, about 3.5 years.</time_frame>
    <description>Doppler ultrasound will be used to assess movement induced hyperemia in the femoral artery.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">130</enrollment>
  <condition>Aging</condition>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PLM participants</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants who undergo passive leg movement, with and without LNMMA.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>NG-Monomethyl-L-Arginine</intervention_name>
    <description>Inhibitor of nitric oxide synthase.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PLM participants</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>LNMMA</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Subjects will range from young healthy volunteers to patients undergoing angiography.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Young healthy subjects: No evidence of cardiovascular disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing angiography: Clinical referral for an angiography.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Young healthy subjects: Evidence of cardiovascular disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing angiography: Poor kidney function.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Russell S. Richardson, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>VA Salt Lake City Health Care System, Salt Lake City, UT</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Van R Reese, BS MS</last_name>
    <phone>(801) 582-1565</phone>
    <phone_ext>4335</phone_ext>
    <email>van.reese@hsc.utah.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Russell S Richardson, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>(801) 582-1565</phone>
    <phone_ext>4344</phone_ext>
    <email>r.richardson@hsc.utah.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA Salt Lake City Health Care System, Salt Lake City, UT</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84148</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Van R Reese, BS MS</last_name>
      <phone>801-582-1565</phone>
      <phone_ext>4335</phone_ext>
      <email>van.reese@hsc.utah.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Russell S. Richardson, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 24, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 8, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 10, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>omega-N-Methylarginine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

