<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04666194</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1011004273/0801-16</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04666194</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Pilot Randomized Trial of Polypectomy Techniques for 4-6 mm Colonic Polyps</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pilot Randomized Trial of Polypectomy Techniques for 4-6 mm Colonic Polyps</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Indiana University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>American Society for Gastrointestinal Endoscopy</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Indiana University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Complete polypectomy is one of the major factors for effectiveness of colonoscopy to prevent&#xD;
      colon cancer. Given the prevalence of the 4-6 mm polyp, and the concern about interval&#xD;
      cancers at polypectomy sites, there is a clear and significant need to determine which&#xD;
      technique(s) are most appropriate for clinical practice. This study was to compare the three&#xD;
      commonly used polypectomy techniques in terms of efficacy and efficiency.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Colonoscopic polypectomy is one of the most commonly performed procedures in the United&#xD;
      States. Despite the frequency with which polypectomy is performed, there is a remarkable&#xD;
      absence of data regarding which polypectomy techniques most effectively remove polyps and&#xD;
      minimize complications. As a result, polypectomy practice is based on the observational&#xD;
      experience of experts and is how it is taught by attending physicians in fellowship training&#xD;
      programs. It is not surprising therefore, that polypectomy practice is not consistent across&#xD;
      the U.S., particularly for polyps in the 4-6 mm range, with 19% of endoscopists using cold&#xD;
      forceps, 21% using hot forceps, 31% using a hot snare, 15% using a cold snare, and the&#xD;
      remainder using a combination of these techniques.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The effectiveness of colonoscopy in the prevention of colorectal cancer (CRC) depends on&#xD;
      polypectomy; most polyps removed during colonoscopy are &lt; 1 cm in size. Because of their&#xD;
      greater prevalence relative to larger polyps, polyps &lt; 1 cm are responsible for most cases of&#xD;
      post-polypectomy bleeding (even though the absolute risk is higher with larger polyps).&#xD;
      Perhaps more concerning, several studies of surveillance colonoscopy have reported finding&#xD;
      CRC within a few years of a complete colonoscopy. Nearly 30% of these cancers have occurred&#xD;
      in colonic segments where prior polypectomy was performed, suggesting that incomplete removal&#xD;
      may be responsible for the recurrence of neoplasia; in more than half of these cases, the&#xD;
      initial polyp removed was 1 cm or less in size. Unfortunately, these studies are limited&#xD;
      because the precise location of the polypectomy site relative to the subsequent cancer is&#xD;
      uncertain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given the prevalence of the 4-6 mm polyp, the variation in polypectomy technique among&#xD;
      endoscopists, and the concern about interval cancers at polypectomy sites, there is a clear&#xD;
      and significant need to determine which technique(s) are most appropriate for clinical&#xD;
      practice in terms of having the lowest risk for recurrent neoplasia and for major adverse&#xD;
      effects (major bleeding, perforation).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of this trial is to determine the superior method for polypectomy [cold biopsy&#xD;
      forceps (CF), cold snare (CS), or hot snare (HS)] in the removal of adenomatous colonic&#xD;
      polyps that are 4-6 mm in maximal diameter for the subsequent risk of recurrent neoplasia at&#xD;
      the polypectomy site. A randomized trial comparing these three polypectomy techniques for the&#xD;
      outcome of recurrent neoplasia at the polypectomy site requires at least 700 persons per&#xD;
      group (at least 2100 persons total). (A trial powered to compare complication rates would&#xD;
      require a sample size that is an order of magnitude greater than this and is beyond the&#xD;
      feasibility and scope of both pilot and definitive trials.) Further, patients would need to&#xD;
      undergo 3- or 5-year surveillance colonoscopy, which requires a research infrastructure to&#xD;
      ensure complete and accurate data collection. Before embarking on this large-scale trial to&#xD;
      examine effectiveness of polypectomy techniques, we must first demonstrate feasibility of&#xD;
      conducting such a trial and determine the time frame, sampling frame, and resources required.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The specific aim of this proposal is to conduct a pilot randomized trial to establish:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. the feasibility of conducting a definitive, single-institution, multi-site clinical&#xD;
           trial comparing the three modalities for removing adenomatous colonic polyps 4-6 mm. The&#xD;
           processes that will be assessed are patient enrollment, recruitment, exclusion, and&#xD;
           determination of final eligibility for the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. the numbers of patients at each site (IU Hospital, Wishard Memorial Hospital/Eskenazi&#xD;
           Health Hospital) who would be candidates for the larger, definitive study (This&#xD;
           information will help estimate the time line and resources required for the definitive&#xD;
           study).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. the proportions of recruited patients that fall into the 3- and 5-year surveillance&#xD;
           groups (or other surveillance interval, along with the reason(s) for the interval).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypotheses:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. A single-institution, three-site clinical trial is feasible: patients can be recruited&#xD;
           and enrolled as potential subjects; final eligibility based on endoscopic and&#xD;
           histological findings can be established within a week of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Investigators can identify the number of patients at each site who would be eligible for&#xD;
           participation in a larger, more definitive study, from all patients undergoing&#xD;
           colonoscopy. Investigators can establish refusal and exclusion rates. (Knowing both&#xD;
           rates is necessary for planning the larger study.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. The proportion of recruited patients in the 5-year surveillance group is approximately&#xD;
           80% of all persons with neoplasia; the remaining 20% comprise the 3-year surveillance&#xD;
           group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MATERIALS AND METHODS:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators conducted an randomized controlled trial (RCT) comparing polypectomy using&#xD;
      CF, CS and HS. This trial was approved by the Institutional Review Board at Indiana&#xD;
      University on March 6, 2008. It was conducted at three endoscopy units staffed by Indiana&#xD;
      University Medical Center Gastroenterology faculty: Indiana University Hospital, Springmill&#xD;
      endoscopy center and Eskenazi Health Hospital. Patients were recruited between September 2009&#xD;
      and May 2013 and were followed with surveillance colonoscopy until October 2019. Sample size&#xD;
      for the study was estimated based on the primary outcome of recurrent neoplasia at the&#xD;
      polypectomy site at surveillance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outpatients between ages 18- and 70 years undergoing outpatient screening, surveillance, or&#xD;
      diagnostic colonoscopy and able to provide informed consent were eligible. Eligible patients&#xD;
      presenting for colonoscopy, at 1 of 3 endoscopy units, from July 2009 to May 2013 were&#xD;
      invited to participate in the study by research coordinators (RC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Colonoscopy was performed in standard fashion with Olympus 180 series colonoscopes. If the&#xD;
      subject was found to have ≥1 adenomatous colon polyps (as predicted by endoscopist) 4-6 mm in&#xD;
      size with Paris morphology of types I or Paris morphology IIa in the colon, randomization to&#xD;
      one of three polypectomy methods was done in a 1:1:1 ratio.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following parameters for each study polyp (SP) were recorded: a) location, b) size, c)&#xD;
      morphology (flat, sessile, or pedunculated), d) method of removal and e) pathology. For CF&#xD;
      polypectomy, standard-sized radial jaw 4 biopsy forceps with a 2.8 mm needle were used and&#xD;
      the number of bites for complete polypectomy was recorded. Polypectomy time was measured from&#xD;
      time of appearance of forceps through the endoscope channel to polyp retrieval. For CS and HS&#xD;
      polypectomy, 11 mm snares were used and the number of times the snare was used to complete&#xD;
      the polypectomy was recorded. The size of the polyps was assessed using the span of the open&#xD;
      radial jaw 4 forceps (7 mm) and the diameter of the snare catheter (2.5 mm) or the open snare&#xD;
      diameter (11 mm). For any single patient, up to 5 SPs were removed under research protocol.&#xD;
      HS polypectomy was performed using monopolar forced coagulation current, wattage range 18-20.&#xD;
      There was no limit to the non-study polyps (NSP) resected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The time to perform CS polypectomy was recorded from the time of appearance of snare through&#xD;
      endoscope channel to polyp retrieval or the determination that the polyp was not retrievable.&#xD;
      For HS, time was recorded from initiation of cautery set up to polyp retrieval or the&#xD;
      determination that the polyp was not retrievable. For any single patient all SPs were removed&#xD;
      using the same technique. Patients with non-neoplastic polyps were excluded post hoc from the&#xD;
      analytical sample. Patients were also excluded post randomization if the assigned polypectomy&#xD;
      method could not be used or if additional methods were required.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following polyp resection and retrieval, 2-5 ml of tattoo ink (SPOTⓇ Ex stain) was injected&#xD;
      1-2 cm to the left and proximal to the polypectomy site. The surveillance interval was&#xD;
      determined according to guidelines as follows: a) For 1-2 tubular adenomas (TA), 5-10 years;&#xD;
      b) For 3 or more TAs, 3 years; c) For a TA &gt;= 1 cm, a polyp with villous histology, or one&#xD;
      with high-grade dysplasia, 3 years; d) For a large sessile polyp removed piecemeal, 3-6&#xD;
      months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During surveillance colonoscopy, the previous polypectomy site was examined. Adequacy of&#xD;
      polypectomy was determined by absence of recurrent adenoma tissue. Biopsy of the previous&#xD;
      polypectomy site was not required unless neoplasia recurrence was suspected based on visual&#xD;
      inspection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data were collected using standardized data collection forms, and the information was&#xD;
      transferred to an Excel spreadsheet (Version 16) for analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 1, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 1, 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>There were 3 arms: cold forceps, cold snare, hot snare. Randomization was computer generated. Subjects were assigned to one of the 3 arms. Up to 5 study polyps were removed under research protocol from each subject using the same technique</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participant did not know which polypectomy technique was used. Endoscopists could not be blinded</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incomplete resection rate</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of recurrent neoplasia at polypectomy site</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient participation</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Rates of patient refusal, participation, ineligibility and requirement for a 3-years vs. 5-year surveillance colonoscopy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sample size calculation</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Sample size required for a definitive, adequately powered trial.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of polypectomy</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Time taken for each intervention</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">353</enrollment>
  <condition>Colon Polyps</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cold forceps</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>4-6mm polyps were removed with cold forceps</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cold snare</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>4-6mm polyps were removed with cold snare</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hot snare</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>4-6mm polyps were removed with hot snare</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cold forceps</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Cold forceps</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cold snare</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Cold snare</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hot snare</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Hot snare</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons undergoing screening, surveillance, or diagnostic colonoscopy who are found to&#xD;
             have 1 or more adenomatous colon polyps 4-6 mm in size with Paris morphology of types&#xD;
             I or IIa in well-defined segments of the colon.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Requirement for long-term anticoagulation or clopidogrel (Plavix)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known International normalized ratio (INR) ≥ 1.5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than satisfactory colon preparation quality&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to intubate the cecum or reach the surgical anastomosis in case of cecectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age greater than 75&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inpatient status (acute lower GI bleeding, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Comorbidity that precludes the need for surveillance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Already included in the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre- solid organ transplantation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas Imperiale, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Indiana University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hala Fatima, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>IUHP</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Douglas Rex</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Indiana University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Springmill endoscopy center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Carmel</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46290</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Indiana University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wishard Memorial Hospital/Eskenazi Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tolliver KA, Rex DK. Colonoscopic polypectomy. Gastroenterol Clin North Am. 2008 Mar;37(1):229-51, ix. doi: 10.1016/j.gtc.2007.12.009. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18313548</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gómez V, Badillo RJ, Crook JE, Krishna M, Diehl NN, Wallace MB. Diminutive colorectal polyp resection comparing hot and cold snare and cold biopsy forceps polypectomy. Results of a pilot randomized, single-center study (with videos). Endosc Int Open. 2015 Feb;3(1):E76-80. doi: 10.1055/s-0034-1390789. Epub 2014 Nov 19. Erratum in: Endosc Int Open. 2015 Feb;3(1):C1.</citation>
    <PMID>26134778</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Desai S, Gupta S, Copur-Dahi N, Krinsky ML. A prospective randomized study comparing jumbo biopsy forceps to cold snare for the resection of diminutive colorectal polyps. Surg Endosc. 2020 Mar;34(3):1206-1213. doi: 10.1007/s00464-019-06874-z. Epub 2019 Jun 10.</citation>
    <PMID>31183796</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lee CK, Shim JJ, Jang JY. Cold snare polypectomy vs. Cold forceps polypectomy using double-biopsy technique for removal of diminutive colorectal polyps: a prospective randomized study. Am J Gastroenterol. 2013 Oct;108(10):1593-600. doi: 10.1038/ajg.2013.302. Epub 2013 Sep 17.</citation>
    <PMID>24042189</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 7, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Indiana University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Hala Fatima</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>polypectomy</keyword>
  <keyword>cold snare</keyword>
  <keyword>hot snare</keyword>
  <keyword>cold forceps</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Polyps</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Colonic Polyps</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol, Statistical Analysis Plan, and Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>November 23, 2019</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/94/NCT04666194/Prot_SAP_ICF_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

