<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04666584</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Odense University Hospital</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>S-20200114</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04666584</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Optimal Predilatation Treatment Before Implantation of a Magmaris Bioresorbable Scaffold in Coronary Artery Stenosis</brief_title>
  <acronym>OPTIMIS</acronym>
  <official_title>Optimal Predilatation Treatment Before Implantation of a Magmaris Bioresorbable Scaffold In Coronary Artery Stenosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Odense University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Odense University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the study is to investigate if lesion preparation with a ScoreFlex balloon&#xD;
      compared to a standard non-compliant balloon improve vascular healing and minimize lumen&#xD;
      reduction after implantation of a Magmaris bioresorbable scaffold.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction: Ischemic heart disease (IHD) is characterized by progressive atherosclerosis in&#xD;
      coronary arteries and may cause coronary artery stenosis or acute thrombus and occlusion. IHD&#xD;
      is often treated with percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) with balloon dilatation and&#xD;
      implantation of a stent. The drug-eluting stents (DES) have been developed to minimize&#xD;
      neointimal growth after implantation and reduce the risk of in-stent restenosis compared to&#xD;
      bare-metal stents (BMS). Newer devices, bioresorbable scaffold (BRS), are made from a&#xD;
      bioresorbable material slowly dissolving after implantation. The BRS guarantees optimal&#xD;
      vessel support after balloon dilatation and implantation, but the artery can obtain original&#xD;
      function and flexibility after the BRS has vanished. The development of the Magmaris BRS,&#xD;
      with its improved radial strength, thinner struts compared to previous BRSs, is developed to&#xD;
      reduce the complications seen in earlier generation BRS such as recoil, fracture and late&#xD;
      stent thrombosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous studies have shown that coronary lesions treated with the previous generation of the&#xD;
      Magmaris BRS resulted on lumen area reduction, possibly a consequence by increased plaque&#xD;
      burden, compromising the scaffold area, combined with increased neointimal formation in the&#xD;
      early phase of vascular healing and fast resolution.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to decreased radial strength of the BRS compared to metal stents, modification of plaque&#xD;
      prior to BRS-implantation is necessary. The ScoreFlex balloon is a non-compliant balloon with&#xD;
      circumference of fixated, scoring elements and permits controlled expansion and fragmentation&#xD;
      of calcified plaque, compared to standard treatments with a non-compliant balloon.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intravascular imaging with Intravascular Ultrasound (IVUS) and Optical Coherence Tomography&#xD;
      (OCT) can assess the morphology and location of plaques in the coronary stenosis prior to PCI&#xD;
      thereby optimizing the implantation. The scaffold-treated segment can also be evaluated with&#xD;
      intravascular imaging components such as stent coverage, malapposition and neointimal&#xD;
      hyperplasia, but only if the scaffold is visible. If the scaffold is dissolved, another&#xD;
      method to assess the vascular healing is needed. IVUS can evaluate change in elastic external&#xD;
      membrane (EEM), change in remodeling and minimal lumen area (MLA). The reduction in MLA is&#xD;
      associated with increased neointimal hyperplasia and plaque burden in the vessel wall.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the study is to investigate if lesion preparation with a ScoreFlex balloon&#xD;
      compared to a standard non-compliant balloon improve vascular healing and minimize lumen&#xD;
      reduction after implantation of a Magmaris bioresorbable scaffold.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method: The study is designed as a prospective randomized trial conduced at a single center&#xD;
      (Odense University Hospital, Denmark). Eighty-two patients with stable angina pectoris and&#xD;
      non-ST-segment elevation myocardial infarctions are included, if they meet the criteria.&#xD;
      Pre-dilatation with a 2.0 mm balloon is performed followed by pre-interventional IVUS and&#xD;
      OCT. Patients are randomized to lesion preparation and pre-dilatation with either the&#xD;
      ScoreFlex balloon or a standard non-compliant balloon with a 1:1 balloon-to-artery ratio by&#xD;
      measuring the reference segments. The residual stenosis should be less than 20 %. If the&#xD;
      pre-dilatation goal is not achieved, up-scaling to a balloon 0,5 mm larger is allowed. The&#xD;
      lesion is treated with implantation of a Magmaris scaffold. Finally, IVUS and OCT-images of&#xD;
      the final result are obtained. Follow-up IVUS and OCT images are performed after 6 and 12&#xD;
      months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post-PCI OCT-images are analyzed at baseline and 6 and 12 months after index procedure.&#xD;
      Change in MLA in the stented segment is measured with IVUS and OCT. The vascular healing is&#xD;
      based on finding from the OCT images.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is submitted and approved by the Regional Committees on Health Research Ethics for&#xD;
      Southern Denmark (Project-ID: S-20200114) and Danish Data Agency (Journal nr.: 20/49900)&#xD;
      Statistics: Assuming data are normally distributed, categorical data will be presented as&#xD;
      numbers and frequencies and compared using chi2-test. Continuous data will be presented as&#xD;
      mean ± SD and compared using Student t-test- SPSS version 26.0 will be used for the&#xD;
      statistical analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The estimated sample size is based on data, from the HONEST study by Fallesen et al. The&#xD;
      reduction of MLA from 6.99 mm2 to 5.01 mm (27%) 6 months after implantation of a Magmaris&#xD;
      BRS, represented the expected reference group. Optimal lesion preparation with pre-dilatation&#xD;
      with a ScoreFlex balloon is estimated to minimize MLA reduction from 6.99 mm2 to 6.22 mm2&#xD;
      (11%). A power calculation is conducted using the expected MLA after 6 months (6.22 mm2 for&#xD;
      the ScoreFlex balloon and 5.01 mm2 for the standard non-compliant balloon). Inclusion of 35&#xD;
      patients in each group is necessary to reach statistical significance in case of 2-tailed&#xD;
      significance level of 0.05 and power of 80 %. Loss to follow-up and poor image quality&#xD;
      finalize an expected drop-out rate of 15 %, thereby requiring 82 patients in total.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Eligible patients randomized to predilatation with ScoreFlex balloon or a standard non-compliant balloon before percutaneous coronary intervention with implantation of a Magmaris bioresorbable scaffold.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Offline data analysis will be performed without knowing the allocated intervention group.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Minimal Lumen Area</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after index percutaneous coronary intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Minimal Lumen Area</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in remodeling Index</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months and 12 months after index percutaneous coronary intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Change in remodeling Index</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Minimal Lumen Area</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months and 12 months after index percutaneous coronary intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Minimal Lumen Area</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of incomplete scaffold apposition</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months and 12 months after index percutaneous coronary intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of incomplete scaffold apposition</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of uncovered struts</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months and 12 months after index percutaneous coronary intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of uncovered struts</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">82</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronary Artery Disease</condition>
  <condition>Stable Angina</condition>
  <condition>Coronary Artery Stenosis</condition>
  <condition>Myocardial Infarction</condition>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Myocardial Ischemia</condition>
  <condition>Atherosclerosis of Artery</condition>
  <condition>Coronary Disease</condition>
  <condition>Heart Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Arterial Occlusive Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ScoreFlex balloon</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pre-dilatation with a ScoreFlex balloon before implantation with a Magmaris bioresorbable scaffold</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard non-compliant balloon</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pre-dilatation with a non-compliant balloon before implantation with a Magmaris bioresorbable scaffold</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ScoreFlex balloon</intervention_name>
    <description>Pre-dilatation with a ScoreFlex balloon</description>
    <arm_group_label>ScoreFlex balloon</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Device: standard non-compliant balloon</intervention_name>
    <description>Pre-dilatation with a standard non-compliant balloon</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard non-compliant balloon</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with stable angina pectoris and non-ST elevation myocardial infarction&#xD;
             referred for invasive coronary angiography and percutaneous coronary intervention at&#xD;
             Department of Cardiology, Odense University Hospital (Odense, Denmark)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  participation in other randomized clinical trials&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  life expectancy &lt; 1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  allergy to aspirin, clopidogrel, ticagrelor or prasugrel&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  eGFR &lt; 30 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  tortuous and angiographically estimated extremely calcified lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ostial, left main and bifurcation lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  lesions in a reference vessel diameter &lt; 2.0 mm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hemodynamic instability&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  scheduled for coronary artery bypass grafting&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lisette O. Jensen, MD PhD Prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Odense University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kirstine N. Hansen, MD</last_name>
    <phone>004565412620</phone>
    <email>kirstine.norregaard.hansen@rsyd.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Odense University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Odense</city>
        <zip>5000</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kirstine N. Hansen, MD</last_name>
      <phone>004565412620</phone>
      <email>kirstine.norregaard.hansen@rsyd.dk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kirstine N. Hansen, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lisette O. Jensen, MD PhD Prof</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 8, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 8, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Odense University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kirstine Nørregaard Hansen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>bioresorbable scaffolds</keyword>
  <keyword>optical coherence tomography</keyword>
  <keyword>intravascular ultrasound</keyword>
  <keyword>modified balloons</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Angina, Stable</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Arterial Occlusive Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronary Stenosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Constriction, Pathologic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

