<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04664283</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>second hospital of Jilin U</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04664283</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Drug-coated Balloon Versus Drug-eluting Stent for de Novo Lesions in Large Coronary Arteries Guided by Optical Coherence Tomography</brief_title>
  <official_title>Drug-coated Balloon Versus Drug-eluting Stent for de Novo Lesions in Large Coronary Arteries Guided by Optical Coherence Tomography：a Prospective Multi-center Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Liu Bin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Second Hospital of Jilin University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      OCT allows precise evaluation of intimal injury after lesion preparation and may improve the&#xD;
      acute results and long-term outcomes after paclitaxel drug-coated balloon angioplasty. This&#xD;
      prospective multicenter randomized controlled study aims to evaluate the long-term efficacy&#xD;
      and safety of paclitaxel coated balloon in the treatment of native large coronary arteries by&#xD;
      OCT guided is not inferior to drug-eluting stent.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>late lumen loss （LLL）</measure>
    <time_frame>Follow-up coronary angiography at 12 months after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>late lumen loss between DCB treated group and DES treated group evaluated by quantitative coronary analysis in patients with CHD</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The incidence rate of device-related ischemic events</measure>
    <time_frame>Clinical follow up at 30 days, 3，6, 9 and 12 months after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>The incidence rate of device-related ischemic events including cardiovascular death, target vessel related myocardial infarction and ischemia-driven revascularization between DCB treated group and DES treated group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The incidence rate of patient-related ischemic events</measure>
    <time_frame>Clinical follow up at 30 days, 3，6, 9 and 12 months after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>TThe incidence rate of patient-related ischemic events including all myocardial infarction , any revascularization and all-cause death between DCB treated group and DES treated group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">254</enrollment>
  <condition>Angioplasty</condition>
  <condition>Coronary Artery Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>DCB group by OCT guided</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>DES group by OCT guided</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>DCB for de Novo Lesions in Large Coronary Arteries Guided by Optical Coherence Tomography</intervention_name>
    <description>DCB for de Novo Lesions in Large Coronary Arteries Guided by both angiogram and Optical Coherence Tomography</description>
    <arm_group_label>DCB group by OCT guided</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>DES group by OCT guided</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>DES for de Novo Lesions in Large Coronary Arteries Guided by Optical Coherence Tomography</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        18 to 75 years old Patients have ischemic symptoms or evidence of myocardial ischemia&#xD;
        (inducible or spontaneous) in the presence of a stenosis of at least 50% in a native&#xD;
        coronary artery, including stable angina, unstable angina, silent ischemia or myocardial&#xD;
        infarction（≥1month） .&#xD;
&#xD;
        Reference vessel diameter ≥3.0 mm, and &lt;4.5mm. Lesion length of ≤20 mm Written informed&#xD;
        consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Myocardial infarction within 4 weeks, including ST-elevation myocardial infarction and&#xD;
        non-ST-elevation myocardial infarction Cardiogenic shock (systolic arterial pressure&#xD;
        &lt;90mmHg), congestive heart failure (NYHA=4，EF≤35%) Severe valvular heart disease Life&#xD;
        expectancy no more than 1 year or factors causing difficulties in clinical follow up&#xD;
        Intolerance to aspirin and/or clopidogrel, ticagrelor Known intolerance or allergy to&#xD;
        heparin, contrast agents, paclitaxel, iopromide, rapamycin, polylactic acid-glycolic acid&#xD;
        copolymer, Co-Cr alloy or platinum-chromium alloy Leukopenia or thrombopenia A history of&#xD;
        peptic ulcer or GI bleeding in the previously Stroke within 6 months prior to the operation&#xD;
        A history of severe hepatic or renal failure Stents covering a major side branch (≥2.5 mm&#xD;
        need to intervention) Left main lesion Graft lesion Aortic-coronary ostial lesion In-stent&#xD;
        restenotic lesion Chronic total occlusion Severe calcified lesions. Visible angiographic&#xD;
        thrombus&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>the Second hospital of Jilin University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chang chun</city>
        <state>Ji Lin</state>
        <zip>130041</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>jinpeng wang, doctor</last_name>
      <phone>15526891295</phone>
      <email>jinpeng0865@sina.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Second Hospital of Jilin University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Changchun</city>
        <state>Jilin</state>
        <zip>130041</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Liu Y, Zhang YJ, Deng LX, Yin ZY, Hu T, Wang Q, Li Y, Li JY, Guo WY, Mou FJ, Tao L. 12-Month clinical results of drug-coated balloons for de novo coronary lesion in vessels exceeding 3.0 mm. Int J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2019 Apr;35(4):579-586. doi: 10.1007/s10554-018-1505-z. Epub 2019 Mar 30.</citation>
    <PMID>30929102</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Cuculi F, Young M, Beeler R, Schoenenberger AW, Erne P. Good efficacy of drug-eluting balloons in a mixed population of patients with coronary artery disease. J Invasive Cardiol. 2012 Apr;24(4):151-3.</citation>
    <PMID>22477748</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Lu W, Zhu Y, Han Z, Sun G, Qin X, Wang Z, Liu G, Xi W, Wang X, Pan L, Qiu C. Short-term outcomes from drug-coated balloon for coronary de novo lesions in large vessels. J Cardiol. 2019 Feb;73(2):151-155. doi: 10.1016/j.jjcc.2018.07.008. Epub 2018 Oct 23.</citation>
    <PMID>30366637</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Yu X, Ji F, Xu F, Zhang W, Wang X, Lu D, Yang C, Wang F. Treatment of large de novo coronary lesions with paclitaxel-coated balloon only: results from a Chinese institute. Clin Res Cardiol. 2019 Mar;108(3):234-243. doi: 10.1007/s00392-018-1346-8. Epub 2018 Aug 3.</citation>
    <PMID>30074078</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Lansky A, Wijns W, Xu B, Kelbæk H, van Royen N, Zheng M, Morel MA, Knaapen P, Slagboom T, Johnson TW, Vlachojannis G, Arkenbout KE, Holmvang L, Janssens L, Ochala A, Brugaletta S, Naber CK, Anderson R, Rittger H, Berti S, Barbato E, Toth GG, Maillard L, Valina C, Buszman P, Thiele H, Schächinger V, Baumbach A; TARGET All Comers Investigators. Targeted therapy with a localised abluminal groove, low-dose sirolimus-eluting, biodegradable polymer coronary stent (TARGET All Comers): a multicentre, open-label, randomised non-inferiority trial. Lancet. 2018 Sep 29;392(10153):1117-1126. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31649-0. Epub 2018 Sep 3.</citation>
    <PMID>30190206</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Cortese B, Silva Orrego P, Agostoni P, Buccheri D, Piraino D, Andolina G, Seregni RG. Effect of Drug-Coated Balloons in Native Coronary Artery Disease Left With a Dissection. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2015 Dec 28;8(15):2003-2009. doi: 10.1016/j.jcin.2015.08.029. Epub 2015 Nov 25.</citation>
    <PMID>26627997</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Nishiyama N, Komatsu T, Kuroyanagi T, Fujikake A, Komatsu S, Nakamura H, Yamada K, Nakahara S, Kobayashi S, Taguchi I. Clinical value of drug-coated balloon angioplasty for de novo lesions in patients with coronary artery disease. Int J Cardiol. 2016 Nov 1;222:113-118. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2016.07.156. Epub 2016 Jul 27.</citation>
    <PMID>27494722</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 5, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 5, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 5, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Second Hospital of Jilin University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Liu Bin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of cardiology department.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>coronary heart disease</keyword>
  <keyword>large coronary vessel</keyword>
  <keyword>optical coherence tomography</keyword>
  <keyword>Drug-coated Balloon</keyword>
  <keyword>Drug-eluting Stent</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

