<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04664413</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ABOUT</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04664413</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Percentage of BRAFV600E Alleles and Outcome in Thyroid Carcinoma</brief_title>
  <acronym>ABOUT</acronym>
  <official_title>Correlations Between Percentage of BRAFV600E Alleles and Outcome in Thyroid Carcinoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Salerno</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Salerno</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      BRAFV600E is the most frequent oncogene in Papillary thyroid carcinoma (PTC). It correlates&#xD;
      with greater extension, lymph node metastasis, and advanced stage. However, the prognostic&#xD;
      value of BRAFV600Eis weak and the search of this mutation is not recommended in clinical&#xD;
      management of thyroid cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PTC are characterized by intratumor heterogeneity with wild-type and BRAFV600E tumoral cells.&#xD;
      In a previous study, the BRAFV600E/BRAFwild-type ratio correlated with patient age, tumor&#xD;
      volume, lymph node metastasis and with worst disease outcome. While the existence of&#xD;
      intratumor heterogeneity in PTC is supported by many evidences, its extension, biological&#xD;
      signiﬁcance and clinical utility is questioned and must be further investigated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary endpoint of the study is to determine the relationship between the percentage of&#xD;
      BRAFV600E alleles and outcome in PTC patients. Secondary endpoints are to determine the mean&#xD;
      and median BRAFV600E/BRAFwild-type allele ratio in heterogeneous tumors; determine the&#xD;
      relationship between the percentage of BRAFV600E alleles and clinicopathological features.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study protocol entails the assessment by digital-droplet PCR the BRAFV600E/BRAFwild-type&#xD;
      allele ratio in a series of PTC and its correlation with clinicopathology features and&#xD;
      outcome.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BACKGROUND Papillary thyroid carcinoma (PTC) generally shows an excellent prognosis with a&#xD;
      5-year survival of over 95%. Even when PTC metastasizes to the regional lymph nodes, a&#xD;
      frequent occurrence, it generally has an excellent prognosis. However, there are some&#xD;
      patients who present with an aggressive background or with specific clinicopathological&#xD;
      features who exhibit aggressive developmental behavior. Several clinicopathological features,&#xD;
      namely pathology subtype, age, distant and lymph node metastasis, extrathyroid extension, and&#xD;
      completeness of resection can be used to predict prognosis and have been adopted in staging&#xD;
      systems such as the AMES, MACIS, and AJCC TNM classifications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The genetic background is a powerful prognostic determinant only when applied to some gene&#xD;
      mutations such as TERT promoter and p53 mutations. The prognostic value of BRAFV600E, the&#xD;
      most frequent oncogene in PTC, is weak. It correlates with greater extension, lymph node&#xD;
      metastasis, and advanced stage (III/IV). Its correlation with outcome in PTC has been the&#xD;
      object of many not always concordant studies. A large multicenter study was necessary to&#xD;
      unequivocally demonstrate the association between BRAFV600E and cancer recurrence and&#xD;
      mortality. The risk of PTC harboring BRAFV600E remains weak (recurrence hazard ratio 2.66)&#xD;
      and the search of this mutation is not recommended in clinical management of low-risk&#xD;
      patients with thyroid cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Different research groups provided evidence on the heterogeneity of PTC that consist of a&#xD;
      mixture of tumor cells with wild-type and BRAFV600E (5, 6). The importance of the percentage&#xD;
      of BRAFV600E positive cells within the tumor was demonstrated in 168 PTC. The analysis of&#xD;
      BRAFV600E/BRAFwild-type ratio was performed by pyrosequencing and higher ratio positively&#xD;
      correlated with patient age, tumor volume, lymph node metastasis and with worst disease&#xD;
      outcome. Patients with tumors with BRAFV600E/BRAFwild-type ratio ≥ 30% displayed an odds risk&#xD;
      of tumor recurrence of 5.1, whereas it was only 1.75 in BRAFV600E positive tumors if the&#xD;
      allele ratio was not considered. The qualitative analysis BRAFV600E positive versus negative&#xD;
      PTC can explain the discordant correlations with clinicopathological features and outcome in&#xD;
      different cohorts of patients with different ratio of BRAFV600E alleles, and ultimately the&#xD;
      qualitative analysis BRAF mutational status can reduce the strength of its clinical&#xD;
      significance and utility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While the existence of intratumor heterogeneity in PTC is supported by many evidences, its&#xD;
      extension, biological signiﬁcance and clinical utility is questioned and must be further&#xD;
      investigated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Digital-droplet PCR (ddPCR) is an analytical method recently developed, suitable for absolute&#xD;
      quantification of target DNA in a DNA mixture. It is the most accurate method to determine&#xD;
      the BRAFV600E/BRAFwild-type allele ratio.&#xD;
&#xD;
      AIM OF THE RESEARCH&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Determine how frequent are subclonal-BRAFV600E PTC and to determine the mean and median&#xD;
           BRAFV600E/BRAFwild-type allele ratio in heterogeneous tumors;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Determine the relationship between the percentage of BRAFV600E alleles and&#xD;
           clinicopathological features;&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Determine the relationship between the percentage of BRAFV600E alleles and outcome in&#xD;
           PTC patients (primary endpoint)&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY DESIGN&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A large series of PTC formalin-fixed, paraffin-embedded (FFPE) tissues with a clinical&#xD;
           follow up &gt; 3 years will be analyzed by ddPCR to determine the percentage of BRAFV600E&#xD;
           alleles.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The purity of PTC samples and the ratio neoplastic cell/contaminating cells will be&#xD;
           assessed by the a) analysis by rt-PCR of expression of a panel of RNA specific for&#xD;
           lymphoreticular cells and stromal cells; b) microscopic review of adjoining tissue&#xD;
           sections.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Statistical analysis will be performed to search correlations between percentage of&#xD;
           BRAFV600E alleles and a) pathology features, TNM, staging; b) recurrence and survival&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intratumor BRAFV600E heterogeneity and outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>3. Determine the relationship between the percentage of BRAFV600E alleles and outcome in PTC patients</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intratumor BRAFV600E heterogeneity quantification</measure>
    <time_frame>5 months</time_frame>
    <description>1. Determine how frequent are subclonal-BRAFV600E PTC and to determine the mean and median BRAFV600E/BRAFwild-type allele ratio in heterogeneous tumors</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intratumor BRAFV600E heterogeneity and clinicopathological features</measure>
    <time_frame>5 months</time_frame>
    <description>2. Determine the relationship between the percentage of BRAFV600E alleles and clinicopathological features</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Papillary Thyroid Cancer</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      3 adjacent slides of formalin-fixed, paraffin-embedded (FFPE) tissues. One devoted to&#xD;
      microscopy analysis; two for DNA and RNA extraction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Any patient 18 years age or more with a diagnosis of papillary thyroid carcinoma, subjected&#xD;
        to thyroidectomy no less than 3 years before&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergone surgery because of any PTC subtypes 3 years before or more&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Availability of PTC tissue samples, well annotated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Availability of clinical data of the patients including gender, age at diagnosis, type&#xD;
             and extension of surgery, radiation therapy, radio-iodide therapy, TSH suppressive&#xD;
             therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Follow up of 3 years or more after surgery, including periodical 6 months assessment&#xD;
             of TSH, thyroglobulin and AbTG, neck ultrasound evaluation and episodic hrTSH&#xD;
             stimulation test&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inadequate tissue samples or clinical data and follow up&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Purity of PTC samples &lt; 50%&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Medicine and Surgery, Univeristy of Salerno</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baronissi</city>
        <state>Salerno</state>
        <zip>84081</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ito Y, Miyauchi A, Kihara M, Fukushima M, Higashiyama T, Miya A. Overall Survival of Papillary Thyroid Carcinoma Patients: A Single-Institution Long-Term Follow-Up of 5897 Patients. World J Surg. 2018 Mar;42(3):615-622. doi: 10.1007/s00268-018-4479-z.</citation>
    <PMID>29349484</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Xing M, Westra WH, Tufano RP, Cohen Y, Rosenbaum E, Rhoden KJ, Carson KA, Vasko V, Larin A, Tallini G, Tolaney S, Holt EH, Hui P, Umbricht CB, Basaria S, Ewertz M, Tufaro AP, Califano JA, Ringel MD, Zeiger MA, Sidransky D, Ladenson PW. BRAF mutation predicts a poorer clinical prognosis for papillary thyroid cancer. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2005 Dec;90(12):6373-9. Epub 2005 Sep 20.</citation>
    <PMID>16174717</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Xing M, Alzahrani AS, Carson KA, Shong YK, Kim TY, Viola D, Elisei R, Bendlová B, Yip L, Mian C, Vianello F, Tuttle RM, Robenshtok E, Fagin JA, Puxeddu E, Fugazzola L, Czarniecka A, Jarzab B, O'Neill CJ, Sywak MS, Lam AK, Riesco-Eizaguirre G, Santisteban P, Nakayama H, Clifton-Bligh R, Tallini G, Holt EH, Sýkorová V. Association between BRAF V600E mutation and recurrence of papillary thyroid cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2015 Jan 1;33(1):42-50. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2014.56.8253. Epub 2014 Oct 20.</citation>
    <PMID>25332244</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Xing M, Alzahrani AS, Carson KA, Viola D, Elisei R, Bendlova B, Yip L, Mian C, Vianello F, Tuttle RM, Robenshtok E, Fagin JA, Puxeddu E, Fugazzola L, Czarniecka A, Jarzab B, O'Neill CJ, Sywak MS, Lam AK, Riesco-Eizaguirre G, Santisteban P, Nakayama H, Tufano RP, Pai SI, Zeiger MA, Westra WH, Clark DP, Clifton-Bligh R, Sidransky D, Ladenson PW, Sykorova V. Association between BRAF V600E mutation and mortality in patients with papillary thyroid cancer. JAMA. 2013 Apr 10;309(14):1493-501. doi: 10.1001/jama.2013.3190.</citation>
    <PMID>23571588</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guerra A, Sapio MR, Marotta V, Campanile E, Rossi S, Forno I, Fugazzola L, Budillon A, Moccia T, Fenzi G, Vitale M. The primary occurrence of BRAF(V600E) is a rare clonal event in papillary thyroid carcinoma. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2012 Feb;97(2):517-24. doi: 10.1210/jc.2011-0618. Epub 2011 Dec 14.</citation>
    <PMID>22170714</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gandolfi G, Sancisi V, Torricelli F, Ragazzi M, Frasoldati A, Piana S, Ciarrocchi A. Allele percentage of the BRAF V600E mutation in papillary thyroid carcinomas and corresponding lymph node metastases: no evidence for a role in tumor progression. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013 May;98(5):E934-42. doi: 10.1210/jc.2012-3930. Epub 2013 Mar 26.</citation>
    <PMID>23533235</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guerra A, Fugazzola L, Marotta V, Cirillo M, Rossi S, Cirello V, Forno I, Moccia T, Budillon A, Vitale M. A high percentage of BRAFV600E alleles in papillary thyroid carcinoma predicts a poorer outcome. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2012 Jul;97(7):2333-40. doi: 10.1210/jc.2011-3106. Epub 2012 Apr 16.</citation>
    <PMID>22508706</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 5, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 10, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 10, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Salerno</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mario Vitale</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Thyroid Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thyroid Cancer, Papillary</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thyroid Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All results, will be shared before any submission to scientific journal</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

