<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04666818</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FlashMomStudy</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04666818</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy of FGM in Pregestational Diabetes</brief_title>
  <acronym>FlashMom</acronym>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Flash Glucose Monitoring in Pregnant Women With Poorly Controlled Pregestational Diabetes (FlashMom): A Randomized Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Catania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Catania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Diabetes is the most common metabolic disease complicating pregnancy, and the number of women&#xD;
      in childbearing age facing this problem is rising worldwide. The clinical and social&#xD;
      significance of pre-gestational diabetes has become an important issue in the area of public&#xD;
      health because this disease can cause maternal complications and influence the development of&#xD;
      the offspring during the pregnancy and later in life. Pregnancy in women with pregestational&#xD;
      diabetes is indeed associated with adverse perinatal outcomes including large-for&#xD;
      gestational- age infants (ranging from 48.8 to 62.5%), preterm delivery, and other perinatal&#xD;
      complications. Large-for-gestational-age infants to mothers with diabetes are at increased&#xD;
      risk for birth trauma, transient tachypnea, and neonatal hypoglycemia. For all these reasons,&#xD;
      the medical costs and social burdens caused by this disease are problematic. The mainstay of&#xD;
      managing diabetes during pregnancy is glucose monitoring. Conventionally, glucose monitoring&#xD;
      is by self-monitoring of blood glucose (SMBG) involving multiple pricks to the patients. The&#xD;
      limitations of these pricks include pain and a point-in-time assessment without evaluation of&#xD;
      the complete glycemic profile before making therapeutic adjustments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Introduction of continuous glucose monitoring (CGM) by measuring interstitial fluid glucose&#xD;
      has overcome the deficits in SMBG by providing an overview of the glycemic profiles in&#xD;
      patients. In most recent years another promising tool became available: the Flash Glucose&#xD;
      Monitoring (FGM) system. Unlike traditional sensor systems, its wired enzyme sensor is&#xD;
      calibrated in the factory and therefore requires no user calibrations (fingerstick blood&#xD;
      glucose measurements) during the 14 days of wear. Recent studies demonstrated that FGM is&#xD;
      effective in reducing glucose fluctuations and preventing hypoglycemic events in Type 1 and&#xD;
      Type 2 diabetic patients. No evidence is to date available on the efficacy of FGM on the&#xD;
      reduction of the perinatal adverse outcomes during pregnancy in women with pre-gestational&#xD;
      diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators propose to randomize a group of women with poorly controlled pregestational&#xD;
      diabetes to receive SMBG (standard antenatal care) or FGM plus SMBG during pregnancy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Specific Aims Aim 1: To compare the glycemic control and glucose variability during pregnancy&#xD;
      and at first postpartum visit in the two randomized groups. This was accomplished by the&#xD;
      evaluation of the mean glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c) levels and of several glucose variability&#xD;
      indices during gestation and 1 month after delivery. Hypothesis: the real-time information&#xD;
      provided by the FGM system improves glucose control and glycemic excursions during pregnancy&#xD;
      and after delivery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2: To compare the maternal and neonatal adverse outcomes in the two randomized groups at&#xD;
      the time of delivery. This was accomplished by the evaluation of the rate of all the most&#xD;
      important maternal and fetal-neonatal adverse outcomes (e.g. cesarean section, macrosomia,&#xD;
      neonatal hypoglycemia) at the end of gestation. Hypothesis: the use of FGM reduces the rates&#xD;
      of those adverse pregnancy outcomes related to maternal hyperglycemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Significance and Background Pre-gestational diabetes is still associated with adverse&#xD;
      perinatal outcomes largely attributed to maternal hyperglycemia. The risk of adverse outcomes&#xD;
      increases with HbA1c higher than 6-6.5% during gestation. Conversely, mean HbA1c levels &lt;6%&#xD;
      during the second and third trimester are associated with better outcomes and with the lowest&#xD;
      risk of large-forgestational-age infants. Unfortunately, this goal is often difficult to&#xD;
      achieve during pregnancy considering that approximately 60% of all pre-gestational diabetic&#xD;
      women are poorly controlled at the time of conception and that maternal hypoglycemia should&#xD;
      be avoided. Fasting and post-prandial SMBG are recommended in pre-gestational diabetic women&#xD;
      to achieve glycemic control during gestation. Additional useful information on direction,&#xD;
      frequency and duration of glycemic oscillations could be provided by the CGM. This system, in&#xD;
      fact, allows the patients to prevent hypoglycemia and to reduce glucose oscillations&#xD;
      measuring interstitial glucose levels continuously. Despite initial controversial results on&#xD;
      the efficacy of the CGM technology during pregnancy, a recently published trial demonstrated&#xD;
      that Real-Time use of CGM is associated with improved neonatal outcomes (which are likely to&#xD;
      be attributed to reduced exposure to maternal hyperglycemia).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Unfortunately the existing CGM devices still need to be frequently calibrated, using a&#xD;
      minimum of 2-5 daily monitored capillary blood glucose. The recent introduction of FGM using&#xD;
      the factory-calibrated meter has emerged as a novel method to study glycemic patterns. FGM&#xD;
      does not require finger prick calibration. The data are extrapolated using the inbuilt&#xD;
      software to summarize the glycemic variability over 2 weeks. The glucose profile obtained&#xD;
      using this system is called Ambulatory Glucose Profile (AGP). The usefulness of AGP has been&#xD;
      studied in adults and pediatric patients affected by diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nevertheless, to date there are no studies looking into the efficacy of this tool in women&#xD;
      affected by pre-gestational (Type 1 and Type 2) diabetes during pregnancy. The investigators&#xD;
      aim to evaluate the effectiveness of antenatal FGM on maternal glycemic control and pregnancy&#xD;
      related morbidity in the offspring of mothers with poorly controlled Type 1 and Type 2&#xD;
      diabetes at the time of conception (peri-conception HbA1c ≥6.5%).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 26, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 26, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 26, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Glycosylated Hemoglobin (HbA1c) concentration in blood samples</measure>
    <time_frame>38 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the efficacy of FGM on HbA1c reduction during pregnancy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>coefficient of variation (CV): Adimensional coefficient calculated as the Standard Deviation divided by the mean of all glucose values expressed</measure>
    <time_frame>33 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the efficacy of FGM on glucose CV reduction during pregnancy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean amplitude of glycemic excursions (MAGE)= Adimensional coefficient calculated mean amplitude of glycemic excursions</measure>
    <time_frame>33 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>o compare the efficacy of FGM on MAGE reduction during pregnancy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Continuous overlapping net glycemic action (CONGA)= Adimensional coefficient calculated at 1 hour time interval</measure>
    <time_frame>33 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the efficacy of FGM on CONGA reduction during pregnancy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>MODD= Adimensional coefficient calculated as mean of the daily serum glucose difference.</measure>
    <time_frame>33 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the efficacy of FGM on MODD reduction during pregnancy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Macrosomia: Birth weight above 4000 grams regardless gestational age</measure>
    <time_frame>At birth</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of macrosomic newborn</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Large for Gestational Age (LGA)= weight at birth above the 90th percentile for gestational age</measure>
    <time_frame>At birth</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of LGA newborn</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neonatal Hypoglycemia= plasma glucose level of less than 36 mg/dl</measure>
    <time_frame>At birth</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of neonatal hypoglycemia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Premature delivery: &lt;37 weeks of gestation</measure>
    <time_frame>At birth</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of premature delivery</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cesarean section</measure>
    <time_frame>At delivery</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of Cesarean section</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus in Pregnancy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Self Monitoring Blood Glucose (SMBG)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Women used self-monitoring of blood glucose= Control group (CG)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Flash Glucose Monitoring (FGM)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Women used flash glucose monitoring= FGM group (FG)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Use of Flash Glucose Monitoring</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants in the intervention group were advised to monitor glucose levels by means of flash glucose system.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Flash Glucose Monitoring (FGM)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The investigators carried out a multicenter randomized pilot trial by prospectively&#xD;
        recruiting poorly controlled (peri-conception HbA1c &gt;6.5%) pregestational T1D or T2D&#xD;
        outpatients in 5 Italian Diabetes Medical Centers. Enrolling Centers were selected on the&#xD;
        basis of the experience in following women with pregestational diabetes and on the presence&#xD;
        of the neonatal intensive care unit.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Randomization was electronically generated at the first pregnancy visit according to a&#xD;
        predefined randomization sequence. Women were assigned to either the control group (CG,&#xD;
        using the standard SMBG at least 6 times daily) or Flash group (FG, using the FGM system&#xD;
        continuously throughout gestation) in a 1:1 ratio.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women with pregestational diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HbA1c &gt;6.5%&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gestational Diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HbA1c &lt;6.5%&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Laura Laura, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Catania</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Catania, Endocrinology Section, Garibaldi-Nesima Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Catania</city>
        <zip>95122</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 26, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 7, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 7, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 7, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Catania</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Laura Sciacca</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Flash glucose monitoring</keyword>
  <keyword>Pregestational diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Glucose control</keyword>
  <keyword>HbA1c</keyword>
  <keyword>Glycemic variability</keyword>
  <keyword>Adverse pregnancy outcomes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pregnancy in Diabetics</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

