<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04669522</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PHDW-006</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04669522</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Psychological Factors and Oncological Outcomes of Triple-negative Breast Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>PSY-ONC TNBC</acronym>
  <official_title>How do Psychological Factors Interact With the Oncological Outcomes of Women With Triple-negative Breast Cancer?</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pius-Hospital Oldenburg</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Oldenburg</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pius-Hospital Oldenburg</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It has been established that chronic stress can take a toll on one's health. Furthermore,&#xD;
      when an someone falls ill, it is believed that the way that they handle stress and/or&#xD;
      adversity can positively or negatively impact the course of their disease. Against the&#xD;
      background of these findings, this study aims to explore how (1) cumulative lifetime stress&#xD;
      exposure, (2) coping response, (3) perceived social support, and (4) and overall&#xD;
      psychological well-being may relate to the oncological outcomes of women diagnosed with&#xD;
      triple negative breast cancer (TNBC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients treated for TNBC between 01.01.2015-31.12.2019 at the University Clinic for&#xD;
      Gynecology at Pius-Hospital Oldenburg will be asked to complete four questionnaires&#xD;
      corresponding to the abovementioned psychological aspects. The results of these&#xD;
      questionnaires will be analyzed together with the clinical patient data and tumor&#xD;
      characteristics (such as type, size, etc.) to explore whether there is a tendency between one&#xD;
      or more of the above-mentioned psychosocial aspects and the course of the disease (e.g. a&#xD;
      disease recurrence within one year after the initial diagnosis (yes / no), the duration of&#xD;
      the disease-free or progression-free period).&#xD;
&#xD;
      As there is an existing body of evidence supporting a relationship between stress and the&#xD;
      immune system, we expect to see the poorest oncological outcomes in patients who 1) have&#xD;
      faced more stressful/adverse life events, 2) those who present inadequate/inappropriate&#xD;
      coping skills, 3) report less social support, and 4) poorer overall psychological well-being.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a potential connection between psychosocial factors and the course of the TNBC is&#xD;
      identified, further disease specific, it will aid in the development of disease-specific,&#xD;
      health-promoting measures to better support this particular patient group. This is of great&#xD;
      importance, as TNBC is generally associated with clinically aggressive behavior and a worse&#xD;
      prognosis compared to other breast cancer subtypes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Triple negative breast cancer (TNBC) is a highly heterogeneous subtype, which exhibits&#xD;
      aggressive clinical behavior and generally carries a poor prognosis. As it lacks hormone&#xD;
      receptors expression (estrogen and progesterone receptors) and amplification of the Human&#xD;
      epidermal growth factor receptor 2 (HER2), targeted therapies are lacking. Thus, the&#xD;
      identification of any modifiable factors which may influence the course of the disease is&#xD;
      critical both in improving the quality of care and the patient's quality of life. In addition&#xD;
      to lifestyle factors, such as diet and exercise habits, psychological factors, such as&#xD;
      cumulative lifetime stress, coping response, perceived social support, and overall&#xD;
      psychological well-being may also influence cancer progression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While it is known that stress can directly upregulate certain immune mechanisms, it is&#xD;
      suspected that a patient's coping response, perceived social support, and general&#xD;
      psychological well-being may have an indirect influence on cancer progression via altered&#xD;
      health-related behaviors. For example, during stressful periods, alcohol consumption may&#xD;
      rise, sleep quality may be diminished, nutritional needs may not be properly met, and&#xD;
      exercise may be avoided. As a group, TNBC patients face additional challenges not experienced&#xD;
      by other BC patients. Due to the disease's poor prognosis, its relatively new status as a BC&#xD;
      subtype (first mention in 2005), and the lack of targeted treatments; patients may experience&#xD;
      an increased stress-response following their diagnosis. For instance, it is known that an&#xD;
      event induces a stress response when it involves novelty and unpredictability, a lack of&#xD;
      sense of control, and threats to the sense of self; elements that are clearly emphasized in&#xD;
      TNBC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To promote the development of psycho oncological strategies tailored towards women in this&#xD;
      particular patient group, this study aims to explore any trends which might be indicative of&#xD;
      an interaction between psychological aspects and the oncological outcomes of patients treated&#xD;
      for TNBC between 01.01.2015-31.12.2019, at Pius Hospital, in Oldenburg, Germany. Because we&#xD;
      intend to evaluate a retrospective cohort of patients, the psychological instruments were&#xD;
      chosen and slightly adapted to target past events (stress across life span and social&#xD;
      support) and stable traits (psychological well-being, coping).&#xD;
&#xD;
      As there is an existing body of evidence supporting the relationship between stress and the&#xD;
      immune system, we expect to see the poorest oncological outcomes in patients who 1) have had&#xD;
      more adverse life events, and 2) those who present inadequate/inappropriate coping skills.&#xD;
      Additionally, we intend to explore if other psychological variables mentioned in the&#xD;
      literature, including perceived social support and psychological well-being, are also related&#xD;
      to the oncological outcomes in our cohort of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study combines prospective and retrospective approaches since the psychosociological&#xD;
      data is to be collected prospectively from a single retrospective cohort of patients.&#xD;
      Patients could not be randomized into groups, due to the retrospective nature of the study.&#xD;
      Considering that all data derived from this study will be numerical, this will be a&#xD;
      quantitative analysis. This research is comparative since the patients' clinical outcomes&#xD;
      will be analyzed in terms of psychological measures. Lastly, the present study is exploratory&#xD;
      as it aims to shed light on the interplay between psychological and clinical aspects in TNBC,&#xD;
      as psycho-oncological studies are lacking for this BC subtype.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A list of patient names will be obtained from the hospital's Tumor Documentation Office.&#xD;
      Next, patient electronic medical records will be accessed through Pius-Hospital's Orbis&#xD;
      Database program according to the name and date of birth of each patient. Demographic and&#xD;
      clinical variables of interest will be collected from the clinical charts and recorded on the&#xD;
      patient case report form (CRF).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The psychological aspects of interest will be assessed through self-reported questionnaires.&#xD;
      (1 computer-based and 3 paper-based questionnaires). Patients will fill out the surveys in a&#xD;
      proper setting where privacy will be assured. Questionnaires will not include information&#xD;
      which could be directly used to identify participants (i.e. name, DOB), but will instead&#xD;
      contain a code which will allow the psychological data to be combined with the respective&#xD;
      participant's demographic and clinical variables for the subsequent statistical analysis.&#xD;
      After completion, participant's information (pseudonymized) will be transferred to the CRF,&#xD;
      and subsequently case data will be transferred to SPSS (software version 26.0) for further&#xD;
      statistical analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Day</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Severity Score (OSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Cumulative lifetime stress will be quantified as a score (Overall Severity Score; OSS) derived from the Stress and Adversity Inventory (STRAIN) questionnaire (Slavich and Shields, 2018).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hazard ratio associated with OSS</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Triple Negative Breast Neoplasms</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The retrospective cohort will be composed of a minimum of 50 patients diagnosed with TNBC&#xD;
        and treated in the University Hospital for Gynecology, Pius-Hospital Oldenburg, between&#xD;
        01.01.2015-31.12.2019.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a confirmed diagnosis of TNBC, with the ability to speak and understand German, who&#xD;
             can give informed consent, and who were treated in the University Hospital for&#xD;
             Gynecology, Pius-Hospital Oldenburg, between 01.01.2015-31.12.2019&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1) any woman with an unconfirmed TNBC diagnosis, 2) woman whose medical records are&#xD;
             lacking clinical and/or pathological variables of interest, 3) patients with current&#xD;
             or previous mood disorder, psychosis, anxiety disorder, psychosis, anxiety disorder,&#xD;
             or substance abuse disorder according to the DSM V, Diagnostic and Statistical Manual&#xD;
             of Mental Disorders, and 5) all women who currently make use of psychotropic agents or&#xD;
             psychiatric drugs.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 9, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 9, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Pius-Hospital Oldenburg</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Prof. Dr. Dr. med. Rudy Leon De Wilde</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinic Director</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Psychooncology</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Triple Negative Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

