<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04662827</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1403/2019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04662827</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Palmitylethanolamide on Central and Peripheral Sensitization After Heat-induced Hyperalgesia</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Palmitylethanolamide on Central and Peripheral Sensitization After Heat-induced Hyperalgesia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical University of Graz</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of Graz</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This planned study is based on a randomized, placebo-controlled cross-over design.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Palmityhlethanolamide (PEA) is an endogenous fatty acid amide from the group of&#xD;
      N-Acetylethanolamides, which analgesic, anti-inflammatory and neuroprotective effects can be&#xD;
      attributed to this. In clinical studies, PEA has mainly been used as an adjuvant in pain&#xD;
      therapy. The previous data show clinical efficacy without conclusions that can be drawn about&#xD;
      the underlying mechanisms - these have not yet been investigated in a human experiment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The planned study, which demonstrates the mode of action of PEA using an established pain&#xD;
      model on healthy volunteers, will help to assign the efficacy to peripheral or central&#xD;
      nervous systems. These mechanisms allow to establish mechanism-oriented therapy approaches.&#xD;
      These findings are essential for a better understanding of the clinical efficacy and to&#xD;
      evaluate the correct fields of application.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Palmityhlethanolamide (PEA) is an endogenous fatty acid amide from the group of&#xD;
      N-Acetylethanolamides, which analgesic, anti-inflammatory and neuroprotective effects can be&#xD;
      attributed to this. It is referred to as &quot;dietary Food for special medical purposes&quot;.&#xD;
      Different mechanisms of action have been described, including an effect on mast cells,&#xD;
      ATP-sensitive K channels and TRP channels. In an animal study in mice it could be shown that&#xD;
      the antinociceptive properties of PEA can be blocked by a CB2-cannabinoid antagonist.&#xD;
      Overall, PEA seems to play a relevant role in the body's own regulation of neurogenic&#xD;
      inflammation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In clinical studies, PEA has mainly been used as an adjuvant in pain therapy. In a recent&#xD;
      metaanalysis of studies in which PEA was used to treatment of neuropathic or chronic pain, a&#xD;
      significant effect can be shown. Remarkably none of the 1188 patients who took PEA for up to&#xD;
      60 days had reported side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      &quot;Repetitive phasic heat application&quot; is a validated method to generate a short-term&#xD;
      peripheral and central sensitization. As a non-invasive human pain model, it is therefore&#xD;
      well suited to examine analgesic and antihyperalgesic effects of pharmaceuticals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data of the above meta-analysis show clinical efficacy without conclusions that can be&#xD;
      drawn about the underlying mechanisms - these have not yet been investigated in a human&#xD;
      experiment. Our planned study, which demonstrates the mode of action of PEA using an&#xD;
      established pain model on healthy volunteers, will help to assign the efficacy to peripheral&#xD;
      or central nervous systems. These mechanisms allow to establish mechanism-oriented therapy&#xD;
      approaches. These findings are essential for a better understanding of the clinical efficacy&#xD;
      and to evaluate the correct fields of applikation. If there is peripheral efficacy, this&#xD;
      would qualify PEA for use in acute pain. However, if the effect is explained by central&#xD;
      mechanisms, PEA can be useful in the area of chronic pain, and also in neuropathic pain.&#xD;
      Accordingly, the results of this experimental human study are groundbreaking for the planning&#xD;
      of future application studies or clinical use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Questions:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study four questions were to be answered:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Can spontaneous pain after repetitive phasic heat application be reduced by the intake&#xD;
           of PEA?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Can central sensitization be influenced by the intake of PEA?&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Can peripheral sensitization be influenced by the intake of PEA?&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Can the endogenous pain inhibition be influenced by the intake of PEA?&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following methods are used to answer these questions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Spontaneous pain is measured using Visual Analog Scale (VAS).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To assign an effect to central sensitization, the sensitivity to mechanical stimuli,&#xD;
           i.e. Pinprick hyperalgesia or allodynia is the established marker.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Efficacy on peripheral sensitization can be assessed by measuring the heat- thresholds.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. The endogenous pain inhibition is tested by the examination of the &quot;conditioned pain&#xD;
           modulation&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypotheses&#xD;
&#xD;
      Null hypothesis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Taking PEA 3x400mg for 28 days changes, compared to placebo spontaneous pain after repetitive&#xD;
      phasic heat application.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Alternative hypothesis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Taking PEA 3x400mg for 28 days changes, compared to placebo spontaneous pain after repetitive&#xD;
      phasic heat application.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary hypotheses:&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is a significant difference in the size of mechanical allodynia distance after&#xD;
      repetitive phasic heat application compared to placebo intake.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PEA induces a change in Pinprick hyperalgesia compared to placebo after repetitive phasic&#xD;
      heat application.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PEA induces a change in thermal perception and pain threshold compared to placebo after&#xD;
      repetitive phasic heat application.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PEA induces a change in &quot;conditioned pain modulation&quot; compared to placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is based on a randomized, placebo-controlled cross-over design. The patients take&#xD;
      either the test substance or placebo for 28 days according to a randomization generated via&#xD;
      &quot;randomizer.at&quot;. Both the patients and the study staff responsible for collecting the&#xD;
      measurement parameters are blinded by the order in which the tablets are taken, as the&#xD;
      individual tablets are stored in doses that are only marked with a code, that does not allow&#xD;
      to identify whether they are verum or placebo preparations. A staff member not participating&#xD;
      in the study will dissolve the code at the end of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After recruitment, information and inclusion of the subjects in the study, the first baseline&#xD;
      measurement is performed. This is followed by randomization into 2 groups. After 28 days,&#xD;
      during which either the verum or study substance is taken, the influence on the &quot;conditioned&#xD;
      pain modulation&quot; is measured. The repetitive phasic heat application according to the&#xD;
      published procedures follows. A 3x3cm area on the volar forearm is heated repeatedly using a&#xD;
      TSA-II NeuroSensoryAnalyser. The thermode starts at 32.0°C and heats up to 48.0°C at 10°C/sec&#xD;
      and cools down to 32.0°C after 6 seconds. This is repeated 6 times in total. This is followed&#xD;
      by a 30 second pause and then 6 more heatings. A total of 10 blocks with 6 heatings each are&#xD;
      performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the last block, spontaneous pain is determined using the Visual Analogue Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since primary and secondary hyperalgesia is most pronounced at 1 hour after repetitive phasic&#xD;
      heat application, 60 minutes after the last heating, the measurement of allodynia distance&#xD;
      and pinprick hyperalgesia is performed in immediate temporal sequence and the heat pain and&#xD;
      perception threshold is determined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After an 8-week wash-out phase, a new baseline measurement is taken before the other&#xD;
      substance is taken for 28 days. This is followed by a new examination of the conditioned pain&#xD;
      modulation, a repetitive phasic heat application and the recording of the measurement&#xD;
      parameters according to the sequence described above.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistics:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In cooperation with the Institute for Medical Informatics, Statistics and Documentation of&#xD;
      the Medical University of Graz, the T-test for paired samples was defined for biometric&#xD;
      planning, the planned evaluation is based on a linear mixed model.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study substance The volunteers will each receive 90 tablets containing either&#xD;
      palmitoylethanolamide 400mg (OptiPEA.) or an optically identical placebo manufactured by our&#xD;
      institutional pharmacy. The study substance is supplied by the company Innexus&#xD;
      Nutraceuticals. It is taken at 8-hour intervals. The last dose is taken in the morning before&#xD;
      the study visit. To increase the adherence to the therapy, an electronic reminder is given&#xD;
      via cell phone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Parameter&#xD;
&#xD;
      Spontaneous pain:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Directly after the last heat application, the spontaneous pain is recorded using the VAS&#xD;
      scale, which is used throughout the LKH Univ.-Klinikum Graz.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Allodynia:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Starting from the center of the thermal application, a von Frey filament (128 mN) is applied&#xD;
      to the skin in 4 radial lines at a 5 mm interval, first from the inside to the outside, then&#xD;
      from the outside to the inside, and the distance at which an unpleasant pointed sensation&#xD;
      first occurs is determined. The 8 measurements are averaged.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pinprick hyperalgesia:&#xD;
&#xD;
      By means of a pinprick with 256 mN a pointed stimulus is applied. The test site is 5 cm&#xD;
      proximal to the center of the thermal stimulation area. A numerical scale (0-100) is used to&#xD;
      measure how painful this stimulus is.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Heat pain and perception threshold:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The heat detection threshold and the heat pain threshold are determined according to the&#xD;
      guidelines of the German Research Association for Neuropathic Pain, which involves heating&#xD;
      the skin with TSA-II NeuroSensoryAnalyser. The test person can stop the heatig by pressing a&#xD;
      stop button. This should be done at the first time he/she notices that the skin is warming up&#xD;
      (heat detection threshold) or at the time he/she notices a pulling, burning or pricking&#xD;
      sensation in addition to the feeling of heat (heat pain threshold). The measurements are&#xD;
      taken 3 times each and the results are averaged.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conditioned pain modulation Conditioned pain modulation describes the function of the&#xD;
      descending, pain-inhibiting system. First, the force with which pressure on the adductor&#xD;
      pollicis brevis muscle of the non-dominant hand is not only perceived as pressure, but also&#xD;
      as a stabbing, burning or pulling sensation is determined using a pressure gauge.&#xD;
      Subsequently, the contralateral hand is immersed in ice water until the subject feels a pain&#xD;
      intensity of NRS 40 (101-part scale). The pressure pain threshold is then immediately raised&#xD;
      again.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adverse effects:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Possible adverse effects are assessed and documented at each study visit. In addition, the&#xD;
      subjects are informed about the necessity of immediate telephone contact in case of the&#xD;
      occurrence of undesirable side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample Size The sample size was calculated by Mag. Schwantzer, Institute for Medical&#xD;
      Informatics, Statistics and Documentation (IMI), Medical University of Graz. The database was&#xD;
      based on the study by Jurgens et al, in which repetitive phasic heat application was tested&#xD;
      in healthy volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this publication, the mean value for maximum pain was 72.2, the standard deviation was&#xD;
      given as 5.4. Assuming more conservative baseline numbers for case number estimation&#xD;
      (SD=10.8), a sample size of 12 on a paired sample T-test with alpha=5% would have 80% power&#xD;
      to detect a difference of 10 VAS units. To compensate for any drop-outs, a sample size of 14&#xD;
      subjects is included in the study. Statistical evaluation is performed by the T-test for&#xD;
      paired samples or the Wilcoxon sign test, depending on the central tendency.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment of test persons / education Recruitment is done by posting on notice boards at&#xD;
      the ÖH an der KF-Uni Graz (main building, Resowi, Wall building).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects are asked orally whether they participate in another study at the same time or&#xD;
      whether a required period of time has elapsed since participation in another study. They&#xD;
      confirm this with their signature.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An anesthesiologist involved in the study will provide the information. Consent is then given&#xD;
      by signing a written information sheet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PEA is sold as &quot;dietary food for special medical purposes&quot;. In a recent literature analysis,&#xD;
      no side effects were reported in 1188 patients who took PEA for up to 60 days. Nevertheless,&#xD;
      the company Innexus Nutraceuticals describes in an information leaflet that PEA &quot;slows down&#xD;
      intestinal function&quot;. Some people may suffer from constipation or a feeling of fullness as a&#xD;
      result&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigation of pain and perception thresholds according to the specifications of the&#xD;
      &quot;German Research Association for Neuropathic Pain&quot; is an established procedure in both human&#xD;
      research and clinical investigation. No danger is to be expected for the individual test&#xD;
      person.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The application of &quot;repetitive phasic heat application&quot; is an established human pain model.&#xD;
      The maximum heat exposure of 48°C does not lead to skin damage. The changes in pain&#xD;
      sensitivity are locally very limited and normalize within a few hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the individual test person is willing to be exposed to a pain stimulus for a limited&#xD;
      period of time, there is no foreseeable risk for him/her.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 9, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>doubleblind, placebo-controlled,prospective crossover study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The masking is done by the pharmacological department also produces the placebos</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in spontaneous pain intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>--&gt;Day 0 --&gt;Day 28 before repeated heat application --&gt;Day 28 1 hour after repeated heat application --&gt; Day 56 --&gt;Day 112 before repeated heat application --&gt;Day 112 1 hour after repeated heat application</time_frame>
    <description>is measured on a visual analogue scale (0 means no pain and 10 means the worst imaginable pain)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Allodynia</measure>
    <time_frame>--&gt;Day 0 --&gt;Day 28 before repeated heat application --&gt;Day 28 1 hour after repeated heat application --&gt; Day 56 --&gt;Day 112 before repeated heat application --&gt;Day 112 1 hour after repeated heat application</time_frame>
    <description>measured in radial distance in mm</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Hyperalgesia</measure>
    <time_frame>--&gt;Day 0 --&gt;Day 28 before repeated heat application --&gt;Day 28 1 hour after repeated heat application --&gt; Day 56 --&gt;Day 112 before repeated heat application --&gt;Day 112 1 hour after repeated heat application</time_frame>
    <description>measured with pinpricks, that are preset different peak stimulus. A numerical scale (0-100) is used to measure how painful the stimulus is.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in heat detection threshold</measure>
    <time_frame>--&gt;Day 0 --&gt;Day 28 before repeated heat application --&gt;Day 28 1 hour after repeated heat application --&gt; Day 56 --&gt;Day 112 before repeated heat application --&gt;Day 112 1 hour after repeated heat application</time_frame>
    <description>measured in degrees</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in heat pain threshold</measure>
    <time_frame>--&gt;Day 0 --&gt;Day 28 before repeated heat application --&gt;Day 28 1 hour after repeated heat application --&gt; Day 56 --&gt;Day 112 before repeated heat application --&gt;Day 112 1 hour after repeated heat application</time_frame>
    <description>measured in degrees</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in conditioned pain modulation</measure>
    <time_frame>--&gt;Day 0 --&gt;Day 28 before repeated heat application --&gt;Day 28 1 hour after repeated heat application --&gt; Day 56 --&gt;Day 112 before repeated heat application --&gt;Day 112 1 hour after repeated heat application</time_frame>
    <description>measures the descending analgesic System with the help of a pressure agometer in kg</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">14</enrollment>
  <condition>Pain, Chronic</condition>
  <condition>Pain, Acute</condition>
  <condition>Central Sensitisation</condition>
  <condition>Neuroinflammatory Response</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Palmithylethanolamid</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Probands receive PEA 3xday for 28 days, 8 weeks wash out will follow, then they receive placebo for 28 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Probands receive placebo 3xday for 28 days, 8 weeks washout will follow, then they receive PEA for 28 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Palmithylethanolamid</intervention_name>
    <description>PEA 3x/d</description>
    <arm_group_label>Palmithylethanolamid</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>placebo 3x/d</description>
    <arm_group_label>Palmithylethanolamid</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic pain&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Analgesic intake&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurological illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dermatological illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiovascular illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PEA Allergy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>helmar Boremann-cimenti</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care Medicine, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria. helmar.bornemann@medunigraz.at</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kordula Lang-Illievich, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+436645381996</phone>
    <email>kordula.lang-illievich@medunigraz.at</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>helmar Boremann-cimenti, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+437676907181</phone>
    <email>helmar.bornemann@medunigraz.at</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical university of Graz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Graz</city>
        <zip>8010</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>helmar Boremann-cimenti</last_name>
      <phone>+437676907181</phone>
      <email>helmar.bornemann@medunigraz.at</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Paladini A, Fusco M, Cenacchi T, Schievano C, Piroli A, Varrassi G. Palmitoylethanolamide, a Special Food for Medical Purposes, in the Treatment of Chronic Pain: A Pooled Data Meta-analysis. Pain Physician. 2016 Feb;19(2):11-24.</citation>
    <PMID>26815246</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 4, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hyperalgesia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acute Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

