<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04665310</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00018836</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04665310</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of Anti-rejection Drug, Tacrolimus, in African-Americans With Kidney Transplant</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Early Dose Escalation Using Extended-Release Tacrolimus (Envarsus XR®) to Reduce Acute Rejection and Donor Specific Antibodies in African American Renal Transplant Recipients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The Methodist Hospital Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Veloxis Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The Methodist Hospital Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In spite of conventional immunosuppression with lymphocyte-depleting induction followed by&#xD;
      tacrolimus- and mycophenolate-based regimens, African American (AA) renal transplant&#xD;
      recipients experience higher rates of acute rejection (AR), donor specific antibodies (DSA),&#xD;
      and graft failure. Envarsus Extended-Release (XR)® (ENV) is a novel extended-release&#xD;
      formulation of tacrolimus with a favorable pharmacokinetic profile, even in the setting of&#xD;
      CYP3A5*1 allele (rapid metabolizers). The investigator will evaluate the safety and efficacy&#xD;
      of early dose escalation with ENV in AA recipients. The study hypothesis is that higher&#xD;
      tacrolimus target concentrations may be achieved without typical dose-limiting toxicities,&#xD;
      and this may ultimately result in lower incidence of early AR, DSA, and graft loss.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Phase 4 (post-marketing) De novo African American living or deceased donor renal transplant&#xD;
      recipients 18 to 65 years of age Number of subjects to be enrolled: 60&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will receive standard induction immunosuppression according to institution&#xD;
      protocol. Within one week of transplantation, all patients will be converted from&#xD;
      immediate-release tacrolimus (TAC) to extended-release tacrolimus (ENV) at 20% reduction in&#xD;
      total daily dosage. Patients will be randomized to low-, moderate-, or high-intensity ENV&#xD;
      groups, stratified by peak panel reactive antibody (pPRA) greater than or equal to 75%.&#xD;
      Target tacrolimus trough concentrations for the first month post-transplant will be 8-10&#xD;
      ng/mL in low-intensity group, 10-12 ng/mL in moderate-intensity group, and 12-14 ng/mL in&#xD;
      high-intensity group; likewise from month 1-3 post-transplant, target trough concentrations&#xD;
      will be 6-8 ng/mL, 8-10 ng/mL, and 10-12 ng/mL, respectively. Subjects experiencing&#xD;
      dose-limiting adverse events (AEs) will be de-escalated as warranted. Following month 3, all&#xD;
      patients will be maintained on ENV at target tacrolimus trough concentrations according to&#xD;
      institution protocol. Additional maintenance immunosuppression will consist of mycophenolate&#xD;
      mofetil (MMF) at a goal dose of 2000 mg daily along with an oral prednisone taper to 5-10 mg&#xD;
      daily by the end of month 1. All patients will be followed for 6 months post-transplant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Study not started, funding&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Parallel Group - Dose Escalation with 2 groups stratified by pPRA &lt;75% and &gt;75% and then randomized into 3 Intensity Arms (Low, Moderate and High) based on dosing of Envarsus XR.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants reaching the composite endpoint</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Composite endpoint of freedom from all of the following: i) biopsy-proven T-cell mediated rejection Banff Grade ≥1A, ii) antibody-mediated rejection, iii) de novo DSA, or iv) immune-mediated graft loss. The endpoint is a binary endpoint (Yes or No) of the composite of all 4 potential outcomes. The presence of any one of the four possible outcomes will be counted as a No for the binary endpoint (no freedom from the composite endpoint). The absence of all 4 possible outcomes will be counted as Yes for freedom from all of the possible outcomes.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects experiencing nephrotoxicity during the study</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Increase in serum creatinine of ≥0.3mg/dL</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects experiencing neurotoxicity during the study</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical intolerability including headache or significant tremors that resolve with reduction of the dose of Envarsus</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects experiencing infectious complications during the study</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Participants requiring extended (&gt;2 weeks) reduction in dose of Envarsus due to BK-polyomavirus or cytomegalovirus viral loads at 1, 3, and 6 months post-transplant</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in estimated glomerular filtration rate at 1, 3, and 6 months between groups of enrolled subjects</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed as the Chronic Kidney Disease - Epidemiology Collaboration equation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in immunosuppressant side effects between enrolled subjects</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed using the &quot;Immunosuppressant Side Effects Instrument - The Memphis Survey&quot; questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Enrolled subject overall survival and Graft survival at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Freedom from death and from graft loss at 6 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Kidney Disease, End-Stage</condition>
  <condition>Donor Specific Antibodies</condition>
  <condition>Acute Rejection of Renal Transplant</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1 - Low-Intensity</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients will receive standard induction immunosuppression according to institution protocol. TAC will be started when clinically appropriate according to institution protocol.&#xD;
TAC dosing will be 2 mg twice daily to be reduced by 20% after week 1 and start Envarsus XR once daily.&#xD;
Target Tacrolimus Trough Concentrations:&#xD;
Week 0 to Week 4: 8-10 mg/mL Month 1 to Month 3: 6-8 mg/mL</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1 - Moderate-Intensity</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients will receive standard induction immunosuppression according to institution protocol. TAC will be started when clinically appropriate according to institution protocol.&#xD;
TAC dosing will be 3 mg twice daily to be reduced by 20% after week 1 and start Envarsus XR once daily.&#xD;
Target Tacrolimus Trough Concentrations:&#xD;
Week 0 to Week 4: 10-12 mg/mL Month 1 to Month 3: 8-10 mg/mL</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1 - High-Intensity</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients will receive standard induction immunosuppression according to institution protocol. TAC will be started when clinically appropriate according to institution protocol.&#xD;
TAC dosing will be 4 mg twice daily to be reduced by 20% after week 1 and start Envarsus XR once daily.&#xD;
Target Tacrolimus Trough Concentrations:&#xD;
Week 0 to Week 4: 12-14 mg/mL Month 1 to Month 3: 10-12 mg/mL</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2 - Low-Intensity</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients will receive standard induction immunosuppression according to institution protocol. TAC will be started when clinically appropriate according to institution protocol.&#xD;
TAC dosing will be 2 mg twice daily to be reduced by 20% after week 1 and start Envarsus XR once daily.&#xD;
Target Tacrolimus Trough Concentrations:&#xD;
Week 0 to Week 4: 8-10 mg/mL Month 1 to Month 3: 6-8 mg/mL</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2 - Moderate-Intensity</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients will receive standard induction immunosuppression according to institution protocol. TAC will be started when clinically appropriate according to institution protocol.&#xD;
TAC dosing will be 3 mg twice daily to be reduced by 20% after week 1 and start Envarsus XR once daily.&#xD;
Target Tacrolimus Trough Concentrations:&#xD;
Week 0 to Week 4: 10-12 mg/mL Month 1 to Month 3: 8-10 mg/mL</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2 - High-Intensity</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients will receive standard induction immunosuppression according to institution protocol. TAC will be started when clinically appropriate according to institution protocol.&#xD;
TAC dosing will be 4 mg twice daily to be reduced by 20% after week 1 and start Envarsus XR once daily.&#xD;
Target Tacrolimus Trough Concentrations:&#xD;
Week 0 to Week 4: 12-14 mg/mL Month 1 to Month 3: 10-12 mg/mL</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Envarsus XR</intervention_name>
    <description>tacrolimus, extended-release tablets, a calcineurin inhibitor</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1 - High-Intensity</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1 - Low-Intensity</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1 - Moderate-Intensity</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2 - High-Intensity</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2 - Low-Intensity</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2 - Moderate-Intensity</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Life Cycle Pharma (LCP)-tacrolimus</other_name>
    <other_name>once-daily extended-release tacrolimus</other_name>
    <other_name>once-daily prolonged-release tacrolimus</other_name>
    <other_name>Tacrolimus-LCP</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Primary live donor or deceased donor renal allograft&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  African American patients aged 18 to 65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ability to take oral medications&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Not currently on medications known to significantly interfere with tacrolimus&#xD;
                  metabolism, e.g. strong CYP3A4 inducers or inhibitors including but not limited&#xD;
                  to rifampin, rifabutin, phenytoin, carbamazepine, phenobarbital, protease&#xD;
                  inhibitors, azole antifungal (voriconazole, itraconazole, posaconazole,&#xD;
                  ketoconazole)&#xD;
&#xD;
                  o Note: All patients will be discharged on clotrimazole 10 mg three times daily&#xD;
                  for one month for thrush prophylaxis, a known mild-to-moderate CYP3A4 inhibitor&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Female subjects of childbearing potential:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Not current pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Agree not to try to become pregnant during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Agree to consistently use two forms of highly effective birth control&#xD;
                       throughout the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Provision of signed and dated informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stated willingness to comply with all study procedures and availability for the&#xD;
                  duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Presence of a positive T- or B-cell flow cytometry allogeneic crossmatch&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of pre-formed anti-human leukocyte antigen (HLA) donor-specific&#xD;
                  antibodies (DSAs)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Recipient of an ABO-incompatible organ&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Receipt of a multi-organ or dual kidney transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Receipt of pediatric en bloc deceased donor kidneys&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Receipt of deceased donor kidney with a kidney donor profile index (KDPI) greater&#xD;
                  than or equal to 85%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Has undergone desensitization, or received antibody removal, anti-B-cell, or&#xD;
                  anti-plasma cell therapy in the 90 days preceding the transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Planned initiation of antibody removal (i.e. plasmapheresis) within 7 days of the&#xD;
                  transplant procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Positive test for latent tuberculosis (TB) and has not previously received&#xD;
                  adequate anti-microbial therapy or would require TB prophylaxis after transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled concomitant infection that would not allow for targeting escalated&#xD;
                  tacrolimus trough concentrations, as deemed by prescriber&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Known infection or seropositivity for hepatitis B virus (HBV, defined by positive&#xD;
                  HBsAg, anti-HBcAg, or positive viral load) or hepatitis C virus (HCV) with active&#xD;
                  viral load&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Use of an investigational study in the 30 days prior to the transplant procedure&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ahmed O Gaber, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Houston Methodist Physicians Organization</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kidney Disease: Improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO) Transplant Work Group. KDIGO clinical practice guideline for the care of kidney transplant recipients. Am J Transplant. 2009 Nov;9 Suppl 3:S1-155. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-6143.2009.02834.x.</citation>
    <PMID>19845597</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Young CJ, Gaston RS. Renal transplantation in black Americans. N Engl J Med. 2000 Nov 23;343(21):1545-52. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11087885</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Narayanan M, Pankewycz O, Shihab F, Wiland A, McCague K, Chan L. Long-term outcomes in African American kidney transplant recipients under contemporary immunosuppression: a four-yr analysis of the Mycophenolic acid Observational REnal transplant (MORE) study. Clin Transplant. 2014 Feb;28(2):184-91. doi: 10.1111/ctr.12294. Epub 2013 Dec 24.</citation>
    <PMID>24372743</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lamb KE, Lodhi S, Meier-Kriesche HU. Long-term renal allograft survival in the United States: a critical reappraisal. Am J Transplant. 2011 Mar;11(3):450-62. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-6143.2010.03283.x. Epub 2010 Oct 25.</citation>
    <PMID>20973913</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Patel SJ, Suki WN, Loucks-DeVos J, Graviss EA, Nguyen DT, Knight RJ, Kuten SA, Moore LW, Teeter LD, Gaber LW, Gaber AO. Disparate rates of acute rejection and donor-specific antibodies among high-immunologic risk renal transplant subgroups receiving antithymocyte globulin induction. Transpl Int. 2016 Aug;29(8):897-908. doi: 10.1111/tri.12791. Epub 2016 Jul 7.</citation>
    <PMID>27196395</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bunnapradist S, Ciechanowski K, West-Thielke P, Mulgaonkar S, Rostaing L, Vasudev B, Budde K; MELT investigators. Conversion from twice-daily tacrolimus to once-daily extended release tacrolimus (LCPT): the phase III randomized MELT trial. Am J Transplant. 2013 Mar;13(3):760-9. doi: 10.1111/ajt.12035. Epub 2012 Dec 21.</citation>
    <PMID>23279614</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Budde K, Bunnapradist S, Grinyo JM, Ciechanowski K, Denny JE, Silva HT, Rostaing L; Envarsus study group. Novel once-daily extended-release tacrolimus (LCPT) versus twice-daily tacrolimus in de novo kidney transplants: one-year results of Phase III, double-blind, randomized trial. Am J Transplant. 2014 Dec;14(12):2796-806. doi: 10.1111/ajt.12955. Epub 2014 Oct 2.</citation>
    <PMID>25278376</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gaber AO, Alloway RR, Bodziak K, Kaplan B, Bunnapradist S. Conversion from twice-daily tacrolimus capsules to once-daily extended-release tacrolimus (LCPT): a phase 2 trial of stable renal transplant recipients. Transplantation. 2013 Jul 27;96(2):191-7. doi: 10.1097/TP.0b013e3182962cc1.</citation>
    <PMID>23715050</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bunnapradist S, Rostaing L, Alloway RR, West-Thielke P, Denny J, Mulgaonkar S, Budde K. LCPT once-daily extended-release tacrolimus tablets versus twice-daily capsules: a pooled analysis of two phase 3 trials in important de novo and stable kidney transplant recipient subgroups. Transpl Int. 2016 May;29(5):603-11. doi: 10.1111/tri.12770. Epub 2016 Apr 3.</citation>
    <PMID>26953629</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Trofe-Clark J, Brennan DC, West-Thielke P, Milone MC, Lim MA, Neubauer R, Nigro V, Bloom RD. Results of ASERTAA, a Randomized Prospective Crossover Pharmacogenetic Study of Immediate-Release Versus Extended-Release Tacrolimus in African American Kidney Transplant Recipients. Am J Kidney Dis. 2018 Mar;71(3):315-326. doi: 10.1053/j.ajkd.2017.07.018. Epub 2017 Nov 20.</citation>
    <PMID>29162334</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Langone A, Steinberg SM, Gedaly R, Chan LK, Shah T, Sethi KD, Nigro V, Morgan JC; STRATO Investigators. Switching STudy of Kidney TRansplant PAtients with Tremor to LCP-TacrO (STRATO): an open-label, multicenter, prospective phase 3b study. Clin Transplant. 2015 Sep;29(9):796-805. doi: 10.1111/ctr.12581. Epub 2015 Aug 6.</citation>
    <PMID>26113208</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kuypers DR, Claes K, Evenepoel P, Maes B, Vanrenterghem Y. Clinical efficacy and toxicity profile of tacrolimus and mycophenolic acid in relation to combined long-term pharmacokinetics in de novo renal allograft recipients. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2004 May;75(5):434-47.</citation>
    <PMID>15116056</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Winsett RP, Arheart K, Stratta RJ, Alloway R, Wicks MN, Gaber AO, Hathaway DK. Evaluation of an immunosuppressant side effect instrument. Prog Transplant. 2004 Sep;14(3):210-6, 240.</citation>
    <PMID>15495780</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Staatz CE, Tett SE. Clinical pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of tacrolimus in solid organ transplantation. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2004;43(10):623-53. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15244495</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kuypers DR, Peeters PC, Sennesael JJ, Kianda MN, Vrijens B, Kristanto P, Dobbels F, Vanrenterghem Y, Kanaan N; ADMIRAD Study Team. Improved adherence to tacrolimus once-daily formulation in renal recipients: a randomized controlled trial using electronic monitoring. Transplantation. 2013 Jan 27;95(2):333-40. doi: 10.1097/TP.0b013e3182725532.</citation>
    <PMID>23263559</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ho ET, Wong G, Craig JC, Chapman JR. Once-daily extended-release versus twice-daily standard-release tacrolimus in kidney transplant recipients: a systematic review. Transplantation. 2013 May 15;95(9):1120-8. doi: 10.1097/TP.0b013e318284c15b. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23542469</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Beckebaum S, Iacob S, Sweid D, Sotiropoulos GC, Saner F, Kaiser G, Radtke A, Klein CG, Erim Y, de Geest S, Paul A, Gerken G, Cicinnati VR. Efficacy, safety, and immunosuppressant adherence in stable liver transplant patients converted from a twice-daily tacrolimus-based regimen to once-daily tacrolimus extended-release formulation. Transpl Int. 2011 Jul;24(7):666-75. doi: 10.1111/j.1432-2277.2011.01254.x. Epub 2011 Apr 5.</citation>
    <PMID>21466596</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Doesch AO, Mueller S, Konstandin M, Celik S, Erbel C, Kristen A, Frankenstein L, Koch A, Dengler TJ, Ehlermann P, Zugck C, De Geest S, Katus HA. Increased adherence after switch from twice daily calcineurin inhibitor based treatment to once daily modified released tacrolimus in heart transplantation: a pre-experimental study. Transplant Proc. 2010 Dec;42(10):4238-42. doi: 10.1016/j.transproceed.2010.09.074.</citation>
    <PMID>21168673</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Maldonado G, Greenland S. Simulation study of confounder-selection strategies. Am J Epidemiol. 1993 Dec 1;138(11):923-36.</citation>
    <PMID>8256780</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wasserman L. Bayesian Model Selection and Model Averaging. J Math Psychol. 2000 Mar;44(1):92-107.</citation>
    <PMID>10733859</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 2, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 10, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 10, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The Methodist Hospital Research Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ahmed Osama Gaber, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director, Houston Methodist J.C. Walter Jr. Transplant Center</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Renal Transplant</keyword>
  <keyword>Donor Specific Antibodies</keyword>
  <keyword>African American</keyword>
  <keyword>Acute Rejection of Renal Transplant</keyword>
  <keyword>Kidney Transplant</keyword>
  <keyword>End Stage Renal Disease</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

