<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04668443</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-02-DEFT-GIC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04668443</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>D²EFT Graphical Informed Consent</brief_title>
  <acronym>D²EFT-GIC</acronym>
  <official_title>Acceptability and Feasibility of a Graphical Informed Consent in the Informed Consent Process of D²EFT Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kirby Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institute of Human Virology, Nigeria</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kirby Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      D²EFT-GIC is a substudy of D²EFT study (NCT03017872), a randomised clinical trial of&#xD;
      second-line antiretroviral therapies. The goal of D²EFT-GIC is to evaluate a novel tool, the&#xD;
      &quot;Graphical Informed Consent&quot; (GIC), within D²EFT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The GIC is designed to supplement the informed consent process with a set of culturally- and&#xD;
      gender-adapted illustrations, with an explanatory script for researchers, that complements&#xD;
      the mandatory written participant information sheet and consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators propose to assess the acceptability and feasibility of this tool from the&#xD;
      participants and researchers perspectives. The GIC will be first pre-tested in one or more&#xD;
      site(s) - where the informed consent process is challenging because of literacy, language or&#xD;
      culture barriers - in 10 prospective participants for D²EFT. If this stage shows there is no&#xD;
      negative impact of the GIC on the consent process, the second stage will study the&#xD;
      feasibility of implementing the GIC in the usual practice.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Informed consent requires provision of complex medical information in an easily&#xD;
      understandable format. During the consent process, researchers may encounter potential&#xD;
      research participants who are not thoroughly used to care services and thus may struggle to&#xD;
      understand what clinical research is, the purpose of the specific research in relation to&#xD;
      their health, research methods, its risks and benefits, and their options and rights.&#xD;
      Clinical trials in people living with HIV can present additional challenges due to stigma&#xD;
      surrounding the infection, as the need for a third-party witness to ensure adequate&#xD;
      comprehension of the presented information may be concerning to the participant. These&#xD;
      barriers to an optimal informed consent are particularly significant in low and lower-middle&#xD;
      income countries (LMICs).&#xD;
&#xD;
      To try to overcome these barriers and to make written information sheet and consent forms&#xD;
      (PICFs) more accessible and understandable for key-populations, and more user-friendly for&#xD;
      on-site researchers, tools including interactive videos have been developed for various&#xD;
      diseases and different settings. Many of these tools are study-specific or developed in&#xD;
      high-income countries with limited reproducibility; few have been studied in the consent&#xD;
      process for HIV treatment trials or across multiple LMIC settings. Data evaluating these&#xD;
      tools and their impact on participants' understanding or researchers' satisfaction are&#xD;
      limited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With the D²EFT community advisory board (CAB) and protocol steering committee (PSC), the&#xD;
      investigators developed the &quot;Graphical Informed Consent&quot; (GIC). This tool is designed to&#xD;
      supplement the informed consent process with a set of culturally- and gender-adapted&#xD;
      illustrations with an explanatory script for researchers, that complement the mandatory&#xD;
      written PICF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators propose to evaluate this novel tool within D²EFT study, a randomised&#xD;
      clinical trial of HIV second-line therapy in LMICs, by undertaking a pilot study. The study&#xD;
      aims to assess acceptability and feasibility of the GIC by measuring implementation outcomes:&#xD;
      participants' acceptability and acceptance, and researchers' utilisation and satisfaction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 22, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of prospective D²EFT participants to whom researchers offered the supplemental GIC during the informed consent process (Stage 2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Utilisation (uptake) of the GIC by researchers: number of times researchers offered the supplemental GIC during the informed consent process of D²EFT divided by the total number of prospective participants who underwent informed consent for D²EFT during the substudy period when the GIC is freely available</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants who find the illustrations helpful (Stage 1)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>A five-point Likert scale will be used in a questionnaire administered to the participants after they underwent the D²EFT informed consent process with the GIC, during Stage 1. &quot;Overall, supplementing the written information explained by the doctor with illustrations is&quot;: multiple answers will range from &quot;Extremely troublesome&quot; (worst outcome) to &quot;Very interesting (helpful)&quot; (best outcome).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of researchers who think there are issues in using the GIC (Stage 1)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>A questionnaire with a three-point Likert scale will be used: &quot;Yes&quot; (worst outcome) to &quot;No&quot; (best outcome).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants who accept to undergo the D²EFT informed consent process with GIC (Stage 2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Participants' acceptance (uptake) during stage 2. The number of participants who accept/decline the use of illustrations when the researcher offered the GIC with the written informed consent will be recorded</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV-1-infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective participants in D²EFT study</arm_group_label>
    <description>HIV-positive persons who are eligible for the D²EFT study will be proposed to receive the research-related information with the set of pictures (GIC)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Researchers obtaining informed consent for D²EFT study</arm_group_label>
    <description>Healthcare givers involved in the participant informed consent process of D²EFT</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Graphical Informed Consent (GIC)</intervention_name>
    <description>The GIC (set of illustrations that complement the written information and consent form) will be proposed to prospective participants by researchers, systematically during the pre-test (stage 1). If the stage 1 shows no negative impact of the GIC on the consent process, the stage 2 will be implemented and the GIC will be proposed by researchers when they feel it could be beneficial for the participant.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective participants in D²EFT study</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Researchers obtaining informed consent for D²EFT study</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Prospective participants for D²EFT study and researchers obtening the informed consent&#xD;
        process.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fulfil the eligibility criteria for D²EFT and willing to undertake D²EFT informed&#xD;
             consent process;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being able to give a verbal consent for the D²EFT-GIC.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to comply with the substudy requirements.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark Polizzotto, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The Kirby Institute, UNSW</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Emmanuelle Papot, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+61 9385 0902</phone>
    <email>epapot@kirby.unsw.edu.au</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institute of Human Virology Nigeria (IHVN)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Abuja</city>
        <country>Nigeria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maryam Almujtaba, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Eriobu Nnakelu, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Nigeria</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 3, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 13, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Informed consent process</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

