<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04663295</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CIP329</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04663295</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>MiniMed 670G Insulin Pump China Study for Type I Diabetic</brief_title>
  <official_title>Safety, Effectiveness and Usability Evaluation of the Hybrid Closed Loop (HCL) System in Type 1 Adult and Adolescent Subjects in Chinese Population</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medtronic Diabetes</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medtronic Diabetes</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to obtain clinical data in Chinese patients to support product&#xD;
      registration of the MiniMed™ 670G system with the National Medical Product Administration&#xD;
      (NMPA) in China. The results from the study will be submitted to the NMPA for product&#xD;
      registration.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is a multi-center, single arm study in insulin-requiring subjects with type 1&#xD;
      diabetes who are 14 years of age and older. The run-in period will be approximately up to 35&#xD;
      days long, followed by a study period that will be approximately up to 33 days in duration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is anticipated to last no longer than 13 months from investigational center&#xD;
      initiation to completion of all data entry and monitoring procedures. The study will target&#xD;
      approximately 5 months to complete subject enrollment. Subjects can expect to participate for&#xD;
      approximately 2-3 months including the run-in and study periods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of up to 75 subjects (aged 14-75) will be enrolled at a minimum 2 investigational&#xD;
      centers and up to 6 investigational centers (hospitals) in China to have at least 50 subjects&#xD;
      who complete the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 22, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 22, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in time in target range (% of SG): 70 mg/dL (3.9 mmol/L) ≤ SG ≤ 180 mg/dL (10 mmol/L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The overall mean change in % of time in target range from run-in period to study period will be estimated and compared by a simple superiority paired test and a significance level of 0.025 (one-sided).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time in hypoglycemic range</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Time in hypoglycemic range (% of SG): SG &lt; 70 mg/dL (3.9 mmol/L), 60 mg/dL (3.3 mmol/L) and 54 mg/dL(3.0 mmol/L) will be summarized.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time in hyperglycemic range</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Time in hyperglycemic range (% of SG): SG &gt; 180 mg/dL (10 mmol/L), 250 mg/dL (13.9 mmol/L) and 350mg/dL (19.4 mmol/L) will be summarized.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Standard deviation of SG</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The standard deviation (SD) of SG will be summarized.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Glucose variation</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The glucose coefficient of variation (CV) will be summarized.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>TDD</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Change of Total Daily Dose (TDD) of insulin from baseline to EOS will be summarized.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Weight</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Change of weight from baseline to EOS will be summarized.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent in Auto Mode (HCL) versus time spent in Manual Mode (open loop)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Time spent in Auto Mode (HCL) versus time spent in Manual Mode (open loop) will be summarized.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time in target range, time in hypoglycemic range, and time in hyperglycemic range stratified by HbA1c Ranges</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Time in target range, time in hypoglycemic range, and time in hyperglycemic range will be summarized by the stratification of HbA1c Ranges (&lt; 7%, 7 - 7.5%, 7.5 - 8%, &gt; 8%).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">74</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Subjects with Type 1 diabetes wearing HCL pump system</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects 14-75 years of age who have been diagnosed with Type 1 diabetes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MiniMed™ 670G insulin pump system</intervention_name>
    <description>Hybrid closed loop insulin pump with associated CGM and blood glucose meter</description>
    <arm_group_label>Subjects with Type 1 diabetes wearing HCL pump system</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject is age 14- 75 years at time of Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject has a clinical diagnosis of type 1 diabetes for 2 years or more as determined&#xD;
             via medical record or source documentation by an individual qualified to make a&#xD;
             medical diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Study-specific inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject is willing to perform ≥ 4 finger stick BG measurements daily.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject is willing to perform required sensor calibrations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject is willing to wear the system continuously throughout the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject must have a minimum daily insulin requirement (Total Daily Dose) of greater&#xD;
             than or equal to 8 units.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject has a Glycosylated hemoglobin (HbA1c) less than 10% (as processed by the&#xD;
             investigational center lab or their contracted Local Lab) at time of Screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject has thyroid-stimulating hormone (TSH) in the normal range OR if the TSH is out&#xD;
             of normal reference range the Free T3 is below or within the lab's reference range and&#xD;
             Free T4 is within the normal reference range. Prior labs in the last 6 months are&#xD;
             sufficient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subject has been on pump therapy for greater than 6 months prior to screening (with or&#xD;
             without CGM experience).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subject is willing to upload data from the study pump and meter at home.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. If subject has celiac disease, it has been adequately treated as determined by the&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subject has been taking and is willing to take one of the following insulins&#xD;
             throughout the course of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Humalog™* (insulin lispro injection)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  NovoLog™* (insulin aspart)&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subject must be able to carbohydrate count or willing to learn how to carbohydrate&#xD;
             count for the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject has a history of 2 or more episodes of severe hypoglycemia, which resulted in&#xD;
             any the following during the 6 months prior to Screening:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Medical assistance (i.e. Paramedics, Emergency Room (ER) or Hospitalization)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Coma&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Seizures&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject has been hospitalized or has visited the ER in the 6 months prior to Screening&#xD;
             resulting in a primary diagnosis of uncontrolled diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject has had DKA in the 6 months prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject is unable to tolerate tape adhesive in the area of sensor placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject has any unresolved adverse skin condition in the area of sensor placement&#xD;
             (e.g., psoriasis, dermatitis herpetiformis, rash, Staphylococcus infection).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject is a female of child-bearing potential who has a positive pregnancy test at&#xD;
             Screening or plans to become pregnant during the course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject is a female who is sexually active and able to conceive should be excluded if&#xD;
             they are not using an effective method of contraception and do not agree to continue&#xD;
             using an effective method of contraception for the duration of the study as determined&#xD;
             by investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject has had any of the following cardiovascular events within 1 year of screening:&#xD;
             myocardial infarction, unstable angina, coronary artery bypass surgery, coronary&#xD;
             artery stenting, transient ischemic attack, cerebrovascular accident, angina,&#xD;
             congestive heart failure, ventricular rhythm disturbances or thromboembolic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subject is being treated for hyperthyroidism at time of Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subject has a diagnosis of adrenal insufficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subject has taken any oral, injectable, or intravenous (IV) glucocorticoids within 8&#xD;
             weeks from time of Screening, or plans to take any oral, injectable, or IV&#xD;
             glucocorticoids during the course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subject is actively participating in an investigational study (drug or device) wherein&#xD;
             he/she has received treatment from an investigational study drug or investigational&#xD;
             study device in the last 2 weeks. (Please note participation in an observational study&#xD;
             is acceptable.)&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subject is currently abusing illicit drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subject is currently abusing alcohol.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Subject is using pramlintide (Symlin), DPP-4 inhibitor, liraglutide (Victoza or other&#xD;
             GLP-1 agonists), metformin, canagliflozin (Invokana or other SGLT2 inhibitors) at time&#xD;
             of Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Subject has a history of visual impairment which would not allow subject to&#xD;
             participate in the study and perform all study procedures safely, as determined by the&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Subject has elective surgery planned that requires general anesthesia during the&#xD;
             course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Subject has a sickle cell disease, hemoglobinopathy; or has received red blood cell&#xD;
             transfusion or erythropoietin within 3 months prior to time of Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Subject plans to receive red blood cell transfusion or erythropoietin over the course&#xD;
             of study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Subject diagnosed with current eating disorder such as anorexia or bulimia&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Subject has been diagnosed with chronic kidney disease that results in chronic anemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Subject has a hematocrit (Hct) that is below the normal reference range of lab used.&#xD;
             Prior labs in the last 6 months are sufficient.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Subject is on dialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Subject has an estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) of &lt; 30.&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Subject has a pediatric BMI category of underweight (less than the 5th percentile) as&#xD;
             defined by Centers for Disease Control (CDC)&#xD;
             (https://www.cdc.gov/healthyweight/assessing/bmi/childrens_bmi/about_childrens_bmi.htm&#xD;
             l)&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Subject is a member the research staff involved with the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chinese PLA General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beijing</city>
        <state>Beijing</state>
        <zip>100853</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The First Affiliated Hospital, Sun Yat-sen University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Guangzhou</city>
        <state>Guangdong</state>
        <zip>510000</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital The Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing University Medical School</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nanjing</city>
        <state>Jiangsu</state>
        <zip>210008</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Shanghai General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Shanghai</city>
        <state>Shanghai</state>
        <zip>200080</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Type 1</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

