<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04661085</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SHS-ED-11f-2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04661085</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Infection With Unknown Origin in the Emergency Department</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Descriptive Study of Patients Suspected With Infection in the Emergency Department, With a Special Focus on Infection With Unknown Origin.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Southern Denmark</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Southern Denmark</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients suspected with infection is one of the major groups, who are admitted to the Danish&#xD;
      Emergency Departments (ED). Currently, there is no overall description of the distribution of&#xD;
      these infections. The aim of this study is to characterize ED patients with a suspected&#xD;
      infection whereby the focus of the infection is of an unknown origin.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Bacteria resistant to antibiotics are associated with high antibiotic consumption and are&#xD;
      identified by the World Health Organisation as a major public health threat. Despite efforts&#xD;
      to optimize antibiotic consumption in Denmark, the total consumption in the hospital sector&#xD;
      increased from 2009-2018 and the incidence of multi-resistance bacteria (MRB) is increasing.&#xD;
      A Danish multicenter study has shown that every 20th patient in the emergency department has&#xD;
      MRB. Patients with an infection of unknown origin tend to be prescribed a broad-spectrum&#xD;
      antibiotic, as physicians endeavour to target probable origins in the body. The uncertainty&#xD;
      associated with the diagnosis may lead to an overconsumption of antibiotics, which&#xD;
      contributes to increased development of resistant bacteria and threatens future treatment&#xD;
      options.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to characterize patients admitted to the ED suspected with&#xD;
      infection. The study will have three objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To describe the distribution of ED infections according to the registered diagnosis in&#xD;
           the medical record compared to a clinical expert panel assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To identify clinically relevant information available at admission associated with a&#xD;
           patients infection of unknown origin.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To investigate the association between an adverse event and clinically relevant&#xD;
           information for patients with infection of unknown origin&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators' hypothesis is that with an improvement of knowledge about patients with an&#xD;
      infection of unknown origin, a more accurate diagnosis can be made leading to a more&#xD;
      appropriate antibiotic therapy and contributing to the fight against resistance to&#xD;
      antibiotics.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Diagnosis after 2 days</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours after admission emergency department</time_frame>
    <description>Diagnosis code of patient (registered medical record and clinical expert panel assessment)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intensive care unit treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>within 60 days from admission to the emergency department</time_frame>
    <description>Transfer to the intensive care unit will be recorded during the current hospitalization as a binary variable (transferred/not-transferred)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of stay</measure>
    <time_frame>within 60 days from admission to the emergency department</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the time (in days) spent in hospital during the current admission. Measured in days from admission to hospital discharge. Discharge date minus admission date</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>30-days mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>within 30 days from admission to the emergency department</time_frame>
    <description>Mortality within 30 days from admission to the Emergency Department</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Readmission</measure>
    <time_frame>within 30 days from day of discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Binary</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>In-hospital mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>within 60 days from admission to the emergency department</time_frame>
    <description>binary</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Diagnose code at hospital discharge</measure>
    <time_frame>within 60 days from admission to the emergency department</time_frame>
    <description>code registered in medical record at discharge</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>90-day mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 90 days from admission to emergency department</time_frame>
    <description>Mortality - binary</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Level of infection markers</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 4 hours of arrival to emergency department</time_frame>
    <description>concentration of serum procalcitonin, CRP and suPAR</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Level of markers of lung injury</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 4 hours of arrival to emergency department</time_frame>
    <description>concentration of serum surfactant protein D, KL-6, and YKL-40</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Bacteriuria</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 4 hours of arrival to emergency department</time_frame>
    <description>defined by microbiologist on urine culture analysis</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with a suspected infection</arm_group_label>
    <description>Acutely admitted patients from the emergency department across 3 sites who have a suspected infection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Broader Medical history and clinical tests</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will be treated with standard care plus additional blood tests, urine culture and urine flow cytometry,</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with a suspected infection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Acutely admitted patients suspected with infection at three hospitals in the region of&#xD;
        Southern Denmark - Hosptial Sonderjylland, Hospital Lillebaelt and Odense University&#xD;
        Hospital.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults admitted to the ED will be invited to participate in the study, if the&#xD;
             physician, receiving the patient, suspect the patient has an infection (e.g.&#xD;
             indication for blood culture).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If the attending physician considers that participation will delay a life-saving&#xD;
             treatment or patient needs direct transfer to the intensive care unit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Admission within the last 14 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Verified COVID-19 disease within 14 days before admission&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe immunodeficiencies: Primary immunodeficiencies and secondary immunodeficiencies&#xD;
             (HIV positive CD4 &lt;200, Patients receiving immunosuppressive treatment (ATC L04A),&#xD;
             Corticosteroid treatment (&gt;20 mg/day prednisone or equivalent for &gt;14 days within the&#xD;
             last 30 days), Chemotherapy within 30 days)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christian Backer Mogensen</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital of Southern Denmark</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Helene Skjøt-Arkil</last_name>
    <phone>+ 45 7997 1113</phone>
    <email>Helene.Skjoet-Arkil@rsyd.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital of Southern Jutland</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aabenraa</city>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christian B Mogensen, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carter-Storch R, Olsen UF, Mogensen CB. Admissions to emergency department may be classified into specific complaint categories. Dan Med J. 2014 Mar;61(3):A4802.</citation>
    <PMID>24814917</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bager F. DANMAP: monitoring antimicrobial resistance in Denmark. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2000 May;14(4):271-4.</citation>
    <PMID>10794946</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Skjøt-Arkil H, Mogensen CB, Lassen AT, Johansen IS, Chen M, Petersen P, Andersen KV, Ellermann-Eriksen S, Møller JM, Ludwig M, Fuglsang-Damgaard D, Nielsen FE, Petersen DB, Jensen US, Rosenvinge FS. Carrier prevalence and risk factors for colonisation of multiresistant bacteria in Danish emergency departments: a cross-sectional survey. BMJ Open. 2019 Jun 27;9(6):e029000. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2019-029000.</citation>
    <PMID>31253624</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhao MZ, Ruan QR, Xing MY, Wei S, Xu D, Wu ZH, Zhu L, Zhu JL, Zheng CF, Liu S, Yu ZJ, Qi JY, Song JX. A Diagnostic Tool for Identification of Etiologies of Fever of Unknown Origin in Adult Patients. Curr Med Sci. 2019 Aug;39(4):589-596. doi: 10.1007/s11596-019-2078-3. Epub 2019 Jul 25.</citation>
    <PMID>31346995</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Courjon J, Demonchy E, Degand N, Risso K, Ruimy R, Roger PM. Patients with community-acquired bacteremia of unknown origin: clinical characteristics and usefulness of microbiological results for therapeutic issues: a single-center cohort study. Ann Clin Microbiol Antimicrob. 2017 May 19;16(1):40. doi: 10.1186/s12941-017-0214-0.</citation>
    <PMID>28526094</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 8, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>antibiotics</keyword>
  <keyword>source</keyword>
  <keyword>diagnosis</keyword>
  <keyword>fever</keyword>
  <keyword>pyrexia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

