<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04663490</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0717040</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04663490</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neutrophil to Lymphocyte Ratio as a Predictor of Complicated Acute Diverticulitis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Neutrophil to Lymphocyte Ratio as a Predictor of Complicated Acute Diverticulitis: A Retrospective Cohort Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Clinica Universitaria Reina Fabiola, Universidad Catolica de Cordoba</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Clinica Universitaria Reina Fabiola, Universidad Catolica de Cordoba</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Introduction: Various biomarkers have been studied to predict the severity of acute&#xD;
      diverticulitis (AD), such as the leukocyte count and CRP, which are useful but lack&#xD;
      sufficient sensitivity. The neutrophil-lymphocyte ratio (NLR) has been identified as a new&#xD;
      inflammatory biomarker in several abdominal pathologies. However, few studies determine its&#xD;
      association with the severity of AD. The objective of the present study was to determine the&#xD;
      utility and diagnostic precision of NLR in complicated acute diverticulitis (cAD).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material and methods: Descriptive, retrospective and analytical study. Patients older than 18&#xD;
      years with a diagnosis of AD were included, from 2013 - 2018. Demographic variables, days of&#xD;
      hospitalization, leukocyte count, neutrophils, lymphocytes, ESR, CRP, and NLR were analyzed.&#xD;
      The sensitivity and specificity for the diagnosis of cAD were determined using ROC curves.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction Acute diverticulitis (AD) is present in 10-25% of patients with diverticular&#xD;
      disease, being most common in sigmoid colon, with around 200.000 hospitalizations yearly . As&#xD;
      much as one fifth of patients are younger than 50 at the moment of diagnosis and around 5%&#xD;
      under the age of 40 .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Confirming the diagnosis requires the utilization of imaging studies, therefore, American&#xD;
      Society of Colon and Rectal Surgeons (ASCRS) established that computed tomography (CT) is the&#xD;
      standard method for the diagnosis of AD, with a sensitivity of 98% and a specificity of 99%.&#xD;
      The tomographic findings vary according the severity of diverticular disease, which is&#xD;
      categorized through a modified Hinchey classification system. Approximately 10-15% of AD&#xD;
      patients may develop complications that imply the onset of abscesses, fistulas, stenosis,&#xD;
      obstruction and/or perforation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, interest has been raised in the role of biomarkers in diverticular disease as&#xD;
      non-invasive, reliable, inexpensive tools that may help in the early diagnosis of complicated&#xD;
      AD, such as C-reactive protein (CRP), useful marker in the prediction of the level of&#xD;
      inflammation and severity of AD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In 2001 identified the neutrophil-lymphocyte ratio (NLR) as an inflammation marker in&#xD;
      critical patients, defining as the absolute neutrophil count divided by the absolute&#xD;
      lymphocyte count. Over the last decade, NLR effectiveness has been recognized in various&#xD;
      pathologies, both benign and malignant; finding that the levels of neutrophils rise as a part&#xD;
      of the inflammatory cascade, whereas lymphocytes diminish during sepsis, making a novel&#xD;
      subclinical biomarker with a prognostic value in oncological, cardiovascular and infectious&#xD;
      diseases, among others. The NLR may be obtained from the blood count data, which represents a&#xD;
      lower cost regarding other known biomarkers. It was also demonstrated that high values of NLR&#xD;
      are associated with severe abdominal infections and worse outcomes, reason why it started to&#xD;
      be applied as a predictor to evaluate results in surgical patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Currently, the debate on usefulness of NLR as a predictor of complications in AD remains&#xD;
      open, specially, the relation to the severity of the disease, the clinical impact and the&#xD;
      necessity of minimally invasive or emergency surgical procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the other hand, its diagnostic efficacy has not been studied even in our field. Up until&#xD;
      now, there are only four studies published in Ireland, Israel, and South Korea. The purpose&#xD;
      of the study was to determine the usefulness and diagnostic accuracy of NLR in complicated&#xD;
      acute diverticulitis (cAD).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material and methods Study population A descriptive, retrospective cohort and analytical&#xD;
      study was undertaken. Medical histories and an electronic database from General Surgery&#xD;
      Service were reviewed. All the patients over the age of 18 with AD diagnosis through CT were&#xD;
      included, since January 2013 until January 2018 in a University Hospital of Cordoba,&#xD;
      Argentina, with third level reference.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients were excluded if they had chronic diseases, susceptible to modify the immune&#xD;
      inflammatory response, extra-abdominal infections, immunosuppression and neoplasias, and&#xD;
      those who supplied incomplete data in their electronic clinical histories.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study of variables Demographic variables (sex and age), days of inpatient stay, level of&#xD;
      severity in diverticular process (objectified by CT) were analyzed. It was recorded the value&#xD;
      of serum leukocyte, neutrophil, and lymphocyte concentration, Erythrocyte Sedimentation Rate&#xD;
      (ESR), CRP and NLR at the moment of consultation on call.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Variable definition NLR: It can be obtained from the blood count (the absolute neutrophil&#xD;
      count divided by the absolute lymphocyte count) CRP: normal value under 5 mg/l. Statistical&#xD;
      analysis The categorical variables were expressed as frequency (percentage), the continuous&#xD;
      variables as mean value (standard deviation, SD) or median (range) according to the&#xD;
      distribution of data; Mann Whitney test was used to compare the continuous variables,&#xD;
      Chi-square and Fisher's tests were used to compare categorical variables among patients with&#xD;
      simple acute diverticulitis (sAD) and cAD. A value of p&lt;0.05 was considered as statistically&#xD;
      significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ROC (Receiver Operating Characteristic) curves were used as diagnostic tests to evaluate the&#xD;
      diagnostic accuracy of NLR as predictor of complicated AD, determining sensitivity (Se),&#xD;
      specificity (Sp), positive predictive value (PPV) and negative predictive value (NPV). Youden&#xD;
      index was used to find the cut-off point with the best diagnostic yield for NLR in cAD. SPSS&#xD;
      26 software and GraphPad 7 software were used for statistical analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 1, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Demographic variables</measure>
    <time_frame>2013-2018</time_frame>
    <description>sex and age</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>inpatient stay</measure>
    <time_frame>2013-2018</time_frame>
    <description>days</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>level of severity in diverticular process</measure>
    <time_frame>2013-2018</time_frame>
    <description>confirmed by computed tomography</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>value of C-reactive protein</measure>
    <time_frame>2013-2018</time_frame>
    <description>normal value under 5 mg/l</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>value of Neutrophil to Lymphocyte Ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>2013-2018</time_frame>
    <description>It can be obtained from the blood count (the absolute neutrophil count divided by the absolute lymphocyte count)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">325</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Diverticulitis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>simple acute diverticulitis</arm_group_label>
    <description>Ninety-one percent (n=295) were categorized as simple acute diverticulitis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>complicated acute diverticulitis</arm_group_label>
    <description>9% (n=30) presented were categorized as complicated acute diverticulitis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Neutrophil to Lymphocyte Ratio</intervention_name>
    <description>Zahorec et al. identified the neutrophil-lymphocyte ratio (NLR) as an inflammation marker in critical patients, defining as the absolute neutrophil count divided by the absolute lymphocyte count</description>
    <arm_group_label>complicated acute diverticulitis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>simple acute diverticulitis</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        325 patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients older than 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a diagnosis of acute diverticulitis confirmed by computed tomography.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with hematological diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with extra abdominal infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with oncological diseases&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>92 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clínica Universitaria Reina Fabiola</name>
      <address>
        <city>Córdoba</city>
        <zip>5000</zip>
        <country>Argentina</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weizman AV, Nguyen GC. Diverticular disease: epidemiology and management. Can J Gastroenterol. 2011 Jul;25(7):385-9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21876861</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Feingold D, Steele SR, Lee S, Kaiser A, Boushey R, Buie WD, Rafferty JF. Practice parameters for the treatment of sigmoid diverticulitis. Dis Colon Rectum. 2014 Mar;57(3):284-94. doi: 10.1097/DCR.0000000000000075.</citation>
    <PMID>24509449</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Barat M, Dohan A, Pautrat K, Boudiaf M, Dautry R, Guerrache Y, Pocard M, Hoeffel C, Eveno C, Soyer P. Acute colonic diverticulitis: an update on clinical classification and management with MDCT correlation. Abdom Radiol (NY). 2016 Sep;41(9):1842-50. doi: 10.1007/s00261-016-0764-1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27138434</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wasvary H, Turfah F, Kadro O, Beauregard W. Same hospitalization resection for acute diverticulitis. Am Surg. 1999 Jul;65(7):632-5; discussion 636.</citation>
    <PMID>10399971</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bates DDB, Fernandez MB, Ponchiardi C, von Plato M, Teich JP, Narsule C, Anderson SW, Gupta A, LeBedis CA. Surgical management in acute diverticulitis and its association with multi-detector CT, modified Hinchey classification, and clinical parameters. Abdom Radiol (NY). 2018 Aug;43(8):2060-2065. doi: 10.1007/s00261-017-1422-y.</citation>
    <PMID>29204676</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Käser SA, Fankhauser G, Glauser PM, Toia D, Maurer CA. Diagnostic value of inflammation markers in predicting perforation in acute sigmoid diverticulitis. World J Surg. 2010 Nov;34(11):2717-22. doi: 10.1007/s00268-010-0726-7.</citation>
    <PMID>20645093</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zahorec R. Ratio of neutrophil to lymphocyte counts--rapid and simple parameter of systemic inflammation and stress in critically ill. Bratisl Lek Listy. 2001;102(1):5-14. English, Slovak.</citation>
    <PMID>11723675</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zahorec R. Neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio. Sixteen-year-long history since publication of our article in Bratislava Medical Journal. Bratisl Lek Listy. 2017;118(6):321-323. doi: 10.4149/BLL_2017_062.</citation>
    <PMID>28664739</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Miyamoto R, Inagawa S, Sano N, Tadano S, Adachi S, Yamamoto M. The neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio (NLR) predicts short-term and long-term outcomes in gastric cancer patients. Eur J Surg Oncol. 2018 May;44(5):607-612. doi: 10.1016/j.ejso.2018.02.003. Epub 2018 Feb 13.</citation>
    <PMID>29478743</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reynolds IS, Heaney RM, Khan W, Khan IZ, Waldron R, Barry K. The Utility of Neutrophil to Lymphocyte Ratio as a Predictor of Intervention in Acute Diverticulitis. Dig Surg. 2017;34(3):227-232. doi: 10.1159/000450836. Epub 2016 Dec 10.</citation>
    <PMID>27941316</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hogan J, Sehgal R, Murphy D, O'Leary P, Coffey JC. Do Inflammatory Indices Play a Role in Distinguishing between Uncomplicated and Complicated Diverticulitis? Dig Surg. 2017;34(1):7-11. Epub 2016 Jun 24.</citation>
    <PMID>27336407</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zager Y, Horesh N, Dan A, Aharoni M, Khalilieh S, Cordoba M, Nevler A, Gutman M, Rosin D. Associations of novel inflammatory markers with long-term outcomes and recurrence of diverticulitis. ANZ J Surg. 2020 Oct;90(10):2041-2045. doi: 10.1111/ans.16220. Epub 2020 Aug 28.</citation>
    <PMID>32856387</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mari A, Khoury T, Lubany A, Safadi M, Farraj M, Farah A, Kadah A, Sbeit W, Mahamid M. Neutrophil-to-Lymphocyte and Platelet-to-Lymphocyte Ratios Are Correlated with Complicated Diverticulitis and Hinchey Classification: A Simple Tool to Assess Disease Severity in the Emergency Department. Emerg Med Int. 2019 Aug 14;2019:6321060. doi: 10.1155/2019/6321060. eCollection 2019.</citation>
    <PMID>31485352</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kang HS, Cha YS, Park KH, Hwang SO. Delta neutrophil index as a promising prognostic marker of emergent surgical intervention for acute diverticulitis in the emergency department. PLoS One. 2017 Nov 1;12(11):e0187629. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0187629. eCollection 2017.</citation>
    <PMID>29091955</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Agha RA, Borrelli MR, Vella-Baldacchino M, Thavayogan R, Orgill DP; STROCSS Group. The STROCSS statement: Strengthening the Reporting of Cohort Studies in Surgery. Int J Surg. 2017 Oct;46:198-202. doi: 10.1016/j.ijsu.2017.08.586. Epub 2017 Sep 7.</citation>
    <PMID>28890409</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jeon TJ, Park JY. Clinical significance of the neutrophil-lymphocyte ratio as an early predictive marker for adverse outcomes in patients with acute pancreatitis. World J Gastroenterol. 2017 Jun 7;23(21):3883-3889. doi: 10.3748/wjg.v23.i21.3883.</citation>
    <PMID>28638228</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bharucha AE, Parthasarathy G, Ditah I, Fletcher JG, Ewelukwa O, Pendlimari R, Yawn BP, Melton LJ, Schleck C, Zinsmeister AR. Temporal Trends in the Incidence and Natural History of Diverticulitis: A Population-Based Study. Am J Gastroenterol. 2015 Nov;110(11):1589-96. doi: 10.1038/ajg.2015.302. Epub 2015 Sep 29.</citation>
    <PMID>26416187</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 30, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 6, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 6, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 6, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Clinica Universitaria Reina Fabiola, Universidad Catolica de Cordoba</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Palacios Huatuco</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>General Surgeon</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio</keyword>
  <keyword>C-reactive protein</keyword>
  <keyword>biomarkers</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diverticulitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Due to the sensitive nature of the study, patients were assured that the raw data would remain confidential and would not be shared.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

