<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04664777</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Inonu universitesi</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04664777</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Correlation of Non Invasive Hemoglobin Measurement With Laboratory Hemoglobin Measurement in Living Liver Donors</brief_title>
  <official_title>Intraoperative Correlation of Non Invasive Hemoglobin (SpHb) Measurement With Laboratory Hemoglobin Measurement in Living Liver Donors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Inonu University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Inonu University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Pulse CO-Oximetry (Masimo Corp, Irvine, CA, USA) is a method that allows non-invasive&#xD;
      continuous hemoglobin (Hb) measurement. This technology measures continuous Hb with a&#xD;
      multi-wavelength spectrophotometric fingertip sensor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim of investigators in this study is to make continuous Hb measurement with Pulse&#xD;
      CO-Oximetry method in living liver donors, to compare these measurements with the laboratory&#xD;
      results routinely taken during the operation, to determine the level of correlation for this&#xD;
      patient group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Continuous Hb measurement with Pulse CO-Oximetry (SpHb) can be usefull for living liver donor&#xD;
      and improve the quality of intraoperative care. This technology measures continuous Hb with a&#xD;
      multi-wavelength spectrophotometric fingertip sensor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The perfusion index (PI) is the ratio of the pulsatile blood flow to the nonpulsatile or&#xD;
      static blood in peripheral tissue. Perfusion Index thus represents a noninvasive measure of&#xD;
      peripheral perfusion that can be continuously and noninvasively obtained from a pulse&#xD;
      oximeter. Changes in PI can also occur as a result of local vasoconstriction (decrease in PI)&#xD;
      or vasodilatation (increase in PI) in the skin at the monitoring site. These changes occur&#xD;
      with changes in the volumeof oxygenated bloodflow in the skin microvasculature. PI values can&#xD;
      change due to surgical process and may affect SpHb measurement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim of investigators in this study is to make continuous Hb measurement with Pulse&#xD;
      CO-Oximetry method in living liver donors before and after surgery incision, to compare these&#xD;
      measurements with the laboratory results routinely taken during the operation, to determine&#xD;
      the level of correlation for this patient group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 15, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Day</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CHb</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 14 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between non-invazive Hb measurement (measured by the masimo monitoring platform) and laboratuar Hb level.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CPIS</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 14 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between Perfusion index (measured by the masimo monitoring platform) and surgery</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">55</enrollment>
  <condition>Anesthesia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group1</arm_group_label>
    <description>Living liver donors who operated between 1 August and 15 november:&#xD;
After anesthesia induction and surgical field sterilization, before surgical incision; blood sample will be taken, SpHb, PI and vital measurements (SpO2, Heart rate, NIBP, body temperature) will be recorded.&#xD;
After the surgical procedure is over and before the patient is awakened from anesthesia; blood sample will be taken, SpHb, PI and vital measurements (SpO2, Heart rate, NIBP, body temperature) will be recorded.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Masimo Model RDS7A</intervention_name>
    <description>Masimo monitoring platform equipped with Radical-7 Pulse CO-Oximeter fingertip probe for measurement non-invazive hemoglobin level (SpHb) an perfusion index (PI)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        According to ASA physical status classification system ASA 1-2 cases scheduled for&#xD;
        hepatectomy for liver transplantation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients undergoing hepatectomy with general anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient's lack of consent, essential data missing, patient participating in other&#xD;
             research projects, drug allergy, anesthetic complication story, excessive surgical&#xD;
             bleeding, presence of disease that impairs peripheral circulation, use of vasoactive&#xD;
             agents.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Inonu Univercity</name>
      <address>
        <city>Malatya</city>
        <zip>44280</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 30, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 7, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 7, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 7, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Inonu University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Yusuf Ziya ÇOLAK</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Asst. Prof. Yusuf Ziya Çolak</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>hemoglobin level</keyword>
  <keyword>Pulse CO-Oximetry</keyword>
  <keyword>intraoperative</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

