<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04660409</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ADROPINHCC- HMO-CTIL</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04660409</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Assessment of the Correlation Between Serum Levels of Adropin and Degree of Severity of Chronic Liver Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Assessment of the Correlation Between Serum Levels of Adropin and Degree of Severity of Chronic Liver Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hadassah Medical Organization</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hadassah Medical Organization</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Injury to the liver parenchyma associated with an influx of acute or chronic inflammatory&#xD;
      cells is termed hepatitis. Cirrhosis refers to a progressive, diffuse, fibrosing, nodular&#xD;
      condition that disrupts the entire normal architecture of the liver. Patients with chronic&#xD;
      liver disease have sustained hepatic inflammation, fibrosis, and aberrant hepatocyte&#xD;
      regeneration. These abnormalities can cause cirrhosis and favor a series of genetic and&#xD;
      epigenetic events that culminate in the formation of dysplastic nodules, which are actually&#xD;
      preneoplastic lesions . Hepatocellular carcinoma can also arise in patients who have chronic&#xD;
      liver disease but does not have established cirrhosis or marked inflammation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The &quot;gold standard&quot; for evaluation and follow up of liver fibrosis and cirrhosis is liver&#xD;
      biopsy. It's a costly procedure with risks of severe complications, with sampling error and&#xD;
      problematic long term follow up. Non-invasive tools are broadly used with good results, but&#xD;
      none of the commonly used methods is perfect. In one meta-analysis, different methods were&#xD;
      compared for diagnosis of cirrhosis in Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) patients.&#xD;
      For example (sensitivity; specificity): APRI (56.2% ;83.6%), FibroScan M Probe (78.2%;&#xD;
      90.8%), MRE (86.6%; 93.4%) . Child-Pugh classification and model for end-stage liver disease&#xD;
      (MELD) scores are used as measures for assessment of degree of severity of liver disease.&#xD;
      These models have some drawbacks; Ascites and encephalopathy included in Child-Pugh&#xD;
      classification are subjective and may be variable according to the physician's judgment and&#xD;
      the use of diuretics and lactulose. INR which appears in both methods does not sufficiently&#xD;
      reflect coagulopathy and liver function and is also variable throughout different&#xD;
      laboratories. Both are not sensitive enough for short interval periods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One of the major complications of cirrhosis and chronic hepatitis is Hepatocellular carcinoma&#xD;
      (HCC). Most guidelines recommend cirrhotic patients to undergo abdominal ultrasound every 6&#xD;
      much to detect HCC, given the expected tumor growth rate in the target population. Although&#xD;
      widely use, the combination of ultrasound (US) with Alpha fetoprotein (AFP) is not&#xD;
      recommended for surveillance in patients with active liver inflammation as the 6-8% gain in&#xD;
      the detection rate does not counterbalance the increase in false positive results. Like in&#xD;
      previous issues, a specific, cost effective marker is still needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adropin is a 76-amino-acids secreted peptide, which is encoded by the Enho gene. The exact&#xD;
      physiological role of Adropin in the liver is unknown. However, high levels of Adropin are&#xD;
      correlated with low incidence of Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus, higher levels of HDL cholesterol,&#xD;
      lower body-mass index (BMI), LDL cholesterol, Triglyceride levels and blood pressure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Obesity has been recognized long ago as a significant risk factor for developing cancer and&#xD;
      is an independent risk factor for HCC in patients with alcoholic (odds ratio 3.2) and&#xD;
      cryptogenic (odds ratio 11.1) cirrhosis Serum Adropin levels were decreased and negatively&#xD;
      correlated with liver injury in non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH) mice. Knockout of&#xD;
      Adropin significantly exacerbated hepatic steatosis, inflammatory responses and fibrosis in&#xD;
      mice. Furthermore, the treatment with Adropin bioactive peptides slowed NASH progression in&#xD;
      mice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In search for a good diagnostic and prognostic marker in patients with liver disease, Adropin&#xD;
      should be further investigated in humans.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this Open-label, single-center study, 50 adults (&gt;18) male and female with any degree of&#xD;
      chronic liver disease will undergo a single blood test for serum levels of Adropin. Levels&#xD;
      will be measured using ELISA technique. The results will be compared with the Child Pugh and&#xD;
      MELD scores, liver enzymes, lipid profile, coagulation factors and fibroscan results based on&#xD;
      the patients' clinical data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 25, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>correlation between degree of severity of chronic liver disease and serum adropin levels.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>correlation between degree of severity of chronic liver disease and serum adropin levels.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Liver Disease and Cirrhosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Child Pugh A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Child Pugh B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Child Pugh C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HCC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Blood test for serum Adropin</intervention_name>
    <description>Blood test for serum Adropin</description>
    <arm_group_label>Child Pugh A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Child Pugh B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Child Pugh C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>HCC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ages Eligible for Study: 18 Years to 80 Years (Adult) Sexes Eligible for Study: All&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Diagnosis of chronic liver disease of any etiology.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Females of childbearing potential must be non-pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. No known history of significant neurological, renal, cardiovascular, respiratory&#xD;
                  (asthma), endocrinological, gastrointestinal, primary hematopoietic disease,&#xD;
                  neoplasm, or any other clinically significant medical disorder other than liver&#xD;
                  disease and the metabolic syndrome in patients with NASH.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Patients must satisfy a medical examiner about their fitness to participate in&#xD;
                  the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Patients must provide written informed consent to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - 1. Patients with evidence of other serious infectious, autoimmune, hepatic, nephritic or&#xD;
        systemic disease or compromised organ function except for the metabolic syndrome in&#xD;
        patients with NASH.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Patients with any acute medical situation (e.g. acute infection) within 48 hours of&#xD;
        blood tests.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yotam Kolben</last_name>
    <phone>+972507866767</phone>
    <email>yotamkol@hadassah.org.il</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hadassah medical center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jerusalem</city>
        <zip>91120</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yotam Kolben</last_name>
      <phone>0507866767</phone>
      <email>yotamkol@hadassah.org.il</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 8, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 8, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hadassah Medical Organization</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Yotam Kolben</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principle Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

