<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00408369</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>C06-015</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00408369</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prophylactic Antimalarial Activity of DB289 in Volunteers</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prophylactic Antimalarial Activity of DB289 in Volunteers Challenged With Plasmodium Falciparum</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Immtech Pharmaceuticals, Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Immtech Pharmaceuticals, Inc</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the prophylactic activity of orally administered DB289 against Plasmodium&#xD;
      falciparum in non-immune healthy volunteers who are challenged by the bite of five P.&#xD;
      falciparum-infected Anopheles stephensi mosquitoes&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary endpoint of this study is the appearance of erythrocytic parasites (parasitemia),&#xD;
      which indicates a prophylaxis failure. Parasitemia will be sought by multiple means,&#xD;
      including blood culture, polymerase chain reaction (PCR), Quantitative Buffy Coat (QBC)&#xD;
      analysis, and thick and thin blood smears (detailed methods,Appendix II).&#xD;
&#xD;
      QBC and giemsa-stained blood smears will be analyzed in real time and a positive result in&#xD;
      any one of them is sufficient to initiate chloroquine treatment. All positive QBC analyses or&#xD;
      blood smears will be confirmed by two experienced observers. On smears, the location of&#xD;
      parasites will be recorded using a stage micrometer, and slides will be archived and&#xD;
      available for later re-examination. PCR samples will be collected and stored for later&#xD;
      analysis; cultures will be inoculated at once and maintained for 70 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A positive result in any one of these tests constitutes a drug failure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 2007</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 2007</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary endpoint of this study is the appearance of erythrocytic parasites</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>(parasitemia), which indicates a prophylaxis failure. Parasitemia will be sought by</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>multiple means, including blood culture, polymerase chain reaction (PCR), Quantitative</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Buffy Coat (QBC) analysis, and thick and thin blood smears (detailed methods,</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Appendix II).</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To distinguish the mechanism of prophylaxis: causal vs suppressive</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the pharmacokinetics of DB289 and DB75</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the safety of DB289</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">19</enrollment>
  <condition>Prophylactic Activity Against Malaria</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>DB289</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age between 18 and 45 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI between 19 and 30 (Appendix IV)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide home address and phone number; work description, address, and phone&#xD;
             number; and to provide the name, address, and phone number of a person willing and&#xD;
             able to assist the investigators in making contact with the cognate volunteer during&#xD;
             the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to follow-up intensively for 3 months of scheduled visits&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Post-menopausal or surgically sterilized women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Score of 80% or more on a written exam to test malaria knowledge and comprehension of&#xD;
             the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum and red cells support growth of P. falciparum in vitro (Appendix V)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood type A or O&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to provide written informed consent for screening, HIV testing, and&#xD;
             study participation-&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant abnormalities on screening examinations&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST, ALT, bilirubin, hemoglobin, hematocrit, prothrombin time, partial&#xD;
                  thromboplastin time, or creatinine outside the limits of normal as defined at the&#xD;
                  time of testing by the Johns Hopkins Medical Laboratories&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  laboratory evidence of HIV infection or active viral hepatitis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  G6PD deficiency, or hemoglobin S or C&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Significant medical illnesses requiring systemic treatment and/or hospitalization&#xD;
                  within one month of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of chronic medical illnesses, significant in the investigators' judgment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Self-described use of tobacco&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of alcohol or drug abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Use of prescribed or over-the-counter medications or nutritional supplements&#xD;
                  within two weeks of enrollment (vitamins, at or below the daily recommended dose,&#xD;
                  may be taken during the study)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women of childbearing potential&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Blood or plasma donation within 2 weeks of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of malaria or residence in a malaria-endemic area&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Allergy to mosquito bites&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intolerance to chloroquine, Malarone, quinine, quinidine, or tetracycline&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Taken anti-infective drugs or quinine-containing beverages in the week prior to&#xD;
                  enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Currently participating in other clinical trials, participated in a drug trial&#xD;
                  within two weeks of enrollment, or plan to participate in another clinical trial&#xD;
                  within three months from challenge&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any factors for which the investigator believes that participation of the&#xD;
                  volunteer in the study is not appropriate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Theresa A. Shapiro, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Johns Hopkins University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21205-2186</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2008</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 4, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 4, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 6, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 25, 2008</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 25, 2008</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 29, 2008</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>prophylactic</keyword>
  <keyword>malaria</keyword>
  <keyword>challenge</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pafuramidine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

