<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04395898</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EX-24-10-19-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04395898</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pancreaticoduodenectomy: Outcomes of a Complex Surgical Procedure From a Developing Country</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pancreaticoduodenectomy: Outcomes of a Complex Surgical Procedure From a Developing Country</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Shaukat Khanum Memorial Cancer Hospital &amp; Research Centre</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Shaukat Khanum Memorial Cancer Hospital &amp; Research Centre</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      ABSTRACT&#xD;
&#xD;
      BACKGROUND Pancreaticoduodenectomy (PD) plays an integral part in the management of&#xD;
      pancreatic, periampullary and duodenal cancers along with few other pathologies of this&#xD;
      region. Despite advances in surgery PD continues to have significant morbidity and noteworthy&#xD;
      mortality. The aim of this study is to provide an in-depth report on the patient&#xD;
      characteristics, indications and the outcomes of PD) in a tertiary cancer hospital in&#xD;
      Pakistan.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MATERIALS AND METHODS:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study population included patients who underwent PD between January 1st 2014 and march&#xD;
      31st 2019, at Shaukat Khanum Memorial Cancer Hospital and Research Centre (SKMCH&amp;RC) in&#xD;
      Pakistan. The Data was retrospectively analyzed from the Hospital Information System (HIS),&#xD;
      which is a prospectively maintained patient electronic database of SKMCH&amp;RC. Patient&#xD;
      characteristics, procedural details and post-operative outcomes according to internationally&#xD;
      accepted definitions were reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      KEYWORDS: Whipple's procedure, Pancreaticoduodenectomy, Pancreaticogastrostomy, lower middle&#xD;
      income, pancreatic fistula, periampullary cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      INTRODUCTION:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pancreatic cancer is one of the most common cancer worldwide and ranks 7th as the leading&#xD;
      cause of death among all cancers.The estimated 5 year survival of pancreatic cancer is very&#xD;
      poor i.e. 5%. Apart from cancer there is a plethora of benign and pre-malignant pancreatic&#xD;
      lesions that can manifest symptoms in patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgery plays an integral part in the management of pancreatic lesions.&#xD;
      Pancreaticoduodenectomy (PD) is a considered to be one of the most complex and morbid&#xD;
      surgical procedures. The first case series published by Allan Whipple in 1935 reported the&#xD;
      procedure related mortality in excess of 25 percent. With the advancements in surgical&#xD;
      techniques, perioperative and critical care management, mortality rate has dropped down to&#xD;
      less than 5 percent in high volume centers. However, morbidity remains high with some studies&#xD;
      reporting up to 70 percent .&#xD;
&#xD;
      There have been some studies, with small cohort and limited follow up periods, reporting on&#xD;
      outcomes of PD in Pakistan .To our knowledge, no published study has focused on detailed&#xD;
      surgical outcomes and long term follow up. We do not know the long term outcomes after PD in&#xD;
      Pakistan and most information is based on a western literature which may not be applicable to&#xD;
      a Pakistani cohort of patients. SKMCH&amp;RC being a dedicated cancer centre and tertiary care&#xD;
      hospital of the country receives a high number of referrals of patients requiring this&#xD;
      complex procedure in Pakistan.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Every patient that is referred to our hospital has a detailed history and examination in the&#xD;
      walk-in clinic. Every case undergoes a pancreatic protocol Computerised Tomograph scan(CT)&#xD;
      and where appropriate interventions like Endoscopic Retrograde Cholangiography (ERCP) with or&#xD;
      without stent placement, Endoscopic Ultra-sound or Percutaneous Trans-hepatic Cholangiogram&#xD;
      (PTC) are undertaken. Every case is discussed in our Multi-Disciplinary Team (MDT) meeting&#xD;
      comprising of trained hepatobiliary surgeons, gastroenterologists, diagnostic and&#xD;
      interventional radiologists, pathologists, medical and radiation oncologists. Patients with&#xD;
      border-line operable confirmed pancreatic cancers undergo neo-adjuvant treatment, whereas&#xD;
      resectable lesions undergo upfront PD.investigators work at a paperless hospital and all&#xD;
      patient data is put real time into a computerised Hospital Information System (HIS) by all&#xD;
      cadres including nurses, allied health professionals and doctors. The hospital has a unique&#xD;
      in-house developed computerised patient management system (HIS) that collects all patient&#xD;
      information in real time including patient demographics, investigations, Multi-Disciplinary&#xD;
      Team discussions, Nursing assessments, outpatient, operative notes and post- operative&#xD;
      outcomes. As the data is collected in real time and stored, it allows for accurate&#xD;
      retrospective review of the data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to provide a detailed analysis of the patient characteristics,&#xD;
      indications, post-operative and intermediate term outcomes for PD in a Pakistani cohort of&#xD;
      patients. This will provide a reference point for physicians when they counsel their patients&#xD;
      regarding PD outcomes in Pakistan and also help define areas of potential improvement in the&#xD;
      future.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODOLOGY:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients undergoing PD from 1st January 2014 till 31st March 2019 at SKMCH&amp;RC, Pakistan&#xD;
      were retrospectively evaluated from a prospectively maintained database using the HIS system.&#xD;
      The cohort of patients selected included malignant, pre-malignant and benign pathologies.&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria included patients that did not undergo PD after exploratory laparotomy due&#xD;
      to metastatic disease or with involvement of celiac, superior mesenteric or hepatic arteries.&#xD;
      The ethical approval was sought from Institutional Review Board (IRB) of SKMCH &amp; RC vide&#xD;
      number EX-24-10-19-01.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Variables:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Variables recorded were age, gender, co-morbidities, American-Society of Anesthesiologists&#xD;
      score (ASA), pre-operative histopathology, clinical staging, surgical details, post-operative&#xD;
      complications, mortality (30 &amp; 90 day), length of stay, and survival outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pancreatic fistula was recorded as defined by ISGPF 2016 updated criteria.&#xD;
      Post-Pancreatectomy Hemorrhage (PPH) was recorded as defined by International Study Group on&#xD;
      Pancreatic Surgery (ISGPS) 2007 classification. Morbidity was recorded according to&#xD;
      Clavien-Dindo classification.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analyses:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Calculations were performed with Statistical Package for the Social Sciences (SPSS Ver20) for&#xD;
      Windows. Data was described using median with minimum and maximum value for skewly&#xD;
      distributed quantitative variables. For categorical variables, number of observations and&#xD;
      percentages were reported. For survival analyses Kaplan-Miere Curve was applied. The study is&#xD;
      in compliance with the SKMCH&amp;RC guidelines on research involving human subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ETHICAL APPROVAL:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethical approval was obtained from Institutional Review Board (IRB) of Shaukat Khanum&#xD;
      Memorial Cancer Hospital and Research Centre, prior to the commencement of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PATIENTS' CONSENT:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Informed consent was taken from every patient about data collection, analysis and research&#xD;
      publication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DECLARATIONS OF INTEREST:&#xD;
&#xD;
      None&#xD;
&#xD;
      FUNDING:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The research did not receive any specific grant from funding agencies in the public,&#xD;
      commercial, or not-for-profit sectors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 15, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 4, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>disease free and overall survival</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Morbidity</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>morbidity was defined according to Clavien-Dindo classification</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>recurrence</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>recurrence is defined as return of the cancer after initial curative or definitive treatment, can be local or distant</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">161</enrollment>
  <condition>Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>pancreaticoduodenectomy</intervention_name>
    <description>Whipple's procedure</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Pancreatic cancer.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        all patients whose surgeries were done from January 2014 to March 2019&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        None as such&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>78 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Farah Rasheed</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Clinical research officer</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Shaukat Khanam Memorial Cancer Hospital and Research Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lahore</city>
        <state>Punjab</state>
        <zip>54000</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 20, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 15, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 15, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 20, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Shaukat Khanum Memorial Cancer Hospital &amp; Research Centre</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>aun jamal</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Fellow in Surgical Oncology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>will see</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>will see</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>that will be discussed with the hospital IRB and later we will see wether it has to be shared</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

