<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04392505</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DART</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04392505</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Durvalumab(MEDI4736) After chemoRadioTherapy(DART) for NSCLC-a Translational and Biomarker Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>DART</acronym>
  <official_title>Durvalumab (MEDI4736) After chemoRadioTherapy (DART) for NSCLC Patients - a Phase II Translational and Biomarker Study Investigating PDL1 Positive and Negative Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Oslo University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Oslo University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main aim is to identify and describe biomarkers in different sample types related to&#xD;
      chemoradiation followed by durvalumab treatment for stage III PD-L1 negative and positive&#xD;
      non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) patients' eligible for curatively intended chemoradiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis is that clinical differences in course of disease reflect underlying&#xD;
      biological characteristics.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an open, multinational, phase 2 trial to investigate the Properties of cancer cells&#xD;
      before, during and after treatment with the investigational study drug durvalumab in patients&#xD;
      with locally advanced non-small celled lung cancer (NSCLC). Both patients with high and low&#xD;
      PD-L1 expression are allowed to participate. Durvalumab (PD-L1 inhibitor) will be&#xD;
      administered after a period with standardtreatment with chemotherapy and radiationtherapy&#xD;
      (chemoradiotherapy) for around 7 weeks. After maximum 5 weeks break after chemoradiotherapy,&#xD;
      durvalumab will be given in the same dose to all patients for up to 12 months. The follow-up&#xD;
      include a safety follow-up for up to five years, followed by a survival follow-up for up to a&#xD;
      total of ten years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main aim is to identify and describe biomarkers in different sample types related to&#xD;
      chemoradiation followed by durvalumab treatment for stage III PD-L1 negative and positive&#xD;
      non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) patients' eligible for curatively intended chemoradiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis is that clinical differences in course of disease reflect underlying&#xD;
      biological characteristics.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 11, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2032</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>open, exploratory, multinational, phase 2 trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact of tumour mutational burden (TMB) measured in the tumour tissue and blood samples, on the hazard.</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout study, up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Analyses of TMB in tumour tissue. Patients with high Tumour Mutational Burden, TMB (&gt; 8.5 mutations per megabase) have a hazard ratio equal to or less than 0.55 as compared to patients with low TMB. Tumor tissue will be analysed in regard to TMB, and several different cut-offs will be evaluated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Predict assosiation between Tumour Mutational Burden, TMB, measured in tumour tissue and blood samples and clinical response</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study, up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>To investigate different levels of TMB in tumor tissue compared to blood samples, as predictors for development of clinical response</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Specific RNA profiles predict response to treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study, up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>transcriptome characterization (RNA-sequencing) on tumour material to investigate this</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact of Molecular profiles in urine on response to treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study, up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>To investigate urine for predictive biomarkers (ctDNA, miRNA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Analysis of pre-treatment and under-treatment samples may identify biomarkers for predicting which patients will benefit from treatment with durvalumab after chemoradiation</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study, up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Analyses of biomarkers in tumour tissue.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The durvalumab treatment following chemoradiation will induce T cell responses against antigens expressed in each patient´s tumor.</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study, up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Immunological response assessment performed on tumour material from participants.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>A possible change in PD-L1 status will be explored</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study, up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Immunohistochemistry of PD-L1 assessed on tumour tissue.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The durvalumab treatment following chemoradiation has acceptable safety and tolerability in NSCLC patients, as assessed by Patient Reported Outcome measurements.</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study, up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported outcome measurements by standardized Tools; EORTC-QLQ-C30 and LC13.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The gut microbiome influence the responses to chemoradiation followed by durvalumab</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study, up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Genetic analyses on feces samples, by use of feces &quot;Cards&quot;.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Non Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Non Small Cell Lung Cancer Stage III</condition>
  <condition>NSCLC</condition>
  <condition>NSCLC, Stage III</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The whole study population</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients will receive durvalumab for up to 1 months after standard treatment With chemoradiotherapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Durvalumab Injection</intervention_name>
    <description>Included patients will receive durvalumab (fixed dose, 1500mg Q4W) until progressive disease and no clinical benefit, intolerable toxicity or patient's wish, for a maximum duration of 12 months. Treatment with durvalumab should start &lt;5 weeks after last radiotherapy dosing.</description>
    <arm_group_label>The whole study population</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Imfinzi</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Locally-advanced, unresectable, stage III NSCLC (including PET-CT and MRI-brain in the&#xD;
             diagnostic work-up).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Capable of giving signed informed consent which includes compliance with the&#xD;
             requirements and restrictions listed in the informed consent form (ICF) and in this&#xD;
             protocol. Written informed consent and any locally required authorization (European&#xD;
             Union [EU] Data Privacy Directive in the EU) obtained from the patient/legal&#xD;
             representative prior to performing any protocol-related procedures, including&#xD;
             screening evaluations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Diagnostic biopsy with PD-L1 &lt;1% in 50 patients PD-L1 ≥1% in 50 patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Adequate core or excisional biopsy for tumor assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Age &gt; 18 years at time of study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Body weight &gt;30 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Adequate normal organ and marrow function as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
             - Haemoglobin ≥9.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) 1.5 x (&gt; 1500 per mm3)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count ≥100 x 109/L (&gt;75,000 per mm3)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum bilirubin ≤1.5 x institutional upper limit of normal (ULN).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST (SGOT)/ALT (SGPT) ≤2.5 x institutional upper limit of normal unless liver&#xD;
                  metastases are present, in which case it must be ≤5x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Measured creatinine clearance (CL) &gt;40 mL/min or Calculated creatinine CL&gt;40&#xD;
                  mL/min by the Cockcroft-Gault formula (Cockcroft and Gault 1976) or by 24-hour&#xD;
                  urine collection for determination of creatinine clearance:&#xD;
&#xD;
             Males:&#xD;
&#xD;
             - Creatinine CL (mL/min) = Weight (kg) x (140 - Age) 72 x serum creatinine (mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
             Females:&#xD;
&#xD;
             - Creatinine CL (mL/min) = Weight (kg) x (140 - Age) x 0.85 72 x serum creatinine&#xD;
             (mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Evidence of post-menopausal status or negative urinary or serum pregnancy test for&#xD;
             female pre-menopausal patients. Women will be considered post-menopausal if they have&#xD;
             been amenorrheic for 12 months without an alternative medical cause.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) should have a negative urine or serum&#xD;
             pregnancy within 7 days prior to receiving the firs dose of study medication. If the&#xD;
             urine test is positive or cannot be confirmed as negative, a serum pregnancy test will&#xD;
             be required. A woman is considered as WOCBP, i.e. fertile, following menarche and&#xD;
             until becoming post-menopausal unless permanently sterile. Permanent sterilisation&#xD;
             methods include hysterectomy, bilateral salpingectomy and bilateral oophorectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. WOCBP should use an adequate method to avoid pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. males who are sexually active with women of childbearing potential must agree to&#xD;
             follow instructions for method(s) of contraception for a period of 90 days (duration&#xD;
             of sperm turnover) / the time required for the investigational drug to undergo five&#xD;
             half-lives&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patient is willing and able to comply with the protocol for the duration of the study&#xD;
             including undergoing treatment and scheduled visits and examinations including follow&#xD;
             up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Non-small cell lung cancer disease suitable for curative surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Significant cardiac, pulmonary or other medical illness that would limit activity or&#xD;
             survival&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Concurrent enrolment in another clinical study, unless it is an observational&#xD;
             (non-interventional) clinical study or during the follow-up period of an&#xD;
             interventional study during the last 2 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Any concurrent chemotherapy, Investigational Product (IP), biologic, or hormonal&#xD;
             therapy for cancer treatment. Concurrent use of hormonal therapy for&#xD;
             non-cancer-related conditions (e.g., hormone replacement therapy) is acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Major surgical procedure (as defined by the Investigator) within 28 days prior to the&#xD;
             first dose of IP. Note: Local surgery of isolated lesions for palliative intent is&#xD;
             acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of allogenic organ transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Active or prior documented autoimmune or inflammatory disorders (including&#xD;
             inflammatory bowel disease [e.g., colitis or Crohn's disease], diverticulitis [with&#xD;
             the exception of diverticulosis], systemic lupus erythematosus, Sarcoidosis syndrome,&#xD;
             or Wegener syndrome [granulomatosis with polyangiitis, Graves' disease, rheumatoid&#xD;
             arthritis, hypophysitis, uveitis, etc]). The following are exceptions to this&#xD;
             criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with vitiligo or alopecia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with hypothyroidism (e.g., following Hashimoto syndrome) stableon&#xD;
                  hormone replacement&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any chronic skin condition that does not require systemic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients without active disease in the last 5 years may be included but only&#xD;
                  after consultation with the study physician&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with celiac disease controlled by diet alone&#xD;
&#xD;
        i. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness, including but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
        infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, uncontrolled hypertension, unstable angina&#xD;
        pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, interstitial lung disease, serious chronic gastrointestinal&#xD;
        conditions associated with diarrhea, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would&#xD;
        limit compliance with study requirement, substantially increase risk of incurring AEs or&#xD;
        compromise the ability of the patient to give written informed consent j. History of&#xD;
        another primary malignancy except for&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Malignancy treated with curative intent and with no known active disease ≥5 years&#xD;
             before the first dose of IP and of low potential risk for recurrence&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequately treated non-melanoma skin cancer or lentigo maligna without evidence of&#xD;
             disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequately treated carcinoma in situ without evidence of disease k. History of active&#xD;
             primary immunodeficiency or medical condition requiring high doses (&gt;30 mg&#xD;
             prednisolone daily) of systemic steroids or other forms of immunosuppressive therapy&#xD;
             l. Active infection including tuberculosis (clinical evaluation that includes clinical&#xD;
             history, physical examination and radiographic findings, and TB testing in line with&#xD;
             local practice), hepatitis B (known positive HBV surface antigen (HBsAg) result), and&#xD;
             hepatitis C. Patients with a past or resolved HBV infection (defined as the presence&#xD;
             of hepatitis B core antibody [anti-HBc] and absence of HBsAg) are eligible. Patients&#xD;
             positive for hepatitis C (HCV) antibody are eligible only if polymerase chain reaction&#xD;
             is negative for HCV RNA.&#xD;
&#xD;
             m. Current or prior use of immunosuppressive medication within 14 days before the&#xD;
             first dose of durvalumab. The following are exceptions to this criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intranasal, inhaled, topical steroids, or local steroid injections (e.g., intra&#xD;
             articular injection)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic corticosteroids at physiologic doses not to exceed 10 mg/day of prednisone or&#xD;
             its equivalent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Steroids as premedication for hypersensitivity reactions (e.g., CT scan premedication)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of live attenuated vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose of IP. Note:&#xD;
             Patients, if enrolled, should not receive live vaccine whilst receiving IP and up to&#xD;
             30 days after the last dose of IP.&#xD;
&#xD;
             n. Female patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding or male or female patients of&#xD;
             reproductive potential who are not willing to employ effective birth control from&#xD;
             screening to 90 days after the last dose of durvalumab monotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
             o. Known allergy or hypersensitivity to any of the study drugs or any of the study&#xD;
             drug excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
             p. Prior randomisation or treatment in a previous durvalumab clinical study regardless&#xD;
             of treatment arm assignment.&#xD;
&#xD;
             q. Judgement by the investigator that the patient is unsuitable to participate in the&#xD;
             study and the patient is unlikely to comply with study procedures, restrictions and&#xD;
             requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
             r. Patients with grade ≥2 neuropathy will be evaluated on a case-by-case basis after&#xD;
             consultation with the Study physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
             s. Patients with irreverible toxicity not reasonably expected to be exacerbated by&#xD;
             treatment with durvalumab may be included only after consulation with the Study&#xD;
             Physician.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Åslaug Helland, Prof, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Oslo University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Åslaug Helland, Prof, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+47 22934000</phone>
    <email>ahh@ous-hf.no</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Vilde D. Haakensen, MD</last_name>
    <email>vdd@ous-hf.no</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>North Estonia Medical Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tallinn</city>
        <country>Estonia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kersti Oselin, MD</last_name>
      <email>kersi.oselin@regionaalhaigla.ee</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oulu University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oulu</city>
        <country>Finland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jussi Koivunen, MD</last_name>
      <email>jussi.koivunen@ppshp.fi</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tampere University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampere</city>
        <zip>33520</zip>
        <country>Finland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jarkko Ahvonen, PhD</last_name>
      <email>jarkko.ahvonen@pshp.fi</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Turku University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Turku</city>
        <country>Finland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maria Silvionemi, PhD</last_name>
      <email>maria.silvionemi@tyks.fi</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Kirsi Penttilä</last_name>
      <email>kirsi.penttila@tyks.fi</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vilnius</city>
        <country>Lithuania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Saulius Cicenas, MD</last_name>
      <email>saulius.cicenas@nvi.lt</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Haukeland universitetssykehus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bergen</city>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marianne Aanerud, MD</last_name>
      <email>marianne.aanerud@helse-bergen.no</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oslo University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oslo</city>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Åslaug Helland, MD, PhD, Prof</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stavanger University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stavanger</city>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tesfaye Madebo</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitetssykehuset i Nord-Norge</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tromsø</city>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nina Helbekkmo, MD</last_name>
      <email>nina.helbekkmo@unn.no</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Olavs Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Trondheim</city>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Bjørn Henning Grønberg, MD</last_name>
      <email>bjorn.h.gronberg@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Estonia</country>
    <country>Finland</country>
    <country>Lithuania</country>
    <country>Norway</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 8, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 12, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Oslo University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Åslaug Helland</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prof, MD, Head of Research</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Durvalumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

