<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03317158</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HCRN GU16-243</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03317158</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>ADAPT-BLADDER: Modern Immunotherapy in BCG-Relapsing Urothelial Carcinoma of the Bladder</brief_title>
  <official_title>PhAse 1/2 StuDy of Modern ImmunotherApy in BCG-RelaPsing UroThelial Carcinoma of the BLADDER - (ADAPT-BLADDER) HCRN GU16-243</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Noah Hahn, M.D.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hoosier Cancer Research Network</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hoosier Cancer Research Network</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A multi-arm multi-stage (MAMS) phase 1/2 study. Phase 1 will be conducted in BCG-unresponsive&#xD;
      NMIBC patients to establish the safety of durvalumab monotherapy (cohort 1) and durvalumab in&#xD;
      combination with BCG (cohort 2a) and external beam radiation therapy (EBRT) (cohort 2b).&#xD;
      Provided safety is demonstrated and recommended phase 2 doses (RP2D) are established in phase&#xD;
      1, the study will proceed to phase 2 testing. Phase 2 will be conducted in the BCG-relapsing&#xD;
      or persistent NMIBC population. In phase 2, BCG-relapsing or persistent NMIBC subjects will&#xD;
      be randomized between treatment arms examining intravesical BCG in combination with novel&#xD;
      immunotherapy agents (durvalumab), novel immunotherapy in combination with radiation&#xD;
      (durvalumab + EBRT), or retreatment with intravesical BCG. In addition to providing&#xD;
      additional safety data on the combination regimens studied, phase 2 will provide preliminary&#xD;
      efficacy profiles for BCG-relapsing or persistent NMIBC subjects with and without CIS treated&#xD;
      with each regimen. For regimens demonstrating a tolerable safety profile and encouraging&#xD;
      clinical activity in this phase 1/2 design, a randomized phase 3 trial of experimental arm&#xD;
      therapy versus re-treatment with intravesical BCG therapy would be considered.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patient Assignment in Phase 1&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to commencing accrual, each study site will be required to self-identify their site as&#xD;
      a site with (EBRT+) or without (EBRT-) the capacity to provide radiation therapy as specified&#xD;
      in the durvalumab + EBRT arm. The radiation therapy status of each site will remain fixed&#xD;
      throughout the course of the trial. In phase 1 of the protocol, patients will be assigned to&#xD;
      study treatment cohorts based on patient slot availability and study site choice of radiation&#xD;
      therapy arm participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient Randomization in Phase 2&#xD;
&#xD;
      In phase 2 of the protocol, subjects registered at self-identified EBRT+ study sites will be&#xD;
      randomized 1:1 between all actively accruing study arms while subjects registered at&#xD;
      self-identified EBRT- study sites will be randomized 1:1 between all actively accruing study&#xD;
      arms except the durvalumab + EBRT arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Papillary Subgroup Enrollment Cap&#xD;
&#xD;
      As described further in the Section 12 enrollment in Phase 2 of patients with papillary only&#xD;
      (Ta or T1) tumors with no evidence of concurrent CIS within each experimental study arm will&#xD;
      be capped to ensure adequate representation of patients with CIS for planned efficacy&#xD;
      analyses.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 21, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Open-Label</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 1: Determine the recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) from BCG-unresponsive non-muscle invasive bladder cancer (NMIBC) patients treated with immunotherapy doublet combinations</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>durvalumab plus BCG, durvalumab plus radiation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 2: Determine the 6-month relapse-free survival (RFS) rates of BCG-relapsing or persistent non-muscle invasive bladder cancer (NMIBC) subjects treated with immunotherapy doublet combinations or BCG re-treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>durvalumab plus BCG, durvalumab plus radiation, BCG monotherapy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 1: Characterize the 6-month relapse-free survival (RFS) rate of BCG-unresponsive non-muscle invasive bladder cancer (NMIBC) subjects treated with immunotherapy monotherapy or doublet combinations</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>durvalumab monotherapy, durvalumab plus BCG, durvalumab plus radiation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the safety profile of BCG-unresponsive non-muscle invasive bladder cancer (NMIBC) subjects treated with immunotherapy monotherapy or doublet combinations by reporting the highest grade adverse event per patient, as assessed by CTCAE v4.0.</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>durvalumab monotherapy, durvalumab plus BCG, durvalumab plus radiation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 2: Determine the 24-month relapse-free survival (RFS) rates of BCG-relapsing or persistent non-muscle invasive bladder cancer (NMIBC) subjects treated with immunotherapy doublet combinations or BCG re-treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>durvalumab plus BCG, durvalumab plus radiation, BCG monotherapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 2: Identify significant associations between 6- and 24-month RFS rates and baseline tumor immunohistochemistry staining patterns of PD-L1 and other relevant mechanism of action targets for each drug studied within each study arm.</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the relapse-free survival (RFS) rate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 2: Determine the 6-month relapse-free survival (RFS) rate of BCG-unresponsive non-muscle invasive bladder cancer (NMIBC) subjects treated with durvalumab</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the 6 month relapse-free survival (RFS) rate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 2: Determine the 24-month relapse-free survival (RFS) rate of BCG-unresponsive non-muscle invasive bladder cancer (NMIBC) subjects treated with durvalumab.</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the 24 month relapse-free survival (RFS) rate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the safety profile of subjects treated with immunotherapy monotherapy, doublet combinations or BCG re-treatment by reporting the highest grade adverse event per patient as assessed by CTCAE v4.0.</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>durvalumab plus BCG, durvalumab plus radiation, BCG monotherapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">186</enrollment>
  <condition>Urothelial Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Bladder Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1: (cohort 1):</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Durvalumab monotherapy (cohort 1)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1: (cohort 2a) &amp; (cohort 2b):</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>(cohort 2a) - Durvalumab plus BCG&#xD;
(cohort 2b) - Durvalumab plus External Beam Radiotherapy (EBRT)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 2: (cohort 2a), (cohort 2b), &amp; (BCG re-treatment)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>(cohort 2a) - Durvalumab plus BCG&#xD;
(cohort 2b) - Durvalumab plus External Beam Radiotherapy (EBRT)&#xD;
(BCG re-treatment) - Cross-over to Durvalumab Monotherapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Durvalumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Durvalumab 1120 mg intravenously Day 1 every 21 days x 8 cycles.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1: (cohort 1):</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1: (cohort 2a) &amp; (cohort 2b):</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 2: (cohort 2a), (cohort 2b), &amp; (BCG re-treatment)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Imfinzi</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>External Beam Radiotherapy (EBRT)</intervention_name>
    <description>EBRT 6 Gy x 3; Cycle 1 Day 1, 3, and 5</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1: (cohort 2a) &amp; (cohort 2b):</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 2: (cohort 2a), (cohort 2b), &amp; (BCG re-treatment)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bacillus Calmette-Guérin (BCG)</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose level 0 (starting dose) = Full-dose&#xD;
Dose level-1 = 1/3rd-dose BCG. Dose level -1 is expected to be utilized during the phase II portion of the study due to the ongoing and persistent shortage of BCG in the US.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1: (cohort 2a) &amp; (cohort 2b):</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 2: (cohort 2a), (cohort 2b), &amp; (BCG re-treatment)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria (All Patients):&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject must meet all of the following applicable criteria to participate in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed non-muscle invasive urothelial carcinoma of the bladder (Ta,&#xD;
             T1, or Tis stage) on TURBT obtained within 42 days of registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG (WHO) performance status 0 or 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years old at time of consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate hematologic, hepatic, and renal function as defined by the following&#xD;
             laboratory parameters:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  White blood cell count (WBC) &gt; 3.0 K/mm^3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.5 K/mm^3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥ 100 K/mm^3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin (Hgb) ≥ 9 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum total bilirubin: ≤ 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ALT and AST ≤ 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine clearance (CrCl) ≥ 30 mL/min using the Cockcroft-Gault equation,&#xD;
                  see formula below:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  CrCl = [140-age (years)] x weight (kg) / [72 x serum Cr (mg/dL)] (if subject&#xD;
                       is female multiply the above by 0.85)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who give a written informed consent obtained according to local guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria (Phase 1 Only):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In addition to the inclusion criteria required of all patients listed above, the&#xD;
             following inclusion criteria are also required of patients enrolling to Phase 1 of the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BCG-unresponsive disease defined by any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Persistent or recurrent CIS with or without the presence of concurrent Ta or T1&#xD;
                  tumors within 12 months of completion of adequate BCG therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Recurrent high-grade Ta or T1 tumors within 6 months of completion of adequate&#xD;
                  BCG therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: In recognition of the fact that procedure scheduling factors beyond the control of&#xD;
        the patient or treating physician may cause unintended delays in disease evaluations,&#xD;
        patients with pure papillary tumors (Ta or T1) with no components of CIS with recurrence&#xD;
        documented within 9 months of completion of adequate BCG therapy who meet all other&#xD;
        eligibility criteria may be considered for enrollment after consultation with the study&#xD;
        chair.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persistent T1 high-grade tumors at the first disease evaluation (e.g. 3- month&#xD;
             post-treatment evaluation) following an adequate BCG induction course&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prostatic urethra involvement of NMIBC&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adequate BCG therapy is defined as at least one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 5 of 6 doses of an initial induction BCG course plus at least 2 of 3 doses of&#xD;
             maintenance therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 5 of 6 doses of an initial induction BCG course plus at least 2 of 6 doses of&#xD;
             a second induction course&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: Patients with concurrent non-muscle invasive tumors (CIS, Ta, T1) in the prostatic&#xD;
        urethra and/or concurrent non-invasive tumors (CIS, Ta) in the upper urinary tracts&#xD;
        (ureter, renal pelvis) are permitted to enroll in Phase 1 of the study. Patients with&#xD;
        concurrent T1 tumors in the upper urinary tracts (ureter, renal pelvis) are not eligible to&#xD;
        enroll in Phase 1 of the study. Patients who have met the BCG-unresponsive criteria at any&#xD;
        time point in their treatment history are permitted to enroll in Phase 1 of the study&#xD;
        regardless of the time frame between their most recent BCG treatment administration and&#xD;
        study registration dates.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria (Phase 2 Only):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In addition to the inclusion criteria required of all patients listed above, the&#xD;
             following inclusion criteria are also required of patients enrolling to Phase 2 of the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Intermediate or high-risk NMIBC defined according to modified EORTC risk criteria&#xD;
        summarized as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Low-risk Tumors Initial or recurrent tumor &gt; 12 months after resection with all of the&#xD;
             following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Solitary tumor&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Low-grade&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  &lt; 3 cm&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No CIS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intermediate-Risk Tumors: All tumors not defined in the two adjacent categories&#xD;
             (between the category of low- and high-risk).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High-risk Tumors: Any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  T1 tumor&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  High-grade&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CIS&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Multiple and recurrent and large (&gt; 3 cm) Ta low-grade tumors (all conditions&#xD;
                  must be met for this point on Ta low-grade tumors).&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Documented recurrence within 15 months of last exposure to intravesical&#xD;
                       therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Recurrence after 1 prior induction course of intravesical BCG.&#xD;
&#xD;
                       8. BCG-relapsing NMIBC defined as recurrent intermediate- or high-risk NMIBC&#xD;
                       after achievement of a complete response to initial BCG induction therapy&#xD;
                       which does not meet any of the BCG-unresponsive criteria outlined in section&#xD;
                       3.1.2.&#xD;
&#xD;
        OR&#xD;
&#xD;
        BCG-persistent NMIBC defined as persistent intermediate- or high-risk NMIBC at the first&#xD;
        disease evaluation after initial BCG induction therapy (with no intervening achievement of&#xD;
        complete response) for which a second course of BCG induction therapy is considered a&#xD;
        standard of care (e.g. CIS or high grade Ta tumors) which does not meet any of the&#xD;
        BCG-unresponsive criteria outlined in section 3.1.2.&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: Patients who have received additional non-BCG based intravesical therapies (e.g.&#xD;
        chemotherapy, non-BCG investigational agents) are eligible provided they have received only&#xD;
        1 prior course of BCG induction therapy and satisfy the above BCG-relapsing or&#xD;
        BCG-persistent definitions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria (Phase 2 Patients with Persistent or Relapsed NMIBC who Cross-Over to&#xD;
        Durvalumab Only):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In addition to the inclusion criteria described of all patients listed above, the&#xD;
             following inclusion criteria are also required of patients originally enrolled in&#xD;
             Phase 2 of the study who are noted to have NMIBC in follow up and opt to cross-over to&#xD;
             durvalumab monotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subjects with BCG-unresponsive disease defined by any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Prior treatment with 2 or more adequate courses of BCG (at least 5 of 6&#xD;
                       induction installations and at least 2 of 3 maintenance installations for&#xD;
                       subjects on maintenance therapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Persistent T1 high-grade disease at the initial 3-month cystoscopy/TURBT&#xD;
                       assessment in subjects who received 5 of 6 inductions BCG installations.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Relapsed NMIBC within 6 months of last exposure to BCG&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Prostatic urethra involvement of NMIBC&#xD;
&#xD;
        Primary Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria (All Patients):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with muscle-invasive (i.e. T2, T3, T4), locally advanced unresectable, or&#xD;
             metastatic urothelial carcinoma as assessed on baseline radiographic imaging obtained&#xD;
             within 28 days prior to study registration. The required radiographic imaging&#xD;
             includes:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Abdomen/Pelvis - CT scan&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chest - chest x-ray or CT scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with another active second malignancy other than non-melanoma skin cancers&#xD;
             and biochemical relapsed prostate cancer. Subjects that have completed all necessary&#xD;
             therapy and are considered to be at less than 30% risk of relapse are not considered&#xD;
             to have an active second malignancy and are eligible for enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have received the last administration of an anti-cancer therapy including&#xD;
             chemotherapy, immunotherapy, and monoclonal antibodies ≤ 4 weeks prior to starting&#xD;
             study drug, or who have not recovered from the side effects of such therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any unresolved toxicity NCI CTCAE Grade ≥ 2 from previous anticancer therapy with the&#xD;
             exception of alopecia, vitiligo, and the laboratory values defined in the inclusion&#xD;
             criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with Grade ≥ 2 neuropathy will be evaluated on a case-by-case basis&#xD;
                  after consultation with the sponsor-investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with irreversible toxicity not reasonably expected to be exacerbated by&#xD;
                  treatment with durvalumab may be included only after consultation with the&#xD;
                  sponsor-investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have received prior therapy with PD-1 or PD-L1 directed agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have had any prior radiation to the prostate or pelvis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have undergone major surgery (e.g. intra-thoracic, intra-abdominal or&#xD;
             intra-pelvic), open biopsy or significant traumatic injury ≤ 4 weeks prior to starting&#xD;
             study drug, or subjects who have had minor procedures (i.e. TURBT), percutaneous&#xD;
             biopsies or placement of vascular access device ≤ 1 week prior to starting study drug,&#xD;
             or who have not recovered from side effects of such procedure or injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with any of the following concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled medical&#xD;
             conditions which could compromise participation in the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clinically significant cardiac diseases, including any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  History or presence of serious uncontrolled ventricular arrhythmias.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Clinically significant resting bradycardia.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Any of the following within 3 months prior to starting study drug:&#xD;
                       myocardial infarction (MI), severe/unstable angina, Coronary Artery Bypass&#xD;
                       Graft (CABG), Congestive Heart Failure (CHF), Cerebrovascular Accident&#xD;
                       (CVA), Transient Ischemic Attack (TIA), Pulmonary Embolism (PE).&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Uncontrolled hypertension defined by a SBP ≥ 160 mm Hg and/or DBP ≥ 100 mm&#xD;
                       Hg, with or without anti-hypertensive medication(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cirrhosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Active Infection (includes chronic active and chronic persistent).&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Tuberculosis&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Hepatitis B (known positive HBV surface antigen (HbsAg). Patients with a&#xD;
                       past or resolved HBV infection (defined as the presence of hepatitis B core&#xD;
                       antibody [anti-HBc] and absence of HbsAg) are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Hepatitis C. Patients positive for hepatitis C (HCV) antibody are eligible&#xD;
                       only if polymerase chain reaction is negative for HCV RNA.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Known diagnosis of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV/positive HIV 1/2&#xD;
                       antibodies) infection (HIV testing is not mandatory).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Active or prior documented autoimmune or inflammatory disorders (including&#xD;
                  inflammatory bowel disease [e.g., colitis or Crohn's disease], diverticulitis&#xD;
                  [with the exception of diverticulosis], systemic lupus erythematosus, Sarcoidosis&#xD;
                  syndrome, or Wegener syndrome [granulomatosis with polyangiitis, Graves' disease,&#xD;
                  rheumatoid arthritis, hypophysitis, uveitis, etc.]). The following are exceptions&#xD;
                  to this criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Patients with vitiligo or alopecia.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Patients with hypothyroidism (e.g., following Hashimoto syndrome) stable on&#xD;
                       hormone replacement.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Any chronic skin condition that does not require systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Patients without active disease in the last 5 years may be included but only&#xD;
                       after consultation with the study physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Patients with celiac disease controlled by diet alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Other concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled concomitant medical conditions (e.g.&#xD;
                  active or uncontrolled infection, uncontrolled diabetes) that could cause&#xD;
                  unacceptable safety risks or compromise compliance with the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or prior use of immunosuppressive medication within 14 days before the first&#xD;
             dose of durvalumab. The following are exceptions to this criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intranasal, inhaled, topical steroids, or local steroid injections (e.g., intra&#xD;
                  articular injection).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Systemic corticosteroids at physiologic doses not to exceed 10 mg/day of&#xD;
                  prednisone or its equivalent.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Steroids as premedication for hypersensitivity reactions (e.g., CT scan&#xD;
                  premedication).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Usage of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory medications (NSAIDS) for the treatment&#xD;
                  of osteoarthritis and uric acid synthesis inhibitors for the treatment of gout&#xD;
                  are permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast-feeding women. Women of child-bearing potential must have a&#xD;
             negative urine or serum test ≤ 14 days prior to starting study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child-bearing potential, who are biologically able to conceive, and not&#xD;
             employing two forms of highly effective contraception or abstinence. Highly effective&#xD;
             contraception or abstinence must be used from the time of informed consent, throughout&#xD;
             the trial and up to 180 days after the last dose of durvalumab (e.g. male condom with&#xD;
             spermicidal; diaphragm with spermicide; intra-uterine device). Women of child-bearing&#xD;
             potential are defined as sexually mature women who have not undergone a hysterectomy&#xD;
             or who have not been naturally postmenopausal for at least 12 consecutive months&#xD;
             (i.e., who has had menses any time in the preceding 12 consecutive months). Women will&#xD;
             be considered post-menopausal if they have been amenorrheic for 12 months without an&#xD;
             alternative medical cause. The following age-specific requirements apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women &lt;50 years of age would be considered post-menopausal if they have been&#xD;
                  amenorrheic for 12 months or more following cessation of exogenous hormonal&#xD;
                  treatments and if they have luteinizing hormone and follicle-stimulating hormone&#xD;
                  levels in the post-menopausal range for the institution or underwent surgical&#xD;
                  sterilization (bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women ≥50 years of age would be considered post-menopausal if they have been&#xD;
                  amenorrheic for 12 months or more following cessation of all exogenous hormonal&#xD;
                  treatments, had radiation-induced menopause with last menses &gt;1 year ago, had&#xD;
                  chemotherapy-induced menopause with last menses &gt;1 year ago, or underwent&#xD;
                  surgical sterilization (bilateral oophorectomy, bilateral salpingectomy or&#xD;
                  hysterectomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fertile males not willing to use contraception or abstinence, as stated above.&#xD;
             Contraception or abstinence must be followed from screening through 180 days after&#xD;
             receipt of the final dose of durvalumab therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects unwilling or unable to comply with the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of live attenuated vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose of IP.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy or hypersensitivity to any of the study drugs or any of the study drug&#xD;
             excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria (Phase 1 Only):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In Phase 1 of the study, there are no additional exclusion criteria beyond those&#xD;
             described of all patients in the section listed above.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria (Phase 2 Only):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In addition to the exclusion criteria described of all patients listed above, the&#xD;
             following exclusion criteria apply to patients enrolling to Phase 2 of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with BCG-unresponsive disease defined by any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prior treatment with 2 or more adequate courses of BCG (at least 5 of 6 induction&#xD;
                  installations and at least 2 of 3 maintenance installations for subjects on&#xD;
                  maintenance therapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Persistent T1 high-grade disease at the initial 3-month cystoscopy/TURBT&#xD;
                  assessment in subjects who received 5 of 6 inductions BCG installations.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Relapsed NMIBC within 6 months of last exposure to BCG.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prostatic urethra involvement of NMIBC.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with concurrent upper urinary tract (i.e. ureter, renal pelvis) non-invasive&#xD;
             urothelial carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria (Phase 2 Patients with Persistent or Relapsed NMIBC who Cross-Over to&#xD;
        Durvalumab Only):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In addition to the exclusion criteria described of all patients listed above, the&#xD;
             following exclusion criteria apply to patients enrolling to the cross-over to&#xD;
             durvalumab portion of the Phase 2 study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subjects with concurrent upper urinary tract (i.e. ureter, renal pelvis)&#xD;
                  non-invasive urothelial carcinoma.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Noah M. Hahn, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Hoosier Cancer Research Network</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Robyn Lillie, RN</last_name>
    <phone>317.634.5842</phone>
    <phone_ext>60</phone_ext>
    <email>rlillie@hoosiercancer.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Noah M. Hahn, MD</last_name>
    <phone>443.287.0553</phone>
    <email>nhahn4@jhmi.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>BCG Oncology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Phoenix</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Debra Mobley</last_name>
      <phone>602-493-6626</phone>
      <email>Debbi@bcgoncology.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Donald Lamm, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stanford</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94305</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ned Realiza</last_name>
      <phone>650-498-8496</phone>
      <email>nrealiza@stanford.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Eila Skinner, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rush University Medical Cneter</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dawn Paulsen</last_name>
      <phone>312-942-1287</phone>
      <email>Dawn_Paulsen@rush.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Srinivas Vourganti, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Indiana University Melvin and Bren Simon Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nabil Adra, MD</last_name>
      <phone>317-948-6942</phone>
      <email>nadra@iu.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Yvonne Lafary</last_name>
      <phone>317-278-5613</phone>
      <email>ylafary@iu.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nabil Adra, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Costantine Albany, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Roberto Pili, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Hristos Kaimakliotis, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Iowa Hospitals and Clinics</name>
      <address>
        <city>Iowa City</city>
        <state>Iowa</state>
        <zip>52242</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tiffany Kriegel</last_name>
      <phone>319-353-4582</phone>
      <email>tiffany-kriegel@uiowa.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael A. O'Donnell, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins University: Sidney Kimmel Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21231</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Noah Hahn, M.D.</last_name>
      <phone>443-287-0553</phone>
      <email>nhahn4@jhmi.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Linnea Smith-Walters</last_name>
      <phone>410.502.0017</phone>
      <email>lsmithw1@jhmi.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kara Olivier</last_name>
      <email>kolivier@partners.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Matthew Wszolek, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington University School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kirsten Cady</last_name>
      <phone>314-362-7773</phone>
      <email>cadyk@wustl.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Zachary Smith, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University Irving Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Susie Flores</last_name>
      <phone>212-304-6343</phone>
      <email>sf2780@cumc.columbia.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christopher B. Anderson, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27599</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rachel Munoz</last_name>
      <phone>919-445-4188</phone>
      <email>rachel_munoz@med.unc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marc Bjurlin, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fox Chase Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19111</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tracy Kradzinski</last_name>
      <phone>215-728-1133</phone>
      <email>Tracy.Kradzinski@fccc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Daniel Geynisman, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://hoosiercancer.org</url>
    <description>Hoosier Cancer Research Network Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 12, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 17, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 23, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 15, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 15, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hoosier Cancer Research Network</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Noah Hahn, M.D.</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Sponsor-Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>non-muscle invasive bladder cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>BCG</keyword>
  <keyword>immunotherapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Transitional Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Durvalumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>BCG Vaccine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

