<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03315494</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>OSCO-P1202</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03315494</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetics of Multiple Ascending Doses of SKI-O-703 in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Multiple Ascending Dose Study to Assess the Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetics of Multiple Oral Doses of SKI-O-703 in Healthy Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Oscotec Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>PPD</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Oscotec Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This double-blind, placebo-controlled, multiple ascending dose study is designed to evaluate&#xD;
      the safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics (PK) of SKI-O-703 in healthy volunteers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a double-blind, placebo-controlled study in healthy adult volunteers, to evaluate the&#xD;
      safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics (PK) of multiple ascending doses of SKI-O-703. A&#xD;
      total of 24 subjects are planned to participate in 3 cohorts (8 subjects each). In each&#xD;
      cohort, 6 subjects will be randomly assigned to receive SKI-O-703 and 2 subjects will be&#xD;
      randomly assigned to matching placebo. Dosing will be initiated with a 200 mg once daily (QD)&#xD;
      dose cohort and escalated to 400 mg QD, under fasting conditions, for 7 days. In the third&#xD;
      cohort, a 200 mg twice daily (BID) dose will be studied for 7 days. Evening dosing will occur&#xD;
      12 hours after the morning dose and will be preceded by fasting for at least 3 hours. After&#xD;
      all 8 subjects in each cohort have received the study drug and been monitored, the decision&#xD;
      to escalate to the next dose cohort will be made.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 22, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 21, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 21, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants (Healthy Volunteers) with reported adverse events receiving multiple dose of SKI-O-703 as assessment of safety and tolerability.</measure>
    <time_frame>21 days</time_frame>
    <description>Safety and tolerability of SKI-O-703 as measured by subject incidence of treatment-related Adverse Events.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the concentration versus time curve within a dosing interval (AUC0-tau), to investigate pharmacokinetic profiles of SKI-O-592 (the free base of SKI-O-703) and its metabolites (M2 and M4) in healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1-7 (dosing), post-dose (days 8-10).</time_frame>
    <description>AUC0-tau will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the concentration versus time curve from time 0 to the last measurable concentration (AUC0-t), to investigate pharmacokinetic profiles of SKI-O-592 (the free base of SKI-O-703) and its metabolites (M2 and M4) in healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1-7 (dosing), post-dose (days 8-10).</time_frame>
    <description>AUC0-t will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the concentration versus time curve within a dosing interval (AUC0-inf), to investigate pharmacokinetic profiles of SKI-O-592 (the free base of SKI-O-703) and its metabolites (M2 and M4) in healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7 only</time_frame>
    <description>AUC0-inf will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum observed concentration (Cmax), to investigate pharmacokinetic profiles of SKI-O-592 (the free base of SKI-O-703) and its metabolites (M2 and M4) in healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1-7 (dosing), post-dose (days 8-10).</time_frame>
    <description>Cmax will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent oral clearance (CL/F), to investigate pharmacokinetic profiles of SKI-O-592 (the free base of SKI-O-703) and its metabolites (M2 and M4) in healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1-7 (dosing), post-dose (days 8-10).</time_frame>
    <description>CL/F will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal elimination rate constant (Kel), to investigate pharmacokinetic profiles of SKI-O-592 (the free base of SKI-O-703) and its metabolites (M2 and M4) in healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Kel will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to reach the maximum observed concentration, to investigate pharmacokinetic profiles of SKI-O-592 (the free base of SKI-O-703) and its metabolites (M2 and M4) in healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1-7 (dosing), post-dose (days 8-10).</time_frame>
    <description>Tmax will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent terminal elimination half-life (t1/2), to investigate pharmacokinetic profiles of SKI-O-592 (the free base of SKI-O-703) and its metabolites (M2 and M4) in healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7 only</time_frame>
    <description>t1/2 will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent volume of distribution (Vd/F), to investigate pharmacokinetic profiles of SKI-O-592 (the free base of SKI-O-703) and its metabolites (M2 and M4) in healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1-7 (dosing), post-dose (days 8-10).</time_frame>
    <description>Vd/F will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Metabolite ratio (Rmet), to investigate pharmacokinetic profiles of SKI-O-592 (the free base of SKI-O-703) and its metabolites (M2 and M4) in healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1-7 (dosing), post-dose (days 8-10).</time_frame>
    <description>Rmet will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accumulation ratio based on AUC0-tau (RAUC), to investigate pharmacokinetic profiles of SKI-O-592 (the free base of SKI-O-703) and its metabolites (M2 and M4) in healthy volunteers.</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1-7 (dosing), post-dose (days 8-10).</time_frame>
    <description>RAUC will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The pharmacodynamics variable will be the change in the percentage of activated gp53/CD63+ basophils and will be evaluated from serial blood samples collected from subjects who have received SKI-O-703 or placebo.</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1-7 (dosing), post-dose (day 8).</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in the percentage of activated gp53/CD63+ basophils will be reported.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SKI-O-703 200 mg (once daily)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>SKI-O-703 capsule (1 x 200 mg)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SKI-O-703 400 mg (once daily)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>SKI-O-703 capsule (2 x 200 mg, once daily)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SKI-O-703 200 mg (twice daily)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>SKI-O-703 capsule (1 x 200 mg twice daily)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo capsule</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SKI-O-703 capsule</intervention_name>
    <description>SKI-O-703 200 mg capsule with no inactive excipients.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SKI-O-703 200 mg (once daily)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>SKI-O-703 200 mg (twice daily)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>SKI-O-703 400 mg (once daily)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo capsule</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo 180 mg capsule filled with microcrystalline cellulose.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to provide written informed consent for participation prior to&#xD;
             completing any study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Considered by investigator to be in good health, as judged by absence of clinically&#xD;
             significant diseases and clinically significant abnormal values as determined by&#xD;
             detailed medical history review, complete physical examination, and clinical&#xD;
             laboratory evaluations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male subjects and female subjects of non-childbearing potential 18-55 years old,&#xD;
             inclusive, at time of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of non-childbearing potential are those who have been surgically sterile for&#xD;
             at least 6 months or who have been postmenopausal for at least 2 years and have&#xD;
             follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) serum levels consistent with postmenopausal status.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male subjects agree to use a condom with spermicide or to abstain from sexual&#xD;
             intercourse for 90 days after dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male subjects must agree not to donate sperm for 90 days after dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects must have negative pregnancy tests at screening and on Day -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index between 18.0 and 30.0 kg/m2, inclusive, and body weight of ≥ 50 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to understand the study and any risks of participation and able to communicate&#xD;
             with the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of any clinically significant disease or disorder that may put the subject at&#xD;
             risk due to study participation, impact the subject's ability to participate in the&#xD;
             study, or influence the study results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or presence of any gastrointestinal, hepatic or renal disease or any other&#xD;
             condition known to interfere with the absorption, distribution, metabolism, or&#xD;
             excretion of drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any surgical or medical condition that could possibly affect drug absorption,&#xD;
             distribution, metabolism, and excretion (e.g. bariatric procedure).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any medical/surgical procedure or trauma within 4 weeks prior to Day -1 as determined&#xD;
             by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any clinically significant infection within 3 months prior to Day -1 as determined by&#xD;
             the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following abnormal laboratory values upon repeat testing at Screening or&#xD;
             Check-in (Day -1):&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Hemoglobin &lt; lower limit of normal (LLN),&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Platelet count &lt;LLN,&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Absolute neutrophil count &lt;LLN or &gt;upper limit of normal (ULN),&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Alanine aminotransferase or aspartate aminotransferase &gt;ULN,&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Creatinine or blood urea nitrogen &gt;ULN, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Any other clinically significant, in the opinion of the investigator, abnormal&#xD;
                  laboratory result.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of concomitant medications from 30 days or 5 half-lives prior to Day -1 (whichever&#xD;
             is longer) through completion of the End of Study (EOS) visit, including prescription&#xD;
             medications, nutritional supplements, herbal remedies, and over-the-counter&#xD;
             medications (note: use of vitamin supplements should be stopped at least 7 days prior&#xD;
             to Screening through completion of the EOS visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of any investigational medication within 30 days or 5 half-lives prior to Day&#xD;
             -1, whichever is longer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of tobacco or nicotine-containing products within 30 days prior to Day -1 through&#xD;
             the EOS visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of CYP3A inducers and inhibitors (including St. John's wort) within 30 days prior&#xD;
             to dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intake of food or beverage containing alcohol, grapefruit or grapefruit juice, apple&#xD;
             or orange juice, vegetables from the mustard green family (e.g. kale, broccoli,&#xD;
             watercress, collard greens, kohlrabi, Brussels sprouts, mustard), or charbroiled meats&#xD;
             within 1 week prior to dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of substance abuse, drug addiction, or alcoholism.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive urine drug or urine alcohol test at Screening or Day -1 or unable to abstain&#xD;
             from alcohol from 72 hours prior to study entry through the EOS visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to abstain from caffeine- and xanthine-containing products from 72 hours prior&#xD;
             to dosing through discharge from the study center.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects who are pregnant or lactating or have a positive pregnancy test at&#xD;
             Screening or Day -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive result at Screening for human immunodeficiency virus, hepatitis B surface&#xD;
             antigen, or hepatitis C virus antibody or positive result for hepatitis B core&#xD;
             antibody with a negative result for hepatitis B surface antigen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent (within the past 5 years) history of malignancy, except successfully treated&#xD;
             basal cell carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High blood pressure, defined as &gt;140 mm Hg systolic blood pressure or &gt;90 mm Hg&#xD;
             diastolic blood pressure upon repeat confirmation (repeated up to 4 times).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiac arrhythmias or clinically significant electrocardiogram (ECG) findings.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Corrected QT interval &gt;450 milliseconds or deemed clinically significant by the&#xD;
             investigator (may be repeated for confirmation).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Family history of long QT syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood loss or blood donation &gt;450 mL within 4 weeks prior to study drug dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of sensitivity to drugs with chemical similarity to the study medication, its&#xD;
             components, or the excipients.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>PPD Development, LP</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78744</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 6, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 16, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 16, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 16, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>rheumatoid arthritis</keyword>
  <keyword>healthy volunteers</keyword>
  <keyword>moderate to severe</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

