<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03311386</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Collaterals and acute stroke</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03311386</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intracranial Collaterals in Acute Stroke and Clinical Outcome</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Collateral Vessels in Patients With Acute Ischemic Stroke Receiving Thrombolytic Therapy (Clinical and Radiological Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Assessment of the evolution of intracranial collaterals and its relationship with functional&#xD;
      outcomes in acute ischemic stroke (AIS) patients treated with IV tissue plasminogen activator&#xD;
      (tPA).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Intracranial collaterals Assessment in acute ischemic stroke In clinical practice, infarct&#xD;
      growth does not always progress to involve the full extent of the vascular territory, even if&#xD;
      the affected intracranial artery fails to recanalize. The presence and recruitment of various&#xD;
      collateral channels are believed to be responsible for this phenomenon in acute ischemic&#xD;
      stroke (AIS). These collaterals may also play an important role in influencing the safety and&#xD;
      efficacy of acute revascularization approaches. Although blood supply from the leptomeningeal&#xD;
      collaterals may temporarily maintain the ischemic penumbra, the persistence and effectiveness&#xD;
      of this alternative circulatory supply is erratic and unpredictable. Some collaterals may&#xD;
      disappear over time (collateral failure); this is one of the mechanisms responsible for&#xD;
      clinical deterioration following initial improvement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conversely, dramatic resolution of initial neurologic deficits may be seen though the&#xD;
      occluded intracranial artery did not recanalize, often attributable to the rapid improvement&#xD;
      of cerebral perfusion via effective collateral pathways (collateral recruitment). Therefore,&#xD;
      the temporal behavior of intracranial collaterals may play an important role in determining&#xD;
      the functional outcome in AIS patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CT angiography (CTA) of the brain is acutely performed in AIS patients before or immediately&#xD;
      after administering IV tissue plasminogen activator (tPA) The Alberta Stroke Program Early CT&#xD;
      (ASPECTS) leptomeningeal collaterals score on CT-angiography helps in prognosticating&#xD;
      functional outcome in acute ischemic stroke (AIS) patients treated with intravenous&#xD;
      thrombolysis. Leptomeningeal collaterals in AIS are dynamic, especially during the first few&#xD;
      hours or days of AIS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In animals, 3 different types of collaterals have been identified: transient collaterals that&#xD;
      could be seen immediately after the stroke and last less than 90 minutes; impermanent&#xD;
      collaterals that disappear after 90-150 minutes; and persistent collaterals, which can be&#xD;
      seen for longer periods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with good collateral flow demonstrated less hypo perfused tissue and less infarct&#xD;
      growth within the penumbra zone than those with poor collateral . A relationship is found&#xD;
      between good early collaterals on pretreatment imaging and smaller infarct volume with better&#xD;
      outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The initial state of the collateral circulation on the pretreatment CTA also has bearing on&#xD;
      the clinical effect of the collateral recruitment on the day 2 CTA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, collateral recruitment with poor pretreatment collaterals was associated with poor&#xD;
      functional outcome at 3 months and a higher risk of intracranial hemorrhage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One plausible mechanism that delayed collateral recruitment lead to worse outcomes could be&#xD;
      related to the maximal vasodilation in the ischemic area and how collateral recruitment in&#xD;
      the adjacent regions may trigger a steal-like phenomenon with resultant expansion of the&#xD;
      ischemic core. Another possible mechanism could be related to failed autoregulation in the&#xD;
      affected vascular territory, leading to increased hyper perfusion damage with a higher chance&#xD;
      of bleeding.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 23, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>90-days functional outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>90-day modified Rankin Score (mRS) 0-2 or equal to the pre-stroke modified Rankin scale he Modified Rankin Scale (mRS) The scale runs from 0-6 0 - No symptoms.&#xD;
- No significant disability. Able to carry out all usual activities, despite some symptoms.&#xD;
- Slight disability. Able to look after own affairs without assistance, but unable to carry out all previous activities.&#xD;
- Moderate disability. Requires some help, but able to walk unassisted.&#xD;
- Moderately severe disability. Unable to attend to own bodily needs without assistance, and unable to walk unassisted.&#xD;
- Severe disability. Requires constant nursing care and attention, bedridden, incontinent.&#xD;
- Dead.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Early neurologic improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as The National Institutes of Health Stroke Scale score &quot;NIHSS&quot; of 0 to 2 at 24 hours or an 8-point drop in NIHSS score from baseline to 24 hours.&#xD;
The NIHSS is composed of 11 items, each of which scores a specific ability between a 0 and 4. For each item, a score of 0 typically indicates normal function in that specific ability, 0 No stroke symptoms 1-4 Minor stroke 5-15 Moderate stroke 16-20 Moderate to severe stroke 21-42 Severe stroke</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Collateral Circulation, Any Site</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients in AIS receiving actilyse</arm_group_label>
    <description>the patients will receive actilyse intaravenously in a dose of 0.9mg/kg once</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Actilyse</intervention_name>
    <description>thrombolytic therapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients in AIS receiving actilyse</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Alteplase</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients with acute ischemic stroke within 4.5 hours - legible for receiving IV r TPA-&#xD;
        admitted to Neurology department of Asyut University within 1 year (2017-2018)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        IInclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient presenting to the emergency department with symptoms consistent with ischemic&#xD;
             stroke.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 18 yrs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of a visible and symptomatic intracranial occlusion on baseline&#xD;
             CT-angiography (intracranial ICA, M1 MCA segment +/- intracranial ICA, proximal M2&#xD;
             MCA).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with IV tPA.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intracranial hemorrhage (ICH) identified on baseline CT.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous moderate to large stroke in the ipsilesional hemisphere.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Modified Rankin Scale &gt; 2 at baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to have CT-angio performed due to recent estimated creatinine clearance eCCr&lt;60&#xD;
             ml/min, contrast allergy or other reasons.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any terminal illness (patient not expected to survive &gt; 1 year).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Essam Darwish, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ahmed Hamdy, Ass.Prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Assiut university</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <zip>71511</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bang OY, Goyal M, Liebeskind DS. Collateral Circulation in Ischemic Stroke: Assessment Tools and Therapeutic Strategies. Stroke. 2015 Nov;46(11):3302-9. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.115.010508. Epub 2015 Oct 8. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26451027</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 2, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 17, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ahmed Mamdouh Mohammed Tawfeeq</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>principle investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tissue Plasminogen Activator</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

