<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03913078</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HL142679</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03913078</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparative Effectiveness of Social Physical Play and Traditional Exercise Programming</brief_title>
  <acronym>PlayFit</acronym>
  <official_title>Comparative Effectiveness of Social Physical Play and Traditional Exercise Programming</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Milton S. Hershey Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health (NIH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Milton S. Hershey Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will compare the impact of traditional group fitness versus a game-based fitness&#xD;
      program, designed to maximize enjoyment, on physical fitness.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Fewer than 1 in 10 middle-aged US adults get the recommended amount of aerobic physical&#xD;
      activity (PA), greatly increasing their chances of heart disease and stroke. There are over&#xD;
      50 million adults with fitness center memberships, which are used only once per month and,&#xD;
      after joining new programs, people quickly stop coming. While many barriers to PA have been&#xD;
      cited (e.g., time, cost), the investigators believe that a key, modifiable, and&#xD;
      underappreciated barrier is that most adults simply do not enjoy physical activity enough to&#xD;
      do it regularly. Studies consistently observe that people who enjoy physical activity more&#xD;
      are more likely to be more active in the future. Despite this consistent observation, the&#xD;
      investigators are not aware of studies that ask &quot;Would an adult PA program designed to&#xD;
      maximize enjoyment increase PA adherence and fitness?&quot;. In 2015, our team set out to design&#xD;
      an exercise program for adults that maximized enjoyment. Taking inspiration from Pickleball,&#xD;
      a popular game of modified tennis, our team created PlayFit. PlayFit is an exercise program&#xD;
      in which adults come together three times each week to play a range of sports, all modified&#xD;
      to 1) reduce effort (e.g., smaller playing area), 2) reduce injuries (e.g., lightweight&#xD;
      low-pressure balls) and 3) reduce competitiveness (e.g., teams chosen randomly, minimize&#xD;
      physical contact, no keeping score). Pilot work in the summer of 2016 with 22 adults&#xD;
      identified five modified sports that all had Metabolic Equivalent (MET) levels between 5.5&#xD;
      and 6.5 and high satisfaction scores (average of 8.0 out of 10). More importantly, the&#xD;
      comments suggest that the investigators have created a social, enjoyable experience: &quot;that&#xD;
      was SO much fun&quot;, &quot;I've never had so much fun playing soccer&quot;. People liked &quot;the laughter&#xD;
      during the games&quot;, &quot;no pressure, not competitive&quot; and that &quot;it's not about ability, it's just&#xD;
      about having fun with people&quot;. In this study, the investigators propose testing whether&#xD;
      PlayFit leads to greater fitness gains, compared to group fitness, to help providers&#xD;
      understand in a way that helps providers and fitness center staff understand: &quot;What exercise&#xD;
      program should I recommend to promote long-term adherence and fitness?&quot;. All subjects will be&#xD;
      expected to exercise three-times weekly for 60 minutes for 12 months. The investigators will&#xD;
      randomly assign 360adults to two conditions: 1) Group Fitness activities and 2) PlayFit. The&#xD;
      investigators hypothesize that both PlayFit and Group Fitness will increase Maximum Oxygen&#xD;
      Uptake (V02max) significantly at 6 months but, after 12 months, mediated by greater enjoyment&#xD;
      and higher adherence, participants randomized to PlayFit will have greater fitness and&#xD;
      activity gains at 12 months than Group Fitness. The results of this study have the potential&#xD;
      to help patients, providers and fitness center directors by answering the question: &quot;What&#xD;
      exercise program should be recommended to sedentary adults in order to promote long-term&#xD;
      adherence and fitness?&quot;&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 29, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Increases in perceived enjoyment lead to increases in physical activity adherence which lead to increases in physical fitness</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participants are aware of the two different exercise conditions and accept randomization into either of the two. The investigator and outcomes assessor are masked, but participant is aware of group assignment.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Oxygen Uptake (V02Max)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum Oxygen Uptake (V02Max), a measure of aerobic Fitness, will be assessed using a maximal graded treadmill test, using a Bruce protocol and heart rate and expired gas monitoring (74). V02Max is calculated based on the millilitres of oxygen consumed per kilogram of body mass per minute (e.g., mL/(kg·min)).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Minutes of Moderate-Vigorous Physical Activity (MVPA)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Minutes of Moderate-Vigorous Physical Activity (MVPA) will be measured using an Actigraph GT3X tri-axial accelerometer, which can measure the intensity of PA and the frequency/pattern of activity over time.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Body weight</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Body weight in kilograms will be measured by a research assistant using a calibrated stadiometer.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">360</enrollment>
  <condition>Group Fitness (Traditional)</condition>
  <condition>Group Fitness (Game Play-based)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group Fitness</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be offered several sessions per week of a traditional group fitness program led by a trained group leader.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PlayFit</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be offered several sessions per week of a modified sports fitness program, led by a trained group leader.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Group Fitness</intervention_name>
    <description>Traditional Group Fitness consisting of aerobic and strength exercises performed in a group setting and led by a trained instructor.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group Fitness</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PlayFit</intervention_name>
    <description>Modified sports fitness exercise program consisting of games played in groups and led by a trained instructor.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PlayFit</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18+&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sedentary (&lt;90 minutes of self-reported moderate-vigorous activity each week)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Health care provider must give permission.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of heart disease, stroke or chest pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participating in another research study involving physical activity or weight loss.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planning to have surgery or move in the next year.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christopher Sciamanna, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Milton S. Hershey Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Christopher Sciamanna, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>717-531-4417</phone>
    <email>csciamanna@pennstatehealth.psu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Tami Cassel</last_name>
    <phone>717-531-8161</phone>
    <email>tcassel1@pennstatehealth.psu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Penn State Milton S. Hershey Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hershey</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>17033</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christopher Sciamanna, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>717-531-8161</phone>
      <email>csciamanna@pennstatehealth.psu.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christopher Sciamanna, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 9, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 11, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 12, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Milton S. Hershey Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Christopher Sciamanna, MD, MPH</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Medicine and Public Health Sciences</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>fitness</keyword>
  <keyword>exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>physical activity</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Final, clean, data filed will be uploaded to a publicly available site (e.g., ISPSR), within 12 months of finishing study.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Within 12 months of completing the final follow-up visit on the last study subject.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_url>https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

