<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03978923</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UTrieste1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03978923</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Observational Study on the Preparation of the Implant Site With Piezosurgery vs Drill: Comparison Between the Two Methods in Terms of Post-operative Pain, Surgical Times and Operational Advantages</brief_title>
  <official_title>Observational Study on the Preparation of the Implant Site With Piezosurgery vs Drill: Comparison Between the Two Methods in Terms of Post-operative Pain, Surgical Times and Operational Advantages</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Trieste</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Trieste</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Purpose: Recent advances showed that ultrasonic implant site osteotomy is related with a&#xD;
      decreased trauma and a better post operative healing of the surgical site if compared to the&#xD;
      traditional drilling techniques. The micrometric bone cutting control and the operative&#xD;
      advantages related to the piezoelectric approach is also characterized by a learning curve&#xD;
      for the clinician in surgical practice and an increased operative duration of the procedure.&#xD;
      The aim of this investigation was to compare the operative time, the post operative pain and&#xD;
      the patients frequency of intake of painkillers in the healing period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: A total of 75 patients were treated at the Unit of Oral Surgery (Department of&#xD;
      Medical Sciences, Surgery and Health, University of Trieste, Italy) in a split mouth model:&#xD;
      75 drill-inserted implants (G1) and 75 piezoelectric device- inserted implants (G2). The&#xD;
      Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) was performed to evaluate the post-operative pain at 15 days from&#xD;
      the surgery. The operative time and frequency of intake of painkillers was measured.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Materials and Methods The study was conducted after the approval of the local ethical&#xD;
      Comettee (n. 88-10.05.2018) University of Trieste.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following study took into account adult patients undergoing implant therapy with&#xD;
      insertion of two contralateral conical implants with a diameter between 3.8 and 4.5 mm with a&#xD;
      maximum torque of 35 Ncm. One site was prepared with Ultrasonic device (Esacrom, Imola,&#xD;
      Italy) while the contralateral was prepared with micromotor and dedicated drills. All&#xD;
      patients were treated at the Unit of Oral Surgery (Department of Medical Sciences, Surgery&#xD;
      and Health, University of Trieste, Italy). Seventy-five patients were enrolled in the study,&#xD;
      44 women and 31 men, aged between 45 and 70, who underwent implant therapy in the period&#xD;
      between January 2013 and December 2017. The inclusion criteria were: edentulous or partly&#xD;
      edentulous with a bilateral loss of teeth in the maxillary or mandible and bone type D2 or&#xD;
      D3, following Misch classification16.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The exclusion criteria included: general contraindications to implant surgery, severe&#xD;
      coagulation disorders, leukocyte or metabolic diseases, immunosuppressed or immunocompromised&#xD;
      patients, patients receiving chemotherapy for less than 1 year, patients on therapy or having&#xD;
      taken amino- bisphosphonates intravenously, patients irradiated to the head or neck, patients&#xD;
      with uncontrolled diabetes, pregnant and lactating patients, patients with poor oral hygiene&#xD;
      and motivation, patients needing maxillary sinus lift concomitant with implant insertion,&#xD;
      post-extraction sites with acute or purulent infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The final sample of the implants inserted was 150 (75 per technique) then identifying two&#xD;
      dependent groups: the drill-inserted implants (G1) and the ultrasonic device- inserted&#xD;
      implants (G2). Each patient subscribed an informed written consent and underwent a&#xD;
      pre-operative oral hygiene session. Two grams of Amoxicillin were administered to each&#xD;
      patient in the preoperative phase. Before surgery, each patient made a rinse with a 0.2%&#xD;
      chlorhexidine mouthwash for one minute. The surgery was always performed by the same operator&#xD;
      (M.M.) to reduce the bias of the study. Loco-regional anesthesia was performed with&#xD;
      Mepivacaine hydrochloride with 1:100000 adrenaline.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the preparation of implant sites using traditional methods, the drills were used&#xD;
      following manufacturer's protocol by the implant system in use (WINSIX®- BioSAF IN s.r.l,&#xD;
      Trezzano Rosa, Trezzano Rosa, Milano - Italy).&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the preparation of sites was used ultrasonic device, (Surgysonic II, Esacrom S.r.l.,&#xD;
      Imola, Italy). For the final preparation and insertion of implants, 5-6 ultrasound inserts&#xD;
      were used in sequence as follows: tip-shape 1st insert (ES012X) and 2nd insert (ES052XG),&#xD;
      crown-shape 3rd insert (ES040), 4th insert (ES041), 5 ° insert (ES043) and 6th insert&#xD;
      (ES044).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The implant insertion was performed with a maximum torque of 35 Ncm. Finally, the cap screws&#xD;
      were positioned, and the flaps were sutured in Vycril® 3.0.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each patient was prescribed a 0.2% chlorhexidine mouthwash to be used twice a day for two&#xD;
      weeks and paracetamol 1000 mg (maximum 3 tablets a day) as a pain-relieving therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each patient included in the study was therefore in possession of two questionnaires, one per&#xD;
      technique, for the evaluation of the treatment. In the questionnaire the patient was asked to&#xD;
      trace an &quot;X&quot; representing the level of pain experienced. The questionnaire recorded the&#xD;
      individual symptoms experienced during the surgery, after 8 hours, from the 1st to the 7th&#xD;
      day and finally any persistence&#xD;
&#xD;
      of the symptoms on the 15th day after surgery. In the same questionnaire was also asked to&#xD;
      indicate the possible intake of painkillers and the related dose, after surgery and in the&#xD;
      following six days; moreover, after the fifteenth day, the patient was asked if he have&#xD;
      repeated the experience of the implant surgery. Then, for each patient, a postoperative check&#xD;
      was scheduled: after one week all the patients were recalled for a post-operative control and&#xD;
      the removal of the sutures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the subjective analysis of the effects of the two methods, it was decided to use the&#xD;
      Visual Analogue Scale (VAS). This linear scale is the visual representation of the amplitude&#xD;
      of pain that the patient perceives. It is a horizontal line 100 mm long, in which one end&#xD;
      indicates the absence of pain, while the other represents the worst pain imaginable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the surgical procedure the preparation times of the implant site were measured from&#xD;
      the preparation of the flap up to the insertion of the implant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Immediately after the end of the surgical procedure, a questionnaire on the operative&#xD;
      difficulty was compiled by the operator. In particular, the two techniques were compared&#xD;
      considering two factors: the easiness in obtaining a correct axis of implants insertion and&#xD;
      the quality of visibility. Furthermore, a cumulative judgement has been done for the whole&#xD;
      procedure, as &quot;simple&quot;, &quot;of medium difficulty&quot;, &quot;difficult&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis SPSS software (SPSS Inc. Chicago, IL) was used for statistical analysis.&#xD;
      A value of p &lt;0.05 was used in rejecting the null hypothesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, continuous data were analyzed using non-parametric tests given the asymmetric&#xD;
      distribution of some data sets.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Friedman test was used to evaluate the significance of VAS differences within groups over&#xD;
      time. Wilcoxon test was used to evaluate the significance of VAS differences within groups&#xD;
      and between groups at each time point.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Cochrane test was used to assess the significance of differences in the frequency of intake&#xD;
      of painkillers within groups over time. Subsequently, a McNemar test was used for post-hoc&#xD;
      analysis and to assess the significance of differences in the frequency of intake of&#xD;
      painkillers between groups each time point.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After having calculated the mean operative times for G1 and G2 Mann-Whitney test was used to&#xD;
      compare the differences in surgical times between D2 and D3 bone type within each group while&#xD;
      Wilcoxon test was used to intercept the differences between groups in bone type D2 and D3,&#xD;
      respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The same McNemar test was used to test the differences in the operator questionnaire answers&#xD;
      between groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Crossover</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>level of pain experienced</measure>
    <time_frame>1.1.2013-31.12.2017</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">75</enrollment>
  <condition>Preparation of the Implant Site With Piezosurgery vs Drill</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>the drill-inserted implants (G1)</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>the ultrasonic device- inserted implants (G2)</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>preparation of the implant site with Piezosurgery vs drill</intervention_name>
    <description>The surgery was always performed by the same operator (M.M.) to reduce the bias of the study. Loco-regional anesthesia was performed with Mepivacaine hydrochloride with 1:100000 adrenaline.&#xD;
For the preparation of implant sites using traditional methods, the drills were used following manufacturer's protocol by the implant system in use (WINSIX®- BioSAF IN s.r.l, Trezzano Rosa, Trezzano Rosa, Milano - Italy).&#xD;
For the preparation of sites was used ultrasonic device, (Surgysonic II, Esacrom S.r.l., Imola, Italy). For the final preparation and insertion of implants, 5-6 ultrasound inserts were used in sequence as follows: tip-shape 1st insert (ES012X) and 2nd insert (ES052XG), crown-shape 3rd insert (ES040), 4th insert (ES041), 5 ° insert (ES043) and 6th insert (ES044).&#xD;
The implant insertion was performed with a maximum torque of 35 Ncm. Finally, the cap screws were positioned, and the flaps were sutured in Vycril® 3.0.</description>
    <arm_group_label>the drill-inserted implants (G1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>the ultrasonic device- inserted implants (G2)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        . Seventy-five patients were enrolled in the study, 44 women and 31 men, aged between 45&#xD;
        and 70&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  edentulous or partly edentulous with a bilateral loss of teeth in the maxillary or&#xD;
             mandible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  bone type D2 or D3, following Misch classification&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  general contraindications to implant surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe coagulation disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  immunosuppressed or immunocompromised patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients receiving chemotherapy for less than 1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients on therapy or having taken amino-bisphosphonates intravenously&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients irradiated to the head or neck&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with uncontrolled diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnant and lactating patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with poor oral hygiene and motivation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients needing maxillary sinus lift concomitant with implant insertion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  post-extraction sites with acute or purulent infections.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Medical Sciences, University of Trieste</name>
      <address>
        <city>Trieste</city>
        <state>Italy, Trieste</state>
        <zip>34127</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 3, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 5, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 7, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 5, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 5, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 7, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Trieste</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Bevilacqua Lorenzo</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>prof</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ultrasonic surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>piezosurgery</keyword>
  <keyword>implant bed preparation</keyword>
  <keyword>microcracks</keyword>
  <keyword>pain</keyword>
  <keyword>crestal bone resorption</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

