<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05045404</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-0293</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05045404</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Poziotinib and Ramucirumab for the Treatment of EGFR Exon 20 Mutant Stage IV Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Study of Poziotinib and Ramucirumab in EGFR Exon 20 Mutant Advanced Non-small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase II trial tests whether poziotinib and ramucirumab work to shrink tumors in&#xD;
      patients with EGFR Exon 20 gene mutant stage IV non-small cell lung cancer. Poziotinib may&#xD;
      stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth.&#xD;
      Ramucirumab is a monoclonal antibody that may interfere with the ability of cancer cells to&#xD;
      grow and spread. Giving poziotinib and ramucirumab may help to control the disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate the efficacy of the combination of poziotinib and ramucirumab as measured by&#xD;
      progression free survival.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To estimate the objective response rate per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors&#xD;
      (RECIST) 1.1 for the combination of poziotinib and ramucirumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To estimate the disease control rate (complete response + partial response + stable&#xD;
      disease), overall survival, and duration of response of the study combination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To assess the safety and the toxicity of the study combination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To assess molecular markers associated with resistance and response to poziotinib and&#xD;
      ramucirumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive poziotinib hydrochloride orally (PO) twice daily (BID) on day 1 and&#xD;
      ramucirumab intravenously (IV) over 30-60 minutes on days 1 and 15. Cycles repeat every 28&#xD;
      days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed at 30 days, then every 6 months&#xD;
      thereafter.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 16, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment to time of progression or death, whichever occurs first, assessed up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Estimated using the Kaplan and Meier method.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Lung Non-Small Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Lung Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVA Lung Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVB Lung Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (poziotinib hydrochloride, ramucirumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive poziotinib hydrochloride PO BID on day 1 and ramucirumab IV over 30-60 minutes on days 1 and 15. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Poziotinib Hydrochloride</intervention_name>
    <description>1429757-68-5, HM781-36B, NOV-1201 Hydrochloride, NOV120101 Hydrochloride, Poziotinib HCl, POZIOTINIB HYDROCHLORIDE&#xD;
Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (poziotinib hydrochloride, ramucirumab)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>1429757-68-5, HM781-36B, NOV-1201 Hydrochloride, NOV120101 Hydrochloride, Poziotinib HCl, POZIOTINIB HYDROCHLORIDE</intervention_name>
    <description>Biological/Vaccine Ramucirumab 947687-13-0, anti-VEGFR-2 fully human monoclonal antibody IMC-1121B, Anti-VEGFR-2 Fully Human Monoclonal Antibody IMC-1121B, Cyramza, IMC-1121B, IMC-1121B, LY3009806, Monoclonal Antibody HGS-ETR2, ramucirumab, RAMUCIRUMAB&#xD;
Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (poziotinib hydrochloride, ramucirumab)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient, or patient's authorized representative, must be willing and capable of giving&#xD;
             written informed consent and must be able to adhere to dosing and visit schedules as&#xD;
             well as meet all study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has histologically or cytologically confirmed non-small cell lung cancer&#xD;
                  (NSCLC) not amenable to curative intent therapy or stage IV NSCLC&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Documented epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) exon 20 point or insertion&#xD;
                  mutation using a Food and Drug Administration (FDA)-approved in vitro diagnostic&#xD;
                  test (ie, cobas EGFR mutation test version [v] 2 or therascreen EGFR RGQ&#xD;
                  polymerase chain reaction [PCR] kit), a Clinical Laboratory Improvement Act&#xD;
                  (CLIA) certified test (eg, OncoMine Comprehensive Assay (OCA), Guardant360 Assay&#xD;
                  [using plasma], or FoundationOne Assay), or similarly accredited test for tissue&#xD;
                  or plasma&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Brain metastases are allowed, as long as they are stable and do not require&#xD;
                  treatment with anticonvulsants or escalating doses of steroids&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previously untreated and/or any number of prior lines of therapy for metastatic&#xD;
                  disease are allowed in the dose expansion part. Previously untreated patients are&#xD;
                  now allowed in the dose finding portion of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient is at least 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has measurable disease, as per the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid&#xD;
                  Tumors (RECIST, version 1.1)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0 or&#xD;
                  1&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has recovered from prior systemic therapy for metastatic disease to grade&#xD;
                  =&lt; 1 for non-hematologic toxicities (except for grade =&lt; 2 peripheral neuropathy)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Leukocytes &gt;= 3.0 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) must be &gt;= 1.5 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count &gt;= 100 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin =&lt;1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN); if hepatic metastases are&#xD;
                  present, =&lt; 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate aminotransferase/serum glutamic-oxaloacetic transaminase (AST/SGOT),&#xD;
                  alanine aminotransferase/serum glutamic-pyruvic transaminase (ALT/SGPT), and&#xD;
                  gamma-glutamyltransferase (GGT) =&lt; 2.5 x ULN; if hepatic metastases are present,&#xD;
                  =&lt; 0.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine clearance &gt;= 50 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adequate coagulation function as defined by international normalized ratio (INR)&#xD;
                  1.5 and a partial thromboplastin time (PTT) (PTT/activated partial thromboplastin&#xD;
                  time [aPTT]) &lt; 1.5 x ULN. Patients on full-dose anticoagulation must be on a&#xD;
                  stable dose (minimum duration 14 days) of oral anticoagulant or low molecular&#xD;
                  weight heparin (LMWH). If receiving warfarin, the patient must have an INR =&lt;&#xD;
                  3.0. For heparin and LMWH there should be no active bleeding (that is, no&#xD;
                  bleeding within 14 days prior to first dose of protocol therapy) or pathological&#xD;
                  condition present that carries a high risk of bleeding (for example, tumor&#xD;
                  involving major vessels or known varices)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient is willing to practice 2 forms of contraception, one of which must be a&#xD;
                  barrier method, from study entry until at least 30 days after the last dose of&#xD;
                  study combination&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Females of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test within 7&#xD;
                  days prior to enrollment. Females who are postmenopausal for at least 1 year&#xD;
                  (defined as more than 12 months since last menses) or who are surgically&#xD;
                  sterilized do not require this test&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The patient's urinary protein is =&lt; 1+ on dipstick or routine urinalysis (UA; if&#xD;
                  urine dipstick or routine analysis is &gt;= 2+, a 24-hour urine collection for&#xD;
                  protein must demonstrate &lt; 1000 mg of protein in 24 hours to allow participation&#xD;
                  in this protocol)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Patient has EGFR T790M mutation or other acquired EGFR exon 20point mutation&#xD;
             following prior treatment with an EGFR-tyrosine kinase inhibitor (TKI)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previous treatment with poziotinib or ramucirumab&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient is concurrently receiving chemotherapy, biologics, immunotherapy for&#xD;
                  cancer treatment; systemic anti-cancer treatment or investigational treatment&#xD;
                  should not be used within 2 weeks; local radiation therapy for bone pain may be&#xD;
                  allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has a history of congestive heart failure (CHF) class III/IV according to&#xD;
                  the New York Heart Association (NYHA) functional classification or serious&#xD;
                  cardiac arrhythmias requiring treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has a high risk of cardiac disease, as determined by the investigator,&#xD;
                  may undergo either echocardiogram (ECHO) or multi-gated acquisition (MUGA) during&#xD;
                  screening and if the patient has a cardiac ejection fraction &lt; 50%, the patient&#xD;
                  will be excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has a history of other malignancies within the last 3 years, except for&#xD;
                  non-melanoma skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the cervix&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient is confirmed to have clinically significant or recent (within 14 days&#xD;
                  prior to starting treatment) acute gastrointestinal disease presenting as&#xD;
                  diarrhea and/or coloenteritis as a main symptom (ie, acute enteritis,&#xD;
                  malabsorption, or Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events [CTCAE, version&#xD;
                  5.0] grade 2 or above diarrhea due to other etiologies)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient is unable to take drugs orally due to disorders or diseases that may&#xD;
                  affect gastrointestinal (GI) function, such as inflammatory bowel diseases (eg,&#xD;
                  Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis) or malabsorption syndrome, or procedures&#xD;
                  that may affect gastrointestinal function, such as gastrectomy, enterectomy, or&#xD;
                  colectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has an active liver disease or biliary tract disease (except for&#xD;
                  Gilbert's disease, asymptomatic biliary stones, liver metastasis, or stabilized&#xD;
                  chronic liver diseases). Patients with liver cirrhosis at a level of Child-Pugh B&#xD;
                  (or worse) or history of hepatic encephalopathy or clinically meaningful ascites&#xD;
                  resulting from cirrhosis are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has known hypersensitivity to poziotinib or ramucirumab&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has an active uncontrolled infection, underlying medical condition, or&#xD;
                  other serious illness that would impair the ability of the patient to receive&#xD;
                  protocol treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has experienced any grade 3-4 GI bleeding within 3 months prior to first&#xD;
                  dose of protocol therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has a history of deep vein thrombosis (DVT), pulmonary embolism (PE), or&#xD;
                  any other significant thromboembolism (venous port or catheter thrombosis or&#xD;
                  superficial venous thrombosis are not considered &quot;significant&quot;) during the 3&#xD;
                  months prior to first dose of protocol therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The patient has experienced any arterial thromboembolic events, including but not&#xD;
                  limited to myocardial infarction, transient ischemic attack, cerebrovascular&#xD;
                  accident, or unstable angina, within 6 months prior to first dose of protocol&#xD;
                  therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The patient has uncontrolled or poorly-controlled hypertension (&gt; 160 mmHg&#xD;
                  systolic or &gt; 100 mmHg diastolic for &gt; 4 weeks) despite standard medical&#xD;
                  management&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If they experience hemoptysis (defined as bright red blood or &gt;= 1/2 teaspoon)&#xD;
                  within 2 months prior to first dose of protocol therapy or with radiographic&#xD;
                  evidence of intratumor cavitation or has radiologically documented evidence of&#xD;
                  major blood vessel invasion or encasement by cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has had recent major surgery within 28 days prior to starting study&#xD;
                  treatment, or minor surgery/subcutaneous venous access device placement within 7&#xD;
                  days prior to the first dose of protocol therapy. The patient has elective or&#xD;
                  planned major surgery to be performed during the course of the clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The patient has a prior history of GI perforation/fistula (within 6 months of&#xD;
                  first dose of protocol therapy) or risk factors for perforation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The patient has a serious or nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture within 28&#xD;
                  days prior to first dose of protocol therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has EGFR T790M mutation or other acquired EGFR exon 20point mutation&#xD;
                  following prior treatment with an EGFR-tyrosine kinase inhibitor (TKI)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previous treatment with poziotinib or ramucirumab&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient is concurrently receiving chemotherapy, biologics, immunotherapy for&#xD;
                  cancer treatment; systemic anti-cancer treatment or investigational treatment&#xD;
                  should not be used within 2 weeks; local radiation therapy for bone pain may be&#xD;
                  allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has a history of congestive heart failure (CHF) class III/IV according to&#xD;
                  the New York Heart Association (NYHA) functional classification or serious&#xD;
                  cardiac arrhythmias requiring treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has a high risk of cardiac disease, as determined by the investigator,&#xD;
                  may undergo either echocardiogram (ECHO) or multi-gated acquisition (MUGA) during&#xD;
                  screening and if the patient has a cardiac ejection fraction &lt; 50%, the patient&#xD;
                  will be excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has a history of other malignancies within the last 3 years, except for&#xD;
                  non-melanoma skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the cervix&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient is confirmed to have clinically significant or recent (within 14 days&#xD;
                  prior to starting treatment) acute gastrointestinal disease presenting as&#xD;
                  diarrhea and/or coloenteritis as a main symptom (ie, acute enteritis,&#xD;
                  malabsorption, or Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events [CTCAE, version&#xD;
                  5.0] grade 2 or above diarrhea due to other etiologies)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient is unable to take drugs orally due to disorders or diseases that may&#xD;
                  affect gastrointestinal (GI) function, such as inflammatory bowel diseases (eg,&#xD;
                  Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis) or malabsorption syndrome, or procedures&#xD;
                  that may affect gastrointestinal function, such as gastrectomy, enterectomy, or&#xD;
                  colectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has an active liver disease or biliary tract disease (except for&#xD;
                  Gilbert's disease, asymptomatic biliary stones, liver metastasis, or stabilized&#xD;
                  chronic liver diseases). Patients with liver cirrhosis at a level of Child-Pugh B&#xD;
                  (or worse) or history of hepatic encephalopathy or clinically meaningful ascites&#xD;
                  resulting from cirrhosis are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has known hypersensitivity to poziotinib or ramucirumab&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has an active uncontrolled infection, underlying medical condition, or&#xD;
                  other serious illness that would impair the ability of the patient to receive&#xD;
                  protocol treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has experienced any grade 3-4 GI bleeding within 3 months prior to first&#xD;
                  dose of protocol therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has a history of deep vein thrombosis (DVT), pulmonary embolism (PE), or&#xD;
                  any other significant thromboembolism (venous port or catheter thrombosis or&#xD;
                  superficial venous thrombosis are not considered &quot;significant&quot;) during the 3&#xD;
                  months prior to first dose of protocol therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The patient has experienced any arterial thromboembolic events, including but not&#xD;
                  limited to myocardial infarction, transient ischemic attack, cerebrovascular&#xD;
                  accident, or unstable angina, within 6 months prior to first dose of protocol&#xD;
                  therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The patient has uncontrolled or poorly-controlled hypertension (&gt; 160 mmHg&#xD;
                  systolic or &gt; 100 mmHg diastolic for &gt; 4 weeks) despite standard medical&#xD;
                  management&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If they experience hemoptysis (defined as bright red blood or &gt;= 1/2 teaspoon)&#xD;
                  within 2 months prior to first dose of protocol therapy or with radiographic&#xD;
                  evidence of intratumor cavitation or has radiologically documented evidence of&#xD;
                  major blood vessel invasion or encasement by cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has had recent major surgery within 28 days prior to starting study&#xD;
                  treatment, or minor surgery/subcutaneous venous access device placement within 7&#xD;
                  days prior to the first dose of protocol therapy. The patient has elective or&#xD;
                  planned major surgery to be performed during the course of the clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The patient has a prior history of GI perforation/fistula (within 6 months of&#xD;
                  first dose of protocol therapy) or risk factors for perforation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The patient has a serious or nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture within 28&#xD;
                  days prior to first dose of protocol therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient is pregnant or breast-feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The patient is receiving chronic antiplatelet therapy, including dipyridamole or&#xD;
                  clopidogrel, or similar agents. Once-daily aspirin use (maximum dose 325 mg/day)&#xD;
                  is permitted&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The presence of interstitial lung disease, drug-related pneumonitis, or radiation&#xD;
                  pneumonitis at screening&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yasir Elamin, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yasir Elamin, MD</last_name>
    <phone>713-792-6363</phone>
    <email>yyelamin@mdanderson.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>MD Anderson Cancer Center Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

