<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05049798</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CR108938</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>CNTO1959PSA4001</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05049798</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Guselkumab and Interleukin-17 (IL-17) Inhibitor Therapies in Participants With Psoriatic Arthritis in Routine Clinical Practice</brief_title>
  <acronym>PsABIOnd</acronym>
  <official_title>Assessment of Guselkumab (Tremfya) and IL-17 Inhibitor Therapies in Patients With Psoriatic Arthritis in Routine Clinical Practice; A Prospective, Observational Cohort Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Pharmaceutica N.V., Belgium</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Pharmaceutica N.V., Belgium</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate treatment persistence with guselkumab and&#xD;
      interleukin-17 inhibitor (IL-17i) initiated at enrollment into this study (PsABIOnd).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Start and Stop Date of Guselkumab, as Applicable, For Each Participant</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The start and stop date, (first and last administration date, respectively) of guselkumab, as applicable, for each participant will be collected to document treatment persistence.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Start and Stop Date of Interleukin-17 Inhibitor (IL-17i), as Applicable, For Each Participant</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The start and stop date (first and last administration date respectively) of IL-17i, as applicable, for each participant will be collected to document treatment persistence.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in 66 and 68 Joint Counts for Swelling and Tenderness, Respectively</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in 66 and 68 joint counts for swelling and tenderness, respectively will be reported. Joints assessed include the distal interphalangeal, proximal interphalangeal, and metacarpophalangeal joints of the hands; the wrist, elbow, shoulder, acromioclavicular, sternoclavicular, temporomandibular, hip (excluded for swelling), knee, ankle, and midtarsal joints; and the metatarsophalangeal and proximal interphalangeal joints of the feet.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Rheumatologist's Global Assessment of Disease Activity-Psoriatic Arthritis (PGA-PsA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The PGA-PsA will be documented using a Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) that ranges from &quot;no PsA activity&quot; (0 Millimeter [mm]) to &quot;extremely active PsA&quot; (100 mm).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Assessment of Dactylitis</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The presence of and total number of digits of the hands and feet (that is, 0 to 20) with dactylitis will be documented.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Assessment of Enthesitis using Leeds Enthesitis Index (LEI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The presence and a score of enthesitis will be documented using the LEI to evaluate the presence (score of 1) or absence (score of 0) of pain by applying local pressure to the following entheses: the lateral epicondyles (left and right), medial femoral condyles (left and right), and Achilles tendon insertions (left and right).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Nail Involvement</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Nail involvement will be documented by recording the total number of nails of the hands and feet (that is, 0 to 20) with psoriatic nail changes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Body Surface Area (BSA) Psoriasis (PSO) Skin Involvement</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The BSA score indicates the surface area of the participant's body effected by psoriasis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in C-reactive Protein (CRP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in CRP will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Minimal Disease Activity (MDA)/ Very Low Disease Activity (VLDA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from Baseline in MDA/VLDA will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Clinical Disease Activity Index for Psoriatic Arthritis (cDAPSA/DAPSA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>DAPSA assesses the joint domain of PsA and is derived from the sum of the following components: Participant's assessment of pain on VAS (in centimeters), Participant's Global Assessment of Disease Activity on VAS (in centimeters), 66 and 68 joint counts for swelling and tenderness, respectively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response as a Measure of Clinical Improvement in cDAPSA/DAPSA</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Response is defined as a clinical improvement in cDAPSA/DAPSA. DAPSA assesses the joint domain of PsA and is derived from the sum of the following components: Participant's assessment of pain on VAS (in centimeters), Participant's Global Assessment of Disease Activity on VAS (in centimeters), 66 and 68 joint counts for swelling and tenderness, respectively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Start and Stop Dates of All Treatments and the Sequence of Treatment Lines</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Start and stop dates of all treatments and the sequence of treatment lines will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Adverse Events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant participating in a clinical study that does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the pharmaceutical/biological agent under study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>BSA PSO Skin Involvement</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The BSA score indicates the surface area of the participant's body affected by psoriasis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rheumatic Disease Comorbidity Index</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of comorbid medical conditions of the study participants for the Rheumatic Disease Comorbidity Index will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Fibromyalgia Rapid Screening Tool (FiRST)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>FiRST will be used to help determine whether participants have chronic widespread pain or fibromyalgia syndrome at entry into the study. The FiRST is a validated questionnaire consisting of a combination of 6 items that can detect chronic widespread pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in European Quality of Life (EuroQoL) 5-Dimensions 5-Levels Questionnaire (EQ-5D-5L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The EQ-5D-5L is a standardized instrument for use as a measure of health outcome, primarily designed for self-completion by respondents. The EQ-5D-5L descriptive system comprises the following 5 dimensions: mobility, self-care, usual activities, pain/discomfort and anxiety/depression. Each of the 5 dimensions is divided into 5 levels of perceived problems, where Level 1: no problem, Level 2: slight problems, Level 3: moderate problems, Level 4: severe problems and Level 5: extreme problems.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Health Assessment Questionnaire-Disability Index (HAQ-DI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The functional status of the participants will be assessed by the HAQ-DI. This 20-question self-administered instrument assesses the degree of difficulty a person has in accomplishing tasks in 8 functional areas (dressing, arising, eating, walking, hygiene, reaching, gripping, and activities of daily living). The derived HAQ-DI ranges from 0, indicating no difficulty, to 3, indicating inability to perform a task in that area.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Psoriatic Arthritis Impact of Disease-12 (PsAID-12)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>PsAID-12 is a validated, self-administered questionnaire that assesses the impact of PsA on participants' lives. It consists of 12 questions, each answered using a numerical rating scale. Questions related to pain, skin problems, work and/or leisure activities, discomfort, embarrassment and/or shame, social participation, and anger, fear, and uncertainty, and depression are scored from 0 (none) to 10 (extreme), functional capacity and sleep disturbance are scored from 0 (no difficulty) to 10 (extreme difficulty) and coping is scored from 0 (very well) to 10 (very poorly).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Patient Global Disease Activity Visual Analog Scale (VAS) Scores</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Patient Global Disease Activity VAS is a self-administered assessment with scores ranging from &quot;very well&quot; (0 mm) to &quot;very poor&quot; (100 mm) that assesses disease activity over the past week.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Pain VAS Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The pain VAS is a self-administered assessment of average pain during the past week. The scale ranges from &quot;no pain&quot; (0 mm) to &quot;the worst possible pain&quot; (100 mm).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Bath Ankylosing Spondylitis Disease Activity Index (BASDAI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>BASDAI consists of a 1 through 10 scale (1 being no problem and 10 being the worst problem) which is used to answer 6 questions pertaining to the 5 major symptoms of ankylosing spondylitis: fatigue, spinal pain, joint pain/swelling, areas of localized tenderness (also called enthesitis, or inflammation of tendons and ligaments), morning stiffness duration, morning stiffness severity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Ankylosing Spondylitis Disease Activity Score - C-reactive protein (ASDAS-CRP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The ASDAS-CRP is a composite of 5 disease activity variables with only partial overlap. The 4 self-reported items included in this index are back pain (VAS), duration of morning stiffness, peripheral pain/swelling, and participant global assessment of disease activity; these are combined with the CRP value.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The DLQI is a dermatology-specific, validated, 10-question quality of life instrument used to measure the impact of skin disease on the quality of life of an affected person. Each question will address how much the participant's skin problem has affected their life and is scored as: 3 = very much, 2 = a lot, 1 = a little, 0 = not at all, or not relevant.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Patient Acceptable Symptom State (PASS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The PASS measures the level of symptoms beyond which participants consider themselves well. The PASS addresses the concepts of low disease activity, partial remission in symptoms, and well-being.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Work Productivity and Activity Impairment Questionnaire: Psoriatic Arthritis (WPAI: PsA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The WPAI: PsA is a validated, self-administered questionnaire that assesses work and activity impairment during the past 7 days. The WPAI: PsA produces 4 types of scores: absenteeism (work time missed), presenteeism (impairment at work/reduced on-the-job effectiveness), work productivity loss (overall work impairment/absenteeism plus presenteeism), and activity impairment. The WPAI: PsA outcomes are expressed as impairment percentages, with higher numbers indicating greater impairment and less productivity, that is, worse outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Treatment Satisfaction Questionnaire for Medication-9 (TSQM-9)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>TSQM-9 is a 9-item, validated, self-administered instrument used to assess participant's satisfaction with medication. The three domains assessed are effectiveness, convenience, and side effects of the medication.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants Switching or Stopping Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of Participants switching or stopping treatment (including reasons for discontinuation) will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>Arthritis, Psoriatic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1: Guselkumab</arm_group_label>
    <description>Data as available from participant's source medical records will be collected for adult participants with a confirmed diagnosis of Psoriatic Arthritis (PsA) who are starting guselkumab as a first, second, third, or fourth line of PsA biologic therapy either as monotherapy or with other medications per routine clinical practice.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2: Interleukin-17 inhibitor (IL-17i)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Data as available from participant's source medical records will be collected for adult participants with a confirmed diagnosis of PsA who are starting IL-17i as a first, second, third, or fourth line of PsA biologic therapy either as monotherapy or with other medications per routine clinical practice.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Guselkumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will not receive any intervention as a part of this study. Participants who are initiating the treatment with guselkumab, will be observed according to standard clinical practice.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1: Guselkumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>TREMFYA</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>IL-17i</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will not receive any intervention as a part of this study. Participants who are initiating the treatment with IL-17i, will be observed according to standard clinical practice.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2: Interleukin-17 inhibitor (IL-17i)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study population consists of participants initially treated for Psoriatic Arthritis&#xD;
        (PsA) with guselkumab or interleukin-17 inhibitor (IL-17i) per routine clinical practice in&#xD;
        accordance with clinical guidelines.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a confirmed diagnosis of PsA as determined by a rheumatologist with reference to&#xD;
             Classification criteria for Psoriatic Arthritis (CASPAR)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Start guselkumab or any approved IL-17i as a first, second, third, or fourth line of&#xD;
             biologic disease-modifying antirheumatic drugs (bDMARD) therapy for the indication of&#xD;
             PsA as part of standard clinical practice (according to local label, local&#xD;
             regulations, and/or reimbursement requirements) at the time of enrollment into the&#xD;
             observational study or within a maximum of 2 months after the initial baseline visit&#xD;
             or after repeated baseline data collection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sign a participation agreement/Informed consent form (ICF) allowing data collection&#xD;
             and source data verification in accordance with local requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to read, understand, and intend to comply with completion of all Electronic&#xD;
             patient-reported outcome (ePRO) instruments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The treatment decision must be taken by the participating rheumatologist prior to, and&#xD;
             independently of the participant's inclusion into the study, following clinical&#xD;
             practice in accordance with local and overarching guidelines and local regulations&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Start guselkumab or an IL-17i therapy as fifth or further line of biologic treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have already taken a specific IL-17i or IL-23i treatment and are planning on re-taking&#xD;
             that specific treatment again&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling or unable to participate in long-term data collection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received an investigational drug (including investigational vaccines) or used an&#xD;
             invasive investigational medical device within 30 days before the start of the study&#xD;
             (that is, signing of informed consent)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently enrolled in any interventional study or any Janssen-sponsored observational&#xD;
             clinical study (contemporary participation into observational studies or registries&#xD;
             not sponsored by Janssen is acceptable)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janssen Pharmaceutica N.V., Belgium Clinical Trial</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Janssen Pharmaceutica N.V., Belgium</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Study Contact</last_name>
    <phone>844-434-4210</phone>
    <email>JNJ.CT@sylogent.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Barmherzige Brüder Krankenhaus Graz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Graz</city>
        <zip>8020</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Praxis Prim. Priv.Doz. Dr. Burkhard Leeb</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hollabrunn</city>
        <zip>2020</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kepler Universitätsklinikum GmbH</name>
      <address>
        <city>Linz</city>
        <zip>4021</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>LK Weinviertel Stockerau</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stockerau</city>
        <zip>2000</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medizinische Universität Wien</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vienna</city>
        <zip>1090</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Evang. Krankenhaus Gemein. Betriebgesm. Mbh</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wien</city>
        <zip>A-1100</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Pellegrin CHU Bordeaux</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bordeaux</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Pitié-Salpétrière</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75651</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hopital Purpan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse</city>
        <zip>31059</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rheuma-Praxis Bayreuth</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bayreuth</city>
        <zip>95444</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rheumatologische Schwerpunktpraxis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berlin</city>
        <zip>12161</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Schwerpunktpraxis für Rheumatologie und Klinische Immunologi</name>
      <address>
        <city>Burghausen</city>
        <zip>84489</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Düsseldorf</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dusseldorf</city>
        <zip>40225</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitatsklinikum Frankfurt</name>
      <address>
        <city>Frankfurt</city>
        <zip>60590</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rheumapraxis Dr. Liebhaber</name>
      <address>
        <city>Halle-Saale</city>
        <zip>6128</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Praxis fur Klinische Studien und Praxis fur Orthopadie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>22415</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rheumatologie im Struenseehaus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>22767</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rheumazentrum Ruhrgebiet</name>
      <address>
        <city>Herne</city>
        <zip>44649</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Krankenhaus Porz am Rhein</name>
      <address>
        <city>Koln</city>
        <zip>51149</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rheumatologische Praxis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leipzig</city>
        <zip>04109</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rheumatologische Praxis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Magdeburg</city>
        <zip>39104</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Praxiszentrum St. Bonifatius</name>
      <address>
        <city>München</city>
        <zip>81541</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Praxis Thilo Klopsch</name>
      <address>
        <city>Neubrandenburg</city>
        <zip>17033</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rheumazentrum Ratingen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ratingen</city>
        <zip>40878</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Immunologisches Zentrum Vogelsang-Gommern GmbH</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vogelsang-Gommern</city>
        <zip>39245</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ospedale Regionale Cardarelli-Università degli Studi del Mol</name>
      <address>
        <city>Campobasso</city>
        <zip>86100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Azienda Ospedaliera Città della Salute e della Scienza di Torino</name>
      <address>
        <city>Torino</city>
        <zip>10126</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bakoulev Scientific Center For Cardiovascular Surgery Rams</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <zip>121552</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>FGBU Research Institute of Rheumatology named V.A.Nasonova</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <zip>190068</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>North-Western State Medical University named I.I. Mechnikov</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Petersburg</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City Hospital #3</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tomsk</city>
        <zip>634045</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hosp. Univ. A Coruña</name>
      <address>
        <city>A Coruña</city>
        <zip>15006</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hosp. Clinic I Provincial de Barcelona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08036</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hosp. Univ. de Basurto</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bilbao</city>
        <zip>48013</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hosp. Gral. Univ. de Castellon</name>
      <address>
        <city>Castellon</city>
        <zip>12004</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hosp. Gral. Univ. de Elche</name>
      <address>
        <city>Elche</city>
        <zip>03203</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Complejo hospitalario de Granada</name>
      <address>
        <city>Granada</city>
        <zip>18016</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hosp. Univ. 12 de Octubre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28041</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hosp. Univ. de Getafe</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28905</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hosp. Univ. Central de Asturias</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oviedo</city>
        <zip>33011</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitetssjukhuset Örebro</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orebro</city>
        <zip>70185</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Akademiskt Specialistcentrum centrum för reumatologi</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stockholm</city>
        <zip>113 65</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Akademiska Sjukhuset</name>
      <address>
        <city>Uppsala</city>
        <zip>75185</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nevill Hall Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Abergavenny</city>
        <zip>NP7 7EG</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wolfson Centre Royal United Hospitals</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bath</city>
        <zip>BA1 3NG</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Glasgow Royal Infirmary</name>
      <address>
        <city>Glasgow</city>
        <zip>650029</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hull Royal Infirmary</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hull</city>
        <zip>HU3 2JZ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chapel Allerton Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leeds</city>
        <zip>LS7 4SA</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kings College Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SE5 9RS</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Central Manchester University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Manchester</city>
        <zip>M13 9WL</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Newcastle upon Tyne Hospitals NHS Trust - Freeman Hospit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newcastle Upon Tyne</city>
        <zip>NE7 7DN</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Southampton General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Southampton</city>
        <zip>SO16 6YD</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Haywood Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Staffordshire</city>
        <zip>ST6 7AG</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stamford and Rutland hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stamford</city>
        <zip>PE9 1UA</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>Sweden</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://pam.sylogent.com/cr/CR108938</url>
    <description>To learn how to participate in this trial please click here.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 31, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 20, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Arthritis, Psoriatic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

