<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05045768</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>348/28-7-2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05045768</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Postinfectious Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Gelsectan</brief_title>
  <official_title>Treatment of Postinfectious Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Noninfective Irritable Bowel Syndrome With Gelsectan</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Evangelismos Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Evangelismos Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS) is one of the most common conditions diagnosed in&#xD;
      gastroenterology practice. Acute infectious gastroenteritis represents the strongest known&#xD;
      risk factor for IBS development; a condition known as post-infection IBS (PI-IBS). PI-IBS&#xD;
      patients are more likely than sporadic IBS patients to exhibit a diarrhea-predominant&#xD;
      phenotype. The investigators plan to prospectively recruit two groups of patients: patients&#xD;
      with diarrhea-predominant post-infectious IBSand patients with diarrhea predominant classical&#xD;
      IBS (non PI-IBS) who will be used as controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients included in the study will receive for 28 days a capsule containing Tamarind seed&#xD;
      polysaccharide containing xyloglucan, combined with a pea protein reticulated with grape seed&#xD;
      extractand a prebiotic, the xilooligosaccharide (Gelsectan, Devintec Sagl) twice daily.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) is a functional disorder of alimentary system, which is&#xD;
      recently considered as an erroneous gut-brain interaction. IBS is one of the most common&#xD;
      conditions diagnosed in gastroenterology practice. Its prevalence ranges between 7-16% in&#xD;
      western countries and is more common in females and younger individuals. Although the&#xD;
      etiology of IBS is still obscure, its pathophysiology is dominated by a combination of both&#xD;
      psychological factors and gastrointestinal dysfunction. Recent efforts have allowed&#xD;
      identification of several peripheral micro-organic abnormalities. These include changes in&#xD;
      gut microbiota, low grade mucosal inflammation, and epithelial dysfunction. Acute infectious&#xD;
      gastroenteritis represents the strongest known risk factor for IBS development; a condition&#xD;
      known as post-infectiousIBS (PI-IBS). According to a recent survey PI-IBS accounts for around&#xD;
      13% of all IBS. Today the diagnostic criteria for PI-IBS proposed by the Rome Foundation&#xD;
      Working Team are based on the Rome IV criteria. These criteria were not part of the original&#xD;
      Rome IV document as they were prepared after the release of Rome IV publications and need to&#xD;
      be fulfilled for the last 3 months with symptom onset at least 6 months before diagnosis. The&#xD;
      acute infectious gastroenteritis is ideally diagnosed by stool culture (although only&#xD;
      occasionally obtained in community subjects), validated molecular biology analyses (e.g.,&#xD;
      polymerase chain reaction) or by the presence of ≥2 of the following: fever, vomiting, or&#xD;
      diarrhea. The investigators plan to prospectively recruit two groups of patients: patients&#xD;
      with diarrhea-predominant post-infectious IBSand patients with diarrhea predominant classical&#xD;
      IBS (non PI-IBS) who will be used as controls. Patients included in the study will receive&#xD;
      for 28 days a capsule containing Xyloglucan, Pea Protein and Grape Seed Extract and a&#xD;
      prebiotic Xylo-oligosaccharides (Gelsectan, Devintec sagl) twice daily. Drugs that might have&#xD;
      any effect on intestinal motility or secretion will not be allowed during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients responding to treatment will be those in whom diarrhea disappeared, i.e. reported&#xD;
      two or less non-watery stools emissions per day (stool of type 5 or less on the Bristol&#xD;
      scale). Response to treatment will be assessed in the two group of patients immediately after&#xD;
      the end of the 28-day administration of Gelsectan; however all patients will be followed for&#xD;
      another 3 months and long term response to treatment will be assessed in that time period as&#xD;
      well. The presence and intensity of abdominal pain and flatulence will also be measured on a&#xD;
      seven-point Likert scale (7 very much better, 6 much better, 5 somewhat better, 4 same, 3&#xD;
      somewhat worse, 2 much worse, 1 very much worse). These measurements will be made in all&#xD;
      patients immediately at the end of the 28-day administration of Gelsectan and at the end of&#xD;
      the 3 month follow up period as well. Treatment response will be compared between the two&#xD;
      groups using the chi squared test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety and tolerability will be monitored during the entire study period through adverse&#xD;
      events occurence.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Disappearance of diarrhea</measure>
    <time_frame>After the end of the 28-day administration of xyloglycan</time_frame>
    <description>Two or less non-watery stools emissions per day (stool of type 5 or less on the Bristol scale).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Postinfectious ibs and diarrhea predominant classical IBS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Capsule containing Tamarind seed polysaccharide containing xyloglucan, combined with a pea protein reticulated with grape seed extractand a prebiotic, the xilooligosaccharide (Gelsectan, Devintec sagl) twice daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>(Gelsectan, Devintec Sagl)</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients included in the study will receive for 28 days a capsule containing Xyloglucan, Pea Protein and Grape Seed Extract and a prebiotic Xylo-oligosaccharide (Gelsectan, Devintec sagl) twice daily.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Postinfectious ibs and diarrhea predominant classical IBS</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients with diarrhea-predominant post-infectious IBSand patients with diarrhea&#xD;
        predominant classical IBS (non PI-IBS) who will be used as controls&#xD;
&#xD;
        Diagnosis of IBS will be made according to the ROME iV criteria as following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Recurrent abdominal pain, on average, at least 1 day/week in the last 3 months, associated&#xD;
        with two or more of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Related to defecation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Associated with a change in frequency of stool&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Associated with a change in form (appearance) of stool. The above-mentioned criteria&#xD;
             have to be fulfilled for the last 3 months with symptom onset at least 6 months before&#xD;
             diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Diagnosis of post infectious IBS will be made according to the Rome Foundation Working Team&#xD;
        criteria as following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Recurrent abdominal pain, on average, at least 1 day per week in the last 3 months, with&#xD;
        symptom onset at least 6 months before diagnosis, associated with two of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. defecation&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. a change in frequency of stool&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. a change in form (appearance) of stool Symptom development immediately after&#xD;
             resolution of acute infectious gastroenteritis&#xD;
&#xD;
        Infectious gastroenteritis should be defined by positive stool culture in a symptomatic&#xD;
        individual or presence of two of the following acute symptoms (when stool culture not&#xD;
        available):&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. fever&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. vomiting&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. diarrhea&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should not meet criteria for IBS before onset of acute illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  We will exclude patients who are pregnant, who have an oncology history (since these&#xD;
             patients might exhibit diarrhea due to their underlying illness) and patients with&#xD;
             alcohol dependence (due to the non-compliance shown by these patients) and patients&#xD;
             with known hypersensitivity or allergy to any of the ingredients included in&#xD;
             Gelsectan.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Evangelismos Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <state>Attiki</state>
        <zip>10676</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nikos Viazis, Dr</last_name>
      <phone>+302132041000</phone>
      <phone_ext>1609</phone_ext>
      <email>nikos.viazis@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Christos Pontas, Dr</last_name>
      <phone>+302132041000</phone>
      <phone_ext>1273</phone_ext>
      <email>chrispontas@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Evangelismos Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nikos Viazis</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Consultant Gastroenterologist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>irritable bowel syndrome</keyword>
  <keyword>postinfectious</keyword>
  <keyword>xyloglycan</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

