<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05049681</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SHR-1210-EC020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05049681</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Anti-PD-1 Antibody SHR-1210 Plus Apatinib vs SHR-1210 as Second-Line Treatment of Advanced Esophageal Squamous Cell</brief_title>
  <official_title>Anti-PD-1 Antibody SHR-1210 Combined With Apatinib Versus SHR-1210 in the Second-line Treatment of Advanced Esophageal Squamous Cell Carcinoma：A Multicentre，Randomized， Open Label，Phase 3 Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Feng Wang</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to observe and evaluate the efficacy and safety of Anti-PD-1&#xD;
      antibody SHR-1210 plus apatinib versus SHR-1210 as second-line treatment of advanced&#xD;
      esophageal squamous cell.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The incidence of esophageal cancer is ranked seventh in the world, and the mortality rate&#xD;
      ranks sixth in the world. At present, the first-line treatment of advanced esophageal cancer&#xD;
      is mainly based on the combination of paclitaxel, cisplatin and fluorouracil. After the&#xD;
      failure of first-line treatment, there is no standard second-line treatment. Recently the&#xD;
      study of KEYNOTE181, ATTRACTION-3 and ESCORT had confirmed that PD-1 single drug in the&#xD;
      second-line treatment of esophageal cancer is better than the previous traditional&#xD;
      chemotherapy, and has become a new standard treatment. In order to further improve the&#xD;
      therapeutic efficacy and prognosis of advanced esophageal squamous cell carcinoma, we&#xD;
      designed this phase III clinical study to compare the efficacy and safety of shr-1210&#xD;
      combined with apatinib and shr-1210 in the second-line treatment of esophageal squamous cell&#xD;
      carcinoma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 5, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 20, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival(OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 year</time_frame>
    <description>the time from Randomization until death from any reason</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 year</time_frame>
    <description>the time from Randomization to the first disease progression or death from any cause</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>the proportion of patients with complete response or partial response determined by the investigator according to Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) v1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Control Rate (DCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>the proportion of patients with a best overall response of confirmed complete or partial response, or stable disease (CR+ PR + SD)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response（DOR）</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 year</time_frame>
    <description>the time from the first response date to the first disease progression or death date</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to response（TTP）</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>the time from treatment to first confirmed tumour response</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>6-, 9- and 12-month OS rates</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>overall survival rates at 6-, 9- and 12-month</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>adverse events(Safety)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 year</time_frame>
    <description>adverse events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">234</enrollment>
  <condition>Esophageal Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SHR-1210（Camrelizumab）+Apatinib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Apatinib 250mg, q.d.po; SHR-1210（Camrelizumab） 200 mg，Intravenous injection,q2W ,A course of treatment need 28 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SHR-1210（Camrelizumab）</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>SHR-1210（Camrelizumab） 200 mg，Intravenous injection. q2W ,A course of treatment need 28 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Camrelizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>SHR-1210（Camrelizumab） 200 mg，Intravenous injection， q2W ，A course of treatment need 28 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SHR-1210（Camrelizumab）</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>SHR-1210（Camrelizumab）+Apatinib</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SHR-1210</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Apatinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Apatinib 250mg, q.d.po</description>
    <arm_group_label>SHR-1210（Camrelizumab）+Apatinib</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Aged 18-75 years, males or females;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Histologically or cytologically confirmed as ESCC, locally advanced and unresectable,&#xD;
             with local recurrence (local lymph node metastases) or distant metastases;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Having progressed or being intolerant to first-line systemic chemotherapy (including&#xD;
             chemotherapy based on cisplatin, taxol or fluorouracil). Patients are also eligible if&#xD;
             they progress after maintenance treatment following the first-line chemotherapy, or if&#xD;
             patients with postoperative recurrence or metastasis progress after concurrent&#xD;
             radiochemotherapy. As for the radical concurrent chemoradiotherapy,&#xD;
             neoadjuvant/adjuvant treatment (chemotherapy or radiochemotherapy), if patients&#xD;
             progress during the treatment or within six months after treatment, it is considered&#xD;
             as a failure of first-line treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. According to the Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumour (RECIST 1.1), there is&#xD;
             at least one measurable lesion, which has not received any local treatment, such as&#xD;
             radiotherapy (if the lesion within the region of the previous radiotherapy is&#xD;
             confirmed to progress and satisfies RECIST1.1, it can be also selected as the target&#xD;
             lesion) ;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Tissue samples should be provided for biomarker analysis. The newly harvested tissues&#xD;
             are preferred. If the newly harvested tissues are not available, 5-8 archival paraffin&#xD;
             sections (5 um thick) can be provided;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. ECOG: 0~1;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Expected survival time ≥ 12 weeks;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Adequate function of major organs defined as:(1) Routine blood test: a. HB ≥ 90 g/L;&#xD;
             b. ANC ≥ 1.5 × 109/L; c. PLT ≥ 80 × 109/L;(2) Biochemical test: a. ALB ≥ 30 g/L; b.&#xD;
             ALT and AST ≤ 2.5 ULN; if there is no liver metastasis, ALT and AST ≤ 5 ULN; c. TBIL ≤&#xD;
             1.5ULN; d. Plasma Cr ≤ 1.5 ULN or creatinine clearance rate (CCr) ≥ 60 mL/min;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Doppler ultrasound evaluation: Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) ≥ lower limit&#xD;
             of normal (50%).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Women of childbearing age should consent to take contraception measures during the&#xD;
             study period and within 6 months after the end of the study (eg., intrauterine device,&#xD;
             oral contraceptive pills or condoms). The subjects must be negative for the serum or&#xD;
             urine pregnancy test within 7 days before the recruitment. The female subjects must be&#xD;
             non-lactating women. Males should consent to take contraception measures during the&#xD;
             study period and within 6 months after the end of the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. All subjects are recruited on a voluntary basis and sign the informed consent. They&#xD;
             are required to be compliant with the study and cooperative with the follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who have any active autoimmune diseases or a past history of autoimmune&#xD;
             diseases (including but not limited to the following: autoimmune hepatitis,&#xD;
             interstitial pneumonia, uveitis, enteritis, hepatitis, hypophysitis, vasculitis,&#xD;
             nephritis, and hyperthyroidism; leukoderma. Subjects with fully remitted childhood&#xD;
             asthma and no need for any intervention during adulthood can be included; those still&#xD;
             having the need for bronchodilators for medical intervention cannot be included);&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who are currently on immunosuppressors or systemic hormone therapy for&#xD;
             immunosuppressive purposes (dose &gt; 10 mg/day, prednisone or other hormones with&#xD;
             equivalent efficacy), and continue taking them within 2 weeks before recruitment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. ESCC patients with active bleeding in primary lesions;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ESCC patients in whom the primary lesions are not surgically resected and are not&#xD;
             shrunken in size after radiotherapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients who have received treatment with VEGFR inhibitors, such as sorafenib,&#xD;
             sunitinib, and apatinib;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any of the following conditions that will interfere with oral medications: unable to&#xD;
             swallow, having received gastroenterectomy, chronic diarrhea and intestinal&#xD;
             obstruction;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Brain metastasis or brain metastases that have disappeared in less than 3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients who have any severe and/or uncontrolled diseases, including: poor blood&#xD;
             pressure control (systolic pressure ≥ 150 mmHg or diastolic pressure ≥ 100 mmHg);&#xD;
             having myocardial ischemia or myocardial infarction and arrhythmia of Grade 1 and&#xD;
             above (including QT interval ≥ 480 ms) and cardiac insufficiency of Grade 1; active or&#xD;
             uncontrollable severe infection; liver diseases, such as decompensated liver failure,&#xD;
             active hepatitis B (HBV-DNA ≥ 104 copy number/mL or 2000 IU/mL) or hepatitis C&#xD;
             (positive for anti-HCV antibodies, and HCV-RNA higher than the lower limit of&#xD;
             detection with the analytical method); routine urine test indicates urine protein ≥++&#xD;
             and confirms that the 24-hour urinary protein quantification&gt;1.0 g;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients whose wounds or bone fractures remain unhealed for a long period of time;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Pneumorrhagia &gt; NCI-CTC AE Grade1 within four weeks before recruitment; bleeding at&#xD;
             other positions &gt;NCI-CTC AE Grade 2 within four weeks before recruitment; having a&#xD;
             bleeding tendency (eg., active peptic ulcer) or currently receiving thrombolytic or&#xD;
             anticoagulant therapy, such as warfarin, heparin, or their analogs;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients who have experienced arterial/venous thrombotic events within six months,&#xD;
             such as cerebrovascular accidents (including transient ischemic attack), deep venous&#xD;
             thrombosis and pulmonary embolism;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. The invasion of important blood vessels by the tumour or a high probability of the&#xD;
             invasion of important blood vessels by the tumor that may lead to lethal hemorrhage in&#xD;
             the study period ahead, as judged by the investigator according to the radiological&#xD;
             examination;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Pregnancy or lactation;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patients who have a history of other malignancies in the past five years (except for&#xD;
             the cured basal cell carcinoma and cervical carcinoma in situ);&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Patients who have a history of psychotropic drug abuse and unable to quit or having&#xD;
             mental disorders;&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Patients who have participated in other clinical trials of drugs in the past four&#xD;
             weeks;&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Patients who have concomitant diseases that may severely impair the safety of patients&#xD;
             or make the patients unable to complete the study, as judged by the investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Other patients who are considered inappropriate for participation by the investigator.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Feng Wang</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Feng Wang</last_name>
    <phone>13938244776</phone>
    <email>zzuwangfeng@zzu.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 20, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Feng Wang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>doctor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Apatinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

