<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05044442</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SB_T1D_V1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05044442</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>HIT on Hypoglycaemic Risk in T1D</brief_title>
  <official_title>Can High Intensity Interval Training Reduce Fear of Hypoglycaemia and Improve Glycaemic Control in People With Type 1 Diabetes?</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Liverpool John Moores University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Society for Endocrinology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Royal Liverpool University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Exeter</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Liverpool John Moores University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There is clear evidence that regular exercise improves wellbeing and reduces the risk of&#xD;
      diabetes related complications in people with type 1 diabetes. However, many people with type&#xD;
      1 diabetes do not exercise regularly. The primary reason for this is fear of hypoglycaemia&#xD;
      and loss of glycaemic control associated with exercise. This loss of glycaemic control is&#xD;
      associated with traditional moderate intensity continous aerobic exercise advocated in the&#xD;
      guidelines for exercise in people with type 1 diabetes. Recent work (unpublished) from our&#xD;
      lab suggests high intensity interval training (HIT) may reduce the risk of hypoglycaemia in&#xD;
      people with type 1 diabetes, however stronger evidence is needed before firm conclusions can&#xD;
      be drawn.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, the aim of this study is to determine the effects of HIT on glycaemic control in&#xD;
      people with type 1 diabetes compared to no exercise and traditional moderate intensity&#xD;
      continous exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      24 people with type 1 diabetes will be recruited to complete a randomised counterbalanced&#xD;
      cross over study comparing 3x 2-week interventions periods. During these intervention periods&#xD;
      participant will maintain their habitual lifestyle but complete either no exercise (control),&#xD;
      traditional moderate intensity continous exercise or high intensity interval training.&#xD;
      Throughout the intervention periods participants glycaemic control will be monitored using a&#xD;
      flash glucose monitor.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Recruitment 24 people with type 1 diabetes (T1D) will be recruited through local advertising,&#xD;
      e.g. within the Liverpool Type 1 Diabetes (LIVT1D) Group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Protocol The study will use a randomised counterbalanced crossover design, whereby&#xD;
      participants will complete 3x 2-week intervention periods; control (no exercise), moderate&#xD;
      intensity continous training (MICT) and high intensity interval training (HIT).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention period Participants will complete 3x 2-week intervention periods identical in&#xD;
      all respects except for the type of exercise completed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The day before each intervention period participants will attend the lab at Liverpool John&#xD;
      Moores University to have an Abbot Freestyle Libre® flash glucose monitor inserted. To access&#xD;
      the data participants will be provide with a &quot;Reader&quot; in &quot;masked&quot; mode, ensuring the&#xD;
      participant cannot see the data produced. The Reader will also be used to record time of&#xD;
      exercise, insulin doses and blood glucose. Finally, participants will be provided with an&#xD;
      activity monitor (Actigraph®) for the duration of the intervention. Participants will also be&#xD;
      familiarised to the type of exercise being performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Addition, before the first intervention period participants will also be asked to download&#xD;
      MyFitnessPal® to record their daily food intake. An anonymous login email address and&#xD;
      password will be given to the participant for access to this App and associated website. A&#xD;
      1ml finger prick blood sample will also be taken on this first visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will then complete the 2-week intervention period. During this period&#xD;
      participants will be asked to maintain their habitual lifestyle, but only complete the&#xD;
      exercise prescribed by the research team (HIT or MICT), or no exercise during the control&#xD;
      intervention. Participants will be asked to exercise on day 1, 3, 6, 8, 10 and 13 of the&#xD;
      intervention period. Exercise will be completed at any time, but must not be performed&#xD;
      following an overnight fast. Participants will be asked to record their blood glucose&#xD;
      immediately before and after exercise and 2h post exercise using a finger stick blood sample&#xD;
      and automated glucose reader. If participants need to take additional carbohydrates to adjust&#xD;
      blood glucose following exercise the investigators will also ask for this to be recorded&#xD;
      (what was consumed and time after exercise) using a note in the MyFitnessPal app.&#xD;
      Participants will record all insulin doses, time of exercise and food intake for the duration&#xD;
      of the intervention period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Training MICT: Participants will be asked to complete 30 minutes of continuous exercise.&#xD;
      Participants will be able to choose any form of exercise (e.g. running or cycling) as long as&#xD;
      it is continous in nature. During exercise participants will be asked to maintain a heart&#xD;
      rate between 60-70% of their predicted maximum (220-age).&#xD;
&#xD;
      HIT: Participants will be provided with a training guide containing information on the&#xD;
      exercises. The programme involves repeated 1 minute bouts of simple on the spot movements&#xD;
      interspersed with 1 minute of rest. During the intervals participants will be advised to&#xD;
      reach a heart rate of approx. 80% of their predicted maximum heart rate (220-age). The 1&#xD;
      minute interval will be split between 2 consecutive 30 second exercises. The research team&#xD;
      have a library of 18 exercises, with 9 suggested exercise pairs. Participants will be advised&#xD;
      to complete 6 intervals during each session.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will complete training in a place of their choosing. If requested participants&#xD;
      will be able to train in the labs at LJMU.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be given a polar H7/10 Bluetooth heart rate monitor. Participants will be&#xD;
      advised to wear this monitor during all training sessions. The monitor will provide a measure&#xD;
      of training intensity and compliance with the suggested heart rate and training programme.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked to download the App PolarBeat to their smartphone. This App will&#xD;
      be used to monitor heart rate during the training sessions. In addition, participants will be&#xD;
      given a login email address and password for PolarFlow (www.polar.flow.com), a cloud storage&#xD;
      site run by Polar for the storage and analysis of heart rate data. All heart rate data&#xD;
      measured during training sessions will be uploaded to Polar Flow. This will allow the&#xD;
      research team to investigate training intensity achieved during all sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety Subjects will be asked to check their blood glucose level to ensure it is safe to&#xD;
      exercise. The investigators will use the guidelines that are currently used in a national&#xD;
      study of exercise for patients with type 1 diabetes (EXTOD - see attached leaflet). Blood&#xD;
      glucose will be checked immediately following exercise and corrected with fast acting&#xD;
      carbohydrates if low. The investigators will also advise the subjects to check their glucose&#xD;
      level before bed, and if necessary in the early hours of the morning (through setting an&#xD;
      alarm clock) if this is required.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Flash Glucose Monitoring Analysis 9 key metrics of glycaemic control will be assessed,&#xD;
      reported in 3 time blocks (sleep 00:00-06:00, wake 06:00- 00:00 and 24h 00:00- 00:00): 1)&#xD;
      mean glucose, 2) % of time in level 2 hypoglycaemia (&lt;3.0mmol/L), 3) % of time in level 1&#xD;
      hypoglycaemia (3.0-3.9mmol/L), 4) % of time in target range (3.9-10.0mmol/L), 5) % of time in&#xD;
      level 1 hyperglycaemia (10.0-13.9mmol/L), 6) % of time in level 2 hyperglycaemia&#xD;
      (&gt;13.9mmol/L), 7) glycaemic variability, reported as CV and SD, 8) episodes of hypoglycaemia&#xD;
      and hyperglycaemia and 9) area under the curve of episodes of hypoglycaemia and&#xD;
      hyperglycaemia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 1, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 1, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Severe hypoglycaemia (using continuous glucose monitoring)</measure>
    <time_frame>Over a 2 week intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Number of severe hypoglycaemic events (&lt;3mmol/l) during the 2 week intervention period</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean glucose (using continuous glucose monitoring)</measure>
    <time_frame>Over a 2 week intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>mean glucose level over 2 week recording period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>% of time in level 2 hypoglycaemia (&lt;3.0mmol/L) (using continuous glucose monitoring)</measure>
    <time_frame>Over a 2 week intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>% of time in level 2 hypoglycaemia (&lt;3.0mmol/L) over 2 week recording period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>% of time in level 1 hypoglycaemia (3.0-3.9mmol/L) (using continuous glucose monitoring)</measure>
    <time_frame>Over a 2 week intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>% of time in level 1 hypoglycaemia (3.0-3.9mmol/L) over 2 week recording period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>% of time in target range (3.9-10.0mmol/L) (using continuous glucose monitoring)</measure>
    <time_frame>Over a 2 week intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>% of time in target range (3.9-10.0mmol/L) over 2 week recording period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>% of time in level 1 hyperglycaemia (10.0-13.9mmol/L) (using continuous glucose monitoring)</measure>
    <time_frame>Over a 2 week intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>% of time in level 1 hyperglycaemia (10.0-13.9mmol/L) over 2 week recording period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>% of time in level 2 hyperglycaemia (&gt;13.9mmol/L) (using continuous glucose monitoring)</measure>
    <time_frame>Over a 2 week intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>% of time in level 2 hyperglycaemia (&gt;13.9mmol/L) over 2 week recording period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>glycaemic variability (using continuous glucose monitoring)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Standard deviation in glucose concentrations obtained over a 2 week period using a continuous glucose monitoring device.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>area under the curve of episodes of hypoglycaemia and hyperglycaemia</measure>
    <time_frame>Over a 2 week intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>area under the curve of episodes of hypoglycaemia and hyperglycaemia 2 week recording period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Type1diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will continue with their habitual lifestyle but perform no exercise for 2 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Moderate intensity continous training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will complete moderate intensity continous training during a 2 week intervention period</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>high intensity interval training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will complete high intensity interval training during a 2 week intervention period</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>moderate intensity continous training</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will complete 6 sessions of moderate intensity continous training during a 2 week intervention period. Participants will be asked to complete 30 minutes of continuous exercise.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Moderate intensity continous training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>high intensity interval training</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will complete 6 sessions of high intensity interval training during a 2 week intervention period. The programme involves repeated 1 minute bouts of simple on the spot movements interspersed with 1 minute of rest.</description>
    <arm_group_label>high intensity interval training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  T1D diagnosis more than 6 months ago&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Using a basal bolus insulin regime or insulin pump therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI ≤ 32 kg.m-2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy (or planning pregnancy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Disability preventing participation in an exercise regime&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Angina&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Autonomic neuropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medication that affects heart rate (this will affect estimation of fitness)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery planned within 6 weeks of study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled blood pressure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant history of hyperglycaemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe hypoglycaemia requiring third party assistance within the last 3&#xD;
             months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe non-proliferative and unstable proliferative retinopathy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Matthew Cocks</name>
      <address>
        <city>Liverpool</city>
        <zip>L33AF</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 25, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Liverpool John Moores University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sam Shepherd</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Lecturer/Senior Lecturer, Principle Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>No individual participant data will be shared outside the research team. Anonymised group data will be presented in research articles and presentations</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

