<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05042154</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1753461-1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05042154</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prevalence of OSA in COPD and the Clinical Impact of OSA Diagnosis and Treatment</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prevalence of OSA in COPD and the Clinical Impact of OSA Diagnosis and Treatment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Atlantic Health System</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Atlantic Health System</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      COPD is a major cause of morbidity and mortality and is characterized by breathing impairment&#xD;
      and related symptoms. Obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) is a highly prevalent condition that&#xD;
      adversely affects breathing during sleep. The co-occurrence of OSA and COPD in an individual&#xD;
      has been referred to as the overlap syndrome (OVS). Regardless of whether OVS represents a&#xD;
      single unique entity or two separate conditions in the same patient, the combined respiratory&#xD;
      derangements of OSA and COPD are felt to be synergistic. Patients with COPD and OSA may have&#xD;
      more frequent and severe nocturnal arterial hypoxemia and hypercapnia than in patients with&#xD;
      OSA alone, as well as increased pulmonary hypertension and dysrhythmias. The reported&#xD;
      prevalence of OSA in COPD varies widely depending on patient setting, COPD severity,&#xD;
      diagnostic methodology, etc., ranging from 10 to 75%. The presence of OSA in patients with&#xD;
      COPD has also been implicated as a risk factor for COPD exacerbations and associated&#xD;
      hospitalizations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The coexistence of OSA and COPD is associated with increased risk of COPD exacerbation and&#xD;
      shorter time to first exacerbation following diagnosis. 20% of patients discharged following&#xD;
      an exacerbation of COPD are readmitted within 30 days, usually for respiratory-related&#xD;
      problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A randomized controlled trial on Gagnon 3 at Morristown Medical Center will be conducted to&#xD;
      diagnose OSA in patients admitted with AECOPD. The WatchPAT One device will be used and can&#xD;
      detect the presence of OSA. If OSA is diagnosed, the patient will then be offered and&#xD;
      prescribed a home CPAP for use after hospital discharge. We will investigate 30-day of AECOPD&#xD;
      readmission rates.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. The initial phase of the study will be a prospective cohort design to determine the&#xD;
           prevalence of OSA in outpatients with stable COPD who are part of the Atlantic Medical&#xD;
           Group/ Pulmonary and Allergy Associates. Home sleep apnea testing will be performed&#xD;
           using WatchPAT on consecutive, unselected outpatients with COPD (GOLD stage 3 or 4) who&#xD;
           are being managed in an office setting. Inclusion criteria will include age 18 or&#xD;
           greater, ability to participate and known dx of COPD with GOLD stage 3 or 4.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. A second phase of our trial will determine OSA prevalence in hospitalized patients&#xD;
           admitted with AECOPD who are part of the Atlantic Medical Group/ Pulmonary and Allergy&#xD;
           Associates (AMG/PAA). This observational cohort will include both new admissions and&#xD;
           30-day readmissions. Inclusion criteria will include a primary admitting diagnosis of&#xD;
           AECOPD, age 18 or greater, ability to participate and known dx of COPD with GOLD stage 3&#xD;
           or 4.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. A third study phase will enroll COPD patients admitted to the pulmonary care unit of&#xD;
           Morristown Medical Center and Overlook Medical Center under AMG / PAA. This phase will&#xD;
           randomize diagnostic testing and initiate CPAP treatment in those testing positive for&#xD;
           OSA. We will then determine CPAP treatment in those with COPD and OSA has an impact on&#xD;
           subsequent 30-day hospital readmissions.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Inclusion criteria for this phase of our study will include an admission diagnosis of&#xD;
           AECOPD, age greater than 18 years, ability to participate in a portable sleep monitoring&#xD;
           study, known COPD diagnosed by a pulmonologist (defined by GOLD, GOLD stage 3 or 4.&#xD;
           Standard care patients will not be tested for OSA and will receive routine clinical&#xD;
           management as per their treating physicians based on the GOLD Criteria. Consented&#xD;
           patients will undergo group randomization to either standard AECOPD care or to overnight&#xD;
           sleep apnea testing with the WatchPAT (Itamar Medical, Israel). If OSA is diagnosed,&#xD;
           patients will then be offered and prescribed a home CPAP for use upon hospital&#xD;
           discharge. The authors will investigate the percentage of 30- day acute exacerbation of&#xD;
           COPD (AECOPD) readmission rates for both patient groups once discharged home.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Questionnaire data will be collected from all participants regarding OSA risk factors,&#xD;
           sleepiness, fatigue, quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. The primary outcome is reduction in 30-day COPD hospital readmissions. Secondary&#xD;
           outcomes include determining the prevalence of OSA in outpatient and hospitalized COPD&#xD;
           patients. Tertiary outcomes will relate to CPAP usage and compliance, as well as other&#xD;
           measures of sleep quality and quality of life on CPAP.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Timeline of Proposal Pre-study Months 0-6 Study Period Months 6-12 Post-study Months 12-24&#xD;
      IRB Submission Study Enrollment Protocol preparations Finalize Case Report Form Data&#xD;
      collection and analysis Data analysis Training sessions for Gagnon 3 at MMC and 10 CD at OMC&#xD;
      Ongoing clinical follow-up and management of OSA and COPD Generate hypotheses for future&#xD;
      research studies&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the diagnostic phases of the study on out-patients and in-patients, we will include&#xD;
      50-100 patients' total. For the randomization portion of the study, we will include 300&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria include GOLD stage 3 or 4 for outpatients and for in-patients, criteria&#xD;
      will include an admission diagnosis of AECOPD, age greater than 18 years, ability to&#xD;
      participate in a supine sleep study, known COPD diagnosed by a pulmonologist (GOLD stage 3 or&#xD;
      4). Informed consent will be obtained from each patient. The study population will be&#xD;
      composed of patients admitted to the pulmonary units at our two hospitals. All new admissions&#xD;
      to those units will be screened daily by study personnel for enrollment using the author's&#xD;
      inclusion and exclusions criteria. Permission to approach patients and families will be&#xD;
      requested from the attending pulmonologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will exclude patients unable or unwilling to participate in the home sleep study, medical&#xD;
      problems or medications affecting the diagnostic accuracy/application of WatchPAT One&#xD;
      (peripheral vascular disease, peripheral neuropathy, alpha blockade), admission to the ICU,&#xD;
      finger deformity which prevented adequate sensor application.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Questionnaire data will be obtained directly from the patient regarding OSA risk factors,&#xD;
      sleepiness, fatigue, and quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who are not enrolled in the RCT will receive the standard of care for AECOPD based&#xD;
      on the current GOLD Guidelines. Patients who meet inclusion criteria will be enrolled in the&#xD;
      intervention group and spend one night wearing the WatchPAT One to determine the presence of&#xD;
      OSA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consented patients will undergo group randomization to either standard AECOPD care or to the&#xD;
      WatchPAT One cohort (WPC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The authors will use The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI, a self-rated questionnaire&#xD;
      which assesses sleep quality and disturbances over a one-month time interval. Nineteen&#xD;
      individual items generate seven &quot;component&quot; scores: subjective sleep quality, sleep latency,&#xD;
      sleep duration, habitual sleep efficiency, sleep disturbances, use of sleeping medication,&#xD;
      and daytime dysfunction. The sum of scores for these seven components yields one global&#xD;
      score.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The authors will use the STOP BANG questionnaire developed by Chung et al. which has been&#xD;
      widely used as a sensitive screening tool for OSA. It is composed of both subjective and&#xD;
      objective questions. The STOP-BANG acronym stands for: Snoring history, Tired during the day,&#xD;
      observed stop breathing while sleep, High blood pressure, BMI more than 35 kg/m2, Age more&#xD;
      than 50 years, Neck circumference more than 40 cm and male Gender.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Epworth Sleepiness Questionnaire measures propensity to fall asleep in eight different&#xD;
      situations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fatigue severity score measures level of fatigue based on nine questions to assess severity&#xD;
      of fatigue&#xD;
&#xD;
      Long term data will be analyzed with regard to COPD status, including hospital admissions and&#xD;
      readmissions as well as outcomes of OSA treatment with CPAP, including morbidity and&#xD;
      mortality and quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our primary goal is to determine the 30-day AECOPD admission and readmission rate comparing&#xD;
      those with and without OSA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additional outcomes will measure prevalence of OSA in COPD and additional outcomes effected&#xD;
      by treatment of OSA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization method will be used using the REDCap platform.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The RNs and RTs caring for patients in the &quot;usual AECOPD care&quot; arm will be blinded to the&#xD;
      WatchPAT One intervention. All subjects must have enrollment, randomization, and home sleep&#xD;
      study with the WatchPAT One on day 4 or day 5 of hospitalization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may be withdrawn from the study without their consent if they are unable to&#xD;
      tolerate the sleep testing or comply with other aspects of their medical care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>30-Day Hospitals Readmissions for COPD</measure>
    <time_frame>30 Days</time_frame>
    <description>30-Day Hospital Readmissions from the Index COPD Hospital Stay</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Diagnosis of OSA</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Diagnosis of obstructive sleep apnea in the COPD population</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Prevalence of OSA in Patients Hospitalized With COPD Exacerbation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care Cohort for COPD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard care patients will receive routine clinical management as per their treating physicians based on the GOLD Criteria.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>WatchPAT Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Consented patients will undergo group randomization to either standard AECOPD care or to the WatchPAT One cohort (WPC). The WPC will undergo a single night of in-hospital sleep apnea testing from 2200 to 0600 using the WatchPAT One, a portable and disposable home sleep apnea testing device (Itamar Medical, Israel [WPAT]).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>WatchPAT</intervention_name>
    <description>The WatchPAT One can detect the presence of OSA based on measurement of peripheral arterial tone (PAT), pulse rate, oxygen saturation, actigraphy, snoring, and body position.</description>
    <arm_group_label>WatchPAT Cohort</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: Inclusion criteria include GOLD stage 3 or 4 for outpatients and for&#xD;
        in-patients, criteria will include an admission diagnosis of AECOPD, age greater than 18&#xD;
        years, ability to participate in a supine sleep study, known COPD diagnosed by a&#xD;
        pulmonologist (GOLD stage 3 or 4). Informed consent will be obtained from each patient. The&#xD;
        study population will be composed of patients admitted to Gagnon 3 from the emergency&#xD;
        department (ED) and to 10 CD from the ED. All new admissions to Gagnon 3 at MMC and 10 CD&#xD;
        at OMC will be screened daily by study personnel for enrollment using the author's&#xD;
        inclusion and exclusions criteria. Permission to approach patients and families will be&#xD;
        requested from the attending pulmonologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: a. List exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        We excluded patients unable or unwilling to participate in the home sleep study, medical&#xD;
        problems or medications affecting the diagnostic accuracy/application of WatchPAT One&#xD;
        (peripheral vascular disease, peripheral neuropathy, alpha blockade), admission to the ICU,&#xD;
        finger deformity which prevented adequate sensor application.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Matthew Epstein, MD</last_name>
    <phone>862-432-2279</phone>
    <email>matthew.epstein@atlantichealth.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Moira Kendra, DNP</last_name>
    <phone>908-403-3727</phone>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Atlantic Health System</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Matthew Epstein</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

