<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05041933</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>87RI20_0054</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05041933</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Secure Outsourcing of Carfilzomib in the Treatment of Multiple Myeloma to the Hospital at Home Setting</brief_title>
  <acronym>Carfil-HAD</acronym>
  <official_title>Pilot Study: Secure Outsourcing of Carfilzomib in the Treatment of Multiple Myeloma to the Hospital at Home (HAH) Setting. Care Organisation Model for New Short Intravenous Infusion Chemotherapies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Limoges</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Limoges</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Since 2009, the Department of Clinical Haematology at Limoges University Hospital Centre,&#xD;
      supported by the HEMATOLIM network, has been operating the regional &quot;ESCADHEM&quot; system:&#xD;
      [Secure outsourcing of injectable chemotherapy to the home care setting for malignant blood&#xD;
      diseases]. In addition to Limoges University Hospital, Brive Hospital and Guéret Hospital,&#xD;
      this system involves four Hospital at Home (HAH) structures across the three départements of&#xD;
      the former Limousin region.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this process, chemotherapy administered by subcutaneous injection is prescribed by a&#xD;
      hospital physician in one of the hospitals &quot;authorised to deliver cancer treatments&quot; in the&#xD;
      former region of Limousin: Limoges University Hospital Centre, Brive Hospital or Guéret&#xD;
      Hospital. This chemotherapy is then prepared in one of the three hospital pharmacies&#xD;
      authorised to perform centralised reconstitution, in accordance with current standards. The&#xD;
      preparation is then transferred to one of the four Hospital at Home (HAH) structures, which&#xD;
      transports the product to the patient's home where it is administered by the nurse (IDE).&#xD;
      This last step in the process is under the responsibility of the HAH structure coordinating&#xD;
      physician, who is also responsible for waste collection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Supported by its experience within the ESCADHEM system with subcutaneous drugs and in the&#xD;
      context of the arrival of new intravenous drugs, in short infusion form, the Department of&#xD;
      Clinical Haematology, supported by the HEMATOLIM network (which became the HEMATOLIM&#xD;
      association on 1 January 2020) and the professionals involved began the process of&#xD;
      outsourcing these drugs to the HAH setting. One of these drugs is carfilzomib, used to treat&#xD;
      multiple myeloma, and its outsourcing to the HAH setting was put in place from the end of&#xD;
      2018.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In parallel with this, the Department of Clinical Haematology would like to set up a study to&#xD;
      evaluate the feasibility of outsourcing this new drug, administered intravenously, based on a&#xD;
      model that we know to be operational and secure for chemotherapies administered by&#xD;
      subcutaneous injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      the Department of Clinical Haematology hope to be able to confirm the value of caring for&#xD;
      multiple myeloma patients in an HAH setting by improving their quality of life and optimising&#xD;
      their care pathway in organisational and economic terms. the Department of Clinical&#xD;
      Haematology hope to be able to demonstrate that this organisation is not only efficient in&#xD;
      the view of patients, but also for the healthcare professionals working in the Hospital, the&#xD;
      HAH structure and in the community, involved throughout the care process.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To conduct our study, the Department of Clinical Haematology selected the novel drug&#xD;
      carfilzomib, used in the treatment of multiple myeloma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The prescribing conditions, treatment administration regimen and outsourcing quality&#xD;
      processes for this drug are available in the annexes. These standard regimens were&#xD;
      constructed on the basis of the protocols in the ESCADHEM system, extensively trialled and&#xD;
      validated by the HAS, for drugs injected subcutaneously and following a collegial approach.&#xD;
      We thus hope to demonstrate that the protocols used for drugs administered by subcutaneous&#xD;
      injection - in particular, bortezomib and azacytidine - are applicable to carfilzomib&#xD;
      following minor modifications to the procedures given the IV administration of the latter&#xD;
      drug as a short infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It should be noted that it is essential that the first cycle of carfilzomib be administered,&#xD;
      in its entirety, in an outpatient clinic setting. Thereafter, if the patient is eligible for&#xD;
      treatment in an HAH setting, the 1st day of each cycle will be performed in an outpatient&#xD;
      clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following this study, the Department of Clinical Haematology hope to be able to publish our&#xD;
      research and promote it at national and/or international congresses. This research should&#xD;
      further reinforce our already significant experience in this type of care strategy for&#xD;
      malignant blood diseases in the HAH setting, which we believe is simultaneously innovative,&#xD;
      practical and beneficial for all the players in the care pathway concerned. The model will&#xD;
      probably be useful for outsourcing to the HAH setting other novel drugs progressively&#xD;
      arriving on the market with profiles similar to that of the drug we wish to study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Finally, our project aims to demonstrate that our procedures for the secure outsourcing of&#xD;
      carfilzomib to the HAH setting, in place since the end of 2018 are valid and could be&#xD;
      extended to other regions of France. Furthermore, the current health landscape is undergoing&#xD;
      profound changes associated with budget constraints, as well as societal and technological&#xD;
      evolutions, with the result that home care, and hence HAH structures, appear, more than ever,&#xD;
      to be the model of the future.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of deviations from SOPs occurring in the context of secure outsourcing of carfilzomib administered by short IV infusion, for 3 cycles, to a mixed outpatient clinic/HAH care setting.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Hematological Diseases</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>outsourcing of chemotherapy to Hospital at Home</intervention_name>
    <description>outsourcing of chemotherapy to Hospital at Home</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patient with relapsed or refractory multiple myeloma (having received at least one previous&#xD;
        treatment),&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects aged 18 years or over.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eligible for care by one of the four HAH structures in accordance with HAS criteria,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With relapsed or refractory multiple myeloma (having received at least one previous&#xD;
             treatment),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Whose case has been examined at multidisciplinary team (MDT) meetings at Limoges&#xD;
             University Hospital Centre,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving carfilzomib parenteral chemotherapy outsourced to an HAH setting (all&#xD;
             patients receive the entire first cycle of carfilzomib and the 1st day of each of the&#xD;
             subsequent cycles in an outpatient clinic).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having read the information leaflet concerning the Carfil-HAD study,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not objecting to the use of their data in the context of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to understand the protocol or complete the questionnaires.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refusing to complete the questionnaires.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mohamed TOUATI, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+33 (0)5 55 05 60 63</phone>
    <email>Mohamed.Touati@chu-limoges.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Limoges Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Limoges</city>
        <zip>87 042</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mohammed Touati, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+33 (0)5 55 05 60 63</phone>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <phone>Mohamed.Touati@chu-limoges.fr</phone>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 3, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hematologic Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

