<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05044299</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IsopedPhase1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05044299</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Development of the Isoped Device for Increasing Blood Flow in a Sedentary Aging Population</brief_title>
  <official_title>Development of the Isoped Device for Increasing Blood Flow in a Sedentary Aging Population</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Utah</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Utah</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The Isoped (patented) is a portable medical device that provides a safe and engaging&#xD;
      opportunity for regular physical activity to those with limited mobility and difficulties&#xD;
      with performing traditional exercise tasks. It is a tool designed to encourage regular and&#xD;
      repeated low impact movement of the lower extremities that can improve blood flow and lead to&#xD;
      improved cardiovascular function. By restoring healthier cardiovascular tone, Isoped users&#xD;
      may be able to progress to more demanding activities leading to a healthy lifestyle change.&#xD;
      Experiencing these improvements can boost confidence, mood, and overall quality of life.&#xD;
      Isoped users can exercise while sitting at a desk, watching television, or in a&#xD;
      rehabilitation facility. The lightweight device sits on the floor beneath the user's feet and&#xD;
      can be operated from a seated, reclined, or supine position. Circulation and lower&#xD;
      extremities' blood flow increase as the feet slide the pedals in a forward and backward&#xD;
      movement similar to a shuffling walk or in cross-country skiing. Resistance load can be&#xD;
      controlled by the user for a customized experience using a smartphone app. Physical exercise&#xD;
      is widely recommended as a primary treatment by physicians to improve circulation and prevent&#xD;
      cardiovascular diseases associated with physical inactivity and a sedentary lifestyle. Isoped&#xD;
      is a healthy and innovative alternative to pharmacological, surgical or other treatment&#xD;
      modalities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aim 1, Refine Device Prototype: A prototype Isoped device will be refined and calibrated for&#xD;
      use. Engineering challenges include refining the design to incorporate these features and&#xD;
      functions: Electronic Resistance mode (adjustable wirelessly through the Graphical User&#xD;
      Interface (GUI)); Stride Length Adjustment (through the GUI); Stride Width Adjustment;&#xD;
      Incline Adjustment (powered or manual); Footpad rotation and removal; Bluetooth connectivity&#xD;
      to the GUI; comfortable stabilizing modifications to footpads.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2, Evaluate Device Efficacy and Safety: Isoped will be evaluated for safety and efficacy&#xD;
      in a pilot clinical study of 40 volunteers aged 65 to 85 meeting criteria for a sedentary&#xD;
      lifestyle and limited physical activity. To non-invasively determine the peripheral&#xD;
      hemodynamic effect of the Isoped, we will quantify the lower extremity blood flow response to&#xD;
      Isoped facilitated lower leg movement using doppler ultrasound measured at the femoral&#xD;
      artery. Changes in mean blood pressure and heart rate will provide secondary measures of&#xD;
      effect. Participant safety will be monitored using a 12-lead ECG and beat-by-beat measures of&#xD;
      blood pressure and cardiac output. Device performance and safety will be evaluated by&#xD;
      recording any deviations in device operability and any adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On completion of Phase 1, Phase 2 funding will provide the means to further evaluate the&#xD;
      device for use in a patient population as a means for encouraging progression to regular&#xD;
      health improving exercise regimens. A planned clinical trial in frail and sedentary aging&#xD;
      persons using the Isoped over a period of several weeks will evaluate health improvement and&#xD;
      willingness to engage in more demanding exercise regimens. This will position Isoped for&#xD;
      commercialization as a tool for encouraging effective non-invasive, low-impact activity for&#xD;
      improving the health and quality of life in a wide variety of patients having compromised&#xD;
      circulation and who are unable and/or unwilling to engage in more rigorous physical activity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Study has two arms comparing device with and without resistance load over equal period of operation</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood flow</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>blood flow measured at femoral artery using doppler ultrasound</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>continuous heart rate</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>heart rate measured using Finapres</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>continuous blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>systolic, diastolic, and mean blood pressure measured continuously (Finapres)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Sedentary Behavior</condition>
  <condition>Aging</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Isoped mobilization with resistance load</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Use of Isoped with movement at 3 levels of resistance load: zero, low, high, each condition lasts 3 minutes at 9 minutes total work</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Isoped mobilization without resistance load</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Use of Isoped with movement at zero resistance load lasts 9 minutes of work</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Isoped</intervention_name>
    <description>Isoped is a mechanical device allowing movement of lower extremities in a forward and backward motion, with phone-based app to control resistance load</description>
    <arm_group_label>Isoped mobilization with resistance load</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Isoped mobilization without resistance load</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-reported sedentary behavior and physically inactive&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Activity level confirmed via questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Activity level confirmed by wearing activity monitor (Actigraph) over 7 days&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cardiopulmonary&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cardiovascular pathology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of musculoskeletal conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other pathology precluding light exercise as evaluated by licensed geriatrician&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David H Bradshaw, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Utah</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>David H Bradshaw, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>801-585-7690</phone>
    <email>David.bradshaw@hsc.utah.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lani Arst</last_name>
    <phone>360-949-9908</phone>
    <email>laniarst@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 3, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Utah</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>David Bradshaw</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Adjunct research assistant professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>aging</keyword>
  <keyword>sedentary behavior</keyword>
  <keyword>blood flow</keyword>
  <keyword>device</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

