<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01806909</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>130081</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>13-I-0081</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01806909</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intranasal AD4-H5-VTN as an Adenovirus Vaccine</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 1 Study of Safety and Immunogenicity of Intranasal Ad4-H5-VTN in Ad4 Seronegative and Seropositive Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adenoviruses are viruses that typically cause symptoms of a cold or eye infection. These&#xD;
           viruses are being tested as part of a possible new vaccine. Researchers hope that the&#xD;
           adenovirus will help carry the vaccine into the body and cause an immune response. An&#xD;
           immune response is the body s release of cells and substances that protect the body from&#xD;
           infection. If an adenovirus vaccine can be developed, it might be used as part of a&#xD;
           vaccine for malaria or other serious illnesses. Researchers want to test the adenovirus&#xD;
           vaccine as a nasal spray in healthy volunteers. The vaccine is called AD4-H5-VTN.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Because the vaccine contains a live adenovirus, there is a possibility that participants&#xD;
           can infect other people. Therefore, participants' intimate contacts must join this&#xD;
           study. An intimate contact is someone who the participant will kiss on the mouth or have&#xD;
           sexual intercourse with during the period of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To study the immune response of the AD4-H5-VTN vaccine in healthy volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To see if the adenovirus in the AD4-H5-VTN vaccine is contagious or spreads to others.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Healthy volunteers between 18 and 49 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Intimate contacts of healthy volunteers between 18 and 65 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants must not have evidence of previous exposure to adenovirus type 4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be screened with a physical exam and medical history. Blood and urine&#xD;
           samples will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants who will receive the vaccine must be willing to be hospitalized for between&#xD;
           5 and 7 days. They will come to the National Institutes of Health for follow-up visits&#xD;
           weekly for the first month, after 8 weeks, in 6 months, and possibly 1 year. They must&#xD;
           also avoid all vaccines (including seasonal flu vaccine) and allergy shots for 30 days&#xD;
           before and after having the study vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will enter the hospital for the vaccine study visit. They will receive the&#xD;
           vaccine as a nasal spray. Because the vaccine uses a live virus, participants may be&#xD;
           contagious for the virus for up to 4 weeks. They will remain in the hospital in&#xD;
           respiratory isolation for 7 days, or until they have two negative nasal washes taken 1&#xD;
           day apart. A negative nasal wash means that there is no live virus in the nose.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After leaving the hospital, participants will keep a diary at home for at least 3 weeks.&#xD;
           They will record their temperature, any symptoms, or other health changes every day&#xD;
           during this time.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants should avoid intimate contact with others for 28 days after having the&#xD;
           vaccine. Intimate contact includes kissing on the mouth and sexual intercourse. Also,&#xD;
           participants should not share kitchen utensils, drinking cups, towels, or hair combs&#xD;
           with others. Intimate contacts will also keep track of any illnesses or symptoms they&#xD;
           develop during this time.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At the follow-up visits, participants will provide blood and swab samples for study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 1 single center, dose-escalation study designed to evaluate the safety and&#xD;
      immunogenicity of live, replication competent recombinant Adenovirus type 4-H5N1 Influenza&#xD;
      Vietnam 1194 Hemagglutinin (HA) (Ad4-H5-Vtn). Determining the optimal route and dose for this&#xD;
      recombinant platform will greatly accelerate investigations of this vector as an influenza&#xD;
      vaccine and an HIV vaccine platform.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary goal of this study is to evaluate safety of ascending dosages of the Ad4-H5-Vtn&#xD;
      vaccine following intranasal administration. A dosage will be selected to further evaluate&#xD;
      the humoral, cellular, and mucosal immune responses against both the vector and the inserted&#xD;
      gene. The Ad4-H5-Vtn will be initiated at 103 viral particles (vp). Once safety is&#xD;
      established at the initial dose, a second round of testing will begin at the next ten-fold&#xD;
      higher dose. The Ad4-H5-Vtn vaccine will be assessed in three participants at each dosage&#xD;
      level. The maximum viral dose administered will be 108 vp.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to clinical and laboratory monitoring of safety, the principal assessments will&#xD;
      be shedding of the Ad4-H5-Vtn virus in rectal, cervicovaginal, throat, and nasal swabs, and&#xD;
      assessment of the antibody (mucosal and systemic) response to the HA and to the Ad4 virus.&#xD;
      Participants will remain in the NIH Special Clinical Studies Unit until they have 2&#xD;
      consecutive negative nasal washes or 7 days have elapsed since vaccination, whichever occurs&#xD;
      first; they may remain on the unit longer if medically necessary. When safety has been&#xD;
      confirmed in all 3 participants at a given dosage level, the next higher dose group is&#xD;
      enrolled. If one grade 3 or greater toxicity (or pre-specified grade 2 toxicity, see Section&#xD;
      3.4) at least possibly related to the vaccine is observed, the group will be expanded at that&#xD;
      dose. If a second at least possibly related grade 3 or greater toxicity (or pre-specified&#xD;
      Grade 2 toxicity, see Section 3.4) is observed, the dose will be reduced one level and the&#xD;
      group will be expanded. Up to 25 Ad4-seronegative individuals will be enrolled at the maximum&#xD;
      tolerated dose to fully evaluate safety and immunogenicity in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will be followed for 28 days following immunization, and again at 8 and 26&#xD;
      weeks to evaluate any long-term toxicity and persistence of immunity. All subjects will be&#xD;
      offered to receive a booster vaccine at the 26-week visit and be seen for follow-up visits 4&#xD;
      and 8 weeks following booster immunization with an additional telephone follow-up 6 months&#xD;
      after boosting. Household and intimate contacts will also be enrolled and monitored for&#xD;
      Adenovirus and HAI antibodies following Ad4-H5-Vtn administration only; household and&#xD;
      intimate contacts will not be enrolled or monitored during the boost portion of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will conduct an expansion H5N1 boost phase of this study, in which all vaccinees from the&#xD;
      initial phase of the study will be offered re-enrollment to receive a booster vaccination&#xD;
      with an FDA-approved H5N1 inactivated monovalent influenza vaccine. We will offer enrollment&#xD;
      in the expansion phase to all participants who received the Ad4-H5-Vtn vaccine in the initial&#xD;
      phase, regardless of whether they also received the recombinant hemagglutinin influenza H5&#xD;
      vaccine boost. We will also enroll individuals who have never received an H5 influenza&#xD;
      vaccine as controls. Participants will receive a single vaccination with the H5N1 vaccine and&#xD;
      be seen for follow-up visits 4 and 8 weeks later for immunogenicity evaluations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 6, 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 22, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 9, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the safety of the Ad4-H5-Vtn recombinant vaccine in Ad4 seronegative humans when administered intranasally</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the immunogenicity of the Ad4-H5-Vtn recombinant vaccine in Ad4 seronegative humans when administered intranasally</measure>
    <time_frame>Months 2, 6</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the optimal dose for the nasal Ad4 vaccine platform, up to a maximum dose of 108 vp.</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To monitor transmission to household and intimate contacts of vaccines and To monitor shedding and stability of recovered Ad4 recombinants.</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">51</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Volunteer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intranasal</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Ad4-H5-VTN intranasal vaccine administered in cohorts of 3 at increasing dosages</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ad4-H5-Vtn</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Intranasal</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All participant (vaccinees, household contacts, and intimate contacts) must meet all of the&#xD;
        following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 18 to 49 years for vaccinees. Vaccinnees may be greater than 49 years of age at&#xD;
             the time of booster vaccination. Age 18 to 65 years for household and intimate&#xD;
             contacts.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able to provide proof of identity to the acceptance of the Principal Investigator or&#xD;
             designee during enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Available and willing to participate in follow-up visits and tests for the duration of&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Willing to have samples stored for future research&#xD;
&#xD;
        The following inclusion criteria apply to vaccines and intimate contacts, but not to&#xD;
        household contacts:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. In good general health without clinically significant medical history.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Negative b-HCG pregnancy test for females presumed to be of reproductive potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. A female must meet one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. No reproductive potential because of menopause (one year without menses) or&#xD;
                  because of a hysterectomy, bilateral oophorectomy, or tubal ligation.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Participant agrees to be heterosexually inactive or consistently practice&#xD;
                  contraception at least 21 days prior to enrollment and 28 days following&#xD;
                  vaccination. Acceptable methods of contraception include the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  condoms, male or female, with a spermicide&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  diaphragm or cervical cap with spermicide&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  contraceptive pills, Norplant, or Depo-Provera&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  male partner has previously undergone a vasectomy for which there is&#xD;
                       documentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  intrauterine device&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Male participants must agree to practice abstinence or effective birth control for at&#xD;
             least 21 days prior to enrollment and during the first 28 days following vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The following inclusion criteria apply only to vaccinees and not to household or intimate&#xD;
        contacts:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Willing to receive HIV test results and abide by NIH guidelines for partner&#xD;
             notification of positive HIV results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Physical examination and laboratory results without clinically significant findings&#xD;
             within the 8 weeks prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Willing to avoid vaccination other than the study agent for 30 days prior to and 30&#xD;
             days after administration of the Ad4-H5-Vtn vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Safety Laboratory Criteria within 8 weeks prior to enrollment:&#xD;
&#xD;
             Hematopoietic: White blood cell count and Lymphocyte count +/- 25% the normallimits&#xD;
             for the NIH Clinical Center&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count of least 125,000/mm(3)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin greater than 11.2 g/dL for females and greater than 13.0 g/dL for&#xD;
                  males.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Renal: BUN less than 23 mg/dL; creatinine within normal limits for the NIH&#xD;
                  Clinical Center&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hepatic: Serum total bilirubin less than or equal to 2 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Metabolic: ALT &lt; 2 times upper limit of normal range&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Endocrine: Serum glucose within normal range&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Additional Laboratory Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Immunologic: No history of hypogammaglobulinemia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serologic: Ad4 neutralizing antibody 80% inhibitory dilution less than 1:100&#xD;
                  ((This criterion does not apply to participants in vaccine arm B.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Willing to be hospitalized at the Clinical Center under respiratory precautions for up&#xD;
             to 7 days or longer if medically indicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria for the expansion H5N1 boost phase:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 18 to 64.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Negative pregnancy test (women of childbearing potential).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Group-specific inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  For participants in the study group: prior receipt of the Ad4-H5-Vtn vaccine in&#xD;
                  the initial phase of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  For participants in the control group: no prior receipt of an H5 vaccine product&#xD;
                  (by self-report).&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A participant (vaccinees, household contacts, and intimate contacts) will be excluded if&#xD;
        they have the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Any condition that, in the investigator s judgement, places the subject at undue risk by&#xD;
        participating in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The following exclusion criterion applies to vaccines and intimate contact, but not to&#xD;
        household contacts:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of any prior disease or therapy which would affect immune or pulmonary&#xD;
             function.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Prior malignancy, except curatively-treated basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of&#xD;
             the skin or carcinoma in situ of the cervix.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of radiation therapy or cytotoxic/cancer chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of diabetes mellitus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Immunodeficiency or autoimmune disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Acute infection or a recent (within 6 months) history of chronic infection suggestive&#xD;
             of immunodeficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Taking any medication which may affect immune function, except participants may be&#xD;
             taking low doses of nonprescription strength NSAIDS (including e.g. ibuprofen or&#xD;
             aspirin) or acetaminophen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Chronic respiratory disorders including asthma, emphysema, interstitial lung disease,&#xD;
             pulmonary hypertension, recurrent pneumonia, or recent or ongoing respiratory tract&#xD;
             infection. If a respiratory disorder is transient, defer immunization but do not&#xD;
             exclude the participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Active Hepatitis B or C infection (i.e. Hepatitis B or C positive serology with the&#xD;
             presence of virus antigen or DNA. Ongoing viral replication will be confirmed by a&#xD;
             Hepatitis B antigen or Hepatitis C viral load).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Female of child-bearing potential who is breast-feeding or planning pregnancy during&#xD;
             the 28 days following vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The following exclusion criteria apply only to vaccinees and not to household or intimate&#xD;
        contacts:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any medical, psychiatric, or social condition, or occupational or other responsibility&#xD;
             that, in the judgment of the investigator, would interfere with or serve as a&#xD;
             contraindication to receipt of live virus vaccine, protocol adherence, or a&#xD;
             participant s ability to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Psychiatric condition that precludes compliance with the protocol; past or present&#xD;
             psychoses; past or present bipolar disorder requiring therapy that has not been well&#xD;
             controlled on medication for the past two years; disorder requiring lithium; or&#xD;
             suicidal ideation occurring within five years prior to&#xD;
&#xD;
             enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participants that live in the same house or apartment with any of the following will&#xD;
             be excluded:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. An individual under 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. An immunocompromised or immunosuppressed individual&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. An individual with chronic respiratory disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. A woman who is currently pregnant or planning a pregnancy during the period of&#xD;
                  immunization&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Healthcare worker who has direct contact with immunodeficient, unstable patients, or&#xD;
             pediatric patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participants caring for children less than 36 months of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Receipt of any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Antiviral medications within 30 days prior to vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Blood products within 120 days prior to HIV screening&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Immunoglobulin within 60 days prior to HIV screening&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Investigational research drugs or any other investigational agent that in the&#xD;
                  judgement of the PI might interact with the study vaccine within 30 days prior to&#xD;
                  initial study vaccine administration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Allergy treatment with antigen injections within 30 days of study vaccine&#xD;
                  administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of Guillain-Barr(SqrRoot)(Copyright) syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of H5 influenza vaccination. (This criterion does not apply to participants in&#xD;
             vaccine arm B.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria for the expansion H5N1 boost phase:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of systemic hypersensitivity reactions to egg proteins or life-threatening&#xD;
             reactions to previous influenza vaccinations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of Guillain-Barr(SqrRoot)(Copyright) syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Acute infection or a recent (within 6 months) history of chronic infection suggestive&#xD;
             of immunodeficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Taking any medication which may affect immune function, except participants may be&#xD;
             taking low doses of nonprescription strength NSAIDS (including e.g. ibuprofen or&#xD;
             aspirin) or acetaminophen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Receipt of an approved vaccine, investigational research drugs, or any other&#xD;
             investigational agent that in the judgement of the PI might interact with the study&#xD;
             vaccine within 30 days prior to H5N1 vaccine administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any medical, psychiatric, or social condition, or occupational or other responsibility&#xD;
             that, in the judgment of the investigator, would interfere with or serve as a&#xD;
             contraindication to receipt of the H5N1 vaccine, protocol adherence, or a participant&#xD;
             s ability to give informed consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark Connors, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Connors M, Collins PL, Firestone CY, Sotnikov AV, Waitze A, Davis AR, Hung PP, Chanock RM, Murphy BR. Cotton rats previously immunized with a chimeric RSV FG glycoprotein develop enhanced pulmonary pathology when infected with RSV, a phenomenon not encountered following immunization with vaccinia--RSV recombinants or RSV. Vaccine. 1992;10(7):475-84.</citation>
    <PMID>1609551</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Couch RB, Cate TR, Fleet WF, Gerone PJ, Knight V. Aerosol-induced adenoviral illness resembling the naturally occurring illness in military recruits. Am Rev Respir Dis. 1966 Apr;93(4):529-35.</citation>
    <PMID>4286394</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Edmondson WP, Purcell RH, Gundelfinger BF, Love JW, Ludwig W, Chanock RM. Immunization by selective infection with type 4 adenovirus grown in human diploid tissue culture. II. specific protective effect against epidemic disease. JAMA. 1966 Feb 7;195(6):453-9.</citation>
    <PMID>4285433</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 22, 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 6, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 6, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 7, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 4, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 4, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 7, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Flu Vaccine</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteer</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

