<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01802931</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>117016</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01802931</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>GSK239512 DDI Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open Label Study in Healthy Volunteers to Investigate the Effect of Ketoconazole on the Pharmacokinetics of GSK239512</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>GlaxoSmithKline</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study will determine the effect of 400 mg once daily of ketoconazole at steady state on&#xD;
      the pharmacokinetics of a single oral dose of GSK239512 in young healthy volunteers.&#xD;
      Ketoconazole is a strong inhibitor of CYP3A4, which is involved in metabolism of drugs. A&#xD;
      two-cohort design will be applied with cohort 1 aimed at providing a first estimate of the&#xD;
      interaction potential of GSK239512 and ketoconazole in terms of pharmacokinetic parameters in&#xD;
      a small number of subjects. Data from Cohort 1 will inform the decision of which dose to use&#xD;
      in Cohort 2, in which a larger number of subjects will be exposed to GSK239512 without and&#xD;
      with ketoconazole. The target maximum exposure is aimed to be similar to the exposure by a&#xD;
      single dose of 80 mcg of GSK239512 without CYP3A4 inhibition. In summary, the results from&#xD;
      this study will help to estimate the maximum increase in exposure of GSK239512 during&#xD;
      concomitant use of strong CYP3A4 inhibitors and will help define the subsequent dosing&#xD;
      strategy around GSK239512 and co-medications with potential to inhibit CYP3A4.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 7, 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 15, 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 15, 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC of GSK239512</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose and up to 120 hour post dose of GSK239512</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax of GSK239512</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose and up to 120 hour post dose of GSK239512</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with adverse events as a measure of safety and tolerability</measure>
    <time_frame>15 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">22</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Session 1 or Session 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single dose sessions without ketoconazole co-administration</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Co-dose Session</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single dose session with ketoconazole co-administration</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>GSK239512</intervention_name>
    <description>H3 receptor antagonist, potential victim of drug-drug interaction</description>
    <arm_group_label>Co-dose Session</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Session 1 or Session 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ketoconazole</intervention_name>
    <description>CYP3A4 inhibitor, potential perpetrator of drug-drug interaction</description>
    <arm_group_label>Co-dose Session</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male between 18 and 45 years of age inclusive, at the time of signing the informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Healthy as determined by a responsible and experienced physician, based on a medical&#xD;
             evaluation including medical history, physical examination, laboratory tests and&#xD;
             cardiac monitoring. A subject with a clinical abnormality or laboratory parameters&#xD;
             outside the reference range for the population being studied may be included only if&#xD;
             the Investigator and the GSK Medical Monitor agree that the finding is unlikely to&#xD;
             introduce additional risk factors and will not interfere with the study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. ALT, alkaline phosphatase and bilirubin &lt; or = 1.5xULN (isolated bilirubin &gt;1.5xULN is&#xD;
             acceptable if bilirubin is fractionated and direct bilirubin &lt;35%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. QTcF &lt; 450 msec.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Male subjects with female partners of child-bearing potential must agree to use one of&#xD;
             the contraception methods listed in the protocol. This criterion must be followed from&#xD;
             the time of the first dose of study medication until 1 month post-last dose of&#xD;
             GSK239512.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Body weight &gt; 50 kg, and body mass index (BMI) between 19.0 - 29.9 kg/m2 inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Capable of giving informed consent and can comply with the study requirements and&#xD;
             timetable.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. A positive pre-study Hepatitis B surface antigen or positive Hepatitis C antibody&#xD;
             result within 3 months of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Current or chronic history of liver disease, or known hepatic or biliary abnormalities&#xD;
             (with the exception of Gilbert's syndrome or asymptomatic gallstones).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. A positive pre-study drug/alcohol screen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. A positive test for Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) antibody.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of alcohol consumption exceeding, on average, 21 drinks/week for men (1 drink&#xD;
             = 100 mL of wine or 240 mL of beer or 30 mL of hard liquor in Australia) within 6&#xD;
             months of the first dose of study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of smoking cigarettes or using tobacco products or any nicotine-containing&#xD;
             products (including nicotine patches) within 3 months of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The subject has participated in a clinical trial and has received an investigational&#xD;
             product within 30 days or 5 half lives (whichever is longer) prior to the first dosing&#xD;
             day in the current study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Exposure to more than four new chemical entities within 12 months prior to the first&#xD;
             dosing day.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Unable to refrain from the use of prescription or non-prescription drugs, including&#xD;
             vitamins, herbal and dietary supplements (including St John's Wort) within 7 days (or&#xD;
             14 days if the drug is a potential enzyme inducer) or 5 half-lives (whichever is&#xD;
             longer) prior to the first dose of study medication, unless in the opinion of the&#xD;
             Investigator and GSK Medical Monitor the medication will not interfere with the study&#xD;
             procedures or compromise subject safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of sensitivity to ketoconazole, or to the excipients contained in GSK239512 or&#xD;
             Nizoral, or a history of drug or other allergy that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator or GSK Medical Monitor, contraindicates their participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Where participation in the study would result in donation of blood or blood products&#xD;
             in excess of 500 mL within a 56 day period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Unwillingness or inability to follow the procedures outlined in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subject is mentally or legally incapacitated.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Have used the following medications within the last 30 days or 5 half-lives (whichever&#xD;
             is longer) prior to screening and are not able to discontinue use throughout&#xD;
             participation in the clinical trial:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any CNS stimulants (e.g., modafinil, dexamphetamine, methylphenidate).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Known potent P-glycoprotein inhibitors (e.g. itraconazole, ketoconazole,&#xD;
                  cyclosporin, loperamide, diltiazem, verapamil, spironolactone, quinidine,&#xD;
                  bepridil, quinine, carvedilol).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Known potent inhibitors or inducers of the CYP3A4 enzyme (see Appendix 3).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CNS-penetrant antihistamines (e.g. bromopheniramine, chlorpheniramine,&#xD;
                  clemastine, diphenhydramine, hyrdoxyzine)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any other medicines that are contraindications of Nizoral (see Appendix 4).&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Unable to refrain from consumption of red wine, seville oranges, grapefruit or&#xD;
             grapefruit juice from 7 days prior to the first dose of study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. The subject has a history of significant psychiatric illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Presence or history of hallucinations that, in the judgement of the investigator, may&#xD;
             increase the safety risk to the subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. At risk of suicide, as indicated by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A documented history of attempted suicide or significant suicidal ideation during&#xD;
                  the 6 months preceding the screening visit, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If in the investigator's judgment the subject is at risk of a suicide attempt&#xD;
                  based on the screen visit assessment, including the C-SSRS.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Diagnosis of any type epilepsy&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Night shift workers within 4 weeks of first dosing&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Presence of significant and routine sleep disturbance that has a negative impact on&#xD;
             quality of life that, in the judgement of the investigator, may increase the risk of&#xD;
             tolerability issues during dose escalation.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Examples of significant sleep disturbances may be: severe insomnia, nocturnal&#xD;
                  wandering, confusion, disorientation, agitation, or vivid dreams.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>GSK Clinical Trials</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>GlaxoSmithKline</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Randwick</city>
        <state>New South Wales</state>
        <zip>2031</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</url>
    <description>Researchers can use this site to request access to anonymised patient level data and/or supporting documents from clinical studies to conduct further research.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>July 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 4, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 28, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 4, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 24, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 24, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 26, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>GSK239512</keyword>
  <keyword>H3 receptor antagonist</keyword>
  <keyword>drug-drug interaction</keyword>
  <keyword>pharmacokinetics</keyword>
  <keyword>ketoconazole</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ketoconazole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Patient-level data for this study will be made available through www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com following the timelines and process described on this site.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <study_docs>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>117016</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Dataset Specification</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>117016</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Annotated Case Report Form</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>117016</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Statistical Analysis Plan</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>117016</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Individual Participant Data Set</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>117016</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Clinical Study Report</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>117016</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Informed Consent Form</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>117016</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Study Protocol</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
  </study_docs>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

