<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01874808</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GAITALS-C12-13</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2012-A01247-36</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01874808</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>From Movement Preparation to Gait Execution in ALS</brief_title>
  <acronym>GAITALS</acronym>
  <official_title>From Movement Preparation to Gait Execution in ALS: : Combined Neurophysiological and Neuroimaging Approaches</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Institut National de la Santé Et de la Recherche Médicale, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Université Paris Ouest-EA 2931-CEntre de Recherches sur le Sport et le Mouvement</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institut National de la Santé Et de la Recherche Médicale, France</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research program will focus on gait initiation and postural control in Amyotrophic&#xD;
      Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) patients, by comparing patients with vs without postural instability&#xD;
      (but also in comparison to controls), by using a multidisciplinary approach which combines&#xD;
      neurophysiological and neuroimaging analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After clinical evaluation, two groups of ALS patients, defined upon the feature of postural&#xD;
      instability, and one group of healthy subjects (n=25 for each group of patients and 20 for&#xD;
      healthy subjects) will be included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The neurophysiological evaluation will be performed through a gait initiation assessment,&#xD;
      which will alow us to collect biomechanical and electromyographical data, such as the braking&#xD;
      index.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The neuroradiological evaluation will include first an fMRI analysis, a study of specific&#xD;
      circuits in networks will be performed which will provide the first description of neural&#xD;
      network dynamics associated with the preparation and execution of movement in ALS patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators major research hypothesis is:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  By comparing patients with vs without postural instability, but also in comparison to&#xD;
           controls, the investigators main research neurophysiological hypothesis is that patients&#xD;
           with postural instability will display an impaired braking.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This impaired braking could be partly explained by a dysfunction and/or lesion of the&#xD;
           basal ganglia and brain stem structures, corresponding to the investigators main&#xD;
           neuroradiological hypothesis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Compared to other movement disorders, such as Parkinson Disease (PD), the mechanisms of&#xD;
      movement impairment in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) have not been a focus of great&#xD;
      interest. It is at least partly related to the classical assumption that impairment of&#xD;
      movement in ALS simply reflects a dysfunction of the final motor pathways. However, the&#xD;
      concept that ALS purely involves upper and lower motor neuron has been definitively&#xD;
      challenged. Accumulating evidence for the concept that ALS is a multisystem degenerative&#xD;
      disease is supported by histological, neurophysiological and neuroimaging studies.&#xD;
      Clinically, lower limb stiffness is associated with extrapyramidal rigidity and postural&#xD;
      instability in 69% of ALS patients. These latter may also display abnormalities of movement&#xD;
      initiation impairing walking, such as gait initiation failure, usually reported in PD&#xD;
      patients. All these data support the hypothesis that some balance troubles in ALS patients&#xD;
      may result from an additional dysfunction and/or lesion of the basal ganglia circuitry and/or&#xD;
      of its output structures, such as the cortex or the midbrain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In PD patients, which represent a model of basal ganglia system dysfunction, length and&#xD;
      velocity of the first step during gait initiation are known to be reduced and improved by&#xD;
      dopaminergic therapy whereas postural instability is less sensitive to the treatment&#xD;
      suggesting the involvement of other brain structures dysfunction and/or lesion. One way to&#xD;
      evaluate the postural control during the gait initiation process is to measure the vertical&#xD;
      velocity of the centre of gravity by using a force platform. In healthy adults, during the&#xD;
      single support phase, a forward fall of the centre of gravity occurs and is actively reversed&#xD;
      by the stance leg soleus muscle activation prior foot contact. In parkinsonian patients with&#xD;
      postural instability, this phenomenon, called active braking, is altered. It is assumed that&#xD;
      this postural instability results from additional lesions and/or dysfunction in the basal&#xD;
      ganglia output structures, especially in the midbrain, containing the pedunculopontine&#xD;
      nucleus and the mesencephalic locomotor region, two structures known to participate to the&#xD;
      control of locomotion and posture in animals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This research program will focus on gait initiation and postural control in ALS patients, by&#xD;
      comparing patients with vs without postural instability (but also in comparison to controls),&#xD;
      by using a multidisciplinary approach which combines neurophysiological and neuroimaging&#xD;
      analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After clinical evaluation, two groups of ALS patients, defined upon the feature of postural&#xD;
      instability, and one group of healthy subjects (n=25 for each group of patients and 20 for&#xD;
      healthy subjects) will be included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The neurophysiological evaluation will be performed through a gait initiation assessment,&#xD;
      which will alow us to collect biomechanical and electromyographical data, such as the braking&#xD;
      index.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The neuroradiological evaluation will include first an fMRI analysis. A study of specific&#xD;
      circuits in networks will be performed which will provide the first description of neural&#xD;
      network dynamics associated with the preparation and execution of movement in ALS patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the investigators get a deeper understanding of the neural substrates underlying the&#xD;
      hypothetical impairment of gait initiation and postural control, the investigators will then&#xD;
      be able to develop adequate therapeutical strategies (pharmacological interventions, surgical&#xD;
      therapies, rehabilitation programs) aimed at improving movement preparation and gait&#xD;
      execution in ALS patients&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 21, 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 21, 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Neurophysiological evaluation (braking index)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day of the experiment</time_frame>
    <description>Braking index</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation in neuroimaging</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day of the experiment</time_frame>
    <description>FMRI analysis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">59</enrollment>
  <condition>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Healthy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ALS with postural instability</arm_group_label>
    <description>ALS with postural instability</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ALS without postural instability</arm_group_label>
    <description>ALS without postural instability</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        ALS patients with motor deficit with or without postural instability&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Between 18 (exclusive) and 75 (inclusive) years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With a defined, probable or laboratory possible ALS according to El Escorial18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With a disease duration between 3 months (inclusive) and 5 years (exclusive)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to walk at least 10 meters without an aid and to perform the foot-tapping task&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Right handed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to understand thoroughly the given information; able to sign the informed consent&#xD;
             form (signature of spouse or family relative or acceptable third party is acceptable&#xD;
             if the patient is physically unable to sign)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With a social insurance&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a fronto temporal dementia (according to Neary' criteria)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any concomitant life-threatening disease or any disease or impairment&#xD;
             likely to interfere with functional assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any major evolving psychiatric disorder or major anxiety disorder&#xD;
             according to DSM-IV criteria (APA, 1996)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with contraindications for the MRI scan&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pierre François Pradat, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hôpital Pitié-Salpétrière, Département des Maladies du Système Nerveux 47-83 Boulevard de l'Hôpital 75013 Paris France</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Pitié-Salpétrière, Département des Maladies du Système Nerveux 47-83 Boulevard de l'Hôpital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75013</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 20, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 10, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 11, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>movement preparation</keyword>
  <keyword>gait</keyword>
  <keyword>gait initiation</keyword>
  <keyword>postural control</keyword>
  <keyword>neuroimaging</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Motor Neuron Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

