<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04795037</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CU06-1004-DME-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04795037</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>First-In-Human Study of CU06-1004 Following Single and Multiple Ascending Doses in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetic Study of Escalating Single and Multiple Doses of CU06-1004 in Healthy Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Curacle Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>KCRN Research, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Curacle Co., Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This clinical trial is the first-in-human study of CU06-1004. The purpose of this phase 1&#xD;
      study is to assess the safety and tolerability of single and multiple ascending oral doses of&#xD;
      CU06-1004 in healthy adult subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 21, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A Single Ascending Dose(SAD) study with 7 Cohorts including 1 Cohorts for Food effect (FE) assessment with 8 subjects each (6 active and 2 placebo) and A Multiple Ascending Dose(MAD) study with 3 Cohorts with 8 subjects each (6 active and 2 placebo).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The number and severity of treatment emergent adverse events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of first dose through 7 days after the last dose</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the safety and tolerability of single and multiple ascending oral doses of CU06-1004 in healthy adult subjects.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum plasma concentration (Cmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 4 (SAD), Day 1 through Day 10 (MAD)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess Cmax of single and multiple ascending oral doses of CU06-1004 in healthy adult subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to reach maximum plasma concentration (Tmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 4 (SAD), Day 1 through Day 10 (MAD)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess Tmax of single and multiple ascending oral doses of CU06-1004 in healthy adult subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the concentration-time curve (AUC)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 4 (SAD), Day 1 through Day 10 (MAD)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess AUC of single and multiple ascending oral doses of CU06-1004 in healthy adult subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal elimination rate constant (Kel)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 4 (SAD), Day 1 through Day 10 (MAD)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess Kel of single and multiple ascending oral doses of CU06-1004 in healthy adult subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal elimination half-life (t½)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 4 (SAD), Day 1 through Day 10 (MAD)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess t½ of single and multiple ascending oral doses of CU06-1004 in healthy adult subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum plasma concentration (Cmax) under fed conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 4 (SAD)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess Cmax of single oral dose under fed conditions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the concentration-time curve (AUC) under fed conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 4 (SAD)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess AUC of single oral dose under fed conditions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Amount of unchanged drug excreted in the urine collection (Ae)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 4 (SAD), Day 1 through Day 10 (MAD)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess Ae of single and multiple ascending oral doses of CU06-1004 in healthy adult subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Renal Clearance (CLR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 4 (SAD), Day 1 through Day 10 (MAD)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess CLR of single and multiple ascending oral doses of CU06-1004 in healthy adult subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fraction of drug excreted unchanged in urine (Fe)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 4 (SAD), Day 1 through Day 10 (MAD)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess Fe of single and multiple ascending oral doses of CU06-1004 in healthy adult subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetic Macular Edema</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CU06-1004 for SAD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Fifty-six (56) healthy subjects are planned to be enrolled in 7 cohorts&#xD;
6 of out 8 subjects per cohort will be randomized to receive CU06-1004</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo for SAD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Fifty-six (56) healthy subjects are planned to be enrolled in 7 cohorts&#xD;
2 of out 8 subjects per cohort will be randomized to receive placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CU06-1004 for MAD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Twenty-four (24) healthy subjects are planned to be enrolled in 3 cohorts&#xD;
6 of out 8 subjects per cohort will be randomized to receive CU06-1004</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo for MAD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Twenty-four (24) healthy subjects are planned to be enrolled in 3 cohorts&#xD;
2 of out 8 subjects per cohort will be randomized to receive placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CU06-1004, Single dose</intervention_name>
    <description>Single dose of CU06-1004, 7 dose levels, oral capsule : 6 Cohorts (100mg, 300mg, 600mg, 900mg, 1200mg, 300mg bid) + 1 Cohort (Food effect)＊&#xD;
＊Cohort S7(TBD mg) will receive a single oral dose of CU06-1004 or placebo under fed conditions. When administered under fed conditions, CU06-1004 or placebo will be administered following a high-fat/high-calorie breakfast. Cohort S7 will be conducted following completion of Cohort S5</description>
    <arm_group_label>CU06-1004 for SAD</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CU06-1004, Multiple doses</intervention_name>
    <description>Multiple doses of CU06-1004, 7 days, 3 dose levels＊, oral capsule&#xD;
＊The dose levels, regimen (i.e., schedule), and conditions (i.e., fasted versus fed conditions) will be determined based on the safety, tolerability, and plasma PK data from SAD</description>
    <arm_group_label>CU06-1004 for MAD</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo matched to CU06-1004, oral capsule</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo for MAD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo for SAD</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy, adult, male or female (of non-childbearing potential only), 19-55 years of&#xD;
             age, inclusive, at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Body mass index (BMI) ≥ 18.0 and ≤ 32.0 kg/m2 at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Continuous non-smoker who has not used nicotine-containing products for at least 3&#xD;
             months prior to the first dosing and throughout the study, based on subject&#xD;
             self-reporting.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Medically healthy with no clinically significant medical history, physical&#xD;
             examination, laboratory profiles, vital signs or ECGs, as deemed by the PI or&#xD;
             designee.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Female must be of non-childbearing potential and must have undergone one of the&#xD;
             following sterilization procedures at least 6 months prior to the first dosing:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  hysteroscopic sterilization;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  bilateral tubal ligation or bilateral salpingectomy;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  hysterectomy;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  bilateral oophorectomy; or be postmenopausal with amenorrhea for at least 1 year&#xD;
                  prior to the first dosing and follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) serum levels&#xD;
                  consistent with postmenopausal status.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. A non-vasectomized, male subject must agree to use a condom with spermicide or abstain&#xD;
             from sexual intercourse during the study until 90 days after the last dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
             (No restrictions are required for a vasectomized male provided his vasectomy has been&#xD;
             performed 4 months or more prior to the first dosing. A male who has been vasectomized&#xD;
             less than 4 months prior to the first dosing must follow the same restrictions as a&#xD;
             non-vasectomized male).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. If male, must agree not to donate sperm from the first dosing until 90 days after the&#xD;
             last dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Able to swallow multiple capsules.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Understands the study procedures in the informed consent form (ICF), and be willing&#xD;
             and able to comply with the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Is mentally or legally incapacitated or has significant emotional problems at the time&#xD;
             of the screening visit or expected during the conduct of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History or presence of clinically significant medical or psychiatric condition or&#xD;
             disease in the opinion of the PI or designee.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of any illness that, in the opinion of the PI or designee, might confound the&#xD;
             results of the study or poses an additional risk to the subject by their participation&#xD;
             in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History or presence of alcohol or drug abuse within the past 2 years prior to the&#xD;
             first dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History or presence of hypersensitivity or idiosyncratic reaction to the study drug or&#xD;
             related compounds.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Female subjects of childbearing potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Female subjects with a positive pregnancy test at screening or first check-in or who&#xD;
             are lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Positive urine drug or alcohol results at screening or first check-in.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Positive results at screening for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B&#xD;
             surface antigen (HBsAg) or hepatitis C virus (HCV).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Seated blood pressure is less than 90/40 mmHg or greater than 140/90 mmHg, at&#xD;
             screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Seated heart rate is lower than 40 bpm or higher than 99 bpm at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. QTcF interval is &gt;460 msec (males) or &gt;470 msec (females) or has ECG findings deemed&#xD;
             abnormal with clinical significance by the PI or designee at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Unable to refrain from or anticipates the use of:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any drug, including prescription and non-prescription medications, herbal&#xD;
                  remedies, or vitamin supplements (especially sulforaphane-containing supplement)&#xD;
                  beginning 14 days prior to the first dosing and throughout the study. After&#xD;
                  randomization, acetaminophen (up to 2 g per 24 hours) may be administered at the&#xD;
                  discretion of the PI or designee.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Food and beverages containing xanthines/caffeine for 24 hours prior to the first&#xD;
                  dosing (small amounts of caffeine derived from normal foodstuffs e.g.,250 mL/8&#xD;
                  oz./1 cup decaffeinated coffee or other decaffeinated beverage, per day, with the&#xD;
                  exception of espresso; 45 g/1.5 oz. chocolate bar, per day, would not be&#xD;
                  considered a deviation to this restriction).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Food and beverages containing alcohol for 48 hours prior to the first dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Food and beverages containing grapefruit/Seville orange for 14 days prior to the&#xD;
                  first dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Food and beverages containing vegetables from the mustard green family (e.g.,&#xD;
                  kale, broccoli, watercress, collard greens, kohlrabi, Brussels sprouts, mustard)&#xD;
                  and charbroiled meats for 14 days prior to the first dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Has received COVID-19 vaccine within 30 days of first dosing and until the end of the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Has been on a diet incompatible with the on-study diet, in the opinion of the PI or&#xD;
             designee, within the 30 days prior to the first dosing and throughout the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Is lactose intolerant (FE cohort only).&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Donation of blood or significant blood loss within 56 days prior to the first dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Plasma donation within 7 days prior to the first dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Participation in another clinical study within 30 days prior to the first dosing. The&#xD;
             30-day window will be derived from the date of the last blood collection or dosing,&#xD;
             whichever is later, in the previous study to the first dose of study drug in the&#xD;
             current study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ji-Hye Kang, Ph.D</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Curacle Co., Ltd.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hugh Lee, Ph.D</last_name>
    <phone>301-540-2600</phone>
    <email>hughlee@kcrnresearch.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Heewon Seo, Master</last_name>
    <phone>+82-70-4410-2135</phone>
    <email>hw2121@curacle.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Celerion</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lincoln</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68502</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Allen Hunt, M.D.</last_name>
      <phone>402-476-2811</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Allen Hunt, M.D.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Maganti L, Panebianco DL, Maes AL. Evaluation of methods for estimating time to steady state with examples from phase 1 studies. AAPS J. 2008;10(1):141-7. doi: 10.1208/s12248-008-9014-y. Epub 2008 Feb 28. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18446514</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schuirmann DJ. A comparison of the two one-sided tests procedure and the power approach for assessing the equivalence of average bioavailability. J Pharmacokinet Biopharm. 1987 Dec;15(6):657-80.</citation>
    <PMID>3450848</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>DME</keyword>
  <keyword>Endothelial dysfunction blocker</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Macular Edema</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

