<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04797130</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NL75126.068.20</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04797130</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Hospital Fit 2.0 on Patients Physical Activity</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of a Smartphone App With Accelerometer on Patients' Physical Activity: a Randomised Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Maastricht University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Maastricht University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this study is to investigate if using Hospital Fit 2.0 as part of&#xD;
      the usual care physiotherapy treatment of patients hospitalised at the department of Internal&#xD;
      Medicine and the department of Pulmonology in MUMC+ will result in an increase in the amount&#xD;
      of PA performed compared to patients who do not use Hospital Fit 2.0 as part of the&#xD;
      physiotherapy treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Rationale: Low physical activity (PA) levels are common in hospitalised patients. Digital&#xD;
      health tools could be valuable to prevent negative effects of inactivity. We therefore&#xD;
      developed Hospital Fit 1.0; a smartphone application with accelerometer, designed for&#xD;
      hospitalised patients. It enables objective activity monitoring, provides patients insight in&#xD;
      their recovery progress and offers a tailored exercise program. Hospital Fit 1.0 has recently&#xD;
      been updated, resulting in the improved Hospital Fit 2.0. Improvements in the accelerometer&#xD;
      algorithm are made, a goalsetting and reminder function are added, and data from the app can&#xD;
      be linked to the electronic medical record. It is hypothesized that using Hospital Fit 2.0 as&#xD;
      part of the physiotherapy treatment of hospitalised patients will result in an increase in&#xD;
      the amount of PA performed compared to patients who do not use Hospital Fit 2.0 as part of&#xD;
      the physiotherapy treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: To investigate if using Hospital Fit 2.0 as part of the usual care physiotherapy&#xD;
      treatment will result in an increase in the amount of PA performed compared to patients who&#xD;
      did not use Hospital Fit 2.0 as part of the usual care physiotherapy treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: Assessor blinded randomised controlled trial. Study population: 78 patients&#xD;
      hospitalised equally distributed over the department of Internal Medicine and the department&#xD;
      of Pulmonology at the Maastricht University Medical Center.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention (if applicable): PA will be measured with an accelerometer until discharge with&#xD;
      a maximum of seven days in all patients. The control group receives usual care physiotherapy&#xD;
      (n=39), while the intervention group uses Hospital Fit additionally (n=39).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main study parameters/endpoints: Primary outcome parameter: time spent walking per day (min).&#xD;
      Secondary outcome parameters: time spent standing per day (min.), average time spent standing&#xD;
      and walking (min.) measured over total measurement time (max. 7 days), number of transitions&#xD;
      per day and average number of transitions measured over total measurement time (max. 7 days),&#xD;
      number of times walking longer than 5 minutes per day and the average number measured over&#xD;
      total measurement time (max.7 days), number of times sitting/lying longer than 30 minutes per&#xD;
      day and the average number measured over total measurement time (max. 7 days) and the mILAS&#xD;
      score per day (max. 7 days).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nature and extent of the burden and risks associated with participation, benefit and group&#xD;
      relatedness: The burden and risks on patients are minimal. The control group will receive&#xD;
      usual care physiotherapy and will wear an accelerometer. The intervention group will use&#xD;
      Hospital Fit 2.0 additionally. Wearing a small accelerometer and using Hospital Fit 2.0&#xD;
      should not be a burden to patients. The only burden is the time it take to prepare subjects&#xD;
      (install app, explain study). No invasive interventions will take place.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 23, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized Controlled Trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Investigators and outcome assessors are blinded for treatment (control group: usual care physiotherapy treatment versus intervention group: usual care physiotherapy treatment and Hospital Fit 2.0 use)</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent walking per day (min.)</measure>
    <time_frame>Period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the total number of minutes walking per day.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average time spent walking</measure>
    <time_frame>Period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the total number of minutes walking divided by the total number of valid measurement days in the period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent standing per day (min.)</measure>
    <time_frame>Period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the total number of minutes walking per day.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average time spent standing</measure>
    <time_frame>Period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the total number of minutes standing divided by the total number of valid measurement days in the period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of transitions from a sedentary position (lying or sitting) to an active position (standing or walking) per day</measure>
    <time_frame>Period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the total number of transitions from being sedentary (lying or sitting) to being physically active (standing or walking) per day</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average number of transitions from a sedentary position (lying or sitting) to an active position (standing or walking)</measure>
    <time_frame>Period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</time_frame>
    <description>defined as the total number of transitions divided by the total number of valid measurement days in the period between inclusion and discharge with a maximum of seven days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of times walking longer than five minutes</measure>
    <time_frame>Period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the total number of times per day a patient spent walking for more than 5 minutes continuously without being interrupted by a standing or sedentary activity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average number of times walking longer than 5 minutes</measure>
    <time_frame>Period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the total number of times per day a patient spent walking for more than 5 minutes continuously without being interrupted by a standing or sedentary activity, divided by the total number of valid measurement days in the period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of times sitting/lying longer than 30 minutes</measure>
    <time_frame>Period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the total numer of times per day a patient spent more than 30 minutes lying and/or sitting without interrupting this behavior with a standing or walking activity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average number of times sitting/lying longer than 30 minutes</measure>
    <time_frame>Period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the total numer of times per day a patient spent more than 30 minutes lying and/or sitting without interrupting this behavior with a standing or walking activity, divided by the total number of valid measurement days in the period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>mILAS score per day</measure>
    <time_frame>Period between inclusion and discharge, with a maximum of seven days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the modified Iowa Level of Assistance Score per day</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">78</enrollment>
  <condition>Telemedicine</condition>
  <condition>Internal Medicine</condition>
  <condition>Pulmonary Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>All subjects eligible for inclusion in this study receive usual care physiotherapy as prescribed by the physician. The number of treatment sessions and content of physiotherapy treatment sessions will depend on the diagnosis and needs of the individual patient. This study will not interfere with the content of the usual care physiotherapy treatment. Patients in the control group will receive an accelerometer, measuring PA, which is applied by the physiotherapist during the first treatment. They receive no other additional intervention. Usual care physiotherapy sessions will take approximately 20-30 minutes per session.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in the intervention group will receive usual care physiotherapy and use Hospital Fit 2.0 (HF) additionally. After the last treatment session (max. 7 days), the therapist will remove the accelerometer and participation in the study will end.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hospital Fit 2.0</intervention_name>
    <description>HF consists of a smartphone app combined to an accelerometer. HF provides patients and physiotherapists direct feedback on patients' physical activity behavior.. Individual goals regarding the number of minutes per day spent walking can be set by the therapist. HF also shows patients insight into their own recovery progress. During every treatment, the physiotherapist will evaluate the extent of functional recovery. In addition, Hospital Fit will give physiotherapists the option of creating a patient-specific exercise program supported by videos. During every treatment session, the patient and physiotherapist will evaluate (and if necessary adapt) the amount of activity performed since the previous treatment, the extent of functional recovery and the exercise program.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged between 18 and 75 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving physiotherapy while hospitalised at the department of Internal Medicine&#xD;
             department or the department of Pulmonology at the Maastricht University Medical&#xD;
             Centre (MUMC+)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sufficient understanding of the Dutch language&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having access to a smartphone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to walk independently 2 weeks before admission, as scored on the Functional&#xD;
             Ambulation Categories (FAC &gt;3)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A contraindication to walking (as reported by the attending medical specialists in the&#xD;
             medical record)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A contraindication to wearing an accelerometer, fixed by a hypoallergenic plaster at&#xD;
             the upper leg (such as active bilateral upper leg infection, severe edema or bilateral&#xD;
             transfemoral amputation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Admission at the intensive care department&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impaired cognition (delirium / dementia) as reported by the attending doctor&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Incapacitated subjects as reported by the attending medical specialist in the medical&#xD;
             record. When any doubt arises, the patient will not be considered eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A life expectancy shorter than 3 months as mentioned by the attending medical&#xD;
             specialist in the medical record&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous participation in this study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Antoine F Lenssen, Prof, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Maastricht University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hanneke C van Dijk, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>+31433</phone>
    <phone_ext>877146</phone_ext>
    <email>hanneke.huisman@mumc.nl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Rachel Senden, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+31433</phone>
    <phone_ext>877146</phone_ext>
    <email>rachel.senden@mumc.nl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MaastrichtUMC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Maastricht</city>
        <state>Limburg</state>
        <zip>6229 HX</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Antoine F Lenssen, Prof., PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+3143-3</phone>
      <phone_ext>877146</phone_ext>
      <email>af.lenssen@mumc.nl</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Hanneke C van Dijk - Huisman, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>+3143-3</phone>
      <phone_ext>877146</phone_ext>
      <email>hanneke.huisman@mumc.nl</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mandy Welters, BSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Physical activity</keyword>
  <keyword>eHealth</keyword>
  <keyword>Accelerometer</keyword>
  <keyword>Hospitalization</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>We do not intent to make IPD available to other researchers.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

