<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04791410</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Neurogenic Hypertension</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04791410</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Study on the Efficacy of Microvascular Decompression in the Treatment of Neurogenic Hypertension</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Study on the Efficacy of Microvascular Decompression in the Treatment of Neurogenic Hypertension</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Peking University People's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Peking University People's Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Hypertension has always been a threat to human health, so the prevention and treatment is of&#xD;
      great significance. At present, the treatment of primary hypertension is mainly drug&#xD;
      treatment, but many patients can not control their blood pressure in the normal range.&#xD;
      Therefore, it is urgent to explore new and effective treatment methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Microvascular compression type of neurogenic hypertension is mainly due to abnormal tortuous&#xD;
      vascular pulsatile compression of blood pressure center - rostral ventrolateral medulla&#xD;
      (RVLM), resulting in the release of sympathetic active substances, leading to hypertension.&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to explore the efficacy and safety of microvascular&#xD;
      decompression for hypertension in patients of hemifacial spasm complicated with hypertension,&#xD;
      and to explore the common characteristics of patients with effective decompression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The type of study design was prospective cohort study. According to certain inclusion and&#xD;
      exclusion criteria, patients with RVLM compression were treated with RVLM decompression at&#xD;
      the same time of facial nerve decompression. Patients who were followed up for 3 months were&#xD;
      taken as control group, and the blood pressure of the two groups were measured after 3&#xD;
      months. The main outcome measure was 24-hour ambulatory systolic blood pressure change from&#xD;
      baseline to 3 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Research steps: If the patients with hemifacial spasm are complicated with hypertension and&#xD;
      have the intention of surgical treatment, researchers would introduce the process, possible&#xD;
      benefits and possible complications of the clinical trial in detail. Patients who agree to be&#xD;
      enrolled and meet the inclusion conditions will sign the informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The history of hypertension, the relationship between hypertension and hemifacial spasm, the&#xD;
      highest blood pressure, oral medication, blood pressure maintenance, whether complicated with&#xD;
      dyslipidemia, diabetes, smoking history, etc. Before operation, 24-hour ambulatory blood&#xD;
      pressure monitoring was performed to record preoperative systolic blood pressure, diastolic&#xD;
      blood pressure and heart rate. The measurement interval is automatically measured every 20&#xD;
      minutes in the daytime (8:00am ~ 10:00pm) and every 30 minutes at night (10:00pm ~ 8:00am).&#xD;
      CBP was recorded in the morning (8:00-10:00 AM) before taking medication, and completed in&#xD;
      the morning of 8:00-9:00 am the next day. The cuff was placed on the left upper arm. During&#xD;
      the monitoring period, the patient was required to reduce the movement of the left upper arm&#xD;
      as much as possible to avoid the cuff loosening or falling off, which would affect the&#xD;
      measurement results. The record of effective monitoring times must be more than 80% and the&#xD;
      covering time must be more than 20h, otherwise the measurement should be repeated. Patients&#xD;
      should rest for at least 5 minutes before blood pressure measurement. The upper arm was&#xD;
      placed at the heart level. Using OMRON electronic sphygmomanometer, the size of the cuff is&#xD;
      suitable for the patient's upper arm circumference, covering at least 2 / 3 of the upper arm&#xD;
      circumference. The blood pressure of both upper arms was measured, and the blood pressure of&#xD;
      the higher side was taken as the criterion. Repeat the measurement at an interval of 1-2 min,&#xD;
      and record the average value of the two readings. If the difference between the two readings&#xD;
      of systolic or diastolic blood pressure is more than 5 mmHg, it should be measured again, and&#xD;
      the average of the three readings should be taken as the baseline blood pressure measurement&#xD;
      result.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Both the experimental group and the control group need to continue to take antihypertensive&#xD;
      drugs orally, and the type and dose of drugs remain unchanged.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The experimental group was hospitalized and completed the corresponding hematology and&#xD;
      imaging examination. The control group was followed up for 3 months, after the end of the&#xD;
      follow-up can be hospitalized and improve the corresponding hematology and imaging&#xD;
      examination. If the control group matched with the experimental group is excluded, the&#xD;
      control group needs to be rematched. The experimental group received RVLM and (or) IX / X rez&#xD;
      decompression at the same time of facial nerve decompression, while the control group&#xD;
      received no operation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow up: Patients should be followed up at 3 months. The following items were evaluated and&#xD;
      recorded in CRF during follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Physical examination;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Laboratory examination;&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Vital signs (heart rate, respiration);&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Ambulatory blood pressure examination&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Office blood pressure&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Antihypertensive medication: the patient's blood pressure and the use of&#xD;
           antihypertensive drugs were closely monitored after the operation, and the adjustment&#xD;
           time, the type and dosage of antihypertensive drugs after the adjustment were recorded&#xD;
           when making adjustments according to the blood pressure and the cardiologist's&#xD;
           suggestions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Postoperative adverse reactions and duration / remission time: adverse reactions such as&#xD;
           dizziness, headache, nausea and vomiting, tinnitus, hearing loss, diplopia, facial&#xD;
           paralysis, drinking water cough and hoarseness. The above adverse reactions can be&#xD;
           recovered in a few days after the operation. The duration of adverse reactions should be&#xD;
           recorded and relieved in a few days after the operation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Postoperative adverse events: such as patient death, acute cardiovascular events (such&#xD;
           as cardiac arrest, ventricular fibrillation, myocardial infarction and hypertensive&#xD;
           crisis), severe anesthesia or surgical complications (such as long-term mechanical&#xD;
           ventilation due to inability to remove endotracheal intubation, pulmonary embolism,&#xD;
           postoperative cerebral hemorrhage, severe intracranial infection), etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis: SPSS software was used to analyze the follow-up results of the&#xD;
      intervention group and the control group. The general statistical test uses the two-sided&#xD;
      test, and the one-sided test needs to be explained. P value less than or equal to 0.05 was&#xD;
      used to judge whether the difference was statistically significant. The description of&#xD;
      quantitative indicators will calculate the mean, standard deviation, median, quartile,&#xD;
      minimum and maximum. The classification index is described by the number and percentage of&#xD;
      cases. The demographic characteristics, general situation and baseline (before treatment) of&#xD;
      the three groups were compared. Among them, t test was used for measurement data and chi&#xD;
      square test was used for grade data. Binary logistic regression was used to further verify&#xD;
      the influence of age, gender, side, BMI, family history of hypertension and changes of serum&#xD;
      catecholamine on the effect of microvascular decompression in the treatment of neurogenic&#xD;
      hypertension.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>3 Months</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Decreased systolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>After 3 months of treatment, 24 h ambulatory blood pressure was measured, systolic blood pressure was compared with baseline level, and the difference was calculated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Decreased diastolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>After 3 months of treatment, 24 h ambulatory blood pressure was measured, diastolic blood pressure was compared with baseline level, and the difference was calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Decreased office systolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>After 3 months of treatment, office blood pressure was measured, systolic blood pressure was compared with baseline level, and the difference was calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Decreased office diastolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>After 3 months of treatment, office blood pressure was measured, diastolic blood pressure was compared with baseline level, and the difference was calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The cure rate of hypertension 3 months after treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>effective rate of hypertension 3 months after treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">260</enrollment>
  <condition>Neurogenic Hypertension</condition>
  <condition>Hypertension</condition>
  <condition>Surgery</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <description>patients who met the inclusion criteria were treated with RVLM decompression at the same time of facial nerve decompression.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients who met the inclusion criteria were followed up for 3 months before surgery</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>microvascular decompression</intervention_name>
    <description>Microvascular decompression of rostral ventrolateral medulla</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Hemifacial spasm patients with hypertension in our center.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 18 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Preoperative MRI showed RVLM compression;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Primary hemifacial spasm without other secondary factors;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The office systolic blood pressure is higher than 140mmHg and the systolic blood&#xD;
             pressure of ambulatory blood pressure is higher than 130mmHg;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Sign informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Secondary hypertension, such as renal hypertension, vascular hypertension, etc;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. No antihypertensive drugs were taken after admission and ambulatory blood pressure&#xD;
             monitoring showed that the blood pressure was within the normal range;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pregnancy plan or lactation period during pregnancy or within 2 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with congestive heart failure (NYHA grade II-IV), myocardial infarction and&#xD;
             unstable angina pectoris within 6 months before enrollment; patients with severe heart&#xD;
             diseases, such as cardiogenic shock, arrhythmia requiring treatment, heart valve&#xD;
             disease, etc;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Severe cerebrovascular diseases (hypertensive encephalopathy, cerebrovascular injury,&#xD;
             stroke, transient ischemic attack, etc.) within 6 months before admission;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with severe liver disease or dysfunction (ALT or AST &gt; 2 times the upper&#xD;
             limit of normal reference value);&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients with renal impairment (male serum creatinine &gt; 2.0mg/dl (176 μ mol / L),&#xD;
             female serum creatinine &gt; 1.8mg/dl (159 μ mol / L));&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Other surgical contraindications, such as coagulation disorders, severe anemia, severe&#xD;
             pulmonary infection, persistent state of asthma, upper respiratory tract infection,&#xD;
             uncorrected respiratory failure, diabetic ketoacidosis, hepatic encephalopathy,&#xD;
             hepatic coma, acute cerebral infarction, etc;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Type I diabetic patients; diabetic patients with poor glycemic control (FBG &gt; 11.1&#xD;
             mmol / L) or type 2 diabetic patients with microalbuminuria;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Had Cushing's syndrome, coarctation of aorta, hyperthyroidism and other diseases in&#xD;
             the past;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients can not cooperate with the test and follow-up, such as mental disorders,&#xD;
             dementia, advanced tumor, etc;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. If the antihypertensive drugs were adjusted within 2 weeks before admission, the&#xD;
             patients were excluded or re enrolled after the blood pressure was stable for 2 weeks;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Preoperative anesthesia score ≥ grade III;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. To screen those who participated in other clinical studies and used research drugs&#xD;
             within 3 months before the trial, or planned to participate in other clinical studies&#xD;
             during the trial period.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ruen Liu, Professor</last_name>
    <phone>+8618210021286</phone>
    <email>liuruen@pku.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Haidong Song, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+8618210021286</phone>
    <email>songhaidong@pku.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Peking University People's Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Liu Ruen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PekingUPH</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>neurogenic hypertension</keyword>
  <keyword>microvascular decompression</keyword>
  <keyword>hemifacial spasm</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All patient information is confidential.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

