<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04790253</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1901</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04790253</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PRophylactic Cerebral Irradiation or Active MAgnetic Resonance Imaging Surveillance in Small-cell Lung Cancer Patients (PRIMALung Study)</brief_title>
  <acronym>PRIMALung</acronym>
  <official_title>PRophylactic Cerebral Irradiation or Active MAgnetic Resonance Imaging Surveillance in Small-cell Lung Cancer Patients (PRIMALung Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>European Organisation for Research and Treatment of Cancer - EORTC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>UNICANCER</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>European Organisation for Research and Treatment of Cancer - EORTC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this phase III study, the primary objective is to test with a one-sided significance of 5%&#xD;
      whether for the treatment of small cell lung cancer (SCLC) patients, brain MRI surveillance&#xD;
      alone is non-inferior in terms of overall survival compared to prophylactic cranial&#xD;
      irradiation (PCI) combined with brain MRI surveillance in the entire study population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective is to test with a one-sided significance of 5% whether for the&#xD;
      treatment of small cell lung cancer (SCLC) patients, brain MRI surveillance alone is&#xD;
      non-inferior in terms of overall survival compared to prophylactic cranial irradiation (PCI)&#xD;
      combined with brain MRI surveillance in the entire study population under the treatment&#xD;
      policy strategy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To test with a one-sided type I error of 2.5% whether brain MRI surveillance is superior&#xD;
           in terms of cognitive failure free survival (CFFS) compared to prophylactic cranial&#xD;
           irradiation (PCI) combined with brain MRI surveillance in the study population.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To test with a one-sided type I error of 2.5% whether brain MRI surveillance is superior&#xD;
           in terms of global health status/QoL and cognitive functioning according to EORTC&#xD;
           QLQ-C30 questionnaire compared to prophylactic cranial irradiation (PCI) combined with&#xD;
           brain MRI surveillance in the study population.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the frequency and severity of toxicities according to CTCAE v5.0 in the two&#xD;
           arms in the treated population (i.e. patients who have started treatment).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The exploratory objectives are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare OS and CFFS between the arms within the subgroups of patients with LS and ES&#xD;
           disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare OS and CFFS between the arms within the subgroups: HA-PCI or not, first-line&#xD;
           immunotherapy or not, memantine or not.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare cognitive failure free survival (CFFS) rate at 12 months after randomization&#xD;
           between the arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare the cumulative incidence of cognitive failures with death as a competing risk&#xD;
           between the arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare brain-metastasis-free survival (BMFS) between the arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare progression free survival (PFS) between the arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare time to brain-metastasis-attributed death (TBMAD) between the arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare other QoL scales according to EORTC QLQ-C30 and QLQ-BN20 questionnaires&#xD;
           between arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the cost-effectiveness of MRI surveillance alone versus MRI surveillance&#xD;
           combined with PCI.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To collect blood for biobanking.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>After eligibility checks, patients will be randomized between the 2 arms, and stratified by stage of disease (limited versus extensive), immunotherapy as part of the first-line treatment (yes/no), and ECOG Performance Status (0 or 1 versus 2).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary objective is to test with a one-sided significance of 5% whether for the treatment of small cell lung cancer (SCLC) patients, brain MRI surveillance alone is non-inferior in terms of overall survival compared to prophylactic cranial irradiation (PCI) combined with brain MRI surveillance in the entire study population</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>cognitive failure free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>To test with a one-sided type I error of 2.5% whether brain MRI surveillance is superior in terms of cognitive failure free survival (CFFS) compared to prophylactic cranial irradiation (PCI)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>To test with a one-sided type I error of 2.5% whether brain MRI surveillance is superior in terms of global health status/QoL and cognitive functioning according to EORTC QLQ-C30 questionnaire compared to prophylactic cranial irradiation (PCI) combined with brain MRI surveillance in the study population.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety profiling</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>evaluate the frequency and severity of toxicities according to CTCAE v5.0 in the two arms in the treated population (i.e. patients who have started treatment).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Limited Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Extensive-stage Small-cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PCI followed by brain MR surveillance</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Prophylactic cranial irradiation will be delivered at the dose of 25 Gy in 10 fractions to the whole brain.&#xD;
Patients must have a brain MRI performed within 28 days before randomisation and at 3, 6, 9, 12, 18 and 24 months.&#xD;
Extracranial imaging is recommended and will be performed per institutional standards at the discretion of the treating physician.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MRI Active Surveillance</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients must have a brain MRI performed within 28 days before randomisation and at 3, 6, 9, 12, 18 and 24 month. Clinical evaluation will be performed every 3 months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prophylactic cranial irradiation</intervention_name>
    <description>Prophylactic cranial irradiation (PCI) is a technique used to combat the occurrence of metastasis to the brain in highly aggressive cancers that commonly metastasize to brain, most notably small-cell lung cancer.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PCI followed by brain MR surveillance</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically/cytologically proven diagnosis of SCLC&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Limited and extensive stage&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  LS SCLC: Stage I-III (T any, N any, M0, according to UICC TNM staging v8.0) that can&#xD;
             be safely treated with definitive radiation doses. Excludes T3-4 due to multiple lung&#xD;
             nodules that are too extensive or have tumour/nodal volume that is too large to be&#xD;
             encompassed in a tolerable radiation plan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ES SCLC: Stage IV (T any, N any, M 1a/b), or T3-4 due to multiple lung nodules that&#xD;
             are too extensive or have tumour/nodal volume that is too large to be encompassed in a&#xD;
             tolerable radiation plan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Completed standard therapy prior to randomization:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For patients with LS-SCLC, this includes a combination of 4-6 cycles of platinum-based&#xD;
             doublet chemotherapy and either definitive thoracic radiotherapy (including SBRT for&#xD;
             early-stage T1-2 N0 M0 disease who do not undergo surgery) or definitive surgical&#xD;
             resection; thoracic radiation in addition to definitive surgical resection is allowed&#xD;
             at the discretion of the treating physician, but is not mandated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For patients with ES-SCLC, this includes 4-6 cycles of platinum-based doublet&#xD;
             chemotherapy either with or without thoracic radiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
             o Immunotherapy concurrent with and/or adjuvant to standard therapy is allowed at the&#xD;
             discretion of the treating physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of progressive disease after completed standard therapy on systemic imaging&#xD;
             (computed tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of Chest/Abdomen/Pelvis&#xD;
             and brain MRI), 28 days before randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of brain metastases or leptomeningeal disease after completed standard therapy&#xD;
             on systemic imaging (computed tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of&#xD;
             Chest/Abdomen/Pelvis and brain MRI), within 28 days before randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Interval from day 1 of last cycle of chemotherapy to randomization of ≤8 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG PS ≤ 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Estimated creatinine clearance ≥ 30 mL/min as calculated using the MDRD formula&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child bearing potential (WOCBP) must have a negative serum pregnancy test&#xD;
             within 3 days prior to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: women of childbearing potential are defined as premenopausal females capable of&#xD;
        becoming pregnant (i.e. females who have had any evidence of menses in the past 12 months,&#xD;
        with the exception of those who had prior hysterectomy). However, women who have been&#xD;
        amenorrheic for 12 or more months are still considered to be of childbearing potential if&#xD;
        the amenorrhea is possibly due to prior chemotherapy, antioestrogens, low body weight,&#xD;
        ovarian suppression or other reasons.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients Women of childbearing / reproductive potential should use adequate birth&#xD;
             control measures, as defined by the investigator, during the entire period of the&#xD;
             radiotherapy treatment study participation and for at least 30 days after the last&#xD;
             dose of radiotherapy. A highly effective method of birth control is defined as a&#xD;
             method which results in a low failure rate (i.e. less than 1% per year) when used&#xD;
             consistently and correctly. Such methods include:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Combined (oestrogen and progestogen containing) hormonal contraception associated with&#xD;
             inhibition of ovulation (oral, intravaginal, transdermal)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progestogen-only hormonal contraception associated with inhibition of ovulation (oral,&#xD;
             injectable, implantable)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intrauterine device (IUD)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intrauterine hormone-releasing system (IUS)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bilateral tubal occlusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vasectomized partner&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexual abstinence (the reliability of sexual abstinence needs to be evaluated in&#xD;
             relation to the duration of the clinical trial and the preferred and usual lifestyle&#xD;
             of the patient)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects who are breast feeding should discontinue nursing prior to the first&#xD;
             dose of radiotherapy and during the entire period of the radiotherapy treatmentuntil&#xD;
             30 days after the administration of the last dose of radiotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is willing and able to comply with the protocol for the duration of the study&#xD;
             including undergoing treatment and scheduled visits and examinations including follow&#xD;
             up&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Before patient registration/randomization, written informed consent must be given&#xD;
             according to ICH/GCP, and national/local regulations.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior radiotherapy to the brain or whole brain radiotherapy. Note: Patients who have&#xD;
             undergone prior stereotactic radiosurgery for benign tumours or conditions (e.g.,&#xD;
             acoustic neuroma, grade I meningioma, trigeminal neuralgia) may be considered on a&#xD;
             case-by-case basis. Discussion with EORTC Headquarters is mandatory, before the&#xD;
             randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known contraindication to imaging tracer or any product of contrast media, such as&#xD;
             allergy or insufficient renal function. Known contraindication to MRI, such as&#xD;
             implanted metal devices or foreign bodies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other active hematologic or solid tumour malignancy requiring current active&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any unresolved toxicities from prior therapy (e.g., chemotherapy, radiotherapy)&#xD;
             greater than CTCAE grade 2 (according to CTCAE v5.0) at the time of randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with severe active comorbidities, defined as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unstable angina and/or congestive heart failure requiring hospitalization within 6&#xD;
             months prior to randomization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Transmural myocardial infarction within 6 months prior to randomization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute infection requiring treatment at the time of randomization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease exacerbation or other acute respiratory illness&#xD;
             precluding study therapy at the time of randomization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe hepatic disease defined as a diagnosis of Child-Pugh class B or C hepatic&#xD;
             disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV positive with CD4 count &lt; 200 cells/microliter. Note: patients who are HIV&#xD;
             positive are eligible, provided they are under treatment with highly active&#xD;
             antiretroviral therapy (HAART) and have a CD4 count ≥ 200 cells/microliter within 16&#xD;
             weeks prior to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any severe comorbidity that in the opinion of the Investigator might hamper the&#xD;
             participation to the study and/or the treatment administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe neurological (including dementia and epilepsy) or psychiatric disorder&#xD;
             requiring active treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition potentially&#xD;
             hampering compliance with the study protocol and follow-up schedule; those conditions&#xD;
             should be discussed with the patient before randomization in the trial&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Corinne Faivre-Finn, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The Christie NHS Foundation Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Antonin Levy, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre Gustave Roussy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>EORTC Reception</last_name>
    <phone>+3227741611</phone>
    <email>eortc@eortc.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Prophylactic cerebral Irradiation</keyword>
  <keyword>small cell lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>PCI</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

