<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04793178</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>YuksekIhtisasH</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04793178</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effectivity of End-tidal CO2 and Oxygen Reserve Index (ORI) Monitoring in Sedation</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effectivity of End-tidal CO2 and Oxygen Reserve Index (ORI) Monitoring to Detect Respiratory Events and Hypoxemia Before Pulse Oxymetry in Sedation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yuksek Ihtisas Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yuksek Ihtisas Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Endoscopic procedures are commonly performed using sedation. As drug-induced respiratory&#xD;
      depression is a major cause of sedation-related morbidity, pulse oximetry has been&#xD;
      established as standart practice . However SpO2 does not completely reflect ventilation.&#xD;
      Capnography is an additional monitoring parameter which demonstrates respiration activity&#xD;
      breath by breath. Unfortunately, in the state of moderate or deep sedation during diagnostic&#xD;
      or therapeutic procedures (e.g.ERCP or colonoscopies), regular breathing is often disturbed&#xD;
      by moving, squeezing, coughing or changes between nose and mouth ventilation causing leakage&#xD;
      and therefore artifacts or misinterpretation of data acquired with ETCO2. These problems&#xD;
      often restrict the use of side-stream capnography in clinical practice, although the American&#xD;
      Society of Anesthesiologists have suggested in their guidelines that extended monitoring with&#xD;
      capnography 'should be considered'in deep sedation. The oxygen reserve index (ORI) is a new&#xD;
      feature of multiple wavelength pulse oximetry that provides real-time visibility to&#xD;
      oxygenation status in the moderate hyperoxic range (PaO2 of approximately 100-200 mm Hg). The&#xD;
      ORI is an &quot;index&quot; with a unit-less scale between 0.00 and 1.00 that can be trended and has&#xD;
      optional alarms to notify clinicians of changes in a patient's oxygen status. When utilized&#xD;
      in conjunction with SpO2 monitoring the ORI may extend the visibility of a patient's oxygen&#xD;
      status into ranges previously unmonitored in this fashion. The ORI may make pre-oxygenation&#xD;
      visible, may provide early warning when oxygenation deteriorates, and may facilitate a more&#xD;
      precise setting of the required FiO2 level. In this study we aimed to show effectivity of&#xD;
      capnography and ORİ monitoring to avoid respiratory events and hypoxia in sedated endoscopic&#xD;
      patients. In this study we targeted totally 300 sedated endoscopy patients. Patients will&#xD;
      randomize to two groups. In Group I anaesthesiologis will be able to use all the monitoring,&#xD;
      where as in Group II will be blinded for ORİ. We will apply pre-oxygenation to obtain long&#xD;
      safe apnea time. Approximately 5 min pre-oxygenation (5L/min via nasal cannula) will be used&#xD;
      to reach steady state in oxygen reserve. We defined hypoxemia ; SpO2&lt;95% and severe hypoxemia&#xD;
      SpO2≤90%, hypoventilation; rise10 mmHg in ETCO2 compare to baseline, ETCO2≤30 mmHg and flat&#xD;
      capnography.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Endoscopy constitutes a wide range of procedures with many indications.&#xD;
      Esophagogastroduodenoscopy, colonoscopy, endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography&#xD;
      (ERCP), endoscopic ultrasonography (EUS), and enteroscopy comprise the most commonly&#xD;
      performed procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There has been a considerable progress in the practice of sedation and anaesthesia for&#xD;
      endoscopic procedures. The use of sedation reduces patient discomfort and anxiety while&#xD;
      improving the technical quality of the procedure, and as a result, over 98% of clinicians&#xD;
      have adopted the practice. The tremendous benefits of sedation are offset by heightened&#xD;
      costs, increased patient discharge time, and cardiopulmonary complication risks.(1) It has&#xD;
      been well accepted that the most important negative impact of sedation and anaesthesia is the&#xD;
      compromise of respiratory function in the form of hypoxemia, hypoxia and alveolar&#xD;
      hypoventilation. Recent analysis of procedural sedation has revealed an overall incidence of&#xD;
      respiratory depression of 4,1%, with 1,1% of patients requiring assisted ventilation or&#xD;
      reversal agents for respiratory depression.(2) Respiratory monitoring is a fundamental&#xD;
      component of every anaesthetic regimen. Its major relevance for maintenance of homeostasis&#xD;
      and patients' safety is recognized in its position as a mandatory element in national and&#xD;
      international standards for anaesthetic monitoring. (3)Through the decades, advances in&#xD;
      respiratory monitoring have reduced the incidence of anaesthetic morbidity and mortality and&#xD;
      have opened a new era of safe anaesthetic practice. The inherent liabilities of putting&#xD;
      patients under sedation have necessitated a large number of physiological monitoring systems&#xD;
      in order to ensure patient comfort and safety. Currently American Society of&#xD;
      Anaesthesiologist (ASA) guidelines recommend monitoring of pulse oximetry, blood pressure,&#xD;
      heart rate, and end-tidal CO2; although important safeguards, these physiological&#xD;
      measurements do not allow for the reliable assessment of patient sedation. Proper monitoring&#xD;
      of patient state ensures procedure quality and patient safety; however no &quot;gold-standard&quot; is&#xD;
      available to determine the depth of sedation, which is comparable to the anaesthesiologist's&#xD;
      professional judgment. The 2010 House of Delegates of the American Society of&#xD;
      Anaesthesiologists (ASA) amended its Standards for Basic Anaesthetic Monitoring to include&#xD;
      mandatory exhaled end-tidal carbon dioxide (ETCO2) monitoring during both moderate and deep&#xD;
      sedation to its existing requirement for endotracheal and laryngeal mask airway general&#xD;
      anaesthesia. (4) Changes in the respiratory rate, visual inspection of the chest rise and&#xD;
      pulse oximetry (SpO2) have been considered the most conventional and oldest non-invasive&#xD;
      methods to determine changes in the ventilator status of patients.(5,6) However, derived&#xD;
      respiratory rate alone cannot measure of ventilation. Clinical organization guidelines and&#xD;
      growing body of studies suggest that respiratory rate alone is an inadequate measure of&#xD;
      ventilation, as severe respiratory depression may develop in the presence of a normal&#xD;
      respiratory rate.(7,8) Pulse oximetry (SpO2) is a non-invasive, reliable, and simple method&#xD;
      for continuously monitoring the fractional arterial oxygen saturation and is essential&#xD;
      component of respiratory monitoring. SpO2 is an estimate of SaO2 and it does not provide&#xD;
      information about tissue oxygenation. Moreover SpO2 does not completely reflect&#xD;
      ventilation.(9) Due to the S-shape of the oxygen dissociation curve, large changes in the&#xD;
      partial oxygen tension (PaO2) may remain unnoticed over a period of time if monitoring is&#xD;
      carried out with SpO2 alone.(10) If healthy subjects are pre-oxygenated with 100% oxygen and&#xD;
      ventilate effectively and then become apneic, it may take up to 6 min for an adult before&#xD;
      SpO2 drops below 90%. (11)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Monitoring ETCO2 for the anaesthesiologists is far superior to the pulse oximeter for&#xD;
      immediately detecting an obstructed airway, opiate induced apnea, or other airway problems&#xD;
      that only much later may be detected by the pulse oximeter. As hypoventilation is directly&#xD;
      reflected by an increase in arterial carbon dioxide tension (PaCO2), capnography suggests&#xD;
      itself as an additional monitoring parameter, which furthermore demonstrates respiration&#xD;
      activity breath by breath. (10,12,13) Monitoring ETCO2 is particularly important when&#xD;
      anaesthesiologists provide moderate sedation for patients who are medically compromised, such&#xD;
      as an ASA IV patient with severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease who may retain high&#xD;
      levels of CO2 during sedation or a morbidly obese, insulin-dependent diabetic patient with&#xD;
      severe obstructive sleep apnea. Additionally, in the case of colonoscopy the&#xD;
      anaesthesiologist's only option for managing severe discomfort in the moderately sedated&#xD;
      patients is to deepen the level of sedation until the patient becomes unconsciousness, when&#xD;
      monitoring ETCO2 may be deemed much more important. ASA believes that other less qualified,&#xD;
      non-anaesthesiologist sedation practitioners need it even more than anaesthesiologists.(4)&#xD;
      Some of the independent risk factors for hypoxemia described by Friedrich-Rust et al. are&#xD;
      age, high body mass index, history of sleep apnea, standart monitoring group (without&#xD;
      capnography), total dose of propofol and dose of ketamine.(14) Quader et al. found a&#xD;
      significant difference in the detection of hypoxemic events in 247 patients undergoing an&#xD;
      endoscopic procedure using capnography versus routine surveillance. When capnography was&#xD;
      blinded to the health care provider, 69% of the patients developed hypoxemia compared to 46%&#xD;
      when capnography was available to the provider (p&lt;0.001).(15) Slagelse et al. explored if the&#xD;
      addition of capnography to standard monitoring during endoscopy could reduce number, duration&#xD;
      and level of hypoxia in 540 patients. They found that the number and total duration of&#xD;
      hypoxia was reduced by 39,3 and 21,1% in the intervention group compared to the control group&#xD;
      (p&gt;0.05). (16) Actually in intubated patients or under stable conditions without oral leakage&#xD;
      the measurement of end-tidal carbon dioxide tension in the exhaled air shows an adequate&#xD;
      correlation with PaCO2.(10) Unfortunately, in the state of moderate or deep sedation during&#xD;
      diagnostic or therapeutic procedures (e.g.ERCP or colonoscopies), regular breathing is often&#xD;
      disturbed by moving, squeezing, coughing or changes between nose and mouth ventilation&#xD;
      causing leakage and therefore artifacts or misinterpretation of data acquired with ETCO2.&#xD;
      These problems often restrict the use of side-stream capnography in clinical practice,&#xD;
      although the American Society of Anesthesiologists as well as the American Society of&#xD;
      Gastrointestinal Endoscopy (ASGE) have suggested in their guidelines that extended monitoring&#xD;
      with capnography 'should be considered'in deep sedation. (12,17) Furthermore, while breathing&#xD;
      room air, alveolar hypoventilation can be easily detected with capnography as an increase in&#xD;
      the ETCO2. Since the alveolar oxygen partial pressure decreases, it may lead to an immediate&#xD;
      decrease of SpO2. However up to 35% of all hypoxemic events in patients undergoing endoscopic&#xD;
      procedures occur with completely normal ventilation. In contrast, supplemental oxygen results&#xD;
      in increased alveolar oxygen partial pressure despite the presence of hypoventilation. Rising&#xD;
      ETCO2 and/or flattening of capnography indicates hypoventilation with hypoxia being a&#xD;
      relatively late finding, especially in a patient receiving supplemental oxygen. (18) Arakawa&#xD;
      et al. recently evaluated the masking effects of oxygen supplementation in SpO2 when alveolar&#xD;
      ventilation develops during sedated endoscopy in 70 patients. They found that SpO2 was&#xD;
      significantly higher in the oxygen supplementation group than in the group breathing room air&#xD;
      (98.6 1,4% vs 93,1 p&lt;0.001) at peak ETCO2, and oxygen supplementation caused SpO2 to be&#xD;
      overestimated by greater than 5% when compared with room air. SpO2 at peak ETCO2 was reduced&#xD;
      from the baseline before sedation for the oxygen supplementation and room air breathing&#xD;
      groups by 0,5 1,1% and 4,1 3,1% respectively (p&lt;0.001). (19) The patients breathing a FiO2 as&#xD;
      little as 1 L/min via nasal cannula could be at risk for extreme hypercarbia and CO2 narcosis&#xD;
      from inadequate breathing before patient's arterial hemoglobin oxygen saturation falls below&#xD;
      90%. (20) Under these circumstances, it's the visual inspection of the chest that may alert&#xD;
      the clinician on the presence of hypoventilation. Even capnography monitoring during&#xD;
      neurosurgery has been reported by several studies as a non-reliable method to monitor CO2 due&#xD;
      to its underestimation of the PaCO2. (6)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Masimo Corporation has developed a new parameter for noninvasive monitoring by optical&#xD;
      sensors, Oxygen Reserve index (ORI). The oxygen reserve index (ORI) is a new feature of&#xD;
      multiple wavelength pulse oximetry that provides real-time visibility to oxygenation status&#xD;
      in the moderate hyperoxic range (PaO2 of approximately 100-200 mm Hg). The ORI is an &quot;index&quot;&#xD;
      with a unit-less scale between 0.00 and 1.00 that can be trended and has optional alarms to&#xD;
      notify clinicians of changes in a patient's oxygen status. When utilized in conjunction with&#xD;
      SpO2 monitoring the ORI may extend the visibility of a patient's oxygen status into ranges&#xD;
      previously unmonitored in this fashion. The ORI may make pre-oxygenation visible, may provide&#xD;
      early warning when oxygenation deteriorates, and may facilitate a more precise setting of the&#xD;
      required FiO2 level.(21) The administration of high levels of inspired O2 before tracheal&#xD;
      intubation (pre-oxygenation) is considered to be a routine practice as oxygen reserves are&#xD;
      not always sufficient to prevent hypoxia during the duration of intubation.(22) The ORI may&#xD;
      make this process visible, ensuring that the PaO2 is indeed rising in the presence of a&#xD;
      constant maximal SpO2 level. The ORI may eventually become a performance indicator, attesting&#xD;
      to the fact that pre-oxygenation has indeed been properly performed. Monitoring the ORI may&#xD;
      be especially important in the presence of predictive risk factors for inadequate&#xD;
      pre-oxygenation, which overlap with criteria predictive of difficult mask ventilation.(22) It&#xD;
      may also be extremely important during pre-oxygenation before suctioning hypoxemic patients&#xD;
      (23), during emergency rapid sequence induction, in obese patients, during intubation in the&#xD;
      ICU, and especially in hypoxic patients who may require non-invasive ventilation before&#xD;
      intubation.(21) The ORI may provide early warning of impending hypoxia before any changes in&#xD;
      SpO2 occur. In anesthetized pediatric patients the mean time (±SD) from the start of the ORI&#xD;
      alarm to a decrease in SpO2 below 98 % and from SpO2 98 to 90 % was 40 ± 523 and 52 ± 44 s,&#xD;
      respectively. (24) In another recent trial in 103 anesthetized adult patients, ORI could be&#xD;
      calculated ~91.5 % of monitored time, and was positively correlated with PaO2 values ≤240&#xD;
      mmHg but not with PaO2 &gt;240 mmHg. PaO2 was ≥150 mmHg in 96.5 % of ORI &gt;0.54, and was &gt;100&#xD;
      mmHg for all ORI &gt;0.24 (25)The early warning that the ORI provides before any decrease in&#xD;
      SpO2 occurs may provide precious time for an earlier detection of the event and the provision&#xD;
      of timely remedial measures.(21) Most of the studies about ETCO2 monitoring in moderate and&#xD;
      deep sedation patients focused on the range of hypoxic events with or without ETCO2&#xD;
      monitoring.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 25, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 1, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 25, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The investigator and assessor are blinded to study arms.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hypoxemia</measure>
    <time_frame>during the procedure when/if occured</time_frame>
    <description>SpO2&lt;95%</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Severe hypoxemia</measure>
    <time_frame>during the procedure when/if occured</time_frame>
    <description>SpO2≤90%,</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>hypoventilation</measure>
    <time_frame>during the procedure when/if occured</time_frame>
    <description>rise10 mmHg in ETCO2 compare to baseline, ETCO2≤30 mmHg and flat capnography.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>low oxygen reserve index</measure>
    <time_frame>during the procedure when/if occured</time_frame>
    <description>decreases 10% compare baseline in ORI level.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypoxemia</condition>
  <condition>Procedural Sedation</condition>
  <condition>Hypercapnia</condition>
  <condition>Apnea</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Oxygen Reserve Index Blinded Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Aneshesist will be blinded for oxygen reserve index monitoring (ORI, Masimo Corporation), but he will be allowed to use pulse oxymetry and end-tidal carbon dioxide monitoring to manage the respiratory conditions and depth of sedation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Oxygen Reserve Index Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Aneshesist will be allowed to use pulse oxymetry, end-tidal carbon dioxide and oxygen reserve index (ORI) monitoring. He will manage the depth of sedation, respiaratory conditions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Oxygen Reserve Index, Masimo Corporation, USA.</intervention_name>
    <description>The oxygen reserve index (ORI) is a new feature of multiple wavelength pulse oximetry that provides real-time visibility to oxygenation status in the moderate hyperoxic range (PaO2 of approximately 100-200 mm Hg).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Oxygen Reserve Index Blinded Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Oxygen Reserve Index Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  300 patients with age between 18-75 who are scheduled for endoscopic procedures under&#xD;
             moderate or deep sedation, in Türkiye Yüksek İhtisas Training and Research Hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1- Patient who refuse to concent. 2- Hepatic disease, e.g. twice the normal level of&#xD;
             liver enzymes. 3- EF&lt;40%.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Merry AF, Cooper JB, Soyannwo O, Wilson IH, Eichhorn JH. International Standards for a Safe Practice of Anesthesia 2010. Can J Anaesth. 2010 Nov;57(11):1027-34. doi: 10.1007/s12630-010-9381-6. Epub 2010 Sep 21.</citation>
    <PMID>20857254</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sacchetti A, Senula G, Strickland J, Dubin R. Procedural sedation in the community emergency department: initial results of the ProSCED registry. Acad Emerg Med. 2007 Jan;14(1):41-6. Epub 2006 Aug 31.</citation>
    <PMID>16946280</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 23, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Yuksek Ihtisas Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Seyhan Yagar</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associated Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>sedation, end-tidal carbon dioxide, oxygen reserve index</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypoxia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypercapnia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

