<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04798703</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R39-17-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04798703</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of ONCOFID-P-B™ (PACLITAXEL-HYALURONIC ACID)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I Exploratory Study of ONCOFID-P-B™ (PACLITAXEL-HYALURONIC ACID) Administered for 12 Consecutive Weeks Followed by Maintenance Therapy in BCG Unresponsive/ Intolerant Patients With Bladder Carcinoma in Situ (CIS)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fidia Farmaceutici s.p.a.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fidia Farmaceutici s.p.a.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Phase I exploratory, open-label, single arm, multicenter study to assess safety, tolerability&#xD;
      and antitumor activity of ONCOFID-P-B™ therapy in adult patients with histologically&#xD;
      confirmed diagnosis of bladder carcinoma in situ (CIS), who were unresponsive or intolerant&#xD;
      to Bacillus Calmette-Guérin (BCG)-therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients are initially treated with 12 weekly intravesical instillations of ONCOFID-P-B™&#xD;
      (intensive treatment phase). Patients who achieve a complete response (CR) after the 12&#xD;
      weekly instillations entered the maintenance phase of the study, during which ONCOFID-P-B™ is&#xD;
      furtherly administered once a month for 12 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 24, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 18, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 4, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events (AEs) will be coded using MedDRA and their severity graded according to the NCI Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 4.03.</measure>
    <time_frame>Safety data will be evaluated in the treated patient population through study completition, an average of 15 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Overall safety profile evaluated based on clinical safety parameters (i.e. hematology and blood chemistry, urinalysis, vital signs and adverse events).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Laboratory test values will be graded according to the NCI CTCAE scale, v 4.03.</measure>
    <time_frame>Safety data will be evaluated in the treated patient population through study completition, an average of 15 months.</time_frame>
    <description>For each laboratory test included in the NCI CTCAE system, the incidence of abnormalities will be evaluated by considering the worst occurrence for each patient throughout the whole treatment period.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete Response Rate (CRR) - End of intensive treatment phase,</measure>
    <time_frame>CRR will be evaluated after intensive treatment phase, at 12 weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>Calculated as the proportion of patients who achieved a complete response after 12 weekly instillations of ONCOFID-P-B™.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CRR - End of maintenance phase</measure>
    <time_frame>CRR will be evaluated after the end of the entire treatment period (intensive and maintenance), at 15 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Calculated as the proportion of patients who achieved a complete response after the end of the entire treatment period (intensive + maintenance).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CRR - At 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>CRR will be evaluated at 6 months since treatment start.</time_frame>
    <description>Calculated as the proportion of patients who achieved a complete response after 6 months since treatment start.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of Overall Complete Response - Duration of Response (DoR), defined as the time from when criteria for Complete Response were first met until the first documented occurrence of CIS relapse or progression was reported.</measure>
    <time_frame>CR will be evaluated at any time during the study up to 12 months after the end of treatment period</time_frame>
    <description>Calculated as the proportion of patients who achieved complete response at any time during the study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Bladder Carcinoma in Situ (CIS)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ONCOFID-P-B™ (PACLITAXEL-HYALURONIC ACID)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ONCOFID-P-B™ (PACLITAXEL-HYALURONIC ACID)</intervention_name>
    <description>12 weekly intravesical instillations of ONCOFID-P-B™ (intensive treatment phase) followed by maintenance phase of the study, during which ONCOFID-P-B™ is furtherly administered once a month for 12 months in patients who achieved a complete response (CR) after the 12 weekly instillations.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ONCOFID-P-B™ (PACLITAXEL-HYALURONIC ACID)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with histologically confirmed CIS of the bladder. A portion of patients up to&#xD;
             30% could have concomitant Ta and/or T1 lesions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Complete resection of papillary lesions before entering the trial in patients with&#xD;
             concomitant CIS and papillary tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients were to be unresponsive or intolerant to BCG, had to have refused radical&#xD;
             cystectomy or were not clinically suitable for cystectomy. Patients unresponsive to&#xD;
             BCG were defined as patients for whom further BCG would be unlikely to be of benefit.&#xD;
             This included all patients treated with an adequate course of induction plus&#xD;
             maintenance BCG who either had persistent disease or who relapsed within 6 months of&#xD;
             their last BCG treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥18 yrs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female in non-reproductive years (defined as surgically sterile or one year&#xD;
             postmenopausal). Female of childbearing potential had to agree to practice complete&#xD;
             abstinence or to use an effective contraceptive method.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to comply with scheduled visits, therapy plans, and laboratory tests&#xD;
             required in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed and dated Independent Ethics Committee (IEC)-approved Informed Consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following in the previous 6 months: myocardial infarction, uncontrolled&#xD;
             cardiac arrhythmia, unstable angina, coronary/peripheral artery bypass graft,&#xD;
             symptomatic congestive heart enrolled cerebrovascular accident or transient ischemic&#xD;
             attack, pulmonary embolism, deep vein thrombosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to paclitaxel or any of its constituents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery, other than diagnostic surgery, within 4 weeks prior to treatment start.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Muscle-invasive disease T2-T4.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous or concomitant cancer of the upper urinary tract or the prostatic urethra.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior (within the previous 3 years) or concurrent malignancies at other sites, except&#xD;
             for adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer or in situ carcinoma of&#xD;
             the cervix uteri.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Last intravesical immunotherapy dose administration &lt;8 weeks prior to study entry.&#xD;
             Patients had to have documentation of persistent or recurrent disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous intravesical chemotherapy &lt; 28 days prior to study entry with the exception&#xD;
             of patients who underwent transurethral resection (TUR) &lt; 7 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bladder capacity lower than 150 ml.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of significant urologic disease interfering with intravesical therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent enrollment or participation in another therapeutic clinical trial within 4&#xD;
             weeks preceding treatment start.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known active substances and/or alcohol abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other severe acute or chronic medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory&#xD;
             abnormality that could increase the risk associated with study participation or&#xD;
             interfere with the interpretation of study results and, in the judgment of the&#xD;
             Investigator, would make the patients inappropriate for entry into the study or, in&#xD;
             the opinion of the Investigator and/or the Sponsor, could compromise protocol&#xD;
             objectives.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istituto Europeo di Oncologia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milan</city>
        <state>Mi</state>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IRCCS Humanitas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rozzano</city>
        <state>MI</state>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Parc de Recerca Biomèdica de</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Gregorio Marañón</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Fundación Alcorcón</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma in Situ</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hyaluronic Acid</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

