<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04792294</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1541/2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04792294</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Multicenter Analysis of Efficacy and Outcomes of Extracorporeal Photopheresis as Treatment of Chronic Lung Allograft Dysfunction</brief_title>
  <official_title>Multicenter Analysis of Efficacy and Outcomes of Extracorporeal Photopheresis as Treatment of Chronic Lung Allograft Dysfunction</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical University of Vienna</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of Vienna</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Lung transplantation is an established therapy for end-stage lung disease such as chronic&#xD;
      obstructive pulmonary disease, idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, cystic fibrosis and pulmonary&#xD;
      hypertension. However, Chronic Lung Allograft Dysfunction (CLAD) is a major cause of&#xD;
      morbidity and mortality in long-term survivors. The 5-year survival rate is reported to be&#xD;
      50%, which is considerably inferior compared to other solid organ transplantation. In&#xD;
      addition, the financial burden of CLAD (around 80.000 euro/year for a patient with CLAD) is&#xD;
      considerable. No curative therapy is available yet. To date, the two most effective treatment&#xD;
      are azithromycin and extracorporeal photopheresis. Azithromycin is used as first-line&#xD;
      treatment and it is effective in stopping FEV1 decline, however its effects are only limited&#xD;
      to a set of patients. ECP can be used as second-line treatment in patients unresponsive to&#xD;
      azithromycin. ECP has been firstly developed for treatment of cutaneous T cell lymphomas and&#xD;
      later used in a variety of other indications including solid organ transplantation. The&#xD;
      process starts with leukapheresis, followed by incubation of the isolated cells with&#xD;
      8-methoxypsoralen (8-MOP) and subsequent activation of 8-MOP with ultraviolet A radiation. At&#xD;
      the end, the cells are reinfused into the patient. 8-MOP is a biologically inert substance,&#xD;
      but in the presence of UVA light it cross-links DNA by forming covalent bonds with pyrimidine&#xD;
      bases and causes apoptosis. ECP is effective in the palliative treatment of cutaneous T-cell&#xD;
      lymphoma but its effectiveness was also shown in several other T-cell-mediated diseases,&#xD;
      particularly in the treatment and prevention of acute and chronic graft-versus-host disease.&#xD;
      In depth knowledge on the mechanisms whereby ECP manipulates the immune system are still&#xD;
      unclear. Most of the experimental studies have been performed in murine models of GvHD.&#xD;
      Apoptotic cells isolated during ECP treatment have the potential to induce IL-10 secretion,&#xD;
      reduce dendritic cells activation and increase percentage of Tregs. In addition, ECP reduces&#xD;
      the production of IL-6 and TNF-α and increases TGF-β production. In lung transplantation, ECP&#xD;
      treatment is used as second-line treatment of CLAD and it has the potential to stabilize lung&#xD;
      function decline and to improve long-term graft. According to the published literature,&#xD;
      however, approximately 30 to 40% of treated recipients did not profit from ECP. Greer and&#xD;
      colleagues found that RAS patients as well as rapid lung function decliners showed lower rate&#xD;
      of response and worse long-term outcomes. On the contrary in a more recent analysis only BOS&#xD;
      diagnosis was associated with better outcomes. A single prospective interventional study was&#xD;
      published by our group and it confirmed results from other previous retrospective analysis.&#xD;
      Up to now, no clear predictors for response have been identified yet.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in forced expiratory value in 1 second at 3 months after start of extracorporeal photopheresis</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage change in FEV1 within 3 months after start of extracorporeal photopheresis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>change in maximal expiratory flow (50%) at 3 months after start of extracorporeal photopheresis</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage change in MEF50 within 3 months after start of extracorporeal photopheresis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in forced expiratory value in 1 second/dorced vital capacity ratio at 3 months after start of extracorporeal photopheresis</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage change in FEV1/FVC within 3 months after start of extracorporeal photopheresis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total lung capacity at 3 months after start of extracorporeal photopheresis</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage change in TLC within 3 months after start of extracorporeal photopheresis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patients' survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 5 years from start of extracorporeal photopheresis</time_frame>
    <description>Patients' survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Graft survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 5 years from start of extracorporeal photopheresis</time_frame>
    <description>Graft survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events on extracorporeal photopheresis</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 5 years from start of extracorporeal photopheresis</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events on extracorporeal photopheresis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">800</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Transplant Rejection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lung transplant recipients with chronic lung allograft dysfunction</arm_group_label>
    <description>Lung transplant recipients with chronic lung allograft dysfunction, who underwent extracorporeal photopheresis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Extracorporeal photopheresis</intervention_name>
    <description>ECP can be used as second-line treatment in patients unresponsive to azithromycin. ECP has been firstly developed for treatment of cutaneous T cell lymphomas and later used in a variety of other indications including solid organ transplantation. The process starts with leukapheresis, followed by incubation of the isolated cells with 8-methoxypsoralen (8-MOP) and subsequent activation of 8-MOP with ultraviolet A radiation. At the end, the cells are reinfused into the patient. 8-MOP is a biologically inert substance, but in the presence of UVA light it cross-links DNA by forming covalent bonds with pyrimidine bases and causes apoptosis.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lung transplant recipients with chronic lung allograft dysfunction</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Lung transplant recipients with chronic lung allograft dysfunction who received&#xD;
        extracorporeal photopheresis as treatment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Diagnosis of CLAD Adult transplant recipients (&gt;18 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        ECP for other diagnosis Recipients of multi-organ transplantation Recipients of single lung&#xD;
        transplantation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Medical University of Vienna</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Alberto Benazzo</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD, Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

