<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04791722</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MAHHU0041-18</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04791722</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Optimizing Smoke-free Residential Housing Policies</brief_title>
  <official_title>Optimizing the Impact of Smoke-Free Residential Policies Using an Evidence-Informed Implementation Approach</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Harvard School of Public Health (HSPH)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Harvard School of Public Health (HSPH)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This project will be conducted to investigate activities on housing-related health and safety&#xD;
      issues. The focus of this project is the development of evidence-based approaches to&#xD;
      implement smoke-free policies to reduce harms associated with exposure to secondhand smoke&#xD;
      (SHS).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Chronic exposure to secondhand smoke (SHS) is a major health concern for public housing&#xD;
      residents. While the prevalence of adult cigarette smoking in the United States has declined&#xD;
      to 15.1% in 2015, recent data show that 34% of public housing residents still smoke. A&#xD;
      federal rule issued by HUD now requires Public Housing Agencies (PHAs) to adopt a smoke-free&#xD;
      policy to reduce SHS exposure. However, no evidence-based approaches are available to support&#xD;
      post-adoption implementation by PHAs to ensure that the rule yields optimal benefits for&#xD;
      residents. This research gap also applies to the larger population of affordable housing&#xD;
      properties that are likely to adopt smoke-free rules in the future. The focus of this&#xD;
      research is the development of evidence-based approaches to implement smoke-free policies to&#xD;
      reduce harms associated with exposure to secondhand smoke (SHS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will use six key implementation strategies identified in earlier research&#xD;
      on the experiences of early-adopter PHAs. The investigators will partner with a for-profit&#xD;
      affordable housing management company that recently expanded its portfolio with the&#xD;
      acquisition of 55 affordable housing properties in Pennsylvania, Ohio, West Virginia,&#xD;
      Virginia and Kentucky. This provides a unique opportunity to address the implementation&#xD;
      research gap, because these properties are in geographic locations where the smoking rate is&#xD;
      close to twice the national smoking rate. The for-profit affordable housing management&#xD;
      company has committed to adopting a smoke-free policy in these properties, to go into effect&#xD;
      in early 2020.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Using an established implementation science framework to guide the approach, the&#xD;
      investigators will work with property managers and staff of properties located in five&#xD;
      high-smoking states to strategically incorporate the six implementation strategies to reduce&#xD;
      SHS exposure among affordable housing residents. The findings will provide accessible,&#xD;
      practical, and effective evidence for property managers and staff to support ongoing efforts&#xD;
      to optimize the impact of a smoke-free residential policy. The investigators will test this&#xD;
      approach in a geographic region with high smoking rates and a disproportionate burden of&#xD;
      tobacco-related mortality, covering western Pennsylvania, southern Ohio, West Virginia,&#xD;
      Virginia and Kentucky.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 20, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ambient secondhand smoke (SHS) in common indoor areas</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (prior to smoke-free policy implementation); 1 month post smoke-free policy implementation; 12 months post smoke-free policy implementation</time_frame>
    <description>SHS will be monitored using a passive nicotine dosimeter and measured in units of µg/m3 of airborne nicotine. Monitors will be placed in three common areas of each property.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Self-reported exposure to secondhand smoke (SHS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (prior to smoke-free policy implementation); 1 month post smoke-free policy implementation; 7 months post smoke-free policy implementation</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported exposure to secondhand smoke (smell or sight) in the home or around the property using the questions: Over the past month: how many times did you smell cigarette smoke that came from another apartment or hallway?/ how many times did you smell cigarette smoke anywhere on the property? Measured by resident self-report on the survey.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resident attitude (support) for the smoke-free policy</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (prior to smoke-free policy implementation); 1 month post smoke-free policy implementation; 7 months post smoke-free policy implementation</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported attitude on resident survey</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resident knowledge of the smoke-free policy</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (prior to smoke-free policy implementation); 1 month post smoke-free policy implementation; 7 months post smoke-free policy implementation</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported knowledge on resident survey</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Smoking behavior (cigarettes/day in the past 30 days).</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (prior to smoke-free policy implementation); 1 month post smoke-free policy implementation; 7 months post smoke-free policy implementation</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported smoking behavior on resident survey</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">386</enrollment>
  <condition>Smoking, Tobacco</condition>
  <condition>Second Hand Tobacco Smoke</condition>
  <condition>Smoking Cessation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Wave 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Properties in Wave 1 (n=4) will implement a smoke-free policy on January 1, 2020.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Wave 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Properties in Wave 2 (n=4) will implement a smoke-free policy on May 1, 2020.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Wave 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Properties in Wave 3 (n=4) will implement a smoke-free policy on October 1, 2020.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Adaptive Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>The investigators will conduct an adaptive intervention using six key implementation strategies identified in earlier research on the experiences of public housing authorities adopting a smoke-free housing policy: resident engagement, smoking cessation support, smoker compliance strategies, smoke-free policy enforcement, staff training and community partnership development. The implementation approach will be tailored for each property by varying the order and intensity of smoke-free policy implementation approaches. The design will determine the optimal plan for utilizing the six implementation strategies by learning from the challenges and successes of other properties (previous waves) and providing support to property managers to refine an implementation plan.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Wave 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Wave 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Wave 3</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Property Manager Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Property Manager (or designated appointee) at one of the 12 selected sites&#xD;
             implementing a smoke-free policy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Property Manager Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None&#xD;
&#xD;
        Resident Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 18 and over&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A resident of the housing development (12 selected sites) implementing the smoke-free&#xD;
             policy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Resident Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable/unwilling to complete surveys&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Harvard TH Chan School of Public Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Harvard School of Public Health (HSPH)</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Vaughan Rees</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director, Center for Global Tobacco Control</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

