<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04791007</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>OB-002H-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04791007</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>OB-002H Gel Administered Vaginally and Rectally in HIV-1 Seronegative Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Monocentric Phase I Safety, Acceptability, and Pharmacokinetic Trial of OB-002H Gel Administered Vaginally and Rectally in Open-Label and Randomised, Double- Blind, Placebo-Controlled Cohorts of HIV-1 Seronegative Adults</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Orion Biotechnology Polska Sp. z o.o.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>SCOPE International AG</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Orion Biotechnology Polska Sp. z o.o.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a monocentric phase I study in open-label and randomized, double-blind,&#xD;
      placebo-controlled cohorts of HIV-1 seronegative adults to evaluate the safety,&#xD;
      acceptability, and pharmacokinetic of OB-002H Gel administrated vaginally and rectally.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 5, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 6, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the safety of OB-002H gel after single- and multiple-dose application based on the number of observed AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>approximately 5 weeks for single dose and approximately five to seven weeks for multi-dose</time_frame>
    <description>For the primary safety analysis, the number of ≥ Grade 2 AEs, as well as the number and the percentage of participants with corresponding AEs, will be tabulated overall and per cohort, by system organ class (SOC) and by preferred term (PT).&#xD;
Additional AE analyses will also tabulate the number of AEs ≥ Grade 2 observed overall, by relationship and by severity. AEs ≥ Grade 2 that lead to discontinuation of trial participation will be tabulated separately. The safety set will be used for the primary safety analysis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability</measure>
    <time_frame>assessment done on the visit conducted 24 hours after IMP administration</time_frame>
    <description>Participants will receive a placebo sample to check and evaluate the OB-002H gel and will be asked to answer the questions in the questionnaire with Likert scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>OB-002 serum concentration at different time points for the calculation of PK parameters (area under the concentration-time curve (AUC).</measure>
    <time_frame>Serum samples collected within 24 hours after dosing</time_frame>
    <description>In each Part of the trial, the parameters will be summarised descriptively by cohort and treatment arm (Part 2 only: OB-002H and placebo).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>OB-002 serum concentration at different time points for the calculation of PK parameters (maximum concentration (Cmax).</measure>
    <time_frame>Serum samples collected within 24 hours after dosing</time_frame>
    <description>In each Part of the trial, the parameters will be summarised descriptively by cohort and treatment arm (Part 2 only: OB-002H and placebo).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>OB-002 serum concentration at different time points for the calculation of PK parameters (time to maximum concentration (tmax).</measure>
    <time_frame>Serum samples collected within 24 hours after dosing</time_frame>
    <description>In each Part of the trial, the parameters will be summarised descriptively by cohort and treatment arm (Part 2 only: OB-002H and placebo).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>OB-002 serum concentration at different time points for the calculation of PK parameters (minimum concentration (Cmin).</measure>
    <time_frame>Serum samples collected within 24 hours after dosing</time_frame>
    <description>In each Part of the trial, the parameters will be summarised descriptively by cohort and treatment arm (Part 2 only: OB-002H and placebo).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>OB-002 serum concentration at different time points for the calculation of PK parameters (concentration half-life (t½).</measure>
    <time_frame>Serum samples collected within 24 hours after dosing</time_frame>
    <description>In each Part of the trial, the parameters will be summarised descriptively by cohort and treatment arm (Part 2 only: OB-002H and placebo).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory</measure>
    <time_frame>Serum samples collected within 24 hours after dosing (for cohorts with vaginal gel application)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the drug concentration in the vaginal fluid after OB-002H gel application</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory</measure>
    <time_frame>Fluid samples collected within 24 hours after dosing (for cohort with rectal gel application)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the drug concentration in the rectal fluid after OB-002H gel application</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory</measure>
    <time_frame>Samples collected on baseline and follow up vist (approximately one week after dosing)</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if any changes in vaginal microflora are observed after OB-002H gel application</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory</measure>
    <time_frame>Samples collected on baseline and follow up vist (approximately one week after dosing)</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if any changes in rectal microflora are observed after OB-002H gel application</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory</measure>
    <time_frame>Samples collected on baseline and follow up vist (approximately one week after dosing)</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if any changes in cervical histopathology are observed after OB-002H gel application</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory</measure>
    <time_frame>Samples collected on baseline and follow up vist (approximately one week after dosing)</time_frame>
    <description>To determine changes in rectal histopathology are observed after OB-002H gel application</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Prevention</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single dose administration (Part 1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>the dose of the drug (4g OB-002H (8.0 mg/g)) administrated once vaginally or rectally</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Multidose administration (Part 2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>the dose of the drug (4g OB-002H (8.0 mg/g)) or placebo administered vaginally through five consecutive days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>OB-002</intervention_name>
    <description>vaginal or rectal administration</description>
    <arm_group_label>Multidose administration (Part 2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Single dose administration (Part 1)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>vaginal or rectal administration</description>
    <arm_group_label>Multidose administration (Part 2)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age between 18 and 45 years (inclusive).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. HIV-1 antibody negative as documented at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Understands and agrees to local sexually transmitted infection (STI) reporting&#xD;
             requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Able and willing to provide written informed consent to take part in the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willing and able to return for a follow-up visit one week after last IMP&#xD;
             administration, barring unforeseen circumstances.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Of good general health in the opinion of the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Willing to be sexually abstinent (anal and vaginal sex) for 72 hours before and after&#xD;
             each visit except Visit 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. No participation in other clinical trials within the last three months prior Visit 1&#xD;
             and throughout the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Willing to abstain from inserting any non-trial products for rectal or vaginal&#xD;
             application for 72 hours prior to each trial visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. For female participants only:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Using (or willing to use) highly effective (i.e. failure rate &lt;1% per year)&#xD;
                  methods of contraception for the duration of trial participation. Such methods&#xD;
                  include combined oral or transdermal hormonal contraception associated with&#xD;
                  inhibition of ovulation, oral, injectable or implantable progestogen-only&#xD;
                  hormonal contraception associated with inhibition of ovulation, intrauterine&#xD;
                  device [IUD] or intrauterine hormone-releasing system [IUS] inserted at least 28&#xD;
                  days prior to the Screening Visit, bilateral tubal occlusion, surgical&#xD;
                  sterilization, successful vasectomisation of male partner or sexually abstinent&#xD;
                  for the past 90 days and during the trial. If the female participant has female&#xD;
                  partners only, the method of contraception will be noted as abstinence to&#xD;
                  heterosexual activities in the trial documentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Not pregnant at the screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Not breastfeeding at screening nor intending to breastfeed during trial&#xD;
                  participation per participant report.&#xD;
&#xD;
             In addition, participants enrolled in the corresponding cohorts must meet the&#xD;
             following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Cohorts A1 and B1 only: Willing to stay at the site overnight for two nights.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Cohort A2 only: Willing to stay at the site overnight for six nights.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Cohort A3 only: Willing to stay at the site overnight from Day 1 to Day 2 and from Day&#xD;
             5 to Day 6 for PK blood sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Following laboratory findings at screening:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Haemoglobin &lt; 10.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Platelet count &lt; 100 000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. White blood cell count &lt; 2 000 cells/mm3 or &gt; 15 000 cells/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &lt; 60 mL/min/1.73 m2&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Alanine transaminase (ALT) and/or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &gt; 2.5×&#xD;
                  laboratory upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Abnormal glucose or protein on urinalysis (UA)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known allergy or intolerance to any of the IMP excipients (sodium sorbate, sodium&#xD;
             chloride, acetic acid, natrasol).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. By participant report at screening: Use of post-exposure prophylaxis (PEP) for HIV&#xD;
             exposure, systemic immunomodulatory medications vaginally or rectally administered&#xD;
             medications, and vaginally or rectally administered products (including condoms)&#xD;
             containing nonoxynol-9 (N-9) within the last four weeks prior to Visit 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Any significant underlying medical condition or prior therapy that, in the opinion of&#xD;
             the investigator, would preclude informed consent, make trial participation unsafe,&#xD;
             make the individual unsuitable for the trial or unable to comply with the trial&#xD;
             requirements. Such conditions may include, but are not limited to, current or recent&#xD;
             history of severe, progressive, or uncontrolled renal, hepatic, haematological,&#xD;
             gastrointestinal, endocrine, pulmonary, neurological, cardiovascular, immunological or&#xD;
             cerebral disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Abnormalities of the cervical (females only), vaginal (females only), or colorectal&#xD;
             mucosa, or significant symptom(s), which in the opinion of the clinician represents a&#xD;
             contraindication to protocol-required biopsies (including but not limited to presence&#xD;
             of any unresolved injury, infectious or inflammatory condition of the local mucosa,&#xD;
             and presence of symptomatic external haemorrhoids).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Suspected or confirmed drug or alcohol abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Positive hepatitis B virus (HBV) or hepatitis C virus (HCV) test results. HSV-1 or&#xD;
             HSV-2 seropositive diagnosis will only be allowed if no active lesions are present and&#xD;
             since treatment is not required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Body mass index (BMI) &lt; 18 or &gt; 30 kg/m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Previous enrolment to any preceding cohort of this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Persons committed to an institution by virtue of an order issued either by the&#xD;
             judicial or other authorities.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. In addition to the criteria listed above, female participants will be excluded if they&#xD;
             meet any of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Last pregnancy outcome or gynaecological surgery within 90 days prior to&#xD;
                  screening&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Chronic and/or recurrent symptomatic vaginal candidiasis at screening&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>BioVirtus Centrum Medyczne Sp. z o.o.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Józefów</city>
        <zip>05-410</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

