<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04794881</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04794881</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Repeat Lumbar Puncture at 24 Versus 48 Hours After Traumatic Lumbar Puncture in Neonates</brief_title>
  <official_title>Repeating a Lumbar Puncture at 24 Hours Versus 48 Hours After a Macro-traumatic Lumbar Puncture in Newborn Infants: a Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Visibly traumatic as well as microtraumatic lumbar punctures (LP) are very common in the&#xD;
      neonatal period. The presence of blood makes it difficult to interpret cerebro-spinal fluid&#xD;
      (CSF) findings. Clinicians often perform a repeat LP in the hope that some of the red blood&#xD;
      cells would have cleared by then, allowing a better interpretation of the CSF findings. There&#xD;
      is no published information whether a repeat LP provides any added information to the&#xD;
      original traumatic LP, and if so what is the best time to repeat an LP after a traumatic LP.&#xD;
      In this randomised controlled trial (RCT), we plan to randomly allocate neonates following a&#xD;
      visibly traumatic LP to either undergo a repeat LP at 24 hours or 48 hours later to determine&#xD;
      which LP gives more accurate results.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      STUDY DESIGN An open-label Randomised Control Trial, with stratification and blocking. STUDY&#xD;
      SETTING The Newborn unit and Neonatal Unit of Pediatric Emergency of Post graduate Institute&#xD;
      of medical education and research (PGIMER).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The former is a level 3 Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU). STUDY PERIOD Mentioned elsewhere&#xD;
      ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA Mentioned elsewhere CONSENT A parent information sheet was provided.&#xD;
      Informed written consent was obtained from the parents of the patient following which&#xD;
      subjects were included in the study. The consent included information about the procedure and&#xD;
      study related to it. It also included the risk factors associated with and after the&#xD;
      procedure. All subjects were included after obtaining wilful consent from respective parents.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PROCEDURE Post enrolment uncorrected White blood cell (WBC), corrected WBC count, red blood&#xD;
      cell (RBC) count, Glucose concentration, Protein concentration, CSF Procalcitonin&#xD;
      concentration, Gram stain and culture and sensitivity of microorganism was performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post-LP the subject was randomized and repeat LP was performed either after 24 hours or 48&#xD;
      hours, and uncorrected WBC, corrected WBC count, RBC count, Glucose concentration, Protein&#xD;
      concentration, Gram stain, and Culture and sensitivity of microorganism was studied.&#xD;
&#xD;
      BASELINE PARAMETERS Gestation, Birth weight, Sex, Postnatal age, Current weight, Indication&#xD;
      for initial lumbar puncture in the neonate, Seniority level of the person doing the initial&#xD;
      lumbar puncture, Platelet count when available before initial lumbar puncture, The&#xD;
      coagulation study report, if available, before initial lumbar puncture and repeat lumbar&#xD;
      puncture, Whole blood glucose measured by glucometer before the initial LP.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Parameters measured in the initial lumbar puncture&#xD;
&#xD;
      o Uncorrected and corrected WBC count: Cells were counted using two methods. One was in&#xD;
      Neubauer chamber within 30 minutes of performing an LP. 60 μL of CSF was split in 2 Eppendorf&#xD;
      tubes, labeled A and B. 27 μL of CSF in the first Eppendorf tube i.e labeled A was diluted&#xD;
      with Methylene Blue using lab standard micropipettes and was used to charge the chamber. Cell&#xD;
      count of both WBC and RBC were performed as standard procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Another 27 μL CSF from Eppendorf tube labeled B was diluted using 3 μL Turk's fluid with&#xD;
      composed of Gentian Violet and Glacial Acetic. The Turk's fluid essentially lyses the RBCs.&#xD;
      Following which one side of the chamber is charged and WBCs are calculated in the light grey&#xD;
      squares (n). The WBC count per microlitre = n x 25/9. For RBC count - 3 μL of Methylene Blue&#xD;
      was added to 27 μL of CSF to make 30 μL. One side of the chamber was charged and RBCs were&#xD;
      counted on the dark grey squares (n). The total RBCs counted per microliter = n x 500/9. As&#xD;
      mentioned WBCs and RBCs were also counted in automated machines available in the Main&#xD;
      Hematology lab as well as the emergency lab. The fully automated machine analyzer is the&#xD;
      Sysmex XN-1000(Sysmex-Kobe, Japan). The XN series analyzer has research mode which uses&#xD;
      fluorescence flow cytometry and impedance measurements to count the number of WBCs and RBCs&#xD;
      in CSF. To measure RBCs, both the optical(for lower concentration ranges) and impedance (for&#xD;
      higher concentration) techniques were used. In the WBC Differential Fluorescence channel, the&#xD;
      total WBC and differential WBC counts are based on flow cytometry measurements (e.g side&#xD;
      scatter, forward scatter, and DNA/RNA fluorescence). Before analysis using the XN hsA&#xD;
      research mode, the sample didn't require any preparation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Glucose concentration- Glucose concentration in CSF was estimated using a colorimetry-based&#xD;
      method after enzymatic oxidation in the presence of glucose oxidase but didn't break down the&#xD;
      protein. The hydrogen peroxide produced during the reaction reacts with phenol and&#xD;
      4-aminophenazone to form a red-violet quiononimine dye which acts as an indicator. The&#xD;
      intensity of the color that is produced is directly proportional to the glucose concentration&#xD;
      and is measured at a wavelength of 505 nm. The machine model is Adiva 1800 from Siemens.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Protein concentration- This is also a quantitative determination by a photometric color test&#xD;
      performed in a Beckman Coulter analyzer. Pyrogallol red is combined with molybdate to form a&#xD;
      red complex with maximum absorption at a wavelength of 470 nm. The assay is based on the&#xD;
      shift absorption that occurs when the pyrogallol red-molybdate complex binds basic amino acid&#xD;
      groups of protein molecules. A blue purple complex is formed with a maximum absorbance at a&#xD;
      wavelength of 600 nm. The absorbance of this complex is directly proportional to the protein&#xD;
      concentration in the sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procalcitonin concentration - CSF procalcitonin was determined using a two-step sandwich&#xD;
      electrochemiluminescence immunoassay using biotin-labeled procalcitonin specific antibody and&#xD;
      a monoclonal procalcitonin specific antibody labeled with a Ruthenium complex (Roche&#xD;
      Diagnostics, Germany). 200 μL of the CSF sample was incubated at 37 degrees C with the Biotin&#xD;
      and Ruthenium labeled anti- procalcitonin antibodies. In the second incubation,&#xD;
      streptavidin-coated anti microparticles were added which binds the complex via the&#xD;
      biotin-streptavidin interaction. The reaction mixture is aspirated into a measuring cell&#xD;
      where microparticles are magnetically captured onto the surface of the electrode. Unbound&#xD;
      substances are removed by washing and upon application of a voltage to the electrode,&#xD;
      chemiluminescence would be induced which is measured by a photomultiplier. The measuring&#xD;
      range of the assay is 2 ng/dl - 10000ng/dl with a functional sensitivity of 6ng/dl and&#xD;
      analytical sensitivity of 2 ng/dl.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Gram stain of traumatic lumbar puncture Culture and sensitivity of traumatic lumbar puncture&#xD;
      As per unit policy, CSF cell count was performed within 30 minutes of LP in the microscope in&#xD;
      the NICU side lab by personnel trained in CSF cell count. This was done to avoid degeneration&#xD;
      of WBCs and RBCs and drop in WBC count due to delay in the analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      RANDOMISATION SEQUENCE Eligible subjects were enrolled within less than 24 hours after the&#xD;
      initial LP. A block randomization sequence was generated from the website&#xD;
      www.randomization.com. Permuted, even-numbered, randomly varying block sizes with a 1:1&#xD;
      allocation ratio were used in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ETHICS COMMITTEE APPROVAL The study was approved by The Institutional Ethics Committee of&#xD;
      PGIMER, Chandigarh (INT/IEC/2019/000557) POST-RANDOMIZATION EXCLUSIONS Mentioned elsewhere&#xD;
      CONCEALMENT OF ALLOCATION The random allocation sequence was concealed using serially&#xD;
      numbered opaque sealed envelopes which contained slips of a paper, mentioning a group of&#xD;
      randomization. After enrolment, the name of the patient was written on the envelope. Only&#xD;
      after writing the name, the envelope was torn and the allocated intervention inside the&#xD;
      envelope was implemented subsequently.&#xD;
&#xD;
      INTERVENTION GROUPS Subjects were randomly allocated to 2 groups. One group consisted of&#xD;
      patients where a repeat LP was done 24 hours after the initial traumatic LP. The 2nd group&#xD;
      consisted of patients where LP was repeated at 48 hours after the initial traumatic LP.&#xD;
&#xD;
      BLINDING It was not possible to blind doctors and nurses working in the NICU. However,&#xD;
      Microbiology, Hematology and Biochemistry lab personnel were blinded to the group of&#xD;
      allocation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTCOMES MEASURED IN REPEAT LP:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood glucose before doing LP, Whether CSF sample obtained, CSF sample: whether frank blood,&#xD;
      visibly blood-tinged, micro-traumatic, or nontraumatic, CSF RBC count, CSF WBC count&#xD;
      (uncorrected and corrected), CSF glucose, CSF protein, CSF Gram stain, culture, and&#xD;
      sensitivity. Similar to the first LP, CSF cell count was performed within 30 minutes of LP in&#xD;
      the microscope in the NICU side lab by personnel trained in CSF cell count.&#xD;
&#xD;
      REFERENCE STANDARD Definite meningitis CSF culture and/or gram stain positive Probable&#xD;
      meningitis CSF procalcitonin (PCT) positive. To define CSF PCT positive, we took a cut-off of&#xD;
      33 ng/dL or more. This was based upon the study by Reshi et al(18). The study was conducted&#xD;
      in the Neonatal Intensive care unit of the Department of Neonatology and Pediatrics at SKIMS,&#xD;
      Srinagar, over a period of 2 years (January 2014 to December 2015). The study was a&#xD;
      prospective study that included infants 28 days old, who qualified LP as a part of sepsis&#xD;
      workup. They defined traumatic lumbar puncture as a CSF sample with ⩾500 red blood cells/mm3,&#xD;
      and leukocyte count adjustments were done at an average ratio of 500 red blood cells to 1&#xD;
      white blood cells. The diagnosis of bacterial meningitis was made in neonates with sepsis&#xD;
      with either positive CSF and/or blood culture or positive gram staining. They excluded&#xD;
      infants who were more than 28 days old or neonates who had received antibiotics prior to&#xD;
      hospital admission, neonates who had undergone recent brain surgery if another focus of&#xD;
      infection was present in addition to meningitis or Viral meningitis (herpes simplex virus).&#xD;
      Post exclusion criteria the study was concluded on 168 neonates. They observed, at a value of&#xD;
      0.33ng/ml, CSF PCT has a sensitivity of 92%, a specificity of 87%, a positive predictive&#xD;
      value (PPV) of 85.2%, and a negative predictive value (NPV) of 93%. We in our study didn't&#xD;
      include other CSF conventional parameters for probable meningitis, such as CSF WBC, CSF&#xD;
      Sugar, and CSF Protein for the definition of probable meningitis because we intended to study&#xD;
      these tests as index tests, and hence they could not also be part of the reference standard.&#xD;
&#xD;
      COMPARISON OF OUTCOME MEASURES Mentioned elsewhere&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 18, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 28, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve of uncorrected CSF WBC count in the repeat LP, with &quot;definite or probable meningitis&quot; taken as the reference standard.</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the repeat LP reports are available</time_frame>
    <description>Primary outcome- area under the ROC curve of uncorrected CSF WBC count in the repeat LP- will be compared between the 24 hour LP and the 48 hour LP groups. The reference standard will be &quot;definite or probable meningitis&quot; defined as &quot;CSF culture and/or CSF Gram stain and/or CSF Procalcitonin positive&quot; in the baseline traumatic LP.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the ROC curve of corrected CSF WBC count (using 500:1 formula) in the repeat LP, with &quot;definite or probable meningitis&quot; taken as a reference standard</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the repeat LP reports are available</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the ROC curve of corrected CSF WBC count (using 500:1 formula) in the repeat LP, with &quot;definite or probable meningitis&quot; taken as the reference standard will be compared between the 24-hour LP and the 48-hour LP groups. Reference standard will be defined as in the primary outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the ROC curve of corrected CSF WBC count (using 500:1 formula) in the repeat LP, with only &quot;definite meningitis&quot; taken as a reference standard</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the repeat LP reports are available</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the ROC curve of corrected CSF WBC count (using 500:1 formula) in the repeat LP, with only &quot;definite&quot; taken as the reference standard will be compared between the 24-hour LP and the 48-hour LP groups. Reference standard will be defined as &quot;CSF culture and/or Gram stain positive&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the ROC curve of corrected CSF WBC count (using 500:1 formula) in the repeat LP, with only &quot;probable meningitis&quot; taken as a reference standard</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the repeat LP reports are available</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the ROC curve of corrected CSF WBC count (using 500:1 formula) in the repeat LP, with only &quot;probable&quot; taken as the reference standard will be compared between the 24-hour LP and the 48-hour LP groups. Reference standard will be defined as &quot;CSF Procalcitonin positive&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the ROC curve of CSF glucose in the repeat LP, with &quot;definite or probable meningitis&quot; taken as a reference standard</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the repeat LP reports are available</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the ROC curve of CSF glucose in the repeat LP, with &quot;definite or probable meningitis&quot; taken as the reference standard will be compared between the 24-hour LP and the 48-hour LP groups. Reference standard will be defined as under primary outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the ROC curve of CSF glucose in the repeat LP, with only &quot;definite meningitis&quot; taken as a reference standard</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the repeat LP reports are available</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the ROC curve of CSF glucose in the repeat LP, with &quot;definite meningitis&quot; taken as the reference standard will be compared between the 24-hour LP and the 48-hour LP groups. Reference standard will be defined as mentioned earlier.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the ROC curve of CSF glucose in the repeat LP, with only &quot;probable meningitis&quot; taken as a reference standard</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the repeat LP reports are available</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the ROC curve of CSF glucose in the repeat LP, with &quot;probable meningitis&quot; taken as the reference standard will be compared between the 24-hour LP and the 48-hour LP groups. Reference standard will be defined as mentioned earlier.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the ROC curve of CSF protein in the repeat LP, with &quot;definite or probable meningitis&quot; taken as a reference standard</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the repeat LP reports are available</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the ROC curve of CSF glucose in the repeat LP, with &quot;definite or probable meningitis&quot; taken as the reference standard will be compared between the 24-hour LP and the 48-hour LP groups. Reference standard will be defined as mentioned earlier.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the ROC curve of CSF protein in the repeat LP, with only &quot;definite meningitis&quot; taken as a reference standard</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the repeat LP reports are available</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the ROC curve of CSF glucose in the repeat LP, with &quot;definite meningitis&quot; taken as the reference standard will be compared between the 24-hour LP and the 48-hour LP groups. Reference standard will be defined as mentioned earlier.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the ROC curve of CSF protein in the repeat LP, with only &quot;probable meningitis&quot; taken as a reference standard</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the repeat LP reports are available</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the ROC curve of CSF glucose in the repeat LP, with &quot;probable meningitis&quot; taken as the reference standard will be compared between the 24-hour LP and the 48-hour LP groups. Reference standard will be defined as mentioned earlier.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage change in RBC count from baseline traumatic LP to the repeat LP</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the repeat LP reports are available</time_frame>
    <description>Change in the CSF RBC count from the baseline traumatic LP to the repeat LP, expressed as a percentage of the baseline value, will be compared between the 24-hour LP group and the 48-hour LP group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage change in uncorrected CSF WBC count from baseline traumatic LP to the repeat LP</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the repeat LP are available</time_frame>
    <description>Change in the uncorrected CSF WBC count from the baseline traumatic LP to the repeat LP, expressed as a percentage of the baseline value, will be compared between the 24 hour LP group and the 48 hour LP group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">42</enrollment>
  <condition>Neonate</condition>
  <condition>Meningitis</condition>
  <condition>Spinal Puncture</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>24 hours</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Newborn infants in this group will undergo repeat lumbar puncture at 24 hours after a traumatic lumbar puncture</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>48 hours</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Newborn infants in this group will undergo repeat lumbar puncture at 48 hours after a traumatic lumbar puncture</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>24 hours</intervention_name>
    <description>Performing a lumbar puncture at 24 hours after a traumatic lumbar puncture</description>
    <arm_group_label>24 hours</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>48 hours</intervention_name>
    <description>Performing a lumbar puncture at 48 hours after a traumatic lumbar puncture</description>
    <arm_group_label>48 hours</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Newborn infants admitted anywhere in the Neonate unit or Neonatal Unit of Paediatric&#xD;
             Emergency&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Underwent lumbar puncture as part of the workup for sepsis&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Cerebrospinal fluid visibly tinged with blood (macro traumatic). To ensure&#xD;
             objectivity, two Pediatricians must have a consensus that the CSF sample is visibly&#xD;
             blood-tinged when viewed in bright ambient light.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinically too unstable to undergo 2 lumbar punctures within the span of 48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Lumbar puncture performed after more than 3 doses of antibiotics administered&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. CSF sample of traumatic lumbar puncture not sent for analysis of WBC, RBC counts,&#xD;
             glucose, protein, Gram stain, and culture&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Sample appears to be pure blood from the initial needle prick.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Post-randomization exclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinically too unstable to undergo the 2nd LP&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Development of fresh contraindications for performing the 2nd LP&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>28 Days</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sourabh Dutta</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Post Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research (PGIMER)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chandigarh</city>
        <zip>160012</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sourabh Dutta</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Pediatrics</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>neonate</keyword>
  <keyword>meningitis</keyword>
  <keyword>lumbar puncture</keyword>
  <keyword>traumatic</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Meningitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

