<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04795778</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IAyas2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04795778</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Validity and Reliability of FIT-HaNSA in Breast Cancer Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Validity and Reliability of FIT-HaNSA (Functional Impairment Test-Hand and Neck/Shoulder/Arm) in Breast Cancer Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Gazi University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Gazi University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Breast cancer is the most common type of cancer among women and covers 25% of all cancers.&#xD;
      After mastectomy and reconstruction, many patients develop various upper extremity&#xD;
      complications such as joint movement limitation, pain, lymphedema, and axillary cord. Because&#xD;
      of such upper extremity problems, evaluation and treatment of upper extremity functions are&#xD;
      important. Upper extremity functions are generally evaluated with questionnaires filled out&#xD;
      by the patients themselves and which reflect their own perspectives subjectively. However,&#xD;
      these questionnaires cannot reflect the observations and evaluations of the clinicians.&#xD;
      Performance tests are important for clinicians to make decisions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With this study, we want to examine the usability of the FIT-HaNSA test in the evaluation of&#xD;
      upper extremity functions in patients with breast cancer. Our hypothesis; The FıtHaNSA test&#xD;
      is successful in evaluating the upper extremity function in patients with breast cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>FIT-HaNSA test for upper extremity performance</measure>
    <time_frame>For the patient group; at least 3 months after all treatments have been completed</time_frame>
    <description>FIT-HaNSA protocol includes 3 steps.In the first step of the test 3 weights of 1kg are placed on the shelf at the waist level of the individual at 10 cm intervals.The person moves these weights in rows to the 25 cm upper rack and then place them back on the lower rack.The person is asked to continue this process for 5 minutes.In the second step of the test, the first shelf is placed at eye level, the second shelf is placed 25 cm below it and the procedures in the first step are repeated.In the 3rd step, a wooden plate with 3 holes is placed perpendicular to the shelf at eye level of the individual.The hole in the middle is left empty by placing nuts and bolts in the first and third holes before. The individual must return to the starting point in order by attaching the bolt in the first hole to the second hole, the bolt in the third hole to the first hole and finally the bolt in the second hole to the third hole and this process is 5 minutes.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Upper extremity disability</measure>
    <time_frame>For the patient group; at least 3 months after all treatments have been completed</time_frame>
    <description>Upper extremity disability will be evaluated with DASH questionnaire (Disabilities of the Arm, Shoulder and Hand). It is a questionnaire consisting of 30 questions that evaluates the dysfunctions of the entire upper extremity. It consists of questions evaluating the degree of difficulty in performing different activities using the upper extremity in daily life (21 questions), pain, numbness, joint stiffness and weakness symptoms (5 questions), social life, sleep, work and psychological status (4 questions) in the last week.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Upper extremity functionality</measure>
    <time_frame>For the patient group; at least 3 months after all treatments have been completed</time_frame>
    <description>Upper extremity functionality will be evaluated with Upper Extremity Functional Index (UEFI). It is a questionnaire consisting of 20 questions that questions the functional difficulty of the upper extremity in daily life activities. Each question is scored between 0 and 4 (0: extremely difficult, 4: no difficulty).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Shoulder disability</measure>
    <time_frame>For the patient group; at least 3 months after all treatments have been completed</time_frame>
    <description>Shoulder disability will be evaluated with Shoulder Pain and Disabilty Index (SPADI). The scale, which consists of 13 questions in total, has two subsections as pain and disability. The pain section consists of 5 questions describing the pain of the patient, and the disability section consists of 8 questions that indicate the degree of difficulty experienced when using the upper extremity. Each question is scored from 0 to 10 (0 is no difficulty, 10 is very difficult).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>FIT-HaNSA</condition>
  <condition>Upper Extremity Dysfunction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with breast cancer</arm_group_label>
    <description>Breast cancer patients with or without breast cancer surgery, with or without mastectomy, with or without lymphedema</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Healty individuals with no disease</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Breast cancer patients referred to physiotherapy and rehabilitation from Gazi University&#xD;
        hospital&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those whose treatments for breast cancer have been completed 18 years and over&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a history of upper extremity surgery, excluding breast cancer surgery Have a&#xD;
             history of upper extremity trauma Those who have orthopedic, neurological,&#xD;
             rheumatological or cognitive impairments that may interfere with the application of&#xD;
             the test.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>inci ayas</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Gazi University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>inci ayas</last_name>
    <phone>0 312 216 26 21</phone>
    <email>inciayass@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>ilke keser</last_name>
    <phone>0 312 216 26 21</phone>
    <email>ilkekeser@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Inci Ayas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ankara</city>
        <zip>06560</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>inci ayas</last_name>
      <phone>0 312 216 26 21</phone>
      <email>inciayass@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>ilke keser</last_name>
      <phone>0 312 216 26 21</phone>
      <email>ilkekeser@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>elif sakizli erdal</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Gazi University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>İnci Hazal Ayas</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>FIT-HaNSA</keyword>
  <keyword>Upper Extremity Dysfunction</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Only study officials will be able to view patient data The statistical analysis will also be done by the study officials.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

