<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04793737</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PROMMEL</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04793737</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Precision Radiation of Immune Checkpoint Therapy Resistant Melanoma Metastases</brief_title>
  <acronym>PROMMEL</acronym>
  <official_title>Precision Radiation of Immune Checkpoint Therapy Resistant Melanoma Metastases</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Karolinska University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Karolinska University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate tumor response, survival and adverse effects after precision radiotherapy (SBRT)&#xD;
      in melanoma patients with ongoing PD-1 inhibitor treatment that have tumor progression.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A phase II open-label multicenter trial evaluating response rate (RR) in patients receiving&#xD;
      precision radiation (SBRT) to melanoma metastasis that have progressed on PD-1 inhibitor&#xD;
      therapy. Patients will continue on PD-1 inhibitor therapy (pembrolizumab or nivolumab) for up&#xD;
      to one year after completed precision radiation and will be followed-up for 24 months or&#xD;
      until disease progression or death. The primary endpoint of the study is overall response&#xD;
      rate (ORR) in non-irradiated lesions. The study will be conducted according to Simon´s two&#xD;
      Stage minimax Design. Patients will be enrolled in two batches, first consisting of 13&#xD;
      patients. If no objective responses (complete response (CR) or partial response (PR)) are&#xD;
      reported after the first stage, the study is interrupted early for futility. When the 13th&#xD;
      patient is recruited, if there is at least one objective response in patient´s non-irradiated&#xD;
      lesion(s), the recruitment can proceed into second stage. 14 more patients will then be&#xD;
      included up to a total of 27 patients to determine ORR along with the 95% confidence&#xD;
      interval. The test result is considered positive when at least 15% of the patients have a&#xD;
      confirmed objective response.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 8, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Phase II open-label multicenter trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate (ORR) in non-irradiated lesions</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of precision radiation start until the date of first documented progression or date of death from any cause, whichever comes first, assessed up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Overall response rate (ORR) in non-irradiated lesions according to RECIST 1.1</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median PFS (months)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Median PFS (months) at 6 and 12 months according to RECIST 1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PFS rate (%)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>PFS rate (%) at 6 and 12 months according to RECIST 1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median OS (months)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Median OS (months) at 6 and 12 months according to RECIST 1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response rate (RR) in the patient's irradiated lesions</measure>
    <time_frame>From radiation start to end of follow-up, progression or death (3, 6, 9, 12, 15, 18, 21, 24 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Response rate (RR) in the patient's irradiated lesions according to RECIST 1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate and type of AEs and SAEs on patient level</measure>
    <time_frame>From precision radiation start to end of follow-up, progression or death, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse Events and Serious Adverse Events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory outcome measure: Predictive biomarkers</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of diagnosis until the date of first documented progression or date of death from any cause, whichever comes first, assessed up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Translational research to investigate predictive biomarkers based on sequential tumor biopsies and/or fine needle tumor aspirations and blood</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">27</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Melanoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Precision Radiation (SBRT)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Precision radiation of melanoma metastases</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Precision Radiation (SBRT)</intervention_name>
    <description>Precision radiation of melanoma metastases</description>
    <arm_group_label>Precision Radiation (SBRT)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 18 and above&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ECOG performance status of 0-1&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Signed and dated written informed consent before the start of specific protocol&#xD;
             procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient has initiated PD-1 inhibitor treatment (alone or in combination with CTLA-4&#xD;
             inhibitor) as the first line of therapy for unresectable metastatic cutaneous melanoma&#xD;
             and been on the treatment for at least 3 months and progressed on the treatment.&#xD;
             Patients with primary or secondary resistance to the PD-1 inhibitor treatment will be&#xD;
             included. Progression is defined as at least 30% enlargement of at least one&#xD;
             metastasis or appearance of new metastasis. A fine-needle aspiration (FNA) biopsy from&#xD;
             a progressing lesion or a new lesion is recommended to confirm the presence of viable&#xD;
             tumor cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients on adjuvant treatment with PD-1 inhibitors that during the treatment develop&#xD;
             unresectable biopsy confirmed metastases can also be included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Have at least one new or progressing lesion safely amenable to irradiation in the&#xD;
             opinion of the treating radiation oncologist AND at least one, not-to-be-irradiated&#xD;
             new or progressing lesion measurable by CT or MRI per RECIST 1.1 criteria where up to&#xD;
             four radiation target fields are allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. No contraindication for continuing immunotherapy after the radiotherapy intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Inability to understand given information or undergo study procedures according to&#xD;
             protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pregnant or breast-feeding. Patients must agree to use safe contraception during and&#xD;
             for 3 months after study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. A condition requiring systemic treatment with either corticosteroids (&gt; 10 mg daily&#xD;
             prednisone equivalents) or other immunosuppressive medications within 30 days before&#xD;
             start of study treatment. Inhaled or topical steroids and adrenal replacement doses&#xD;
             &gt;10 mg daily prednisone equivalents are permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Has an active infection requiring systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Concomitant therapy with any anti-tumor medications, other than PD-1/CTLA-4 inhibitors&#xD;
             or 30 days before and after treatment in this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Prior radiotherapy preventing the study intervention with precision radiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Location, size or number of metastases is deemed as excessive or not appropriate for&#xD;
             precision radiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Central nervous system (CNS) metastases at baseline, with the exception of those&#xD;
             subjects who have previously-treated CNS metastases (surgery ± radiotherapy,&#xD;
             radiosurgery, or gamma knife) and who meet both of the following criteria: a) are&#xD;
             asymptomatic and b) have no requirement for steroids or anticonvulsants.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Prior malignancy. Subjects who have had another malignancy should be disease-free for&#xD;
             5 years, or should have a history of completely resected non-melanomatous skin&#xD;
             carcinoma or successfully treated in situ carcinoma&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Signe Friesland, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Karolinska University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hildur Helgadottir, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+46(0)8 51773415</phone>
    <email>hildur.helgadottir@sll.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Division of Head-Neck, Lung and Skin cancers, Theme Cancer, Karolinska University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stockholm</city>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hildur Helgadottir, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+46(0)8 51773415</phone>
      <email>hildur.helgadottir@sll.se</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Hildur Helgadottir, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 17, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Karolinska University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Hildur Helgadottir</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Precision radiation</keyword>
  <keyword>PD-1 inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>SBRT</keyword>
  <keyword>Immune Checkpoint Inhibitor</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

