<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04796168</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1240/2019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04796168</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Post Operative Ankle Splint Study - Prospective Multi Center Randomized Controlled Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>PASS</acronym>
  <official_title>Post Operative Ankle Splint Study - Prospective Multi Center Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kuwait Institute for Medical Specialization</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Kuwait University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kuwait Institute for Medical Specialization</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Ankle fractures are some of the most common orthopedic presentations, however,&#xD;
      controversy in their management and their post-operative rehabilitation protocols exist. Most&#xD;
      displaced ankle fractures treated with anatomical reduction and stable internal fixation to&#xD;
      allow early range of motion by allowing rigid fixation and restoration of ankle joint&#xD;
      congruence. Post-operative rehabilitation protocols varies between surgeons and institutions&#xD;
      with the majority emphasising early rehabilitation protocols. The use of a splint. The&#xD;
      rational for splinting ankle fractures after rigid fixation is to decrease pain level, rest&#xD;
      the soft tissues and prevent equinus deformity. Up to date there is no scientific research to&#xD;
      question the benefit of routine use of splints after rigid fixation of ankle fractures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: A prospective multi-centre randomised control trial. Approximately fifty patients&#xD;
      will be enrolled from 3 hospitals (Adan, Mubarak and Farwaniya hospital) over a 1 year&#xD;
      period. The studied sample will be randomised into 2 groups using computerised randomisation&#xD;
      software: splint group and no-splint group. The patients will be examined at set intervals&#xD;
      for pain, swelling, deep-vein thrombosis and a set of scoring tools. The tools include:&#xD;
      visual analogue score (VAS) for pain, Short Form Health Survey (SF-36), American Orthopaedic&#xD;
      Foot and Ankle Society (AOFAS) Ankle-Hindfoot score, physical and radiological assessment at&#xD;
      2 weeks, 3 months, 6 months and 1 year intervals. Statistical Package for the Social Sciences&#xD;
      program (SPSS) will be used for statistical analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Results/outcomes: Functional scores, symptoms and signs, complications, radio-graphic and&#xD;
      clinical follow up will be recorded.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Overview&#xD;
&#xD;
      The mainstay of unstable ankle fractures is surgical in nature, however controversy and an&#xD;
      unclear consensus exists regarding post-operative rehabilitation; is a splint necessary or&#xD;
      not? Splinting the ankle post-op is traditionally used to reduce pain and limit motion.&#xD;
      However, the evidence is unclear and benefits are not well established. Further, splinting&#xD;
      the ankle in the traditional back-slab is accompanied by complications including; pressure&#xD;
      sores, skin irritation and deep-vein thrombosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is incomplete evidence supporting early commencement of weight-bearing and the use of a&#xD;
      detachable type of immobilization to allow exercise during the immobilization period after&#xD;
      surgical fixation(1). It is also noteworthy that its believed that because of the potential&#xD;
      increased risk of adverse events, the patient's compliance with the use of a removable type&#xD;
      of immobilisation to enable controlled exercise is essential(1). To date there is lacking&#xD;
      scientific research to question the benefit of routine use of splints after rigid fixation of&#xD;
      ankle fractures. There is little evidence that any specific rehabilitation program improves&#xD;
      clinical outcome (2). One study found that active ankle movements in combination with weight&#xD;
      bearing facilitate and improve the rehabilitation following operation for an ankle fracture&#xD;
      [3]. A systematic review of 38 controlled trials related to the rehabilitation of ankle&#xD;
      fractures found that early ambulation post-op may improve ankle range of motion, yet with&#xD;
      limited quality evidence [3, 6]. . Early performance of ankle exercises following surgical&#xD;
      fixation improved ankle function and mobility, while decreasing pain, but was associated with&#xD;
      higher rates of adverse events (e.g. surgical wound complications), although most problems&#xD;
      were minor(3). Use of a removable immobilization device was necessary for this approach. It&#xD;
      could be plausible that determent and harm to the patient is being done in the form of&#xD;
      dermatological adverse effects of splints if there is in fact no benefit to their use. There&#xD;
      is a clear need to define whether or not a splint is needed for the sake of patient safety&#xD;
      and comfort postoperatively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Question/Hypothesis What are the benefits and risks of splinting ankle fractures&#xD;
      post-op. The investigators believe that there is no considerable benefit to splinting ankle&#xD;
      fractures after fixation, in fact, splinting may even result in stiffness, cast-associated&#xD;
      complications and reduced patient satisfaction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives and aims&#xD;
&#xD;
      Overall Objective To critically assess the benefits of splints after rigid fixation of ankle&#xD;
      fractures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aims&#xD;
&#xD;
      1- To assess the level of pain between the splint and no-splint groups. 2- To compare the&#xD;
      range of motion between the splint and no-splint groups. Secondary objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To assess patient satisfaction between the splint and no-splint groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To assess other complications and radiological finding differences between the splint&#xD;
           and no-splint groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To check the difference in time-to-union between the splint and no-splint groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      BACKGROUND AND SIGNIFICANCE&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ankle fractures&#xD;
&#xD;
      Over five million ankle injuries occur each year in the United States alone, and the&#xD;
      incidence of these fractures is approximately 187 fractures per 100,000 people each year (4).&#xD;
      This figure has been increasing, most probably because of the exponential growth of the&#xD;
      population and the growing amount of people practising sports(4). Cigarette smoking and a&#xD;
      high body mass index have been associated with ankle fractures(5, 6). Ankle fractures can be&#xD;
      categorised into stable and unstable fractures. Isolated malleolar fractures are usually&#xD;
      stable if they are not displaced but, care should be taken with fractures of the medial&#xD;
      malleolus. Disturbance of nearby structures often occurs in association with these fractures,&#xD;
      and they sometimes appear to be isolated injuries at first. Bimalleolar Fractures, which is&#xD;
      fracture of both the lateral and medial malleoli, are generally unstable. Trimalleolar&#xD;
      fractures are unstable and typically occur with injuries of greater force. These are&#xD;
      bimalleolar fractures with a fracture of the posterior malleolus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fracture stability determines treatment. Emergent conditions, such as an open fracture or&#xD;
      neurovascular impairment, necessitate surgical consultation and treatment. Fracture&#xD;
      dislocations must be reduced to avoid serious complications, such as avascular necrosis.&#xD;
      After emergency situations are excluded, the fracture should be evaluated more closely, with&#xD;
      focus on any malalignment or instability, to determine proper management. Standard treatment&#xD;
      for stable ankle is Immobilization in a cast (CI) for approximately six weeks but, new&#xD;
      evidence is growing and supporting that shorter periods of casting allows a similar level of&#xD;
      healing with less risk of complications. A randomized trial of 247 adults with stable&#xD;
      fractures of the lateral malleolus, 3 week long immobilization in a short-leg walking cast or&#xD;
      rigid ankle orthosis reduced the short-term loss of ankle mobility and the risk for deep vein&#xD;
      thrombosis as compared with care, without compromising fracture healing(4). Confirmation of&#xD;
      these results is needed, but 3 weeks of immobilization may be a reasonable approach in&#xD;
      healthy adults with uncomplicated fractures. Unstable ankle fractures are treated surgically.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research design and methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Overview&#xD;
&#xD;
      The PASS Trial is going to be a 1-2 year long randomised control trial where a qualified team&#xD;
      of doctors will administer a questionnaire, take clinical examination results, and assign&#xD;
      patients to treatment groups of splint and non-splint post-surgical repair. Range of motion&#xD;
      will be evaluated with a Goniometer and information will be gathered in a standardized&#xD;
      manner. Patients aged 18-65 taken from Adan, Mubarak, and Farwaniya hospitals will be&#xD;
      consented and randomly assigned to a treatment group after which they will be followed&#xD;
      periodically at their designated follow up appointments, which are at 2 weeks, 3 months, 6&#xD;
      months and 1 year. Patients will be collected over the duration of 2 years until a quota of&#xD;
      50-75 participants is achieved. Only isolated A.O 44 ankle fractures requiring surgical&#xD;
      fixation will be included in the study. Pathological fractures, polytrauma patients and open&#xD;
      fractures will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Strengths and weaknesses of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is a double blinded Randomized Control Trial to eliminate as much bias as&#xD;
      possible. All Principle investigators who measured the results are near equal in terms of&#xD;
      experience and education. Methods of gathering and collecting data as well as tools to do so&#xD;
      were standardized. Our study will utilize multivariate regression models and intention to&#xD;
      treat analysis. The study covers the major trauma centres in Kuwait providing adequate&#xD;
      representation of the population. Recall bias is minimized due to close proximity of&#xD;
      questioning and the event.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential Limitations Patient compliance to treatment arms is the main potential issue of our&#xD;
      study. The extent of non-compliance was measured through questionnaire. There is a lack of&#xD;
      literature on this subject, which results in deficient comparison with other populations&#xD;
      around the globe and in the region.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Public health significance&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the Individual Level The Patients as individuals will feel liberated as they may no longer&#xD;
      consider themselves disabled and diseased while they are not wearing a split providing&#xD;
      physiological relief. This benefit could even translate to earlier return to work and benefit&#xD;
      society. Individuals will no longer be inconvenienced by being required to wear a splint.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On The Global Level It is in the interest of public health care systems to conduct this trial&#xD;
      because there is a possibility that the costs of splints provide by the hospitals will be cut&#xD;
      and put to better use. Such a trial could impact public health policy because it can provide&#xD;
      good evidence to change the current standards of care. This study may also reveal&#xD;
      associations that are possibly good targets for public health intervention. This is&#xD;
      especially important in our country as there is a locally observed predisposition to injury&#xD;
      for hard labour and construction workers, so there it is necessity to see if there is an&#xD;
      association between current working conditions and likeliness of injury.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessing the change in the level of pain between the splint and no-splint groups</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in pain from 2 weeks postop to 1 year postop</time_frame>
    <description>Visual analogue scale (0;lowest pain, 10;highest pain)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessing the change in ankle swelling from 2 weeks postop to 1 year postop in the splint and no-splint groups</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in swelling from 2 weeks postop to 1 year postop</time_frame>
    <description>Measuring tape to assess supramalleolar, mid-foot, and mid-calf circumference</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the functional scoring system used below</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in American Orthopaedic Foot and Ankle Society (AOFAS) Ankle-Hindfoot Scorefrom 2 weeks postop to 1 year postop</time_frame>
    <description>The American Orthopaedic Foot and Ankle Society (AOFAS) Ankle-Hindfoot Score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with; infection, nonunion, deep-vein thrombosis, stiffness, equinus</measure>
    <time_frame>From 2 weeks postop - 1 year postop</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of infection, nonunion, deep-vein thrombosis, stiffness, equinus</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Ankle Fractures</condition>
  <condition>Splints</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>post operative Ankle fractures with splint</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patient who meet the inclusion criteria of having ankle fracture that rigidly fixed and randomized to receive splint post operative</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>post operative Ankle fractures without splint</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patient who meet the inclusion criteria of having ankle fracture that rigidly fixed and randomized to receive NO splint post operative</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Splinting (plaster of paris)</intervention_name>
    <description>Placing stockinette followed by cotton rolls and 10-12 layer of posterior ankle splint made of plaster of paris</description>
    <arm_group_label>post operative Ankle fractures with splint</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A.O 44 ankle fractures requiring surgical fixation (uni or bimalleolar with /without&#xD;
             syndesmotic injury)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pathological fracture&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  poly trauma pilon fractures open fractures other associated fractures in same&#xD;
             extremity peripheral neuropathy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ali Jarragh, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Kuwait University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>ALi A Jarragh, MD,FRCS</last_name>
    <phone>+96599776755</phone>
    <email>ali.esmaeel@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ali Lari, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+96566428328</phone>
    <email>Dr.Alilari@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mubarak Al kabeer hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kuwait</city>
        <country>Kuwait</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>ALi Jarragh, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+96599776755</phone>
      <email>ali.esmaeel@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Ali Lari, MD</last_name>
      <phone>66428328</phone>
      <email>Dr.Alilari@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Kuwait</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Michelson JD. Fractures about the ankle. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1995 Jan;77(1):142-52. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>7822349</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ahl T, Dalén N, Selvik G. Mobilization after operation of ankle fractures. Good results of early motion and weight bearing. Acta Orthop Scand. 1988 Jun;59(3):302-6.</citation>
    <PMID>3132812</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Daly PJ, Fitzgerald RH Jr, Melton LJ, Ilstrup DM. Epidemiology of ankle fractures in Rochester, Minnesota. Acta Orthop Scand. 1987 Oct;58(5):539-44.</citation>
    <PMID>3425285</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Valtola A, Honkanen R, Kröger H, Tuppurainen M, Saarikoski S, Alhava E. Lifestyle and other factors predict ankle fractures in perimenopausal women: a population-based prospective cohort study. Bone. 2002 Jan;30(1):238-42.</citation>
    <PMID>11792591</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Honkanen R, Tuppurainen M, Kröger H, Alhava E, Saarikoski S. Relationships between risk factors and fractures differ by type of fracture: a population-based study of 12,192 perimenopausal women. Osteoporos Int. 1998;8(1):25-31.</citation>
    <PMID>9692074</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Smeeing DP, Houwert RM, Briet JP, Kelder JC, Segers MJ, Verleisdonk EJ, Leenen LP, Hietbrink F. Weight-bearing and mobilization in the postoperative care of ankle fractures: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials and cohort studies. PLoS One. 2015 Feb 19;10(2):e0118320. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0118320. eCollection 2015. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25695796</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Lin CW, Donkers NA, Refshauge KM, Beckenkamp PR, Khera K, Moseley AM. Rehabilitation for ankle fractures in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012 Nov 14;11:CD005595. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD005595.pub3. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23152232</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Kuwait Institute for Medical Specialization</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ali Jarragh</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ankle Fractures</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

