<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04798482</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-P00035865</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04798482</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Dexmedetomidine of Gastrointestinal Motility</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Dexmedetomidine of Gastrointestinal Motility</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Boston Children's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Boston Children's Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Anorectal manometry requires that the patient be able to respond to command and not receive&#xD;
      any medications which could alter muscle tone or motility. In the pediatric population,&#xD;
      anorectal manometry can be psychologically challenging to parents and their child, as it is&#xD;
      traditionally performed without adjuvant sedation or anesthesia. Sedatives and anesthesia can&#xD;
      alter motility and smooth muscle activity, as well as render it difficult or impossible for&#xD;
      the child to follow commands required of the study. Patient or parent non-compliance,&#xD;
      inability to follow commands or to tolerate the procedure often renders the study invalid or&#xD;
      impossible to complete. Dexmedetomidine is a sedative who's effect on anorectal musculature&#xD;
      has not been studied nor determined. It would be important to determine whether it spares&#xD;
      smooth muscle function, as it would provide a viable option to provide sedation to children&#xD;
      while still preserving their ability to respond to command. The primary objective of this&#xD;
      study is to examine the effects of dexmedetomidine on gastrointestinal smooth muscle by&#xD;
      observing changes in anorectal manometry before and after dexmedetomdine administration.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Primary objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To examine the effects of dexmedetomidine on intra-anal pressure and the dose response curve&#xD;
      to balloon distention by comparing the baseline measurements with those after dexmedetomidine&#xD;
      administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dexmedetomidine is an alpha-2 agonist that is considered to be a smooth muscle relaxant. It's&#xD;
      a potential use as a sedative for endoscopies has been considered. It is important to know&#xD;
      whether or not it has effect on smooth muscle tone and would affect manometry studies in&#xD;
      those patients who could receive it. The investigator hypothesizes that dexmedetomidine will&#xD;
      have minimal effects in the dosing that is being administered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anorectal manometry requires that the patient be able to respond to command and not receive&#xD;
      any medications which could alter muscle tone or motility. These patients typically have the&#xD;
      manometry performed without any adjuvant sedatives, anesthetics or medications. In the&#xD;
      pediatric population, anorectal manometry can be psychologically challenging to parents and&#xD;
      their child, particularly without adjuvant sedation or anesthesia. There are some exceptional&#xD;
      circumstances which require sedation/anesthesia administration for these procedures, either&#xD;
      because the children are young (&lt; 5 years), they have behavioral issues (like autism) or&#xD;
      because they have severe anxiety. In those patients with severe issues even general&#xD;
      anesthesia may be needed. The risk of administering any medication to these patients is that&#xD;
      they can alter motility and smooth muscle activity, consequently artificially altering the&#xD;
      results of the anal manometry. It is important to know which medications can be administered&#xD;
      without affecting anal muscle tone. Dexmedetomidine is a newer sedative and anxiolytic. It&#xD;
      could be valuable for anxiolysis for anal manometry. It's effect on anal smooth muscle,&#xD;
      however, has never been studied. It would be important to determine whether it spares smooth&#xD;
      muscle function, as it would provide a viable option to provide sedation to children while&#xD;
      still preserving their ability to respond to command.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dexmedetomidine is one of the standard drugs administered for sedation in children who&#xD;
      require sedation for diagnostic (gastroendoscopic upper and lower procedures) and radiologic&#xD;
      diagnostic imaging studies (MRI, CT and Nuclear Medicine). Over 17,000 infants, children and&#xD;
      developmentally compromised young adults have been sedated with dexmedetomidine at Boston&#xD;
      Children's Hospital without a cardiac or respiratory arrest, or a need to provide positive&#xD;
      pressure assisted ventilation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will undergo the usual anal manometry study, with no adjuvant medications, per&#xD;
      routine practice currently in the gastrointestinal unit. Following completion of manometry,&#xD;
      0.5 mcg/kg DEX will be administered over 1 minute followed by an infusion of 0.15 mcg/kg/hr.&#xD;
      Manometry measurements will be followed for 15 minutes in response to DEX.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Definition of Primary Endpoint:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcome: To examine the effects of dexmedetomidine on intra-anal pressure and the&#xD;
      dose response curve to balloon distention by comparing the baseline measurements with those&#xD;
      after dexmedetomidine administration. The pressure measurements will be recorded by the&#xD;
      research team member who will be present, every 30 seconds starting from 5 minutes prior to&#xD;
      DEX to 15 minutes following DEX administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Analysis Plan:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be analyzed after the completion of the study. The manometry measurements will be&#xD;
      done blindly by one of the investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following endpoints will be analyzed at the completion of the study: time to meet&#xD;
      modified Aldrete discharge criteria, adverse events, need for unplanned airway interventions,&#xD;
      intravenous anesthetic duration of sedation, presence of agitation/delirium (PAED score), and&#xD;
      time of BIS score to return to baseline (pre-sedation level).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Power and Sample Considerations:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study was powered and sample size calculated assuming a mean intra-anal pressure of 90&#xD;
      mmHg, with a mean reduction to 65 mmHg, and a standard deviation of 32. With a significance&#xD;
      level of 0.05, it would require approximately 15 subjects to achieve power of 80.3%.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 14, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Examine the effect of dexmedetomidine of gastrointestinal motility by observing changes in intra-anal manometry.</measure>
    <time_frame>20 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The effects of dexmedetomidine on intra-anal pressure will be examined by observing the dose response curve to balloon distention by comparing the baseline measurements with those after dexmedetomidine administration. Intra-anal pressure measurements (mmHg) will be recorded every 30 seconds starting from 5 minutes prior to dexmedetomidine administration to 15 minutes following dexmedetomidine administration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Anesthesia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is a single arm, open label, interventional study examining the effects of dexmedetomidine on anal manometry. All subjects will be administered dexmedetomidine following their baseline manometry measurements. Following dexmedetomidine administration, anal manometry measurements will be observed for 15 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexmedetomidine</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will undergo the usual anal manometry study, with no adjuvant medications, per routine practice currently in the gastrointestinal unit. Following completion of manometry, 0.5 mcg/kg DEX will be administered over 1 minute followed by an infusion of 0.15 mcg/kg/hr. Manometry measurements will be followed for 15 minutes in response to DEX.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ages 3-18 years who are scheduled to have an anorectal manometry followed by an upper&#xD;
             or lower endoscopic procedures at Boston Children's Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients are cooperative to do the anorectal manometry without sedation (besides&#xD;
             pre-med midazolam)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anticipates to receive standard sedation with dexmedetomidine and propofol for a&#xD;
             gastrointestinal procedure in the Gastroenterology Procedure Unit (GPU)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provides written consent to participate in the research study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In females of reproductive age, pregnancy testing&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not meet established sedation criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who require sedation prior to their anal manometry testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergy, intolerance, or reaction to dexmedetomidine or propofol or&#xD;
             hypersensitivity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current, repaired or risk of Moya-Moya disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent stroke (cerebrovascular accident) within past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant use of opioids, beta antagonist, alpha 2 agonist or calcium channel&#xD;
             blocker&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Egg, soy or lecithin allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI greater than 30 or weight above 110th percentile&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refuses insertion of intravenous catheter while awake&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently receiving pharmacologic agents for hypertension or cardiac disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently receiving or has received digoxin within the past 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active, uncontrolled gastroesophageal reflux - an aspiration risk&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current (or within past 3 months) history of apnea requiring an apnea monitor&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unstable cardiac status (life threatening arrhythmias, abnormal cardiac anatomy,&#xD;
             significant cardiac dysfunction)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Craniofacial anomaly, which could make it difficult to effectively establish a mask&#xD;
             airway for positive pressure ventilation if needed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active, current respiratory issues that are different from the baseline status&#xD;
             (pneumonia, exacerbation of asthma, bronchiolitis, respiratory syncytial virus).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Keira Mason, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Boston Children's Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Keira Mason, MD</last_name>
    <phone>617-355-5775</phone>
    <email>Keira.Mason@childrens.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Brooke A Sens, BSN, RN</last_name>
    <phone>617-919-6311</phone>
    <email>Brooke.Sens@childrens.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Boston Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Brooke Sens</last_name>
      <email>brooke.sens@childrens.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Karina Lukovits</last_name>
      <email>karina.lukovits@childrens.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Keira Mason, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Aantaa R, Kanto J, Scheinin M, Kallio A, Scheinin H. Dexmedetomidine, an alpha 2-adrenoceptor agonist, reduces anesthetic requirements for patients undergoing minor gynecologic surgery. Anesthesiology. 1990 Aug;73(2):230-5.</citation>
    <PMID>1974394</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ambartsumyan L, Rodriguez L, Morera C, Nurko S. Longitudinal and radial characteristics of intra-anal pressures in children using 3D high-definition anorectal manometry: new observations. Am J Gastroenterol. 2013 Dec;108(12):1918-28. doi: 10.1038/ajg.2013.361. Epub 2013 Oct 29.</citation>
    <PMID>24169274</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ozkose Z, Demir FS, Pampal K, Yardim S. Hemodynamic and anesthetic advantages of dexmedetomidine, an alpha 2-agonist, for surgery in prone position. Tohoku J Exp Med. 2006 Oct;210(2):153-60.</citation>
    <PMID>17023769</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gurbet A, Basagan-Mogol E, Turker G, Ugun F, Kaya FN, Ozcan B. Intraoperative infusion of dexmedetomidine reduces perioperative analgesic requirements. Can J Anaesth. 2006 Jul;53(7):646-52.</citation>
    <PMID>16803911</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pestieau SR, Quezado ZM, Johnson YJ, Anderson JL, Cheng YI, McCarter RJ, Choi S, Finkel JC. High-dose dexmedetomidine increases the opioid-free interval and decreases opioid requirement after tonsillectomy in children. Can J Anaesth. 2011 Jun;58(6):540-50. doi: 10.1007/s12630-011-9493-7. Epub 2011 Apr 2.</citation>
    <PMID>21461792</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Le Guen M, Liu N, Tounou F, Augé M, Tuil O, Chazot T, Dardelle D, Laloë PA, Bonnet F, Sessler DI, Fischler M. Dexmedetomidine reduces propofol and remifentanil requirements during bispectral index-guided closed-loop anesthesia: a double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Anesth Analg. 2014 May;118(5):946-55. doi: 10.1213/ANE.0000000000000185.</citation>
    <PMID>24722260</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Morera C, Nurko S. Rectal manometry in patients with isolated sacral agenesis. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2003 Jul;37(1):47-52.</citation>
    <PMID>12827005</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sen S, Chakraborty J, Santra S, Mukherjee P, Das B. The effect of dexmedetomidine infusion on propofol requirement for maintenance of optimum depth of anaesthesia during elective spine surgery. Indian J Anaesth. 2013 Jul;57(4):358-63. doi: 10.4103/0019-5049.118558.</citation>
    <PMID>24163449</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Al-Zaben KR, Qudaisat IY, Al-Ghanem SM, Massad IM, Al-Mustafa MM, Al-Oweidi AS, Abu-Halaweh SA, Abu-Ali HM, Saleem MM. Intraoperative administration of dexmedetomidine reduces the analgesic requirements for children undergoing hypospadius surgery. Eur J Anaesthesiol. 2010 Mar;27(3):247-52. doi: 10.1097/EJA.0b013e32833522bf.</citation>
    <PMID>19952754</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mason KP, Zurakowski D, Zgleszewski SE, Robson CD, Carrier M, Hickey PR, Dinardo JA. High dose dexmedetomidine as the sole sedative for pediatric MRI. Paediatr Anaesth. 2008 May;18(5):403-11. doi: 10.1111/j.1460-9592.2008.02468.x. Epub 2008 Mar 18.</citation>
    <PMID>18363626</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mason KP, Zgleszewski SE, Dearden JL, Dumont RS, Pirich MA, Stark CD, D'Angelo P, Macpherson S, Fontaine PJ, Connor L, Zurakowski D. Dexmedetomidine for pediatric sedation for computed tomography imaging studies. Anesth Analg. 2006 Jul;103(1):57-62, table of contents.</citation>
    <PMID>16790626</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Heard C, Burrows F, Johnson K, Joshi P, Houck J, Lerman J. A comparison of dexmedetomidine-midazolam with propofol for maintenance of anesthesia in children undergoing magnetic resonance imaging. Anesth Analg. 2008 Dec;107(6):1832-9. doi: 10.1213/ane.0b013e31818874ee.</citation>
    <PMID>19020127</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kol IO, Egilmez H, Kaygusuz K, Gursoy S, Mimaroglu C. Open-label, prospective, randomized comparison of propofol and sevoflurane for laryngeal mask anesthesia for magnetic resonance imaging in pediatric patients. Clin Ther. 2008 Jan;30(1):175-81. doi: 10.1016/j.clinthera.2008.01.008.</citation>
    <PMID>18343254</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Koroglu A, Teksan H, Sagir O, Yucel A, Toprak HI, Ersoy OM. A comparison of the sedative, hemodynamic, and respiratory effects of dexmedetomidine and propofol in children undergoing magnetic resonance imaging. Anesth Analg. 2006 Jul;103(1):63-7, table of contents.</citation>
    <PMID>16790627</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cravero JP, Beach ML, Blike GT, Gallagher SM, Hertzog JH; Pediatric Sedation Research Consortium. The incidence and nature of adverse events during pediatric sedation/anesthesia with propofol for procedures outside the operating room: a report from the Pediatric Sedation Research Consortium. Anesth Analg. 2009 Mar;108(3):795-804. doi: 10.1213/ane.0b013e31818fc334.</citation>
    <PMID>19224786</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bassett KE, Anderson JL, Pribble CG, Guenther E. Propofol for procedural sedation in children in the emergency department. Ann Emerg Med. 2003 Dec;42(6):773-82.</citation>
    <PMID>14634602</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guenther E, Pribble CG, Junkins EP Jr, Kadish HA, Bassett KE, Nelson DS. Propofol sedation by emergency physicians for elective pediatric outpatient procedures. Ann Emerg Med. 2003 Dec;42(6):783-91.</citation>
    <PMID>14634603</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hauber JA, Davis PJ, Bendel LP, Martyn SV, McCarthy DL, Evans MC, Cladis FP, Cunningham S, Lang RS, Campbell NF, Tuchman JB, Young MC. Dexmedetomidine as a Rapid Bolus for Treatment and Prophylactic Prevention of Emergence Agitation in Anesthetized Children. Anesth Analg. 2015 Nov;121(5):1308-15. doi: 10.1213/ANE.0000000000000931.</citation>
    <PMID>26332857</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nafiu OO, Kheterpal S, Morris M, Reynolds PI, Malviya S, Tremper KK. Incidence and risk factors for preincision hypotension in a noncardiac pediatric surgical population. Paediatr Anaesth. 2009 Mar;19(3):232-9. doi: 10.1111/j.1460-9592.2008.02871.x. Epub 2008 Dec 1.</citation>
    <PMID>19143955</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Anderson JL, Junkins E, Pribble C, Guenther E. Capnography and depth of sedation during propofol sedation in children. Ann Emerg Med. 2007 Jan;49(1):9-13. Epub 2006 Aug 17.</citation>
    <PMID>17141136</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Miller P, Mack CD, Sammer M, Rozet I, Lee LA, Muangman S, Wang M, Hollingworth W, Lam AM, Vavilala MS. The incidence and risk factors for hypotension during emergent decompressive craniotomy in children with traumatic brain injury. Anesth Analg. 2006 Oct;103(4):869-75.</citation>
    <PMID>17000796</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chandran V, Jagadisan B, Ganth B. Validation of Adapted Dartmouth Operative Conditions Scale for sedation during pediatric esophagogastroduodenoscopy. Paediatr Anaesth. 2017 Jun;27(6):621-628. doi: 10.1111/pan.13127. Epub 2017 Apr 3.</citation>
    <PMID>28370856</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Boston Children's Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Keira Mason</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Anaesthesia, Harvard Medical School Boston Children's Hospital</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

