<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00720486</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>K23MH070400</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>K23MH070400</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>DSIR 82-SEMS</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00720486</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness of Anger Management Treatment in Reducing Anger-Related Behaviors in Female Juvenile Offenders</brief_title>
  <official_title>Anger Management Treatment for Female Juvenile Offenders</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>naomi goldstein</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Drexel University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will evaluate the effectiveness of an anger management treatment program, Juvenile&#xD;
      Justice Anger Management for Girls, in reducing anger-related behaviors displayed by girls in&#xD;
      the juvenile justice system.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Girls represent a growing segment of the juvenile justice population in the United States,&#xD;
      with a large number of them being victims of sexual, physical, and psychological abuse. These&#xD;
      girls have special needs in terms of treatment and rehabilitation; however, little research&#xD;
      exists on effective mental health treatments for female juvenile offenders in justice&#xD;
      facilities. Despite the severity of anger-related behaviors displayed by girls in the&#xD;
      juvenile justice system, no anger management treatments have been systematically developed to&#xD;
      meet the unique treatment needs of delinquent girls. Treatment programs that provide&#xD;
      gender-specific education, counseling, and emotional support are necessary for addressing the&#xD;
      aggressive behaviors and psychological distress often displayed among this population. One&#xD;
      such treatment program, the Juvenile Justice Anger Management (JJAM) for Girls, is an anger&#xD;
      management program adapted from Lochman's Coping Power program, an empirically supported&#xD;
      school-based anger management treatment for younger children. This study will evaluate the&#xD;
      effectiveness of JJAM for Girls in reducing anger-related behaviors displayed by girls in the&#xD;
      juvenile justice system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation in this study will last about 8 months. All participants will first undergo&#xD;
      initial assessments that will include a combination of structured interviews, self-report&#xD;
      measures, rating scales, and reviews of program behavioral records and incident reports.&#xD;
      Participants will then be assigned randomly to receive JJAM for Girls plus treatment as usual&#xD;
      or treatment as usual alone. Participants receiving JJAM for Girls will attend two 1.5-hour&#xD;
      sessions per week for 8 weeks. Sessions will aim to help youth develop skills in the&#xD;
      following areas: identifying different types of physical and relational aggression,&#xD;
      recognizing early warning signs of anger, avoiding anger-provoking situations, managing anger&#xD;
      to prevent aggression, solving problems, communicating about anger-related events, and&#xD;
      repairing relationships damaged by anger-related behaviors. Participants will also complete&#xD;
      between-session practice activities that will include practicing skills involved in planning&#xD;
      personal goals. Treatment as usual for all participants will include all standard activities&#xD;
      in the female juvenile justice program. All participants will repeat the initial assessments&#xD;
      at treatment completion and Month 6 of follow-up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction in anger</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at pretreatment, post-treatment, and Month 6 follow-up</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">75</enrollment>
  <condition>Anger</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive Juvenile Justice Anger Management for Girls plus treatment as usual.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive treatment as usual.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Juvenile Justice Anger Management (JJAM) for Girls</intervention_name>
    <description>JJAM will include two 1.5-hour group treatment sessions per week for 8 weeks. JJAM sessions will be manual based and will be designed to help youth develop skills in the following areas: identifying different types of physical and relational aggression, recognizing early warning signs of anger, avoiding anger-provoking situations, managing anger to prevent aggression, solving problems, communicating about anger-related events, and repairing relationships damaged by anger-related behaviors.</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Treatment as usual</intervention_name>
    <description>Treatment as usual will include standard activities in the female juvenile justice program.</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Assigned to one of the designated juvenile justice facilities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has the ability to speak, read, and understand English sufficiently well to complete&#xD;
             the procedures of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Disposition to the juvenile justice program must last the 8 weeks of scheduled&#xD;
             treatment plus 1 week before and after treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fails to complete pretreatment assessments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current psychotic symptoms, mental retardation, or severe developmental disabilities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Considered to be a ward of the state (defined as a youth without a parent, either&#xD;
             biological or adoptive, as the legal custodian)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>19 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Naomi Goldstein, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Drexel University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Drexel University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19102</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Goldstein NE, Kemp KA, Leff SS, Lochman JE. Guidelines for Adapting Manualized Interventions for New Target Populations: A Step-Wise Approach Using Anger Management as a Model. Clin Psychol (New York). 2012 Dec 1;19(4):385-401.</citation>
    <PMID>25110403</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Goldstein NE, Serico JM, Riggs Romaine CL, Zelechoski AD, Kalbeitzer R, Kemp K, Lane C. Development of the Juvenile Justice Anger Management Treatment for Girls. Cogn Behav Pract. 2013 May;20(2):171-188.</citation>
    <PMID>27642247</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lane C, Goldstein NE, Heilbrun K, Cruise KR, Pennacchia D. Obstacles to research in residential juvenile justice facilities: recommendations for researchers. Behav Sci Law. 2012 Jan-Feb;30(1):49-68. doi: 10.1002/bsl.1991. Epub 2012 Jan 4.</citation>
    <PMID>22298128</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 18, 2008</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 18, 2008</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 22, 2008</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 26, 2014</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 26, 2014</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 28, 2014</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Drexel University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>naomi goldstein</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PI</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

