<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03106415</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MC1632</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2017-00496</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>MC1632</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>P30CA015083</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03106415</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pembrolizumab and Binimetinib in Treating Patients With Locally Advanced or Metastatic Triple Negative Breast Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I/II Trial of Pembrolizumab in Combination With Binimetinib in Unresectable Locally Advanced or Metastatic Triple Negative Breast Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mayo Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mayo Clinic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I/II trial studies the best dose of pembrolizumab and binimetinib and how well it&#xD;
      works when given together with pembrolizumab in treating patients with triple negative breast&#xD;
      cancer that has spread to other parts of the body (metastatic). Immunotherapy with monoclonal&#xD;
      antibodies, such as pembrolizumab, may help the body's immune system attack the cancer, and&#xD;
      may interfere with the ability of tumor cells to grow and spread. Binimetinib may stop the&#xD;
      growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth. Giving&#xD;
      pembrolizumab and binimetinib may work better in treating patients with triple negative&#xD;
      breast cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of binimetinib in combination with&#xD;
      pembrolizumab. (Phase I) II. To evaluate the objective response rate (ORR) of binimetinib in&#xD;
      combination with pembrolizumab in patients with unresectable locally advanced or metastatic&#xD;
      triple negative breast cancer by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST).&#xD;
      (Phase II)&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate the safety and tolerability of binimetinib in combination with pembrolizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To evaluate the ORR by immune-related RECIST criteria (irRECIST). III. To evaluate the&#xD;
      progression free survival (PFS), duration of response (DoR), and disease control rate (DCR)&#xD;
      by RECIST and irRECIST.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To assess overall survival (OS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      CORRELATIVE RESEARCH OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To assess the correlation between ORR, PFS, or OS and baseline and/or change in tumor&#xD;
      infiltrating lymphocytes (TILs).&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To assess the correlation between ORR, PFS, or OS and baseline and/or change in immune&#xD;
      related gene signature and PDJ amplification.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To assess the change in immunoregulatory cells (IRC). IV. To assess the change in the&#xD;
      cytokine profile. V. To assess the change in circulating tumor cells (CTC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: This is phase I, dose-escalation study of binimetinib followed by a phase II study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive binimetinib orally (PO) twice daily (BID) on days 1-14 of cycle 1 and on&#xD;
      days 1-21 of cycle 2 and subsequent cycles. Beginning cycle 2, patients also receive&#xD;
      pembrolizumab intravenously (IV) over 30 minutes on day 1. Cycle 1 equals 14 days. Cycles 2&#xD;
      and beyond repeat every 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable&#xD;
      toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 30 days and then every 3&#xD;
      months until progressive disease, then every 6 months for up to 3 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 26, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 15, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of pembrolizumab in combination with binimetinib using the standard 3+3 design (Phase I)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to course 2 (35 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Will be assessed by Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events version 4.0. Safety/adverse events data will be tabulated, including adverse events of all grades.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR) as (Phase II)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be assessed by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST). Will utilize Simon's Two-Stage Optimal Design to test the null hypothesis. Will be estimated using the approach of Jung and Kim. The 90% lower confidence bound will be calculated using the approach of Koyama and Chen.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ORR by immune-related (ir)RECIST</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated as a binomial proportion with a 2-sided 95% confidence intervals. Baseline tumor infiltrating lymphocyte (TILs) and percent change in TILs from baseline will be summarized. Logistic regression models will be used to assess the correlation between these biomarkers and ORR in order to assess their prognostic significance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>The time from study enrollment to date of progression, assessed up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Patients who are alive (including those lost to follow-up) at the time of data analysis will be censored at the last known alive date. A Kaplan-Meier curve will be used to summarize the PFS experience of this patient cohort. Cox Proportional Hazard models will be used to assess baseline TILs and percent change in TILs from baseline and their correlation with PFS.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>The time from study enrollment to death attributable to any cause, assessed up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Patients who are alive (including those lost to follow-up) at the time of data analysis will be censored at the last known alive date. A Kaplan-Meier curve will be used to summarize the OS experience of this patient cohort. Cox Proportional Hazard models will be used to assess baseline TILs and percent change in TILs from baseline and their correlation with OS.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">38</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Triple-Negative Breast Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage III Breast Cancer AJCC v7</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA Breast Cancer AJCC v7</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIB Breast Cancer AJCC v7</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIC Breast Cancer AJCC v7</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Breast Cancer AJCC v6 and v7</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (binimetinib, pembrolizumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive binimetinib PO BID on days 1-14 of cycle 1 and on days 1-21 of cycle 2 and subsequent cycles. Beginning cycle 2, patients also receive pembrolizumab IV over 30 minutes on day 1. Cycle 1 equals 14 days. Cycles 2 and beyond repeat every 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Binimetinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (binimetinib, pembrolizumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ARRY-162</other_name>
    <other_name>ARRY-438162</other_name>
    <other_name>MEK162</other_name>
    <other_name>Mektovi</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Laboratory Biomarker Analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (binimetinib, pembrolizumab)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (binimetinib, pembrolizumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Keytruda</other_name>
    <other_name>Lambrolizumab</other_name>
    <other_name>MK-3475</other_name>
    <other_name>SCH 900475</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histological confirmation of adenocarcinoma of the breast&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Estrogen receptor (ER) and progesterone receptor (PR) negative; defined as ER =&lt; 10%&#xD;
             and PR =&lt; 10% staining by immunohistochemistry (IHC)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HER2 negative in the primary or metastatic tumor tissue defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Immunohistochemistry (IHC) grade 0 as defined by no staining observed or membrane&#xD;
                  staining that is incomplete and is faint/barely perceptible and within =&lt; 10% of&#xD;
                  the invasive tumor cell; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  IHC 1+ as defined by incomplete membrane staining that is faint/barely&#xD;
                  perceptible and within &gt; 10% of the invasive tumor cell; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  IHC grade 2+ staining intensity by means of IHC analysis with no gene&#xD;
                  amplification below; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No gene amplification on in situ hybridization (ISH) based on:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Single-probe average HER2 copy number &lt; 4.0 signals/cell OR&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Dual-probe HER2/CEP17 ratio &lt; 2.0 with an average HER2 copy number &lt; 4.0&#xD;
                       signals/cell&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For phase II part of the trial: =&lt; 3 prior lines of treatment in the metastatic&#xD;
             setting for the current breast cancer; however, there is no limit on number of prior&#xD;
             line of therapy in phase I part of the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) 0 or 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9.0 g/dL (must be &gt;= 7 days after most recent transfusion) (obtained =&lt;&#xD;
             14 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1500/mm^3 or &gt;= 1.5 x 10^9/L (obtained =&lt; 14 days&#xD;
             prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &gt;= 100,000/mm^3 or &gt;= 100 x 10^9/L (must be &gt;= 7 days after most recent&#xD;
             transfusion) (obtained =&lt; 14 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) (obtained =&lt; 14 days prior to&#xD;
             registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate transaminase (AST) and/or alanine transaminase (ALT) =&lt; 2.5 x ULN or =&lt; 5 x&#xD;
             ULN for patients with liver metastases (obtained =&lt; 14 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine =&lt; 1.5 x ULN OR calculated creatinine clearance must be &gt;= 50 ml/min using&#xD;
             the Cockcroft-Gault formula (obtained =&lt; 14 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  International normalized ratio (INR) or prothrombin time (PT) and activated partial&#xD;
             thromboplastin time (aPTT) =&lt; 1.5 x ULN unless patient is receiving anticoagulant&#xD;
             therapy as long as PT or PTT is within therapeutic range of intended use of&#xD;
             anticoagulants (obtained =&lt; 14 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate cardiac function:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &gt;= 50% as determined by multigated&#xD;
                  acquisition (MUGA) scan or echocardiogram (echo)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Corrected QT (QTc) interval =&lt; 480 ms&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative serum pregnancy test done =&lt; 7 days prior to registration, for women of&#xD;
             childbearing potential only&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to swallow oral medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both female and male patients of reproductive potential must agree to avoid pregnancy&#xD;
             or impregnating a partner (respectively) while receiving drug and for 120 days after&#xD;
             last dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to return to enrolling institution for follow-up (during the active monitoring&#xD;
             phase of the study)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to provide mandatory tissue and blood for correlative research purposes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: Treatment cannot begin prior to registering to the&#xD;
             retreatment phase and will ideally begin =&lt; 7 days after registration for the&#xD;
             retreatment phase&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: Stopped initial treatment with pembrolizumab and binimetinib&#xD;
             after attaining an investigator-determined confirmed complete response (CR) according&#xD;
             to RECIST 1.1, and:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Was treated for at least 24 weeks with pembrolizumab and binimetinib before&#xD;
                  discontinuing therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Received at least 2 cycles with pembrolizumab and binimetinib beyond the date&#xD;
                  when the initial CR was declared OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Had stable disease (SD), partial response (PR), or CR and stopped pembrolizumab&#xD;
                  and binimetinib treatment after 24 months of study therapy for reasons other than&#xD;
                  disease progression or intolerability&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: ECOG performance status (PS) 0 or 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: Hemoglobin &gt;= 9.0 g/dL (must be &gt;= 7 days after most recent&#xD;
             transfusion) (obtained =&lt; 14 days prior to re-registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1500/mm^3 or &gt;= 1.5 X&#xD;
             10^9/L (obtained =&lt; 14 days prior to re-registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: Platelet count &gt;= 100,000/mm^3 or &gt;= 100 X 10^9/L (must be&#xD;
             &gt;= 7 days after most recent transfusion) (obtained =&lt; 14 days prior to&#xD;
             re-registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
             (obtained =&lt; 14 days prior to re-registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: Aspartate transaminase (AST) and alanine transaminase (ALT)&#xD;
             =&lt; 2.5 x ULN or =&lt; 5 x ULN for patients with liver metastases (obtained =&lt; 14 days&#xD;
             prior to re-registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: Creatinine =&lt; 1.5 x ULN OR calculated creatinine clearance&#xD;
             must be &gt;= 50 ml/min using the Cockcroft-Gault formula (obtained =&lt; 14 days prior to&#xD;
             re-registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: International normalized ratio (INR) or prothrombin time&#xD;
             (PT) and activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) =&lt; 1.5 x ULN unless patient is&#xD;
             receiving anticoagulant therapy as long as PT or PTT is within therapeutic range of&#xD;
             intended use of anticoagulants (obtained =&lt; 14 days prior to re-registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: Females of childbearing potential should have a negative&#xD;
             serum or urine pregnancy test =&lt; 72 hours prior to re-registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: Females or males of childbearing potential must be willing&#xD;
             to use adequate methods of contraception or abstain from heterosexual activity for the&#xD;
             course of the study through 120 days after last dose of study medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: Experienced an investigator-determined confirmed&#xD;
             radiographic disease progression after stopping their initial treatment with&#xD;
             pembrolizumab and binimetinib&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following because this study involves an investigational agent whose&#xD;
             genotoxic, mutagenic and teratogenic effects on the developing fetus and newborn are&#xD;
             unknown:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Nursing women&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Men or women of childbearing potential who are unwilling to employ adequate&#xD;
                  contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving any other investigational agent which would be considered as a treatment for&#xD;
             the primary neoplasm OR participated in a study of an investigational agent, received&#xD;
             study therapy or used an investigational device =&lt; 4 weeks prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunocompromised patients and patients with known immunodeficiency; or receiving&#xD;
             systemic steroid therapy or any other immunosuppressive therapy =&lt; 7 days prior to&#xD;
             registration; NOTE: inhaled steroids and low-dose corticosteroids are allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of active tuberculosis (TB), human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), active&#xD;
             hepatitis B (e.g., hepatitis B surface antigen [HBsAg] reactive) and/or active&#xD;
             hepatitis C infection (e.g. hepatitis C virus [HCV] ribonucleic acid [RNA] qualitative&#xD;
             is detected)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received a live vaccine =&lt; 30 days prior to registration; NOTE: seasonal influenza&#xD;
             vaccines for injection are generally inactivated flu vaccines and are allowed; however&#xD;
             intranasal influenza vaccines (e.g., FluMist) are live attenuated vaccines, and are&#xD;
             not allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypersensitivity to pembrolizumab, binimetinib, or any excipients of either drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior anti-cancer therapy with a monoclonal antibody (mAb) =&lt; 4 weeks prior to&#xD;
             registration OR failure to recover (to =&lt; grade 1) from adverse events (AE)&#xD;
             attributable to agents received &gt; 4 weeks prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior therapy including chemotherapy, targeted small molecule therapy or radiation&#xD;
             therapy =&lt; 2 weeks prior to registration OR failure to recover (to =&lt; grade 1 or to&#xD;
             baseline) from adverse events (AE) attributable to agents received &gt; 4 weeks prior to&#xD;
             registration; NOTE: exception for neuropathy =&lt; grade 2, which is allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any active central nervous system (CNS) lesion (i.e., those with radiographically&#xD;
             unstable, symptomatic lesions) and/or leptomeningeal metastases; NOTE: patients&#xD;
             treated with stereotactic radiotherapy or surgery are eligible if no evidence of CNS&#xD;
             disease progression &gt;= 4 weeks and patients must be off corticosteroid therapy for &gt;=&#xD;
             3 weeks; NOTE: carcinomatous meningitis is excluded regardless of clinical stability&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active autoimmune disease requiring systemic treatment in the past 2 years (i.e. use&#xD;
             of disease modifying agents, corticosteroids or immunosuppressive drugs); NOTE:&#xD;
             replacement therapy (e.g., thyroxine, insulin, or physiologic corticosteroid&#xD;
             replacement therapy for adrenal or pituitary insufficiency, etc.) is not considered a&#xD;
             form of systemic treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of, or any evidence of active, non-infectious pneumonitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection requiring systemic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of acute or chronic pancreatitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of or current evidence of retinal vein occlusion (RVO) or predisposing factors&#xD;
             to RVO (e.g. uncontrolled glaucoma or ocular hypertension, history of hyperviscosity&#xD;
             or hypercoagulability syndromes)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of retinal degenerative disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of Gilbert's syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other active malignancy =&lt; 3 years prior to registration; EXCEPTIONS: adequately&#xD;
             treated non-melanotic skin cancer (adequate wound healing is required prior to study&#xD;
             entry) or carcinoma-in-situ of the cervix; NOTE: if there is a history of prior solid&#xD;
             tumor malignancy, it must have been treated curatively with no evidence of recurrence&#xD;
             =&lt; 3 years prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impaired cardiovascular function or clinically specific cardiovascular disease&#xD;
             including any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of acute coronary syndromes (including myocardial infarction unstable&#xD;
                  angina, coronary artery bypass grafting, coronary angioplasty, or stenting) =&lt; 6&#xD;
                  months; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Symptomatic chronic heart failure history or current evidence of clinically&#xD;
                  significant cardiac arrhythmia and/or conduction abnormality &lt; 6 months prior to&#xD;
                  screening; except atrial fibrillation and paroxysmal supraventricular tachycardia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled arterial hypertension defined as persistent elevation of systolic blood&#xD;
             pressure &gt;= 150 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure &gt;= 100 mmHg despite medical treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of neuromuscular disorders that are associated with elevated creatine kinase&#xD;
             (CK) (e.g., inflammatory myopathies, muscular dystrophy, amyotrophic lateral&#xD;
             sclerosis, spinal muscular atrophy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planning to embark on a new strenuous exercise regimen after first dose of study&#xD;
             treatment; NOTE: muscular activities, such as strenuous exercise, that can result in&#xD;
             significant increases in plasma CK levels should be avoided while on binimetinib&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impairment of gastrointestinal function or gastrointestinal disease (e.g., ulcerative&#xD;
             disease, uncontrolled nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, malabsorption syndrome, small bowel&#xD;
             resection); NOTE: gastric bypass is allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition that would, in the investigator's judgment, contraindicate the&#xD;
             patient's participation in the clinical study due to safety concerns or compliance&#xD;
             with clinical study procedures, e.g., infection/inflammation, intestinal obstruction,&#xD;
             unable to swallow medication, social/psychological issues, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery =&lt; 3 weeks prior to registration or failure to adequately recover from&#xD;
             surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical, psychiatric, cognitive or other conditions that may compromise the patient's&#xD;
             ability to understand the patient information, give informed consent, comply with the&#xD;
             study protocol or complete the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: Received any type anti-cancer treatment since the last dose&#xD;
             of pembrolizumab&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: History or current evidence of any condition, therapy, or&#xD;
             laboratory abnormality that might interfere with subject's participation for the full&#xD;
             duration of the trial or is not in the best interest of the subject to participate, in&#xD;
             the opinion of the treating investigator&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Saranya Chumsri</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mayo Clinic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic in Florida</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jacksonville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32224-9980</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Clinical Trials Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>855-776-0015</phone>
      <email>mayocliniccancerstudies@mayo.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Saranya Chumsri, M.D.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic in Rochester</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Clinical Trials Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>855-776-0015</phone>
      <email>mayocliniccancerstudies@mayo.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ciara C. O'Sullivan, M.D.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 3, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 3, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 10, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Triple Negative Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

