<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00992693</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>C2009.140</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00992693</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment of Viral Hemorrhagic Fevers With Intravenous Ribavirin in Military Treatment Facilities</brief_title>
  <official_title>Treatment of Viral Hemorrhagic Fever (Crimean-Congo Hemorrhagic Fever or Lassa Fever) With Intravenous Ribavirin in Department of Defense (DOD) Associated Medical Treatment Facilities: A Phase 2 Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>U.S. Army Medical Research and Development Command</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bausch Health Americas, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>U.S. Army Medical Research and Development Command</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 2 study of the safety and efficacy of Intravenous (IV) Ribavirin in treating&#xD;
      patients presenting with a probable or suspected case of viral hemorrhagic fever (either&#xD;
      Crimean Congo or Lassa Fever) at a military medical treatment hospital. All patients will be&#xD;
      treated with a 10 day course of IV Ribavirin if they meet all the inclusion and none of the&#xD;
      exclusion criteria.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Department of Defense operations have resulted in the deployment of personnel to areas&#xD;
      endemic for Viral Hemorrhagic Fever (VHF): Crimean-Congo Hemorrhagic Fever (CCHF) or Lassa&#xD;
      Fever. Unfortunately, beyond supportive care, there is no approved therapy for treating&#xD;
      either infection. Previous studies with intravenous (IV) Ribavirin have shown IV Ribavirin as&#xD;
      a promising treatment for both infections. This study will provide experience in U.S.&#xD;
      Department of Defense associated treatment facilities in the use of IV Ribavirin for the&#xD;
      experimental treatment of viral hemorrhagic fevers primarily among U.S. Service personnel&#xD;
      deployed to disease-endemic areas.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The rationale for conducting the study is a) to allow the DoD to gain experience in treating&#xD;
      VHF b) to offer this experimental but promising therapy to patients with probable or&#xD;
      suspected VHF c) to collect safety data while obtaining experience using Ribavirin.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 17, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 19, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of deaths of individuals with viral hemorrhagic fever (Crimean-Congo hemorrhagic fever or Lassa fever) who received at least four doses of IV Ribavirin</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of clinical events</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Crimean-Congo Hemorrhagic Fever</condition>
  <condition>Lassa Fever</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment with IV Ribavirin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this open label treatment study, the investigators intend to treat all subjects who present with a tentative diagnosis of VHF and meet entry criteria with a 10 day course of IV Ribavirin.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavirin (Virazole) Injection</intervention_name>
    <description>The drug is to be administered in a volume of 50-100 ml of normal saline to be infused over 30-40 minutes.&#xD;
1) Loading dose: 33 mg/kg (maximum dose 2.64 g)(1 dose) 2) Followed by a dose of 16 mg/kg (max dose 1.28 g) every 6 hours for the first 4 days (15 doses) 3) Followed by a dose of 8 mg/kg (maximum dose 0.64 g) every 8 hours for the subsequent 6 days (18 doses) Ten day course of treatment with follow up between day 28 to day 60.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment with IV Ribavirin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Virazole Injection, 100 mg/ml</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        An individual will be enrolled in this study if the patient:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meets the case definition for a probable or a suspected case of CCHF or LF (see&#xD;
             below).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has read and signed the Informed Consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is at least 18 years of age (17, if active military) and not greater than 65 years of&#xD;
             age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a blood sample drawn and a type and cross-match ordered for transfusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees to collection of required specimens.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees to report any Adverse Events, Serious and Unexpected Adverse Events for the&#xD;
             duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees to a follow-up visit and to donate blood and urine specimens at day 14 (±2&#xD;
             days) and once between days 28 and 60 after the first dose of IV Ribavirin and to all&#xD;
             follow-up visits for anemia or other medical conditions as required by the attending&#xD;
             physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Woman of childbearing age must have a pregnancy test performed. If negative, she must&#xD;
             agree not to become pregnant during treatment and for 7 months after receiving&#xD;
             Ribavirin. She also must agree to not breast feed during treatment and for 7 months&#xD;
             after receiving Ribavirin. Two reliable forms of effective contraception must be used&#xD;
             including one barrier method during treatment and during the 7 month post-treatment&#xD;
             period. She will be counseled concerning the risks of IV Ribavirin versus no treatment&#xD;
             if the pregnancy test is positive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Man agrees not to have intercourse with pregnant woman during treatment and for 7&#xD;
             months after receiving Ribavirin, and take precautions to avoid producing pregnancies&#xD;
             during treatment and for 7 months after receiving Ribavirin. At least two reliable&#xD;
             forms of effective contraception must be used including one barrier method during&#xD;
             treatment and during the 7 month post-treatment period to avoid a pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a hemoglobin greater than or equal to10 g/dL before starting IV Ribavirin&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: Malaria should be excluded as a possibility for illness in patients suspected to have&#xD;
        VHF.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Probable Case of Crimean-Congo Hemorrhagic Fever:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All subjects will have a history of possible exposure to CCHF, either having:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Worked or slept outdoors in the CCHF endemic area within 2 weeks of illness onset,&#xD;
             with or without a history of tick-bite or tick exposure, (Endemic area includes, but&#xD;
             not necessarily limited to: Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Oman, United Arab Emirates, Iran,&#xD;
             Iraq, Turkey, Greece, Bulgaria, Albania, Montenegro, the Kosovo region of Serbia,&#xD;
             Bosnia-Herzegovina, Macedonia, the whole of Africa, India, Pakistan, Afghanistan,&#xD;
             Kazakhstan, Uzbekistan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, Azerbaijan, Georgia, the&#xD;
             Crimean region of the Ukraine, Rostov-Don and Astrakhan regions of Russia, and the&#xD;
             Xinjiang [northwestern] region of the People's Republic of China), OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Handled blood or freshly butchered meat of domestic livestock in CCHF endemic area&#xD;
             during 2 weeks before the onset of illness, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had direct contact with blood, tissues, secretions, or excretions of a CCHF patient&#xD;
             (suspected or confirmed), including laboratory specimens, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Worked with the virus in the laboratory setting and have a clinical syndrome&#xD;
             consistent with CCHF as defined by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acute illness with fever and at least two of these symptoms: myalgia, low back&#xD;
                  pain, and headache,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  And the appearance of three or more of the following five groups of&#xD;
                  signs/symptoms:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Hemorrhage (one or more petechiae, ecchymoses, purpura, gingival bleeding,&#xD;
                       epistaxis, gastrointestinal tract bleeding),&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Elevated AST levels (above the upper limits of normal for the laboratory),&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Thrombocytopenia (below the lower limits of normal),&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Hypotension (systolic pressure &lt; 90 mm Hg), or&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Azotemia, renal failure (serum creatinine above the upper limits of normal).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prognostic indicators exist for subjects at increased risk of severe CCHF. Any of&#xD;
             these indicators occurring in the first 5 days of illness, predict a mortality greater&#xD;
             than 90% (Swanepoel et al., 1989). Patients with these prognostic indicators may&#xD;
             benefit most from drug therapy, if resources become limiting:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  WBC &gt; 10,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count &lt; 20 x 103/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST &gt; 200 U/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ALT &gt; 150 U/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  APTT &gt; 60 seconds&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fibrinogen &lt; 110 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
        Probable Case of Lassa Fever:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All subjects will have a history of possible exposure to Lassa fever, either having:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  By residence or travel in an endemic area where contact with rodents was possible&#xD;
             within 3 weeks of onset of illness, (Endemic area includes, but not necessarily&#xD;
             limited to: Sierra Leone, Liberia, Nigeria, Mali, Central African Republic, and&#xD;
             Guinea.) or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contact with a suspect patient or their body fluids (including laboratory specimens)&#xD;
             within 3 weeks of symptom onset, or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Worked with the virus in the laboratory setting. And have&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A negative malaria smear. And have&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signs and symptoms compatible with Lassa fever, either:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fever plus pharyngitis plus retrosternal pain plus proteinuria (positive&#xD;
                  predictive value of 81% when these three criteria are met, McCormick et al.,&#xD;
                  1987a,b),OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fever plus unexplained mucosal bleeding, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fever plus unexplained edema of the face and neck, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Suspected Case of CCHF or LF&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a clinical syndrome consistent with CCHF or LF, meeting most of the above&#xD;
             criteria of a probable case and the patient has an epidemiological history of&#xD;
             potential exposure to the bunyavirus or arenavirus (i.e., recent field duty and/or&#xD;
             other individuals in his troop have CCHF or LF).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has known intolerance to Ribavirin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is irreversibly ill on presentation, as defined by presence of profound shock (shock&#xD;
             which does not respond to supportive therapy within 3 hours after admission).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has hemoglobin less than 10 g/dL that cannot be corrected to 10 g/dL before initiation&#xD;
             of IV Ribavirin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has history of hemoglobinopathies (i.e., sickle-cell anemia or thalassemia major).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has history of autoimmune hepatitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a calculated serum creatinine clearance of &lt; 30 mL/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of such as second or third degree heart block or sick sinus syndrome and&#xD;
             without a pacemaker and no capability of a pacemaker placement or&#xD;
             Wolfe-Parkinson-White Syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A sinus bradycardia of less than 40 beats per minute.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently being treated with Didanosine (ddI). ddI must be discontinued before&#xD;
             starting IV Ribavirin.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Relative Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        At the principal investigator's (PI) discretion, an individual may be treated with IV&#xD;
        Ribavirin, with caution, if one of these criteria is present:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A positive pregnancy test. The individual will be informed of the risk and benefit of&#xD;
             treatment with IV Ribavirin versus no treatment with IV Ribavirin in CCHF (generally&#xD;
             associated with high mortality) and severe cases of Lassa fever with high mortality&#xD;
             rates versus mild cases of Lassa fever with low mortality rates.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A New York Heart Association Cardiac functional capacity of Class II or greater for&#xD;
             ASHD and CHF.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known cardiac defects that my predispose the subject to bradyarrhythmias, such as&#xD;
             second or third degree heart block or sick sinus syndrome without a pacemaker, but&#xD;
             capability of pacemaker placement, if needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sinus bradycardia of 41-49 beats per minutes if the individual is not known to have a&#xD;
             low resting heart rate related to physical conditioning.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of drugs known to result in bradyarrhythmias (certain betablockers and calcium&#xD;
             channel blockers, digoxin).&#xD;
&#xD;
             f. History of gout or tophaceous gout.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>17 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elizabeth Rini, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Landstuhl Regional Medical Center, Germany</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Landstuhl Regional Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Landstuhl</city>
        <state>Rheinland-Pfalz</state>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 8, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 8, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 9, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 30, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 30, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 2, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Crimean-Congo Hemorrhagic Fever</keyword>
  <keyword>Lassa Fever</keyword>
  <keyword>CCHF</keyword>
  <keyword>LF</keyword>
  <keyword>Viral Hemorrhagic Fever</keyword>
  <keyword>VHF</keyword>
  <keyword>Ribavirin</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhagic Fevers, Viral</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lassa Fever</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhagic Fever, Crimean</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fever</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hyperthermia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

