<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00997100</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>09575704</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2009-011245-55</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00997100</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Exploratory Study of Changes in Disease Activity and Biomarkers With ABR-215757 in Patients With Mild Active Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE)</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Exploratory Study to Evaluate Changes in Disease Activity and Biomarkers During Treatment With ABR-215757 in Patients With Mild Active Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Active Biotech AB</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Active Biotech AB</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an exploratory open label single arm study to evaluate changes in disease activity&#xD;
      and biomarkers in patients with mild active SLE, during treatment with ABR-215757 given as&#xD;
      add-on to standard therapy. To be eligible for the study SLE patients should present with&#xD;
      symptoms from skin, mouth and/or joints. After a screening period of one week patients will&#xD;
      be treated with ABR-215757 for 12 weeks. The initial dose of ABR-215757 will be 1.5 mg/day.&#xD;
      There will be an option to increase the dose to 3.0 mg/day following 28 days of treatment.&#xD;
      Follow-up visits will take place 4 weeks and 8 weeks after last day of treatment. Disease&#xD;
      activity during treatment will be studied using the Systemic Lupus Erythematosus disease&#xD;
      Activity Index (SLEDAI-2K) as well as organ system specific disease activity indexes (CLASI&#xD;
      for skin involvement and number of swollen/tender joints using 28- and 66/68-joint counts).&#xD;
      At specified time points during the study, blood samples and biopsies will be collected for&#xD;
      analysis of established and exploratory biomarkers of SLE. Concomitant SLE treatment allowed&#xD;
      include: prednisolone or equivalent at a dose of ≤15 mg/day, hydroxychloroquine,&#xD;
      azathioprine, methotrexate and mycophenolate mofetil, all at stable doses from specified&#xD;
      timepoints prior to the study and throughout the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      All patients will initially receive ABR-215757 at 1.5 mg/day. There will be an option to&#xD;
      increase the dose to 3.0 mg/day following 28 days of treatment. The selected dose levels (1.5&#xD;
      and 3.0 mg/day ABR-215757) are predicted to be effective based on preclinical studies of&#xD;
      autoimmune disease including the SLE MRL model. Previous experience in humans as well as in&#xD;
      preclinical models supports safe administration of ABR-215757 at doses up to and including&#xD;
      3.0 mg/day. The duration of the study is expected to be sufficient to detect changes in&#xD;
      disease activity in this group of patients. Near steady state plasma levels of ABR-215757 in&#xD;
      humans are reached in 14 days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in disease activity and biomarkers in patients with mild active SLE treated with ABR-215757</measure>
    <time_frame>Patients will be treated for 12 weeks with ABR-215757. During treatment there will be scheduled visits on days 14, 28, 56 and 84. Follow-up visits will take place 29 days and 57 days after last dose of ABR-215757</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the safety and tolerability of ABR-215757 in SLE patients with mild active disease. To assess plasma levels of ABR-215757 during the study</measure>
    <time_frame>Patients will be treated for 12 weeks with ABR-215757. During treatment there will be scheduled visits on days 14, 28, 56 and 84. Follow-up visits will take place 29 days and 57 days after last dose of ABR-215757</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">13</enrollment>
  <condition>Systemic Lupus Erythematosus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ABR-215757</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>paquinimod (ABR-215757)</intervention_name>
    <description>The initial daily dose of ABR-215757 is changed to 1.5 mg/day. There will be an option to increase the dose to 3.0 mg/day following 28 days of treatment</description>
    <arm_group_label>ABR-215757</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ABR-215757</other_name>
    <other_name>paquinimod</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age &gt; 18 years at the time of signing the informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Fulfil at least 4 criteria for SLE as defined by the American College of Rheumatology&#xD;
             (ACR)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Present with active SLE disease with at least one of the following symptoms:&#xD;
&#xD;
             i) Arthritis - &gt; 2 joints with pain and signs of inflammation (i.e. tenderness,&#xD;
             swelling, or effusion) ii) Inflammatory-type skin rash iii) Oral ulcers&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Laboratory values as follows&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 100 g/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1.0 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST (SGOT) / ALT (SGPT) ≤ 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Ability to take and retain oral medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Ability to sign and date a written informed consent prior to entering the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Willingness and ability to comply with the protocol for the duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Active severe SLE flare with central nervous system (CNS) manifestations, active renal&#xD;
             lupus, systemic vasculitis, active pericarditis, active pleuritis, active peritonitis&#xD;
             or other SLE manifestations requiring treatment not allowed by the study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Severe renal impairment (estimated or measured GFR &lt;50%)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Oral treatment with corticosteroids (&gt;15 mg/day prednisolone or equivalent) or changes&#xD;
             in corticosteroid dosing within 30 days prior to the first dose of study medication.&#xD;
             This also includes intraarticular steroid injections or topical treatment for SLE&#xD;
             symptoms. Inhaled or topical steroids may be given for reasons other than SLE disease&#xD;
             activity (such as asthma, contact dermatitis) as clinically indicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Intravenous corticosteroids within 3 months prior to the first dose of study&#xD;
             medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Intravenous cyclophosphamide within 6 months prior to the first dose of study&#xD;
             medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Treatment with anti-rheumatic/immunosuppressive drugs within 3 months prior to first&#xD;
             dose of study medication, other than the following medications at stable doses:&#xD;
             methotrexate (≤25 mg/week), azathioprine (≤2.5 mg/kg/day), hydroxychloroquine and&#xD;
             mycophenolate mofetil (≤3000 mg/day).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. B-cell depletion therapy (such as treatment with Rituximab) within 12 months prior to&#xD;
             the first dose of study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Potent inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A4 intravenously or orally within 14 days prior&#xD;
             to first dose of study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of myocardial infarction or current uncontrolled angina, severe uncontrolled&#xD;
             ventricular arrhythmias, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina&#xD;
             pectoris, or electrocardiographic evidence of acute ischemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Marked baseline prolongation of QT/QTc interval (eg, repeated demonstration of a QTc&#xD;
             interval &gt;450 milliseconds&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of additional risk factors for torsade de pointes (eg, heart failure,&#xD;
             hypokalemia, family history of long QT syndrome)&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Treatment with concomitant medications that prolong the QT interval.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. History of, or current, ischemic CNS disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Current malignancy. A 5-year cancer-free period is required with the exception of skin&#xD;
             basal or squamous cell carcinoma or cervical cancer in situ that has been excised.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Current severe infection&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Positive result on screening for hepatitis B surface antigen, hepatitis C antibodies&#xD;
             or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) antibodies.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Drug abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Major surgery within 3 weeks prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Known or suspected hypersensitivity to ABR-215757 or excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Female subject of child-bearing potential who is not using a medically accepted safe&#xD;
             method of contraception. All female subjects of child-bearing potential must have a&#xD;
             negative urine pregnancy test at the Screening and Baseline Visits. As interaction&#xD;
             studies between ABR-215757 and oral contraceptives have not yet been performed, women&#xD;
             using the contraceptive pill must also use a complementary contraceptive device, i.e.&#xD;
             barrier method, during the treatment period and for at least 1 month thereafter.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Female subject of child-bearing potential who is pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Simultaneous participation or participation within 4 months or 5 half lives (whichever&#xD;
             is longer) prior to study entry in any other study involving investigational drugs or&#xD;
             other experimental therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Other significant, unstable medical disease not related to SLE that in the&#xD;
             investigator's opinion would confound the study result or put the patient at risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Patients likely to receive oral or intravenous steroids or immunosuppressant for other&#xD;
             non-SLE condition during the study duration, as this will confound the study result.&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Vaccination within 4 weeks prior to the first dose of study medication.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marie Wallén Öhman, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Active Biotech AB</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Soren Jacobsen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen</city>
        <zip>2100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dept of Rheumatology, University Hospital in Lund</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lund</city>
        <zip>220 07</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Iva Gunnarsson M.D.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stockholm</city>
        <zip>171 76</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lars Rönnblom M.D.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Uppsala</city>
        <zip>751 85</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 16, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 16, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 19, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 24, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 24, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">June 25, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE)</keyword>
  <keyword>ABR-215757</keyword>
  <keyword>Change in Biomarkers</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

