<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04425967</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>M20SCP</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04425967</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Short Course Of Preoperative Radiotherapy in Head and Neck-, Trunk- and Extremity Soft Tissue Sarcomas</brief_title>
  <acronym>SCOPES</acronym>
  <official_title>Short Course Of Preoperative Radiotherapy in Head and Neck-, Trunk- and Extremity Soft Tissue Sarcomas; a Randomized Phase II Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The Netherlands Cancer Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Leiden University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The Netherlands Cancer Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Currently, soft tissue sarcomas (STS) are preoperatively irradiated in a conventionally&#xD;
      fractionated regimen of 25 x 2 Gy in five weeks. Recent radiobiological investigations,&#xD;
      however, suggest sensitivity to (modest) hypofractionation. Within this study, patients will&#xD;
      be randomized to receive either the conventional schedule of 25 x 2 Gy or a shorter&#xD;
      preoperative regimen of 14 x 3 Gy, in the hypothesis that both the postoperative wound&#xD;
      complication rate until 30 days after surgery, as well as the local control probability at&#xD;
      two years are comparable in both arms.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Surgery is the cornerstone in the treatment of non-metastatic sarcomas. Whenever feasible the&#xD;
      resection should include a free surgical margin providing a rim of uninvolved tissue&#xD;
      surrounding the tumor. In most deep located tumors however, to preserve essential&#xD;
      neurovascular and bone structures and thus to preserve function, the margins are often&#xD;
      limited. High grade tumors are, even with wider margins, at higher risk of local failure.&#xD;
      Radiotherapy can reduce this risk of local failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preoperative radiotherapy does increase the risk for early complications due to unavoidable&#xD;
      irradiation of the normal tissues surrounding the sarcoma mass, particularly for lower&#xD;
      extremity lesions (6-9).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preoperative radiotherapy aims to reduce tumor vitality prior to resection, theoretically&#xD;
      allowing more conservative surgical therapy. Postoperative RT allows histological examination&#xD;
      of the tumor specimen, especially the margins, aiding in further treatment planning; it may&#xD;
      also be associated with fewer early wound complications. (10, 11).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In preoperative radiotherapy, as compared to postoperative radiotherapy, lower doses (50&#xD;
      versus 60 to 66 Gy) and smaller field sizes can be used, resulting in a reduced risk of late,&#xD;
      often irreversible, complications. Consequently, preoperative RT is the preferred approach in&#xD;
      many centers. Although the outcomes of combined RT and surgery are favorable, approximately&#xD;
      15% of the patients may relapse locally and about 30-50% distantly (dependent upon, among&#xD;
      others, age, histopathology, size and grade), stressing the need for further improvement.&#xD;
      These improvements should not only be sought in the domain of oncological endpoints, but also&#xD;
      in decreasing treatment burden. A reduction in treatment duration, maintaining local control&#xD;
      rates without increasing the rates of postoperative wound complications would serve the&#xD;
      latter endpoints. For this purpose, quality of life questionnaires as well as patient&#xD;
      reported outcomes measurements could come of help.Modern radiobiological investigations&#xD;
      suggest that, on average, intermediate to high-grade soft tissue sarcomas may have α/β&#xD;
      ratio's substantially below 10 Gy, justifying clinical studies exploring the possibility of&#xD;
      (modest) hypofractionation. Obviously, various subtype derived cell lines exhibit different&#xD;
      characteristics but on average an α/β ratio of 5 Gy would be a reasonable denominator for&#xD;
      sarcomas as a group. However, it is important not to exaggerate hypofractionation in a&#xD;
      setting where patients still need to undergo surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2034</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>randomization between the standard arm A of 50 Gy in 5 weeks or arm B with hypofractination of 14x3Gy</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>the short-term toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days post operative</time_frame>
    <description>wound complications</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>local control</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>percentage of patients without local failure after surgery</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>long-term toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>fibrosis, edema, joint impairment and bone fractures</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">163</enrollment>
  <condition>Soft Tissue Sarcomas</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>25x2Gy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>the conventional schedule of 25 x 2 Gy, once daily fractionation in a five-week OTT</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>14x3Gy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>the study schedule of 14 x 3 Gy, once daily fractionation in a three-week overall treatment time</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>pre-operative radiotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>pre-operative radiotherapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>14x3Gy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>25x2Gy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>radiotherapy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed newly diagnosed intermediate to high grade soft tissue&#xD;
             sarcoma localized to the extremities, trunk and chest wall or the head and neck area,&#xD;
             for which the standard treatment is a combination of and radiotherapy and surgery&#xD;
             (deep seated and/or &gt; 5cm in largest tumor diameter and/or an anticipated close&#xD;
             resection margin and/or grade II/III according to the FNCLCC definition);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Absence of regional and/or distant disease. Patients staged by at least a CT scan of&#xD;
             the chest (. Staging may also be performed by FDG-PET scanning and or total body MRI&#xD;
             scans. Patients with an uncertain metastatic status (e.g. small indifferent lung&#xD;
             nodules) and patients with a low metastatic burden not precluding the application of&#xD;
             both preoperative radiotherapy and definitive surgery, are allowed to participate;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  WHO Performance Status ≤ 2;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to undergo preoperative radiotherapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to undergo definitive surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to comply with regular follow-up visits;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to complete patient reported outcome questionnaires (health-related&#xD;
             quality of life and cost effectiveness);&#xD;
&#xD;
             • Able and willing to undergo randomization;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior malignancies; except another malignancy and disease-free for ≥ 5 years, or&#xD;
             completely resected non-melanomatous skin carcinoma or successfully treated in situ&#xD;
             carcinoma;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with recurrent sarcomas who underwent prior radiotherapy to the target lesion&#xD;
             (if the primary sarcoma was managed by surgery only and no perioperative RT, patients&#xD;
             are eligible);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ewing sarcoma and other PNET family tumors, rhabdomyosarcomas (both pediatric and&#xD;
             adult), osteosarcomas;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition potentially&#xD;
             hampering compliance with the study protocol and follow-up schedule; those conditions&#xD;
             should be discussed with the patient before registration in the trial;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients who are pregnant;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intention to perform an isolated limb perfusion, instead of a tumor resection;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neoadjuvant chemotherapy to be scheduled between end of radiotherapy and definitive&#xD;
             surgery (neoadjuvant chemotherapy before radiotherapy is allowed);&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rick Haas, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The Netherlands Cancer Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rick Haas, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+31 20 512 9111</phone>
    <email>r.haas@nki.nl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Astrid Scholten, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+31 20 512 9111</phone>
    <email>a.scholten@nki.nl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitair Medisch Centrum Groningen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Groningen</city>
        <zip>9713GZ</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hans Langendijk, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+31 50 361 5532</phone>
      <email>j.a.langendijk@umcg.nl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Leids Universitair Medisch Centrum</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leiden</city>
        <zip>2333ZA</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lisette M Wiltink, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>(071) 526 91 11</phone>
      <email>l.m.wiltink@lumc.nl</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Stijn Krol, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>(071) 526 91 11</phone>
      <email>a.d.g.krol@lumc.nl</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Radboudumc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nijmegen</city>
        <zip>6525GA</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Petra Braam, MD,PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+31243614023</phone>
      <email>p.braam@radboudumc.nl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 3, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>preoperative radiotherapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

