<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01633905</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2010_01</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2010-A00595-34</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01633905</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Electrophysiological Correlates of Emotional and Crossmodal Stimuli Processing Among Alcohol-dependent Participants</brief_title>
  <acronym>ALCOLAT</acronym>
  <official_title>Electrophysiological Correlates of Emotional and Crossmodal Stimuli Processing Among Alcohol-dependent Participants : Exploration of the Peripheral Presentation Effect</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Lille</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Lille</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Alcohol-dependence is the most widespread addiction in Western countries and leads to a wide&#xD;
      range of impairments at cerebral and cognitive levels. It has also been showed that&#xD;
      alcohol-dependence is associated with emotional disturbances, particularly for the decoding&#xD;
      of emotional facial expressions (EFE). In view of the crucial role played by EFE to develop&#xD;
      and maintain satisfactory interpersonal relations, this emotional processing impairment may&#xD;
      have deleterious consequences on alcohol-dependent patient's social well-being, and this&#xD;
      deficit is thus of particular clinical interest. Nevertheless, this deficit has up to now&#xD;
      been evaluated only by means of experiments using paradigms with low ecological value (i.e.&#xD;
      presentation of EFE in isolation and in the central vision field), while in the real life,&#xD;
      emotional stimuli are most frequently appearing together with other emotional stimulations&#xD;
      (particularly voices) and in the peripheral vision field. Moreover, the cerebral correlates&#xD;
      of this emotional deficit are still to be determined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The present study thus aims at exploring the Emotional Facial Expressions (EFE) decoding in&#xD;
      alcoholism using a more ecological paradigm, based on peripheral presentation of emotional&#xD;
      crossmodal stimuli (i.e. the simultaneous presentation of emotionally congruent face and&#xD;
      voice).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main aim: Determining the electrophysiological characteristics (latencies and amplitudes) of&#xD;
      the event-related components elicited among recently detoxified alcohol-dependent&#xD;
      participants, while performing an emotion-detection task on crossmodal stimuli (voices and/or&#xD;
      faces) presented centrally or peripherally, and comparing these characteristics with those&#xD;
      obtained among paired healthy participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Exploring the electrophysiological pattern modifications among alcohol-dependent&#xD;
           participants for the emotional faces and voices decoding (unimodal conditions), using&#xD;
           spatio-temporal analyses methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Exploring the electrophysiological waves associated with peripheral crossmodal stimuli&#xD;
           processing among healthy participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Exploring the behavioral correlates (reaction times and accuracy) of the&#xD;
           emotion-detection task among alcohol-dependent participants while processing peripheral&#xD;
           stimuli.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Exploring the psychopathological comorbidities among alcohol-dependent participants and&#xD;
           their influence on the behavioral and electrophysiological results.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Methodology: Evaluation the event-related potentials elicited among alcohol-dependent and&#xD;
      healthy participants while performing an emotion-detection task on unimodal (visual or&#xD;
      auditory) or crossmodal (visuo-auditory) stimulations presented centrally or peripherally.&#xD;
      Event-related potentials allow to monitor the electrical activity of the brain with high&#xD;
      temporal resolution and to detect even minor neurocognitive restrictions. This cerebral&#xD;
      measures will be completed by behavioral (reaction times and accuracy) and psychopathological&#xD;
      measures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      No specific interventions assigned to the subjects of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Evaluations: The room contains a panoramic screen (2.4 X 4 meters) covering a 180 degrees of&#xD;
      visual angle. Participants will seat in a chair situated two meters away from the screen, in&#xD;
      front of a table on which the response pad will be placed. Three projectors will display the&#xD;
      visual stimulations, either centrally or lateralized (-12°, -24°on the left or +12°, +24° on&#xD;
      the right). Headphones will be placed on participants' ears in order to display the auditory&#xD;
      stimulations, either on both ears or lateralized (left or right ear), and presented&#xD;
      separately (unimodal conditions) or simultaneously (crossmodal condition) with the visual&#xD;
      stimuli. Visual stimuli, constructed using FaceGen 3.4 program, will be emotional faces (two&#xD;
      males, two females) depicting happiness, anger or a neutral expression. Auditory stimuli (two&#xD;
      males, two females), from a validated battery, will be emotional voices depicting happiness,&#xD;
      anger or a neutral prosody and presented at a 70 decibels level. Crossmodal stimulations will&#xD;
      be a combination of visual and auditory stimuli, congruent for gender and emotion. Experiment&#xD;
      will be composed of 39 conditions: 3 stimulations (visual, auditory, visuo-auditory) X 3&#xD;
      emotions (anger, happiness, neutral) X 3/5 lateralisation (-24°, -12°, 0°, 12°, 24°). Each&#xD;
      condition will be evaluated on the basis of 50 stimulations. Event-related potentials will be&#xD;
      recorded during the whole experiment by means of a 128 electrodes cap placed on participant's&#xD;
      head and connected with an amplifier (Advanced Neuro Technology, ANT) and a recording&#xD;
      computer, synchronised with the stimulation system. Behavioral responses will be recorded by&#xD;
      means of a response pad. Psychopathological measures will be conducted using validated&#xD;
      questionnaires: State and trait anxiety (STAI A and B, Spielberger et al., 1983), depression&#xD;
      (BDI, Beck et al., 1987), interpersonal problems (Horowitz et al. (1988)), evaluating the&#xD;
      quantity and quality of the social interactions, and the integration in the family and&#xD;
      relationship background and alexithymia (Bagby et al., 1994).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>brain electrical responses amplitudes and latencies</measure>
    <time_frame>participants will be followed an average of 2 hours for the duration of experiment</time_frame>
    <description>Differences in latencies, mainly the P3b wave, in milliseconds and differences in brain electrical responses amplitudes in millivolts, between the alcohol-dependent group and the healthy participants group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>reactions times</measure>
    <time_frame>participants will be followed an average of 2 hours for the duration of experiment</time_frame>
    <description>Differences in reactions times during the emotion-detection task between the two groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>behavioural and psychopathological measures</measure>
    <time_frame>participants will be followed an average of 2 hours for the duration of experiment</time_frame>
    <description>Differences in anxiety level, psychopathology, interpersonal problems level, alexithymia level, measured by validated questionnaires.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>percentage of correct answers</measure>
    <time_frame>participants will be followed an average of 2 hours for the duration of experiment</time_frame>
    <description>Differences in percentage of correct answers between the two groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Alcohol-dependence</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>alcohol-dependent patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>22 recently detoxified participants diagnosed as alcohol-dependant on the basis of DSM-IV criteria who will performed an emotion-detection task on unimodal (visual or auditory) or crossmodal (visuo-auditory) stimulations presented centrally or peripherally</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <description>22 healthy controls without any psychiatric or neurological diagnosis who will performed an emotion-detection task on unimodal (visual or auditory) or crossmodal (visuo-auditory) stimulations presented centrally or peripherally</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        -  22 recently detoxified participants, diagnosed as alcohol-dependent on the basis of&#xD;
             DSM-IV criteria, free of any alcohol consumption during the last 15 days, and without&#xD;
             any other DSM-IV criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  22 healthy controls paired for gender, age and educational level with&#xD;
             alcohol-dependent participants, without any alcohol consumption during the last three&#xD;
             days and without any psychiatric or neurological diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        All participants will be between 18 and 60 years of age, will be French-speaking and will&#xD;
        present a normal or corrected-to-normal auditory and visual acuity.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  for alcohol-dependence group : alcohol-dependent subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  for control group : healthy volunteers without psychiatric&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  for control group : healthy volunteers without neurological diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  more than 60 years old and less than 18 years old,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no French-speaking,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  not normal or not corrected-to-normal auditory acuity,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  not normal or not corrected-to-normal visual acuity&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Olivier COTTENCIN</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Lille</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital, Lille</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lille</city>
        <zip>59037</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 9, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 29, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 4, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 16, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 16, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">June 17, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>alcohol-dependence</keyword>
  <keyword>event-related potentials</keyword>
  <keyword>emotion</keyword>
  <keyword>crossmodal</keyword>
  <keyword>peripheral processing</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

