<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01378273</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00007464</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>U01NS077953</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01378273</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Preterm Erythropoietin Neuroprotection Trial (PENUT Trial)</brief_title>
  <acronym>PENUT</acronym>
  <official_title>Preterm Erythropoietin Neuroprotection Trial (PENUT Trial)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Washington</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Washington</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Recombinant human erythropoietin (Epo) is a promising novel neuroprotective agent. Epo&#xD;
      decreases neuronal programmed cell death resulting from brain injury; it has&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory effects, increases neurogenesis, and protects oligodendrocytes from injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We hypothesize that neonatal Epo treatment of ELGANs will decrease the combined outcome of&#xD;
      death or severe NDI from 40% to 30% (primary outcome), or the combined outcome of death plus&#xD;
      moderate or severe NDI from 60% to 40% (secondary outcome) measured at 24-26 months corrected&#xD;
      age.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To determine whether Epo decreases the combined outcome of death or NDI at 24-26 months&#xD;
           corrected age. NDI is defined as the presence of any one of the following: CP, Bayley&#xD;
           Scales of Infant and Toddler Development, 3rd Edition (Bayley-III) Cognitive Scale &lt; 70&#xD;
           (severe, 2 SD below mean) or 85 (moderate, 1 SD below mean). CP will be diagnosed and&#xD;
           classified by standardized neurologic exam, with severity classified by Gross Motor&#xD;
           Function Classification System (GMFCS).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To determine whether there are risks to Epo administration in ELGANs by examining, in a&#xD;
           blinded manner, Epo-related safety measures comparing infants receiving Epo with those&#xD;
           given placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To test whether Epo treatment decreases serial measures of circulating inflammatory&#xD;
           mediators, and biomarkers of brain injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. To compare brain structure (as measured by MRI) in Epo treatment and control groups at&#xD;
           36 weeks PMA. MRI assessments will include documentation of intraventricular hemorrhage&#xD;
           (IVH), white matter injury (WMI) and hydrocephalus (HC), volume of total and deep gray&#xD;
           matter, white matter and cerebellum, brain gyrification, and tract-based spatial&#xD;
           statistics (TBSS based on diffusion tensor imaging). As an exploratory aim, we will&#xD;
           determine which of the above MRI measurements best predict neurodevelopment (CP,&#xD;
           cognitive and motor scales) at 24-26 months corrected age.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anticipated outcomes: Early Epo treatment of ELGANs will decrease biochemical and MRI markers&#xD;
      of brain injury, will be safe, and will confer improved neurodevelopmental outcome at 24-26&#xD;
      months corrected age compared to placebo, and will provide a much-needed therapy for this&#xD;
      group of vulnerable infants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, placebo-controlled, study of Epo treatment of preterm infants 24-0/7 to&#xD;
      27-6/7 weeks of gestation, beginning in the first 24 hours after birth. Randomization will be&#xD;
      stratified by site and gestational age at birth (&lt;26 week or 26-27-6/7). Study size sample is&#xD;
      940 patients. We expect to evaluate 752 subjects at 24-26 months corrected age, our primary&#xD;
      endpoint. There is no enrollment restriction based on gender, ethnicity or race. Enrollment&#xD;
      is expected to take 24-26 months, with each subject participating through 24-26 months&#xD;
      corrected age when neurodevelopmental outcomes are assessed. The combined outcome of death or&#xD;
      severe NDI will be compared between Epo-treated and control subjects. All outcomes will be&#xD;
      collected in a blinded manner. Subjects will be randomized by the data-coordinating center&#xD;
      (DCC) to Epo treatment or placebo, and Epo treatment will continue until 32-6/7 weeks post&#xD;
      menstrual age. Serial measurements of circulating inflammatory mediators and biomarkers of&#xD;
      brain injury will be made. A brain MRI will be done at 36 weeks post menstrual age in the&#xD;
      same subset of infants. Phone contact will occur at 4, 8, 12, and 18 months. Face to face&#xD;
      follow up will occur at 24-26 months corrected age. The primary outcome is death or severe&#xD;
      NDI at 24-26 months corrected age, with a secondary outcome of death or moderate NDI. Our&#xD;
      primary sample size calculation is based on the conservative assumptions that Epo treatment&#xD;
      will result in a 40% reduction in the severe NDI rate (the range in animal studies is 49-70%)&#xD;
      and minimal impact on death. This would yield a control group rate for the primary outcome of&#xD;
      40.4% and an expected treated rate of 31.5% thus yielding an 8.9% lower rate of Death + NDI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical information including co-morbidities of extreme prematurity, information about&#xD;
      transfusions, and specific laboratory values were collected in the PENUT database.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 28, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 28, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Death or Severe Neurodevelopmental Impairment (NDI) at 22-26 Months Corrected Age</measure>
    <time_frame>22-26 months corrected age</time_frame>
    <description>Severe NDI was defined as Bayley Scales of infant Development, 3rd edition composite motor score or composite cognitive score &lt;70. This instrument is normed at 100 with standard deviation of 15.&#xD;
Cerebral palsy was classified as hemiplegia, diplegia, or quadriplegia, and severity was determined according to the Gross Motor Function Classification System (GMFCS) (levels range from 0 [no impairment] to 5 [most severe impairment]). Severe cerebral palsy was defined as a GMFCS level higher than 2.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With a Serious Adverse Events (SAE)</measure>
    <time_frame>From birth to hospital discharge (average 12-16 weeks depending on gestational age at birth)</time_frame>
    <description>Serious adverse events were prespecified. These included any symptomatic thrombosis involving a major vessel, unrelated to an infusion catheter requiring anticoagulation therapy, hematocrit level &gt;65% or an increase of ≥15% in hematocrit in the absence of a preceding blood transfusion, hypertension (defined by receipt of antihypertensive therapy for more than 1 month, discharge with medication, or both), severe pulmonary hemorrhage, severe necrotizing enterocolitis (defined as Bell's stage 2b or 3), severe retinopathy of prematurity resulting in laser surgery or bevacizumab therapy, severe sepsis (defined as culture-proven bacterial or fungal sepsis resulting in blood-pressure support or substantive new respiratory support), grade 3 or 4 intracranial hemorrhage, cardiac arrest that did not result in death, and death.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Imaging</measure>
    <time_frame>36 weeks postmenstrual age</time_frame>
    <description>Brain MRI at 36 weeks PMA. Injury scoring was done using a modified scoring system of Kidokoro, with higher scores indicating greater brain injury. Scoring Range: 0-39</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Biomarkers</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (first 24 hours after birth), days 7, 9 and 14 after birth</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma Epo concentrations were measured in both groups within the first 24 h after birth before study drug administration (baseline), 30 minutes after study drug administration on day 7 (peak Epo concentration) and 30 minutes before study drug on day 9 (trough Epo) and a random level on day 14 after transition to subcutaneous dosing.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">941</enrollment>
  <condition>Extreme Prematurity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive 6 doses of vehicle intravenously during the first 2 weeks of life. Doses will be administered at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following high dose administration, sham subcutaneous injections will be given three times a week through to 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Epo 1000 U/kg followed by 400 U/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive 6 doses of intravenous Epo 1000 U/kg/dose at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following the high dose period, subjects will receive subcutaneous Epo 400 U/kg/dose three times a week until 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Epo</intervention_name>
    <description>Enrollment will occur within 24 hours of birth. Study drug will be administered intravenously for the first 6 doses. Subjects in the Epo arm will then receive 400 U/kg/dose three times a week until they reach 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age. Control infants will receive sham injections.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Epo 1000 U/kg followed by 400 U/kg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Epotin</other_name>
    <other_name>Erythropoietin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will receive 6 doses of vehicle intravenously during the first 2 weeks of life. Doses will be administered at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following high dose administration, sham subcutaneous injections will be given three times a week through to 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Saline</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. NICU inpatients between 24-0/7 and 27-6/7 weeks of gestation&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Less than twenty four hours of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Parental informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Major life-threatening anomalies (brain, cardiac, chromosomal anomalies)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Hematologic crises such as DIC, or hemolysis due to blood group incompatibilities&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Polycythemia (hematocrit &gt; 65)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Congenital infection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>24 Weeks</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>27 Weeks</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sandra E Juul, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Washington</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Arkansas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Little Rock</city>
        <state>Arkansas</state>
        <zip>72202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Florida</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32610</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South Miami Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33146</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Florida Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orlando</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32804</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>All Childrens Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Petersburg</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33701</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Prentice Women's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60611</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Hospital of the University of Illinois</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Louisville</name>
      <address>
        <city>Louisville</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21224</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Beth Israel Deaconess Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Hospital of Minnesota, MN</name>
      <address>
        <city>Minneapolis</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55404</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Minnesota Amplatz Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Minneapolis</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55455</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Hospital of Minnesota, St. Paul</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Paul</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55102</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of New Mexico Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Albuquerque</city>
        <state>New Mexico</state>
        <zip>87131</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Maia Fareri Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valhalla</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10595</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wake Forest School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winston-Salem</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27157</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Methodist Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Utah</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84108</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Washington</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://PENUT-trial.org</url>
    <description>website for the PENUT Trial</description>
  </link>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Juul SE, Mayock DE, Comstock BA, Heagerty PJ. Neuroprotective potential of erythropoietin in neonates; design of a randomized trial. Matern Health Neonatol Perinatol. 2015 Dec 2;1:27. doi: 10.1186/s40748-015-0028-z. eCollection 2015. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27057344</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Starr MC, Askenazi DJ, Goldstein SL, MacDonald JW, Bammler TK, Afsharinejad Z, D Brophy P, Juul SE, Mayock DE, Hingorani SR. Impact of processing methods on urinary biomarkers analysis in neonates. Pediatr Nephrol. 2018 Jan;33(1):181-186. doi: 10.1007/s00467-017-3779-0. Epub 2017 Aug 19.</citation>
    <PMID>28821985</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Juul SE, Comstock BA, Wadhawan R, Mayock DE, Courtney SE, Robinson T, Ahmad KA, Bendel-Stenzel E, Baserga M, LaGamma EF, Downey LC, Rao R, Fahim N, Lampland A, Frantz Iii ID, Khan JY, Weiss M, Gilmore MM, Ohls RK, Srinivasan N, Perez JE, McKay V, Vu PT, Lowe J, Kuban K, O'Shea TM, Hartman AL, Heagerty PJ; PENUT Trial Consortium. A Randomized Trial of Erythropoietin for Neuroprotection in Preterm Infants. N Engl J Med. 2020 Jan 16;382(3):233-243. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1907423.</citation>
    <PMID>31940698</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 20, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 21, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 22, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>July 2, 2020</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>August 6, 2020</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Actual">August 17, 2020</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 14, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 14, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 26, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Washington</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sandra Juul</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Pediatrics</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>neuroprotection</keyword>
  <keyword>erythropoietin</keyword>
  <keyword>Epo</keyword>
  <keyword>ELGANs</keyword>
  <keyword>preterm</keyword>
  <keyword>neonate</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epoetin Alfa</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified individual participant data will be made available through the NINDS Data Archive: https://www.ninds.nih.gov/Current-Research/Research-Funded-NINDS/Clinical-Research/Archived-Clinical-Research-Datasets. The data will be de-identified and a limited access data set will be available after December 2020 through a request form on that page. Data dictionaries, in addition to study protocol, the statistical analysis plan, and the informed consent form will be included. The data will be made available upon publication of all PENUT Trial related manuscripts to researchers who provide a methodologically sound proposal for use in achieving the goals of the approved proposal.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>December 2020</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>The data will be made available upon publication of all PENUT Trial related manuscripts to researchers who provide a methodologically sound proposal for use in achieving the goals of the approved proposal.</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>https://www.ninds.nih.gov/Current-Research/Research-Funded-NINDS/Clinical-Research/Archived-Clinical-Research-Datasets</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>October 14, 2019</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/73/NCT01378273/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Control</title>
          <description>Subjects will receive 6 doses of vehicle intravenously during the first 2 weeks of life. Doses will be administered at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following high dose administration, sham subcutaneous injections will be given three times a week through to 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age.&#xD;
Control: Subjects will receive 6 doses of vehicle intravenously during the first 2 weeks of life. Doses will be administered at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following high dose administration, sham subcutaneous injections will be given three times a week through to 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P2">
          <title>Epo 1000 U/kg Followed by 400 U/kg</title>
          <description>Subjects will receive 6 doses of intravenous Epo 1000 U/kg/dose at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following the high dose period, subjects will receive subcutaneous Epo 400 U/kg/dose three times a week until 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age.&#xD;
Epo: Enrollment will occur within 24 hours of birth. Study drug will be administered intravenously for the first 6 doses. Subjects in the Epo arm will then receive 400 U/kg/dose three times a week until they reach 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age. Control infants will receive sham injections.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="464"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="477"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="460"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="476"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="4"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="1"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Control</title>
          <description>Enrollment will occur within 24 hours of birth. Subjects will receive 6 doses of vehicle intravenously during the first 2 weeks of life. Doses will be administered at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following high dose administration, sham subcutaneous injections will be given three times a week through to 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age. Subjects are then followed until 22-26 months for neurodevelopmental testing.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B2">
          <title>Epo 1000 U/kg Followed by 400 U/kg</title>
          <description>Enrollment will occur within 24 hours of birth. Epo 1000 U/kg/dose will be administered intravenously for the first 6 doses. Subjects in the Epo arm will then receive 400 U/kg/dose three times a week until they reach 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age. Subjects are then followed until 22-26 months for neurodevelopmental testing.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B3">
          <title>Total</title>
          <description>Total of all reporting groups</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="460"/>
            <count group_id="B2" value="476"/>
            <count group_id="B3" value="936"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age, Customized</title>
          <population>Gestational age at birth</population>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>24 weeks of gestation</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="119"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="113"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="232"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>25 weeks of gestation</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="124"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="121"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="245"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>26 weeks of gestation</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="118"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="103"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="221"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>27 weeks of gestation</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="99"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="139"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="238"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="218"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="232"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="450"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="242"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="244"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="486"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Ethnicity (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="85"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="115"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="200"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Not Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="370"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="354"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="724"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="7"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="12"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Race (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>American Indian or Alaska Native</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="7"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="16"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Asian</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="18"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="10"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="28"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="8"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Black or African American</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="120"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="120"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="240"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>White</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="293"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="317"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="610"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>More than one race</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="14"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="16"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="30"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Region of Enrollment</title>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>United States</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="460"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="476"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="936"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Consented and received first study drug dose</title>
          <description>Consented subjects who were enrolled according to IRB procedures and who received 1st study drug dose.</description>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="460"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="476"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="936"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Number of Participants With Death or Severe Neurodevelopmental Impairment (NDI) at 22-26 Months Corrected Age</title>
        <description>Severe NDI was defined as Bayley Scales of infant Development, 3rd edition composite motor score or composite cognitive score &lt;70. This instrument is normed at 100 with standard deviation of 15.&#xD;
Cerebral palsy was classified as hemiplegia, diplegia, or quadriplegia, and severity was determined according to the Gross Motor Function Classification System (GMFCS) (levels range from 0 [no impairment] to 5 [most severe impairment]). Severe cerebral palsy was defined as a GMFCS level higher than 2.</description>
        <time_frame>22-26 months corrected age</time_frame>
        <population>936 subjects 24-0/7 to 27-6/7 weeks' gestation were randomized and received Epo (n=476) or placebo (n=460) in a double-blinded manner. Survivors who were fully evaluated at 2 years of age are included in the analysis.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Control</title>
            <description>Subjects received 6 doses of vehicle intravenously during the first 2 weeks of life. Doses were administered at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following high dose administration, sham subcutaneous injections were given three times a week through to 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Epo 1000 U/kg Followed by 400 U/kg</title>
            <description>Subjects received 6 doses of intravenous Epo 1000 U/kg/dose at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following the high dose period, subjects received subcutaneous Epo 400 U/kg/dose three times a week until 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Number of Participants With Death or Severe Neurodevelopmental Impairment (NDI) at 22-26 Months Corrected Age</title>
          <description>Severe NDI was defined as Bayley Scales of infant Development, 3rd edition composite motor score or composite cognitive score &lt;70. This instrument is normed at 100 with standard deviation of 15.&#xD;
Cerebral palsy was classified as hemiplegia, diplegia, or quadriplegia, and severity was determined according to the Gross Motor Function Classification System (GMFCS) (levels range from 0 [no impairment] to 5 [most severe impairment]). Severe cerebral palsy was defined as a GMFCS level higher than 2.</description>
          <population>936 subjects 24-0/7 to 27-6/7 weeks' gestation were randomized and received Epo (n=476) or placebo (n=460) in a double-blinded manner. Survivors who were fully evaluated at 2 years of age are included in the analysis.</population>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="365"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="376"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="94"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="97"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <analysis_list>
          <analysis>
            <group_id_list>
              <group_id>O1</group_id>
              <group_id>O2</group_id>
            </group_id_list>
            <groups_desc>We evaluated the primary outcome of death or neurodevelopmental impairment using generalized estimating equations to account for potential correlation within siblings from the same pregnancy, with adjustment for gestational age at birth and recruitment site as a fixed effect. The primary analysis included infants with complete data and excluded data from infants known to be alive but in whom neurodevelopmental outcomes were not assessed.</groups_desc>
            <non_inferiority_type>Superiority</non_inferiority_type>
            <non_inferiority_desc>We assumed no effect of treatment on death, but that Epo will lead to a decrease in the rate of NDI. If we assume a multiplicative reduction in the NDI rate of 0.45 then we expect a treated NDI rate of 12 percent and an overall rate of death+NDI of 30.4% as compared to the control rate of 40.4% corresponding to an overall treatment rate ratio of 0.75. This leads to a sample size of 376 evaluated subjects per arm or a total evaluated sample size of 752 subjects.</non_inferiority_desc>
            <p_value>0.05</p_value>
            <p_value_desc>A two-sided type I error of 0.05 with no formal adjustment for multiple comparisons unless otherwise specified (such as with safety outcomes).</p_value_desc>
            <method>GEE Wald test based on logistic regressi</method>
            <method_desc>adjustments were made for gestational age at birth and recruitment site as a fixed effect.</method_desc>
            <param_type>Risk Ratio (RR)</param_type>
            <param_value>1.03</param_value>
            <ci_percent>.05</ci_percent>
            <ci_n_sides>2-Sided</ci_n_sides>
            <ci_lower_limit>0.81</ci_lower_limit>
            <ci_upper_limit>1.32</ci_upper_limit>
            <estimate_desc>The numerator is the Epo group, denominator is the control group</estimate_desc>
          </analysis>
        </analysis_list>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Number of Participants With a Serious Adverse Events (SAE)</title>
        <description>Serious adverse events were prespecified. These included any symptomatic thrombosis involving a major vessel, unrelated to an infusion catheter requiring anticoagulation therapy, hematocrit level &gt;65% or an increase of ≥15% in hematocrit in the absence of a preceding blood transfusion, hypertension (defined by receipt of antihypertensive therapy for more than 1 month, discharge with medication, or both), severe pulmonary hemorrhage, severe necrotizing enterocolitis (defined as Bell's stage 2b or 3), severe retinopathy of prematurity resulting in laser surgery or bevacizumab therapy, severe sepsis (defined as culture-proven bacterial or fungal sepsis resulting in blood-pressure support or substantive new respiratory support), grade 3 or 4 intracranial hemorrhage, cardiac arrest that did not result in death, and death.</description>
        <time_frame>From birth to hospital discharge (average 12-16 weeks depending on gestational age at birth)</time_frame>
        <population>All subjects who received at least one dose of study drug.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Control</title>
            <description>Subjects received 6 doses of vehicle intravenously during the first 2 weeks of life. Doses were administered at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following high dose administration, sham subcutaneous injections were given three times a week through to 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age (PMA)</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Epo 1000 U/kg Followed by 400 U/kg</title>
            <description>Subjects received 6 doses of intravenous Epo 1000 U/kg/dose at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following the high dose period, subjects received subcutaneous Epo 400 U/kg/dose three times a week until 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age (PMA).</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Number of Participants With a Serious Adverse Events (SAE)</title>
          <description>Serious adverse events were prespecified. These included any symptomatic thrombosis involving a major vessel, unrelated to an infusion catheter requiring anticoagulation therapy, hematocrit level &gt;65% or an increase of ≥15% in hematocrit in the absence of a preceding blood transfusion, hypertension (defined by receipt of antihypertensive therapy for more than 1 month, discharge with medication, or both), severe pulmonary hemorrhage, severe necrotizing enterocolitis (defined as Bell's stage 2b or 3), severe retinopathy of prematurity resulting in laser surgery or bevacizumab therapy, severe sepsis (defined as culture-proven bacterial or fungal sepsis resulting in blood-pressure support or substantive new respiratory support), grade 3 or 4 intracranial hemorrhage, cardiac arrest that did not result in death, and death.</description>
          <population>All subjects who received at least one dose of study drug.</population>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="460"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="476"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="284"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="282"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <analysis_list>
          <analysis>
            <group_id_list>
              <group_id>O1</group_id>
              <group_id>O2</group_id>
            </group_id_list>
            <groups_desc>We hypothesized that Epo would be safe, with no excess of SAEs compared to control infants. Sample size was based on the primary outcome, severe neurodevelopmental impairment or death.</groups_desc>
            <non_inferiority_type>Other</non_inferiority_type>
            <non_inferiority_desc>SAEs were defined prospectively. The rate of total SAEs observed through hospital discharge were compared after accounting for potential within-sibship correlation (with multiple gestations) using Generalized Estimating Equations (GEE) with robust standard errors. We used a GEE Wald test based on Poisson or logistic regression for total SAE count and individual events respectively. All other non-categorical data were assessed with GEE regression models appropriate for continuous outcomes.</non_inferiority_desc>
            <p_value>0.05</p_value>
            <p_value_desc>Statistical significance was set at 0.05 for the efficacy analysis and for the final safety analysis comparing the rate of total SAEs between treatment groups, and 0.031 for death and 0.004 for the ten individual SAEs due to sequential monitoring.</p_value_desc>
            <method>Poisson regression</method>
            <method_desc>Adjusted for multiple gestation and gestational age</method_desc>
            <param_type>Risk Ratio (RR)</param_type>
            <param_value>1.01</param_value>
            <ci_percent>95</ci_percent>
            <ci_n_sides>2-Sided</ci_n_sides>
            <ci_lower_limit>0.83</ci_lower_limit>
            <ci_upper_limit>1.22</ci_upper_limit>
            <estimate_desc>Epo is numerator and Control is denominator</estimate_desc>
          </analysis>
        </analysis_list>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Imaging</title>
        <description>Brain MRI at 36 weeks PMA. Injury scoring was done using a modified scoring system of Kidokoro, with higher scores indicating greater brain injury. Scoring Range: 0-39</description>
        <time_frame>36 weeks postmenstrual age</time_frame>
        <population>Patients who survived to 36 weeks postmenstrual age at 9 preselected sites</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Control</title>
            <description>Subjects received 6 doses of vehicle intravenously during the first 2 weeks of life. Doses were administered at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following high dose administration, sham subcutaneous injections were given three times a week through to 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age (PMA)</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Epo 1000 U/kg Followed by 400 U/kg</title>
            <description>Subjects received 6 doses of intravenous Epo 1000 U/kg/dose at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following the high dose period, subjects received subcutaneous Epo 400 U/kg/dose three times a week until 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age (PMA).</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Imaging</title>
          <description>Brain MRI at 36 weeks PMA. Injury scoring was done using a modified scoring system of Kidokoro, with higher scores indicating greater brain injury. Scoring Range: 0-39</description>
          <population>Patients who survived to 36 weeks postmenstrual age at 9 preselected sites</population>
          <units>score on a scale</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="101"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="93"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="4.1" spread="2.6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="3.8" spread="2.1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <analysis_list>
          <analysis>
            <group_id_list>
              <group_id>O1</group_id>
              <group_id>O2</group_id>
            </group_id_list>
            <groups_desc>For all statistical comparisons between groups, Generalized Estimating Equations (GEE) with robust standard errors and a working independence correlation structure for infants included from a multiple gestation were used. A GEE-based Wald test was used to examine differences in the global brain injury severity score between treatment groups, with adjustment for gestational age (GA) at birth used to stratify treatment randomization (24+0 to 25+6 vs. 26+0 to 27+6 in weeks+days of GA).</groups_desc>
            <non_inferiority_type>Superiority</non_inferiority_type>
            <p_value>0.36</p_value>
            <p_value_desc>Statistical significance was evaluated using a Wald's test and declared significant if p &lt; 0.05.</p_value_desc>
            <method>Generalized estimating equation</method>
            <method_desc>Adjusted for gestational age at birth and treatment assignment.</method_desc>
          </analysis>
        </analysis_list>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Biomarkers</title>
        <description>Plasma Epo concentrations were measured in both groups within the first 24 h after birth before study drug administration (baseline), 30 minutes after study drug administration on day 7 (peak Epo concentration) and 30 minutes before study drug on day 9 (trough Epo) and a random level on day 14 after transition to subcutaneous dosing.</description>
        <time_frame>Baseline (first 24 hours after birth), days 7, 9 and 14 after birth</time_frame>
        <population>Patients who had a baseline Epo level drawn</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Control</title>
            <description>Subjects received 6 doses of vehicle intravenously during the first 2 weeks of life. Doses will be administered at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following high dose administration, sham subcutaneous injections were given three times a week through to 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age. Bayley scores of infant development were assessed at 22-26 months</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Epo 1000 U/kg Followed by 400 U/kg</title>
            <description>Enrollment occured within 24 hours of birth. Epo 1000 U/kg/dose was administered intravenously for the first 6 doses. Subjects then received 400 U/kg/dose three times a week until 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age. Bayley scores of infant development were assessed at 22-26 months</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Biomarkers</title>
          <description>Plasma Epo concentrations were measured in both groups within the first 24 h after birth before study drug administration (baseline), 30 minutes after study drug administration on day 7 (peak Epo concentration) and 30 minutes before study drug on day 9 (trough Epo) and a random level on day 14 after transition to subcutaneous dosing.</description>
          <population>Patients who had a baseline Epo level drawn</population>
          <units>mU/mL</units>
          <param>Median</param>
          <dispersion>Inter-Quartile Range</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="384"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="391"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Baseline</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="7.6" lower_limit="3.4" upper_limit="20.5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="7" lower_limit="3.9" upper_limit="21.4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Peak Epo</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="2.2" lower_limit="1.1" upper_limit="4.8"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="2,907" lower_limit="1,731" upper_limit="6998"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Trough Epo</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="5.1" lower_limit="1.7" upper_limit="8.9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="15.3" lower_limit="7.4" upper_limit="28.9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Random (day 14)</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="4.6" lower_limit="2.1" upper_limit="8.6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="25" lower_limit="9.6" upper_limit="66.5"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <analysis_list>
          <analysis>
            <group_id_list>
              <group_id>O1</group_id>
              <group_id>O2</group_id>
            </group_id_list>
            <groups_desc>For statistical inference, we utilized generalized estimating equations (GEE) with robust standard errors to appropriately account for potential correlation of biomarkers for same-birth siblings. Each respective GEE model adjusted for gestational age at birth and treatment assignment as fixed factors associated with the original study design. Biomarker levels at each follow-up time point were analysed using separate GEE models. Epo levels were log-transformed in all statistical analyses.</groups_desc>
            <non_inferiority_type>Superiority</non_inferiority_type>
            <p_value>&lt;0.001</p_value>
            <p_value_desc>Statistical significance was evaluated using a Wald's test and declared significant if p &lt; 0.007.</p_value_desc>
            <method>Generalized estimating equation</method>
            <method_desc>Adjusted for gestational age at birth and treatment assignment.</method_desc>
          </analysis>
        </analysis_list>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>Birth to hospital discharge (generally 12 to 16 weeks, depending on gestational age at birth)</time_frame>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Control</title>
          <description>Subjects received 6 doses of vehicle intravenously during the first 2 weeks of life. Doses were administered at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following high dose administration, sham subcutaneous injections were given three times a week through to 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age (PMA)</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E2">
          <title>Epo 1000 U/kg Followed by 400 U/kg</title>
          <description>Subjects received 6 doses of intravenous Epo 1000 U/kg/dose at 48 hour intervals from the time of enrollment. Following the high dose period, subjects received subcutaneous Epo 400 U/kg/dose three times a week until 32-6/7 weeks postmenstrual age (PMA).</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <default_assessment>Systematic Assessment</default_assessment>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="45" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="53" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="284" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="282" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Blood and lymphatic system disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Polycythemia</sub_title>
                <description>Hematocrit &gt; 65</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Major Thrombosis</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="5" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Cardiac disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Hypertension</sub_title>
                <description>Requiring treatment</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="10" subjects_affected="10" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="6" subjects_affected="6" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Eye disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Severe retinopathy of prematurity</sub_title>
                <description>Requiring treatment</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="30" subjects_affected="30" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="30" subjects_affected="30" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Gastrointestinal disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Necrotizing enterocolitis</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="36" subjects_affected="36" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="28" subjects_affected="28" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>General disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Nonfatal cardiac arrest</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="8" subjects_affected="8" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="9" subjects_affected="9" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Other unexpected life-threatening events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="31" subjects_affected="31" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="27" subjects_affected="27" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Death</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="45" subjects_affected="45" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="53" subjects_affected="53" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Infections and infestations</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Severe sepsis</sub_title>
                <description>Culture positive and symptomatic</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="38" subjects_affected="38" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="35" subjects_affected="35" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Nervous system disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Severe intracranial hemorrhage</sub_title>
                <description>Grade III or IV</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="64" subjects_affected="64" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="57" subjects_affected="57" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Respiratory, thoracic and mediastinal disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Severe pulmonary hemorrhage</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="19" subjects_affected="19" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="30" subjects_affected="30" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>0</frequency_threshold>
        <default_assessment>Systematic Assessment</default_assessment>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="460" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="476" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Blood and lymphatic system disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Blood transfusion</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="401" subjects_affected="401" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="341" subjects_affected="341" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Cardiac disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Treated patent ductus arteriosus</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="172" subjects_affected="172" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="178" subjects_affected="178" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Eye disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Retinopathy of Prematurity (all grades)</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="258" subjects_affected="258" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="244" subjects_affected="244" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Gastrointestinal disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Necrotizing enterocolitis</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="53" subjects_affected="53" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="46" subjects_affected="46" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Nervous system disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Intracranial hemorrhage (all grades)</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="181" subjects_affected="181" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="168" subjects_affected="168" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Periventricular leukomalasia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="43" subjects_affected="43" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="41" subjects_affected="41" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Cerebellar hemorrhage</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="10" subjects_affected="10" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="8" subjects_affected="8" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Respiratory, thoracic and mediastinal disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Bronchopulmonary dysplasia</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="161" subjects_affected="161" subjects_at_risk="460"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="172" subjects_affected="172" subjects_at_risk="476"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>Principal Investigators are NOT employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Sandra Juul MD, PhD</name_or_title>
      <organization>University of Washington</organization>
      <phone>2062216814</phone>
      <email>sjuul@uw.edu</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

