<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03610490</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017-0671</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2018-01509</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2017-0671</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03610490</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Autologous Tumor Infiltrating Lymphocytes MDA-TIL in Treating Patients With Recurrent or Refractory Ovarian Cancer, Colorectal Cancer, or Pancreatic Ductal Adenocarcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Study to Assess Efficacy and Safety of MDA-TIL (Autologous Expanded Tumor Infiltrating Lymphocytes) Across Multiple Tumor Types</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bristol-Myers Squibb</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Iovance Biotherapeutics</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase II trial studies how well autologous tumor infiltrating lymphocytes MDA-TIL works&#xD;
      in treating patients with ovarian cancer, colorectal cancer, or pancreatic ductal&#xD;
      adenocarcinoma that has come back (recurrent) or does not respond to treatment (refractory).&#xD;
      Autologous tumor infiltrating lymphocytes MDA-TIL, made by collecting and growing specialized&#xD;
      white blood cells (called T-cells) from a patient's tumor, may help to stimulate the immune&#xD;
      system in different ways to stop tumor cells from growing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate efficacy using objective response rate (ORR) using the Response Evaluation&#xD;
      Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version (v)1.1 in subjects with ovarian cancer, pancreatic&#xD;
      ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC), and colorectal cancers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Determine the disease control rate (DCR) within and across cohorts. II. Determine the&#xD;
      duration of response (DOR). III. Determine progression-free survival (PFS) and overall&#xD;
      survival (OS). IV. Further characterize the safety profile of adoptive cell therapy (ACT)&#xD;
      with tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes (TIL) across multiple tumor types.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Establish duration of TIL persistence. II. Compare the molecular and immunological&#xD;
      features of tumors before and after TIL therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. Prospectively evaluate the existing immunotherapy response criteria (immune-related&#xD;
      Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors [irRECIST]) as the best response assessment tool&#xD;
      for TIL therapy among a diverse group of solid tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. Investigate TIL attributes (CD8 %, CD27 and CD28 expression) and correlation with&#xD;
      response to therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      V. Assess tumor marker (CA19-9; CA-125) response in patients who produce this tumor marker.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VI. Assess Health-Related Quality of Life (HRQOL).&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      LYMPHODEPLETION REGIMEN: Patients receive cyclophosphamide intravenously (IV) over 2 hours on&#xD;
      days -7 and -6, and fludarabine IV over 15-30 minutes on days -5 to -1 in the absence of&#xD;
      disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      T-CELL INFUSION: Patients receive autologous tumor infiltrating lymphocytes MDA-TIL IV over&#xD;
      45 minutes on day 0. Patients then receive IL-2 IV over 30 minutes on days 1-4 for up to 6&#xD;
      doses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at week 18, at 6, 9, 12, 18,&#xD;
      and 24 months, and then every 3 months for up to 3 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 17, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be measured by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1 criteria. ORR will use 80% confidence interval by the Wilson score method.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete response rate (CRR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be measured by RECIST 1.1 criteria. CRR will adopt the 2-sided 95% criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease control rate (DCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be measured by RECIST 1.1 criteria. DCR will adopt the 2-sided 95% criteria. DCR includes complete response, partial response, and stable disease.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response (DOR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be measured by RECIST 1.1 criteria. DOR will adopt the 2-sided 95% criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Will be measured by RECIST 1.1 criteria. PFS will be summarized using Kaplan-Meier estimates.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>OS will be summarized using Kaplan-Meier estimates.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be graded according to Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 4.03. Safety endpoints will include overall assessment of adverse events (AEs) including grade 3 or greater non-hematological toxicities, serious adverse events and treatment-emergent AEs by grade and relationship to the study treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of tumor infiltrating lymphocyte (TIL) persistence</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of TIL persistence is determined by T cell receptor (TCR) sequencing of infused T cells serially isolated following MDA-TIL infusion, or alternatively iRepertoire assessment of messenger ribonucleic acid for the TCRs. A paired t-test will be used to examine the molecular and immunological features of tumors before and after TIL therapy. Pearson correlation coefficient and linear regression, when appropriate, will be used to quantify the relationship between phenotypic attributes (CD8 %, CD27 and CD28 expression, etc.) and response to therapy.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be determined by the immune-related response criteria. A paired t-test will be used to examine the molecular and immunological features of tumors before and after TIL therapy. Pearson correlation coefficient and linear regression, when appropriate, will be used to quantify the relationship between phenotypic attributes (CD8 %, CD27 and CD28 expression, etc.) and response to therapy.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of immunological phenotype of autologous tumor infiltrating lymphocytes MDA-TIL</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of infusion</time_frame>
    <description>A paired t-test will be used to examine the molecular and immunological features of tumors before and after TIL therapy. Pearson correlation coefficient and linear regression, when appropriate, will be used to quantify the relationship between phenotypic attributes (CD8 %, CD27 and CD28 expression, etc.) and response to therapy.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Tumor assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be determined by immunohistochemistry, TCR sequencing, and transcriptional analysis. A paired t-test will be used to examine the molecular and immunological features of tumors before and after TIL therapy. Pearson correlation coefficient and linear regression, when appropriate, will be used to quantify the relationship between phenotypic attributes (CD8 %, CD27 and CD28 expression, etc.) and response to therapy.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Health-related quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be assessed by European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer core 30 quality of life questionnaire. A paired t-test will be used to examine the molecular and immunological features of tumors before and after TIL therapy. Pearson correlation coefficient and linear regression, when appropriate, will be used to quantify the relationship between phenotypic attributes (CD8 %, CD27 and CD28 expression, etc.) and response to therapy.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">27</enrollment>
  <condition>Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Colorectal Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Ovarian Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Pancreatic Ductal Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Platinum-Resistant Ovarian Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent High Grade Ovarian Serous Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Ovarian Carcinosarcoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Colorectal Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVA Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVB Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVC Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (autologous tumor infiltrating lymphocytes MDA-TIL)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>LYMPHODEPLETION REGIMEN: Patients receive cyclophosphamide IV over 2 hours on days -7 and -6, and fludarabine IV over 15-30 minutes on days -5 to -1 in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
T-CELL INFUSION: Patients receive autologous tumor infiltrating lymphocytes MDA-TIL IV over 45 minutes on day 0. Patients then receive IL-2 IV over 30 minutes on days 1-4 for up to 6 doses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Autologous Tumor Infiltrating Lymphocytes MDA-TIL</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (autologous tumor infiltrating lymphocytes MDA-TIL)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MDA Autologous TILs</other_name>
    <other_name>MDA Autologous Tumor Infiltrating Lymphocytes</other_name>
    <other_name>MDA-TILs</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cyclophosphamide</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (autologous tumor infiltrating lymphocytes MDA-TIL)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>(-)-Cyclophosphamide</other_name>
    <other_name>2H-1,3,2-Oxazaphosphorine, 2-[bis(2-chloroethyl)amino]tetrahydro-, 2-oxide, monohydrate</other_name>
    <other_name>Carloxan</other_name>
    <other_name>Ciclofosfamida</other_name>
    <other_name>Ciclofosfamide</other_name>
    <other_name>Cicloxal</other_name>
    <other_name>Clafen</other_name>
    <other_name>Claphene</other_name>
    <other_name>CP monohydrate</other_name>
    <other_name>CTX</other_name>
    <other_name>CYCLO-cell</other_name>
    <other_name>Cycloblastin</other_name>
    <other_name>Cycloblastine</other_name>
    <other_name>Cyclophospham</other_name>
    <other_name>Cyclophosphamid monohydrate</other_name>
    <other_name>Cyclophosphamide Monohydrate</other_name>
    <other_name>Cyclophosphamidum</other_name>
    <other_name>Cyclophosphan</other_name>
    <other_name>Cyclophosphane</other_name>
    <other_name>Cyclophosphanum</other_name>
    <other_name>Cyclostin</other_name>
    <other_name>Cyclostine</other_name>
    <other_name>Cytophosphan</other_name>
    <other_name>Cytophosphane</other_name>
    <other_name>Cytoxan</other_name>
    <other_name>Fosfaseron</other_name>
    <other_name>Genoxal</other_name>
    <other_name>Genuxal</other_name>
    <other_name>Ledoxina</other_name>
    <other_name>Mitoxan</other_name>
    <other_name>Neosar</other_name>
    <other_name>Revimmune</other_name>
    <other_name>Syklofosfamid</other_name>
    <other_name>WR- 138719</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fludarabine</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (autologous tumor infiltrating lymphocytes MDA-TIL)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Fluradosa</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Interleukin-2</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (autologous tumor infiltrating lymphocytes MDA-TIL)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Epidermal Thymocyte Activating Factor</other_name>
    <other_name>ETAF</other_name>
    <other_name>IL-2</other_name>
    <other_name>IL2</other_name>
    <other_name>IL2 Protein</other_name>
    <other_name>Interleukin 2</other_name>
    <other_name>Interleukin 2 Precursor</other_name>
    <other_name>Interleukin II</other_name>
    <other_name>Lymphocyte Mitogenic Factor</other_name>
    <other_name>Mitogenic Factor</other_name>
    <other_name>Ro-236019</other_name>
    <other_name>T Cell Growth Factor</other_name>
    <other_name>T-Cell Growth Factor</other_name>
    <other_name>TCGF</other_name>
    <other_name>Thymocyte Stimulating Factor</other_name>
    <other_name>TSF</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Quality-of-Life Assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>Ancillary studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (autologous tumor infiltrating lymphocytes MDA-TIL)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Quality of Life Assessment</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must be willing and able to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical performance status of Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) 0 or 1 at&#xD;
             enrollment and within 7 days of initiating lymphodepleting chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have an area of tumor amenable to excisional biopsy (core biopsies may&#xD;
             be allowed) for the generation of TIL separate from, and in addition to, a target&#xD;
             lesion to be used for response assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any prior therapy directed at the malignant tumor, including radiation therapy,&#xD;
             chemotherapy, and biologic/targeted agents must be discontinued at least 28 days prior&#xD;
             to tumor resection for preparing TIL therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1000/mm^3 (within 7 days of enrollment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9.0 g/dL (transfusion allowed) (within 7 days of enrollment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &gt;= 100,000/mm^3 (within 7 days of enrollment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT)/serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase (SGPT) and&#xD;
             aspartate aminotransferase (AST)/serum glutamic-oxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT) &lt; 2.5&#xD;
             x the upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with liver metastases may have liver function test [LFT] =&lt; 5.0 x ULN&#xD;
                  (within 7 days of enrollment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Calculated creatinine clearance (Cockcroft-Gault) &gt;= 50.0 mL/min (within 7 days of&#xD;
             enrollment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x ULN (within 7 days of enrollment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prothrombin time (PT) &amp; activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) =&lt; 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
             (correction with vitamin K allowed) unless subject is receiving anticoagulant therapy&#xD;
             (which should be managed according to institutional norms prior to and after&#xD;
             excisional biopsy) (within 7 days of enrollment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative serum pregnancy test (female subjects of childbearing potential) (within 7&#xD;
             days of enrollment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must not have a confirmed human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have a 12-lead electrocardiogram (EKG) showing no active ischemia and&#xD;
             Fridericia's corrected QT interval (QTcF) less than 480 ms&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must also have a negative dobutamine stress echocardiogram before beginning&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects of childbearing potential must be willing to practice an approved highly&#xD;
             effective method of birth control starting at the time of informed consent and for 1&#xD;
             year after the completion of the lymphodepletion regimen. Approved methods of birth&#xD;
             control are as follows: hormonal contraception (i.e. birth control pills, injection,&#xD;
             implant, transdermal patch, vaginal ring); intrauterine device (IUD); tubal ligation&#xD;
             or hysterectomy; subject/partner status post vasectomy; implantable or injectable&#xD;
             contraceptives; and condoms plus spermicide&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to adhere to the study visit schedule and other protocol requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pulmonary function tests (spirometry) demonstrating forced expiratory value (FEV) 1&#xD;
             greater than 65% predicted or forced vital capacity (FVC) greater than 65% of&#xD;
             predicted&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ovarian cancer cohort only: Subjects must have high grade non-mucinous histology&#xD;
             (carcinosarcomas are allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ovarian cancer cohort only: Subjects must have failed at least two prior lines of&#xD;
             chemotherapy (i.e. frontline adjuvant chemotherapy plus one additional line for&#xD;
             recurrent/progressive disease), or have platinum resistant disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Colorectal cohort only: Subjects with colorectal adenocarcinoma must have metastatic&#xD;
             disease that is considered incurable with currently available therapies and have&#xD;
             derived maximal benefit from or have become refractory to frontline conventional&#xD;
             therapy (e.g. leucovorin calcium [calcium folinate], 5-fluorouracil and oxaliplatin&#xD;
             [FOLFOX], leucovorin calcium, 5-fluorouracil, and irinotecan [FOLFIRI]).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Colorectal cohort only: Subjects should have low disease burden such that in the&#xD;
             treating physician's opinion the patient would not require additional intervening&#xD;
             treatment for 7-8 weeks (required for TIL harvest and manufacturing)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pancreatic adenocarcinoma cohort only: Subjects must have histologically or&#xD;
             cytologically documented diagnosis of PDAC with oligo-metastatic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pancreatic adenocarcinoma cohort only: Subjects must have progressed on, or received&#xD;
             maximal benefit from, front-line therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pancreatic adenocarcinoma cohort only: Patients may have received unlimited lines of&#xD;
             prior standard of care therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pancreatic adenocarcinoma cohort only: Patients with ascites or carcinomatosis are not&#xD;
             eligible for the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pancreatic adenocarcinoma cohort only: Patients will need an albumin of &gt;= 3.0 mg/dL&#xD;
             within 7 days of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  TREATMENT INCLUSION CRITERION: Within 24 h of starting lymphodepleting chemotherapy,&#xD;
             subjects must meet the following laboratory criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1000/mm^3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9.0 g/dL (transfusion allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count &gt;= 100,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ALT/SGPT and AST/SGOT =&lt; 2.5 x the upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Patients with liver metastases may have liver function tests (LFT) =&lt; 5.0 x&#xD;
                       ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Calculated creatinine clearance (Cockcroft-Gault) &gt;= 50.0 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 X ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active systemic infections requiring intravenous antibiotics, coagulation disorders or&#xD;
             other major medical illnesses of the cardiovascular, respiratory or immune system.&#xD;
             Principal investigator (PI) or his/her designee shall make the final determination&#xD;
             regarding appropriateness of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active viral hepatitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have a left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt; 45% at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of prior adoptive cell therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persistent prior therapy-related toxicities greater than grade 2 according to Common&#xD;
             Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) v. 4.03, except for peripheral&#xD;
             neuropathy, alopecia, or vitiligo prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary immunodeficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of organ or hematopoietic stem cell transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic steroid therapy, however prednisone or its equivalent is allowed at &lt; 10&#xD;
             mg/day&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are pregnant or nursing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of a significant psychiatric disease, which in the opinion of the principal&#xD;
             investigator or his/her designee, would prevent adequate informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of clinically significant autoimmune disease including active, known, or&#xD;
             suspected autoimmune disease. Subjects with resolved side effects from prior&#xD;
             checkpoint inhibitor therapy, vitiligo, psoriasis, type 1 diabetes or resolved&#xD;
             childhood asthma/atopy would be an exception to this rule. Subjects that require&#xD;
             intermittent use of bronchodilators or local steroid injections would not be excluded.&#xD;
             Subjects with hypothyroidism stable on hormone replacement or Sjogren's syndrome will&#xD;
             not be excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of clinically significant chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD),&#xD;
             asthma, or other chronic lung disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of a second malignancy (diagnosed in the last 5 years). Exceptions include&#xD;
             basal cell carcinoma of the skin, squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, or in situ&#xD;
             cervical cancer that has undergone potentially curative therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of known active central nervous system metastases and/or carcinomatous&#xD;
             meningitis. Subjects with previously treated brain metastases may participate provided&#xD;
             they are stable (without evidence of progression by imaging for at least four weeks&#xD;
             prior to the first dose of trial treatment and any neurologic symptoms have returned&#xD;
             to baseline), have no evidence of new or enlarging brain metastases, and are not using&#xD;
             steroids for at least 7 days prior to initiation of lymphodepletion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received a live vaccine within 30 days prior to the initiation of lymphodepletion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have a contraindication to or history of hypersensitivity reaction to any&#xD;
             components or excipients of the TIL therapy or the other study drugs: NMA-LD&#xD;
             (cyclophosphamide, mesna, and fludarabine); IL-2; any component of the TIL infusion&#xD;
             product formulation including human serum albumin (HSA), IL-2, and dextran-40&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition that in the investigator's judgement would significantly increase&#xD;
             the risks of participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has any complication or delayed healing from excisional procedure that in the&#xD;
             investigator's opinion would increase the risks of lymphodepletion, adoptive TIL&#xD;
             therapy and adjuvant IL-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients has a decline in performance status to ECOG &gt; 1 (at the visit prior to&#xD;
             admission for lymphodepletion)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Amir A Jazaeri</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M D Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>MD Anderson Cancer Center Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 24, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 31, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 1, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Ovarian Epithelial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cystadenocarcinoma, Serous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinosarcoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fludarabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interleukin-2</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mitogens</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

