<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03611868</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APG-115-US-002</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>Keynote MK-3475-B66</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03611868</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of APG-115 in Combination With Pembrolizumab in Patients With Metastatic Melanomas or Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase Ib/II Study of APG-115 in Combination With Pembrolizumab in Patients With Unresectable or Metastatic Melanomas or Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ascentage Pharma Group Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ascentage Pharma Group Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Part 1 is the dose escalation of APG-115 in combination with label dose of pembrolizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part 2 is phase II design of APG-115 at recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) in combination with&#xD;
      pembrolizumab in patients with programmed cell death protein 1 (PD-1)/programmed death-ligand&#xD;
      1 (PD-L1) refractory/relapsed melanoma or NSCLC, lung adenocarcinoma with STK11 mutation,&#xD;
      solid tumors with P53 WT and ATM mutation, P53 WT and MDM2 amplification liposarcomas,&#xD;
      PD-1/PD-L1 refractory/relapsed urothelial carcinoma without FGFR translocation mutation, and&#xD;
      MPNST.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Part 1 is the open label, dose-escalation phase Ib portion of the study to establish the&#xD;
      maximum tolerated dose (MTD)/RP2D of APG-115 in combination with pembrolizumab. Four dose&#xD;
      levels of APG-115 will be administered: 50 mg, 100 mg, 150 mg, and 200 mg. APG-115 will be&#xD;
      administered orally every other day (QOD) for consecutive 2 weeks and 1 week off dosing as a&#xD;
      cycle of 21 days (3 weeks), pembrolizumab will administrated with label dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part 2 is a phase II study design, includes cohort A-F six arms. The patients will be treated&#xD;
      with APG-115 at 150 mg QOD (RP2D) in combination with pembrolizumab until disease&#xD;
      progression, unacceptable toxicity, or another discontinuation criterion is met.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 29, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Tolerated Dose</measure>
    <time_frame>21 days</time_frame>
    <description>Part I is to assess the safety and tolerability of APG-115 by assessing the dose-limiting toxicity (DLT) of APG-115 in combination with pembrolizumab. End points included: Incidence of DLTs during the first 3 weeks of treatment of each dose cohort; Severity and frequency of any adverse event(s) (AE) and serious adverse event(s) (SAE) based on NCI CTCAE 5.0</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recommended Phase II Dose</measure>
    <time_frame>21 days</time_frame>
    <description>Part I is aimed to generate data to select the recommended Phase II dose</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Phase II is to assess overall response rate of APG-115 in combination with pembrolizumab defined as the percentage of subjects with a best overall confirmed complete response (CR) or a partial response (PR) at any time as per RECIST 1.1</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">203</enrollment>
  <condition>Unresectable or Metastatic Melanoma or Advanced Solid Tumors</condition>
  <condition>Melanoma</condition>
  <condition>Uveal Melanoma</condition>
  <condition>Non Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>ATM Gene Mutation</condition>
  <condition>P53 Mutation</condition>
  <condition>MDM2 Gene Mutation</condition>
  <condition>Liposarcoma</condition>
  <condition>Urothelial Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>MPNST</condition>
  <condition>Cutaneous Melanoma</condition>
  <condition>Mucosal Melanoma</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Peripheral Nerve Sheath Tumors</condition>
  <condition>STK11 Gene Mutation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>APG-115+Pembrolizumab open label, two-part phase Ib/II</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>single arm dose escalation and dose expansion</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>APG-115+Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>dose escalation of APG-115 in combination with label dose of pembrolizumab, Four dose levels of APG-115 will be tested: 50, 100, 150, and 200 mg. APG-115 will be administrated orally every other day (QOD) for consecutive 2 weeks (ie. dosed at Day 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, and 13), with one week dosing off as 3-weeks a cycle. Pembrolizumab is administrated following FDA approved label dose, i.e., 200 mg intravenous infusion at Day 1 of every 3 weeks as a cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>APG-115+Pembrolizumab open label, two-part phase Ib/II</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Keytruda</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or non-pregnant, non-lactating female patients age ≥18 years, an exception for&#xD;
             MPNST cohort: adolescents ≥12 years old (who weigh at least 40 kg) is allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Part 1:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Histologically confirmed, unresectable or metastatic melanoma, or advanced solid&#xD;
                  tumor patients who failed standard of care therapy and no further effective&#xD;
                  therapy is available&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Part 2:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Cohort A: Histologically confirmed, unresectable or metastatic melanoma, and&#xD;
                  refractory or relapse after PD-1 antibody treatment and ineligible for other&#xD;
                  standard of care therapy per NCCN guideline (previous PD-1/PD-L1 antibody&#xD;
                  treatment not required for uveal melanoma)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Cohort B: Histologically confirmed, unresectable or metastatic NSCLC, and&#xD;
                  refractory or relapse after PD-1/PD-L1 antibody treatment and ineligible for&#xD;
                  other standard of care therapy per NCCN guideline or Histologically confirmed,&#xD;
                  unresectable or metastatic lung adenocarcinoma with STK-11 mutation, and with or&#xD;
                  without previous anti-PD-1/PD-L1 antibody treatment and ineligible for other&#xD;
                  standard of care therapy per NCCN guideline&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Cohort C: Histologically confirmed, unresectable or metastatic solid tumors with&#xD;
                  P53WT and ATM mutation (including germline ATM mutation)&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Cohort D: Histologically confirmed, locally advanced or metastatic&#xD;
                  well-differentiated or dedifferentiated liposarcomas who have or haven't received&#xD;
                  prior systemic therapy (either ineligible or declining chemotherapy), and with&#xD;
                  P53 WT and MDM2 amplification&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Cohort E: Histologically confirmed, unresectable or metastatic urothelial&#xD;
                  carcinoma, and refractory or relapse after PD-1/PD-L1 antibody treatment and&#xD;
                  ineligible for other standard of care therapy per NCCN guideline&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Cohort F: Histologically confirmed, metastatic or unresectable MPNST&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Measurable disease according to RECIST 1.1. Lesions situated in a previously&#xD;
                  irradiated area, or an area subject to other loco-regional therapy (e.g.,&#xD;
                  intralesional injections) should be considered non-measurable&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. ECOG performance status 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy ≥ 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Continuance of treatment related toxicities (except alopecia) due to prior&#xD;
             radiotherapy or chemotherapy agents or biological therapy (including PD-1/PD-L1&#xD;
             antibodies) must be ≤ grade 1 at the time of dosing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate bone marrow and organ function as indicated by the following laboratory&#xD;
             values without continuous supportive treatment (such as blood transfusion, coagulation&#xD;
             factors and/or platelet infusion, red/white blood cell growth factor administration,&#xD;
             or albumin infusion) as assessed by laboratory for eligibility&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  QTcF interval (mean of 3, 1-3 minutes between two tests) ≤450 ms in males and ≤470 ms&#xD;
             in females&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) ≥ lower limit of institutional normal (LLN)&#xD;
             as assessed by echocardiogram (ECHO) or multigated acquisition (MUGA) scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tumor tissue must be provided for all subjects for biomarker analysis before treatment&#xD;
             with investigational product&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to use contraception by a method that is deemed effective by the&#xD;
             investigator by both male and female patients of child bearing potential&#xD;
             (postmenopausal women must have been amenorrhea for at least 12 months to be&#xD;
             considered of non-childbearing potential) and their partners throughout the treatment&#xD;
             period and for at least three months following the last dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and willingness to sign a written informed consent form (the&#xD;
             consent form must be signed by the patient prior to any screening procedures).&#xD;
             Willingness and ability to comply with study procedures and follow-up examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any prior systemic MDM2-p53 inhibitor treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received chemotherapy within 21 days (42 days for nitrosoureas or mitomycin C) prior&#xD;
             to first dose&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Part 2 Cohort A: Prior loco-regional treatment with intralesional therapy (e.g.,&#xD;
             talimogene laherparepvec) for unresectable or metastatic melanoma in the last 6 weeks&#xD;
             prior to start of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Part 2 Cohort B: Has received radiation therapy to the lung that is &gt;30Gy within 6&#xD;
             months of the first dose of trial treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Part 2 Cohort E: Known FGFR translocation mutation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received hormonal and biologic, small molecule targeted therapies or other anti-cancer&#xD;
             therapy within 21 days prior to first dose&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiation or surgery within 14 days prior to first dose, thoracic radiation within 28&#xD;
             days prior to first dose&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has known active central nervous (CNS) metastases and/or carcinomatous meningitis. Or&#xD;
             has neurologic instability per clinical evaluation due to tumor involvement of the&#xD;
             CNS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Requirement for corticosteroid treatment (with the exception of megestrol and local&#xD;
             use of steroid: i.e., topical corticosteroids, inhaled corticosteroids for reactive&#xD;
             airway disease, ophthalmic, intraarticular, and intranasal steroids&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent treatment with an investigational agent or device within 21 days prior to&#xD;
             the first dose of therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure to recover adequately, as judged by the investigator, from prior surgical&#xD;
             procedures. Patients with active wound healing, patients who have had major surgery&#xD;
             within 28 days from 1st dose of study treatment, and patients who have had minor&#xD;
             surgery within 14 days from 1st dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unstable angina, myocardial infarction, or a coronary revascularization procedure&#xD;
             within 180 days of study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active rheumatoid arthritis (RA), active inflammatory bowel disease, chronic&#xD;
             infections, or any other disease or condition associated with chronic inflammation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection requiring systemic antibiotic/ antifungal medication, and known&#xD;
             clinically active viral infection such as hepatitis B or C, HIV infection, or active&#xD;
             COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled concurrent illness including, but not limited to: symptomatic congestive&#xD;
             heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric&#xD;
             illness/social situations that would limit compliance with the study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an active autoimmune disease, or a documented history of autoimmune disease, or a&#xD;
             syndrome, that requires systemic steroids or immunosuppressive agents. Subjects with&#xD;
             vitiligo or resolved childhood asthma/atopy would be exception to this rule. Subjects&#xD;
             that require intermittent use of bronchodilators or local steroid injections are not&#xD;
             excluded from the study. Subjects with hypothyroidism stable on hormone replacement&#xD;
             are not excluded from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received a live vaccine within 30 days prior to first dose. Note that killed&#xD;
             vaccines, mRNA vaccines, and non-live attenuated vaccines (i.e., for the SARS-Cov-2&#xD;
             virus or COVID-19) are allowed for patients on study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has had an allogeneic tissue/solid organ transplant, prior stem cell or bone marrow&#xD;
             transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of (non-infectious) pneumonitis that required steroids or current&#xD;
             pneumonitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has previously had a severe hypersensitivity reaction to treatment with another&#xD;
             monoclonal antibody (mAb)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition or circumstance that would, in the opinion of the investigator,&#xD;
             make the patient unsuitable for participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of organ transplant requiring use of immunosuppressive medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A woman of childbearing potential who has a positive urine pregnancy test (within 72&#xD;
             hours) prior to treatment. If the urine test is positive or cannot be confirmed as&#xD;
             negative, a serum pregnancy test will be required.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yifan Zhai, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Ascentage Pharma Group Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kathryn Shantz</last_name>
    <phone>301-802-3414</phone>
    <email>kate.shantz@ascentage.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Arizona Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tucson</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85724</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Montaser Shaheen</last_name>
      <phone>520-626-5972</phone>
      <email>shaheenm@email.arizona.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Montaser Shaheen, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Highlands Oncology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rogers</city>
        <state>Arkansas</state>
        <zip>72703</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Allie Pittman, MD</last_name>
      <phone>479-695-4167</phone>
      <email>apittman@hogonc.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Thad Beck, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCLA Hematology &amp; Oncology Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90095</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rosleen Mala</last_name>
      <phone>310-794-3879</phone>
      <email>RMala@mednet.ucla.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bartosz Chmielowski, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's National Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Shari Walker</last_name>
      <phone>202-476-2802</phone>
      <email>dvl@childrensnational.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>AeRang Kim, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sarah Cannon/FCSRI</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Myers</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33908</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Joseph Morris</last_name>
      <phone>845-661-4479</phone>
      <email>Joseph.Morris@FLCancer.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>James Reeves, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington University School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michele Landeau</last_name>
      <phone>314-747-9488</phone>
      <email>landeaum@wustl.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Brian Van Tine, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sujana Movva</last_name>
      <email>movvas@mskcc.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sujana Movva, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Penn State Hershey Medical Center Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hershey</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>17033</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Barbara Husic</last_name>
      <phone>717-531-5471</phone>
      <email>bhusic@pennstatehealth.psu.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joseph Drabick, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Thomas Jefferson University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19107</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carolyn Palumbo</last_name>
      <phone>215-955-9980</phone>
      <email>carolyn.palumbo@jefferson.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marlana Orloff, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sarah Cannon Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37203</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <phone>844-482-4812</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Meredith McKean, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gracy Zacharian</last_name>
      <email>gzachari@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Neeta Somaiah, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Next Oncology</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anthony Tolcher</last_name>
      <phone>210-580-9500</phone>
      <email>atolcher@nextoncology.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anthony Tolcher, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Virginia Cancer Specialists</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fairfax</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>22031</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carrie Friedman</last_name>
      <email>Carrie.Friedman@usoncology.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alexander Spira, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Metro South Hospital and Health Services via Princess Alexandra Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brisbane</city>
        <state>Queensland</state>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Steve Turner</last_name>
      <phone>+61 7 3443 7288</phone>
      <email>trials@tri.edu.au</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kenneth O'Byrne</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Queensland Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>South Brisbane</city>
        <state>Queensland</state>
        <zip>4101</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Steve Foresto</last_name>
      <phone>+61 7 3068 1111</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Steven Foresto</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Flinders Medical Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bedford Park</city>
        <state>South Australia</state>
        <zip>5042</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alison Richards</last_name>
      <phone>82046200</phone>
      <email>Alison.richards@sa.gov.au</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christos Karapetis</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 27, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 27, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 2, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>pembrolizumab</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liposarcoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nerve Sheath Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neurofibrosarcoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

