<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03613896</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>hadeer's protocol</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03613896</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Accuracy of 3D Printed Maxillary Complete Dentures</brief_title>
  <official_title>Accuracy of 3D Printed Maxillary Complete Dentures Compared With Conventional Complete Dentures: Non-Randomized Control Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Conventional complete dentures have been used for almost a century as a treatment choice for&#xD;
      edentulous patients, despite of their inaccuracy &amp; dimensional changes during manufacturing.&#xD;
      Recently, new manufacturing techniques like RP/3D printing (rapid prototyping) has progressed&#xD;
      in the dental field including prosthodontics, does the 3D printed complete denture show more&#xD;
      accuracy than conventional ones?&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Conventional complete dentures have been used as a clinically accepted prosthetic treatment&#xD;
      for completely edentulous patients for almost a century. [1] One of its advantages is ability&#xD;
      to customize teeth arrangement and to check each step of the preceding steps before the&#xD;
      delivery stage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conventional complete dentures fabrication consist of several steps of recording,&#xD;
      transferring, evaluating, and creating artificial substitutes for patient's teeth and gingiva&#xD;
      which must be in harmony with patient's mouth and face. All this steps demand high&#xD;
      experience, artistic, and skillful operator and technician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However denture processing results in polymerization shrinkage of the resin (due to flask&#xD;
      cooling), and distortion of the denture base (due to stress release after denture base&#xD;
      removal from the stone cast), and decreasing the accuracy and denture adaptation. [2] These&#xD;
      dimensional changes increase the gap between the denture base and underlying mucosa,&#xD;
      resulting in an ill-fitting denture.[3] Denture adaptation and fitting plays a crucial role&#xD;
      in complete denture retention (by physical means), stability, and patient comfort. [4]&#xD;
&#xD;
      Also, flask closure must be done under considerable pressure to ensure metal-to-metal contact&#xD;
      between the halves of the flask to confine the resin inside the mold with no excess.[5] In&#xD;
      addition to the inherent processing shrinkage and/or expansion properties of the acrylic&#xD;
      resin.[6] Researchers tried to overcome these disadvantages by changing the technique of&#xD;
      polymerization of the resin, by using of microwave energy, dry heat, and visible light.[7]&#xD;
      But unfortunately researchers found that, Discrepancies in the base adaptation shown by&#xD;
      several techniques are not easily corrected after complete denture processing.[8] Denture&#xD;
      base adaptation to the stone cast is usually not satisfactory, especially in the midline&#xD;
      section of the central portion of the posterior border.[9] To overcome the previous&#xD;
      disadvantages computer aided manufacturing technology was applied to complete dentures. Some&#xD;
      advantages of digitally fabricated complete dentures are 1) reduced number of patient visits;&#xD;
      2) superior strength and fit of dentures; 3) omitting multiple error-introducing steps such&#xD;
      as impression, waxing, and casting.[10] 4) reduced cost for patient and clinician; 5) easy&#xD;
      denture duplication (due to stored digital data); 6) standardization of clinical research on&#xD;
      complete dentures and implant-retained overdentures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To fabricate physical prototype (model) there are two different approaches: subtractive and&#xD;
      additive manufacturing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subtractive manufacturing is based on milling the denture from a larger blank by a computer&#xD;
      numeric controlled (CNC) machine. The input data for this method are principally from an&#xD;
      optical or contact probe digitizer, which can only capture the external surface data of the&#xD;
      anatomy and not the internal tissue surface of the object.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although CAD/CAM dentures have many advantages compared to conventional ones, but the CAD/CAM&#xD;
      protocol introduces additional steps (like scanning, software modeling, and milling) in the&#xD;
      fabrication process that can lead to inaccuracies.[11] Another disadvantage of CAD/CAM is its&#xD;
      inability to reproduce fine details by milling .[12] Additive manufacturing is the process&#xD;
      that creates objects from 3D model data, in an additive layer by layer manner.[13] The&#xD;
      additive systems used in dentistry are stereo-lithography, selective laser sintering or&#xD;
      melting, and 3D printing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main advantage of additive technology is the ability to create minor details (undercuts,&#xD;
      voids, complex internal geometries) in the proposed model. In addition to Incremental&#xD;
      vertical object build-up, no material wastage, large objects produced, passive production&#xD;
      (i.e., no force application), and ability to print multiple materials at the same time (in&#xD;
      case of 3D printing). [15] A clinical study was done to compare the accuracy values of&#xD;
      maxillary conventional heat-polymerized trial denture bases with those RR printed ones and&#xD;
      the results were as follows: Mean deviation was (-0.0051mm), (SD, 0.19mm).[16]&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the same study authors used ratings from 100-mm VAS in 10 patients and 20 prosthodontists&#xD;
      comparing conventional and RP methods and the results were as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients comparing overall satisfaction: P=0.59, prosthodontists comparing overall&#xD;
      satisfaction: P=0.87 The term selective laser sintering is used to describe the fabrication&#xD;
      of a pattern from ceramics or polymers while selective laser melting describes pattern&#xD;
      fabrication from metal.[14] The laser beam locally raises the temperature close to the&#xD;
      melting point of the metal particle, to avoid complete melting. The platform is slightly&#xD;
      immersed in the powder, and powder thickness is controlled by a cylinder rolling on the&#xD;
      powder pool. After each new powder layer application, the laser melting process is repeated&#xD;
      until the 3D object is completed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stereo lithography technology consists of photosensitive resin bath, a model-building&#xD;
      platform, and ultraviolet laser for curing. To fabricate the desired model the layers are&#xD;
      cured successively, and bonded together from bottom to top. As the first layer is polymerized&#xD;
      the model-building platform is brought down inside the bath, and another layer of resin is&#xD;
      added and cured. This process continues until the desired model is completed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In 3D printing system the material is extruded from a nozzle that solidifies as soon as it is&#xD;
      deposited on the manufacturing platform. The layer pattern is achieved through horizontal&#xD;
      nozzle movement and interrupted material flow. This is followed by vertical movement for the&#xD;
      sequential layer deposition.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The captured 3D data of model slice into cross-sections by a certain thickness. Inputting the&#xD;
      processing parameters based on the contour information of each layer sheet allows for the&#xD;
      automatic generation of the numerical code. Finally, a 3D object consisting of a series of&#xD;
      layers is formed by stacking. This technology can receive CAD data directly and create new&#xD;
      samples or models quickly without need for molds, cutting tools, or tooling fixtures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thanks to this technology, wasting less material, employing less human power, decreasing&#xD;
      treatment time at the chair side, decreasing treatment cost, and lowering the rates of&#xD;
      contamination, is possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, a combination of conventional technique and RP will be used to fabricate&#xD;
      complete dentures to overcome the polymerization shrinkage which results from conventional&#xD;
      processing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Explanation for choice of comparators:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Heat processed denture base is the treatment of choice for most of edentulous patients and it&#xD;
      is considered as the golden standard and the main comparator for the new techniques. But&#xD;
      using Heat Cured Acrylic resin would require many laboratory steps which introduce several&#xD;
      errors.[14] Meanwhile, the introduction of rapid prototyping method with high accuracy which&#xD;
      eliminates some of the laboratory steps was the reason for choosing it to compare it with the&#xD;
      conventional method&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy in terms of dimensional changes in denture base</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after denture construction</time_frame>
    <description>we will use radio-opaque markers to measure accuracy on software</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">13</enrollment>
  <condition>Accuracy of 3d Printed Dentures</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>conventional dentures</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>a complete denture made through conventional processing technique</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>3D printed dentures</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>a complete denture made through 3d printing</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>conventional dentures</intervention_name>
    <description>conventional dentures</description>
    <arm_group_label>conventional dentures</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>3d printed denture</intervention_name>
    <description>construction of a 3d printed denture through a recent method instead of conventional heat processing</description>
    <arm_group_label>3D printed dentures</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cooperative patients with well developed ridges..&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pathological changes of residual ridges.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any systemic diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with xerostomia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with flabby and flat ridges.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with allergy to resins.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with sever undercuts, or irregular bony exostosis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hadeer mohamed olaiwa, masters</last_name>
    <phone>01024455385</phone>
    <email>hadir2015@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>August 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 5, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 2, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 2, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 2, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Hadeer mohamed mohamed</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

