<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03858972</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ODO-TE-B201</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03858972</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Tesetaxel Plus Reduced Dose of Capecitabine in Patients With HER2 Negative, HR Positive, LA/MBC</brief_title>
  <acronym>CONTESSA 2</acronym>
  <official_title>Multinational, Multicenter, Phase 2 Study of Tesetaxel Plus a Reduced Dose of Capecitabine in Patients With HER2 Negative, Hormone Receptor Positive, Locally Advanced or Metastatic Breast Cancer Who Have Not Previously Received a Taxane</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Odonate Therapeutics, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Odonate Therapeutics, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      CONTESSA 2 is a multinational, multicenter, Phase 2 study of tesetaxel in patients with HER2&#xD;
      negative, HR positive, locally advanced or metastatic breast cancer (LA/MBC) not previously&#xD;
      treated with a taxane. The primary objective of the study is to establish the efficacy of&#xD;
      tesetaxel plus a reduced dose of capecitabine based on objective response rate (ORR) as&#xD;
      assessed by an Independent Radiologic Review Committee (IRC). 152 patients were enrolled.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      CONTESSA 2 is a multinational, multicenter, Phase 2 study of tesetaxel, an investigational,&#xD;
      orally administered taxane, in patients with HER2 negative, HR Positive, LA/MBC not&#xD;
      previously treated with a taxane in the neoadjuvant, adjuvant or metastatic setting. This&#xD;
      Study complements CONTESSA, a multinational, multicenter, randomized, Phase 3 study in&#xD;
      patients with HER2 negative, HR positive LA/MBC previously treated with a taxane in the&#xD;
      neoadjuvant or adjuvant setting. 152 patients were enrolled, including 149 who received&#xD;
      treatment. Patients are administered tesetaxel at 27 mg/m2 orally once every 21 days on the&#xD;
      first day of each 21-day cycle plus capecitabine at 825 mg/m2 orally twice daily (for a total&#xD;
      daily dose of 1,650 mg/m2) for 14 days of each 21-day cycle. Patients in the dense&#xD;
      pharmacokinetics (PK) cohort receive a single dose of capecitabine monotherapy prior to&#xD;
      starting the combination regimen. Capecitabine is an oral chemotherapy agent that is&#xD;
      considered a standard-of-care treatment in LA/MBC. The primary efficacy endpoint is ORR as&#xD;
      assessed by the IRC. The secondary efficacy endpoints are duration of response (DoR) as&#xD;
      assessed by the IRC, progression-free survival (PFS) as assessed by the IRC, disease control&#xD;
      rate (DCR) as assessed by the IRC and overall survival (OS). CONTESSA 2 also investigates the&#xD;
      PK of tesetaxel.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    The Sponsor has discontinued the development of tesetaxel&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 5, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 11, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 11, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ORR as assessed by the IRC</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2.0-2.5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>DoR as assessed by the IRC</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2.0-2.5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PFS as assessed by the IRC</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2.0-2.5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>DCR as assessed by the IRC</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2.0-2.5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>OS</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 3.0-3.5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Central nervous system (CNS) ORR as assessed by the CNS IRC in patients with CNS metastases at baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2.0-2.5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CNS DoR as assessed by the CNS IRC in patients with CNS metastases at baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2.0-2.5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CNS PFS as assessed by the CNS IRC in patients with CNS metastases at baseline or a history of CNS metastases and in the intent-to-treat (ITT) population</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2.0-2.5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CNS OS in patients with CNS metastases at baseline or a history of CNS metastases</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 3.0-3.5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events, including deaths and other serious adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 3.0-3.5 years</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of clinical laboratory abnormalities (e.g., CBC, serum chemistry and coagulation testing)</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 3.0-3.5 years</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Peak plasma concentration (Cmax) of tesetaxel</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2.0-2.5 years</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve (AUC) of tesetaxel</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2.0-2.5 years</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The effect of tesetaxel on capecitabine and 5-FU Cmax</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2.0-2.5 years</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The effect of tesetaxel on capecitabine and 5-FU AUC</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2.0-2.5 years</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">152</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Tesetaxel (oral) and capecitabine (oral)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cohort 1: Tesetaxel (27 mg/m2) once every 21 days on Day 1 of each 21-day cycle; and capecitabine (825 mg/m2) twice daily (total daily dose of 1,650 mg/m2) beginning with the evening dose on Day 1 through the morning dose on Day 15 of each 21-day cycle.&#xD;
Cohort 2: On Cycle 1, Day -1, either a single morning dose of capecitabine at 825 mg/m2 (Cohort 2A) or 1,250 mg/m2 (Cohort 2B). On Cycle 1, Day 1, a single dose of tesetaxel (27 mg/m2), followed 2 hours later by capecitabine (825 mg/m2), followed by an evening dose of capecitabine (825 mg/m2). Capecitabine (825 mg/m2) twice daily (total daily dose of 1,650 mg/m2) beginning with the morning dose on Day 2 through evening dose on Day 14 of Cycle 1. Starting with Cycle 2, tesetaxel (27 mg/m2) once every 21 days on Day 1 of each 21-day cycle; and capecitabine (825 mg/m2) twice daily (total daily dose of 1,650 mg/m2) beginning with the evening dose on Day 1 through the morning dose on Day 15 of each 21-day cycle.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tesetaxel</intervention_name>
    <description>Tesetaxel plus reduced dose of capecitabine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Tesetaxel (oral) and capecitabine (oral)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Capecitabine</intervention_name>
    <description>Reduced dose of capecitabine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Tesetaxel (oral) and capecitabine (oral)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Female or male patients at least 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Histologically or cytologically confirmed breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. HER2 negative disease based on local testing: American Society of Clinical&#xD;
             Oncology/College of American Pathologists (ASCO/CAP) guidelines should be utilized for&#xD;
             assessing HER2 status&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. HR (ER and/or PgR) positive disease based on local testing: ASCO/CAP guidelines should&#xD;
             be utilized for assessing HR status&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Measurable disease per RECIST 1.1, including bone-only disease with measurable lytic&#xD;
             component.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Patients with bone-only metastatic cancer must have a measurable lytic or mixed&#xD;
             lytic-blastic lesion that can be accurately assessed by computed tomography (CT) or&#xD;
             magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). Patients with bone-only disease without a measurable&#xD;
             lytic component (ie, blastic-only metastasis) are not eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Known metastases to the CNS are permitted but not required. The following criteria&#xD;
             apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients must be neurologically stable and either off corticosteroids or&#xD;
                  currently treated with a maximum daily dose of 4 mg of dexamethasone (or&#xD;
                  equivalent), with no increase in corticosteroid dose within 7 days prior to&#xD;
                  Enrollment (defined as the time of Sponsor approval of treatment dose)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with a history of CNS metastases but with no current evidence of CNS&#xD;
                  lesions following local therapy are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients may have CNS metastases that are stable or progressing radiologically&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with current evidence of leptomeningeal disease are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients may have untreated brain metastases or previously treated brain&#xD;
                  metastases, as long as no immediate local CNS-directed therapy is indicated&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any prior whole brain radiation therapy must have been completed &gt; 14 days prior&#xD;
                  to the date of Enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prior stereotactic brain radiosurgery is permitted&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CNS surgical resection must have been completed &gt; 28 days prior to the date of&#xD;
                  Enrollment; patient must have complete recovery from surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0, 1, or 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Prior endocrine therapy with or without a CDK 4/6 inhibitor unless endocrine therapy&#xD;
             is not indicated (ie, short relapse-free interval while on adjuvant endocrine therapy&#xD;
             [endocrine resistance]; rapidly progressing disease/visceral crisis; or endocrine&#xD;
             intolerance). Any targeted therapies approved for HER2 negative, HR positive LA/MBC,&#xD;
             including everolimus, are permitted as prior therapy. There is no limit to the number&#xD;
             of prior endocrine therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Documented (including de novo): (a) locally advanced breast cancer that is not&#xD;
             considered curable by surgery and/or radiation; or (b) metastatic breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Adequate hematologic, hepatic and renal function, as evidenced by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1,500/μL without colony-stimulating factor&#xD;
                  support&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count ≥ 100,000/μL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 10 g/dL without need for hematopoietic growth factor or transfusion&#xD;
                  support&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin &lt; 1.5 × upper limit of normal (ULN); does not apply to patients&#xD;
                  with Gilbert's syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &lt; 3 × ULN unless hepatic metastases are present&#xD;
                  then &lt; 5 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &lt; 3 × ULN unless hepatic metastases are present&#xD;
                  then &lt; 5 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alkaline phosphatase &lt; 2.5 × ULN unless hepatic metastases are present then &lt; 5 ×&#xD;
                  ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 50 mL/min (by Cockcroft-Gault formula or local&#xD;
                  standard)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum albumin ≥ 3.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prothrombin time (PT) &lt; 1.5 × ULN or international normalized ratio (INR) &lt; 1.3&#xD;
                  and partial thromboplastin time (PTT) &lt; 1.5 × ULN, unless the patient is on a&#xD;
                  therapeutic anticoagulant&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Complete recovery to baseline or Grade 1 per National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common&#xD;
             Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 5.0 from adverse effects of&#xD;
             prior surgery, radiotherapy, endocrine therapy, and other therapy, as applicable, with&#xD;
             the exception of Grade 2 alopecia from prior chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Ability to swallow an oral solid-dosage form of medication&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. A negative serum pregnancy test within 7 days prior to the first dose of Study&#xD;
             treatment in women of childbearing potential (ie, all women except those who are post&#xD;
             menopause for ≥ 1 year or who have a history of hysterectomy or surgical&#xD;
             sterilization)&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Women of childbearing potential must use an effective, non-hormonal form of&#xD;
             contraception from Screening throughout the Treatment Phase and until 70 days after&#xD;
             the last dose of Study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acceptable methods include: copper intrauterine device or double barrier methods,&#xD;
                  including male/female condoms with spermicide and use of contraceptive sponge,&#xD;
                  cervical cap, or diaphragm&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Male patients must use an effective, non-hormonal form of contraception from Screening&#xD;
             throughout the Treatment Phase and until 130 days after the last dose of Study&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acceptable methods include: male/female condoms with spermicide, or vasectomy&#xD;
                  with medical confirmation of surgical success&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Written informed consent and authorization to use and disclose health information&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Ability to comprehend and comply with the requirements of the Study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Two or more prior chemotherapy regimens for advanced disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Prior treatment with a taxane at any dose&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Prior treatment with capecitabine at any dose&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Current evidence of leptomeningeal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Other cancer that required therapy within the preceding 5 years other than adequately&#xD;
             treated: (a) non-melanoma skin cancer or in situ cancer; or (b) following approval by&#xD;
             the Medical Monitor, other cancer that has a very low risk of interfering with the&#xD;
             safety or efficacy endpoints of the Study&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Known human immunodeficiency virus infection, unless well controlled. Patients who are&#xD;
             on an adequate antiviral regimen with no evidence of active infection are considered&#xD;
             well controlled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Active hepatitis B or active hepatitis C infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Other severe acute or chronic medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory&#xD;
             abnormality that may increase the risk associated with Study participation or&#xD;
             investigational product administration or may interfere with the interpretation of&#xD;
             Study results and, in the judgment of the Investigator, would make the patient&#xD;
             inappropriate for entry into this Study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Presence of neuropathy &gt; Grade 1 per NCI CTCAE version 5.0&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Anticancer treatment, including endocrine therapy, radiotherapy (except stereotactic&#xD;
             brain radiosurgery), chemotherapy, biologic therapy, or therapy in an investigational&#xD;
             clinical study, ≤ 14 days prior to the date of Enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Major surgery ≤ 28 days prior to the date of Enrollment; patient must have complete&#xD;
             recovery from surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Less than 2 weeks or 5 plasma half-lives (whichever is greater) since last use of a&#xD;
             medication or ingestion of an agent, beverage, or food that is a known clinically&#xD;
             relevant strong inhibitor or known clinically relevant inducer of the cytochrome P450&#xD;
             (CYP)3A pathway (patients should discontinue taking any regularly-taken medication&#xD;
             that is a strong inhibitor or inducer of the CYP3A pathway)&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. History of hypersensitivity or unexpected reactions to capecitabine, fluoropyrimidine&#xD;
             agents or any of their ingredients&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Known dihydropyrimidine dehydrogenase (DPD) deficiency. Testing for DPD deficiency&#xD;
             must be performed where required by local regulations, using a validated method that&#xD;
             is approved by local health authorities.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. If, in the opinion of the Investigator, the patient is deemed unwilling or unable to&#xD;
             comply with the requirements of the Study&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Treatment with brivudine, sorivudine, or its chemically-related analogs ≤ 28 days&#xD;
             prior to the date of Enrollment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joseph O'Connell, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Odonate Therapeutics, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Innovative Clinical Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Whittier</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90603</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rocky Mountain Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lakewood</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80228</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sarah Cannon Research Institute - Florida Cancer Specialists</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Myers</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33901</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Florida Cancer Specialists and Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Petersburg</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33705</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>New York Cancer and Blood Specialists</name>
      <address>
        <city>East Setauket</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11733</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>West Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Germantown</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>38138</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Oncology - Baylor Charles A. Sammons Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75246</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Virginia Oncology Associates</name>
      <address>
        <city>Norfolk</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23502</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Border Medical Oncology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Albury</city>
        <state>New South Wales</state>
        <zip>2640</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hopital Maisonneuve-Rosemont</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montréal</city>
        <zip>H1T 4B3</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Center Hospitalier de Montreal CHUM McPeak Sirois</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montréal</city>
        <zip>H2X 3E4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CIUSSS de Centre-Ouest-de-l'Île-de-Montréal Jewish General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montréal</city>
        <zip>H3T IE2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>McGill University Health Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montréal</city>
        <zip>H4J 3J1</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU de Quebec-University Laval</name>
      <address>
        <city>Québec</city>
        <zip>G1S 4L8</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Sherbrooke CIUSSS de lEstrie CHUS patyre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sherbrooke</city>
        <zip>J1H 5N4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kyungpook National University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Daegu</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Goyang</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gangnam Severance Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>06273</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Asan Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ajou University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Suwon</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Teresa Herrera Materno-Infantil (CHUAC)</name>
      <address>
        <city>A Coruña</city>
        <zip>15006</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fundacion Jimenez Diaz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28040</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Taiwan University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei City</city>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Koo Foundation Sun Yat-Sen Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 26, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 28, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 1, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Tesetaxel</keyword>
  <keyword>Capecitabine</keyword>
  <keyword>HER2 negative</keyword>
  <keyword>Combination of tesetaxel and capecitabine</keyword>
  <keyword>Taxane-naive</keyword>
  <keyword>Locally advanced or metastatic breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Hormone receptor positive</keyword>
  <keyword>Metastatic breast cancer (MBC)</keyword>
  <keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Central nervous system (CNS) metastases</keyword>
  <keyword>de novo metastatic breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Oral chemotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Taxane</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

