<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03852433</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MYR 204</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2019-001485-15</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03852433</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Assess Efficacy and Safety of Bulevirtide in Combination With Pegylated Interferon Alfa-2a in Participants With Chronic Hepatitis Delta (CHD)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Open-label, Randomized Phase 2b Clinical Study to Assess Efficacy and Safety of Bulevirtide in Combination With Pegylated Interferon Alfa-2a in Patients With Chronic Hepatitis Delta</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Gilead Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Gilead Sciences</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of bulevirtide combination&#xD;
      with pegylated interferon in participants with chronic hepatitis delta (CHD).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 31, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Sustained Virological Response 24 (SVR 24) Defined as Undetectable (&lt; limit of detection (LoD)) Hepatitis Delta Virus (HDV) Ribonucleic acid (RNA) at Week 24 after the Scheduled End of Treatment (Arms B, C and D Only)</measure>
    <time_frame>Posttreatment Week 24</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Undetectable HDV RNA at Week 48</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 48</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Undetectable HDV RNA at Week 96 (Arms B, C, and D Only)</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 96</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Combined Sustained Response at Week 24 After the Scheduled End of Treatment: Percentage of Participants With Undetectable HDV RNA or Decrease by ≥ 2 log10 IU/ml From Baseline and Alanine Transaminase (ALT) Normalization</measure>
    <time_frame>Posttreatment Week 24</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Combined Sustained Response at Week 48 After the Scheduled End of Treatment: Percentage of Participants With Undetectable HDV RNA or Decrease by ≥ 2 log10 IU/ml From Baseline and Alanine Transaminase (ALT) Normalization</measure>
    <time_frame>Posttreatment Week 48</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Sustained Virological Response 48 (SVR 48) Defined as Undetectable HDV RNA at Week 48 after the Scheduled End of Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Posttreatment Week 48</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Liver Stiffness as Measured by Elastography at Week 48</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 48</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Liver Stiffness as Measured by Elastography at Week 96</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 96</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Liver Stiffness as Measured by Elastography at Week 144</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 144</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants who Permanently Discontinue Study Drug due to an Adverse Event</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 144 Weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">175</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Hepatitis Delta</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pegylated Interferon alfa-2a (PEG-IFN alfa) (Arm A)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive PEG-IFN alfa 180 microgram (mcg) once a week for 48 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Bulevirtide 2 mg/day + PEG-IFN alfa (Arm B)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive bulevirtide 2 mg/day in combination with PEG-IFN alfa 180 mcg once a week for 48 weeks followed by bulevirtide 2 mg/day for 48 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Bulevirtide 10 mg/day + PEG-IFN alfa (Arm C)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive bulevirtide 10 mg/day in combination with PEG-IFN alfa 180 mcg once a week for 48 weeks followed by bulevirtide 10 mg/day for 48 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Bulevirtide 10 mg/day (Arm D)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive bulevirtide 10 mg/day for 96 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bulevirtide</intervention_name>
    <description>Administered via subcutaneous injections</description>
    <arm_group_label>Bulevirtide 10 mg/day (Arm D)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Bulevirtide 10 mg/day + PEG-IFN alfa (Arm C)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Bulevirtide 2 mg/day + PEG-IFN alfa (Arm B)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Myrcludex B</other_name>
    <other_name>Hepcludex®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Peginterferon Alfa-2a (PEG-IFN alfa)</intervention_name>
    <description>Administered via subcutaneous injections</description>
    <arm_group_label>Bulevirtide 10 mg/day + PEG-IFN alfa (Arm C)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Bulevirtide 2 mg/day + PEG-IFN alfa (Arm B)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pegylated Interferon alfa-2a (PEG-IFN alfa) (Arm A)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provision of signed and dated informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive serum hepatitis delta virus (HDV) antibody results or polymerase chain&#xD;
             reaction (PCR) results for serum/ plasma HDV RNA for at least 6 months before&#xD;
             screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive PCR results for serum/ plasma HDV RNA at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alanine transaminase level &gt;1 x upper limit of normal (ULN), but less than 10 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum albumin &gt;28 g/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thyroid stimulating hormone (TSH) within normal ranges (including on medication for&#xD;
             control of thyroid function)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative urine pregnancy test for females of childbearing potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inclusion criteria for female individuals:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Postmenopausal for at least 2 years, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Surgically sterile (total hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy, bilateral tubal&#xD;
                  ligation, staples, or another type of sterilization), or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Abstinence from heterosexual intercourse throughout the treatment period, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Willingness to use highly effective contraception (double barrier method or&#xD;
                  barrier contraception in combination with hormonal or intrauterine contraceptive)&#xD;
                  throughout the treatment period and for 6 months after the last dose of the study&#xD;
                  medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male individuals must agree to use a highly effective contraception (double barrier&#xD;
             method or barrier contraception in combination with hormonal or intrauterine&#xD;
             contraceptive used by female partners) and not to donate sperm throughout the&#xD;
             treatment period and for 6 months after the last dose of the study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Child-Pugh hepatic insufficiency score of B-C or over 6 points. Note: Child-Pugh&#xD;
             hepatic insufficiency score of 6 points is allowed. Only individuals with compensated&#xD;
             cirrhosis are allowed. Uncomplicated oesophageal varices allowed; individuals with&#xD;
             current bleeding or ligation, or history of bleeding or ligation within the last 2&#xD;
             years are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatitis C virus (HCV) or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) coinfection. Individuals&#xD;
             with HCV antibodies can be enrolled, if screening HCV RNA test is negative.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine clearance &lt; 60 mL/min as estimated using Cockcroft-Gault formula.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin ≥ 34.2 µmol/L. (Individuals with higher total bilirubin values may be&#xD;
             included after the consultation with the Study Medical Monitor, if such elevation can&#xD;
             be clearly attributed to Gilbert's syndrome associated with low-grade&#xD;
             hyperbilirubinemia.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of an active or suspected malignancy, or an untreated pre-malignancy&#xD;
             disorder, or a history of malignancy within the last 5 years (with the exception of&#xD;
             successfully treated carcinoma of the cervix in situ and successfully treated basal&#xD;
             cell carcinoma and squamous cell carcinoma not less than 1 year prior to screening&#xD;
             [and no more than 3 excised skin cancer within the last 5 years prior to screening])&#xD;
             or history of hepatic carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic connective tissue disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New York Heart Association (NYHA) class III-IV congestive heart failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with uncontrolled arterial hypertension: systolic blood pressure &gt; 150 mm&#xD;
             Hg and/ or diastolic blood pressure &gt; 100 mm Hg at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous or unstable concurrent diseases or conditions that prevent individual's&#xD;
             enrolment into the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with mental disorders or social circumstances that preclude them from&#xD;
             following protocol requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or previous decompensated liver disease, including coagulopathy, hepatic&#xD;
             encephalopathy and esophageal varices hemorrhage.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  One or more additional known primary or secondary causes of liver disease, other than&#xD;
             hepatitis B (e.g., alcoholism, autoimmune hepatitis, malignancy with hepatic&#xD;
             involvement, hemochromatosis, alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency, Wilson's Disease, other&#xD;
             congenital or metabolic conditions affecting the liver, congestive heart failure or&#xD;
             other severe cardiopulmonary disease, etc.). Gilbert's syndrome, a benign disorder&#xD;
             associated with low-grade hyperbilirubinemia, will not exclude individauls from&#xD;
             participation in this trial. Autoimmune hepatitis stigmata attributed to HDV infection&#xD;
             in the opinion of the investigator are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  White blood cells (WBC) count &lt; 3000 cells/mm^3 (&lt;1500 if African individuals).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count &lt; 1500 cells/mm^3 (&lt;1000 if African individuals).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &lt; 90,000 cells/mm^3.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Haemoglobin &lt; 12 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of prohibited psychotropic agents at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of interferons within 6 months before Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of solid organ transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current alcohol abuse or alcohol abuse within 6 months prior to enrolment in this&#xD;
             study; current drug addict or history of drug use within 2 years prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of disease requiring regular use of systemic glucocorticosteroids (inhalative&#xD;
             glucocorticosteroids are allowed) or other immunosuppressants.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast-feeding females.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in another clinical study with investigational drugs within 30 days&#xD;
             prior to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of bulevirtide previously, e.g. in clinical trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to follow protocol requirements and undergo all protocol procedures. Note:&#xD;
             Individuals with medical contraindication for liver biopsy are allowed to participate&#xD;
             in this study. Such individuals will exempt from liver biopsy requirements in this&#xD;
             study. Individuals receiving prohibited treatment at screening cannot be included into&#xD;
             the study unless this treatment is withdrawn prior to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindications, intolerance or hypersensitivity to interferons alfa, genetically&#xD;
             engineered E.coli medications, polyethylene glycol or other components of&#xD;
             peginterferon alfa-2а.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence or history of severe retinopathy, significant diabetic or hypertensive&#xD;
             retinopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled cardiovascular disorders within 6 months before screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of autoimmune disorder (e.g. myositis, hepatitis, thrombotic thrombocytopenic&#xD;
             purpura, idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura, severe psoriasis, rheumatoid arthritis,&#xD;
             interstitial nephritis, thyroiditis, and systemic lupus erythematosus)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence or history of significant psychiatric disorder (e.g. severe depression,&#xD;
             suicide attempt, severe neurosis or cognitive disorder).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence or history of chronic lung disease with respiratory malfunction.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gilead Study Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Gilead Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Beaujon-Pavillon Abrami -Sce Hépatologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Clichy</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Grenoble Alpes</name>
      <address>
        <city>Grenoble</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Croix Rousee</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lione</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Saint Joseph Hépato-Gastroentérologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Marseille</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CH Pitié-Salpétrière - Hépato-Gastroentérologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Cochin - Unité d'Hépatologie Pavillon Achard</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Infectious Clinical Hospital &quot;T. Ciorba&quot;, Department 4 / Medical University Department of Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chisinau</city>
        <country>Moldova, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Infectious Clinical Hospital &quot;T. Ciorba&quot;, Department 5 / Medical University Department of Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chisinau</city>
        <country>Moldova, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>&quot;Matei Bals&quot; National Institute of Infectious Diseases, Hospital department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bucharest</city>
        <country>Romania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>&quot;Matei Bals&quot; National Institute of Infectious Diseases,Clinical Trials department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bucharest</city>
        <country>Romania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>&quot;Victor Babes&quot; Centre of Diagnostic and Treatment</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bucharest</city>
        <country>Romania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dr. V. Babes Clinical Hospital of Infectious and Tropical Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bucharest</city>
        <country>Romania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State Budgetary Educational Institution of Higher Professional Education &quot;South Ural State Medical University&quot; of the Ministry of Healthcare of the Russian Federation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chelyabinsk</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Specialized clinical Infectious diseases Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Krasnodar</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Federal Budget Institute of Science &quot;Central Research Institute for Epidemiology&quot; of Federal Service on Consumers Rights Protection and Human Well-Being Surveillance</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Federal State Budgetary Institution National Research Medical Center for Phthisiopulmonology and Infectious Diseases of the Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>LLC&quot;Clinic of Modern Medicine&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Moscow Regional Scientific and Research Clinical Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>N.V.Sklifosovsky Scientific Research Institute of Emergency care of the Moscow Healthcare Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>LLC Medical Company &quot;Hepatolog&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Samara</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Moldova, Republic of</country>
    <country>Romania</country>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 21, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 21, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 25, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis D</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2a</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

