<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03852368</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017-3836</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03852368</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effects of Exercise on Executive Functions</brief_title>
  <official_title>UC Reliance# 3107: Exercise and the Brain: Measuring Executive Functions During and Following an Acute Bout of Aerobic Exercise</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, Irvine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Irvine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this research is to develop an assessment protocol that can be used to study&#xD;
      the effect of different intensities of exercise on executive functions (EF: attention,&#xD;
      working memory, inhibition, and cognitive flexibility). It has been shown that exercise has&#xD;
      the potential to improve the development of EF in healthy and special needs children.&#xD;
      However, many exercise interventions in the literature lack rigorous control of critical&#xD;
      components, such as intensity, making it difficult to draw conclusions about what type and&#xD;
      how much exercise might be most beneficial for EF. In addition, to date, no studies have been&#xD;
      able to demonstrate the engagement of EF during exercise. This study will focus on developing&#xD;
      an assay that measures important self-regulation or EF sub-processes (e.g., attention and&#xD;
      inhibitory control) as well as examining engagement of these targets during different&#xD;
      exercise intensities. Participants will exercise in different intensities on a cycle&#xD;
      ergometer and perform cognitive assessments before, during, and after exercise to evaluate&#xD;
      EF. This research will allow us to develop an assessment protocol that can be used in future&#xD;
      research to understand the underlying mechanisms underpinning the effects of exercise on EF.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Self-regulation, self-control, and executive functioning are umbrella constructs that&#xD;
      encompass processes involved in exerting control over cognitive and behavioral processes.&#xD;
      Self-regulation was described as an ability reflecting mature cognition: Mature cognition is&#xD;
      characterized by abilities that include being able: (a) to hold information in mind,&#xD;
      including complicated representational structures, to mentally manipulate that information&#xD;
      and to act on the basis of it, (b) to act on the basis of choice rather than impulse,&#xD;
      exercising self-control (or self-regulation) by resisting inappropriate behaviors and&#xD;
      responding appropriately, and (c) to quickly and flexibly adapt behavior to changing&#xD;
      situations. These abilities are referred to respectively as working memory, inhibition, and&#xD;
      cognitive flexibility. Together they are key components of both &quot;cognitive control&quot; and&#xD;
      &quot;executive functions…&quot; Some researchers have proposed an integrative framework of&#xD;
      self-regulation than encompasses executive functions and self-control. Thus, in this&#xD;
      proposal, we have adopted such an integrative framework whereby self-regulation encompasses&#xD;
      executive functions, self-control, and other sub-processes. As noted in the specific aims,&#xD;
      our meta-analysis and narrative review examining the impact of 28 physical activity (PA) and&#xD;
      exercise interventions on EF outcomes in healthy children reported that the targets often&#xD;
      shown to improve after exercise were attention, working memory, inhibition, and cognitive&#xD;
      flexibility, and preliminary research suggests the strongest effects are on attention and&#xD;
      inhibition. The goal of this project is to develop an assay to examine engagement of&#xD;
      attention and inhibitory control across several rigorously controlled exercise conditions.&#xD;
      This proposal is built on an integrative framework whereby self-regulation encompasses&#xD;
      executive functions (EF), self-control, and other sub-processes. Although there is a growing&#xD;
      awareness of the benefits of exercise on self-regulatory processes in children including EF,&#xD;
      there are still many critical gaps in the research. A recent publication which is a&#xD;
      meta-analysis and narrative review examining the impact of 28 physical activity and exercise&#xD;
      interventions on EF outcomes in healthy children that highlights some of these gaps. Although&#xD;
      earlier results showed that interventions had a significant, small to moderate positive&#xD;
      effect on EF, the effects varied widely across studies. This research informed this&#xD;
      application in several ways. First, no study demonstrated how or why the interventions&#xD;
      improved EF outcomes. Additionally, the behavioral assays or measures varied widely targeting&#xD;
      numerous components of EF. The EF targets most often shown to improve after exercise were&#xD;
      attention, working memory, inhibition, and cognitive flexibility (each improved in at least&#xD;
      five of the included studies). These findings are consistent with recent work at the UC&#xD;
      Irvine Pediatric Exercise and Genomics Research Center (PERC); in studies with healthy&#xD;
      children and children with special needs, improvements were found after exercise in all four&#xD;
      components. Few, if any, studies have been able to demonstrate empirically why participants&#xD;
      exhibit improvements in EF after exercise, and studies have not yet demonstrated engagement&#xD;
      of EF during exercise. Thus, there is a need to understand why exercise seems to improve&#xD;
      these targets. However, the tools used in exercise research to date are limited. Many have&#xD;
      been adopted from developmental or educational research, rather than developed specifically&#xD;
      to test targets in exercise research; our search yielded only one published measure of&#xD;
      self-regulation (cognitive, affective, and motor self-regulation) that has been administered&#xD;
      during physical activity. This proposal begins to address these gaps in the literature, by&#xD;
      focusing on the development of an assay for important EF targets are improved through&#xD;
      exercise and by testing engagement of these targets during exercise of varying intensity&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Nonapplicable clinical trial&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 6, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 6, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 6, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Effects of Light, Moderate and Heavy Exercise on Attention</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Attention will be tested with the Hearts and Flowers test</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Effects of Light, Moderate and Heavy Exercise on Working Memory</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Working Memory will be tested with the Hearts and Flowers test</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Effects of Light, Moderate and Heavy Exercise on Inhibition</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Inhibition will be tested with Stroop Color-Word test</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Effects of Light, Moderate and Heavy Exercise on Cognitive Flexibility</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Cognitive Flexibility will be tested with Stroop Color-Word test</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Effects of Light, Moderate and Heavy Exercise on temporal dynamics of executive function processes</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The temporal dynamics of executive function processes will be measured with EEG/Event-Related Potential (ERP) test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>The Effects of Exercise on Executive Functions</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The Effects of Light Exercise in Executive Functions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The effects of light exercise in executive functions of adolescents</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The Effects of Moderate Exercise in Executive Functions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The effects of moderate exercise in executive functions of adolescents</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The Effects of Heavy Exercise in Executive Functions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The effects of heavy exercise in executive functions of adolescents</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exercise</intervention_name>
    <description>The effects of exercise with different intensity on the executive functions of adolescents</description>
    <arm_group_label>The Effects of Heavy Exercise in Executive Functions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>The Effects of Light Exercise in Executive Functions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>The Effects of Moderate Exercise in Executive Functions</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of health problems that would preclude participation in exercise&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female between the ages of 10-15 years inclusive at the time of consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minimum level of intellectual functioning, as determined by an IQ (based on cognitive&#xD;
             testing) score of 80 or above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to complete EF testing in English&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other limitations which in the opinion of a physician would preclude ability to&#xD;
             perform exercise testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of illegal drugs or abuse of alcohol based on self-report during screening (this&#xD;
             will occur during the one-on-one brief psychological evaluation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or breastfeeding based on urine sample test&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pediatric Exercise and Genomics Research Center, University of California, Irvine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Irvine</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92697/92617</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 21, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 21, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 25, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

