<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03850795</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HC1119-CS-03</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03850795</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>HC-1119 Versus Enzalutamide in Metastatic Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer (mCRPC)</brief_title>
  <official_title>PROCADE: A Multinational Phase 3, Randomized, Double-Blind, Non-inferiority, Efficacy and Safety Study of Oral HC-1119 Versus Enzalutamide in Metastatic Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer (mCRPC)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hinova Pharmaceuticals USA, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hinova Pharmaceuticals USA, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a multinational Phase 3, randomized, double-blind, non-inferiority, efficacy&#xD;
      and safety study of oral HC-1119 (80 mg/day) versus enzalutamide (160 mg/day) in asymptomatic&#xD;
      or mildly symptomatic patients with progressive metastatic castration-resistant prostate&#xD;
      cancer (mCRPC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following assessment of prostate cancer status will be collected during the course of the&#xD;
      trial: soft tissue disease on computed tomography (CT) scan or on magnetic resonance imaging&#xD;
      (MRI), bone disease on radionuclide bone scans, FACT-P and EQ-5D, Brief Fatigue Inventory,&#xD;
      and PSA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Throughout the study, safety and tolerability will be assessed by the recording of adverse&#xD;
      events, monitoring of vital signs and physical examinations, safety laboratory evaluations,&#xD;
      and 12-lead electrocardiograms (ECGs). Blood samples for population pharmacokinetics for&#xD;
      HC-1119 and enzalutamide and related metabolites will be collected.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is a multinational Phase 3, randomized, double-blind, non-inferiority, efficacy&#xD;
      and safety study of oral HC-1119 (80 mg/day) versus enzalutamide (160 mg/day) in asymptomatic&#xD;
      or mildly symptomatic patients with progressive metastatic castration-resistant prostate&#xD;
      cancer (mCRPC). Patients must not have been previously treated with next generation&#xD;
      AR-Inhibitors or Androgen-biosynthesis Inhibitors, or prior progression on ketoconazole.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following assessments of prostate cancer status will be collected during the course of&#xD;
      the trial: soft tissue disease on computed tomography (CT) scan or on magnetic resonance&#xD;
      imaging (MRI), bone disease on radionuclide bone scans, FACT-P and EQ-5D, Brief Fatigue&#xD;
      Inventory, and PSA. Radiographic disease progression is defined by the Response Evaluation&#xD;
      Criteria in Solid Tumors, version 1.1 (RECIST 1.1) for soft tissue disease, or the appearance&#xD;
      of two or more new bone lesions on bone scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Throughout the study, safety and tolerability will be assessed by the recording of adverse&#xD;
      events, monitoring of vital signs and physical examinations, safety laboratory evaluations,&#xD;
      and 12-lead electrocardiograms (ECGs). Blood samples for population pharmacokinetics for&#xD;
      HC-1119 and enzalutamide and related metabolites will be collected pre-dose on Day 1 and&#xD;
      prior to dosing on Days 8 (Week 2), 15 (Week 3) and 22 (Week 4), 29 (Week 5), 57 (Week 9), 85&#xD;
      (Week 13) and Day 169 (Week 25). Blood samples for calculating a 24 hour pharmacokinetic&#xD;
      profile of HC-1119 and enzalutamide and related metabolites will be collected in a subset of&#xD;
      24 Caucasian (non-Chinese) patients on Day 1 and at steady state in week 9.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will have a safety follow-up visit 30 days after their last dose of study drug or&#xD;
      prior to initiation of any new therapy, or an investigational agent, whichever occurs first.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 24</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the efficacy of HC-1119 as compared to enzalutamide as assessed by overall response rate (ORR) by RECIST 1.1.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PSA decline of ≥50% from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 24</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the efficacy of HC-1119 as compared to enzalutamide as assessed by decline of ≥50% from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Radiographic Progression-free Survival (rPFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 24</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the efficacy of HC-1119 as compared to enzalutamide as assessed by radiographic progression-free survival (rPFS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 24</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the efficacy of HC-1119 as compared to enzalutamide as assessed by overall survival (OS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and Tolerability (based on Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE), version 5.0)</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 24</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the safety and tolerability of orally administrated HC-1119 as compared to enzalutamide based on Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE), version 5.0.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">430</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer Metastatic</condition>
  <condition>Castration-resistant Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HC-1119</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral dose of 80 mg/day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>enzalutamide</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral dose of 160 mg/day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HC-1119</intervention_name>
    <description>oral once daily 80 mg</description>
    <arm_group_label>HC-1119</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Enzalutamide</intervention_name>
    <description>oral once daily 160 mg</description>
    <arm_group_label>enzalutamide</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects must meet the following inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 18 or older and willing and able to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Histologically or cytologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the prostate without&#xD;
             significant and relevant neuroendocrine differentiation or small cell features, per&#xD;
             investigator's judgment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Ongoing ADT with a GnRH analogue, antagonist or bilateral orchiectomy (i.e., surgical&#xD;
             or medical castration).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. For patients who have not had a bilateral orchiectomy, there must be a plan to&#xD;
             maintain effective GnRH analogue or antagonist therapy for the duration of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Serum testosterone level &lt; 1.7 nmol/L (50 ng/dL) at the Screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients receiving bisphosphonate or denosumab therapy must have been on stable doses&#xD;
             for at least four weeks (from Day 1 visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Progressive disease at study entry defined as one or more of the following three&#xD;
             criteria that occurred while the patient was on ADT as defined in eligibility&#xD;
             criterion #3:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. PSA progression defined by a minimum of two rising PSA levels with an interval of&#xD;
                  ≥ 1 week between each determination. Patients who received an anti-androgen agent&#xD;
                  must have progression after withdrawal (≥ 4 weeks since last flutamide or ≥ 6&#xD;
                  weeks since last bicalutamide or nilutamide). The PSA value at the Screening&#xD;
                  visit should be ≥ 2 µg/L (2 ng/mL)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Soft tissue disease progression defined by RECIST 1.1&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Bone disease progression defined by PCWG3 with two or more new lesions on bone&#xD;
                  scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Metastatic disease documented by measurable soft tissue disease by CT/MRI per RECIST&#xD;
             1.1 criteria. Patients are allowed to have any metastatic disease (i.e. bone&#xD;
             metastasis) as long as they also have measurable soft tissue lesions per RECIST 1.1..&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. No prior cytotoxic chemotherapy for prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Asymptomatic or mildly symptomatic from prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. ECOG performance status of 0-1 per the Investigators' clinical assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Estimated life expectancy of ≥ 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Able to swallow the study drug and comply with study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. All sexually active patients are required to use a condom as well as meet 1 of the&#xD;
             following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patient is non-fertile (orchiectomy) or has a female partner of non-childbearing&#xD;
                  potential (i.e., post-menopausal, surgically sterilized, hysterectomy)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patient and his female partner must agree to use an adequate contraceptive method&#xD;
                  from the first day of dosing until 3 months after the last dose to prevent&#xD;
                  pregnancies. Adequate contraceptive method is defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
             i. Established use of oral, injected, or implanted hormonal methods of contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
             ii. Placement of an intra-uterine device or intra-uterine system. iii. Occlusive cap&#xD;
             (diaphragm or cervical/vault caps) with spermicidal foam/gel/film/cream/suppository.&#xD;
&#xD;
             iv. Tubal ligation for at least 6 months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Male patient engaged in sexual activity with a pregnant female is required to use a&#xD;
             condom from the first day of dosing until 3 months after the last dose of treatment&#xD;
             with study drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects must NOT meet any of the following exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Severe concurrent disease, infection, or co-morbidity that, in the judgment of the&#xD;
             investigator, would make the patient inappropriate for enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known or suspected brain metastasis or active leptomeningeal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Regular daily use of opiate analgesics for pain from prostate cancer within four weeks&#xD;
             of enrollment (Day 1 visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. WBC count &lt; 3,000/µL, or absolute neutrophil count &lt; 1,500/µL, or platelet count &lt;&#xD;
             100,000/µL, or hemoglobin &lt; 5.6 mmol/L (9 g/dL) at the Screening visit (NOTE: patients&#xD;
             may not have received any growth factors or blood transfusions or any therapeutic&#xD;
             invention within 14 days of the hematologic laboratory values obtained at the&#xD;
             Screening visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Total bilirubin, alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &gt;&#xD;
             2.5 times the upper limit of normal at the Screening visit; no therapeutic invention&#xD;
             within 14 days before screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Creatinine clearance &lt; 30 mL/min as calculated using the Cockcroft-Gault equation at&#xD;
             the Screening visit. Creatinine Clearance (mL/min) = [[140-Age (years)] * Weight (kg)]&#xD;
             / [72 * Serum Creatinine (mg/dL)]&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Albumin &lt; 30 g/L (3.0 g/dL) at the Screening visit, no therapeutic invention within 14&#xD;
             days before screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of another malignancy within the previous two years other than curatively&#xD;
             treated non-melanomatous skin cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Treatment with flutamide within four weeks of enrollment (Day 1 visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Treatment with bicalutamide or nilutamide within six weeks of enrollment (Day 1&#xD;
             visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Treatment with 5-α reductase inhibitors (finasteride, dutasteride), estrogens within&#xD;
             four weeks of enrollment (Day 1 visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Treatment with systemic biologic therapy for prostate cancer (other than approved bone&#xD;
             targeted agents) within four weeks of enrollment (Day 1 visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Use of herbal products that may have hormonal anti-prostate cancer activity and/or are&#xD;
             known to decrease PSA levels (e.g., saw palmetto) or systemic corticosteroids greater&#xD;
             than the equivalent of 10 mg of prednisone/prednisolone per day within four weeks of&#xD;
             enrollment (Day 1 visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Prior use, or participation in a clinical trial, of an agent that blocks androgen&#xD;
             synthesis (e.g., abiraterone) or blocks the AR (e.g., apalutamide, darolutamide,&#xD;
             enzalutamide, proxalutamide).&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Participation in a previous clinical trial of HC-1119.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Use of an investigational agent within four weeks of enrollment (Day 1 visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Radiation therapy for treatment of the primary tumor within three weeks of enrollment&#xD;
             (Day 1 visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Radionuclide therapy (Radium 223) for treatment of metastasis within four weeks of&#xD;
             enrollment (Day 1 visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Clinically significant cardiovascular disease or condition&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Treatment with strong CYP2C8 inhibitors and inducers, CYP3A4 inducers, medications&#xD;
             which are known to prolong the QT interval (see Appendix C).&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. History of seizure or any condition that may predispose to seizure.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Conditions that predispose subjects to increased risk for falls or fractures according&#xD;
             to the discretion of the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Gastrointestinal disorder affecting absorption (e.g., gastrectomy, active peptic ulcer&#xD;
             disease within last three months).&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Major surgery within four weeks prior to enrollment (Day 1 visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Have active infection with HBV measured by hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) test,&#xD;
             HCV measured by RNA test and HIV measured by antibody test.&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Have known active tuberculosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. Known hypersensitivity to HC-1119, enzalutamide, or any of the excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
         28. Rare hereditary problems of fructose intolerance due to sorbitol&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>For general questions about this study</last_name>
    <phone>please contact</phone>
    <email>procade@hinovapharma.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Do not include personal information in email</last_name>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Urology Center of Colorado, 2777 Mile High Stadium Circle</name>
      <address>
        <city>Denver</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80211</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lawrence Karsh</last_name>
      <phone>303-421-5783</phone>
      <email>lkarsh@tucc.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Urologic Surgeons of Washington</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20036</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jason Engel</last_name>
      <phone>703-246-9505</phone>
      <email>jengel@dcurology.net</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>First Urology PSC, 101 Hospital Boulevard</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jeffersonville</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>47130</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>James Bailen</last_name>
      <phone>812-282-3899</phone>
      <email>jbailen@1sturology.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Research Solutions PC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Middleburg Heights</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44130</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lawrence Gervasi</last_name>
      <phone>440-340-9010</phone>
      <email>drgervasi@crssites.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MidLantic Urology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bala-Cynwyd</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19004</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Laurence Belkoff</last_name>
      <phone>610-667-3020</phone>
      <email>lbelkoff@ucsepa.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Keystone Urology Specialists</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lancaster</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>17604</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Paul Sieber</last_name>
      <phone>717-431-2285</phone>
      <email>psieber@lancuro.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Urology San Antonio Stone Oak, 18915 Meisner Drive</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78258-4223</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kethsaly Salinas</last_name>
      <phone>210-617-4116</phone>
      <email>kethsaly.salinas@urologysa.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Providence Regional Cancer System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lacey</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98503</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Xingwei Sui</last_name>
      <phone>360-754-3934</phone>
      <email>david.sui@providence.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ashford Cancer Centre Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kurralta Park</city>
        <state>South Australia</state>
        <zip>5037</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Francis Parnis</last_name>
      <phone>+618 8292 2220</phone>
      <email>fparnis@adelaidecancercentre.com.au</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Affinity Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nedlands</city>
        <zip>6009</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Simon Troon</last_name>
      <phone>+61892242334</phone>
      <email>simon.troon@health.wa.gov.au</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fe/Male Health Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oakville</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>L6H 3P1</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Richard Casey</last_name>
      <phone>(905) 338-3130</phone>
      <email>drrcasey@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aalborg Universitetshospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aalborg</city>
        <zip>9000</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Niels Christian Langkilde</last_name>
      <phone>+4597663229</phone>
      <email>ncl@rn.dk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hopital Foch</name>
      <address>
        <city>Suresnes</city>
        <state>Hauts-de-Seine</state>
        <zip>92151</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Raffaele Ratta</last_name>
      <phone>+33146252168</phone>
      <email>r.ratta@hopital-foch.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Jean Bernard Clinique Victor Hugo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Le Mans</city>
        <zip>72000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Eric Voog</last_name>
      <phone>+33243479493</phone>
      <email>essaisvoog@i-l-c.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHRU Lille</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lille Cedex</city>
        <zip>59037</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Arnauld Villers</last_name>
      <phone>+33320444235</phone>
      <email>arnauld.villers@chru-lille.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Léon Berard</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lyon</city>
        <zip>69008</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Aude Flechon</last_name>
      <phone>+33478782643</phone>
      <email>aude.flechon@lyon.unicancer.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Lyon Sud</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pierre-Bénite</city>
        <zip>69495</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alain Ruffion</last_name>
      <phone>+33472678808</phone>
      <email>alain.ruffion@chu-lyon.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hopital d'Instruction des Armées de Begin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint-Mandé</city>
        <zip>94160</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carole Helissey</last_name>
      <phone>+33143985243</phone>
      <email>carole.helissey@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Azienda Ospedaliera S Maria Di Terni</name>
      <address>
        <city>Terni</city>
        <state>Umbria</state>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sergio Bracarda</last_name>
      <phone>+390744205631</phone>
      <email>s.bracarda@aospterni.it</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Integrata Di Verona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Verona</city>
        <zip>37126</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andrea Zivi</last_name>
      <phone>+39 045 8123876</phone>
      <email>andrea.zivi@aovr.veneto.it</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Antonius Ziekenhuis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sneek</city>
        <state>Friesland</state>
        <zip>8601 ZK</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Erik Roos</last_name>
      <phone>+31515488995</phone>
      <email>e.roos@antonius-sneek.nl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Canisius Wilhelmina Ziekenhuis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nijmegen</city>
        <state>Gelderland</state>
        <zip>6532 SZ</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Diederik Somford</last_name>
      <phone>+31 24 3658255</phone>
      <email>r.somford@cwz.nl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Catharina Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Eindhoven</city>
        <state>Noord-Brabant</state>
        <zip>5623 EJ</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Evert Koldewijn</last_name>
      <phone>+31402397040</phone>
      <email>evert.koldewijn@catharinaziekenhuis.nl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hagaziekenhuis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Den Haag</city>
        <state>Zuid-Holland</state>
        <zip>2545 AA</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Daniel Houtsma</last_name>
      <phone>+31 702107680</phone>
      <email>d.houtsma@hagaziekenhuis.nl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NZOZ Centrum Urologiczne Sp zoo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mysłowice</city>
        <state>Slaskie</state>
        <zip>41-400</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Grzegorz Wagner</last_name>
      <phone>+48792455152</phone>
      <email>grzwag@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Research Center Spolka z Ograniczona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Poznań</city>
        <state>Wielkopolskie</state>
        <zip>60-848</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michal Kretkowski</last_name>
      <phone>+48503035225</phone>
      <email>michal.kretkowski@cr-center.pl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Onko-Centrum Sp. z o.o.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lublin</city>
        <zip>20-250</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pawel Iberszer</last_name>
      <phone>+48601813454</phone>
      <email>piberszer@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Urologica Praktyka Lekarska Adam Marcheluk</name>
      <address>
        <city>Siedlce</city>
        <zip>08-110</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Adam Marcheluk</last_name>
      <phone>+48504283093</phone>
      <email>am@urologica.pl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Altay Regional Oncology Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barnaul</city>
        <zip>656045</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sergey Varlamov</last_name>
      <phone>+7 3852 75 46 41</phone>
      <email>sergei_varlamov@mail.ru</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ivanovo Regional Oncology Dispensary</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ivanovo</city>
        <zip>153040</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andrey Semenov</last_name>
      <phone>+7 910 667-28-33</phone>
      <email>andrey.semenov@mail.ru</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Federal State Institution Medical Radiology Research Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Obninsk</city>
        <zip>249036</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Oleg Karyakin</last_name>
      <phone>+74 843 99 30 44</phone>
      <email>karyakin@mrrc.obninsk.ru</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Oncology Dispensary</name>
      <address>
        <city>Omsk</city>
        <zip>644013</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Evgeniy Kopyltsov</last_name>
      <phone>+73812601724</phone>
      <email>kopyltsov_evgen@mail.ru</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>First St. Petersburg State Medical University n.a. I.P Pavlov</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Petersburg</city>
        <zip>197022</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Salman Al-Shukri</last_name>
      <phone>+78123386918</phone>
      <email>Alshukri@mail.ru</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GBUZ Saint Petersburg Clinical Research Center of Specialized Types of Care (Oncology)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Petersburg</city>
        <zip>197758</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Leonid Rodygin</last_name>
      <phone>+79214209097</phone>
      <email>rodyginlm@mail.ru</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Orkli LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Petersburg</city>
        <zip>199178</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Vladimir Kheyfets</last_name>
      <phone>+79219676794</phone>
      <email>vladimirkh52@mail.ru</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>C.H. Regional Reina Sofia - PPDS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Córdoba</city>
        <zip>14004</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>María José Méndez Vidal</last_name>
      <phone>+34957011464</phone>
      <email>mjosemv@yahoo.es</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Lucus Augusti</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lugo</city>
        <zip>27003</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sergio Vazquez Estevez</last_name>
      <phone>+34982296459</phone>
      <email>sergio.vazquez.estevez@sergas.es</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario 12 de Octubre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28041</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Daniel Castellano</last_name>
      <phone>+34913908339</phone>
      <email>cdanicas@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Regional Universitario de Malaga - Hospital Civil</name>
      <address>
        <city>Málaga</city>
        <zip>29009</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>David Hernandez Alcaraz</last_name>
      <phone>+34951290000</phone>
      <email>davidhauro@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Virgen del Rocio - PPDS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sevilla</city>
        <zip>41013</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rafael Medina</last_name>
      <phone>+34955012366</phone>
      <email>rantonio.medina.sspa@juntadeandalucia.es</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fundacion Instituto Valenciano de Oncologia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <zip>46009</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Miguel Ramirez Backhaus</last_name>
      <phone>+34961114229</phone>
      <email>miramirez@fivo.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Diana Princess of Wales Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Grimsby</city>
        <state>South Humberside</state>
        <zip>DN33 2BA</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sanjay Dixit</last_name>
      <phone>+443033 302263</phone>
      <email>sanjay.dixit@nhs.net</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Marsden Hospital - London</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SW3 6JJ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Vincent Khoo</last_name>
      <phone>+442078082788</phone>
      <email>vincent.khoo@rmh.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mount Vernon Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Northwood</city>
        <zip>HA6 2RN</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Peter Hoskin</last_name>
      <phone>+441923 844 533</phone>
      <email>peterhoskin@nhs.net</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>Denmark</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
    <country>Poland</country>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 20, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 21, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 22, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HC-1119</keyword>
  <keyword>enzalutamide</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

