<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03650998</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ZUH-TQL-TLH</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03650998</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Transmuscular Quadratus Lumborum Block for Total Laparoscopic Hysterectomy.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Ultrasound-guided Transmuscular Quadratus Lumborum Block for Laparoscopic Hysterectomy. A Double Blind, Randomized, Placebo Controlled Trial.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Zealand University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Zealand University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Study is designed to assess the effect of the transmuscular quadratus lumborum block on&#xD;
      postoperative opioid consumption and pain for patients undergoing laparoscopic hysterectomy.&#xD;
      Study is randomized, placebo-controlled and blinded. Seventy patients will be included.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Every year three hundred patients undergo hysterectomy at the department of obstetric and&#xD;
      gynaecologic surgery at Zealand University Hospital, University of Copenhagen. The most&#xD;
      common procedure is Total Laparoscopic Hysterectomy (TLH), which is the preferred technique&#xD;
      in about four out of five hysterectomies at our facility. Multimodal analgesia consists of&#xD;
      Paracetamol 1 g, Ibuprofen 400 mg and Dexamethasone 8 mg and Sufentanil 0.2 micrograms/kg for&#xD;
      emergence if no contraindications are present. Standard general anaesthesia is total&#xD;
      intravenous anaesthesia (TIVA) with an induction consisting of Remifentanil and Propofol&#xD;
      infusions, a bolus of Propofol followed by muscle relaxation with Rocuronium. Patients are&#xD;
      intubated in the trachea. Anaesthesia is maintained with Remifentanil and Propofol infusions&#xD;
      and boluses of Rocuronium are administered whenever the surgeon requires it. Patients are&#xD;
      always in Trendelenburg's position. Thirty minutes prior to emergence a bolus of Sufentanil&#xD;
      0.2 microg/kg is administered, as mentioned previously. Of interest: two other different&#xD;
      opioid based regimens are currently used in the other two hospitals in Region Zealand where&#xD;
      this procedure is performed. There is no national standards defined for dosages used for this&#xD;
      kind of surgery. Additionally, no regional techniques are defined for this surgical&#xD;
      procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our research group at Zealand University Hospital has conducted a thorough retrospective&#xD;
      one-year survey for this patient group in order to define the quantity of the research&#xD;
      problem. The electronic anaesthesia files, PACU files and ward files were meticulously&#xD;
      reviewed. The survey revealed an accumulated morphine consumption in the first 12&#xD;
      postoperative hours of 44.1±30.8 mg of oral morphine equivalents in TLH patients. This dosage&#xD;
      should be evaluated in relation to the standardized multimodal regimen described above.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anaesthesiologists have primarily used either epidural catheters or long-lasting opioids as&#xD;
      the basis for the postoperative pain management of expected or manifest moderate to severe&#xD;
      pain. An epidural blockade can be contraindicated for some patients, and might cause bladder&#xD;
      paralysis, lower extremity paralysis, hypotension etc. In addition, the epidural technique is&#xD;
      labour-intensive in application as well as in its requirements for monitoring. Thus, the&#xD;
      continuous epidural blockade is not a possibility of interest to the gynaecologists at our&#xD;
      hospital. Therefore, until recently, opioids have been the sole treatment of pain, when&#xD;
      over-the-counter medicine does not suffice. This presents a problem for the patients due to&#xD;
      the well-known adverse effects of morphine including postoperative nausea and vomiting&#xD;
      (PONV), itching, fatigue, constipation, confusion, respiratory depression and delayed&#xD;
      mobilization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Postoperative complications to surgery are more frequent in patients experiencing&#xD;
      postoperative pain, and besides reducing the immediate postoperative pain perception, the&#xD;
      investigators consider reduction of the total morphine consumption and the potential of&#xD;
      reducing development of chronic pain through better treatment of the acute pain, as very&#xD;
      interesting and promising for the patients in our study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators have the technical capability to improve perioperative pain management by&#xD;
      taking advantage of USG peripheral nerve blocks (PNBs). The investigators' group of&#xD;
      researchers have described the transmuscular quadratus lumborum (TQL) block and the mechanism&#xD;
      by which the TQL block works has been proven in a major cadaveric study and some case&#xD;
      reports.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The TQL block is applied with the patient in the lateral position, with the side to be&#xD;
      blocked turned upwards. The ultrasound transducer is placed in the transverse position at the&#xD;
      posterior axillary line, just above the iliac crest, and adjusted to visualize the QL and&#xD;
      psoas major (PM) muscles and the transverse process of vertebrae L3 or L4. The needle is&#xD;
      subsequently inserted at the posterolateral end of the transducer and advanced in plane. The&#xD;
      needle is advanced through the QL muscle until the tip of the needle penetrates the investing&#xD;
      fascia of the QL muscle. The local anaesthetic is then injected in the interfascial plane,&#xD;
      but posterior to the transversalis fascia (TF) and between the QL and PM muscles.&#xD;
      Confirmation of correct application can subsequently be visualized when the two muscles are&#xD;
      seen to spread apart on the ultrasound image.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators want to perform evidence-based research using the USG TQL for patients&#xD;
      undergoing TLH. The hypothesis is that the USG TQL block administered bilaterally and applied&#xD;
      pre-operatively in the PACU or in the theatre for the TLH patients can reduce the&#xD;
      postoperative morphine consumption by 50 % during the first 12 postoperative hours. It is&#xD;
      considered a block with very little discomfort for the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients scheduled for a TLH will be screened according to the inclusion and exclusion&#xD;
      criteria. The suitable candidates will be asked prior to surgery, whether they want to&#xD;
      participate in the trial. If so, before elective TLH, the patient will receive the block,&#xD;
      allocated in a randomised fashion to either active LA or placebo. The block will be performed&#xD;
      under standard perioperative monitoring by a trained and skilled physician from the&#xD;
      department of anaesthesia. The active treatment will be a bilateral TQL block with 30 mL&#xD;
      Ropivacaine 0.375% on each side, whereas the placebo group will receive the same volume of&#xD;
      isotonic Saline, applied in the exact same way. The patients will all receive the same&#xD;
      multimodal analgesic regimens, consisting of 1 g Acetaminophen, 400 mg Ibuprofen and 8 mg of&#xD;
      Dexamethasone prior to surgery, and a regimen of 3 x Ibuprofen and 4 x Acetaminophen a day&#xD;
      until discharge. An IV Morphine Patient-Controlled Analgesia (PCA) - pump will be used for 24&#xD;
      hours after instructions are given and the pump is set to begin in the PACU. In order to keep&#xD;
      the pooled administration of local anaesthetic below the accepted maximum recommended dosage,&#xD;
      neither local anaesthetic infiltration performed by the surgeon nor supplemental rescue&#xD;
      regional techniques will be performed. Whenever pain exceeds an NRS of three despite the&#xD;
      primary use of the PCA pump, the PACU nurses will administer additional Morphine or&#xD;
      Sufentanil as they already do by the present standards.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim with this study is to investigate the efficacy of the USG TQL block vs. Placebo in&#xD;
      patients undergoing TLH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis is that the bilateral TQL block will significantly reduce the opioid&#xD;
      consumption during the first 12 postoperative hours and significantly reduce the Numerical&#xD;
      Rating Scale (NRS) pain score (0-10/10) and opioid related side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcome:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome of the study will be:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Morphine consumption in the first 12 postoperative hours (data from PCA pump and the&#xD;
      patient's medical record).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary outcomes will be:&#xD;
&#xD;
      (A) Pain intensity (NRS 0-10/10) in the study period at T0 (arrival in the PACU), after 15,&#xD;
      30 and 45 minutes. And again at 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 8, 10, 12, 15, 18, 21 and 24 hours&#xD;
      postoperatively. In addition, NRS score will be recorded electronically in relation to all&#xD;
      morphine administrations, since all patients must enter their NRS pain score on the PCA pump&#xD;
      display in relation to administration of the PCA boluses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      (B) Total morphine consumption. Morphine consumption at 3, 6, 9, 12, 18 and 24 postoperative&#xD;
      hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      (C) Duration of block (time to first opioid). (D) Patient satisfaction with application of&#xD;
      the block. (E) The degree of morphine-related side effects (PONV, itching, fatigue, etc.).&#xD;
      (F) Time from operation to ambulation. The investigators regard these outcome parameters as&#xD;
      essential for the selected patient group, and it is the investigators' hope that this could&#xD;
      lead to a better amelioration of postoperative pain and reduced morphine consumption&#xD;
      postoperatively.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 28, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 1, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 1, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative opioid consumption</measure>
    <time_frame>Twelve hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>How much cumulated opioid in oral morphine equivalents does the participant require/use.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative pain intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>12 hours.</time_frame>
    <description>NRS scale of 0-10.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Postoperative Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Active bilateral ultrasound-guided transmuscular quadratus lumborum (TQL) block. 60 mL ropivacaine 0.375% single shot.&#xD;
In both arms morphine will be administered IV as part of a patient controlled analgesia PCA)-pump regimen or additionally after contact with the nursing staff as it is the standard treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo bilateral ultrasound-guided transmuscular quadratus lumborum (TQL) block. 60 mL Saline single shot.&#xD;
In both arms morphine will be administered IV as part of a patient controlled analgesia PCA)-pump regimen or additionally after contact with the nursing staff as it is the standard treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ropivacaine</intervention_name>
    <description>See arm description</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Saline</intervention_name>
    <description>See arm description</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Scheduled for TLH&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years at the date of inclusion Have received thorough information, orally and&#xD;
             in written, and signed the &quot;Informed Consent&quot; form on participation in the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to cooperate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to speak, read and understand Danish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to local anaesthetics or opioids&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Daily intake of opioids, according to the investigators decision&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Local infection at the site of injection or systemic infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Difficulty visualisation of muscular and fascial structures in ultrasound&#xD;
             visualisation necessary to the block administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Co-morbidity, ASA&gt;3&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Hysterectomy requires a uterus.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jens Borglum, Ph.D.; MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Consultant, associate professor.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Zealand University Hospital, Department of Anaesthesiology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roskilde,</city>
        <state>Zealand</state>
        <zip>4000</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 27, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 28, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 29, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 9, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 9, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 13, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>nerve block</keyword>
  <keyword>ultrasound</keyword>
  <keyword>opioids</keyword>
  <keyword>hysterectomy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ropivacaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

