<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03653975</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HD-DZIF-MUHAS</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03653975</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Features and Potential Etiology of Epilepsy and Nodding Syndrome in the Mahenge Area, Ulanga District</brief_title>
  <acronym>NSEC</acronym>
  <official_title>Clinical Features and Potential Etiology of Epilepsy and Nodding Syndrome in the Mahenge Area, Ulanga District</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Heidelberg University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Heidelberg University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Childhood epilepsy disorders are particular frequent in the area around Mahenge,&#xD;
      southern Tanzania and recent studies have described a novel type of epilepsy with repetitive&#xD;
      head nodding episodes and often progressive cognitive dysfunction. Despite the disease&#xD;
      affecting thousands in Tanzania, Uganda and South Sudan, etiology and pathogenesis of the&#xD;
      disorder termed Nodding Syndrome (NS) is still obscure as the phenotype remains imprecisely&#xD;
      described. Epidemiological associations with Onchocerca volvulus and Mansonella spp. were&#xD;
      noted at different African sites and remain robust even though no evidence for the presence&#xD;
      of O. volvulus in CSF or any previous contact with the CSF was found.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: With regard to the complex host immune reaction to O. volvulus, the investigators&#xD;
      hypothesize that the immune response against filariae might contribute to NS and epilepsy.&#xD;
      The investigators further assume that specific genetic traits might play a role in the&#xD;
      pathogenesis of NS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims In the present study the investigators aim to examine if and how O. volvulus and/or&#xD;
      Mansonella spp. contribute to the pathology of NS/epilepsy and therefore intend to analyze&#xD;
      the filarial infection and the host immune response in affected children. To identify&#xD;
      inherited traits predisposing for epilepsy, NS or specific immune responses, a genetic workup&#xD;
      that includes whole-exome sequencing (WES) is performed. The clinical and EEG characteristics&#xD;
      are further defined. Cognitive impairment of people with epilepsy and NS is assessed using&#xD;
      the Wechsler Nonverbal Scale of Ability (WNV).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: A cross-sectional observational (groups I-III) and a case-control (groups I-V)&#xD;
      study recruiting in total 250 patients and controls (I: people with NS, n=50; II: people with&#xD;
      epilepsy (PWE) and onchocerciasis, n=50; III: PWE without onchocerciasis, n=50; IV: controls&#xD;
      with onchocerciasis but otherwise healthy, n= 50; healthy controls without evidence for&#xD;
      onchocerciasis, n= 50) is performed to describe the clinical characteristics in children with&#xD;
      NS/epilepsy and to evaluate differences in infection and immune response between groups,&#xD;
      respectively. The WNV should be validated in 500 healthy controls to obtain reference data in&#xD;
      rural Africa.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Summary: In summary, the study aims to elucidate clinical characteristics and the&#xD;
      pathogenesis of NS/epilepsy in children of southern Tanzania and role of parasitic infection&#xD;
      as a cause for NS/epilepsy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Childhood epilepsy disorders are particular frequent in low income countries and especially&#xD;
      common in the area around Mahenge, Ulanga region, southern Tanzania, with an epilepsy&#xD;
      prevalence of up to 39 per 1000 inhabitants. Therefore, in 1959 Prof. Louise Jilek-Aall&#xD;
      founded the Mahenge Epilepsy Clinic to provide basic care to people suffering from convulsive&#xD;
      disorders and to enable further in-depth investigations regarding epilepsy. In the summer of&#xD;
      2005, a multinational a team of researchers including the founder of the clinic, Prof. Louise&#xD;
      Jilek-Aall, Prof. Erich Schmutzhard, Dr. Andrea Winkler and Prof. William Matuja performed&#xD;
      several in-depth etiological investigations. In intensive field research they were able to&#xD;
      examine a large number of clinic patients and healthy controls, perform&#xD;
      electro-encephalographic and magnetic resonance studies and collect biological materials,&#xD;
      such as blood, cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) and skin samples for further sophisticated&#xD;
      laboratory tests in Europe. Among others, the studies confirmed the presence of a new type of&#xD;
      childhood epilepsy with repetitive head nodding episodes and often progressive cognitive&#xD;
      dysfunction. Even though the disease termed Nodding Syndrome (NS) affects thousands in&#xD;
      Tanzania, Uganda and South-Sudan, clinical, metabolic and EEG phenotypes are still&#xD;
      imprecisely described, and etiology and pathogenesis remain obscure. The high familial&#xD;
      occurrence and clustering within circumscribed villages and tribes suggests that genetic&#xD;
      traits might play a role. Epidemiological associations with Onchocerca volvulus and&#xD;
      Mansonella spp. were noted at different African sites. Despite lacking evidence for the&#xD;
      presence of O. volvulus in the CSF the association to NS remains robust.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is basis for the present study where the investigators aim to examine if and how O.&#xD;
      volvulus and/or Mansonella spp. contribute to the pathology of NS, elucidate associated&#xD;
      genetic traits, further specify the clinical, metabolic and EEG phenotypes. The investigators&#xD;
      will use a cross-sectional observational design including children with NS and epilepsy in&#xD;
      order to describe the clinical characteristics and a case-control design to evaluate&#xD;
      associated factors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is intended to enroll 250 patients and controls between 3 and 18 years of age (I: people&#xD;
      with NS, n=50 (inclusion according to the WHO case definition from the first &quot;International&#xD;
      Conference on Nodding Syndrome&quot;, Kampala, Uganda, July 2012); II: people with epilepsy (PWE)&#xD;
      and onchocerciasis, n=50; III: PWE without onchocerciasis, n=50; IV: controls with&#xD;
      onchocerciasis but otherwise healthy, n= 50; healthy controls without evidence for&#xD;
      onchocerciasis, n= 50). Patients with cardiovascular or renal comorbidities, a history of&#xD;
      birth or traumatic brain injuries, lacking or withdrawing consent will be excluded. Groups II&#xD;
      to V will be matched to Group I for age, gender and social status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators intend to analyze the filarial infection and host immune response in&#xD;
      affected children compared to unaffected controls. PCR assays will be performed to&#xD;
      characterize Onchocerca and Mansonella spp. strains found in patients with NS/PWE and&#xD;
      determine Wolbachia loads and features. A novel unique biomarker,&#xD;
      N-acetyltyramine-O,ß-glucuronide (NATOG) will be determined to quantify infection with O.&#xD;
      volvulus and correlated with other markers that define the host immune response and immune&#xD;
      regulation (e.g. regulatory T cells (Treg), cytokines). As polymorphisms in the&#xD;
      multidrug-resistance gene 1 (MDR-1) that alter p-glycoprotein expression or function may&#xD;
      enhance neurotoxicity of widely used antihelmintic drugs, single nucleotide polymorphism&#xD;
      (SNP)-arrays will be determined to investigate if specific polymorphisms might be associated&#xD;
      with NS. In addition, the investigators aim to define the clinical picture and course of NS&#xD;
      and conduct further EEG investigations and validated neuropsychological tests, follow up&#xD;
      patients of previous studies and perform metabolic analyses to specify the metabolic&#xD;
      characteristics of NS. A genetic workup that includes whole-exome sequencing (WES) to&#xD;
      identify traits predisposing to epilepsy, NS or specific immune responses is scheduled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In summary, the study aims to elucidate factors that contribute to the high prevalence of NS&#xD;
      and epilepsy in the Mahenge area in Southern Tanzania. Also, the research project will have&#xD;
      immediate benefits for the population under investigation as people newly diagnosed with&#xD;
      epilepsy will be offered treatment at the Mahenge Epilepsy Clinic and staff, patients and&#xD;
      relatives will receive further education regarding epilepsy, thereby contributing to&#xD;
      sustainability of a standardized approach to care for children with NS and PWE. Conclusions&#xD;
      drawn from our study will not only relate to the Mahenge area, but may be applicable to vast&#xD;
      numbers of children with NS (northern Uganda and South Sudan) and PWE in other areas.&#xD;
      Dissemination of the data through scientific meetings and publications may stimulate further&#xD;
      research regarding risk factors for epilepsy in the low income countries.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Describing clinical features in children with Nodding Syndrome and other forms of epilepsy e.g. characteristics of the seizures, EEG abnormalities and reporting co-morbidities and impairments.</measure>
    <time_frame>2014-2018</time_frame>
    <description>Obtaining clinical features and medical history. Comparing medical history, Seizure types and -frequency and other clinical Features between the groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Describing EEG features in children with Nodding Syndrome and other forms</measure>
    <time_frame>2014-2018</time_frame>
    <description>Performing EEG recordings and comparing EEG abnormalities (numbers, types and site of epileptiform discharges (ED), background alterations) between the groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measuring the rate of filarial infections in patients with NS, epilepsy and controls.</measure>
    <time_frame>2014-2018</time_frame>
    <description>Performing skin snip microscopy and PCR analysis to detect O. volvulus and Mansonella spp. in patients with NS, epilepsy and controls.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterization of O. volvulus in patients with Nodding Syndrome and epilepsy.</measure>
    <time_frame>2014-2018</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterization of the host immune response to O. volvulus.</measure>
    <time_frame>2014-2018</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Analyzing for genetic traits associated with epilepsy, NS, enhanced Ivermectin toxicity or specific immune responses.</measure>
    <time_frame>2014-2018</time_frame>
    <description>Performing a genetic workup for known monogenetic forms of epilepsy, single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNP) associated with enhanced Ivermectin toxicity and adverse immune reactions. Performing a Whole-exome sequencing (WES) with biomedical analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measuring the cognitive impairment in patients with NS and epilepsy.</measure>
    <time_frame>2014-2018</time_frame>
    <description>Using the Wechsler Nonverbal Scale of Ability (WNV) and comparing the results to matched healthy controls.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>6</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">250</enrollment>
  <condition>Nodding Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Epilepsy</condition>
  <condition>Onchocerciasis</condition>
  <condition>Cognitive Impairment</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Nodding syndrome</arm_group_label>
    <description>I) probable Case of Nodding Syndrom (according to the &quot;WHO epidemiologic surveillance case definition&quot;) *reported head nodding ** in a previously healthy person with at least 2 major and 1 minor criteria&#xD;
Major criteria&#xD;
Age 3 to 18 y at onset of head nodding&#xD;
Nodding frequency 5 to 20 times per min&#xD;
Minor criteria&#xD;
Other neurologic abnormalities&#xD;
Clustering in space or time with similar cases&#xD;
Triggering by eating or cold weather&#xD;
Delayed sexual or physical development&#xD;
Psychiatric manifestations&#xD;
As agreed upon at the first International Conference on Nodding Syndrome, Kampala, Uganda, July 2012 (16). ** Repetitive involuntary drops of the head toward the chest on &gt;2 occasions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>epilepsy and onchocerciasis</arm_group_label>
    <description>II) People with epilepsy (PWE) and onchocerciasis (n= 50)&#xD;
confirmed or suspected generalized and idiopathic epilepsy&#xD;
confirmed active infection with O. volvulus (microscopy, PCR and serology)&#xD;
Patients with cardiovascular or renal comorbidities, a history of birth or traumatic brain injuries, psychiatric comorbidities, insecure comprehension of the information given, lacking or withdrawn consent will be excluded.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>epilepsy, no onchocerciasis</arm_group_label>
    <description>III) People with epilepsy (PWE) without onchocerciasis (n= 50)&#xD;
confirmed or suspected generalized and idiopathic epilepsy&#xD;
excluded active or past infection with O. volvulus (microscopy, PCR and serology)&#xD;
Patients with cardiovascular or renal comorbidities, a history of birth or traumatic brain injuries, psychiatric comorbidities, insecure comprehension of the information given, lacking or withdrawn consent will be excluded.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>no epilepsy but onchocerciasis</arm_group_label>
    <description>IV) Controls with onchocerciasis, otherwise healthy (n= 50)&#xD;
no evidence for epilepsy or other neurological diseases&#xD;
confirmed active infection with O. volvulus (microscopy, PCR and serology)&#xD;
Patients with cardiovascular or renal comorbidities, a history of birth or traumatic brain injuries, psychiatric comorbidities, insecure comprehension of the information given, lacking or withdrawn consent will be excluded.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>no epilepsy, no onchocerciasis</arm_group_label>
    <description>V) Healthy Controls without onchocerciasis (n= 50)&#xD;
no evidence for epilepsy or other neurological diseases&#xD;
excluded active or past infection with O. volvulus (microscopy, PCR and serology)&#xD;
Patients with cardiovascular or renal comorbidities, a history of birth or traumatic brain injuries, psychiatric comorbidities, insecure comprehension of the information given, lacking or withdrawn consent will be excluded.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>controls for Wechsler Nonverbal (WNV)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Healthy Controls for cognitive assessment only, (n= 750)&#xD;
no evidence for epilepsy or other neurological diseases no detailled examination on O. volvulus performed&#xD;
Patients with cardiovascular or renal comorbidities, a history of birth or traumatic brain injuries, psychiatric comorbidities, insecure comprehension of the information given, lacking or withdrawn consent will be excluded.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>no intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>no intervention</description>
    <arm_group_label>Nodding syndrome</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>controls for Wechsler Nonverbal (WNV)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>epilepsy and onchocerciasis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>epilepsy, no onchocerciasis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>no epilepsy but onchocerciasis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>no epilepsy, no onchocerciasis</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      To further describe the clinical features of NS, a complete physical and neurological&#xD;
      examination in patients with NS and controls is performed at the Mahenge Epilepsy Clinic. All&#xD;
      individuals will have to undergo sampling of blood and skin snips from at least two different&#xD;
      areas of the body, one of which must be close to the head. Time expenditure for the&#xD;
      individual participant is estimated with 60 min (Introduction of the study, consent, skin&#xD;
      snip, lumbar puncture and venipuncture) extended for about 60 minutes if EEG recordings are&#xD;
      obtained.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        With support of the hospital staff, participants aged 3 to 99 years will be recruited&#xD;
        consecutively among the registered patients as they are seen once a month for a clinical&#xD;
        check-up and to receive their medication. Suitable relatives of patients will also be asked&#xD;
        to take part in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The study groups with their respective inclusion criteria are defined above. Patients of&#xD;
        group I-III will be first recruited into the cross-sectional study and subsequently into&#xD;
        the case-control study. Groups II to VI will be matched to Group I for age, gender, social&#xD;
        status and stay within the Mahenge area.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        I) Patients with Nodding syndrome confirmed or suspected Case of Nodding syndrome&#xD;
        (according to the WHO epidemiologic surveillance case definition: reported head nodding in&#xD;
        a previously healthy person with at least 2 major and 1 minor criteria Major criteria Age 3&#xD;
        to 18 y at onset of head nodding Nodding frequency 5 to 20 times per min Minor criteria&#xD;
        Other neurologic abnormalities (cognitive decrease, school dropout due to cognitive or&#xD;
        behavioral problems, other seizures or neurologic abnormalities) Clustering in space or&#xD;
        time with similar cases Triggering by eating or cold weather Delayed sexual or physical&#xD;
        development Psychiatric manifestations&#xD;
&#xD;
        As agreed upon at the first International Conference on Nodding Syndrome, Kampala, Uganda,&#xD;
        July 2012 (16). EEG,&#xD;
&#xD;
        II) People with epilepsy (PWE) and onchocerciasis confirmed or clinically suspected&#xD;
        generalized and idiopathic epilepsy confirmed active infection with O. volvulus&#xD;
        (microscopy, PCR and serology)&#xD;
&#xD;
        III) People with epilepsy (PWE) without onchocerciasis confirmed or clinically suspected&#xD;
        generalized and idiopathic epilepsy excluded active or past infection with O. volvulus&#xD;
        (microscopy, PCR and serology)&#xD;
&#xD;
        IV) Controls with onchocerciasis, otherwise healthy no evidence for epilepsy or other&#xD;
        neurological diseases confirmed active infection with O. volvulus (microscopy, PCR and&#xD;
        serology)&#xD;
&#xD;
        V) Controls without onchocerciasis, otherwise healthy no evidence for epilepsy or other&#xD;
        neurological diseases excluded active or past infection with O. volvulus (microscopy, PCR&#xD;
        and serology)&#xD;
&#xD;
        VI) Healthy controls for cognitive assessment, matched to Groups I to V&#xD;
&#xD;
        inclusion criteria: The study groups with their respective inclusion criteria are defined&#xD;
        above.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients of group I-III will be first recruited into the cross-sectional study and&#xD;
        subsequently into the case-control study. Groups II to VI will be matched to Group I for&#xD;
        age, gender, social status and stay within the Mahenge area.&#xD;
&#xD;
        exlusion criteria: Patients with evidence for co-infections with HIV, Tb, Malaria or other&#xD;
        parasites, cardiovascular or renal comorbidities, a history of birth or traumatic brain&#xD;
        injuries, psychiatric comorbidities, insecure comprehension of the information given,&#xD;
        lacking or withdrawn consent will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Thomas Wagner, MD</last_name>
    <email>Wagner.Thomas@rheuma-kinderklinik.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Thomas Wagner, MD</last_name>
    <email>Thomasiminternet@gmx.de</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mahenge Epilepsy Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mahenge</city>
        <country>Tanzania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>William Matuja, Professor</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Tanzania</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 25, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 28, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 28, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 28, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Heidelberg University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Thomas Wagner</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Nodding Syndrome</keyword>
  <keyword>Head Nodding</keyword>
  <keyword>Epilepsy</keyword>
  <keyword>Onchocerciasis</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognitive impairment</keyword>
  <keyword>Mahenge</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Onchocerciasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nodding Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cognitive Dysfunction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

