<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04965909</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0379520202023</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04965909</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pain Neuroscience Education and Graded Exposure to Movement in Breast Cancer Survivors</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of an Online Physical Therapy Intervention, Based on of Pain Neuroscience Education and Graded Exposure to Movement, on the Quality-of-life and Chronic Pain in Breast Cancer Survivors: Protocol of a Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Seville</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Seville</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Introduction: Chronic pain stands out among the sequelae of breast cancer due to its&#xD;
      prevalence and impact on the breast cancer survivors' quality-of-life. Pain neuroscience&#xD;
      education (PNE) and gradual exposure to movement (GEM) are techniques that have been shown to&#xD;
      be effective in the management of chronic pain in other populations; however, there are no&#xD;
      previous studies that combine them to develop a therapeutic program aimed at this population.&#xD;
      Objective: To evaluate the effectiveness, compared to a control group, of an online&#xD;
      physiotherapy program based on PNE and GEM on the quality-of-life related to chronic pain in&#xD;
      breast cancer survivors. Methodology: Randomized controlled clinical trial. A total of 62&#xD;
      participants will be recruited. Subjects in the experimental group will receive an online&#xD;
      physiotherapy program lasting 3 months (24 sessions) that combines the application of PNE and&#xD;
      GEM (observation of motor actions and yoga as a method of therapeutic exercise). The&#xD;
      intervention will be carried out in small groups of 10-11 people. The control group will&#xD;
      receive the 'usual care'. Primary outcome will be the quality-of-life related to pain;&#xD;
      factors related to chronic pain are the secondary outcomes. Four evaluations will be made,&#xD;
      before the intervention (T0), at the end of the application of PNE module (T1), at the end of&#xD;
      the GEM intervention (T2) and at 3 months of follow-up (T3). Different validated scales will&#xD;
      be used in this population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Design: A Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial of two groups (experimental and control). This&#xD;
      study responds to a quantitative design from the perspective of the biopsychosocial model and&#xD;
      the 'enactive approach'. For its preparation, the CONSORT Declaration, the Physiotherapy&#xD;
      Evidence Database (PEDro) Scale, a quantitative methodology manual and the Template for&#xD;
      Intervention, Description and Replication Checklist (TIDieR) will be used as a guide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Population and sample: For sampling, a non-probabilistic convenience and snowball methods&#xD;
      will be used. The sample size of this study is 62 adult breast cancer survivors (31/group).&#xD;
      To calculate it the researchers are based on the literature and on the use of the 'G * Power&#xD;
      3.1.9.4' tool. The parameters applied in this study were: type I risk or α 0.05, type II risk&#xD;
      or β 0.05 (study power of 95%), considering 2 groups, 3 measurements and a partial Eta2&#xD;
      effect size of 0.05 for the variable global Quality of life (Functional Assessment of Cancer&#xD;
      Therapy - Breast (FACT-B)). The researchers considered a possible proportion of losses to&#xD;
      follow-up from 15%, and a intention-to-treat analysis will be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample for this study will be recruited through associations of Seville and social&#xD;
      network. The researchers followed the established inclusion and exclusion criteria in order&#xD;
      to choose the final participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization and masking: A random assignment method will be carried out, using an online&#xD;
      computer program (random allocation software). The assignment sequence will be hidden from&#xD;
      the evaluator and the study subjects, through an automated assignment system, and will be&#xD;
      guarded by the member of the research team that generates it. The preparation of the&#xD;
      sequence, the inclusion of the individuals in each group and the assignment of the treatments&#xD;
      will be carried out by different members of team. In relation to the masking techniques used,&#xD;
      the figure of the evaluator and the study statistician will be blinded in order to minimize&#xD;
      information biases, however, the physical therapist and the subject will not be blinded by&#xD;
      the type of intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Variables and measurement: (Main variable) quality-of-life related to pain - the Functional&#xD;
      Assessment of Cancer Therapy - Breast (FACT-B+4). (Secondary variables) pain intensity,&#xD;
      catastrophism level, self-efficacy level, kinesiophobia, fear avoidance beliefs - different&#xD;
      validated instrument of measurement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention and follow-up: The intervention will take place for 3 months. The intervention&#xD;
      in the experimental group will consist of the application of an online therapeutic program&#xD;
      that combines 'education in pain neuroscience' (1 month) and 'graded exposure to movement' (2&#xD;
      months). The intervention will be group (3 small groups) and the sessions will have a&#xD;
      frequency of 2 weekly sessions of 1.5 hours each, being taught by a physiotherapist. In&#xD;
      addition, an educational booklet will be sent via e-mail. The intervention in the control&#xD;
      group will consist of the application of 'usual care'. In addition, they will receive an&#xD;
      educational booklet online and the possibility of carrying out the program after completing&#xD;
      this study. 4 measurements will be made: prior to the start of the intervention (T0), between&#xD;
      the two therapies that make up the program (T2), at the end of the intervention (T3), and&#xD;
      after 3 months of follow-up (T4).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method for results and data analysis: For the data analysis, a data matrix will be prepared,&#xD;
      according to the coding methods that will be described in the 'variables' section. A&#xD;
      descriptive and an inferential statistical analysis will be carried out, assuming that the&#xD;
      groups are independent, which will include the calculation of a point estimate of the effect&#xD;
      together with the confidence interval (95% CI) and a linear model for each subgroup.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The SPSS program, version 26.0 for Windows will be used for data analysis. The researchers&#xD;
      will begin by conducting a descriptive analysis of the data for the study variables.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The absolute frequency and the percentages of each category will be calculated in the nominal&#xD;
      qualitative variables, while in the quantitative variables the mean and standard deviation&#xD;
      will be provided. Next, the homogeneity in the baseline between the experimental and control&#xD;
      groups will be studied with respect to the variables to control and pre-test of all our&#xD;
      dependent variables. In the dichotomous nominal qualitative variables, Pearson's bilateral&#xD;
      asymptotic Chi2 test will be used, or, failing that, Fisher's exact test. In the polytomous&#xD;
      nominal qualitative variables, Pearson's bilateral asymptotic Chi2 test or Pearson's exact&#xD;
      test will be used. On the other hand, in the quantitative variables that are homoscedastic,&#xD;
      the researchers will use the Student's t test for independent samples, and in those that are&#xD;
      heteroscedastic, the Welch t test. Next, a mixed-model analyses of variance factorial ANOVA&#xD;
      (2x4) will be used to study the effects of the treatment on the dependent variables evaluated&#xD;
      in the present investigation, considering the group as an inter-subject between-subjects&#xD;
      factor and time (the different measurements performed) as an intra-subject within-subjects&#xD;
      factor. The hypothesis of interest will be the interaction group by time with an a priori&#xD;
      alpha level of 0.05. In addition, the effect size of the observed differences will be&#xD;
      estimated by calculating the partial Eta squared coefficient. An &quot;intention to treat&quot;&#xD;
      analysis will be performed in the study of the effects of the applied intervention. All&#xD;
      statistical tests will be performed considering a confidence interval (hereinafter CI) of 95%&#xD;
      (p-value &lt;0.05).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Planned timing: the project would be carried out from 2020 to 2023.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethical considerations: All the procedures used to carry out this study will be in accordance&#xD;
      with those ethical considerations to be taken into account for any research project. This&#xD;
      project has the approval of the Research Ethics Committee (CEI) of the Virgen Macarena -&#xD;
      Virgen del Rocío University Hospitals and will carry out an exhaustive process of informed&#xD;
      consent in writing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial of two groups (experimental and control) will be carried out.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>double-blind (researcher and statistician)</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from quality of life related to pain</measure>
    <time_frame>Four evaluations will be made, before the intervention (T0, at the baseline), at the end of the application of PNE module (T1, 1 month), at the end of the GEM intervention (T2, 3 month) and at 3 months of follow-up (T3).</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of life related to pain measured by the Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy - Breast (FACT-B+4). The FACT-B+4 is a 41-item instrument designed to measure six domains of QOL in breast cancer patients: Physical, social, emotional and functional well-being, and breast-cancer (BCS) and lymphedema (ARM) subscales. The score obtained ranges from 0-148 points. The ARM subscale was not included in the total score. A higher score translates into a better quality of life.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from pain intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>Four evaluations will be made, before the intervention (T0, at the baseline), at the end of the application of PNE module (T1, 1 month), at the end of the GEM intervention (T2, 3 month) and at 3 months of follow-up (T3).</time_frame>
    <description>Pain intensity measured by the Brief Pain Inventory - Short Form (BPI - SF). The PBI -SF is a 9-item instrument designed to measure pain intensity and pain interference with the diary daily activities. The questionnaire has two subareas, one related to pain intensity, whose score ranges from 0-50, with a higher score being an indication of greater intensity; and another related to the interference of pain in activities of daily living, whose score ranges from 0-70, with a higher score being indicative of a greater impact on daily life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from catastrophism level</measure>
    <time_frame>Four evaluations will be made, before the intervention (T0, at the baseline), at the end of the application of PNE module (T1, 1 month), at the end of the GEM intervention (T2, 3 month) and at 3 months of follow-up (T3).</time_frame>
    <description>Catastrophim level measured by the Pain Catastrophizing Scale. This scale allows us to assess the degree of catastrophizing of pain in adolescents and adults who face this condition as a result of various pathologies or diseases. The scale consists of 3 subscales (rumination, magnification and helplessness), whose items will be valued from 0 (nothing) to 4 (all the time) to obtain a total score that ranges between 0-52. A higher score translates into a higher level of catastrophizing.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from self-efficacy level</measure>
    <time_frame>Four evaluations will be made, before the intervention (T0, at the baseline), at the end of the application of PNE module (T1, 1 month), at the end of the GEM intervention (T2, 3 month) and at 3 months of follow-up (T3).</time_frame>
    <description>Self-efficacy level measured by the pain self-efficacy questionnaire (PSEQ). The PSEQ is a 22-item instrument designed to measure self-efficacy level. Each item is scored from 0 - 10. 0 is equal to 'I think I am totally incapable' and 10 is equal to 'I think I am totally capable'. The total score ranges from 0-220. A higher score on the questionnaire corresponds to a higher level of self-efficacy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Kinesiophobia</measure>
    <time_frame>Four evaluations will be made, before the intervention (T0, at the baseline), at the end of the application of PNE module (T1, 1 month), at the end of the GEM intervention (T2, 3 month) and at 3 months of follow-up (T3).</time_frame>
    <description>Kinesiophobia measured by the Tampa Scale for Kinesiophobia (TSK-11). This scale is one of the most used to evaluate kinesiophobia in patients with pain. It is composed of two factors (avoidance of activity and harm) with a total of 11 items that are valued from 1 (totally disagree) to 4 (totally agree). The total score obtained ranges from 11 - 44. More punctuation shows higher kinesiophobia level.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Fear Avoidance Beliefs</measure>
    <time_frame>Four evaluations will be made, before the intervention (T0, at the baseline), at the end of the application of PNE module (T1, 1 month), at the end of the GEM intervention (T2, 3 month) and at 3 months of follow-up (T3).</time_frame>
    <description>Fear avoidance beliefs measured by the Fear Avoidance Components Scale Questionnaire - Spanish Version (FACS - SP) . The FACS- SP is a questionnaire that allows us to evaluate patient's fear of pain and consequent avoidance of physical activity due to fear. The questionnaire consists of 20 items in which a patient rates his agreement with each statement on a 6-point Likert scale. Where 0 = completely disagree, 6 = completely agree. There is a maximum score of 100. A higher score indicates more strongly held fear-avoidance beliefs. Five severity levels are available for clinical interpretation: subclinical (0-20), mild (21-40), moderate (41-60), severe (61-80), and extreme (81-100).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">62</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Neoplasms</condition>
  <condition>Pain, Chronic</condition>
  <condition>Quality of Life</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Educational and therapeutic exercise program</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive a 3-month online physiotherapy program comprised of 'pain neuroscience education' (month 1) and 'gradual exposure to movement' (month 2 and 3). They will receive an informative booklet online.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Passive control group (usual care)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive the 'usual care'. They will receive an informative booklet online and the possibility of receiving the therapeutic program, once the study is completed.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Online physiotherapy protocol based on pain neuroscience education and gradual exposure to movement.</intervention_name>
    <description>Online group therapeutic program (small groups), applied for 3 months.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Educational and therapeutic exercise program</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Woman aged between 18 - 65 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of stage 0 - III breast cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary treatment (surgery, radiotherapy and chemotherapy) completed at least 3 months&#xD;
             ago may still be receiving hormonal therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pain related to primary treatment in the last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to Internet and an electronic device that allows the use of the applications&#xD;
             used in this study and skills for their use or assistance from a close person who has&#xD;
             them.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hability to communicate fluently verbally and in writing in the language of the&#xD;
             research team (Spanish).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Approval of participation in the study by the coordinator of the health team that&#xD;
             assisted her during the course of cancer and its treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Another previous type of cancer or breast cancer recurrence in a period of less than 1&#xD;
             year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical diagnosis of a neurological, autoimmune or cardiovascular disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Some type of pathology that is associated with a contraindication to physical&#xD;
             exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of serious psychiatric disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of mental disorder.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Patricia Martínez Miranda</last_name>
    <phone>620278275</phone>
    <email>patrimartinez37@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universidad de Sevilla, departamento de Fisioterapia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sevilla</city>
        <zip>41009</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Patricia Martínez Miranda</last_name>
      <phone>620278275</phone>
      <email>patrimartinez37@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Watson JA, Ryan CG, Cooper L, Ellington D, Whittle R, Lavender M, Dixon J, Atkinson G, Cooper K, Martin DJ. Pain Neuroscience Education for Adults With Chronic Musculoskeletal Pain: A Mixed-Methods Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Pain. 2019 Oct;20(10):1140.e1-1140.e22. doi: 10.1016/j.jpain.2019.02.011. Epub 2019 Mar 1.</citation>
    <PMID>30831273</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>De Groef A, Penen F, Dams L, Van der Gucht E, Nijs J, Meeus M. Best-Evidence Rehabilitation for Chronic Pain Part 2: Pain during and after Cancer Treatment. J Clin Med. 2019 Jul 5;8(7). pii: E979. doi: 10.3390/jcm8070979. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31284377</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cramer H, Lauche R, Klose P, Lange S, Langhorst J, Dobos GJ. Yoga for improving health-related quality of life, mental health and cancer-related symptoms in women diagnosed with breast cancer. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017 Jan 3;1:CD010802. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD010802.pub2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28045199</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gatchel RJ, Peng YB, Peters ML, Fuchs PN, Turk DC. The biopsychosocial approach to chronic pain: scientific advances and future directions. Psychol Bull. 2007 Jul;133(4):581-624. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17592957</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Seville</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Patricia Martínez Miranda</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Doctoranda Programa del Doctorado Interuniversitario en CCSS</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>pain</keyword>
  <keyword>quality of life</keyword>
  <keyword>pain neuroscience education</keyword>
  <keyword>graded exposure to movement</keyword>
  <keyword>therapeutic exercise</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The personal data of the participants will be treated in accordance with the Organic Law 3/2018, of December 5, on the Protection of Personal Data and guarantee of digital rights</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

