<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04963855</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GEN-0101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04963855</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase I Study of GT300 in Healthy Subjects</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Two-part, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled, Phase I Study of the Safety and Pharmacokinetics of Single Doses of GT300 in Healthy Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Generian Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Generian Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Descriptive safety and pharmacokinetics of GT300, exploratory biomarker effects for the&#xD;
      evaluation of the effect of GT300 on the autophagy-lysosomal pathway (ALP), food effect on PK&#xD;
      and fasting effect on biomarkers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a two-part study to be conducted under double-blind conditions. Part A will be&#xD;
      conducted first and completed before Parts B is conducted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part A is a single ascending dose evaluation of GT300 under double blind conditions in a&#xD;
      population of healthy male and female subjects. Part B will be conducted once follow-up of&#xD;
      the last cohort Part A has been conducted. On each study day in which drug is administered,&#xD;
      dosing will be &quot;staggered&quot;. Additionally, during Part A, a &quot;sentinel&quot; group comprising 1&#xD;
      active and 1 placebo subject will be dosed approximately 24 hours prior to dosing the&#xD;
      remaining 6 subjects in group 1 (5 active, 1 placebo).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conduct of the study including clinical evaluation of subjects (up to the safety review&#xD;
      meeting) will be under double-blind conditions. Progress from one cohort to the next will be&#xD;
      contingent on satisfactory review of the safety and other data from each cohort.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part B is a single dose evaluation of the effect of food and prolonged fasting on the GT300&#xD;
      PK and biomarkers. The dose of GT300 will be equal to, or less than the maximum dose&#xD;
      evaluated in Part A.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 23, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 15, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 15, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic</measure>
    <time_frame>8 days</time_frame>
    <description>Cmax</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">56</enrollment>
  <condition>Lewy Body Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CT300</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>GT300 capsule given once daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Microcrystalline cellulose capsule given once daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>GT300</intervention_name>
    <description>SIngle oral dose</description>
    <arm_group_label>CT300</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Microcrystalline cellulose</intervention_name>
    <description>placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy, adult, male or female (non-lactating) subjects age 18 to 55 inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Good general health, with no significant medical history. Subjects must have no&#xD;
             clinically significant abnormalities on physical examination at screening, and/or&#xD;
             before administration of the initial dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Body weight ≥ 50 kg at the screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Body Mass Index (BMI) between 18 and 32 kg/m2 inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Has laboratory values (clinical chemistry, hematology and coagulation) within the&#xD;
             normal reference range. Deviations from this range may be acceptable if they are&#xD;
             considered 'not clinically significant' (NCS) by the PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Women of childbearing potential may be enrolled if one of the following criteria&#xD;
             applies:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Must be using an effective form of contraception (e.g., oral contraceptives,&#xD;
                  vaginal ring, IUD, injected or implanted hormonal contraception) for at least one&#xD;
                  month prior to study entry, must have maintained a normal menstrual pattern for&#xD;
                  the three months prior to study entry and have a negative pregnancy test (urine)&#xD;
                  at the time of admission to the unit. Women must be willing to continue this&#xD;
                  contraception for 90 days following administration of study drug. Their male&#xD;
                  partner should use a condom.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Is sexually abstinent (Investigator judgement)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Is monogamous with a vasectomized (by history; see section 4.2) months prior)&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Is postmenopausal (i.e., amenorrheic for at least 12 months prior to dosing and&#xD;
                  demonstrating FSH (follicle-stimulating hormone) consistent with post-menopausal&#xD;
                  state&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. negative pregnancy test (urine) both at Screening (serum) and Day -1(urine)&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Is surgically sterilized (confirmed by medical record review)&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Has had a total hysterectomy a minimum of 3 months prior to dosing on Day 1&#xD;
                  (confirmed by medical record review)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Males who are sexually abstinent may be enrolled or, if sexually active, may be&#xD;
             enrolled if one of the following criteria applies:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Has had a vasectomy (&gt;3 months prior to dosing, by history; see section 4.2)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Using condoms and whose partner is using an acceptable form of contraception&#xD;
                  (IUD, oral contraceptives, birth control patch or vaginal ring, injectable or&#xD;
                  implanted contraceptives, or tubal ligation [surgical sterilization]) from Day -1&#xD;
                  to 90 days after study drug administration; using condom with same sex partner&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Is a light smoker (on average &lt;10 cigarettes/week) or non-smoker and must not have&#xD;
             used any nicotine products within one months prior to dosing. Able and willing to&#xD;
             attend the necessary visits to the study center.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Blood donation or recipient of blood transfusion in previous 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of clinically significant endocrine, neurological, gastrointestinal,&#xD;
             cardiovascular, hematological, hepatic, immunological, renal, respiratory, or&#xD;
             genitourinary abnormalities or diseases. Cardiovascular history should include&#xD;
             assessment of risk factors for Torsades de Pointes Risk (e.g., heart failure,&#xD;
             pulmonary edema, cardiomyopathy, hypokalemia, hypomagnesemia, or hypocalcemia, or&#xD;
             family history of Long QT Syndrome, syncope or sudden death).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of neoplastic disease (with the exception of adequately treated&#xD;
             non-melanomatous skin carcinoma).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Mentally or legally incapacitated (e.g., has significant emotional problems at the&#xD;
             time of Screening Visit or expected during the conduct of the study, or has a history&#xD;
             of a clinically significant psychiatric disorder within the last 5 years).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Fever (body temperature &gt;38C) or symptomatic viral/bacterial infection or use of&#xD;
             antibi-otics within 2 weeks prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Resting blood pressure (semi-recumbent) (BP) &gt;140/90 mmHg or heart rate (HR) outside&#xD;
             the range 40 to 100 beats per minute at Screening and at Day -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Clinically significant abnormality on ECG performed at the Screening Visit or prior to&#xD;
             administration of the initial dose of study drug. (Sick sinus syndrome, second or&#xD;
             third degree atrioventricular block, myocardial infarction, symptomatic or significant&#xD;
             cardiac arrhythmia, prolonged QTcF interval, or bundle branch block.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Clinically significant laboratory abnormalities including: Impaired renal function&#xD;
             (estimated creatinine clearance (CrCl) of &lt;80 mL/minute based on Creatinine Clearance&#xD;
             Value as determined by the clinical chemistry laboratory. Additionally, subjects with&#xD;
             elevated unconjugated bilirubin consistent with Gilbert's Syndrome are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Positive test for hepatitis C antibody, hepatitis B surface antigen, or human&#xD;
             immunodefi-ciency virus (HIV) antibody at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Participants with a positive toxicology screening panel (urine test including&#xD;
             qualitative identi¬fication of barbiturates, tetrahydrocannabinol, amphetamines,&#xD;
             benzodiazepines, opiates, cocaine and cotinine).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Participants with a history of substance abuse or dependency or history of&#xD;
             recreational IV drug use (by self-declaration).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Alcohol consumption &gt;21 alcohol units per week. (One unit of alcohol is 10 ml,&#xD;
             information on calculation the content of drinks is provided at: the &quot;alcohol.gov.au&quot;&#xD;
             website.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Unable to refrain from or anticipates the use of any medications, including&#xD;
             prescription and non-prescription drugs and herbal remedies (such as St. John's Wort&#xD;
             [Hypericum perforatum]), beginning 14 days (or 5 half-lives, whichever is longer)&#xD;
             before administration of the initial dose of study drug and continuing throughout the&#xD;
             study until the follow-up visit. There may be certain medications that are permitted&#xD;
             at the discretion of the Investigator and Sponsor (including&#xD;
             paracetamol/acetaminophen, multi-vitamin preparations, medications for the treatment&#xD;
             of AEs following administration of study drug and immunizations, in particular any one&#xD;
             of the COVID-19 vaccines currently in use in AU).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subjects who are unlikely to comply with the study protocol or, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             inves-tigator, would not be a suitable candidate for participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Have participated in any other investigational drug trial within 30 days of dosing in&#xD;
             the present study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lewy Body Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

