<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04961515</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>I2021001524</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04961515</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Orelabrutinib and Sintilimab in Relapsed or Refractory Central Nervous System Lymphoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase Ib/II Study of Orelabrutinib and Sintilimab in Treating Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Central Nervous System Lymphoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Second Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>First Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Wenzhou Central Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Second Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Zhejiang Provincial Tongde Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>First People's Hospital of Hangzhou</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Zhejiang Provincial People's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Jinhua Central Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Jinhua People's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Yinzhou Hospital Affiliated to Medical School of Ningbo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Huizhou Municipal Central Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Second Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase Ib/II trial is evaluating the efficacy and side effect of orelabrutinib and&#xD;
      sintilimab as possible treatments for relapsed or refractory central nervous system lymphoma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Both orelabrutinib and sintilimab are promising classes of therapy for central nervous system&#xD;
      lymphoma. Given the poor outcomes and limited options for relapsed or refractory central&#xD;
      nervous system lymphoma. The investigators seek to evaluate the efficacy and toxicity of the&#xD;
      combination of orelabrutinib with sintilimab in this patient population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 1b (maximum 12 total cycles) Orelabrutinib dose escalation will occur using a standard&#xD;
      3+3 dose-escalation approach to determined the maximum tolerated dose(MTD) of orelabrutinib&#xD;
      dose in combined regimen, beginning at dose level I (150 mg daily) and potentially escalating&#xD;
      to dose level 2 (200mg) and dose level 3 (250mg) with rules for escalation and de-escalation.&#xD;
      If the dose-limiting toxicity is not found, the dose of 250mg qd will be used for phase II&#xD;
      trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Orelabrutinib: orally daily Sintilimab: The dose of sintilimab is fixed dose. 200 mg&#xD;
      intravenously every 3 weeks (maximum 12 total dose)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 2 Participants will receive orelabrutinib and sintilimab at the pre-determined dosage&#xD;
      level established in Phase 1b, until progression of the disease (PD), unacceptable toxicity,&#xD;
      or patient/investigator discretion. The response will be evaluated every 2 cycles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Orelabrutinib: orally maximum tolerated dose from phase 1b daily (150 mg or 200 mg or 250mg)&#xD;
      Sintilimab: The dose of sintilimab is fixed dose. 200 mg intravenously every 3 weeks&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safe and tolerable dose of regimen for phase Ib study</measure>
    <time_frame>Completion of first 12 cycles of treatment within phase I portion of study (estimated to be 10 months)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR) for Phase II study</measure>
    <time_frame>2years</time_frame>
    <description>The objective response rate (ORR) is defined as the proportion of patients with a best response of CR or PR</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>PFS is defined as the duration of time from start of treatment to time of progression or death, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>OS is defined as the duration of time from start of treatment to time of death.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The duration of overall response is measured from the time measurement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>ctDNA mutation and mean ctDNA concentration in serum and cerebrospinal fluid</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, every two months for up to three years after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Types of ctDNA mutations and frequency are measured by next generation sequencing. The mean ctDNA concentration is the concentration of ctDNA expressed as mean tumor molecules /ml at specific time points.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The levels of cytokine concentration in serum and cerebrospinal fluid</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, every two months for up to three years after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>The levels of cytokine will be analyzed by ELISA in all patients recruited. The cytokine profile includes IL-6, IL-10, TNF-α, IFN-γ, IL-2 and IL-4</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">48</enrollment>
  <condition>Primary Central Nervous System Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase Ib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Orelabrutinib dose escalation will occur using a standard 3+3 dose-escalation approach to determined the maximum tolerated dose(MTD) of orelabrutinib dose in combined regimen, beginning at dose level I (150 mg daily) and potentially escalating to dose level 2 (200mg) and dose level 3 (250mg) with rules for escalation and de-escalation. If the dose-limiting toxicity is not found, the dose of 250mg qd will be used for phase II trial.&#xD;
Orelabrutinib: orally daily Sintilimab: The dose of sintilimab is fixed dose. 200 mg intravenously every 3 weeks (maximum 12 total dose)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive orelabrutinib and sintilimab at the pre-determined dosage level established in Phase 1b, until progression of the disease (PD), unacceptable toxicity, or patient/investigator discretion. The response will be evaluated every 2 cycles.&#xD;
Orelabrutinib: orally maximum tolerated dose from phase 1b daily (150 mg or 200 mg or 250mg) Sintilimab: The dose of sintilimab is fixed dose. 200 mg intravenously every 3 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Orelabrutinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Orelabrutinib dose escalation will occur using a standard 3+3 dose-escalation approach to determined the maximum tolerated dose(MTD) of orelabrutinib dose in combined regimen, beginning at dose level I (150 mg daily) and potentially escalating to dose level 2 (200mg) and dose level 3 (250mg) with rules for escalation and de-escalation. If the DLT is not found, the dose of 250mg qd will be used for phase II trial.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase Ib</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Orelabrutinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Orelabrutinib: orally maximum tolerated dose from phase 1b daily (150 mg or 200 mg or 250mg)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sintilimab</intervention_name>
    <description>The dose of sintilimab is fixed dose. 200 mg intravenously every 3 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase Ib</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Histologically documented primary central nervous system(CNS) lymphoma or secondary&#xD;
             diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLBCL) isolated to CNS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Relapsed or refractory disease with at least 1 prior methotrexate-based therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participant must be able to understand and willing to sign a written informed consent&#xD;
             document.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participant must have signed and dated written informed consent form in accordance&#xD;
             with regulatory and institutional guidelines. This must be obtained before the&#xD;
             performance of any protocol-related procedures that are not part of normal subject&#xD;
             care.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participant must be willing and able to comply with scheduled visits, treatment&#xD;
             schedule, laboratory tests, and other requirements of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participant must be at least 18 years old on day of signing informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. PCNSL subjects should have evidence of measurable or evaluable enhancing disease on&#xD;
             MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Able to submit at least 10 but up to 20 unstained formalin-fixed, paraffin-embedded&#xD;
             (FFPE) slides from the initial or most recent tissue diagnosis for correlative&#xD;
             studies. Histologically confirmed tissue will be required from the time of relapse or&#xD;
             at the time of initial surgery. If tissue is unavailable and/or diagnosis was made&#xD;
             from cerebrospinal fluid or vitreal biopsy, approval from the overall principal&#xD;
             investigator is needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 to 3.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Life expectancy of &gt;3 months (in the opinion of the investigator)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Toxicities due to prior therapy must be stable and recovered to ≤ Grade 1&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Must be able to tolerate lumbar puncture and MRI/CT.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Demonstrate adequate organ function as defined below, all screening labs should be&#xD;
             performed within 14 days of treatment initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.0 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Platelets ≥ 75 x 10^9/L and no platelet transfusion within the past 7 days prior&#xD;
                  to initiation of protocol treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Prothrombin time (PT), partial thromboplastin time (PTT), and international&#xD;
                  normalized ratio (INR) &lt; 2 times the upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤ 2.5 times&#xD;
                  the upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Serum bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times the upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Creatinine clearance &gt; 30 mL/min calculated by the Cockcroft-Gault formula using&#xD;
                  actual body weight&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Women of child-bearing potential, must agree to use a highly effective method of&#xD;
             contraception consistently and correctly as described below during study treatment and&#xD;
             for 120 days after study discontinuation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Male participants must agree to use at least one of the following methods of&#xD;
             contraception starting with the first dose of study therapy through 120 days after the&#xD;
             last dose of therapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Ability to swallow oral medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. CNSL with systematic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The pathological diagnosis was T-cell lymphoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Prior chemotherapy within 4 weeks or prior targeted small molecule therapy within 2&#xD;
             weeks , prior antibody-drug-conjugates within 10weeks, autologous stem cell transplant&#xD;
             within 6 months, prior to the first day of study treatment, prior to the first day of&#xD;
             study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prior allogenic stem cell transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participation in another clinical study with an investigational product during the 4&#xD;
             weeks prior to the first day of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. External beam radiation therapy to the CNS within 14 days of the first day of study&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patient requires more than 8 mg of dexamethasone daily or the equivalent for control&#xD;
             of CNS symptoms at the time of initiation of study therapy. Patients must taper off&#xD;
             high dose corticosteroids for the control of CNS symptoms within 14 days after&#xD;
             starting on study therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of intracranial hemorrhage or clinically significant stroke within 6 months&#xD;
             prior to first day of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of significant gastrointestinal disease that would limit absorption of oral&#xD;
             medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Active concurrent malignancy requiring active therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Prior therapy with a checkpoint inhibitor or BTK inhibitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Warfarin or any other Coumadin-derivative anticoagulant or vitamin K antagonists.&#xD;
             Patients must be off warfarin-derivative anticoagulants for at least seven days prior&#xD;
             to starting the study drug. Use of low molecular weight heparin and novel oral&#xD;
             anticoagulants (eg. rivaroxaban, apixaban) is permitted if required.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Concurrent use of a moderate or strong inhibitor or inducer of the P450 isoenzyme&#xD;
             CYP3A. Participants must be off P450/CYP3A inhibitors and inducers prior to starting&#xD;
             the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Receipt of live attenuated vaccine within 30 days prior to the first day of study&#xD;
             treatment. Note: Patients, if enrolled, should not receive live vaccine while&#xD;
             receiving IP and up to 30 days after the last day of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Suspicion of or confirmed progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Active autoimmune disease (including autoimmune hemolytic anemia and immune&#xD;
             thrombocytopenia purpura) requiring systemic treatment within the past two years (i.e.&#xD;
             with the use of disease modifying agents, corticosteroids, or immunosuppressive&#xD;
             drugs). The following are exceptions to this criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients with vitiligo or alopecia&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patients with hypothyroidism (e.g., due to Hashimoto syndrome) stable on hormone&#xD;
                  replacement&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Any chronic skin condition that does not require systemic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Patients without active disease in the last 5 years may be included but only&#xD;
                  after consultation with the study physician&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Patients with celiac disease controlled by diet alone&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Replacement therapy (e.g. thyroxine, insulin, or physiologic corticosteroids&#xD;
                  replacement therapy for adrenal or pituitary insufficiency, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Significant medical diseases or conditions, as assessed by the investigator, that&#xD;
             would substantially increase the risk to benefit ratio of participating in the study.&#xD;
             This includes, but is not limited to, acute myocardial infarction in the past 6&#xD;
             months, unstable angina, uncontrolled diabetes mellitus, significant active&#xD;
             infections, severely immunocompromised state, and congestive heart failure, New York&#xD;
             Heart Association Class III-IV.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Known bleeding diathesis (e.g. von Willebrand's disease), hemophilia, or active&#xD;
             bleeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Known Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Known active infection with hepatitis C virus (HCV) or hepatitis B virus (HBV) as&#xD;
             determined by serologic tests and/or PCR.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. History of invasive fungal infection, including invasive aspergillosis, or known&#xD;
             active tuberculosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Major surgery ≤ 6 weeks prior to starting the trial treatment (or has not recovered&#xD;
             from the side effects of such surgery) or plans to have surgery within 2 weeks of the&#xD;
             first dose of the study drug.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Wenbin Qian, Prof.</last_name>
    <phone>+8613605801032</phone>
    <email>qianwb@zju.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Xianggui Yuan, Dr.</last_name>
    <phone>+8613989883884</phone>
    <email>yuanxg@zju.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>2nd Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hangzhou</city>
        <state>Zhejiang</state>
        <zip>310009</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Xianggui Yuan, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+8613989883884</phone>
      <email>yuanxg@zju.edu.cn</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Wenbin Qian, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+8613605801032</phone>
      <email>qianwb@zju.edu.cn</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

