<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04966871</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>USSPZV6</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04966871</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety, Tolerability and Efficacy of PfSPZ Vaccine Against Heterologous CHMI in US Malaria naïve Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1 Clinical Trial of a 3-dose, 28-Day Regimen of PfSPZ Vaccine in Healthy, Malaria-Naïve, Adult Subjects to Determine Safety, Tolerability and Efficacy Against Heterologous CHMI Conducted 14, 42 or 70 Days After Immunization</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sanaria Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sanaria Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, double blind, placebo-controlled, single site, Phase 1 trial of a&#xD;
      condensed regimen of PfSPZ Vaccine administered on Days 1, 8 and 29 by direct venous&#xD;
      inoculation (DVI) to assess safety, tolerability, immunogenicity and vaccine efficacy (VE)&#xD;
      against heterologous controlled human malaria infection (CHMI) conducted at varying time&#xD;
      intervals after the third immunization (14, 42 or 70 days). The trial is designed to simulate&#xD;
      pre-deployment immunization of military personnel. Prior studies with this regimen show high&#xD;
      level protection (&gt;80%) against CHMI at 21 days, but the onset and duration of protection&#xD;
      have not been fully defined.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      USSPZV6 is a single site, double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled, clinical trial. Study&#xD;
      groups will be randomized in a 14:4 ratio (vaccine to NS placebo) among healthy,&#xD;
      malaria-naive adults aged 18-50 years. There will be three groups of subjects. Each of the 3&#xD;
      groups will have 14 subjects who receive 3 injections with 9 x 10^5 PfSPZ of PfSPZ Vaccine&#xD;
      and 4 subjects who receive 3 injections with normal saline placebo. Subjects who complete all&#xD;
      immunizations will receive a total 2.7 x 10^6 PfSPZ. VE will be assessed by exposure to PfSPZ&#xD;
      Challenge (7G8) (cryopreserved infectious sporozoites originating from a Pf strain isolated&#xD;
      in Brazil, and thus heterologous to the vaccine). The day of CHMI will vary per group with&#xD;
      Groups A, B and C receiving PfSPZ Challenge (7G8) on days 14, 42 or 70 after Vaccination 3&#xD;
      (V3), respectively. Direct observation will be for 30 minutes following each dose of PfSPZ&#xD;
      Vaccine or PfSPZ Challenge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A research/safety monitor and a Safety Monitoring Committee (SMC) will provide safety&#xD;
      oversight. Clinical study monitoring will be the responsibility of Sanaria or Sanaria's&#xD;
      designated and authorized representative.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Screening will be done within 90 days of enrollment. For the second and third immunizations,&#xD;
      allowable windows are assigned. The entire study will take approximately 8 months to&#xD;
      complete, including 2 months of recruitment because the study will be conducted in two&#xD;
      sequential cohorts. The period of follow-up for each immunized subject and placebo controls&#xD;
      is through 8 weeks post-CHMI. Study participation will last between 99 and 154 days (not&#xD;
      including screening) depending upon group assignment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Case report forms (CRFs) will serve as the repository of source documents and other relevant&#xD;
      data for each study subject. Only information that cannot be collected initially into the CRF&#xD;
      (for instance, EKGs and AE medical records) will first be collected onto separate source&#xD;
      documents before transcription into the CRF. Laboratory results will be entered from source&#xD;
      documents directly into the database.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Solicited adverse events (AEs) will be collected for 7 days after each immunization.&#xD;
      Unsolicited AEs will be collected from the first immunization (V1) until 28 days after the&#xD;
      third immunization (V3) and for 28 days after CHMI. Physical exams and medical history will&#xD;
      be assessed as indicated. Safety laboratories will be collected at screening, day of V1, 14&#xD;
      days after V2, 7 days after V3, day of CHMI and 28 days after CHMI. Surveillance for SAEs&#xD;
      will occur for the duration of the study. Follow-up of AEs (including SAEs) occurs until&#xD;
      resolution or stability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If clinical laboratories expire (meaning they were obtained greater than 90 days prior to&#xD;
      planned enrollment), specific safety labs will be repeated for screening purposes. Safety&#xD;
      evaluation includes an electrocardiogram (ECG) performed at screening. Subjects with abnormal&#xD;
      cardiovascular symptoms or findings that appear clinically significant will be excluded and&#xD;
      if appropriate, referred to a cardiologist for further evaluation.Clinical laboratory&#xD;
      testings will be conducted by Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Detection of parasitemia post CHMI will be based upon qRT-PCR. Subjects who have 2 positive&#xD;
      qRT-PCR results separated by greater than or equal to 12 hours or a single qRT-PCR result&#xD;
      reading &gt; 250 estimated parasites/mL will be treated with anti-malaria therapy. Anti-malarial&#xD;
      therapy will consist of: First-line: Malarone, Second-line: Coartem.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Vaccine efficacy (VE) of PfSPZ Vaccine against Pf malaria in adults</measure>
    <time_frame>7-28 days after CHMI</time_frame>
    <description>VE computed as one minus the estimated risk ratio for Pf infection (parasitemia) detected by qRT-PCR beginning 7 days after CHMI and censoring subjects at 28 days in the &quot;modified Intention to Treat&quot; (mITT) population</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of 3 doses of 9.0x10^5 PfSPZ of PfSPZ Vaccine- solicited AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Day of first immunization until 8 weeks post CHMI</time_frame>
    <description>The differences in proportions of vaccinees compared to controls experiencing related solicited adverse events after vaccination.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of 3 doses of 9.0x10^5 PfSPZ of PfSPZ Vaccine- solicited AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Day of first immunization until 8 weeks post CHMI</time_frame>
    <description>The differences in proportions of vaccinees compared to controls experiencing related unsolicited adverse events after vaccination.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of 3 doses of 9.0x10^5 PfSPZ of PfSPZ Vaccine- SAEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Day of first immunization until 8 weeks post CHMI</time_frame>
    <description>The differences in proportions of vaccinees compared to controls experiencing related serious adverse events (SAEs) after vaccination.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of 3 doses of 9.0x10^5 PfSPZ of PfSPZ Vaccine- Lab abnormalities</measure>
    <time_frame>Day of first immunization until 8 weeks post CHMI</time_frame>
    <description>The differences in proportions of vaccinees compared to controls experiencing related laboratory abnormalities after vaccination.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antibody responses to PfCSP post-immunization/CHMI and correlation with protection in vaccinees vs controls</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks post Vaccination 2 until 4 weeks post CHMI</time_frame>
    <description>Antibody levels to PfCSP measured by ELISA comparing vaccinees to controls</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antibody responses to PfCSP post-immunization/CHMI and correlation with protection in protected vs unprotected vaccinees</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks post Vaccination 2 until 4 weeks post CHMI</time_frame>
    <description>Antibody levels to PfCSP measured by ELISA comparing protected (no parasitemia occurring post CHMI) and non-protected (parasitemia occurring post CHMI) vaccinees.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>VE between different groups with CHMI at 14, 42 or 70 days after Vaccination 3</measure>
    <time_frame>Day of first immunization until 8 weeks post CHMI</time_frame>
    <description>VE computed as one minus the estimated risk ratio for Pf infection (parasitemia) detected by qRT-PCR beginning 7 days after CHMI and censoring subjects at 28 days in the mITT population</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">54</enrollment>
  <condition>Malaria</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group A (PfSPZ Vaccine; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>14 volunteers will receive 3 doses of 9 x 10^5 PfSPZ Vaccine on days 1, 8, 29.&#xD;
Controlled human malaria infection (CHMI) with PfSPZ Challenge (7G8) will be administered on day 14 by DVI injection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group B (PfSPZ Vaccine; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>14 volunteers will receive 9 x 10^5 PfSPZ Vaccine on days 1, 8, 29.&#xD;
Controlled human malaria infection (CHMI) with PfSPZ Challenge (7G8) will be administered on day 42 by DVI injection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group C (PfSPZ Vaccine; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>14 volunteers will receive 9 x 10^5 PfSPZ Vaccine on days 1, 8, 29.&#xD;
Controlled human malaria infection (CHMI) with PfSPZ Challenge (7G8) will be administered on day 70 by DVI injection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group A controls (Saline; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>4 volunteers will receive Normal Saline (NS) as placebo on days 1, 8, 29.&#xD;
Controlled human malaria infection (CHMI) with PfSPZ Challenge (7G8) will be administered on day 14 by DVI injection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group B controls (Saline; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>4 volunteers will receive Normal Saline (NS) as placebo on days 1, 8, 29.&#xD;
Controlled human malaria infection (CHMI) with PfSPZ Challenge (7G8) will be administered on day 42 by DVI injection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group C controls (Saline; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>4 volunteers will receive Normal Saline (NS) as placebo on days 1, 8, 29.&#xD;
Controlled human malaria infection (CHMI) with PfSPZ Challenge (7G8) will be administered on day 70 by DVI injection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PfSPZ Vaccine</intervention_name>
    <description>Metabolically active, non-replicating, radiation attenuated, aseptic, purified, cryopreserved NF54 P. falciparum (Pf) sporozoites (PfSPZ Vaccine)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A (PfSPZ Vaccine; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group B (PfSPZ Vaccine; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group C (PfSPZ Vaccine; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PfSPZ Challenge (7G8) for CHMI</intervention_name>
    <description>Live, infectious, aseptic, purified, vialed, cryopreserved, Plasmodium falciparum sporozoites, strain 7G8</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A (PfSPZ Vaccine; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group A controls (Saline; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group B (PfSPZ Vaccine; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group B controls (Saline; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group C (PfSPZ Vaccine; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group C controls (Saline; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Normal Saline</intervention_name>
    <description>normal saline placebo control</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A controls (Saline; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group B controls (Saline; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group C controls (Saline; PfSPZ Challenge 7G8)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy adults (male or non-pregnant female) 18 to 50 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to participate for the duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to provide written (not proxy) informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physical examination and laboratory results without clinically significant findings&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals of childbearing potential must agree to use effective means of birth&#xD;
             control (e.g. oral or implanted contraceptives, IUD, female condom, diaphragm with&#xD;
             spermicide, cervical cap, abstinence, use of a condom by the sexual partner or sterile&#xD;
             sexual partner) during the entire study. Female participants with a history of&#xD;
             surgical or chemical sterilization (e.g. tubal ligation, hysterectomy, other) must&#xD;
             provide written documentation of the procedure from a health care provider&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to refrain from blood donation for 3 years following CHMI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agree not to travel to a malaria endemic region during the entire course of the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of malaria infection within 2 years prior to study participation or travel&#xD;
             to a malaria endemic region within six months prior to first immunization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of a malaria vaccine in a prior clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of a splenectomy or sickle cell disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of a neurologic disorder (including non-febrile seizures or complex febrile&#xD;
             seizures) or formal history of migraine headache&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of systemic immunosuppressant pharmacotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of a live vaccine within 4 weeks of first immunization or of a non-live&#xD;
             vaccine within 2 weeks of first immunization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are breast-feeding, pregnant or planning to become pregnant during the&#xD;
             study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy to atovaquone-proguanil (Malarone®), artemether-lumefantrine (Coartem),&#xD;
             or any component of the investigational products&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of anaphylaxis or other life-threatening reaction to a vaccine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in any study involving investigational vaccine or drug within 4 weeks&#xD;
             prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of increased cardiovascular disease risk; defined as &gt;10% five-year risk by&#xD;
             non-laboratory method (Gaziano, 2008)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Plan to participate in another investigational vaccine/drug research during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Plan for major surgery between enrollment until 28 days post-CHMI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use or planned use of any drug with anti-malarial activity that would preceed or&#xD;
             coincide with malaria challenge.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anticipated use of medications known to cause drug reactions with atovaquone-proguanil&#xD;
             or artemether-lumefantrine such as cimetidine, metoclopramide, antacids, and kaolin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive HIV, HBsAg or HCV serology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An abnormal electrocardiogram, defined as one showing pathologic Q waves and&#xD;
             significant ST-T wave changes; left ventricular hypertrophy; any non-sinus rhythm&#xD;
             including isolated premature ventricular contractions, but excluding isolated&#xD;
             premature atrial contractions; right or left bundle branch block; or advanced&#xD;
             (secondary or tertiary) A-V heart block; or other clinically significant abnormalities&#xD;
             on the electrocardiogram as determined by the consulting cardiologist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any clinically significant deviation from the normal range in biochemistry or&#xD;
             hematology tests measured at screening and not resolving.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any medical, psychiatric, social, behavioral or occupational condition or situation&#xD;
             (including active alcohol or drug abuse) that, in the judgment of the PI, impairs the&#xD;
             volunteer's ability to give informed consent, increases the risk to the subject of&#xD;
             participation in the study, affects the ability of the subject to participate fully in&#xD;
             the study, or might negatively impact the quality, consistency, integrity or&#xD;
             interpretation of data derived from their participation in the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>James Kublin, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>206-667-1970</phone>
    <email>jkublin@fredhutch.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>James Kublin, MD. PhD</last_name>
      <phone>206-667-1970</phone>
      <email>jkublin@fredhutch.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 3, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>PfSPZ Vaccine</keyword>
  <keyword>Malaria</keyword>
  <keyword>Plasmodium falciparum</keyword>
  <keyword>Controlled human malaria infection</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

