<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04966923</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>3.0840453</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04966923</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phenotype and Prognosis of Patients With Breast Cancer and Pathogenic Variants of TP53</brief_title>
  <acronym>BREAST TP53</acronym>
  <official_title>Phenotype and Prognosis of Patients With Breast Cancer and Pathogenic Variants of TP53 (BREAST TP53)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Instituto do Cancer do Estado de São Paulo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Instituto do Cancer do Estado de São Paulo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      We did a prospective and retrospective cohort study of patients with a documented pathogenic&#xD;
      or likely pathogenic variants of TP53 were identified using blood DNA colection and breast&#xD;
      cancer diagnosis by histological confirmation, between 1999 and 2021. All patients were&#xD;
      followed by the Hereditary Group of a single cancer center (Instituto do Cancer do Estado de&#xD;
      Sao Paulo) and AC Camargo Cancer Center Patients were included if they had a&#xD;
      histopathological diagnosis of localized invasive carcinoma or in situ carcinoma of the&#xD;
      breast. All patients met Revised Chompret criteria or Li Fraumeni like syndrome or family&#xD;
      member of carrier TP53. Patients with only other types of breast cancer such as sarcoma and&#xD;
      phyllodes tumor were excluded from the analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary outcome was progression free survival from specific breast cancer from patients&#xD;
      with BC and TP53 mutation versus BC and no pathogenic variants documented in genetic test. We&#xD;
      proposed 45 cases TP53 pathogenic carriers and breast cancer diagnosed for each case included&#xD;
      we will be selected 2 controls resulting in 90 control patients, for control are estimated&#xD;
      with the same age (range 10 years), staging and immunohistochemistry subtype with no&#xD;
      documented pathogenic variants in genetic test. With a sample of 135 patients with&#xD;
      distribution 2:1, considering a two-tailed alpha of 5%, the study will have 80% power to&#xD;
      identify a hazard hatio of 0.62 in the comparison of progression-free survival between the&#xD;
      groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Descriptive statistics will be used to summarize clinical characteristics and treatments&#xD;
      performed. Continuous variables may be compared between groups using T Student test or&#xD;
      Mann-Whitney test, in the case of normal and non-normal data distribution, respectively.&#xD;
      Categorical variables may be compared between groups using the Fisher exact test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Progression-free survival will be estimated from the date of breast cancer diagnosis until&#xD;
      the date of progression or date of recurrence (in cases of localized disease treated) of&#xD;
      breast cancer. Death will not be considered as an event for progression-free survival, since&#xD;
      patients with PV TP53 may have an increased risk of deaths from other neoplasms. The breast&#xD;
      cancer specific survival will be estimated from the date of diagnosis of breast cancer until&#xD;
      the date of death from the breast cancer. Patients without the specific events will be&#xD;
      censored on the date of last follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Kaplan-Meyer method will be used for survival estimates, comparing survival curves with&#xD;
      log-rank testing. The Cox regression model will be used for hazard-ratio calculation and 95%&#xD;
      confidence-interval. P value less than 0.05 will be considered statistically significant.&#xD;
      Statistical analyses will be performed through Stata program, version 15.1 (StataCorp, Texas,&#xD;
      USA).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 2, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 5, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 7, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>We proposed 45 cases TP53 pathogenic carriers and breast cancer diagnosed for each case included we will be selected 2 controls resulting in 90 control patients, for control are estimated with the same age (range 10 years)</time_frame>
    <description>progression free survival from specific breast cancer from patients with BC and TP53. mutation versus BC and no pathogenic variants documented in genetic test. gnosed for each case included we will be selected 2 controls resulting in 90 control patients, for control are estimated with the same age (range 10 years), staging and immunohistochemistry</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival, causes of deaths</measure>
    <time_frame>We proposed 45 cases TP53 pathogenic carriers and breast cancer diagnosed for each case included we will be selected 2 controls resulting in 90 control patients, for control are estimated with the same age (range 10 years)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">135</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>TP53 R337H</condition>
  <condition>Li-Fraumeni Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Prognosis Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Breast Cancer and documented pathogenic variant TP53</arm_group_label>
    <description>Documented pathogenic or likely pathogenic variants of TP53 were identified using blood DNA colection and breast cancer diagnosis by histological confirmation. All patients met Revised Chompret criteria or Li Fraumeni like syndrome or family member of carrier TP53</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Breast Cancer and no documented pathogenic variants in genetic test</arm_group_label>
    <description>Control with patients breast cancer and no pathogenic variants documented in a genetic test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No intervention in this study</intervention_name>
    <description>Analyses of pathogenic variant TP53 and variants in genetic test</description>
    <arm_group_label>Breast Cancer and documented pathogenic variant TP53</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Breast Cancer and no documented pathogenic variants in genetic test</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      The TP53 molecular analyses were initially based on the investigation of the p.R337H mutation&#xD;
      by polymerase chain reaction/restriction fragment length polymorphism (PCR). In this method,&#xD;
      PCR amplicons of exon 10 of the TP53 gene were digested by the Hha I restriction enzyme and&#xD;
      then separated by agarose gel electrophoresis. This analysis can distinguish between&#xD;
      different genotypes at the p.R337H mutation site, identifying homozygous, heterozygous and&#xD;
      wild-type individuals for this specific mutation. Sanger sequencing of coding and splicing&#xD;
      regions was performed in all negative cases to investigate other variants. Amplification&#xD;
      products of exons 2-11 of TP53 were sequenced using the BigDye terminator v3.1 cycle&#xD;
      sequencing kit, according to the manufacturer's instructions. Sequencing analyses were&#xD;
      carried out on the 3130xl Genetic Analyzer. Classification of the variant pathogenicity was&#xD;
      done according to the American College of Medical Genetics and Genomics guidelines, using&#xD;
      VarSome.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        We did a prospective and retrospective cohort study of patients with a documented&#xD;
        pathogenic or likely pathogenic variants of TP53 were identified using blood DNA colection&#xD;
        and breast cancer diagnosis by histological confirmation, between 1999 and 2021. All&#xD;
        patients were followed by the Hereditary Group of a single cancer center (Instituto do&#xD;
        Cancer do Estado de Sao Paulo) and AC Camargo Cancer Center Patients were included if they&#xD;
        had a histopathological diagnosis of localized invasive carcinoma or in situ carcinoma of&#xD;
        the breast. All patients met Revised Chompret criteria or Li Fraumeni like syndrome or&#xD;
        family member of carrier TP53. Patients with only other types of breast cancer such as&#xD;
        sarcoma and phyllodes tumor were excluded from the analysis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breast cancer (histopathological diagnosis of localized invasive carcinoma or in situ&#xD;
             carcinoma of the breast) and documented germline pathogenic variants of TP53.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with only other types of breast cancer such as sarcoma and phyllodes tumor&#xD;
             were excluded from the analysis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>ICESP</name>
      <address>
        <city>São Paulo</city>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Vanessa Petry, MD</last_name>
      <phone>11-982816564</phone>
      <email>vanessa.petry@hc.fm.usp.br</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Maria Del Pilar Estevez Diaz, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Maria Candida Barisson Villares Fragoso, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>José Claudio Casali da Rocha, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>TP53</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Li-Fraumeni Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

