<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04968678</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRAS 287263-Local21/CAR/492</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04968678</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Exploring P-Wave Duration in Arrhythmia Recurrence in Patients Undergoing AF Ablation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Exploring the Relationship Between Duration of the Amplified P-Wave Arrhythmia and Recurrence in Patients With Persistent, Long Persistent or Paroxysmal AF Undergoing Cryoablation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nik Spinthakis</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dr Guy Haywood</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital Plymouth NHS Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to investigate whether P-wave duration in a baseline surface 12-lead&#xD;
      ECGs correlates with recurrence of AF recurrence post successful ablation at the time of the&#xD;
      procedure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients with paroxysmal AF are often treated arrhythmia-free (75%) with a single catheter&#xD;
      ablation at 12 months post procedure . In contrast, in patients with persistent AF or long&#xD;
      persistent AF, catheter ablation is more complex and often yields in lower success rates of&#xD;
      around 50% often requiring multiple attempts .&#xD;
&#xD;
      The success rates remain low despite several different ablation sites having been proposed&#xD;
      (additional lines plus PVI, epicardial approach).&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is growing evidence that PWD is associated with the extent of left atrial scarring and&#xD;
      this can be used a potential predictor of AF recurrence . Moreover, results from the&#xD;
      investigators group has previously shown that PWD correlated with the duration of the AF and&#xD;
      this could be altered by extensive ablation .&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is uncertain whether PWD prior to any procedure for persistent AF, long persistent or&#xD;
      paroxysmal AF can accurately predict failure of procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a single centre observational study of persistent, long persistent and paroxysmal AF&#xD;
      population who have undergo AF cryoablation in University Hospital Plymouth . All patients&#xD;
      receive this current procedure as standard of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study does not involve any patient contact out of the standard routine clinical follow&#xD;
      up and therefore no public involvement has been sought.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 13, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 13, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 13, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>24 Months</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrence of atrial fibrillation.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Primary.This will be documented in a 12 lead ECG &gt;30sec post ablation according to standard operation procedures follow up. Patients are actively followed up in regular intervals (4-12-24 months) post procedure and are able to contact department for advise if clinically suspected recurrence of atrial fibrillation. This is well studied and documented in previous studies as an outcome of measure.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Atrial Fibrillation Recurrent</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>P-wave duration measurement on 12 lead ECG with standard parameters</intervention_name>
    <description>Hospital records will be used in order to obtain baseline characteristics and the most recent 12-lead ECG in sinus rhythm prior to ablation will be used to calculate PWD. Measurement of the PWD will be obtained at standard surface ECG recording settings of 25mm/s and 10mm/mV and measured accordingly to our previous protocol. In brief, all ECGs obtained will subsequently be anonymised and randomised by an Independent Clinical Investigator (ICI) before measured by the main clinical investigators blinded to initial results. If a dispute of the measurements arouse, consensus will be used to resolve it after consulting the Chief Investigator (CI) blinded to the results. Bland-Altman plots to minimise bias will be used</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This is a prospective single centre study of the investigators current registry of patients&#xD;
        undergoing AF ablation from existing clinical procedural database which contains a record&#xD;
        of all cryoablation performed within the hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
        All records once obtained from the main database, will then be uploaded into a password&#xD;
        protected Excel spreadsheet and anonymised at the time of entry by the ICI.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with persistent, long persistent or paroxysmal AF undergone AF cryoablation&#xD;
             from 2016 onwards&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age &gt;18&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient does not meet exclusion criteria -&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients whose records cannot be obtained&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with persistent, long persistent or paroxysmal AF undergone AF ablation prior&#xD;
             to 2016&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with no documented ECG in sinus rhythm prior to ablation&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients not undergoing cryoablation for AF -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Guy Haywood, MBBD,MD</last_name>
    <phone>07785955893</phone>
    <email>guyhaywood@nhs.net</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Univeristy Hospital Plymouth</name>
      <address>
        <city>Plymouth</city>
        <state>Devon</state>
        <zip>PL68DH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Guy Haywood</last_name>
      <phone>07785955893</phone>
      <email>guyhaywood@nhs.net</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Chris Rollinson</last_name>
      <phone>07870636429</phone>
      <email>CROLLINSON@NHS.NET</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 20, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University Hospital Plymouth NHS Trust</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nik Spinthakis</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PI,Cardiology ST5,MBBS,MRCP,MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>P-wave duration</keyword>
  <keyword>AF</keyword>
  <keyword>cryoablation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>To comply with the Data Protection legislation information must be collected and used fairly, stored safely and not disclosed to any unauthorised person. This applies to both manual and electronically held data.&#xD;
The Chief Investigator will preserve the confidentiality of participants taking part in the study and ensure the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) in conjunction with the UK Data Protection Act 2018, which sets out the statutory requirements for the processing of personal data, is adhered to.&#xD;
Study documents will be anonymised by allocation of a study number, and will not contain personal identifiable data. Finalised data in an anonymised electronic format will be sent via encrypted USB devices in order to be analysed in a password protected computer. For each patient, a study number will be allocated, and data entered on an anonymised electronic CRF (case report form) in the way of an excel spreadsheet.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

