<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04966676</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ATLAS</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04966676</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Nivolumab-Ipilimumab and cfDNA in Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>ATLAS</acronym>
  <official_title>Beyond Chemotherapy: Nivolumab-Ipilimumab With cfDNA-guided Treatment Intensification as a Chemotherapy-sparing Strategy in Metastatic Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Health Network, Toronto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bristol-Myers Squibb</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Health Network, Toronto</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this research study is to look at how effective two drugs, nivolumab and&#xD;
      ipilimumab, are for people with non-small lung cancer that has metastasized (has spread to&#xD;
      other parts of the body) and to see what effects these drugs have on these tumors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study will use a special blood test to evaluate the response of the cancer to treatment.&#xD;
      This blood test will analyze tumor DNA present in the blood (deoxyribonucleic acid, molecules&#xD;
      that contain instructions for the development and function of cells). Patients that do not&#xD;
      have evidence of a good response using this blood test will also undergo a short course of&#xD;
      chemotherapy in addition to nivolumab and ipilimumab.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants whose disease does not worsen (progression-free survival rate) at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average percentage of tumor cfDNA detected in the blood (tumor cfDNA clearance rate) at 3 weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average percentage of tumor cfDNA detected in the blood (tumor cfDNA clearance rate) at 12 weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number participants with adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average time from the date of study enrolment until death (overall survival)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Non Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non-Small cell Lung Cancer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nivolumab, intravenously (given by vein), once every 3 weeks Ipilimumab, intravenously (given by vein), once every 6 weeks&#xD;
Participants will have blood samples taken for cell free deoxyribonucleic acid (cfDNA) testing.&#xD;
If there is an increasing or stable tumor cfDNA, platinum-doublet chemotherapy will be given.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>cfDNA blood test</intervention_name>
    <description>Blood sample will be taken for cfDNA testing</description>
    <arm_group_label>Non-Small cell Lung Cancer</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nivolumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Antineoplastic agent</description>
    <arm_group_label>Non-Small cell Lung Cancer</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ipilimumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Antineoplastic agent</description>
    <arm_group_label>Non-Small cell Lung Cancer</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Platinum-based Chemotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>May include carboplatin with gemcitabine, or paclitaxel or pemetrexed</description>
    <arm_group_label>Non-Small cell Lung Cancer</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years at the time of screening or age of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent obtained from the subject prior to performing any&#xD;
             protocol-related procedures, including screening evaluations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight ≥ 35 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have a life expectancy of at least 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recurrent or newly diagnosed metastatic non-small cell lung cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tumor PDL1 status &lt;50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-Squamous and squamous histologies are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologies with targetable mutations are not eligible, regardless of prior treatment&#xD;
             with tyrosine kinase inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No prior radiation, surgery or chemotherapy is allowed for the current diagnosis of&#xD;
             non-small cell lung cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate organ and marrow function&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of any conventional or investigational anticancer therapy within 21 days or&#xD;
             palliative radiotherapy within 14 days prior to the scheduled first dose of study&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior receipt of any immune-mediated therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Incomplete surgical resection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent enrolment in another therapeutic clinical study. Enrolment in observational&#xD;
             studies will be allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any toxicity (excluding alopecia) from prior standard therapy that has not been&#xD;
             completely resolved to baseline at the time of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with prior history of myocardial infarction, transient ischemic attack,&#xD;
             congestive heart failure ≥ Class 3 based on New York Heart Association Functional&#xD;
             Classification or stroke within the past 3 months prior to the scheduled first dose of&#xD;
             study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active or prior documented autoimmune disorders within the past 3 years prior to the&#xD;
             scheduled first dose of study treatment with exceptions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with confirmed human immunodeficiency virus (even if viral load is&#xD;
             undetectable), chronic or active hepatitis B or C, or active hepatitis A.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of primary immunodeficiency, solid organ transplantation, or active&#xD;
             tuberculosis (by clinical evaluation that includes clinical history, physical&#xD;
             examination and radiographic findings, and tuberculosis testing in line with local&#xD;
             practice).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other invasive malignancy within 2 years. Non-invasive malignancies (i.e., cervical&#xD;
             carcinoma in situ, in situ prostate cancer, non-melanomatous carcinoma of the skin,&#xD;
             ductal carcinoma in situ of the breast that has been surgically cured) are excluded&#xD;
             from this definition.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy or hypersensitivity to investigational product formulations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of more than one event of infusion related reactions requiring permanent&#xD;
             discontinuation of intravenous drug treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection requiring antibiotic therapy, uncontrolled hypertension, bleeding diatheses,&#xD;
             or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study&#xD;
             requirements, substantially increase risk of incurring adverse events, or compromise&#xD;
             the ability of the subject to give written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or prior use of immunosuppressive medication within 14 days prior to the&#xD;
             scheduled first dose of study treatment with exceptions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of live, attenuated vaccine within 30 days prior to the scheduled first dose&#xD;
             of study treatment - Major surgery within 28 days prior to scheduled first dose of&#xD;
             study treatment or still recovering from prior surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females who are pregnant, lactating, or intend to become pregnant during their&#xD;
             participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who are involuntarily incarcerated or are unable to willingly provide&#xD;
             consent or are unable to comply with the protocol procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would interfere with safe&#xD;
             administration or evaluation of the investigational products or interpretation of&#xD;
             subject safety or study results.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adrian Sacher, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Princess Margaret Cancer Centre</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Adrian Sacher, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>416-946-4501</phone>
    <phone_ext>3550</phone_ext>
    <email>adrian.sacher@uhn.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Princess Margaret Cancer Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5G 2M9</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Adrian Sacher, M.D.</last_name>
      <phone>416-946-4501</phone>
      <phone_ext>3550</phone_ext>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Adrian Sacher, M.D.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ipilimumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

