<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04962828</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>REC/00973</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04962828</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Inter Disciplinary Approach to Vocabulary Development in Hearing Impairment</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect Of An Inter Disciplinary Approach On Vocabulary Development in Children With Hearing Impairment; A Randomized Control Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Riphah International University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Riphah International University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The research aims to address to address the role of interdisciplinary working between&#xD;
      professionals in the field of speech and language pathology/therapy. There is considerable&#xD;
      evidence to state that when professionals work in collaboration with each other on particular&#xD;
      goals that the outcomes are more favorable, functional and beneficial for the child.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the current research is to devise a joint interventional program between the&#xD;
      speech and language pathologist and teachers in order to support their comprehension and&#xD;
      expression of functional vocabulary. This study was devised as there is a gap in&#xD;
      collaborative working by professionals in Pakistan. Often therapy is provided through a&#xD;
      medical model of taking the child outside the class for one to one sessions. There is lack of&#xD;
      lack of collaborative goal planning. This is particularly true for children who are in&#xD;
      hearing impairment centres.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Pakistan, the prevalence of all hearing loss in rural Pakistan has been estimated to be&#xD;
      7.9%, in a general population setting. The high prevalence rates are a source of concern. The&#xD;
      impact of hearing impairment manifests itself in many ways. As is evident from the studies&#xD;
      carried out on the impact of hearing impairment on vocabulary skills and speech-language and&#xD;
      communication difficulties in general of children and adolescents, that these difficulties if&#xD;
      not identified in a timely manner will affect later schooling and educational attainment.&#xD;
      Vocabulary knowledge is a key predictor of reading comprehension, which is essential for&#xD;
      academic progress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the field of early intervention and early childhood special education caregiver&#xD;
      involvement has been documented as important. Speech, language and communication needs (SLCN)&#xD;
      are prevalent among primary school-aged children. Collaboration between speech and language&#xD;
      therapists (SLTs) and teachers is beneficial for supporting children's communication skills.&#xD;
      Findings from an Australian study suggests that change to service delivery needs to be&#xD;
      considered at an individual, interpersonal and organizational level to enable better outcomes&#xD;
      for children with SLCN and increased support for their families and the professionals who&#xD;
      work with them.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hence, timely identification and management plays a pivotal role. It is critical that therapy&#xD;
      is provided in a manner as to generalize learnt skills. Research described speech therapy&#xD;
      services as largely happening outside of the classroom such as removing individuals or small&#xD;
      groups from the classroom for intervention sessions ('pull out') or that involve the&#xD;
      speech-language pathologist indirectly affecting the child's educational program by providing&#xD;
      modeling or coaching to relevant educators in the use of strategies to promote specific&#xD;
      skills ('consultation').&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is no denying that collaborative working is essential. A study comparing improvement on&#xD;
      a specific study measure designed on selected vocabulary in 12 classrooms with 3 conditions:&#xD;
      (1) Pull-out - 50-minute group or one to one sessions for twelve weeks. (2) Classroom-based -&#xD;
      Weekly 40-minute lessons for 12 weeks (3) Collaborative - Weekly 40-minute SLP-teacher&#xD;
      planned and team taught lessons for 12 weeks. The results suggested evidence for the benefits&#xD;
      of collaborative working such as the ability to discuss, design and plan between the teacher&#xD;
      and SLP, resulting in greater outcomes and facilitating generalization of the activities in&#xD;
      students who require it the most. The study sheds light on the need for such collaboration&#xD;
      and provides evidence sums for further research to address similar outcomes in Pakistan.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 26, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 26, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Vocabulary List</measure>
    <time_frame>9th week</time_frame>
    <description>There will be 10 functional words that will be designed post collaboration with the teachers. The list will accommodate 6 Ling sounds and will be implemented with both groups. The participants will be tested on the list pre-intervention and post intervention. Scoring will be based on binary responses such as correct and incorrect responses. Any further responses will be addressed qualitatively.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Hearing Impaired Children</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Collaboration group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group of children will have targets and vocabulary that has been designed collaboratively and then the therapist and teacher both reinforce the vocabulary during the week</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non-collaborative group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group of children will have targets and vocabulary that has been designed collaboratively but they will only be practiced with the therapist during the week</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vocabulary based intervention- Non Collaborative</intervention_name>
    <description>List of 10 words functional words Therapy 3 times a week for 20 minutes Duration = 9 weeks Only with SLP</description>
    <arm_group_label>Non-collaborative group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Language Intervention</other_name>
    <other_name>Language Intervention for Hearing Impairment</other_name>
    <other_name>Total Communication</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vocabulary based intervention - Collaborative</intervention_name>
    <description>List of 10 words functional words Therapy 3 times a week for 20 minutes Duration = 9 weeks With SLP and to be reinforced by teachers in class over the week</description>
    <arm_group_label>Collaboration group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Language Therapy</other_name>
    <other_name>Inter-disciplinary working</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hearing impaired children from 6 to 11 years of age who have severe unilateral or&#xD;
             bilateral hearing loss from birth and for whom Urdu has their first language. There&#xD;
             hearing age is at least one year. Their parents were not hearing impaired. Children&#xD;
             used hearing aids. Unilateral &amp; bilateral hearing impaired children were equally&#xD;
             distributed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children who did not present with HI as their main diagnosis or may have other&#xD;
             co-morbid conditions.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ayesha Butt, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Riphah International University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Waqar Amjad, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>03335348846</phone>
    <email>waqar.ahmad@riphah.edu.pk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aghosh Special Children's School</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kharian</city>
        <state>Punjab</state>
        <zip>46000</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mathers C, Smith A, Concha M. Global Burden Of Hearing Loss In The Year 2000. Global Burden Of Disease. 2000;18(4):1-30.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McGregor KK, Oleson J, Bahnsen A, Duff D. Children with developmental language impairment have vocabulary deficits characterized by limited breadth and depth. Int J Lang Commun Disord. 2013 May-Jun;48(3):307-19. doi: 10.1111/1460-6984.12008. Epub 2013 Feb 25.</citation>
    <PMID>23650887</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Suleman S, Mcfarlane La, Pollock K, Schneider P, Leroy C, Skoczylas M. Collaboration: More Than</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ebbels SH, McCartney E, Slonims V, Dockrell JE, Norbury CF. Evidence-based pathways to intervention for children with language disorders. Int J Lang Commun Disord. 2019 Jan;54(1):3-19. doi: 10.1111/1460-6984.12387. Epub 2018 Apr 25.</citation>
    <PMID>29696726</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wilson L, McneillBc, Gillon Gt. Understanding The Effectiveness Of Student Speech-Language Pathologists And Student Teachers Co-Working During Inter-Professional School Placements. Child Language Teaching And Therapy. 2019 Jun;35(2):125-43.( 7)</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lowe H, Henry L, Joffe VL. The Effectiveness of Classroom Vocabulary Intervention for Adolescents With Language Disorder. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2019 Aug 15;62(8):2829-2846. doi: 10.1044/2019_JSLHR-L-18-0337. Epub 2019 Jul 24.</citation>
    <PMID>31339808</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Glover A, Mccormack J, Smith-Tamaray M. Collaboration Between Teachers And Speech And Language Therapists: Services For Primary School Children With Speech, Language And Communication Needs. Child Language Teaching And Therapy. 2015 Oct;31(3):363-82.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Murray E, McCabe P, Ballard KJ. A comparison of two treatments for childhood apraxia of speech: methods and treatment protocol for a parallel group randomised control trial. BMC Pediatr. 2012 Aug 3;12:112. doi: 10.1186/1471-2431-12-112.</citation>
    <PMID>22863021</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Spencer TD, Petersen DB, Adams JL. Tier 2 Language Intervention for Diverse Preschoolers: An Early-Stage Randomized Control Group Study Following an Analysis of Response to Intervention. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 2015 Nov;24(4):619-36. doi: 10.1044/2015_AJSLP-14-0101.</citation>
    <PMID>26125951</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thomas DC, McCabe P, Ballard KJ. Combined clinician-parent delivery of rapid syllable transition (ReST) treatment for childhood apraxia of speech. Int J Speech Lang Pathol. 2018 Dec;20(7):683-698. doi: 10.1080/17549507.2017.1316423. Epub 2017 Apr 26.</citation>
    <PMID>28443686</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hearing Impairment</keyword>
  <keyword>Language Intervention</keyword>
  <keyword>Interdisciplinary working</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hearing Loss</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Deafness</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual participant data will not be shared with other researchers</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

