<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04965376</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pending</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04965376</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Trial Comparing Glenohumeral Joint Steroid Injection Versus Suprascapular Nerve Block in Patients With Frozen Shoulder</brief_title>
  <acronym>TIFFS</acronym>
  <official_title>Therapeutic Injections for Frozen Shoulder (TIFFS Study)- Comparing Suprascapular Nerve Block Versus Intra-articular Glenohumeral Joint Injection. A Randomised Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Blackpool Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Blackpool Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to determine if there is any difference in terms of pain relief in&#xD;
      patients with frozen shoulder, when given a steroid injection as a suprascapular nerve block&#xD;
      compared to a glenohumeral joint intra-articular injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our hypothesis is that there is a significant difference in terms of pain relief at 3 months,&#xD;
      6 months and 1 year between a steroid injection as a suprascapular nerve block compared to a&#xD;
      glenohumeral joint intra-articular injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who attend the orthopaedic clinic and are diagnosed with unilateral frozen shoulder&#xD;
      and who are suitable to be treated with a steroid injection will be identified. If the&#xD;
      patient consents to having a steroid injection, he/she will then be invited to participate in&#xD;
      the trial where they will have an injection either into the glenohumeral joint (ball and&#xD;
      socket joint of the shoulder) or as a suprascapular nerve block (injection adjacent to a&#xD;
      nerve over the shoulder blade) under ultrasound guidance. Patients will then be followed up&#xD;
      at 3, 6 and 12 months after their injection and asked to complete a set of questionnaires&#xD;
      assessing pain, function and movement. The results of the groups will then be compared to see&#xD;
      if one treatment is superior to the other.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a single centre, parallel, two-arm, randomized clinical trial. The trial is expected&#xD;
      to take a total of 3 years with 12-18 months for patient recruitment, 12 months for follow up&#xD;
      and 6-12 months for data collection, analysis and publication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The null hypothesis is that there will be no differences in terms of pain relief at 3 months,&#xD;
      6 months and 1 year between a steroid injection as a suprascapular nerve block compared to a&#xD;
      glenohumeral joint intra-articular injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adult patients diagnosed with unilateral frozen shoulder who are suitable to be treated with&#xD;
      a steroid injection will receive a verbal explanation of the study by a suitably qualified&#xD;
      member of the research team alongside an information leaflet. Eligible, consented&#xD;
      participants will be randomised in a 1:1 ratio by the selection of sealed, opaque envelopes&#xD;
      with one of the two injection types documented inside. Participants will be free to withdraw&#xD;
      from the study at any time without prejudice. The injection types include an ultrasound&#xD;
      guided steroid injection into the glenohumeral joint (10mls of 1% lidocaine with 40mg&#xD;
      depo-medrone) or an ultrasound guided steroid injection as a suprascapular nerve block at the&#xD;
      spinoglenoid notch adjacent to the nerve as it traverses under the spinoglenoid ligament&#xD;
      (10mls of 1% lidocaine with 40mg depo-medrone. Following both injections, patients are taken&#xD;
      through a protocol of physiotherapy for their frozen shoulder over the subsequent 3 months.&#xD;
      Participants will be seen back in the outpatient clinic 3 months after their injection to&#xD;
      review their progress and collect follow-up data. Further follow-up data will be collected by&#xD;
      the completion of questionnaires via post at 6 months and 12 months after the injection. The&#xD;
      primary outcome measure of this study is the Oxford Shoulder Score (OSS) at 3 months&#xD;
      post-injection. Secondary end points include Oxford Shoulder Score at 6 months and 1 year,&#xD;
      pain using the Pain Numeric Rating Scale at 3 months, 6 months and 1 year, Quick Disabilities&#xD;
      of Arm, Shoulder and Hand (QuickDASH) questionnaire at 3 months, 6 months and 1 year and&#xD;
      EQ-5D-5L at 3 months, 6 months and 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline demographic and clinical variables will be reported using summary statistics. In&#xD;
      terms of the primary outcome, the change in total Oxford Shoulder Score from baseline to 3&#xD;
      months post-injection will be compared between the two groups using either the Independent&#xD;
      Samples t-Test or Mann-Whitney U Test, with the final choice depending on an exploration of&#xD;
      the data. The same approach will be adopted for secondary outcomes. All analysis will be&#xD;
      performed according to the intention to treat principle.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxford Shoulder Score (OSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months post-injection</time_frame>
    <description>Patient will complete in clinic</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxford Shoulder Score</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months and 12 months post-injection</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months, 6 months and 12 months post-injection</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quick Disabilities of Arm, Shoulder and Hand (QuickDASH)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months, 6 months and 12 months post-injection</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EuroQol-5 Dimension-5 level (EQ-5D-5L)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months, 6 months and 12 months post-injection</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Frozen Shoulder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Glenohumeral joint injection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Ultrasound guided steroid injection into the glenohumeral joint (10mls of 1% lidocaine with 40mg depo-medrone)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Suprascapular nerve block</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Ultrasound guided steroid injection as a suprascapular nerve block at the spinoglenoid notch adjacent to the nerve as it traverses under the spinoglenoid ligament (10mls of 1% lidocaine with 40mg depo-medrone)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Glenohumeral joint steroid injection</intervention_name>
    <description>Ultrasound guided steroid injection into the glenohumeral joint (10mls of 1% lidocaine with 40mg depo-medrone)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Glenohumeral joint injection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Suprascapular nerve block steroid injection</intervention_name>
    <description>Ultrasound guided steroid injection as a suprascapular nerve block at the spinoglenoid notch adjacent to the nerve as it traverses under the spinoglenoid ligament (10mls of 1% lidocaine with 40mg depo-medrone)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Suprascapular nerve block</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient diagnosed with unilateral frozen shoulder, age greater than or equal to 18&#xD;
             years. Diagnosis of frozen shoulder will be based on clinical examination (restriction&#xD;
             of passive external rotation in the affected shoulder &gt; 50% compared to opposite&#xD;
             site), in the presence of normal plain radiographs (antero-posterior and axillary&#xD;
             projections) (other than calcific tendinopathy).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age less than 18 years, lacking capacity/unable to give valid consent for&#xD;
             participation, full thickness rotator cuff tear diagnosed on either Ultrasound scan or&#xD;
             Magnetic Resonance Imaging, unable to complete follow up, unable to speak or read&#xD;
             English, allergy to corticosteroid or local anaesthetic, simultaneous bilateral frozen&#xD;
             shoulder.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Charalambos P Charalambous</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Blackpool Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Charalambos P Charalambous</last_name>
    <phone>01253 300000</phone>
    <email>mr.charalambous@nhs.net</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Blackpool Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Charalambos Charalambous</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Mr Charalambous</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bursitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data will be published in peer review journal on completion of the study.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

