<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04960332</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Prevena-RH-2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04960332</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Negative Pressure Wound Therapy After Surgical Removal of Deep-Seated High-Malignant Soft Tissue Sarcomas of the Extremities and Trunk Wall.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Negative Pressure Wound Therapy After Surgical Removal of Deep-Seated High-Malignant Soft Tissue Sarcomas of the Extremities and Trunk Wall. A Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this research project is to improve the surgical treatment of Soft Tissue&#xD;
      Sarcoma (STS) treatment based upon a Randomized Controlled Trial (RCT). We want to evaluate&#xD;
      the effect of the use of Negative Pressure Wound Therapy (NPWT) versus a conventional wound&#xD;
      dressing on postoperative wound complications after surgical removal of deep-seated&#xD;
      high-malignant STS of the extremities or trunk wall.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sarcomas are a heterogeneous group of rare malignant tumors of mesenchymal cell origin in the&#xD;
      musculoskeletal system comprising 1% of all adult cancers. The reported incidence of all&#xD;
      types of sarcomas is approximately six to eight per 100,000 inhabitants corresponding to 300&#xD;
      cases per year in Denmark (250 STS (100 retroperitoneal/abdominal STS), 50 bone sarcomas).&#xD;
      Sarcomas arise in the body's connective tissues including bone, muscle, cartilage, fat&#xD;
      tissue, blood vessels, and peripheral nerve-sheaths and hence arise in all parts of the body&#xD;
      although most dominant in the extremities (78%).&#xD;
&#xD;
      There exist more than 50 histologic subtypes of STS yielding a broad heterogeneous morphology&#xD;
      and biological behavior of all subtypes. The incidence of STS is in general increasing with&#xD;
      age (median age=65). High-grade soft tissue sarcomas mostly metastasize hematogenous to the&#xD;
      lungs, which is also the primary cause of sarcoma-specific death and approximately 10% of&#xD;
      patients with STS have metastases at diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment of STS requires a multidisciplinary highly specialized team, evaluating risks and&#xD;
      benefits of all available options and expected outcomes with the aim to minimize the&#xD;
      recurrence of disease and preserve function and quality of life. The main treatment&#xD;
      principles that have largely been unchanged since the 1980ies is surgery supplemented with&#xD;
      adjuvant radiotherapy depending on subtype and stage. The use of NPWT after high-risk&#xD;
      orthopedic surgeries such as e.g. amputations, treatment of open fractures and joint&#xD;
      replacement surgery are increasing, but the direct cost is much higher compared to the&#xD;
      conventional wound dressing. However, previous studies have shown that NPWT can reduce&#xD;
      postoperative complications such as wound dehiscence and infection. STS surgery that is often&#xD;
      combined with pre-or postoperative radiation therapy is a high-risk procedure concerning&#xD;
      wound complications and postoperative infections. A retrospective study showed that NPWT&#xD;
      reduced the risk of wound complications in patients with lower extremity STS treated with&#xD;
      preoperative radiation and the use of NPWT was not associated with an increased risk of local&#xD;
      recurrence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design&#xD;
&#xD;
      RCT (no blinding) where the patients will be randomized to wound closure with staples and&#xD;
      either NPWT (PREVENA PLUS™ Incision Management System) for 7 days or a conventional wound&#xD;
      dressing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization&#xD;
&#xD;
      All 160 patients will in the operating room be randomized (randomization with 80 in each&#xD;
      group) to receive one of the two treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group A: Standard wound closure with staples and conventional wound dressing. Group B: Wound&#xD;
      closure with staples and NPWT (PREVENA PLUS™ Incision Management System).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Block randomization with 8 patients in each block stratified for upper extremity/truncal wall&#xD;
      or lower extremity STS verified using a computerized irreversible application - the Research&#xD;
      Electronic Data Capture (REDCap). The randomization sequence will be computer-generated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Institutions&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Rigshospitalet, University of Copenhagen: The surgeries&#xD;
      will be performed in this department, Rigshospitalet in Copenhagen is a tertiary&#xD;
      multidisciplinary center performing highly specialized tumor surgeries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients&#xD;
&#xD;
      Identification and inclusion Patients evaluated at a multidisciplinary conference and&#xD;
      afterward with a biopsy verified STS will be identified in Sundhedsplatformen (electronic&#xD;
      patient journal), the only information needed from the patient journal prior informed consent&#xD;
      is when they will meet in the outpatient clinic. Patients eligible for inclusion will at&#xD;
      their first outpatient visit to plan further final surgery be informed about the study&#xD;
      written and orally. On the day of their surgery written informed consent will be obtained if&#xD;
      they want to participate in this study. No patient will have below 48 hours to answer,&#xD;
      complied with the Helsinki declaration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will be informed orally and written by the principal investigator, information&#xD;
      will be given in a separate room allocated for only the patient and if wanted the assessor,&#xD;
      so interruption occurs. All patient will be asked if they want an assessor and so a new&#xD;
      meeting will be allocated and the information will again in a separate room allocated for the&#xD;
      patient and the assessor be given by the principal investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The written informed consent gives the principal investigator, sponsor and sponsor's&#xD;
      representatives as well as any control authority direct access to obtain information in the&#xD;
      patient's medical record, etc., including electronic medical record, in order to see&#xD;
      information about the subject's health, which is necessary in carrying out the research&#xD;
      project and for control purposes, including self-monitoring, quality control and monitoring,&#xD;
      which they are required to perform.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants are covered by the Danish Patient Compensation Association.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research plan&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Clinical wound follow-up (n=160): preoperatively, 7 days, time for removal of staples&#xD;
           and 4 months after surgery. To all examinations, clinical photos of the wound will be&#xD;
           taken and stored in Sundhedsplatformen (electronic patient journal).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Clinical function evaluation (n=160): Musculoskeletal Tumor Society Score (MSTS) and&#xD;
           Toronto Extremity Salvage Score (TESS) 4 months and 1 year postoperatively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient's wounds will be followed with photo documentation on day 0, day 7, at definitive&#xD;
      wound healing (removal of staples), 4 months postoperatively and in case of major wound&#xD;
      complication by a member of the department staff or research group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up from day 7 and further on will be performed in the outpatient regime, at&#xD;
      Rigshospitalet, orthopedic department, patients will be convened through e-boks and if&#xD;
      necessary, transport will be provided.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Calculation of sample size&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the study of O'Sullivan et al. a major wound complication within 4 months postoperatively&#xD;
      was identified in 16 out of 94 (17%) in the group of STS patients treated with surgery and&#xD;
      postoperative radiation therapy. There exist no studies evaluating the effect of NPWT on&#xD;
      wound complications after surgery for STS combined with postoperative radiation therapy.&#xD;
      However, in retrospective studies it was found that NPWT reduced the risk of wound&#xD;
      complications from 47% to 8% (83% reduction) in patients with lower extremity STS treated&#xD;
      with preoperative radiation [14] and from 27% to 7% (75% reduction) in patients undergoing&#xD;
      hip and knee revision surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a study design with an 80% risk of avoiding type II error, a 5% risk of type I error and&#xD;
      an 80% wound complication risk reduction in a population similar to the study by O'Sullivan&#xD;
      et al. the investigators will need to include 154 STS patients (77 in each group) in an RCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To make allowance for dropouts (since the follow-up period regarding the primary study&#xD;
      endpoint is only 4 months = 120 days few dropouts are expected) during the study period the&#xD;
      investigators plan to include 160 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Risks, side effects and disadvantages&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators do not expect that the patients participating in the study will experience&#xD;
      any special side effects or complications related directly to the specific use of NPWT or the&#xD;
      standard wound closure. The dressing may for some patients give a mild skin irritation of the&#xD;
      skin under the enclosed dressing or a slight discomfort with having to wear an occlusive&#xD;
      dressing. Any skin irritation that is transient (i.e., resolves within 24 hours following&#xD;
      device use and requires no medical intervention), will not be classified as an adverse device&#xD;
      effect. Some blistering formations have been reported in relation to total hip and knee&#xD;
      replacement surgery, but no more than tape trauma in patients with conventional dressing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A retrospective study showed that NPWT reduced the risk of wound complications in patients&#xD;
      with lower extremity STS treated with preoperative radiation and the use of NPWT was not&#xD;
      associated with an increased risk of local recurrence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      No risk or side effects are reported by the manufacture when adhering to the manual of use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prevena™ NPWT are used daily at the orthopedic department, it is a CE classified medical&#xD;
      devised and due to use in the recommended field approval from danish medicines agency are not&#xD;
      necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethical considerations&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will not be started until approval from the Scientific Ethical Committee of the&#xD;
      Capital Region of Denmark and the Danish Data Protection Agency has been obtained, and it&#xD;
      will be registered at clinicaltrials.gov before the inclusion of patients. All patients will&#xD;
      receive both oral and written information before written informed consent to participate is&#xD;
      obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The regulation from data protection regulation and data protection act will always be&#xD;
      followed and a permission from data protection agency have been obtained (P-2021-150).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The significant use of the present study is new knowledge concerning the best way to treat a&#xD;
      certain group of patients with deep-seated STS of an extremity or the trunk wall. Knowledge&#xD;
      from our study will benefit society in general, and optimize utilization of resources, in&#xD;
      terms of the best treatment for future patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In case of serious adverse preliminary results, data will be analyzed and if one of the&#xD;
      treatments is found to cause significant critical problems compared to the other (p&lt;0.05),&#xD;
      the study will be ended. The study is thus designed to minimize unnecessary risks to the&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fisher's exact test will be used for categorical variables. Depending on if the data could be&#xD;
      considered normally distributed or not, a t-test for unpaired data or Mann-Whitney U test&#xD;
      will be used for continuous variables.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Kaplan Meier survival analysis for overall survival (with log-rank test for comparison of&#xD;
      groups). In case of an assumption of a difference in time to delayed wound healing, competing&#xD;
      risk analysis will be used to address differences between the groups with death and&#xD;
      amputation as competing factors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All analyses will be performed in accordance with the intention-to-treat principles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two-sided p-values below 0.05 will be considered statistically significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Time frame&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to the latest report from the Danish Sarcoma Registry, there were approximately 900&#xD;
      newly diagnosed sarcomas in Eastern Denmark (Rigshospitalet) during the 5 years from 2014 to&#xD;
      2018. The majority, but not all of the patients are suffering from high-malignant deep-seated&#xD;
      STS of the extremities or the trunk wall. The inclusion of patients in the study will start&#xD;
      at the first half of of 2021 thus leaving at least 3 years for inclusion and reserve 6 months&#xD;
      for the PhD-student to do data management and writing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective randomized controlled trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Wound complication/healing</measure>
    <time_frame>120 days postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>A major wound complication defined as in O'Sullivan et al. [11]:&#xD;
A secondary surgery under anesthesia for wound repairs such as debridement, operative drainage and secondary wound closure.&#xD;
Wound management without secondary surgery, this includes invasive procedure without anesthesia such as aspiration of seroma and readmission for wound care such as intravenous antibiotic or persistent deep packing within 4 months (120 days) after surgery.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary outcome measures, hospital stay.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Length of hospital stay (measured in days)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary outcome measures, readmission.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Readmission to hospital for treatment of a wound complication (measured in days from primary surgery)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary outcome measures, primary wound healing.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Time to primary wound healing and removal of staples, ready for radiation therapy (measured in days from primary surgery)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary outcome measures, deep infection.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Deep infection (measured in days from primary surgery, any medical or surgical interventions will be described)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary outcome measures, seroma.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Postoperative seroma development (measured in days from primary surgery)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary outcome measures, MSTS.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Musculoskeletal Tumor Society Score (MSTS)&#xD;
MSTS score is a physician-completed score containing following categories:&#xD;
Pain&#xD;
Function&#xD;
Emotional acceptance&#xD;
Support/Assistive device&#xD;
Walking&#xD;
Gait&#xD;
Maximum score is 30 (the value will often be presented in percentage of total).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary outcome measures, TESS.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Toronto Extremity Salvage Score (TESS)&#xD;
TESS is a self-administrated questionnaire that evaluates physical disability, it consists of 29 questions for upper-extremity and 30 for lower-extremity. Each question is scored from 1-5, where 5 is given if there are no problems. Values will often be presented as a percentage of the total possible amount.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary outcome measures, 5Q-5D.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>European Quality of Life - 5 Dimensions (EQ-5D)&#xD;
EQ-5D is a self-reported questionnaire to evaluate the quality of life, it has 5 dimensions:&#xD;
Mobility&#xD;
Personal hygiene&#xD;
Usual activities&#xD;
Pain&#xD;
Anxiety/depression Each dimension is evaluated with a score of 1-5, where 1 is given to patients without problems. Each answer has a different weight in values and the values for a Danish population will be used in analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">160</enrollment>
  <condition>Sarcoma</condition>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Neoplasms, Connective and Soft Tissue</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group A: Standard wound closure with staples and conventional wound dressing.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prevena</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group B: Wound closure with staples and Negative Pressure Wound Therapy (PREVENA PLUS™ Incision Management System).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prevena</intervention_name>
    <description>RCT (no blinding) where the patients will be randomized to wound closure with staples and either Negative Pressure Wound Therapy (PREVENA PLUS™ Incision Management System) for 7 days or a conventional wound dressing.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prevena</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Surgery for a deep-seated STS of an extremity or the trunk wall at Rigshospitalet.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Wound closure not possible without plastic surgery (pedicled or free flaps)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Low malignant (Trojani grade 1) STS or borderline tumors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre- or postoperative chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preoperative radiotherapy to the local site.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergic or hypersensitive to acrylic adhesives or silver&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling or unable to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to comply with planned study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with metastatic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with ischemic surgery such as bypass or endovascular prosthesis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Müjgan Yilmaz, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Müjgan Yilmaz, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+45 29387478</phone>
    <email>muejgan.yilmaz.01@regionh.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Michael Mørk Petersen, Prof.</last_name>
    <phone>+45 35458900</phone>
    <email>Michael.moerk.petersen@regionh.dk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rigshospitalet</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen</city>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michael Mørk Petersen, Professor</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Müjgan Yilmaz</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PhD student and Medical Doctor, department of orthopedic surgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Negative Pressure Wound Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Prevena</keyword>
  <keyword>Sarcoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Neoplasms, Connective and Soft Tissue</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Connective and Soft Tissue</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The regulation from data protection regulation and data protection act will always be followed and a permission from data protection agency have been obtained (P-2021-150).</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

