<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04961229</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0192-21-RMC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04961229</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Booster Dose of COVID-19 Vaccine for Kidney Transplant Recipients Without Adequate Humoral Response</brief_title>
  <acronym>WHO</acronym>
  <official_title>Booster Dose of mRNA SARS-CoV-2 Vaccine for Kidney Transplant Recipients Without Adequate Humoral Response With or Without Immunosuppression Reduction - Protocol for a Randomised Controlled Trial (BECAME Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>dafna yahav</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rabin Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Introduction: Inadequate antibody response to mRNA SARS-CoV-2 vaccination has been described&#xD;
      among kidney transplant recipients. Immunosuppression level and specifically, use of&#xD;
      antimetabolite in the maintenance immunosuppressive regimen, are associated with inadequate&#xD;
      response. In light of the severe consequences of COVID-19 in solid organ transplant&#xD;
      recipients, we believe it is justified to examine new vaccination strategies in these&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods and analysis: BECAME is a single center, open label, investigator-initiated&#xD;
      randomised controlled, superiority trial, aiming to compare immunosuppression reduction&#xD;
      combined with a third BNT162b2 vaccine dose versus third dose alone. The primary outcome will&#xD;
      be seropositivity rate against SARS-CoV-2. A sample size of 154 patients was calculated for&#xD;
      the seropositivity endpoint assuming 25% seropositivity in the control group and 50% in the&#xD;
      intervention group. A sample of participant per arm will be also teste for T-cell response.&#xD;
      We also plan to perform a prospective observational study, evaluating seropositivity among&#xD;
      ~350 kidney transplant recipients consenting to receive a third vaccine dose, who are not&#xD;
      eligible for the randomised controlled trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethics and dissemination: The trial is approved by local ethics committee of Rabin medical&#xD;
      center (RMC-0192- 21). Results of this trial will be published; trial data will be available.&#xD;
      Protocol amendments will be submitted to the local ethics committee.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      All recipients more than 6 months post transplantation and at least 3 weeks following second&#xD;
      vaccine dose will be approached and invited to a first study visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At first visit:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Signed informed consent will be obtained from participants willing to participate by&#xD;
           study investigators who usually work in the transplantation clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Anti-spike antibody response will be assessed using SARS-CoV-2 IgG II Quant (Abbott©)&#xD;
           assay. Participants who have a documented seronegative test in the last 6 weeks will not&#xD;
           be tested again.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be invited for an additional visit once negative serology will be reported,&#xD;
      within 7 days of serology collection. At this second visit all participants who gave informed&#xD;
      consent to participate in either the prospective non-randomised study or RCT will receive a&#xD;
      single vaccine dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, participants in the RCT will be randomised into two groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Third booster dose of BNT162b2 (one standard dose) with no change in immunosuppression&#xD;
           protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Third booster dose of BNT162b2 (one standard dose) with immunosuppression reduction&#xD;
           according to protocol (mycophenolic temporary cessation 4 days before (5 half-lives) and&#xD;
           one week (expected antibody response) after vaccination (to allow for antibody&#xD;
           response).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who will test seronegative will be informed by the study coordinator by phone in&#xD;
      which study arm they will be participating and receive instructions for immunosuppression&#xD;
      reduction both during the phone call and by written instructions provided to each patient&#xD;
      during the first visit (see Appendix). Participants in the observational study will receive a&#xD;
      third vaccine standard dose, without any change in immunosuppression (beyond routine care)&#xD;
&#xD;
      For all groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Antibodies titer against spike protein will be evaluated again 2 weeks and 3, 6, 12&#xD;
           months after the third vaccine dose&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  T-cell response will be evaluated for a subset of patients in each group (estimated 20&#xD;
           patients per arm) before booster dose, at 2 weeks after booster dose, and at 3 months.&#xD;
           For T cell response quantification peripheral blood mononuclear cell (PBMC) will be&#xD;
           stimulated for 24 hours with spike protein and secreted interferon-gamma (IFNg) will be&#xD;
           measured by ELISA.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Follow-up for adverse events, rejection and SARS-CoV-2 infection will be performed at 2&#xD;
           weeks and at three, 6 and 12 months post third vaccination dose&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>anti-spike protein titer above 50 AU/ml 2 weeks post vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks post vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>positive humoral response against SARS-CoV-2</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>anti-spike protein titer above 50 AU/ml 3-, 6-, and 12-months post vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>3-, 6-, and 12-months post vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>positive humoral response against SARS-CoV-2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Log transformed titer of anti-spike protein weeks and 3, 6, and 12 months post vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks and 3, 6, and 12 months post vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Log transformed titer of anti-spike protein</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events to booster dose using CTCAE v4.0 criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks post vaccine</time_frame>
    <description>Severity of adverse events will be assessed using CTCAE v4.0 criteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acute rejection of the allograft either documented by biopsy or clinically suspected, defined as increase in creatinine by 20% from baseline, without any other plausible explanation</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks, 3,6, and 12 months post vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>either documented by biopsy or clinically suspected, defined as increase in creatinine by 20% from baseline, without any other plausible explanation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>positive PCR test to SARS-CoV-2 during the follow up period</measure>
    <time_frame>until 12 months following vaccine</time_frame>
    <description>positive PCR test to SARS-CoV-2 during the follow up period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Positive PCR tests to VZV, CMV</measure>
    <time_frame>during the follow up period</time_frame>
    <description>Other viral reactivation during the follow up period: VZV, CMV, tested according to clinical suspicion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of hospitalizations (numerical count)</measure>
    <time_frame>until 12 months following vaccine</time_frame>
    <description>Number of hospitalizations</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">504</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19 Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Immunosuppression</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Third dose of BNT162b2 vaccine with Immunosuppression reduction</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Third dose of BNT162b2 vaccine with reduction of mycophenolic acid dose</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Third dose of BNT162b2 vaccine without immunosuppression reduction</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Third dose of BNT162b2 vaccine without reduction of mycophenolic acid dose</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Third dose of BNT162b2 vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Third dose of BNT162b2 vaccine with no change in immunosuppression for patients that are excluded from the randomised trial</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The Pfizer mRNA-based BNT162b2 vaccine</intervention_name>
    <description>participants who gave informed consent to participate in either the prospective non-randomised study or RCT will receive a single vaccine dose.&#xD;
In addition, participants in the RCT will be randomised into two groups:&#xD;
Third booster dose of BNT162b2 (one standard dose) with no change in immunosuppression protocol&#xD;
Third booster dose of BNT162b2 (one standard dose) with immunosuppression reduction according to protocol (mycophenolic temporary cessation 4 days before (5 half-lives) and one week (expected antibody response) after vaccination (to allow for antibody response).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Third dose of BNT162b2 vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Third dose of BNT162b2 vaccine with Immunosuppression reduction</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Third dose of BNT162b2 vaccine without immunosuppression reduction</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  kidney transplant recipients that received two doses of BNT162b2 vaccine at least 3&#xD;
             weeks prior to enrollment, and were seronegative (IgG against the spike protein of&#xD;
             SARS-CoV-2 below 50 AU/ml) at least two weeks after the second vaccine dose&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional inclusion criteria for the RCT:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipients treated by three anti-rejection medications including: prednisone,&#xD;
             tacrolimus, mycophenolate mofetil or mycophenolic acid.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tacrolimus trough blood levels 5-10 nGr/ml (lower or higher doses will have to be&#xD;
             adjusted before re-considering for inclusion)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Past infection with SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age below 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional exclusion criteria for RCT only:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Recipients at a high risk for acute or chronic humoral rejection including:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipients with positive panel-reactive antibody (PRA) (any positive value) at any&#xD;
             time before or after transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipients that had an acute rejection in the last year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipients less than 6 months after transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipients that are considered at high risk for rejection according to the primary&#xD;
             care nephrologist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipients taking less than 3 anti-rejection medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipients currently treated with mTOR inhibitors (everolimus, sirolimus) and/or&#xD;
             azathioprine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipients treated with plasmapheresis in the previous 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipients treated with eculizumab in the last year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipient treated with IVIG in the previous 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipient treated with rituximab in the previous 6 months&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ruth Rahaminov</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rabin Medical Center, Beilinson Campus, Petah-Tikva, Israel</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ruth Rahaminov</last_name>
    <phone>97239376475</phone>
    <email>rutir@clalit.org.il</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rabin Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>dafna yahav</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Professor, Infectious Diseases Unit, Rabin Medical Center, Beilinson Campus, Petah-Tikva, Israel</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>kidney transplant recipients</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>vaccine</keyword>
  <keyword>immunosuppression reduction</keyword>
  <keyword>randomized controlled trial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acute Lung Injury</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>According to request</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The data will become available once entered for all patients and analyzed, presumably at 1-January-2022. It will be available for one year.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Researchers who would like to share the data will be requested to send the PI their protocol/reason for asking the data. After reviewing the request, if the protocol seems adequate in terms of clinical question and methodological quality, we will share anonymized data.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

