<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01273194</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>110063</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>11-CC-0063</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01273194</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating Supportive Care for Children With Cancer: A Multi-Institutional Survey Study of Pediatric Oncology Patients and Parents</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluating Supportive Care for Children With Cancer: A Multi-Institutional Survey Study of Pediatric Oncology Patients and Parents</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Palliative care, also known as comfort care, is intended to keep a patient comfortable by&#xD;
      focusing on pain and symptom management to improve quality of life. Although palliative care&#xD;
      has been demonstrated to be beneficial, it is underutilized in children who have been&#xD;
      diagnosed with cancer, because current trends favor palliative care primarily at the end of&#xD;
      life and in only a small number of patients. Children with cancer likely would benefit from&#xD;
      the incorporation of palliative care from the time of diagnosis, but both doctors and&#xD;
      families are often reluctant to include it for a variety of reasons. Researchers are&#xD;
      interested in understanding these reasons to determine better ways to include palliative care&#xD;
      as part of cancer treatment methods in children with cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To collect information on pediatric oncology patients and their parents attitudes towards&#xD;
      palliative care, along with cancer treatment, from the time of diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Children and adolescents between 10 and 17 years of age who have been diagnosed with&#xD;
           cancer in the past year.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Parents of eligible children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will complete a 30-minute survey about experiences with pain, symptom&#xD;
           management, and focus on quality of life in the first month following cancer diagnosis.&#xD;
           Child participants will be asked about their views on the importance of quality of life&#xD;
           in the beginning of their illness, as well as their attitudes toward symptom-oriented&#xD;
           care. Parent participants will be asked questions about their child s illness, which&#xD;
           includes understanding, discussion, and impact of illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Treatment will not be provided as part of this protocol.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Palliative care, while demonstrated to be beneficial, is underutilized in pediatric&#xD;
           oncology.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The current model in the U.S. favors palliative care involvement primarily at the end of&#xD;
           life and only in a fraction of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Children with cancer likely would benefit from the incorporation of palliative care from&#xD;
           the time of diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Obstacles to the incorporation of palliative care from the time of diagnosis include the&#xD;
           possibility that the current model provides sufficient care in these areas and the&#xD;
           possibility that families may be averse to early palliative care involvement on the&#xD;
           grounds that it would be intrusive, detract from their goal of cure, and/or lead to a&#xD;
           loss of hope.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To gather data relevant to evaluating these potential obstacles, we plan to interview&#xD;
           pediatric oncology patients and their parents to determine their views regarding&#xD;
           provision of palliative care, along with cancer therapy, from the time of diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Primary&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  To assess parent and patient attitudes toward the integration of palliative care in&#xD;
                pediatric oncology patients from the time of diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  To develop a survey instrument that can reliably assess the views of pediatric&#xD;
                oncology patients and their parents with regard to patients symptom burden and&#xD;
                management at the beginning of cancer therapy as well as attitudes toward early&#xD;
                integration of palliative care with oncology care.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Secondary/Specific Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  To assess the degree and effect of negative symptoms in children with cancer in the&#xD;
                beginning of cancer therapy as well as the extent to which pediatric patients&#xD;
                symptoms and suffering at this time are being adequately managed.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  To assess the emphasis that families place on quality of life in symptom management&#xD;
                and treatment decision making as well as the satisfaction with the degree of&#xD;
                attention given to quality of life by the medical team.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  To assess patient and parent attitudes toward palliative care in general and&#xD;
                receptivity toward pediatric palliative care team involvement from the time of&#xD;
                diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  To assess understanding of prognosis and its relationship to parent and patient&#xD;
                attitudes toward the integration of palliative care in pediatric oncology care from&#xD;
                the time of diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  To assess concordance between parents and patients in their attitudes toward the&#xD;
                integration of palliative care in pediatric oncology patients from the time of&#xD;
                diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      -Patients eligible for inclusion will be children diagnosed with an oncologic disease at&#xD;
      least 1 month and no greater than 1 year prior with age at diagnosis of 10 to 17 years. Both&#xD;
      patient and parent must agree to participate to be eligible for inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Surveys will be administered to consenting patient/parent pairs with the parent&#xD;
           completing a written survey while the patient is surveyed in the absence of the&#xD;
           participating parent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Total enrollment will be a minimum of 70 subject pairs and a maximum of 110 subject&#xD;
           pairs with a target goal of 100 subject pairs enrolled over a 6 month period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collected from responses to the surveys will be analyzed at the conclusion of the survey&#xD;
      period to assess for individual content as well as concordance between the patients and their&#xD;
      parents.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 20, 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date>September 8, 2015</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Actual">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Pediatric Cancer</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pediatric Oncology Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current patients receiving clinical care for cancer at one of the participating sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 1 month and no more than 1 year after initial diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physically and cognitively able to participate in a 30 minute interview as determined&#xD;
             by the primary medical providers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and speak English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 10-17 at the time of first diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agreement of both parent and child to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Parents:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A parent of an eligible child&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physically and cognitively able to complete a 30 minute self-administered survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to read, understand and speak English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agreement of both parent and child to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to speak English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to understand spoken English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parent s inability to read written English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of agreement of both parent and child to participate.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David Wendler, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Harris MB. Palliative care in children with cancer: which child and when? J Natl Cancer Inst Monogr. 2004;(32):144-9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15263058</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gatta G, Capocaccia R, Coleman MP, Ries LA, Berrino F. Childhood cancer survival in Europe and the United States. Cancer. 2002 Oct 15;95(8):1767-72.</citation>
    <PMID>12365026</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wolfe J, Grier HE, Klar N, Levin SB, Ellenbogen JM, Salem-Schatz S, Emanuel EJ, Weeks JC. Symptoms and suffering at the end of life in children with cancer. N Engl J Med. 2000 Feb 3;342(5):326-33.</citation>
    <PMID>10655532</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 8, 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 7, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 7, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 10, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 5, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 5, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 6, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Palliative Care</keyword>
  <keyword>Survey</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
  <keyword>Attitudes</keyword>
  <keyword>Pediatric Cancer</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

