<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04596345</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PSI.CPE.20.01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04596345</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Psychological Distress in Emerging Adulthood: A Longitudinal Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>DistressEA</acronym>
  <official_title>Psychological Distress in Emerging Adulthood: A Longitudinal Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universidad de las Americas - Quito</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universidad de las Americas - Quito</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Emerging adulthood (18-29 years) is a critical stage in lifespan development. During this&#xD;
      stage, people experience instability: shifts from their families of origin, breakups of&#xD;
      relationships and job changes are frequent before most young adults stabilize their lives and&#xD;
      make more lasting decisions. This study seeks to understand the psychological distress of&#xD;
      emerging adults in Quito, Ecuador and define how it varies over a year.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Emerging adulthood is often a period of some instability with relationship changes and often&#xD;
      a series of job changes before life trajectories clarify and more lasting decisions are&#xD;
      possible. These changes often produce distress and they might explain why most of the&#xD;
      symptoms that impact the individual's mental health throughout their lives appear at this&#xD;
      stage, although full-blown disorders are often only diagnosed subsequently. There are several&#xD;
      studies that describe the prevalence of mental disorders in this age group, however, there&#xD;
      are few studies that refer to how psychological distress changes during this phase of&#xD;
      emotional, social, and financial instability. The few existent studies refer mostly to&#xD;
      college student populations, with relative neglect of the non-student populations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this study is to analyze the intraindividual changes in psychological&#xD;
      distress of emerging adults over one year. These changes will be compared between those&#xD;
      participants who are college students and those who are not. Sociodemographic data will be&#xD;
      recorded in the first assessment and the last assessment, while psychological distress and&#xD;
      health-related quality of life will be monitored bimonthly for seven assessment points in&#xD;
      total. Everyday relevant events will be also recorded bimonthly for seven assessment points,&#xD;
      and this information will be used as a time-varying covariate. An electronic survey will be&#xD;
      used for data collection through formr system (https://formr.org/).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results of this research will show if the distress changes significantly in the studied&#xD;
      population for one year and it will be possible to identify some of the events and variables&#xD;
      that are related to these changes. This knowledge might help to create interventions that are&#xD;
      tailored to the needs of this population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change on the Clinical Outcomes in Routine Evaluation (CORE)</measure>
    <time_frame>One year (seven assessment points at two-month intervals)</time_frame>
    <description>A 34-item self-reported measure that assess psychological distress and how it changes considering four dimensions: subjective well-being (four items), problems and or symptoms (twelve items), life function (twelve items) and risk to self and others (six items). Higher scores indicate higher psychological distress. It is measure that can be downloaded free of charge from: www.coresystemtrust.org.uk. The Clinical Outcomes in Routine Evaluation- Outcome Measure(CORE-OM) has shown good psychometric properties in college students (and a non-student general population sample) from Ecuador (http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/s40359-020-00443-z)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EuroQol five-dimensions - three-level (EQ-5D-3L)</measure>
    <time_frame>One year (seven assessment points at two-month intervals)</time_frame>
    <description>A 5-item self-report measure of health-related quality of life states in adults, considering five dimensions (Mobility, Self-care, Usual activities, Pain &amp; discomfort, Anxiety &amp; Depression), each of which has three severity levels that are described by statements appropriate to that dimension. As result a 5-digit number describes person's health state profile. Higher scores represent more problems with regard to each dimension.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EuroQol Visual Analogue Scale (EQ VAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>One year (seven assessment points at two-month intervals)</time_frame>
    <description>This scale records the patient's self-rated health on a vertical visual analogue scale that ranges from 0= 'Best imaginable health state' to 100 = 'Worst imaginable health state'. The VAS will be used as a quantitative measure of health outcome .</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">800</enrollment>
  <condition>Psychological Distress</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>University students</arm_group_label>
    <description>This group will include all those participants who declare to be attending a study program to get a higher education degree.&#xD;
No intervention will be applied.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non-university-attending peers</arm_group_label>
    <description>This group will include all those participants who are not attending a study program to get a higher education degree.&#xD;
No intervention will be applied.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The population will be emerging adults from Ecuador students and non-students as one&#xD;
        objective is to compare psychological distress variability between both populations.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Competence to read and understand Spanish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Living in Ecuador&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being a student (for the student cohort)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not attending to a formal student program (for the non-student cohort)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>29 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Clara Paz, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+593 2 3981000</phone>
    <phone_ext>2518</phone_ext>
    <email>clara.paz@udla.edu.ec</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Alberto Rodriguez, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>+593 2 3981000</phone>
    <phone_ext>7352</phone_ext>
    <email>alberto.rodriguez@udla.edu.ec</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Metropolitan District</name>
      <address>
        <city>Quito</city>
        <zip>EC170503</zip>
        <country>Ecuador</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Clara Paz</last_name>
      <email>clara.paz@udla.edu.ec</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Ecuador</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universidad de las Americas - Quito</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Clara Paz</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Researcher</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Young Adult</keyword>
  <keyword>Life Change Events</keyword>
  <keyword>Students</keyword>
  <keyword>Mental Health</keyword>
  <keyword>Observational Study</keyword>
  <keyword>Longitudinal Studies</keyword>
  <keyword>Surveys and Questionnaires</keyword>
  <keyword>Self Report</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>August 6, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/45/NCT04596345/SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

