<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04597671</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NVALT28</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04597671</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Durvalumab and Low-dose PCI vs Durvalumab and Observation in Radically Treated Patients With Stage III NSCLC (NVALT28)</brief_title>
  <acronym>NVALT28</acronym>
  <official_title>NVALT 28/ PRL01 Durvalumab and Low-dose Prophylactic Cranial Irradiation (PCI) Versus Durvalumab and Observation in Radically Treated Patients With Stage III Non-small Cell Lung Cancer: A Phase III Randomized Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Association NVALT Studies</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dutch Society of Physicians for Pulmonology and Tuberculosis</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This trial studies the combination of low-dose PCI with or without durvalumab in patients&#xD;
      with radically treated stage III NSCLC. The hypothesis is that the incidence of brain&#xD;
      metastases will be reduced from 30% to 15 % with durvalumab and to a maximum of 5% with the&#xD;
      addition of low-dose PCI. This strategy would make brain metastases in stage III NSCLC&#xD;
      history and this would improve QoL.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The brain is frequently a site of disease relapse in Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)&#xD;
      patients. For radically treated patients, stage III has the highest risk for brain metastases&#xD;
      with a cumulative incidence of brain metastases after radical treatment of approximately 30%&#xD;
      for which there is no cure at the moment, decreasing the long-term survival and Quality of&#xD;
      Life. Strategies to reduce incidence of brain metastases are necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prophylactic Cranial Irradiation (PCI) has been shown to reduce the incidence of brain&#xD;
      metastases in patients with NSCLC. However, PCI leads to a neurocognitive impairment in about&#xD;
      25% of patients without altering the QoL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The addition of durvalumab after chemo-radiotherapy in stage III NSCLC could reduce the&#xD;
      incidence of brain metastases. In pre-clinical models, immunotherapy potentiates the effects&#xD;
      of radiotherapy by a factor two to five. This makes the combination of PCI and immunotherapy&#xD;
      interesting to evaluate whether it can further decrease the percentage of brain metastases as&#xD;
      well as preserve organ function as a lower radiation dose can probably be used when combined&#xD;
      with an antiprogrammed death (ligand)1 (PD(L)-1).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis of the NVALT28 trial is that the combination of PCI with durvalumab will&#xD;
      decrease the incidence of brain metastases from 30% to 15 % with durvalumab and to a maximum&#xD;
      of 5% with the addition of low-dose PCI. This strategy would make brain metastases in stage&#xD;
      III NSCLC history and this would improve QoL.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2028</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction of incidence of brain metastases</measure>
    <time_frame>From randomisation until moment of discovery of brain metastases or latest at 24 months after randomization</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate whether the addition of PCI to durvalumab after concurrent chemo-radiotherapy for stage III NSCLC reduces the cumulative incidence of brain metastases.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect on neurocognitive functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>From randomization until 24 months after randomization</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate what the effect is on neurocognitive functioning to be meassured with HVLT-R carried out by hospital staff.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to develop neurological symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>From randomization until time to develop neurological symptoms with a maximum of 24 months after randomization</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate time to develop neurological symptoms (CTCAE version 5.0)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Toxicity assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>From randomization until end of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate adverse events (CTCAE v 5.0 and PRO-CTCAE) that is the result of study treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient reported neurocognitive decline</measure>
    <time_frame>From randomization until 5 years after randomization</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate patient reported neurocognitive decline using PRO-CTCAE (patient reported outcome)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cost-efficiency</measure>
    <time_frame>From randomization until end of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate cost-efficiency of the addition of PCI to durvalumab with a state-transition model, calculated with Dutch tariff</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">170</enrollment>
  <condition>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Durvalumab with low-dose PCI</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Durvalumab with observation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Durvalumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Durvalumab is used as standard of care</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>low-dose PCI</intervention_name>
    <description>PCI will be given concurrently with durvalumab. PCI will be given to a dose of 15 Gy in 10 fractions</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Prophylactic Cranial Irradiation (PCI)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients must sign a study-specific informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. TNM8 stage IIIA, IIIB or IIIC non-small cell lung cancer (preferentially histology;&#xD;
             cytology is allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Whole body FDG-PET-scan and brain imaging (MRI or CT with iv contrast) before the&#xD;
             start of chemoradiotherapy: No distant metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Additional brain MRI (MRI mandatory) before randomization: no brain metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Eligible for durvalumab treatment according to registration label of durvalumab in the&#xD;
             Netherlands. Durvalumab has to be given in standard of care. (durvalumab has to be&#xD;
             started already before randomization and PCI (i.e. at least one administration of&#xD;
             durvalumab has to be given before randomization).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Treatment completed with concurrent chemoradiation. The last day of thoracic&#xD;
             radiotherapy should be within 52 days of randomization and randomization should be&#xD;
             after start of durvalumab. Any platinum doublet or daily cisplatin regimen that is&#xD;
             standard of care in The Netherlands is allowed. No disease progression after&#xD;
             chemoradiotherapy (evaluated with CT-thorax and upper abdomen during/after the last&#xD;
             cycle of chemotherapy and comparison with CT before start of chemoradiotherapy).&#xD;
             Consolidation chemotherapy cycles after radiotherapy is not permitted but&#xD;
             administration of 1 cycle of chemotherapy prior to concurrent chemo-radiotherapy is&#xD;
             acceptable. Where possible, chemotherapy regimens should be given according to&#xD;
             National Comprehensive Cancer Network (NCCN) Guidelines or European Society for&#xD;
             Medical Oncology (ESMO) Guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. To be eligible for randomization, patients must have received a total dose of thoracic&#xD;
             radiotherapy of 60-66 Gy in 2 - 2.75 Gy per day, oncedaily fractions, or in case of&#xD;
             daily cisplatin regimen 60.5-66 Gy in 22-24 fractions. Other radiotherapy schedules&#xD;
             are not allowed. Sites are encouraged to adhere to the organ at risk constraints as&#xD;
             used in the PACIFIC study as well as the EORTC recommendations for high-dose&#xD;
             radiotherapy for lung cancer:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Mean lung dose must be &lt;20 Gy and/or V20Gy must be &lt;35%&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Mean oesophagus dose must be &lt;34 Gy&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Heart V45Gy &lt;35% or V30Gy &lt;30%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Proton therapy to the chest is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. ECOG performance status 0-1 at the time of randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Evidence of postmenopausal status, or negative urinary or serum pregnancy test for&#xD;
             female premenopausal patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participation in another clinical study with an investigational product during the&#xD;
             last 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Concurrent enrolment in another clinical study, unless it is an observational&#xD;
             (non-interventional) clinical study or a study that will not influence the primary and&#xD;
             secondary endpoint parameters (e.g. bioimpedance measurements, E-Nose) or the&#xD;
             follow-up period of an interventional study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Mixed small cell and non-small cell lung cancer histology.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients who receive sequential chemoradiation therapy for locally advanced NSCLC.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Disease progression after completion of definitive platinum based, concurrent&#xD;
             chemoradiation therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any unresolved toxicity CTCAE (v. 5.0) more than grade 2 (i.e. grade 3 or higher) from&#xD;
             the prior chemoradiation therapy. Patients with irreversible toxicity that is not&#xD;
             reasonably expected to be exacerbated by PCI may be included (e.g. hearing loss) after&#xD;
             consultation with the principal investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any concurrent chemotherapy, immunotherapy, biologic or hormonal therapy for cancer&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Active or prior documented autoimmune disease within the past 2 years. NOTE: Patients&#xD;
             with vitiligo, Grave's disease, or psoriasis not requiring systemic treatment (within&#xD;
             the past 2 years) are not excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Active or prior documented inflammatory bowel disease (e.g. Crohn's disease,&#xD;
             ulcerative colitis).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of primary immunodeficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of organ transplant that requires therapeutic immunosuppression.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, uncontrolled hypertension, unstable&#xD;
             angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, active peptic ulcer disease or gastritis, active&#xD;
             bleeding diatheses or psychiatric illness/ social situations that would limit&#xD;
             compliance with study requirements or compromise the ability of the patient to give&#xD;
             written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Known history of tuberculosis, hepatitis B, hepatitis C or Human Immunodeficiency&#xD;
             Virus (HIV).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. History of another primary malignancy within 2 years prior to starting study drug,&#xD;
             except for adequately treated basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or cancer&#xD;
             of the cervix in situ and the disease under study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Prior cranial irradiation is not allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Except for durvalumab after concurrent chemoradiotherapy, no previous treatment with&#xD;
             PD-(L)1-inhibitors is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Female patients who are pregnant, breastfeeding or male or female patients of&#xD;
             reproductive potential who are not employing an effective method of birth control.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Any condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would interfere with&#xD;
             evaluation of the study drug or interpretation of patient safety or study results.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dirk De Ruysscher, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Maastricht University/ Maastro clinic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lizza Hendriks, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Maastricht UMC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Dirk De Ruysscher, MD PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0031 88 44 55 666</phone>
    <email>dirk.deruysscher@maastro.nl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lizza Hendriks, MD PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0031 43 387 5047</phone>
    <email>lizza.hendriks@mumc.nl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Maastro</name>
      <address>
        <city>Maastricht</city>
        <zip>5912 BL</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dirk De Ruysscher, MD PhD</last_name>
      <phone>0031 88 44 55 600</phone>
      <email>dirk.deruysscher@maastro.nl</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Dirk De Ruysscher, MD PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>PCI</keyword>
  <keyword>immunotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
  <keyword>QoL</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Durvalumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

