<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04596956</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020MZ01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04596956</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Sodium Bicarbonate Ringer Injection</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter Randomized Controlled Trial on the Safety and Efficacy of Sodium Bicarbonate Ringer Injection in Elderly Patients Undergoing Abdominal Surgery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Chinese PLA General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Chinese PLA General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To observe whether sodium bicarbonate Ringer injections can reduce the incidence of&#xD;
           postoperative complications in elderly patients undergoing abdominal surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To observe the effects of sodium bicarbonate Ringer injections on the internal&#xD;
           environment, such as water, electrolytes, acid-base balance, and other physiological&#xD;
           indexes, in the perioperative period of elderly patients undergoing abdominal surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research design：This study adopts a multicenter, prospective, randomized, controlled,&#xD;
      pragmatic clinical trials (PCT) research design.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size：5000 cases. Indication：The experimental group is the elderly patients undergoing&#xD;
      abdominal surgery who were administered sodium bicarbonate Ringer injections&#xD;
      intraoperatively; the control group is the elderly patients with abdominal surgery who were&#xD;
      administered lactated Ringer's injections intraoperatively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Observational index&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preoperative baseline data collection:&#xD;
&#xD;
      General patient information: basic information (age, height, and weight), preoperative&#xD;
      diagnosis, past history, auxiliary examination results, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intraoperative data collection:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Perioperative vital signs information and arterial blood gas analysis results; The surgical&#xD;
      method, operation time, and anaesthesia time; Intraoperative fluid management: The total&#xD;
      amount of intraoperative fluids, blood transfusion volume, bleeding volume, urine volume,&#xD;
      types and dosage of vasoactive drugs, diuretic dosage, sodium bicarbonate dosage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Postoperative index:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Postoperative blood biochemical examination: liver function, renal function (urea nitrogen,&#xD;
      creatinine), osmotic pressure, lactic acid, and blood sugar levels; Postoperative&#xD;
      complications and treatment status Postoperative recovery: postoperative outcome, length of&#xD;
      hospital stay, admission to ICU (duration of stay), postoperative eating time, out of bed&#xD;
      activity time, gastrointestinal recovery time (exhaust), time for removal of various tubes&#xD;
      (gastric tube, urinary tube, and drainage tube), etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The observation cut-off point is the patient's discharge. If the patient is still&#xD;
      hospitalized 30 days after the operation, the observation will be terminated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research process&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Elderly abdominal surgery patients who meet the inclusion criteria will be enrolled and&#xD;
           randomly divided into two groups according to the intraoperative application of&#xD;
           extracellular fluid supplements. The experimental group is sodium bicarbonate Ringer&#xD;
           injection group, and the control group is sodium lactate Ringer injection. Basic&#xD;
           preoperative information of patients will be collected. The vital signs, fluid&#xD;
           treatment, and surgical anaesthesia will be recorded during the operation, while the&#xD;
           recovery and postoperative complications will be recorded during postoperative visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. The ability of sodium bicarbonate Ringer injections to reduce postoperative&#xD;
           complications in elderly patients undergoing abdominal surgery will be observed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. The effects of sodium bicarbonate Ringer injection on the internal environment, such as&#xD;
           water, electrolytes, acid-base balance, and other physiological indexes in elderly&#xD;
           patients undergoing abdominal surgery will be observed and compared.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. The safety and efficacy of sodium bicarbonate Ringer injection in elderly patients with&#xD;
           abdominal diseases will be comprehensively assessed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Complication rate (including death)</measure>
    <time_frame>30days</time_frame>
    <description>Complications include: bleeding, infection (incision infection, blood infection, urinary system infection), gastrointestinal complications (postoperative intestinal obstruction, anastomotic leakage), pulmonary complications (pulmonary infection, pulmonary embolism) ), cardiovascular complications (cardiac arrest, arrhythmia, heart failure, myocardial infarction), neurological complications (delirium, stroke), urinary system complications (renal insufficiency), etc. (refer to International Surgical Prognosis Study, ISOS ), and died during hospitalization.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">5000</enrollment>
  <condition>Ringer Bicarbonate</condition>
  <condition>Elderly Abdominal Surgery</condition>
  <condition>Safety</condition>
  <condition>Effectiveness</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>sodium bicarbonate Ringer injection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ringer lactate solution</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>sodium bicarbonate Ringer injection</intervention_name>
    <description>Used in surgery</description>
    <arm_group_label>sodium bicarbonate Ringer injection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lactated Ringer's solution</intervention_name>
    <description>Used in surgery</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ringer lactate solution</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (1) Patients need to be over 65 years of age, while there is no restriction on gender.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (2) Patients are planned to undergo upper abdominal surgery under general anaesthesia,&#xD;
             with an expected operation time of &gt;2 h, and the infusion volume is &gt;1000ml.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (3) The patient agrees to participate in the clinical research and signs the informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (1) Emergency surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (2) Hypermagnesemia (defined as serum Mg2+ &gt;1.25mmol/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (3) Patients who participated in other drug trials in the past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (4) Known allergic reactions to the test drug and/or its components&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (5) Patients judged to lack the ability of providing informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (6) Other situations considered unsuitable for enrollment by the researcher.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Wenzhu Shi</last_name>
    <phone>+86-15110199887</phone>
    <email>shiwenzhu@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 15, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 15, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Chinese PLA General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Weidong Mi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of the Center for Anesthesia</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

