<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04591184</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ENTVAX01-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04591184</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Clinical Trial of a Prophylactic Plasmid DNA Vaccine for COVID-19 [Covigenix VAX-001] in Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I/II Trial to Evaluate Safety, Tolerability, and Immunogenicity of a Prophylactic Plasmid DNA Vaccine Against SARS CoV-2 [Covigenix VAX-001] in Healthy Adults 18 Years and Older</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Entos Pharmaceuticals Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Aegis Life, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CIHR)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Entos Pharmaceuticals Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a Phase I/II clinical study in healthy adults designed to assess the safety,&#xD;
      tolerability, and immunogenicity of receiving 2 IM injections of Covigenix VAX-001, 14 days&#xD;
      apart. Covigenix VAX-001 is a plasmid DNA vaccine that expresses key antigenic determinants&#xD;
      from SARS-CoV-2 and uses Entos Pharmaceuticals' Fusogenix PLV platform.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Phase I portion of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      ENTVAX01-101 is a phase I/II, placebo-controlled, randomized, observer-blind, dose ranging&#xD;
      clinical trial in males and non-pregnant females, 18 years and older, who are in good health&#xD;
      and meet all eligibility criteria. This clinical trial is designed to assess the safety,&#xD;
      tolerability, and immunogenicity of Covigenix VAX-001 manufactured by Entos Pharmaceuticals.&#xD;
      Covigenix VAX-001 is a novel plasmid DNA-based vaccine that encodes for the full-length Spike&#xD;
      protein from SARS-CoV-2 (VAX-001 encapsulated in a proprietary Fusogenix Proteo-Lipid Vehicle&#xD;
      (PLV)).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrollment for the phase I portion of the study will occur at one Canadian site. Thirty-six&#xD;
      participants will be enrolled in a staggered manner into one cohort an 3 groups (0.100 mg &amp;&#xD;
      0.250 mg vs. placebo) in stage I. Participants will receive an intramuscular (IM) injection&#xD;
      (0.5 milliliter [mL]) on Days 0 and 14 in the deltoid muscle of alternating arms and will be&#xD;
      followed through 12 months post booster vaccination (Day 379). Follow-up visits will occur at&#xD;
      Days 7, 14, 17, 21, 28, 42, 196, and 379.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective is to evaluate the safety of a 2-dose vaccination schedule of the&#xD;
      Covigenix VAX-001 vaccine, given 14 days apart. The secondary objectives are to evaluate the&#xD;
      humoral immune response as measured by Immunoglobulin G (IgG) ELISA to the SARS-CoV-2 S&#xD;
      protein and by pseudo-viral neutralization assay to pseudo-virion following a 2-dose&#xD;
      vaccination schedule of Covigenix VAX-001.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical safety data will be collected at the Day 0 of the study and at defined intervals&#xD;
      (Dose 1: Days 7, 14; Dose 2: Days: 21, 42).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical safety lab testing&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Hematology &amp; Biochemistry:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Immunogenicity testing:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ELISA and pseudo-viral neutralization tests&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  % of responders or individuals who seroconvert (with 95% CI): develop immune response&#xD;
           defined as a 4-fold or greater rise.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Geometric mean concentration/geometric mean titers (with 95% CI) and&#xD;
           pre-/post-vaccination ratios (geometric mean ratios) provide absolute values and&#xD;
           increase in antibody titers at defined time points after each vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Reverse cumulative distribution (RCD) curves display percentage of participants versus&#xD;
           antibody levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following immunogenicity tests will be performed as exploratory objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  SARS-CoV-2 neutralization antibody responses at Days 0, 7, 14, 21, 28, 42, 196, and 379.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Antigen-specific B&amp;T cell interferon (IFN)-γ cell responses measured by ELISPOT up to&#xD;
           Day 379.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Antigen-specific T cell responses measured by flow cytometry up to Day 379&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Antigen-specific T cell responses including cluster of differentiation (CD)4+ and CD8+&#xD;
           cytotoxic T lymphocytes (CTLs), through ICS up to Day 379&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Whole blood immunophenotyping (B and T cell repertoire (BCR and TCR) as measured by high&#xD;
           throughput sequencing of lymphocyte antigen receptor genes, SCS, and RNAseq to identify&#xD;
           all genes regulated by the vaccine) up to Day 379&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size: 36 participants, 24 test subjects and 12 placebo controls;&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study plan:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Table 1. Study groups and treatments Arm Intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Experimental: Low dose (0.100mg), 18-&lt;55 years, 2 doses Biological: Covigenix VAX-001,&#xD;
           0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Experimental: High dose (0.250mg), 18-&lt;55 years, 2 doses Biological: Covigenix VAX-001,&#xD;
           0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Placebo Comparator: Placebo, 18-&lt;55 years Other: Placebo, 0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrollment plan:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrollment plan: Study participants will be enrolled in a staged manner at each dosage level&#xD;
      (Low and High), as described below:&#xD;
&#xD;
      First, three participants of the cohort will be randomized (2:1; Groups 1 and 3) to the low&#xD;
      dose of Covigenix VAX-001 or placebo, a minimum of one hour apart. Once three participants&#xD;
      have received treatment there will be a 72-hour waiting period, and if no holding rule is met&#xD;
      then the remaining participants from Group 1 and 3 will be vaccinated. Similarly, once 7-day&#xD;
      safety data are available on a minimum of 75% (n=14) of participants in Groups 1/3, 1)&#xD;
      participants of the cohort will be randomized (2:1; groups 2 and 3) to the high dose of&#xD;
      Covigenix VAX-001 or placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After review of day 42 data (Day 28 post second dose) on participants in Groups 1/3 (Low&#xD;
      dose), it will be decided whether this group will be enrolled in the Ph II of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Infection during the study: During the observation period of the study, if fever and&#xD;
      respiratory symptoms with cough develop in a participant, he/she should immediately follow&#xD;
      local procedures for care of suspected COVID-19 illness and contact the study team. The&#xD;
      participant's nasopharyngeal and throat swab/sputum will be collected and tested for&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 at a designated provincial testing center. If a COVID-19 infection is found during&#xD;
      the study, a case investigation will be undertaken. Careful monitoring for vaccine-related&#xD;
      enhanced disease will be undertaken in conjunction with the participant's primary physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to the real-time PCR testing for SARS-CoV-2, the collected nasopharyngeal&#xD;
      swab/sputum will be tested for other respiratory pathogens.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants testing positive for SARS CoV 2 between IP Dose 1 and Dose 2 will not receive&#xD;
      Dose 2, but will be followed for safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study duration: 13 months&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design for the phase II portion of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the Phase II part, enrollment will occur at sites globally. Approximately 500&#xD;
      participants will be enrolled into 1 of 5 groups (approximately 100 per group) as safety data&#xD;
      emerge from the Phase I portion . Participants will receive an IM injection (0.5 mL) on Days&#xD;
      0 and 14 in the deltoid muscle of alternating arms and will be followed through 12 months&#xD;
      post Dose 2. Follow-up visits will occur at Days 14, 28, 42, 196, and 379.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The total duration for an individual participant in the Phase II part will be approximately&#xD;
      13 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study arms are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Experimental: Low dose (0.100mg), 18 years and older, 2 doses active Biological:&#xD;
           Covigenix VAX-001, 0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Experimental: Low dose (0.100mg), 18 years and older, 1 dose active, 1 dose placebo&#xD;
           Biological: Covigenix VAX-001, 0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Experimental: High dose (0.250mg), 18 years and older, 2 doses active Biological:&#xD;
           Covigenix VAX-001, 0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Experimental: High dose (0.250mg), 18 years and older, 1 dose active, 1 dose placebo&#xD;
           Biological: Covigenix VAX-001, 0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Placebo Comparator: Placebo, 18 years and older Other: Placebo, 0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical safety lab testing&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Hematology &amp; Biochemistry:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Immunogenicity testing:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ELISA and pseudo-viral neutralization tests&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  % of responders or individuals who seroconvert (with 95% CI): develop immune response&#xD;
           defined as a 4-fold or greater rise.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Geometric mean concentration/geometric mean titers (with 95% CI) and&#xD;
           pre-/post-vaccination ratios (geometric mean ratios) provide absolute values and&#xD;
           increase in antibody titers at defined time points after each vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following immunogenicity tests will be performed as exploratory objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  SARS-CoV-2 neutralization antibody responses at Days 0,14, and 28.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Antigen-specific T cell responses including cluster of differentiation (CD)4+ and CD8+&#xD;
           cytotoxic T lymphocytes (CTLs), through ICS up to Day 379&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 7, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Unblinded study nurse with no other role in the trial administers VAX-001. Observer blinded.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of a 2-dose regimen of VAX-001 when doses are given 14 days apart</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0 - 42</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency and Grade (mild, moderate, severe, potentially life-threatening; Gr. 1-4, respectively) of solicited injection site and systemic adverse events and unsolicited systemic adverse events</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean change from baseline in safety laboratory measures</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0 - 42</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse hematology /clinical chemistry parameter changes (mild, moderate, severe, or life-threatening; Gr. 1-4, respectively)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of treatment-emergent Serious Adverse Events (SAE) throughout the study and up to 12 months post-second dose immunization (Day 379).</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0 - 379</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of serious AEs</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent seroconversion defined as a 4-fold or greater increase in IgG titers after one or two doses as measured by IgG ELISA</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 379</time_frame>
    <description>Percent seroconversion post second dose as measured by ELISA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric mean neutralizing antibody titers against pseudo-virion after one and two doses</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 379</time_frame>
    <description>Geometric mean of antibody titers measured by pseudo-viral neutralization assay.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent seroconversion defined as a 4-fold or greater increase in IgG titers after one or two doses as measured by pseudo-viral neutralization assay.</measure>
    <time_frame>up to Day 379</time_frame>
    <description>Seroconversion as measured by pseudo-viral neutralization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Persistence of IgG antibody titers as measured by ELISA and neutralizing antibody titers measured by pseudo-virion neutralization assay, six months after the second vaccine dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 379</time_frame>
    <description>Maintenance of antibody titers up to 12 months post second dose</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV-2</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active Covigenix VAX-001</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose-ranging, 2 dose levels. 24 subjects receiving active i.m. vaccine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo injection. 12 subjects receiving placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Covigenix VAX-001 placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo vaccine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Covigenix VAX-001</intervention_name>
    <description>Active Covigenix VAX-001</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active Covigenix VAX-001</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria for Phase I:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Each participant must meet all of the following criteria to be enrolled in the Phase 1 part&#xD;
        of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The participant is a healthy adult from 18 &lt;55 years and with a BMI of ≤30 kg/m2 at&#xD;
             the time of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. If the participant is a WOCBP, she must have practiced adequate contraception for 30&#xD;
             days prior to IP Dose 1, have a negative pregnancy test on the day of IP Dose 1, and&#xD;
             have agreed to continue adequate contraception until 90 days after IP Dose 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. If the participant is male, he must agree to continue adequate contraception until 90&#xD;
             days after IP Dose 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The participant is able to provide consent to participate in the study and has signed&#xD;
             an ICF.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The participant is able and willing to complete all the scheduled study procedures&#xD;
             during the whole study period (approximately 13 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The participant is generally in good health, as determined by a review of medical&#xD;
             history and a physical examination within 14 days prior to IP Dose 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria for Phase II&#xD;
&#xD;
        Each participant must meet all of the following criteria to be enrolled in Phase II part of&#xD;
        the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The participant is 18 years and older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. If the participant is a WOCBP, she must have a negative pregnancy test on the day of&#xD;
             IP Dose 1, and have agreed to adequate contraception until 90 days after IP Dose 2&#xD;
             administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. If the participant is male, he must agree to continue adequate contraception until 90&#xD;
             days after IP Dose 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The participant can provide consent to participate in and having signed an ICF.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The participant is able and willing to complete all the scheduled study procedures&#xD;
             during the whole study follow-up period (approximately 13 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria for Phase I&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants meeting any of the following criteria will be excluded from Phase I of the&#xD;
        study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The participant has history of anaphylaxis to any allergen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The participant has history of seizure disorder, encephalopathy or psychosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The female participant is pregnant (positive urine pregnancy test), lactating, or&#xD;
             plans to become pregnant during the 3 months of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The participant has a positive test result for HIV or hepatitis B and C.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The participant has a positive test results of IgG antibodies against SARS CoV 2 from&#xD;
             RCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The participant has a positive test result of real-time quantitative PCR screening of&#xD;
             nasopharyngeal swab/sputum for SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The participant has a laboratory (hematological and biochemistry) examination that is&#xD;
             out of normal range, or greater than a Grade 1 abnormality and clinically significant&#xD;
             as assessed by the investigator including test results for: CBC, PT, PTT, ALT, AST,&#xD;
             ALP, T Bil, Cr, lipase, and blood glucose;&#xD;
&#xD;
             - Transient mild laboratory abnormalities may be rescreened once, and the participant&#xD;
             will be excluded if the laboratory repeat test is abnormal as per local laboratory&#xD;
             normal values and the investigator's assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. The participant presents with any acute febrile disease (oral temperature ≥38.0°C) or&#xD;
             active infectious disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The participant has a medical history of SARS-CoV-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. The participant has unstable concomitant underlying conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
             - Note: Stable condition defined as: The participant is appropriately managed on&#xD;
             consistent disease management, for example participants with well controlled&#xD;
             hypertension, adult-onset diabetes, Benign Prostate Hypertrophy (BPH) or hypothyroid&#xD;
             disease will be eligible for enrollment. The treatment regimen should be stable for at&#xD;
             least 3 months prior to entering the study. Once IP treatment has started, must be&#xD;
             willing to maintain all aspects of the treatment regimen and forgo any elective&#xD;
             changes in medication or management. Emergency changes in medication or management&#xD;
             would be captured as an adverse event.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. The participant has a history of Guillain-Barre Syndrome or degenerative neurological&#xD;
             disorders; a history of autoimmune, inflammatory disease or potential immune-mediated&#xD;
             medical conditions (PIMMCs), or any condition that may put the participant at&#xD;
             increased risk of safety events&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. The participant has serious cardiovascular diseases, such as arrhythmia, conduction&#xD;
             block, history of myocardial infarction, severe hypertension not controlled with&#xD;
             medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. The participant has a serious chronic disease such as asthma, diabetes, or thyroid&#xD;
             disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. The participant has immunodeficiency, asplenia, or functional asplenia.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. The participant has a platelet disorder or other bleeding disorder that may cause&#xD;
             contraindication for IM injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. The participant has chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, current smoker or vaper.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. The participant has a history or diagnosis of coagulopathies.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. The participant has received immunosuppressive medication, cytotoxic therapy, or&#xD;
             corticosteroids (excluding corticosteroid spray for allergic rhinitis, surface&#xD;
             corticosteroid therapy for acute non-complicated dermatitis) in the last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. The participant received the blood products in last 4 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. The participant has received other investigational drugs within 1 month before Day 0,&#xD;
             or planned use during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. The participant had prior administration of any live attenuated vaccine within 1 month&#xD;
             before Day 0.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. The participant had prior administration of a subunit or inactivated non SARS CoV 2&#xD;
             vaccine within 2 weeks before Day 0.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. The participant had prior administration of any other vaccine considered (or being&#xD;
             considered) to be protective against SARS-CoV-2 any time before Day 0.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. The participant had prior participation in other studies involving study intervention&#xD;
             containing lipid nanoparticles.&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. The participant has any condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, may&#xD;
             interfere with the participant's compliance, evaluation of study objectives, or&#xD;
             informed consent process (i.e. medical, psychological, social or other conditions).&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. The participant is at high risk of acquiring SARS-CoV-2 infection due to their&#xD;
             surroundings, contacts or circumstances. Explicitly exclude healthcare and essential&#xD;
             workers/at risk population.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria for Phase II&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants meeting any of the following criteria will be excluded from Phase II part of&#xD;
        the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The participant has history of anaphylaxis to any allergen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The female participant is pregnant (positive urine pregnancy test), lactating, or&#xD;
             plans to become pregnant during the next 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The participant has any acute febrile disease (oral temperature ≥38.0°C [100.4ºF]) or&#xD;
             active infectious disease on the day of IP administration (participants may be re&#xD;
             scheduled).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The participant has a medical history of SARS-CoV-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The participant has a history of immunodeficiency, asplenia, or functional asplenia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The participant has received immunosuppressive medication, cytotoxic therapy, inhaled&#xD;
             corticosteroids (excluding corticosteroid spray for allergic rhinitis, surface&#xD;
             corticosteroid therapy for acute non-complicated dermatitis) in the last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The participant has received other investigational drugs within 1 month before first&#xD;
             dose administration or planned use during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. The participant has received any live attenuated vaccine within 1 month before first&#xD;
             dose administration or any inactivated vaccine within 2 weeks before first dose&#xD;
             administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The participant has received prior administration of any other vaccine considered (or&#xD;
             being considered) to protect against SARS-CoV-2 any time before study onset.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. The participant has a history of any medical conditions that place them at higher risk&#xD;
             for severe illness due to SARS-CoV-2 including but not limited to asthma, chronic&#xD;
             kidney disease being treated with dialysis, chronic lung disease, diabetes, hemoglobin&#xD;
             disorders, immunocompromised, liver disease, serious heart conditions, or severe&#xD;
             obesity.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. The participant has any condition that in the opinion of the investigators may&#xD;
             interfere with the participants' compliance, evaluation of study objectives, or&#xD;
             informed consent process (i.e., medical, psychological, social or other conditions).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>95 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Canadian Centre for Vaccinology, Dalhousie University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Halifax</city>
        <state>Nova Scotia</state>
        <zip>B3K 6R8</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>anti-infective</keyword>
  <keyword>prophylaxis</keyword>
  <keyword>healthy volunteer</keyword>
  <keyword>prevention</keyword>
  <keyword>Covigenix VAX-001</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

