<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04599608</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20HH6332</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04599608</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prediction of Drug Response Using an Ex Vivo Organ Culture (EVOC) on Fresh Human Tumour Samples From Metastatic Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>CURESPONSE</acronym>
  <official_title>Prediction of Patient Drug Response Using an Ex Vivo Organ Culture (EVOC) on Fresh Human Tumour Samples From Metastatic Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Imperial College London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Curesponse Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Imperial College London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this study is to determine how sensitive and specific the Curesponse&#xD;
      Ex Vivo Organ Culture (EVOC) model is at predicting a patient's clinical response to a&#xD;
      specific cancer therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      248 patients from participating UK hospitals will have a biopsy for the development of an&#xD;
      Ex-vivo organ culture at the Curesponse Laboratory. Patients will have standard of care&#xD;
      anticancer therapy after the biopsy and be followed up for 6 months following their biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The combined results of the study will show whether the EVOC has potential to be useful for&#xD;
      future patients prospectively in determining whether a certain clinical treatment is likely&#xD;
      to benefit them.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a A Phase II multi-centre prediction study of the Curesponse Ex Vivo Organ Culture&#xD;
      (EVOC) model in patients with suspected or confirmed advanced or metastatic malignancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with suspected or confirmed, advanced or metastatic malignancy in whom at least 1&#xD;
      site is amenable for biopsy, and who would be planned to receive systemic anti-cancer&#xD;
      therapy, where disease response can be measured by conventional imaging methods will be&#xD;
      recruited for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will undergo a research biopsy where up to 6 tissue samples will be collected.&#xD;
      Patients will also have the option to provide an additional single blood sample for germline&#xD;
      genetic testing. Patients will then attend their hospital clinical to receive standard of&#xD;
      care anticancer therapy as discussed with their oncologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Concurrently to the patients treatment, the tissue samples will be transported to the&#xD;
      Curesponse laboratory for the development of the EVOC. The EVOC will be treated with a range&#xD;
      of anticancer therapies, including the same treatment that the patient will be receiving in&#xD;
      clinic. The model will predict whether the cancer will respond to the therapy. Additionally,&#xD;
      providing the patient consents, the tissue will also undergo tumour gene profiling related to&#xD;
      the secondary and exploratory endpoints and objectives.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The EVOC to demonstrate a sensitivity and specificity of at least 70% for predicting a patients clinical response to a specific anti-cancer therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>From biopsy to the end of the patient's final imaging response assessment at Follow up 3.</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of patient's treatment clinical to the EVOC treated with the same therapy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of tumour heterogeneity in relation to treatment response using the EVOC model</measure>
    <time_frame>During the biopsy</time_frame>
    <description>Tumour gene profiling on tissue samples obtained at the biopsy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess variability in cell populations within the EVOC before and after treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>From pre-treatment of EVOC up to the end of treatment on the EVOC model.</time_frame>
    <description>FACS and other methods of analysis to analyse the changes in cell population of the EVOC.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation and characterisation of viable and resistant cancer cells in the EVOC following treatment and assessment of their response to other therapeutic agents.</measure>
    <time_frame>End of treatment on EVOC model.</time_frame>
    <description>Following treatment of EVOC, viable/resistant cancer cells to be extracted and harvested, to be further grown for further treatment response assessments in the laboratory.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the clinical utility of the EVOC compared to other predictions of response via additional technologies for cancer treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>Biopsy up to end of treatment of EVOC.</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by genomic profiling where relevant, and the comparison of tumour gene profiling to germline genetic testing.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">248</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Cancer</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with suspected or confirmed, advanced or metastatic malignancy in whom at least 1&#xD;
        site is amenable for biopsy, and who would be planned to receive systemic anti-cancer&#xD;
        therapy, where disease response can be measured by conventional imaging methods.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Suspected or confirmed advanced or metastatic cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Aged &gt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Life expectancy &gt; 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ECOG Performance Status 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. At least one tumour lesion which is amenable for 16 G biopsy (minimum of 2 cores)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Planned to receive standard of care therapy or an experimental treatment as part of a&#xD;
             clinical trial following the biopsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Written informed consent and ability to comply with study protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Measurable disease as per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumours (RECIST)&#xD;
             version 1.1 by CT or MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnant and/or breastfeeding woman&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Lesion is non accessible&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any other severe concurrent disease which in the judgment of the investigator would&#xD;
             make the patient inappropriate for entry into this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Known carrier for acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Known carrier for hepatitis B or hepatitis C virus indicating acute or chronic&#xD;
             infection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jonathan Krell, Dr</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Imperial College London</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ayushi J Pabari</last_name>
    <phone>+44 (0)20 3313 0684</phone>
    <email>a.pabari@imperial.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 15, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 21, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 21, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ex Vivo Organ Culture</keyword>
  <keyword>Biopsy</keyword>
  <keyword>Advanced/Metastatic cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Prediction of response to cancer treatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

