<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04599062</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>201504731 (8 milliliter dose)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04599062</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>TVEC and Preop Radiation for Sarcoma (8 ml Dose)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Neoadjuvant Intralesional Injection of Talimogene Laherparepvec With Concurrent Preoperative Radiation in Patients With Locally Advanced Soft Tissue Sarcomas</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Varun Monga, MD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Amgen</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Iowa</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this research study is to determine the safety and tolerability of talimogene&#xD;
      laherparepvec when combined with radiation therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 46 people will take part in this study conducted by investigators at the&#xD;
      University of Iowa.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a single-arm open-label phase Ib and phase II clinical study assessing the safety and&#xD;
      relative efficacy of concurrent talimogene laherparepvec in combination with radiotherapy in&#xD;
      patients with soft tissue sarcomas. Patients will be treated with neoadjuvant radiation and&#xD;
      weekly intratumoral injections of talimogene laherparepvec. Weekly injections of talimogene&#xD;
      laherparepvec will be continued until surgery. Surgery will be performed 4-6 weeks from the&#xD;
      end of radiation therapy to allow for resolution of acute toxicities per current standard of&#xD;
      care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 10, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 1b: Number of Participants With Dose Limiting Toxicities (DLTs)</measure>
    <time_frame>14 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>A DLT is defined as any of the following talimogene laherparepvec-related toxicity or related to the combination of talimogene laherparepvec and radiation therapy during treatment and up to 4 weeks after the last talimogene laherparepvec injection: Grade 3 or greater immune-mediated adverse events, Grade 3 or greater allergic reactions, any grade plasmacytoma, any other unexpected grade 3 or greater hematologic or non-hematologic toxicity, with the exceptions of: any grade of alopecia, expected radiation related skin toxicity of any grade, Grade 3 arthralgia or myalgia, brief (&lt; 1 week) grade 3 fatigue, Grade 3 fever, Grade 3 diarrhea or vomiting responding to supportive case.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 2: Number of Subjects With Pathologic Tumor Necrosis ≥ 90% Following Concurrent Radiation Therapy and Talimogene Laherparepvec.</measure>
    <time_frame>14 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>At the end of the neoadjuvant therapy, patients will undergo resection of the treated tumor. The percentage of post treatment tumor necrosis must be documented. The primary end point for this study is pathologic complete response (pCR), and is defined as ≥ 90% tumor necrosis following concurrent radiation therapy and talimogene laherparepvec.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate (ORR) as Measured by RECIST</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Overall response rate (ORR) as measured by RECIST 1.1. Complete response is the disappearance of all target lesions.Partial response is a 30% decrease in the sum of the longest dimensions of the target lesions, relative to baseline. Progressive disease is an increase of 20% or more in the sum of the longest dimension of target lesions. Stable disease is a decrease in the tumor size of &lt; 30% or an increase of &lt; 20%..</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Disease Progression (TTP)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>TTP is defined as the time from enrollment until objective tumor progression</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival Rate (OS) at 5 Years</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Subjects will be followed for overall survival rate (OS) at 5 years from the last enrollment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">46</enrollment>
  <condition>Soft Tissue Sarcoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Talimogene Laherparepvec in combination with radiotherapy&#xD;
Talimogene Laherparepvec Dose Levels:&#xD;
Dose 0 = talimogene laherparepvec up to 8.0 mL of 108 PFU/mL dosed weekly&#xD;
Dose -1 = talimogene laherparepvec up to 8.0 mL of 108 PFU/mL dosed every 2 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Talimogene Laherparepvec</intervention_name>
    <description>Talimogene Laherparepvec</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Radiotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Concurrent Preoperative Radiation. External Beam Radiation Therapy (EBRT) will be given at the standard dose for resectable soft tissue sarcomas. according to the NCCN sarcoma guidelines.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has provided informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed diagnosis of locally advanced STS that is unresectable with&#xD;
             clear wide margins, for which preoperative radiotherapy is considered appropriate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXAMPLES:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Resectable stage IIB, III, and IV disease that are not suitable for surgically&#xD;
             resection alone due to inability to achieve clear margins.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Including metastatic (stage IV) disease for which radiotherapy and surgical resection&#xD;
             are indicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Except certain histologic subtypes: GIST, Desmoid, Ewing sarcoma, Kaposi sarcoma, bone&#xD;
             sarcomas and myxoid liposarcomas (Grade 1).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous treatment: prior systemic anti-cancer treatment consisting of chemotherapy,&#xD;
             immunotherapy, or targeted therapy are allowed provided therapy completed at least 1&#xD;
             year prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No prior Talimogene laherparepvec or tumor vaccines allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No prior radiation to the same tumor bed allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Age ≥18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Both men and women of all races and ethnic groups are eligible for this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ECOG performance status ≤1.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient must have measurable disease:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tumor size at least ≥ 5 cm in the longest diameter as measured by CT scan or MRI for&#xD;
             which radiation is feasible.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient must have injectable disease (direct injection or ultrasound guided).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Certain histologic subtypes: GIST, Desmoid, Ewing sarcoma, Kaposi sarcoma bone&#xD;
             sarcomas and low grade myxoid liposarcomas ( Grade 1).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or evidence of sarcoma associated with immunodeficiency states (e.g.:&#xD;
             Hereditary immune deficiency, HIV, organ transplant or leukemia).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with retroperitoneal and visceral sarcoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or evidence of gastrointestinal inflammatory bowel disease (ulcerative colitis&#xD;
             or Crohn's disease) or other symptomatic autoimmune disease including, inflammatory&#xD;
             bowel disease, or history of any poorly controlled or severe systemic autoimmune&#xD;
             disease (i.e., rheumatoid arthritis, systemic lupus erythematosus, scleroderma, type I&#xD;
             diabetes, or autoimmune vasculitis).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of other malignancy within the past 3 years except treated with curative&#xD;
             intent and no known active disease present and has not received chemotherapy for ≥ 1&#xD;
             year before enrollment/randomization and low risk for recurrence.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of prior or current autoimmune disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of prior or current splenectomy or splenic irradiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active herpetic skin lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Require intermittent or chronic treatment with an anti-herpetic drug (e.g.,&#xD;
             acyclovir), other than intermittent topical use.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any non-oncology vaccine therapies used for the prevention of infectious disease&#xD;
             within 28 days prior to enrollment and during treatment period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant treatment with therapeutic anticoagulants such as warfarin. Patients on&#xD;
             therapeutic low molecular weight heparin may be allowed provided the dose can be&#xD;
             safely held as per the treating investigator on the morning of scheduled intratumoral&#xD;
             injection and can be resumed 12 hours after the procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) disease (requires negative test for&#xD;
             clinically suspected HIV infection).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute or chronic hepatitis B or hepatitis C infection (requires negative test for&#xD;
             clinically suspected hepatitis B or hepatitis C infection).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of hepatitis B -&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Positive HBV surface antigen (indicative for chronic hepatitis B or recent acute&#xD;
                  hepatitis B).&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Negative HBV surface antigen but positive HBV total core antibody (indicative for&#xD;
                  resolved hepatitis B infection or occult hepatitis B) and detectable copies of&#xD;
                  HBV DNA by PCR (detectable HBV DNA copies suggest occult hepatitis B).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of hepatitis C -&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Positive HCV antibody and positive HCV RNA by PCR (undetectable RNA copies suggest&#xD;
             past and resolved hepatitis C infection).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects who are pregnant or breast-feeding, or planning to become pregnant&#xD;
             during study treatment and through 3 months after the last dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects of childbearing potential or male subjects who are unwilling to use 2&#xD;
             highly effective methods of contraception during study treatment and through 3 months&#xD;
             after the last dose of study treatment. See Section 7.5 for more details.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently receiving treatment in another investigational device or drug study, or less&#xD;
             than 30 days since ending treatment on another investigational device or drug&#xD;
             study(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other investigational procedures while participating in this study that could affect&#xD;
             the primary objective of the study as determined by the PI are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject previously has entered this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are receiving any other investigational agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of CNS metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to talimogene laherparepvec.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with&#xD;
             study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on or requiring immunosuppressive therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following laboratory abnormalities:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin &lt; 9.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt; 1500 per mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count &lt; 100,000 per mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin &gt; 1.5 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt; 2.5 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alkaline phosphatase &gt; 2.5 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  PT (or INR) and PTT (or aPTT) &gt; 1.5 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine &gt; 2.0 × ULN&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Varun Monga, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Iowa Holden Comprehensive Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Varun Monga, MD</last_name>
    <phone>319-384-9497</phone>
    <email>varun-monga@uiowa.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Iowa Hospitals and Clinics</name>
      <address>
        <city>Iowa City</city>
        <state>Iowa</state>
        <zip>52242</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Varun Monga, MD</last_name>
      <phone>319-384-9497</phone>
      <email>varun-monga@uiowa.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Varun Monga, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Iowa</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Varun Monga, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Talimogene laherparepvec</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

