<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04597957</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10511</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04597957</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Fruit and Vegetable Prescription Program Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Control Trial of a Fruit and Vegetable Prescription Program at a Federally Qualified Health System and Its Impact on Health Outcomes in Patients With Diabetes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Henry Ford Health System</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Blue Cross Blue Shield of Michigan Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Henry Ford Health System</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The Fruit and Vegetable Prescription Program Study is a pilot randomized controlled trial of&#xD;
      patients with type 2 diabetes participating in a fruit and vegetable prescription program&#xD;
      from a Federally Qualified Health Center in Detroit, MI . Changes in hemoglobin A1C (%),&#xD;
      blood pressure (BP) and weight (lbs.) will be assessed changes to discern the impact on those&#xD;
      that participated in a fruit and vegetable prescription program compared to those that&#xD;
      received non-incentivized diabetes standard of care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Fresh Prescription (Fresh Rx) Program is a fruit and vegetable prescription program that&#xD;
      brings together the healthcare system and the food system. This fosters innovative&#xD;
      relationships to enhance the understanding of the correlation between food choices and&#xD;
      health, increase consumption of locally grown fruits and vegetables, and build a healthy&#xD;
      sustainable food system. This promising approach to a healthier food system connects patients&#xD;
      to fresh, locally grown produce while providing direct economic benefits to small and midsize&#xD;
      farmers and improving health and quality of life for participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Fresh Rx program allots up to $80 ($10 per visit for up to eight visits) for purchase of&#xD;
      fresh fruits and vegetables at that FQHC's farmers' market (referred to as the Mercado). The&#xD;
      Mercado, which is located outside the entrance to the health center, is a collection of&#xD;
      several local produce farmers. The Mercado operates every Thursday (9am-1pm) and will occur&#xD;
      over 15 weeks from June 2018-October 2018. In addition to selling fresh produce, the Mercado&#xD;
      also offers many other positive health promoting activities including cooking demonstrations,&#xD;
      nutrition education and exercise events.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fresh Rx participants are able fill their prescription at the Mercado for fresh produce up to&#xD;
      eight times during the 15-week Fresh Rx program. The visits can, but do not necessarily need&#xD;
      to be in consecutive weeks. The provided debit cards are loaded with the $10 stipend at each&#xD;
      visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A list will be generated from the electronic medical records of the FQHC, of all non-pregnant&#xD;
      patients with type 2 diabetes who had a HbA1C &gt;8.0% over the 6 months prior to the start of&#xD;
      the Fresh Rx Program. Using simple randomization, the list was randomized into two groups:&#xD;
      The Intervention group and the control group. Those selected for the intervention group and&#xD;
      the control group will be contacted by telephone and offered participation by a Community&#xD;
      Health Worker. Once agreeable to participate, both groups will be brought into the center to&#xD;
      sign an informed consent. At that time, they will have their BP, weight and HbA1C tested.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All Fresh Rx participants will complete a basic program orientation that includes receiving&#xD;
      their Fresh Rx debit card that can be used with Mercado vendors. All participants will then&#xD;
      have their BP, weight and HbA1C checked inside the FQHC after their last visit to the Mercado&#xD;
      or within three months of the completion of the Fresh Rx program (January 2, 2019).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All control group participants will be given flyers describing all the health and wellness&#xD;
      programs at the FQHC including the Mercado. No incentive will be given for the Mercado.&#xD;
      Control group participants will be given a $10 gift card to a national brand pharmacy (no&#xD;
      fresh produce available). The enrollment time for the control group will overlap the Fresh Rx&#xD;
      group (June-September 2018). After a 3-month time period, control group participants will&#xD;
      return and have a repeat BP, weight and HbA1C tested. They then will be given a $20 gift card&#xD;
      to the same national brand pharmacy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 12, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hemoglobin a1c (percent) of intervention and control group.</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Both intervention and control groups will have hemoglobin a1c (%) tested at initial visit and 3 months after initial visit.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in systolic blood pressure (mmhg) of intervention and control group.</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Both intervention and control groups will have systolic blood pressure (mmhg) tested at initial visit and 3 months after initial visit.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in diastolic blood pressure (mmhg) in intervention and control group.</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Both intervention and control groups will have diastolic blood pressure (mmhg) tested at initial visit and 3 months after initial visit.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in weight (pounds) in intervention and control group.</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Both intervention and control groups will have weight (pounds) tested at initial visit and and 3 months after initial visit.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of visits to Clinic based farmers market (the mercardo) per participant in Fresh Rx program.</measure>
    <time_frame>15 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Fresh Rx participants were able fill their prescription at the Mercado for fresh produce up to eight times during the 15-week Fresh Rx program. The visits could, but did not necessarily need to be in consecutive weeks. The number of visits to the Mercado per participant will be recorded.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fresh Rx Intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The Fresh Rx intervention group will receive up to 8 visits to the community based farmers market with $10 incentive for fruits and vegetables at each visit.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Diabetic Standard of Care Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Diabetic standard of care control group will receive no incentive for the community based farmers market.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fresh Rx Intervention group</intervention_name>
    <description>Fresh Rx Intervention participants will be able to fill their prescription at the FQHC based Farmers Market for fresh produce up to eight times during the 15-week Fresh Rx program. The provided debit cards will be loaded with the $10 stipend at each visit. At each market session, cooking demonstrations will take place that reinforce healthy food options and how to prepare foods that were available at the Mercado.&#xD;
All control group participants will be given flyers describing all the health and wellness programs at the FQHC including the Mercado. Control group participants will receive a $10 gift card to a national brand pharmacy (no fresh produce available). The enrollment time for the control group will overlap with the Fresh Rx group. After a 3-month time period, the control group will follow up and be given a $20 gift card to the same national brand pharmacy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Diabetic Standard of Care Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Fresh Rx Intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  FQHC patients with history of type 2 diabetics with a history of a hemoglobin a1c &gt;8.0&#xD;
             % in the last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  individuals &lt;18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  type 1 diabetics&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  those that decline participation in the Fresh Rx program&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Richard Bryce, DO</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Chass Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Henry Ford Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Richard Bryce</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48209</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 17, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 17, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 17, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Henry Ford Health System</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Richard Bryce</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Invesigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

