<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04598516</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NL.MUMC.AMACINGrp.1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04598516</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Maastricht Investigation of Renal Function in Absence of- and Post- Contrast in Patients With eGFR LEss Than 30</brief_title>
  <acronym>MIRACLE</acronym>
  <official_title>Maastricht Investigation of Renal Function in Absence of- and Post- Contrast in Patients With Estimated Glomerular Filtration Rate LEss Than 30mL/Min/1.73m2</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Maastricht University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Maastricht University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Intravascular iodinated contrast administration has become crucial to modern medicine.&#xD;
      Currently it is estimated that over 250 million injections are given each year worldwide&#xD;
      during medical scans and interventions. An acute predefined increase in serum creatinine is&#xD;
      considered an indicator of acute kidney injury (AKI). When such an acute increase in serum&#xD;
      creatinine occurs within 5 days post-contrast in absence of another aetiology, it is assumed&#xD;
      to be iodinated contrast administration induced acute kidney injury. For over 50 years now,&#xD;
      acute kidney injury caused by intravascular administration of iodinated contrast material has&#xD;
      been considered a leading cause of hospital-acquired renal failure. Contrast has been&#xD;
      withheld in fear of kidney injury with misdiagnoses and delayed appropriate patient&#xD;
      management as a result. Since 2018, it is now widely accepted that only patients with eGFR&#xD;
      &lt;30 mL/min/1.73m2 are at risk of renal injury after intravascular iodinated contrast material&#xD;
      injection. However, no study to date has been able to distinguish acute kidney injury caused&#xD;
      by iodinated contrast administration from that for which no causal link is established, and&#xD;
      it is unsure a causal relationship exists. There are several studies, in attempts to evaluate&#xD;
      the causal relationship between contrast exposure and nephrotoxicity, that found fluctuations&#xD;
      in absence of contrast similar to those considered to be contrast-induced acute kidney&#xD;
      injury. Similarly, it is unsure whether longer-term negative outcomes are inherent to the&#xD;
      population studied or a result of contrast administration. However, most of these studies are&#xD;
      observational and retrospective in nature. The issue with retrospective studies is that they&#xD;
      often cannot control for confounders and therefore cannot give us causation, only&#xD;
      association. On the other hand, prospective randomized controlled trials comparing&#xD;
      intravascular iodinated contrast administration to no contrast are unlikely given evident&#xD;
      ethical issues. The current prospective observational study proposes to use intra-patient&#xD;
      comparisons of peak change in renal function during periods in absence of- and with contrast&#xD;
      to elucidate the relationship between renal function and contrast administration in this&#xD;
      population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The current prospective observational study proposes to use intra-patient comparisons of peak&#xD;
      changes in renal function (serum creatinine) in absence of- and post- intravascular iodinated&#xD;
      contrast administration, to elucidate the relationship between renal function and contrast&#xD;
      administration in elective patients with eGFR &lt;30 mL/min/1.73m2. The effects of contrast&#xD;
      administration on risk of 1-month dialysis and mortality will also be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Daily serum creatinine assays will be done 1. during 5 days before contrast (= in absence of&#xD;
      contrast), 2. during 5 days after contrast (= post-contrast), and 3. during 5 days at 1-month&#xD;
      post contrast (= 1-month post contrast in absence of contrast). Baseline serum creatinine&#xD;
      values will be obtained on the day before each 5-day series.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Relevant baseline characteristics of patients will be reported to enable a detailed&#xD;
      description of the study population. To explore whether the magnitude of the mean difference&#xD;
      in peak change in serum creatinine before and after contrast administration depends on other&#xD;
      factors, pre-planned subgroup analyses will be performed. To enable subgroup analyses, data&#xD;
      will be collected on 1) prophylactic hydration (yes vs no); 2) administration route&#xD;
      (intra-arterial versus intravenous contrast administration); 3) contrast volume (high vs low)&#xD;
      and 4) comorbidity (presence vs absence of diabetes).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference in peak change in serum creatinine from baseline between a 5 day period before contrast and a 5 day period immediately after contrast.</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>The underlying hypothesis is that intravascular iodinated contrast administration will cause greater peak changes in serum creatinine within 5 days. The primary outcome is peak changes in serum creatinine within 5 days from a baseline measurement. The effect of contrast administration will be expressed as the mean intra-patient difference in peak changes in serum creatinine between pre- and post-contrast periods. Peak change in eGFR will also be calculated based on the peak serum creatinine values.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference in peak change in serum creatinine from baseline between a 5 day period before contrast and a 5 day period at 1-month post-contrast.</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>mean intra-patient difference between peak changes in serum creatinine occurring within 5 days pre-contrast and 5 days at 1-month post-contrast from baseline measurements (baseline = measurement on the day before every 5-day series). Peak change in eGFR will also be calculated based on the peak serum creatinine values.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to post-contrast peak change in serum creatinine.</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>Time to greatest post-contrast change in serum creatinine from baseline (day 0) within 5 days after contrast administration.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acute kidney injury in absence of- vs post-contrast.</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidences of peak changes in serum creatinine corresponding to definitions for classic CIN (an increase in serum creatinine greater than 44umol/l or greater than 25% from baseline) and KDIGO acute kidney injury (an increase in serum creatinine greater than 26.5 umol/L from baseline or more than 1.5 times the baseline value). Peak changes will be determined within 5 days pre-contrast and 5 days post-contrast.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1 month eGFR decline &gt;=5 mL/min/1.73m2.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Incidences of peak eGFR decline &gt;=5 mL/min/1.73m2 within 5 days pre- and within 5 days at 1-month post-contrast</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1 month dialysis and mortality.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Incidences of dialysis and mortality at 1 month post-contrast.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">72</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Kidney Injury (Nontraumatic)</condition>
  <condition>Contrast-induced Nephropathy</condition>
  <condition>Renal Insufficiency</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>serum creatinine assay</intervention_name>
    <description>peak change in serum creatinine in a period of 5 days from baseline (day 0) will be determined</description>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      serum samples may be stored for renal damage biomarker assays&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with eGFR &lt;30 mL/min/1.73m2 in absence of dialysis referred for an elective&#xD;
        procedure with intravascular administration of iodinated contrast material at Maastricht&#xD;
        UMC+ are eligible for inclusion.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  eGFR &lt;30 mL/min/1.73m2 in absence of dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  referred for an elective procedure with intravascular administration of iodinated&#xD;
             contrast material at Maastricht UMC+&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age &lt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  dialysis or pre-dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  intravascular contrast administration &lt;30 days before the first baseline measurement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  emergency or intensive care status&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inability to complete follow-up&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>intravascular iodinated contrast</keyword>
  <keyword>Post-Contrast Acute Kidney Injury</keyword>
  <keyword>Contrast-induced acute kidney injury</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

