<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04594759</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>00103493</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04594759</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Weekly Isotretinoin Therapy Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>WIT</acronym>
  <official_title>Weekly Isotretinoin Therapy for the Treatment of Moderate Acne Vulgaris</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical University of South Carolina</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of South Carolina</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In current Dermatology practice, options for moderate acne vulgaris remain limited. The&#xD;
      mainstay of treatment for moderate acne remains long courses of oral antibiotics despite&#xD;
      emerging antibiotic resistance. The efficacy of daily to twice daily dosed isotretinoin, an&#xD;
      oral vitamin A derivative, for treatment of severe acne has been well established. The&#xD;
      purpose of this study is to determine if once weekly dosed isotretinoin is effective for the&#xD;
      treatment of patients with moderate acne. Additionally, the study aims to evaluate patient&#xD;
      satisfaction and identify any adverse effects on this alternative dosing regimen.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In current Dermatology practice, options for moderate acne vulgaris remain limited. Moderate&#xD;
      acne is clinically defined as acne that has not responded to at least three months of topical&#xD;
      therapy and is not severe enough for initial treatment with a conventional course of&#xD;
      isotretinoin (formerly known as Accutane). The mainstay of treatment for moderate acne&#xD;
      remains long courses of oral antibiotics, mainly tetracyclines (doxycycline, minocycline) and&#xD;
      occasionally trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole. Males with moderate acne, in particular, are&#xD;
      especially limited in their treatment options as they are not eligible for hormonal&#xD;
      management (spironolactone, oral contraceptive pills) like their female counterparts.&#xD;
      Additionally, even for those regardless of gender who may eventually qualify for a&#xD;
      traditional isotretinoin course, many insurance companies first require failure to respond to&#xD;
      at least three months of oral antibiotics. Nagler et. al found that the average antibiotic&#xD;
      use for moderate to severe acne prior to receiving isotretinoin was 331 days, with 15.3% of&#xD;
      patients prescribed antibiotics for three months or less, 88% for six months or more, and 46%&#xD;
      for at least one year.1 Despite the widespread use of oral antibiotics in acne, antibiotic&#xD;
      resistance is considered a global threat per the CDC2, and there have been calls to limit&#xD;
      their use in acne because of concerns of bacterial resistance3,4,5. Because of this, there is&#xD;
      a significant need for more research on alternative treatment options for moderate acne.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once weekly isotretinoin dosing has the potential to significantly improve moderate acne with&#xD;
      good patient satisfaction and safety profile; however, no study findings on this treatment&#xD;
      option have been published to date. The efficacy of isotretinoin, an oral vitamin A&#xD;
      derivative, for treatment of acne has been well established. The traditional treatment course&#xD;
      for severe acne consists of once to twice daily dosing (0.5-1 mg/kg/day) for 4-7 months (or&#xD;
      150mg/kg total cumulative dose). Though efficacious, there are numerous reported side-effects&#xD;
      due to achieving the cumulative dose rapidly by once to twice daily dosing, such as severe&#xD;
      dry skin, lips, and eyes, as well as liver enzyme and lipid abnormalities. Because of this,&#xD;
      there have been studies exploring alternative isotretinoin dosing regimens including&#xD;
      microdose, lower daily dose regimens (0.15-0.4 mg/kg/day6, 0.25-0.4 mg/kg/day7, 0.3-0.4&#xD;
      mg/kg/day8,9, in addition to 5 mg/day10 and 0.15-0.28 mg/kg/day with additional of local&#xD;
      application of 1% clindamycin gel every other day11) and daily dosing for 7-10 consecutive&#xD;
      days (0.5-0.7 mg/kg/day) out of each month only.7,12,13,14 All studies had favorable outcomes&#xD;
      with alternative dosing, despite the lower total cumulative dose versus conventional dosing.&#xD;
      Those who also analyzed adverse effect rates with alternative isotretinoin dosing found that&#xD;
      these were either rarely observed or similar to conventional dosing.6,8,9,10,12,14 In&#xD;
      contrast, the potential adverse effects of oral antibiotics used for acne include&#xD;
      photosensitivity and nausea/vomiting (doxycycline), drug-induced pigment deposition and&#xD;
      drug-induced systemic lupus erythematosus (minocycline), and angioedema and drug rashes&#xD;
      including drug reaction with eosinophilia and systemic symptoms (DRESS) syndrome&#xD;
      (trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole). Interestingly, rates of acne recurrence between alternative&#xD;
      isotretinoin dosing and conventional dosing were similar at follow-up,6,7,9 despite a much&#xD;
      older study from 1984 that found otherwise.15 Additionally, cost of alternative isotretinoin&#xD;
      dosing was lower than with conventional dosing,8,9,13 and patient satisfaction was highest in&#xD;
      the alternative dosing groups.7,10 For these reasons, this study aims to evaluate the&#xD;
      efficacy of once weekly isotretinoin dosing (1-1.5 mg/kg/week) as a potential alternative to&#xD;
      oral antibiotics for the treatment of patients with moderate acne. Secondary endpoints&#xD;
      include patient satisfaction and adverse effects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 11, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>The study member assessing change in acne using the Comprehensive Acne Severity Scale does not know the medication the participants are taking.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in visible acne (efficacy of once weekly isotretinoin)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, monthly, and end of treatment, total of 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Will look at clinical photos before, during, and after treatment and grade acne using a validated, clinical grading system (Comprehensive Acne Severity Scale, CASS) with &quot;0&quot; being clear skin and &quot;5&quot; being very severe acne</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in patient's quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, monthly, and end of treatment, total of 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Participants will use the Dermatology Life Quality Index survey throughout the study with &quot;0 - 1&quot; being that the intervention had no effect at all on patient's life and &quot;21 - 30&quot; being an extremely large effect on patient's life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Presence of adverse effects</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, monthly, and end of treatment, total of 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Participants will fill out a survey throughout the study regarding presence and severity of any potential side-effects of the medication (that have been reported with isotretinoin traditional dosing). Participants will also get intermittent blood work per standard of care while on isotretinoin to determine if the participant has any blood work abnormalities while on the medication.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Acne Vulgaris</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Isotretinoin</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be getting isotretinoin (1-1.5 mg/kg/week)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients 12 years and older with the diagnosis of moderate acne vulgaris&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are at baseline on long-term tetracycline antibiotics, long-term&#xD;
             trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole, or on spironolactone for any reason&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have taken isotretinoin in the past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with hypersensitivity to isotretinoin or to any of its components&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females who are pregnant, likely to become pregnant, or will be breast-feeding during&#xD;
             the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of major depression, mania, or psychosis with an active&#xD;
             episode during the past year including current psychotic symptoms and/or current&#xD;
             suicidal ideation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients with cognitive impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with baseline kidney or liver disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with baseline hypertriglyceridemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with history of or current pseudotumor cerebri&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any clinically significant unstable medical condition which could pose a&#xD;
             risk to the safety of the patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability or unwillingness of subject or legal guardian/representative to give&#xD;
             informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Samantha Karlin, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Samantha Karline</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charleston</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29403</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nagler AR, Milam EC, Orlow SJ. The use of oral antibiotics before isotretinoin therapy in patients with acne. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2016 Feb;74(2):273-9. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2015.09.046. Epub 2015 Oct 30.</citation>
    <PMID>26525749</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Center for Disease Control (https://www.cdc.gov/drugresistance/biggest-threats.html?CDC_AA_refVal=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cdc.gov%2Fdrugresistance%2Fbiggest_threats.html)</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dreno B, Thiboutot D, Gollnick H, Bettoli V, Kang S, Leyden JJ, Shalita A, Torres V; Global Alliance to Improve Outcomes in Acne. Antibiotic stewardship in dermatology: limiting antibiotic use in acne. Eur J Dermatol. 2014 May-Jun;24(3):330-4. doi: 10.1684/ejd.2014.2309. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24721547</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bowe WP. Antibiotic resistance and acne: where we stand and what the future holds. J Drugs Dermatol. 2014 Jun;13(6):s66-70.</citation>
    <PMID>24918574</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ross JI, Snelling AM, Carnegie E, Coates P, Cunliffe WJ, Bettoli V, Tosti G, Katsambas A, Galvan Peréz Del Pulgar JI, Rollman O, Török L, Eady EA, Cove JH. Antibiotic-resistant acne: lessons from Europe. Br J Dermatol. 2003 Mar;148(3):467-78.</citation>
    <PMID>12653738</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mandekou-Lefaki I, Delli F, Teknetzis A, Euthimiadou R, Karakatsanis G. Low-dose schema of isotretinoin in acne vulgaris. Int J Clin Pharmacol Res. 2003;23(2-3):41-6.</citation>
    <PMID>15018017</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lee JW, Yoo KH, Park KY, Han TY, Li K, Seo SJ, Hong CK. Effectiveness of conventional, low-dose and intermittent oral isotretinoin in the treatment of acne: a randomized, controlled comparative study. Br J Dermatol. 2011 Jun;164(6):1369-75. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2133.2010.10152.x. Epub 2011 May 17.</citation>
    <PMID>21114478</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Amichai B, Shemer A, Grunwald MH. Low-dose isotretinoin in the treatment of acne vulgaris. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2006 Apr;54(4):644-6.</citation>
    <PMID>16546586</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kotori MG. Low-dose Vitamin &quot;A&quot; Tablets-treatment of Acne Vulgaris. Med Arch. 2015 Feb;69(1):28-30. doi: 10.5455/medarh.2015.69.28-30. Epub 2015 Feb 21.</citation>
    <PMID>25870473</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rademaker M, Wishart JM, Birchall NM. Isotretinoin 5 mg daily for low-grade adult acne vulgaris--a placebo-controlled, randomized double-blind study. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2014 Jun;28(6):747-54. doi: 10.1111/jdv.12170. Epub 2013 Apr 26.</citation>
    <PMID>23617693</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sardana K, Garg VK, Sehgal VN, Mahajan S, Bhushan P. Efficacy of fixed low-dose isotretinoin (20 mg, alternate days) with topical clindamycin gel in moderately severe acne vulgaris. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2009 May;23(5):556-60. doi: 10.1111/j.1468-3083.2008.03022.x. Epub 2009 Jan 9.</citation>
    <PMID>19143903</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Akman A, Durusoy C, Senturk M, Koc CK, Soyturk D, Alpsoy E. Treatment of acne with intermittent and conventional isotretinoin: a randomized, controlled multicenter study. Arch Dermatol Res. 2007 Dec;299(10):467-73. Epub 2007 Aug 21.</citation>
    <PMID>17710426</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Goulden V, Clark SM, McGeown C, Cunliffe WJ. Treatment of acne with intermittent isotretinoin. Br J Dermatol. 1997 Jul;137(1):106-8.</citation>
    <PMID>9274635</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kaymak Y, Ilter N. The effectiveness of intermittent isotretinoin treatment in mild or moderate acne. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2006 Nov;20(10):1256-60.</citation>
    <PMID>17062042</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Strauss JS, Rapini RP, Shalita AR, Konecky E, Pochi PE, Comite H, Exner JH. Isotretinoin therapy for acne: results of a multicenter dose-response study. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1984 Mar;10(3):490-6.</citation>
    <PMID>6233335</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 14, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Samantha Karlin, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dermatology Resident Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acne Vulgaris</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Isotretinoin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The individual participant data collected during the study after de-identification</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Immediately following publication, indefinitely</ipd_time_frame>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

