<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04599868</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Mgso4 for PTL in pp</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04599868</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>High Versus Low Dose of Magnesium Sulfate as Initial Tocolytic Agent for Preterm Labour in Symptomatic Placenta Previa.</brief_title>
  <official_title>High Versus Low Dose of Magnesium Sulfate as Initial Tocolytic Agent for Preterm Labour in Symptomatic Placenta Previa: A Randomized Controlled Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To assess the efficacy and safety of alternative magnesium sulfate regimens when used as&#xD;
      single agent tocolytic therapy for prevention of preterm labour in patients with symptomatic&#xD;
      placenta previa and subsequent changes in the cervical length .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Placenta previa is implantation of placenta on or near internal os .It is classified into&#xD;
      major degree when lower edge of placenta lies within 2 cm from internal os , and minor degree&#xD;
      if lower edge of placenta at lower uterine segment but more than 2 cm from internal os .&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are many risk factors for developing placenta previa including multi parity , multiple&#xD;
      pregnancy , increased maternal age (&gt;35y ) , previous uterine surgery , history of placenta&#xD;
      previa (4-8%) .&#xD;
&#xD;
      A significant degree of uterine contractility has been observed with symptomatic placenta&#xD;
      previa. It is directly associated with vaginal bleeding. However, a large percentage of women&#xD;
      who have placenta previa associated with haemorrhage will experience subclinical uterine&#xD;
      contractions before the onset of overt vaginal bleeding. Therefore, the use of tocolytic&#xD;
      agents in management of placenta previa seems reasonable .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Magnesium sulfate alters calcium up take, binding and distribution in smooth muscles of the&#xD;
      uterus, so reduces the frequency of cell depolarization and inhibits myometrial contraction .&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to its tocolytic action magnesium sulfate also provide neuroprotection to preterm&#xD;
      infant . .&#xD;
&#xD;
      At women Health Hospital, Assiut University, Egypt our policy is using magnesium sulfate as&#xD;
      first line for tocolysis for placenta previa patients with preterm uterine contractions. By&#xD;
      giving a loading dose of 4 g on 150 ml saline intravenous infusion over 20 minutes, and a&#xD;
      maintenance dose of 6g/6h on 500 ml saline slow intra venous infusion&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>1) Evaluate efficacy ( postponing delivery for 48h - till administration of dexamethason ) of different regimens 0f MgSO4 in patients with pp in PTL . 2) Different regimens of MGSO4 and changes in cervical length</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hour</time_frame>
    <description>compairing efficacy of low vs high dose of MgSO4 to postpone preterm delivery in patients with symptomatic pp and subsequent changes in cervical length</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>GA at delivery</measure>
    <time_frame>at time of delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>birth weight .</measure>
    <time_frame>at time of delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>number of full term babies</measure>
    <time_frame>at time of delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>fetal and Neonatal death .</measure>
    <time_frame>at time of delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apgar score at five minutes .</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neonatal ICU admission &amp; duration of admition</measure>
    <time_frame>at time of delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">130</enrollment>
  <condition>Preterm Labor in Placenta Previa</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>low dose of magnesium sulfat</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients will receive 4 g intravenous loading dose of magnesium sulfate on 150 ml saline over 20 minute period. Patients then will receive maintenance therapy with magnesium sulfate 1g / h ( low dose group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>High dose of magnesium sulfat</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients will receive 4 g intravenous loading dose of magnesium sulfate on 150 ml saline over 20 minute period. Patients then will receive maintenance therapy with magnesium sulfate 2g/h ( high dose group )</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>magnesium sulfate</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will be assessed hourly for pulse and blood pressure, contraction frequency, vaginal bleeding. With strict monitoring for symptoms of magnesium sulfate toxicity.&#xD;
All patients will receive dexamethasone to enhance fetal lung maturity. RH status will be determined for all patients, . Hb level will be measured and anemic patients will receive correction by blood transfusion Cervical length will be measured after 24 h&amp; 48 h from administration of magnesium sulfate in both groups Maternal serum magnesium will be measured at admission and after 4 hours ,12 hours and 24 hours after administration of magnesium sulfate Patients of both groups will be assessed for their neonatal outcomes include deaths and gestational age at delivery, fetal birth weight. Apgar score at five minutes, neonatal ICU admission and duration of admission and neonatal calcium level at time of delivery will be also assessed.</description>
    <arm_group_label>High dose of magnesium sulfat</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>low dose of magnesium sulfat</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Singleton pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Gestational age between 28 weeks to 37 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients presented to the hospital with per vaginal bleeding and in whom a clinical&#xD;
             diagnosis of placenta previa is confirmed by trans vaginal ultrasound.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Placenta previa with preterm uterine contractions (&lt; 3 contractions in 10 minutes)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Ability to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Placental abruption .&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Women with placenta previa and severe attack of bleeding need immediate termination&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Clinical criteria of intra uterine infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. IUGR.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Fetal anomalies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Fetal distress.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. IUFD.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. PROM&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. High order multiple pregnancies.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Treatment with any tocolytic agent before maternal transport.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Inability or refusal to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Women with any contraindication for use of magnesium sulfate as patients with renal&#xD;
             failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients with bleeding disorder or on anticoagulant therapy .&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>only females</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Doaa Mostafa Mahmoud, resident doctor</last_name>
    <phone>01061699727</phone>
    <email>doaa21122@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Mostafa N eldeen, doctor</last_name>
    <phone>01021216060</phone>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Morfaw F, Fundoh M, Bartoszko J, Mbuagbaw L, Thabane L. Using tocolysis in pregnant women with symptomatic placenta praevia does not significantly improve prenatal, perinatal, neonatal and maternal outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Syst Rev. 2018 Dec 27;7(1):249. doi: 10.1186/s13643-018-0923-2.</citation>
    <PMID>30591076</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Marshall NE, Fu R, Guise JM. Impact of multiple cesarean deliveries on maternal morbidity: a systematic review. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2011 Sep;205(3):262.e1-8. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2011.06.035. Epub 2011 Jun 15. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22071057</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Milosević J, Lilić V, Tasić M, Radović-Janosević D, Stefanović M, Antić V. [Placental complications after a previous cesarean section]. Med Pregl. 2009 May-Jun;62(5-6):212-6. Serbian.</citation>
    <PMID>19650556</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wennberg AL, Opdahl S, Bergh C, Aaris Henningsen AK, Gissler M, Romundstad LB, Pinborg A, Tiitinen A, Skjærven R, Wennerholm UB. Effect of maternal age on maternal and neonatal outcomes after assisted reproductive technology. Fertil Steril. 2016 Oct;106(5):1142-1149.e14. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2016.06.021. Epub 2016 Jul 9.</citation>
    <PMID>27399261</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Saleh Gargari S, Seify Z, Haghighi L, Khoshnood Shariati M, Mirzamoradi M. Risk Factors and Consequent Outcomes of Placenta Previa: Report From a Referral Center. Acta Med Iran. 2016 Nov;54(11):713-717.</citation>
    <PMID>28033694</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>) Almnabri, A.A., et al., Management of Placenta Previa During Pregnancy. The Egyptian Journal of Hospital Medicine, 2017. 68(3): p. 1549-1553</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sharma A, Suri V, Gupta I. Tocolytic therapy in conservative management of symptomatic placenta previa. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2004 Feb;84(2):109-13.</citation>
    <PMID>14871511</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McNamara HC, Crowther CA, Brown J. Different treatment regimens of magnesium sulphate for tocolysis in women in preterm labour. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015 Dec 14;(12):CD011200. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD011200.pub2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26662716</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kawagoe Y, Sameshima H, Ikenoue T, Yasuhi I, Kawarabayashi T. Magnesium sulfate as a second-line tocolytic agent for preterm labor: a randomized controlled trial in Kyushu Island. J Pregnancy. 2011;2011:965060. doi: 10.1155/2011/965060. Epub 2011 Jun 16.</citation>
    <PMID>21773032</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 23, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Doaa M. Mostafa</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Resident of obstetrics &amp;Gynecology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Obstetric Labor, Premature</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Placenta Previa</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Magnesium Sulfate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

