<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04592978</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R01AA028639</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01AA028639</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04592978</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Personalized Feedback Intervention for Alcohol and Opioid Use Among Adults With Chronic Pain</brief_title>
  <official_title>Personalized Feedback Intervention to Address Hazardous Drinking and Alcohol-Opioid Interactions Among Adults With Chronic Pain.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Syracuse University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Syracuse University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Over one-quarter of American adults engage in hazardous drinking (i.e., a pattern of alcohol&#xD;
      consumption that increases risk for harmful consequences), which is the third leading cause&#xD;
      of preventable death in the U.S. Rates of hazardous drinking are significantly higher among&#xD;
      individuals with (vs. without) chronic pain. Moreover, 20% of individuals prescribed opioids&#xD;
      endorse concurrent alcohol and opioid use, which may interfere with chronic pain treatment&#xD;
      and lead to dangerous/potentially fatal health effects. No interventions to date have&#xD;
      targeted either hazardous drinking or concurrent use of alcohol and opioids in the context of&#xD;
      chronic pain. The current four-year R01 builds upon our past work by developing a brief,&#xD;
      single-session, computer-based, personalized feedback intervention (PFI) designed to enhance&#xD;
      knowledge regarding adverse pain-alcohol-opioid interrelations, increase motivation and&#xD;
      intention to reduce hazardous drinking, and reduce positive attitudes and intention regarding&#xD;
      concurrent use of alcohol and prescription opioid medications. Specifically, we will develop&#xD;
      an integrated PFI for hazardous drinkers with chronic pain who are prescribed opioids&#xD;
      (PA-PFI). Our approach will follow a staged model consistent with NIH guidelines for&#xD;
      developing and standardizing behavioral interventions. Phase IA activities will involve&#xD;
      collecting qualitative and quantitative feedback from three iterative focus groups (N = 21)&#xD;
      to refine intervention content and evaluate treatment acceptability and feasibility. Phase IB&#xD;
      activities will include a proof-of-concept and highly rigorous randomized clinical trial&#xD;
      designed to compare PA-PFI to control PFI (C-PFI) among a sample of 174 hazardous drinkers&#xD;
      with chronic pain who are currently prescribed opioid medications. This study represents an&#xD;
      important and pivotal step in the larger landscape of translating basic research to more&#xD;
      efficacious strategies for reducing hazardous drinking among underserved populations with&#xD;
      medical comorbidities. This intervention would be highly disseminable and relevant to&#xD;
      millions of hazardous drinkers with chronic pain. Given the collective public health impact&#xD;
      of chronic pain, hazardous drinking, and concurrent alcohol-prescription opioid use, we&#xD;
      believe the current study will yield findings that enhance scientific knowledge, enhance our&#xD;
      understanding of mechanisms in reciprocal pain-alcohol-opioid relations, and inform the&#xD;
      development of novel treatments for hazardous drinkers with chronic pain that are adaptable&#xD;
      and easily implemented across a variety of healthcare settings.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 26, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Stage 1A will consist of 3 focus groups of 7 individuals used to develop and refine the pain-alcohol personalized feedback intervention (PFI).&#xD;
Stage 1B will employ a randomized controlled trial to compare the effects of the pain-alcohol PFI to a control PFI.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in knowledge of adverse pain-alcohol-opioid interrelations</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and immediately after receiving the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed via greater number of correct responses on the 10-item Pain Alcohol Opioid Knowledge Questionnaire (PAOKQ).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in motivation/readiness to reduce drinking</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and immediately after receiving the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed via Alcohol Ladder: a visual analogue contemplation ladder providing a single continuous metric of motivation and readiness to reduce drinking, where higher responses (range: 1-10) indicating greater motivation/readiness to change/reduce drinking.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in attitudes and intentions to co-use alcohol and opioids</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and immediately after receiving the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed via Alcohol-Opioid Co-Use Attitudes/Intentions (AOAI) measure, where greater scores (range: 16-62) indicate more positive attitudes and greater intentions to co-use alcohol and opioids.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in expectancies for pain-coping/reduction via drinking</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and immediately after receiving the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed via Expectancies for Alcohol Analgesia (EAA) measure, where greater EAA scores (range: 0-45) indicate greater expectancies for alcohol analgesia.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hazardous drinking</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 3 month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed via scores on Alcohol Use Disorders Identification Test (AUDIT), where scores greater than or equal to 8 for males and 7 for females indicate the presence of hazardous drinking.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in frequency of alcohol-opioid co-use</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 3 month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed via self-reported number of days in which alcohol and prescription opioids were concurrently used in the past two weeks.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">195</enrollment>
  <condition>Alcohol Drinking</condition>
  <condition>Pain</condition>
  <condition>Opioid Use</condition>
  <condition>Feedback, Psychological</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pain-Alcohol Personalized Feedback Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Personalized Feedback Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pain-Alcohol Personalized Feeback Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>The intervention will be designed to enhance knowledge regarding adverse pain-alcohol-opioid interrelations as well as increase motivation and intention to reduce hazardous drinking and positive attitudes and intentions regarding concurrent use of alcohol and prescription opioid medications.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pain-Alcohol Personalized Feedback Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control Personalized Feedback Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>The control intervention will incorporate personalized feedback relevant to exercise and nutrition but not address drinking reduction or pain-alcohol-opioid interrelations.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Personalized Feedback Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥ 21 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current hazardous drinker&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current chronic pain&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of prescription opioid medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current alcohol or other substance use treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not being fluent in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current psychiatric distress or thought disorder.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Joseph W. Ditre, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>315-443-1052</phone>
    <email>jwditre@syr.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Syracuse University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Syracuse</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>13210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Joseph W. Ditre</last_name>
      <email>jwditre@syr.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joseph W Ditre, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 6, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Syracuse University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Joseph W. Ditre</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Alcohol</keyword>
  <keyword>Opioids</keyword>
  <keyword>Pain</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alcohol Drinking</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

