<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04597619</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1574642</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>P20GM125507</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04597619</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of a Nonopioid Recovery Pathway Following Surgery for Kidney Stones</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of a Nonopioid Recovery Pathway After Percutaneous Nephrolithotomy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The Miriam Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of General Medical Sciences (NIGMS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Center of Biomedical Research Excellence (COBRE) on Opioids and Overdose</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Minimally Invasive Urology Institute, The Miriam Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Brown Urology Inc., Brown Physicians Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The Miriam Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Evaluation of a nonopioid recovery pathway after percutaneous nephrolithotomy is a pragmatic&#xD;
      pilot study that will apply the knowledge and experience gained with development of an&#xD;
      outpatient opioid reduction protocol to percutaneous nephrolithotomy (PCNL). We have&#xD;
      previously demonstrated that outpatient ureteroscopy and stent placement without&#xD;
      postoperative opioid prescriptions is possible in the vast majority of patients. The success&#xD;
      of this is dependent upon a multimodal approach to the patient's experience of undergoing&#xD;
      endoscopic kidney stone surgery (ureteroscopy) and focuses on the preoperative,&#xD;
      perioperative, and postoperative stages of intervention. Our hypothesis is that a novel&#xD;
      nonopioid pathway after PCNL is both feasible and safe and will reduce postoperative&#xD;
      prescriptions for opioids without impacting clinical outcomes, patient satisfaction or&#xD;
      outpatient resources.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Evaluation of a nonopioid recovery pathway after percutaneous nephrolithotomy is a pragmatic&#xD;
      pilot study which will prospectively compare a cohort undergoing PCNL prior to implementation&#xD;
      of the novel nonopioid pathway undergoing the same procedure utilizing the novel nonopioid&#xD;
      pathway. Current standard of care following PCNL remains the routine prescription of opioid&#xD;
      medications for pain control.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Evaluation of a nonopioid recovery pathway after percutaneous nephrolithotomy has three&#xD;
      specific aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Demonstrate feasibility and acceptability of the novel nonopioid protocol and describe&#xD;
           the barriers to enrollment and reasons for drop out. The feasibility of the protocol&#xD;
           will be measured by dropout of enrolled patients and the acceptability of protocol will&#xD;
           be measured by number of enrolled patients / patients approached and patient&#xD;
           satisfaction via a validated questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Describe what adverse events occur to those on the nonopioid protocol as compared to the&#xD;
           standard of care. Adverse events occurring as an inpatient will be measured by nursing&#xD;
           and physician reporting, and as an outpatient via patient self-reporting, electronic&#xD;
           medical records of emergency department visits and telephone calls to clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Begin to reduce overall opioid prescription writing for patients undergoing PCNL at the&#xD;
           academic institution. The electronic medical records will be queried for prescriptions&#xD;
           written at discharge. The state Opioid Prescription Monitoring Program (PMP) will be&#xD;
           queried for a 30-day period following surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After written consent and enrollment, patients will undergo preoperative counseling regarding&#xD;
      pain after PCNL in the preoperative holding area prior to surgery. The patient will then&#xD;
      undergo percutaneous nephrolithotomy. No procedural changes will be made for study&#xD;
      participants. Postoperatively, patients will be admitted to the post-anesthesia care unit and&#xD;
      standard of care adjunctive and analgesic medications will be administered. The patient will&#xD;
      be admitted to the floor following surgery and postoperative specialized nonopioid PCNL&#xD;
      pathway orders will be communicated to nursing staff. The patient's pain will be treated with&#xD;
      multimodal nonopioid analgesic agents. Opioid medications will not be withheld for patients&#xD;
      with severe pain. On postoperative day one, the patient will be assessed for discharge as in&#xD;
      standard of care. They will be asked about their perceived need for a prescription for&#xD;
      opioids. If requested, the patient will be given a prescription for a limited quantity of&#xD;
      opioids. Nursing staff will complete specialized discharge instructions and patients will be&#xD;
      given written instructions regarding medications and activity. Patients will be seen in 7-10&#xD;
      days for stent removal in the office per standard of care, and will complete a validated&#xD;
      quality of life survey for pain after kidney stone surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 10, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Pragmatic Pilot Study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Protocol Feasibility</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year or until subject accrual is complete</time_frame>
    <description>Number of enrolled patients / patients approached</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adherence to the protocol</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Dropout of enrolled patients</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of the protocol</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Patient satisfaction via validated questionnnaire</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Day of procedure to 30 days after procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events (AEs) while inpatient and following discharge</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid free discharge</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 hours of discharge from hospital</time_frame>
    <description>Whether subject is discharged with prescription for opioids or not</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative inpatient opioid utilization</measure>
    <time_frame>24-48 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Postoperative inpatient opioid utilization (morphine mEq / kg / day)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Discharge opioid prescriptions</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of discharge, average of postoperative day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Opioid prescriptions written at time of discharge (morphine mEq / kg / day)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>USSQ symptom scoring</measure>
    <time_frame>7-10 days postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Ureteral Stent Symptom Questionnaire (USSQ) scores at postoperative visit</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Nonopioid discharge medications</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of discharge, average of postoperative day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Nonopioid medications given for pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of stay (hours)</measure>
    <time_frame>24-48 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Length of inpatient stay (hours)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinic calls</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Quantitative number of telephone calls to clinic for pain / discomfort within 30 days via documentation in EMR</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Refill requests</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Quantitative number of requests for refills of opioid prescriptions within 30 days via documentation in EMR</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ED visits</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Quantitative number of subject presentations to emergency department for pain within 30 days via documentation in EMR</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Nephrolithiasis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pre-Implementation Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cohort undergoing PCNL prior to implementation of the novel nonopioid pathway</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Implementation Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cohort undergoing PCNL with implementation of the novel nonopioid pathway</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Novel Nonopioid Pathway</intervention_name>
    <description>The novel nonopioid pathway consists of preoperative counseling, postoperative standardized orders and standard of care adjunctive and analgesic medications, specialized discharge instructions and written patient instructions regarding medications and activity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Implementation Cohort</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing primary percutaneous nephrolithotomy at a single academic hospital&#xD;
             site.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients will be excluded if currently taking opioids for chronic pain, undergoing&#xD;
             concurrent non-PCNL procedure, second-look PCNL (subsequent PCNL after primary PCNL),&#xD;
             or present with Chronic Kidney Disease Stage &gt;3 or eGFR &lt; 50 mL/min/1.73m2 at time of&#xD;
             surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with allergy to NSAIDs or have history of NSAID related GI bleeding or ulcers&#xD;
             will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Miriam Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Providence</city>
        <state>Rhode Island</state>
        <zip>02906</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The Miriam Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>David Sobel, M.D.</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Urology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Kidney Calculi</keyword>
  <keyword>Surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Nephrolithotomy, Percutaneous</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nephrolithiasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Kidney Calculi</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Analgesics, Non-Narcotic</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

