<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04598828</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00067408</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04598828</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Use of a Non-Invasive Brainstem Neuromodulation Device to Improve Neurovascular Status in Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Using Time Varying Non-Invasive Neuromodulation to Improve Neurovascular Status in Parkinson's Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Wake Forest University Health Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Wake Forest University Health Sciences</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a single-site, double-blinded, randomized clinical trial designed to elucidate&#xD;
      mechanism(s) of action for symptomatic benefits observed in Parkinson's disease (PD)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients treating twice daily using a non-invasive brainstem modulation device. Study&#xD;
      participants will self-administer treatments in the home setting over a period of 12 weeks.&#xD;
      Changes in cerebral blood flow perfusion, cerebrovascular reactivity and functional&#xD;
      connectivity between the pre-treatment baseline and the end of the treatment period will be&#xD;
      monitored and compared to changes in validated standardized clinical measures of motor and&#xD;
      non-motor symptoms in PD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 6, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cerebral blood flow (CBF) perfusion</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Arterial arrival time (AAT) measured using pseudo Continuous Arterial Spin Labeling (pCASL) magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) will be used to monitor changes in global perfusion.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cerebral blood flow (CBF) perfusion</measure>
    <time_frame>end of treatment (week 12)</time_frame>
    <description>Arterial arrival time (AAT) measured using pseudo Continuous Arterial Spin Labeling (pCASL) magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) will be used to monitor changes in global perfusion.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cerebrovascular Reactivity</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>AAT measured using pCASL MRI after a hypercapnic challenge will be used to monitor changes in cerebrovascular reactivity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cerebrovascular Reactivity</measure>
    <time_frame>end of treatment (week 12)</time_frame>
    <description>AAT measured using pCASL MRI after a hypercapnic challenge will be used to monitor changes in cerebrovascular reactivity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in functional connectivity</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and end of treatment (week 12)</time_frame>
    <description>Resting-state magnetic resonance imaging (rs-MRI) will be used to monitor changes in functional connectivity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cerebral haemodynamics</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and end of treatment (week 12)</time_frame>
    <description>Transcranial Doppler sonography (TCD), a non-invasive ultrasound, will be used to monitor changes in cerebral blood flow velocity (cm/s) in response to a hypercapnic challenge.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Durability of change of cerebral blood flow (CBF) perfusion</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and the post-treatment follow-up (week 17)</time_frame>
    <description>Arterial arrival time (AAT) measured using pseudo Continuous Arterial Spin Labeling (pCASL) magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) will be used to monitor changes in global perfusion.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Durability of change of cerebrovascular Reactivity</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and the post-treatment follow-up (week 17)</time_frame>
    <description>AAT measured using pCASL MRI after a hypercapnic challenge will be used to monitor changes in cerebrovascular reactivity</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Durability of change of functional connectivity</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and the post-treatment follow-up (week 17)</time_frame>
    <description>Resting-state magnetic resonance imaging (rs-MRI) will be used to monitor changes in functional connectivity</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the Movement Disorder Society Unified Parkinson's Disease Rating Scale (MDS-UPDRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, end of treatment (week 12), and the post-treatment follow-up (week 17)</time_frame>
    <description>Used to follow the longitudinal course of symptoms of Parkinson's disease - Each parkinsonian sign or symptom is rated on a 5-point Likert-type scale (ranging from 0 to 4), with higher scores indicating more severe impairment. The maximum total UPDRS score is 199, indicating the worst possible disability from PD</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the Timed Up and Go Test</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, end of treatment (week 12) and the post-treatment follow-up (week 17)</time_frame>
    <description>To determine fall risk and measure the progress of balance, sit to stand and walking (ranging from ≤10 seconds as normal to 30 seconds as high fall risk).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the Montreal Cognitive Assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, end of treatment (week 12) and the post-treatment follow-up (week 17)</time_frame>
    <description>Cognitive screening test - range from zero to 30, with a score of 26 and higher generally considered normal.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the Non-Motor Symptom Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Change between the baseline and end of treatment (week 12) measure.</time_frame>
    <description>Scale to assess a wide range of non-motor symptoms in patients with Parkinson's disease - 30-item rater-based scale to assess a wide range of non-motor symptoms in patients with Parkinson's disease (PD). The Non-Motor Symptom Scale measures the severity and frequency of non-motor symptoms across nine dimensions - the total score significantly increased with disease severity and duration meaning that the number of individual non-motor symptoms reported by our patients increases as the disease progresses. Score range 0 - 360.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the Non-Motor Symptom Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Change between the baseline and the post-treatment follow-up (week 17) measure.</time_frame>
    <description>Scale to assess a wide range of non-motor symptoms in patients with Parkinson's disease - 30-item rater-based scale to assess a wide range of non-motor symptoms in patients with Parkinson's disease (PD). The Non-Motor Symptom Scale measures the severity and frequency of non-motor symptoms across nine dimensions - the total score significantly increased with disease severity and duration meaning that the number of individual non-motor symptoms reported by our patients increases as the disease progresses. Score range 0 - 360.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the Geriatric Depression Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, end of treatment (week 12) and the post-treatment follow-up (week 17)</time_frame>
    <description>A self-report measure of depression in older adults - Scores of 0-4 are considered normal, depending on age, education, and complaints; 5-8 indicate mild depression; 9-11 indicate moderate depression; and 12-15 indicate severe depression.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the Parkinson's Anxiety Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, end of treatment (week 12) and the post-treatment follow-up (week 17)</time_frame>
    <description>Anxiety assessment - The PAS is a 12-item observer or patient-rated scale with three subscales, for persistent, episodic anxiety and avoidance behavior - There is a maximum total score of 48. Higher scores indicate great experiences of anxiety.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the Epworth Sleepiness Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, end of treatment (week 12) and the post-treatment follow-up (week 17)</time_frame>
    <description>A self-administered questionnaire to assess the daytime sleepiness - The ESS score (the sum of 8 item scores, 0-3) can range from 0 to 24. The higher the ESS score, the higher that person's average sleep propensity in daily life (ASP), or their 'daytime sleepiness'.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the Functional Assessment of Chronic Illness Therapy - Fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, end of treatment (week 12) and the post-treatment follow-up (week 17)</time_frame>
    <description>A tool to help manage chronic illness - The responses to the 13 items on the FACIT fatigue questionnaire are each measured on a 4-point Likert scale. Thus, the total score ranges from 0 to 52. High scores represent less fatigue</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Arterial Stiffness</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and end of treatment (week 12)</time_frame>
    <description>Arterial stiffness will be assessed as carotid-femoral pulse wave velocity (PWV). PWV is calculated by dividing the distance between the carotid and femoral arteries by the pulse transit time.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">22</enrollment>
  <condition>Parkinson Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive Experimental treatment 1 stimulation for a duration of 12 weeks, twice daily for 19 minutes</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive Experimental treatment 2 stimulation for a duration of 12 weeks, twice daily for 19 minutes</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Non-invasive brainstem stimulation</intervention_name>
    <description>Study participants will self-administer ~19-minute treatments twice daily in the home setting using a non-invasive brainstem modulation device. The device has been deemed as a nonsignificant risk for studies in Parkinson's disease by the United States Food and Drug Administration.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be 21-85 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed with Parkinson's Disease (meeting UK PD Society Brain Bank criteria)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Responsive to oral DRT (dopamine replacement therapy) and treated with oral DRTs for a&#xD;
             minimum of 3 years prior to screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants and investigators must expect that the participant will be able to remain&#xD;
             on a stable regimen of concomitant therapies used for the management of PD motor and&#xD;
             non-motor symptoms and not to introduce new medications used to treat motor or&#xD;
             non-motor symptoms associated with PD during the clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be able to voluntarily give written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be willing and able to comply with study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have ability to reliably use the investigational device&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be able to understand and complete all assessments (provided in English only)&#xD;
             within a given on-state period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be willing and able to undertake a ~1 hour imaging session in a MRI magnet with a&#xD;
             head coil in place during 3 separate clinic visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have a study partner and/or regular caregiver (defined as someone who sees the&#xD;
             participant for more than one hour a day, 3x per week) that is willing to consent and&#xD;
             participate in the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have access and capability to complete assessments using telemedicine platforms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must demonstrate moderate burden of motor symptoms and non-motor symptoms in PD (&#xD;
             MDS-UPDRS part II &gt;12 and MDS-UPDRS part I scores &gt;10)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must consent to being videotaped during motor examination visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be willing to answer questions related to sexual interest, arousal and&#xD;
             performance in an interview with study staff&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant anticipates being unable to attend all study visits and complete all study&#xD;
             activities during the clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child-bearing potential who are pregnant or plan to become pregnant during&#xD;
             the course of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Women of child-bearing potential (i.e., are not yet 3 years removed from their first&#xD;
        menopausal symptom), who are not abstinent or exclusively in same sex relationships must:&#xD;
&#xD;
        test negative for pregnancy as indicated by a negative urine pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
        agree to use an approved contraception method&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have experienced a myocardial infarction, angina or stroke within the past 12 months,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of medications that regulate heart rate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a history or prior diagnosis of dementia or adjusted score ≤ 20 on the Montreal&#xD;
             Cognitive Assessment at the baseline visit. This exclusion criterion has been set&#xD;
             specifically to improve the validity of scores assessed from the scaled questionnaires&#xD;
             rather than reflecting a concern about safety for this population.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those receiving deep brain stimulation therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treated with a pump for continuous delivery of DRT (Dopamine replacement therapy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of Apomorphine rescue&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Works night shifts&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have any significant co-morbidity or illness which in the opinion of the investigator&#xD;
             would prevent safe participation in the study, compliance with protocol requirements&#xD;
             or which presents with symptoms that are also common in PD (e.g., stroke, brain tumor,&#xD;
             epilepsy, Alzheimer's disease, multiple sclerosis, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis,&#xD;
             atypical Parkinsonism or aneurysm)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has history or evidence of unstable mood disorder or demonstrates evidence of&#xD;
             suicidality. Participants that demonstrate risk of suicide should receive a referral&#xD;
             for mental health counseling according to the mandates of the IRB or ethics review&#xD;
             committee.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with hearing aids that are implanted or cannot be easily removed and replaced&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have cochlear implants&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have chronic (&gt; 3 months) tinnitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who have previously been diagnosed with traumatic brain injury with ongoing&#xD;
             sequela&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with a recent history of substance abuse and/or dependence (alcohol or other&#xD;
             drugs)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who have a diagnosed vestibular dysfunction and/or balance dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who have had eye surgery within the previous three months or ear surgery within&#xD;
             the previous six months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with active ear infections, perforated tympanic membrane or labyrinthitis, as&#xD;
             identified by a general ear examination performed by medically qualified Investigators&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with a recent history of frequent ear infections (≥ 1 per year over the past two&#xD;
             years)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who have contraindications for MRI imaging, such as metal implants or a&#xD;
             pacemaker that would preclude the MRI scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who are currently enrolled or have participated in another interventional&#xD;
             clinical trial within the last 30 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who are taking antiemetics chronically (more than 2 times per week,&#xD;
             consistently)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have sequelae from a COVID-19 infection that includes one or more of the exclusion&#xD;
             criteria listed above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who have a planned surgery scheduled to occur during the clinical trial that&#xD;
             requires sedation and/or would typically be followed with a prescription for pain&#xD;
             management&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christopher T Whitlow, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Wake Forest University Health Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Christopher T Whitlow, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>336-713-8793</phone>
    <email>cwhitlow@wakehealth.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Richarlette C Hightower, BA</last_name>
    <phone>336-713-8793</phone>
    <email>rhightow@wakehealth.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wake Forest Health Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winston-Salem</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27157</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Richarlette C Hightower</last_name>
      <email>rhightow@wakehealth.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Christopher T Whitlow, MD, PhD, MHA</last_name>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christoper T Whitlow, MD, PhD, MHA</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>balance disorders</keyword>
  <keyword>motor functions</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual participant data (IPD) will not be available to other researchers.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

