<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04591444</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HDFOUSP</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04591444</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Fluoride Varnish X Glass Ionomer Sealant on Cervical Dentin Hypersensitivity</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of a Fluoride Varnish and a Glass Ionomer Sealant on Cervical Dentin Hypersensitivity: A Randomized Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Sao Paulo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Sao Paulo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Dentin hypersensitivity (DH) can be defined as acute, short-duration pain from open dentin&#xD;
      tubules in exposed dentin. The symptom of DH is subjective and varies from patient to patient&#xD;
      and may present as mild discomfort or as a high-intensity pain, which can affect the&#xD;
      individual's quality of life, interfering with their eating and hygiene habits. One approach&#xD;
      to treatment would be the use of agents that chemically desensitize sensory nerves, blocking&#xD;
      the transmission of nerve stimuli to the central nervous system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The effectiveness of desensitizing treatments is influenced by several factors present in the&#xD;
      oral cavity, which can contribute to a greater effect of these agents but can also be&#xD;
      responsible for removing them from the dental surface. To date, studies have been carried out&#xD;
      in the short term, not exceeding an average period of 12 weeks, so there is no consensus on&#xD;
      the technique or agent that will guarantee the most effective and lasting effect against DH,&#xD;
      not even the ideal period for reapplication. Thus, more studies are needed to assess the&#xD;
      clinical behavior of desensitizing products on the market, especially the most recent&#xD;
      releases. Therefore, the aim of this study was to clinically compare the effectiveness of&#xD;
      different office treatments for DH, being ClinproTM White Varnish, ClinproTM XT Varnish, and&#xD;
      a control group (placebo) through pain assessment with the Visual Analog Scale (VAS), after&#xD;
      stimulation with air from the triple syringe.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study compares the effectiveness of two in-office treatment for dentin hypersensitivity:&#xD;
      G1:ClinproTM White Varnish, G2:ClinproTM XT Varnish, and a G3:placebo (where the application&#xD;
      of a product was only simulated). Recruitment of the 121 volunteers were based on their&#xD;
      self-reported complaint of dentin hypersensitivity, which confirmed with the use of an air&#xD;
      blast from a triple syringe. Then, he/she showed in the VAS scale (which varies from 0=no&#xD;
      pain to 10=the worst pain possible) the value that best describes the pain sensation. The&#xD;
      subjects that present at least one tooth with a value of 4 and above in the VAS scale (if&#xD;
      more than one hypersensitive tooth was present, the mean VAS values obtained were used, for&#xD;
      each patient) was randomly allocated into the experimental groups. Two weeks before the study&#xD;
      started, the volunteers went through a wash out period, where they used only the oral hygiene&#xD;
      products donated by the researchers, which were used up to the end of the study. The&#xD;
      in-office treatments were performed after prophylaxis, according to the manufacturer´s&#xD;
      instructions, by one trained researcher, which was blind to the treatments. DH evaluation was&#xD;
      performed 15 min after the application of the treatments, by a different researcher, which&#xD;
      also blind to the treatment, and which used the same methodology described early for the&#xD;
      detection of initial pain. The volunteers were recalled for the DH evaluation after one and&#xD;
      four weeks of the treatments. DH evaluation was also performed after 12 and 24 weeks of the&#xD;
      treatments, except in the placebo group, which received the proper DH treatment after the&#xD;
      first four weeks of the study. Data was analyzed with the appropriate statistical methods&#xD;
      (α=0.05).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The present study is a parallel, randomized, triple blind clinical trial.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the dentin hypersensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The evaluation was performed with the use of Visual Analog Scale (VAS). The volunteers pointed out on the VAS (ranging from 0=no pain to 10=worst possible pain) the whole number, which best described his perception of pain at the moment.&#xD;
The primary outcome was the difference between the Visual Analog Scale values obtained in the baseline and 4 weeks after the treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dentin hypersensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 15 minutes after the treatments, 1 week and 4 weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>This secondary outcome was the Visual Analog Scale (VAS) score related to dentin hypersensitivity. The volunteers pointed out on the VAS (ranging from 0=no pain to 10=worst possible pain) the whole number, which best described his perception of pain at the moment.&#xD;
Visual Analog Scale was applied before the treatment (baseline), 15 minutes after the procedures, one week, and 4 weeks after treatments to measure the changes in dentin hypersensitivity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the dentin hypersensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The evaluation was performed with the use of Visual Analog Scale (VAS). The volunteers pointed out on the VAS (ranging from 0=no pain to 10=worst possible pain) the whole number, which best described his perception of pain at the moment.&#xD;
This secondary outcome was the difference between the Visual Analog Scale values obtained in the baseline and 3 and 6 months after the treatment (Long-term differences in the VAS values).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">121</enrollment>
  <condition>Dentin Hypersensitivity</condition>
  <condition>Dentin Sensitivity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ClinproTM White Varnish</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Application of ClinproTM White Varnish containing sodium fluoride (5%) and Tricalcium phosphate (TCP).&#xD;
A technology that allows calcium and phosphate ions to coexist with fluoride ions separately, forming a more resistant mineral on the tooth surface (3M ESPE Clinpro White Varnish; 3M ESPE Clinpro 5000).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ClinproTM XT Varnish</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Application of ClinproTM XT Varnish, a resin-modified glass ionomer sealant.&#xD;
Creates a protective layer on exposed dentin, which is durable and has the ability to release fluoride, calcium and phosphate into the surroundings. (3M ESPE Clinpro XT Varnish).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants who were part of the placebo group continuously used only the conventional toothpaste provided in the oral hygiene kit during the initial four weeks of the research and received a simulated treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fluoride Varnish</intervention_name>
    <description>Following the manufacturer's recommendations, it was not necessary to moisten or dry the treated surface beforehand or afterwards. The product was dispensed and manipulated for 15 s until a homogeneous mixture was obtained, applied with a micro brush, flowing into interproximal areas, and quickly adhering to the tooth surface in the presence of saliva.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ClinproTM White Varnish</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ClinproTM White Varnish</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Glass Ionomer Sealant</intervention_name>
    <description>Following the manufacturer's recommendations, prophylaxis and prior drying of the treated surface was carried out, the product was also dispensed and manipulated for 15 s until a homogeneous mixture was obtained, applied with a micro brush and light-cured for 20 s.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ClinproTM XT Varnish</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ClinproTM XT Varnish</other_name>
    <other_name>Resin-modified Glass Ionomer Sealant</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo Group</intervention_name>
    <description>4 weeks after the simulation of the treatment application, participants in the placebo group received DH treatment with the product that had the best effect in the first 4 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minimum age of 18 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presented good general health;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presented at least one tooth with DH reported in the cervical region, which has a&#xD;
             graded sensitivity of 4 or more on the VAS scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presented active caries lesions or with defective restorations in the tooth to be&#xD;
             analyzed;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presented enough dentin loss that required restorative treatment or periodontal&#xD;
             surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Volunteers who underwent any professional desensitizing treatment in the last 6&#xD;
             months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Volunteers who used desensitizing pastes in the 3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Volunteers who were using anti-inflammatory or analgesic drugs at the time of&#xD;
             recruitment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Volunteers were are pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Taís Scaramucci Forlin, Assistant Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of São Paulo</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>School of Dentistry, University of Sao Paulo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sao Paulo</city>
        <zip>05508-000</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 16, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 16, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Sao Paulo</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Fausto Medeiros Mendes</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Dentin hypersensitivity</keyword>
  <keyword>Dentin sensitivity</keyword>
  <keyword>Hypersensitivity</keyword>
  <keyword>Fluorides</keyword>
  <keyword>Sodium fluoride</keyword>
  <keyword>Glass ionomer sealant</keyword>
  <keyword>Desensitizing treatment</keyword>
  <keyword>Glass ionomer cement</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dentin Sensitivity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fluorides</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fluorides, Topical</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

