<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04597723</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Selcuk University Konya</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04597723</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Oxygen Given to Patients in the Postoperative Period on Nausea and Vomiting</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Oxygen Given to Patients Undergoing Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy in the Postoperative Period on Nausea and Vomiting</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Selcuk University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Scientific and Technological Research Council of Turkey</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Selcuk University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Carbon dioxide which is insufflated to inflate the abdominal area is absorbed from the&#xD;
      peritoneal area and it increases endogenous catecholamines, which may consequently increase&#xD;
      nausea and vomiting. In the literature, it is indicated that oxygen application which is one&#xD;
      of the applications aiming to prevent nausea and vomiting is a cheap method with fewer side&#xD;
      effects in the prevention of postoperative nausea and vomiting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the literature, studies on the prevention of nausea and vomiting by oxygen application in&#xD;
      different surgical interventions have not arrived at a consensus regarding surgery type and&#xD;
      oxygen amounts. There are studies evaluating 80% and 30% oxygen amounts in removing&#xD;
      postoperative nausea and vomiting. Taking these conditions into consideration; the study has&#xD;
      been planned for the purpose of examining the impact of giving 80% and 60% oxygen to patients&#xD;
      to whom laparoscopic cholecystectomy is applied on postoperative nausea and vomiting in the&#xD;
      postoperative period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study has been planned as a randomized controlled study for the purpose of determining&#xD;
      the impact of giving oxygen (80% to the group A, 60% to the group B and control group C) to&#xD;
      patients who apply to the general surgery service to undergo a laparoscopic cholecystectomy&#xD;
      on postoperative nausea and vomiting in the postoperative period. The patients in the study&#xD;
      will have the same standard anesthesia protocol and hospital routine. The study will be&#xD;
      terminated once a total of 111 patients have been reached. In the study randomization, the&#xD;
      patients will be assigned to the sample group according to weeks as they may influence each&#xD;
      other. Data will be collected using Patient Introductory Information Form, which evaluates&#xD;
      patients' socio-demographic characteristics, as well as Perioperative Period Patient&#xD;
      Follow-Up Form and Postoperative Period Nausea-Vomiting Frequency and Severity Evaluation&#xD;
      Form. Statistical analysis of the data to be acquired as a result of the study will be&#xD;
      performed in the computer environment. The results to be obtained will be evaluated at p&lt;0,05&#xD;
      significance level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is expected that the study results will provide an alternative method, which will be used&#xD;
      in preventing the possible side effects of postoperative nausea and vomiting in patients who&#xD;
      undergo a laparoscopic cholecystectomy. Thus, the study results may make scientific and&#xD;
      socio-economic contributions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Postoperative nausea and vomiting; defined as any nausea, retching or vomiting. Many studies&#xD;
      are carried out to prevent postoperative nausea and vomiting, which may be a major concern in&#xD;
      patients undergoing surgery. However, this remains the most undesirable complication of the&#xD;
      surgical procedure. While the incidence of postoperative nausea and vomiting is around 30% in&#xD;
      patients receiving general anesthesia, it can rise up to 70-80% in high risk patients.&#xD;
      Postoperative factors affecting nausea and vomiting; are grouped as factors associated with&#xD;
      the patient, surgery, and anesthesia. Factors related to the patient; age, gender, body mass&#xD;
      index, pain, anxiety, presence of a history of road traffic or previous postoperative nausea&#xD;
      and vomiting history. Surgery related factors; surgery duration and type of surgery. Factors&#xD;
      associated with anesthesia are; type and amount of anesthetic substance, ventilation type,&#xD;
      oral intake time, and the amount of opioid taken in the postoperative period. With&#xD;
      postoperative nausea and vomiting; Complications such as fluid-electrolyte imbalance, wound&#xD;
      dehiscence, hemorrhage, aspiration pneumonia, delayed discharge and increased&#xD;
      re-hospitalization rates are seen. All these complications not only increase the length of&#xD;
      hospital stay and cost of patients, but also negatively affect the postoperative recovery&#xD;
      quality of the patients. In addition, postoperative nausea and vomiting is an exhausting&#xD;
      process that requires effort for caregivers. Therefore, postoperative nausea and vomiting&#xD;
      should be prevented. Some antiemetic drugs are used to prevent nausea and vomiting, which are&#xD;
      undesirable complications. The use of these drugs significantly increases the patient's care&#xD;
      costs. Unlike drugs in the prevention of postoperative nausea and vomiting in the literature;&#xD;
      It has been observed that reducing abdominal insufflation pressure, reducing anxiety in the&#xD;
      preoperative period, acupuncture, ginger root application, alcohol sniffing, listening to&#xD;
      music and extra oxygen therapy practices. Oxygen administration, which is one of the&#xD;
      applications to prevent nausea and vomiting, is stated as an inexpensive method with low side&#xD;
      effects in preventing postoperative nausea and vomiting. One of these methods is an&#xD;
      irreversible mask. 60% with 6lt / min oxygen application with non-recyclable mask; 80% oxygen&#xD;
      can be given from 8 lt / min. There are studies In the literature regarding the prevention of&#xD;
      nausea and vomiting by oxygen administration. in a study they conducted on patients who&#xD;
      underwent colon resection; They found that administration of 80% oxygen during anesthesia and&#xD;
      for two hours after anesthesia reduced the postoperative nausea and vomiting rate from 30% to&#xD;
      17%. In the study conducted on gynecological patients who underwent laparoscopy, it was found&#xD;
      that the rates of nausea and vomiting in patients who were given 80% oxygen were&#xD;
      statistically significantly lower than those who were given 30% oxygen. Found that the rate&#xD;
      of nausea and vomiting decreased from 28.3% to 24.5% in the group where they gave oxygen at 8&#xD;
      lt / min with a simple face mask for 6 hours in the postoperative period after cesarean&#xD;
      delivery, but it was not statistically significant. . Laparoscopic cholecystectomy is the&#xD;
      removal of the gallbladder from three or four small holes in cases where polyps and stones&#xD;
      are problematic in the gallbladder. One of the symptoms that patients frequently complain&#xD;
      after laparoscopic cholecystectomy is nausea and vomiting. In laparoscopic interventions&#xD;
      applied in abdominal surgeries, the abdominal area is inflated so that the surgery can be&#xD;
      performed comfortably, thus increasing abdominal pressure. The diaphragm is pushed up due to&#xD;
      the increase in abdominal pressure. This situation causes the diaphragm to be more irritated.&#xD;
      In addition, carbon dioxide insufflated to inflate the abdominal area is absorbed from the&#xD;
      peritoneal area and increases endogenous catecholamines. In this case, nausea and vomiting&#xD;
      may increase.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Postoperative nausea and vomiting, which prolongs the postoperative recovery period, are&#xD;
      often seen in patients within the first 24 hours. Therefore, minimizing nausea and vomiting&#xD;
      after laparoscopic cholecystectomy is important for the patient. In the literature, no study&#xD;
      on oxygen administration has been found in studies conducted to relieve nausea and vomiting&#xD;
      after laparoscopic cholecystectomy. In the studies conducted in the literature regarding the&#xD;
      prevention of nausea and vomiting by oxygen administration in different surgical procedures,&#xD;
      a consensus could not be reached on the type of surgery and the amount of oxygen. In&#xD;
      addition, there are studies evaluating 80% and 30% oxygen content in relieving postoperative&#xD;
      nausea and vomiting.Considering these situations, this research; It was planned to examine&#xD;
      the effects of 80%, 60% and air oxygen on postoperative nausea and vomiting in patients who&#xD;
      underwent laparoscopic cholecystectomy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 3, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 3, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 3, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>severity of nausea</measure>
    <time_frame>0-24 hours in the postoperative period</time_frame>
    <description>severity of nausea was measured using a 10-cm visual analog scale, The patients were explained that 1 point indicated &quot;no nausea&quot; and 10 points indicated &quot;severe nausea,&quot; and then they were asked to give 1-10 points for their severity of nausea.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>severity of vomiting</measure>
    <time_frame>0-24 hours in the postoperative period</time_frame>
    <description>severity of vomiting was measured using a 10-cm visual analog scale, The patients were explained that 1 point indicated &quot;no vomiting&quot; and 10 points indicated &quot;severe vomiting,&quot; and then they were asked to give 1-10 points for their severity of vomiting</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">111</enrollment>
  <condition>Oxygen</condition>
  <condition>Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>80% oxygen</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>80% oxygen given group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>60% oxygen</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>60% oxygen given group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>routine hospital care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The patients in this group received routine hospital care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>oxygen</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will be given different concentrations of oxygen.</description>
    <arm_group_label>60% oxygen</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>80% oxygen</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Surgery time is 2 hours or less&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient does not have peripheral vascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient does not have a psychiatric disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient can communicate verbally&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient is not using anticoagulant drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient's hemoglobin level in the preoperative period is in the range of 12-16 g /&#xD;
             dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient's American Society of Anesthesiologist (ASA) value is between 1-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient is not smoking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient is between 18 and 65 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the intraoperative period, the carbon dioxide gas pressure used to inflate the&#xD;
             abdomen is between 10-12.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient's willingness to participate in the research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient does not have respiratory diseases (such as bronchitis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient does not have claustrophobia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        - The patient is using anticoagulant medication&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hulya Bulut</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Gazi University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sevil Guler Demir</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Gazi University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Faruk Cicekci</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Selcuk University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hulagu Barıskaner</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Selcuk University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mustafa Sahin</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Selcuk University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Inci Kara</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Selcuk University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Pınar t tuna</last_name>
    <phone>05069549225</phone>
    <email>pinartunctuna@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pınar tunç tuna</name>
      <address>
        <city>Konya</city>
        <zip>42500</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pınar t tuna</last_name>
      <phone>05069549225</phone>
      <email>pinartunctuna@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 15, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 21, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 21, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Selcuk University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Tunc Tuna Pinar, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>postoperative nausea and vomiting</keyword>
  <keyword>Oxygen</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nausea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

