<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05037500</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>I 1373721</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2021-08860</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>I 1373721</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05037500</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Decitabine/Cedazuridine and Enzalutamide for the Treatment of Metastatic Castrate Resistant Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1b Clinical Trial: Improving Outcomes With Androgen Pathway Inhibitors by Targeting DNA Methyltransferase Activity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Roswell Park Cancer Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Comprehensive Cancer Network</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Roswell Park Cancer Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase Ib trial is to find out the best dose decitabine/cedazuridine and possible&#xD;
      benefits and/or side effects of decitabine/cedazuridine and enzalutamide in treating patients&#xD;
      with castrate resistant prostate cancer that has spread to other places in the body&#xD;
      (metastatic). Chemotherapy drugs, such as decitabine/cedazuridine, work in different ways to&#xD;
      stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells, by stopping them from dividing,&#xD;
      or by stopping them from spreading. Enzalutamide blocks the use of androgen by the tumor&#xD;
      cells. Giving decitabine/cedazuridine together with enzalutamide may reverse or help prevent&#xD;
      the acquired therapeutic resistance that is observed when enzalutamide is used alone. Drug&#xD;
      resistance occurs when cancer cells stop responding to a chemotherapy that had previously&#xD;
      been effective.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine the safety of oral decitabine and cedazuridine (decitabine/cedazuridine) in&#xD;
      combination with enzalutamide in patients with metastatic castrate resistant prostate cancer&#xD;
      (mCRPC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and recommended phase II dose (RP2D) of oral&#xD;
      decitabine/cedazuridine in combination with enzalutamide in patients with metastatic castrate&#xD;
      resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine the relationship between decitabine/cedazuridine dose and plasma biomarkers&#xD;
      such as HbF and LINE-1 methylation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. Analyze circulating tumor deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) by whole exome sequencing and DNA&#xD;
      methylation analysis to monitor effects of treatment and emergence of ARlow CRPC/NEPC. III.&#xD;
      Measure for achievement of the intended molecular PD-effects of DNMT1-depletion, i.e., LINE-1&#xD;
      demethylation in tumor tissue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. Assess effects of treatment on tumor cell DNA methylation using Infinium Methylation EPIC&#xD;
      Arrays where suitable tissue is accessible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      V. To evaluate drug exposure to decitabine/cedazuridine by pharmacokinetic sampling on day 3,&#xD;
      day 4, or day 5 (Cohorts -1, 1, 2) of cycle 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study of decitabine and cedazuridine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive decitabine and cedazuridine orally (PO) once daily (QD) on either days 1-3,&#xD;
      1-4, or 1-5 and enzalutamide PO QD on days 1-28. Treatments repeat every 28 days for up to 6&#xD;
      cycles in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 30 days, then every 3 months&#xD;
      for 24 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 15, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 15, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Assesses using the National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 5.0.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose (MTD)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to cycle 1 (1 cycle = 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>The MTD will be defined as the dose level at which at least 1 out of 3 or &gt;= 2 out of 6 patients within the same cohort experience dose-limiting toxicity (DLT). DLTs will be defined as an AE or clinically significant abnormal laboratory value assessed as unrelated to disease, disease progression, inter-current illness, or concomitant medications that occurs within the first 28 days of treatment with decitabine in cycle 1. These will be assessed using the NCI CTCAE version 5.0.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">19</enrollment>
  <condition>Castration-Resistant Prostate Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVA Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVB Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (decitabine and cedazuridine, enzalutamide)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive decitabine and cedazuridine PO QD on either days 1-3, 1-4, or 1-5 and enzalutamide PO QD on days 1-28. Treatments repeat every 28 days for up to 6 cycles in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Decitabine and Cedazuridine</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (decitabine and cedazuridine, enzalutamide)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ASTX727</other_name>
    <other_name>C-DEC</other_name>
    <other_name>CDA Inhibitor E7727/Decitabine Combination Agent ASTX727</other_name>
    <other_name>Cedazuridine/Decitabine Combination Agent ASTX727</other_name>
    <other_name>Cedazuridine/Decitabine Tablet</other_name>
    <other_name>DEC-C</other_name>
    <other_name>Inqovi</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Enzalutamide</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (decitabine and cedazuridine, enzalutamide)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ASP9785</other_name>
    <other_name>MDV3100</other_name>
    <other_name>Xtandi</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male &gt;= 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histological or cytological documentation of diagnosis of prostate cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented progressive metastatic castrate resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC) based on&#xD;
             at least one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prostate specific antigen (PSA) progression defined as 25% increase over baseline&#xD;
                  value with an increase in the absolute value of at least 2 ng/mL that is&#xD;
                  confirmed by another PSA level with a minimum of a 1week interval and a minimum&#xD;
                  PSA of 2 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Soft-tissue progression defined as an increase &gt;= 20% in the sum of the longest&#xD;
                  diameter (LD) of all target lesions based on the smallest sum LD since treatment&#xD;
                  started or the appearance of one or more new lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Progression of bone disease (evaluable disease) or (new bone lesion[s]) by bone&#xD;
                  scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to undergo a biopsy, if readily available biopsy site present, i.e., nodal or&#xD;
             visceral metastasis (if adequate formalin-fixed paraffin-embedded (FFPE) archival&#xD;
             mCRPC samples are not available (or biopsy was taken longer than 6 months from start&#xD;
             of study treatment), a fresh pre-treatment mCRPC biopsy needs to be obtained)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0-1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have testosterone &lt; 50 ng/dL. Note: Patients must continue primary androgen&#xD;
             deprivation with an luteinising hormone-releasing factor (LHRH) analogue (agonist or&#xD;
             antagonist) if they have not undergone orchiectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  White blood cells &gt;= 1.5 x 10^9/L (obtained within 14 days prior to treatment start)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &gt;= 100 x 10^9/L (obtained within 14 days prior to treatment start)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin (HGB) &gt;= 9 g/dL (obtained within 14 days prior to treatment start)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine clearance &gt; 50 mL/min (obtained within 14 days prior to treatment start)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) =&lt; 2.5 x upper&#xD;
             limit of normal (ULN (obtained within 14 days prior to treatment start). If the&#xD;
             patient has liver metastases, ALT and AST must still be =&lt; 2.5 x ULN. Patients with&#xD;
             liver metastases and AST/ALT above this limit will not be enrolled&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x ULN; or total bilirubin (TBILI) =&lt; 3.0 x ULN with direct&#xD;
             bilirubin within normal range in patients with well documented Gilbert's Syndrome&#xD;
             (obtained within 14 days prior to treatment start)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to swallow and retain oral medication (without crushing, dissolving, or&#xD;
             chewing tablets)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Initial dose escalation/de-escalation: Prior enzalutamide treatment and/or other&#xD;
             approved treatments for CRPC for the dose finding phase (determination of MTD) of the&#xD;
             study is allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expansion cohort: Once the MTD has been determined from the dose&#xD;
             escalation/de-escalation portion of the study, patient eligibility for the expansion&#xD;
             cohort will be genomically driven and will be restricted to metastatic CRPC patients&#xD;
             with detectable genomic alterations in RB1 and/or TP53&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexually active males must agree to use a condom during intercourse while taking the&#xD;
             study drug and for at least 3 months after stopping study treatment. Sexually active&#xD;
             males should not father a child during this period. A condom is required to be used by&#xD;
             vasectomized men in order to prevent delivery of the drug via seminal fluid. Should a&#xD;
             woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while her partner is participating in&#xD;
             this study, she should inform her treating physician immediately&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must understand the investigational nature of this study and sign an&#xD;
             Independent Ethics Committee/Institutional Review Board approved written informed&#xD;
             consent form prior to receiving any study related procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  NOTE: For blood chemistry labs, Roswell Park clinical blood chemistries are performed&#xD;
             on plasma unless otherwise indicated&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a concurrent malignancy or malignancy within 3 years of treatment&#xD;
             start, with the exception of adequately treated, basal or squamous cell carcinoma or&#xD;
             non-melanomatous skin cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection&#xD;
             (testing not mandatory)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has clinically significant, uncontrolled heart disease and/or recent&#xD;
             events including any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of acute coronary syndromes (including myocardial infarction, unstable&#xD;
                  angina, coronary artery bypass grafting, coronary angioplasty, or stenting) or&#xD;
                  symptomatic pericarditis within 12 months prior to treatment start&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of documented congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association&#xD;
                  functional classification III-IV)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  On screening electrocardiogram (EKG), any of the following cardiac parameters:&#xD;
                  bradycardia (heart rate &lt; 50 at rest), tachycardia (heart rate &gt; 90 at rest), PR&#xD;
                  interval &gt; 220 msec, QRS interval &gt; 109 msec or, corrected QT interval by&#xD;
                  Fredericia (QTcF) &gt; 450 msec. Congenital long QT syndrome or family history of&#xD;
                  long QT syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is currently receiving any of the following medications and cannot be&#xD;
             discontinued 7 days prior to treatment start:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Known strong inducers or inhibitors of CYP3A4/5, including grapefruit, grapefruit&#xD;
                  hybrids and pummelos, star-fruit and, Seville oranges&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Medications that have a known risk to prolong the QT interval or induce Torsades&#xD;
                  de Pointes&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Herbal preparations/medications, dietary supplements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who has received radiotherapy =&lt; 4 weeks prior to start of treatment or&#xD;
             limited field radiation for palliation =&lt; 2 weeks prior to treatment start and, who&#xD;
             has not recovered to grade 1 or better from related side effects of such therapy&#xD;
             (exceptions include alopecia) and/or in whom &gt;= 30% of the bone marrow was irradiated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with central nervous system (CNS) involvement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with seizure disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has not recovered from all toxicities related to prior anticancer therapies to&#xD;
             National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE)&#xD;
             version 5.0 grade &lt;1 (Exception to this criterion: patients with any grade of alopecia&#xD;
             are allowed to enter the study)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling or unable to follow protocol requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has any other concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled medical condition that&#xD;
             would cause, in the investigator's judgment, an unacceptable safety risk&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition which in the Investigator's opinion deems the participant an unsuitable&#xD;
             candidate to receive study drug&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gurkamal S Chatta</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Roswell Park Cancer Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Roswell Park Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Buffalo</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>14263</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gurkamal S. Chatta</last_name>
      <phone>716-845-3117</phone>
      <email>Gurkamal.Chatta@roswellpark.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gurkamal S. Chatta</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 31, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Decitabine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

