<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05031364</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AR200108</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05031364</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>CBT for Youth With Autism and Emotional/Behavioral Needs in Community Care Settings</brief_title>
  <acronym>CYAN</acronym>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of Evidence-Based Mental Health Practices for Youth With Autism Supported by Online Consultation to Practitioners in Community and Navy Clinics</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, Los Angeles</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Virginia Commonwealth University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United States Naval Medical Center, San Diego</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Westside Regional Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Los Angeles</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a 4-year randomized, controlled trial comparing cognitive behavioral therapy&#xD;
      (CBT) to usual clinical care for children (aged 6-14 years) with autism and emotional&#xD;
      dysregulation (e.g., irritability, anxiety). We will randomly assign 50 mental health&#xD;
      clinicians, each treating 2 youth (N = 100 youth total), to CBT program for emotional&#xD;
      dysregulation and core autism symptoms with weekly live consultation with an expert or to&#xD;
      usual clinical care augmented by self-instruction in CBT, in a 1:1 allocation. The CBT manual&#xD;
      is well-supported in our efficacy research, has been replicated in other centers, is&#xD;
      free/open-access (meya.ucla.edu), and has user-friendly digital and traditional print&#xD;
      materials for mental health clinicians (e.g., psychologists, counselors) to use in preparing&#xD;
      for and conducting therapy sessions. The primary outcome measure will be assessed monthly.&#xD;
      Additional assessments will occur at Screening, Mid-treatment, Post- treatment and 3-month&#xD;
      Follow-up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Treatment condition and timepoint will be masked for the outcomes assessors (independent evaluators [IEs]), who will administer the interview-based measures.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Aberrant Behavior Checklist-2 Irritability Subscale (ABC-2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week 0), Session 4 (approximately week 4), Session 8 (approx. week 8), Session 12 (approx. week 12), Immediate Post-Treatment [approx. week 16], and Follow-up (approx. week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>The ABC-2 Irritability Subscale (Aman et al., 1985) is the primary outcome measure for this study, with pretreatment scores of 18 being required for study eligibility. Parents rate the ABC-2 on a 0 to 3 Likert-type scale. Psychometric research on the ABC Irritability Subscale has illustrated its generality to a broad spectrum of emotion dysregulation in youth with ASD, with moderate to high correlations with measures of externalizing symptoms, internalizing symptoms, and total symptoms on broad child behavior symptom inventories (e.g., Kaat et al., 2014; Wheeler et al., 2013). The ABC-2 Irritability subscale is sensitive to treatment effects and it is commonly viewed as the gold standard in the dynamic assessment of emotion dysregulation in RCTs for youth with ASD (Fung et al., 2016). The Irritability Subscale is composed of 15 items, with a scale range of 0 to 45.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Pediatric Anxiety Rating Scale (PARS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week 0), Session 8 (approximately week 8), Immediate Post-Treatment [approx. week 16], and Follow-up (approx. week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>The PARS (RUPP, 2002) is an independent evaluator (IE)-rated scale assessing anxiety symptoms and associated severity and impairment in youth over the past week. The PARS Symptom Checklist consists of 50 items assessing 6 categories of anxiety symptoms, with severity scores &gt; 14 consistent with clinically significant levels of anxiety in youth with and without ASD. Our data (Storch et al., 2012) in youth with ASD and anxiety suggest excellent psychometric properties. The PARS will be conducted over the phone by the IE with the primary parent participating in the study, with administration time of about 20 minutes. The PARS is a gold-standard assessment measure of anxiety in youth with ASD for clinical trials research (LeCavalier et al., 2015).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Social Responsiveness Scale II (SRS-II)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week 0), Session 8 (approximately week 8), Immediate Post-Treatment [approx. week 16], and Follow-up (approx. week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>The SRS-II (Constantino &amp; Gruber, 2012) is a 65-item parent-rated scale measuring the severity of ASD symptoms. The SRS-II has high internal consistency, convergence with other measures of ASD severity, and discriminates between youth with and without ASD (Schanding et al., 2011). It has shown treatment sensitivity in all extant clinical trials of BIACA including the replications by Storch and colleagues; versus treatment-as-usual; and versus standard-of-practice CBT (e.g., Storch et al., 2013, 2015; Wood et al., 2009b, 2015a, 2020).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Consumer Satisfaction Parent Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediate Post-Treatment [approximately week 16]</time_frame>
    <description>Parent satisfaction with treatment will be assessed with an 11-item parent-report measure.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Therapy Procedures Checklist (TPC)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediate Post-Treatment [approximately week 16]</time_frame>
    <description>The TPC (Weersing et al., 2002) is a 62-item self-report measure used to assess practitioners' use of treatment techniques that correspond to cognitive, behavioral, psychodynamic, or family orientations. Techniques in each orientation are summed to create total scores, with high scores reflecting extensive use of techniques consistent with that orientation. The TPC has excellent internal consistency and test-retest reliability (Baumann et al., 2006; Weersing et al., 2002).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in BIACA Fidelity Scales</measure>
    <time_frame>Sessions 3 [approximately week 3], 7 [approx. week 7], 11 [approx. week 11], and 15 [approx. week 15]</time_frame>
    <description>These scales measure both the adherence and competence of clinician delivery of key components of BIACA. Adherence refers to the extent to which the clinician delivers the treatment as designed, while competence refers to the level of skill and responsiveness demonstrated by the clinician when delivering the strategies. Each component captures a unique aspect of treatment integrity (Sutherland et al., 2013). Beginning in session 3, and then every 4 sessions thereafter, clinicians in both treatment arms will record their treatment session with the child and family. These recordings will be rated by trained IEs.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in BIACA Therapist Quiz</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline [week 0] and Immediate Post-Treatment [approximately week 16]</time_frame>
    <description>The BIACA Therapist Quiz assesses clinicians' knowledge of BIACA concepts and clinical scenarios. This measure will be administered to clinicians at pretreatment and posttreatment to assess development of CBT knowledge through the process of training and consultation in BIACA.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Mixed-methods feedback on training and consultation in BIACA</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediate Post-Treatment [approximately week 16]</time_frame>
    <description>Acceptability and feasibility of training/consultation in BIACA will be assessed quantitatively using the Evidence-Based Practice Attitude Scale (Aarons, 2004) and the Usage Rating Profile-Intervention (Chafouleas et al., 2011). We will review answers on the measures and use them to guide approximately 20-minute semi-structured interviews with the mental health clinician at the end of the acute treatment for clinicians in the BIACA arm. In addition, the following areas will be queried in these interviews: the quality and strengths/weaknesses of the online training and consultation interface (e.g., length and content of training and session materials and videochat consultations), system efficiency (how much time was put into the weekly session preparation and was this viewed as too much or acceptable), and clinical strategies as applied to their clients. Recorded interview responses will be transcribed.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Autism</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Consultation-Based Training on BIACA</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Community mental health clinicians will be given online one-on-one training and consultation in the BIACA (Behavioral Interventions for Anxiety in Children with Autism; e.g., Wood et al., 2020) CBT program. Clinicians will be provided with weekly 30-minute video-conference-based consultation sessions with an expert in BIACA. These consultation sessions are manual-driven and utilize a Practice-Based Coaching format, in which a trained consultant meets weekly with clinicians to provide practice-based feedback (cf. McLeod et al., 2018). Consultation meetings include agenda setting, case material review, planning for the next treatment session, and a meeting summary. Relevant online training materials (e.g., demonstration videos of CBT sessions; corresponding written session materials) developed in the context of a NIMH R34 grant available on meya.ucla.edu (1R34MH110591) will also be provided to clinicians for each upcoming therapy session.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care Augmented by Self-Instruction Resources for CBT for Autism</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Community mental health clinicians in this arm will provide any therapy, counseling, and/or behavioral treatment procedures they deem appropriate for each participating child. Clinicians randomized to this arm will be given immediate access to CBT-for-autism self-instruction materials that are already freely available to any clinician at meya.ucla.edu (see Consultation-Based Training on BIACA arm, above), to supplement their usual clinical care, if they so choose, until they complete their Usual Care/Self-Instruction participation and are offered direct training and weekly consultation in BIACA.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Behavioral Interventions for Anxiety in Children with Autism (BIACA)</intervention_name>
    <description>In the BIACA CBT program (e.g., Wood et al., 2020), clinicians work with families for 16 weekly sessions that include both the child and parent(s). In BIACA, anxiety, rigidity and inflexible routines, and irritability are all addressed using in vivo exposure therapy strategies during sessions as well as parent (and teacher) training to promote regulation across settings. ASD-related clinical needs that can impact mental health and emotion regulation such as friendship skills and social entry skills (e.g., joining games at school) are addressed with modeling, self-management, and parent- (or teacher-) implemented social coaching in daily settings. For youth with limited communication, therapy is adapted through the use of play-based representations of challenging situations and an emphasis on more action-oriented exposure therapy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Consultation-Based Training on BIACA</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Treatment-as-Usual Supplemented by Internet-Based Self-Instruction (MEYA)</intervention_name>
    <description>Participating clinicians are expected to have varied training in numerous psychological therapy procedures (e.g., insight-oriented procedures, cognitive interventions, family therapy, etc.), any or all of which they may choose to implement with a participating child. These practices will be characterized through the Therapy Procedures Checklist (Weersing et al., 2002). Additionally, participating clinicians will be provided with information about self-instruction resources on CBT for children with autism, namely, the Modular Evidence-Based Practices for Youth with Autism (MEYA) website developed by our research group. MEYA is freely accessible to clinicians worldwide at meya.ucla.edu. MEYA incorporates treatment elements of both BIACA (Wood et al., 2020) and SEBASTIEN (Wood et al., 2021), which was designed to address additional autism-related clinical needs (e.g., reciprocal conversation). Clinicians in this arm will provide up to 16 therapy sessions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care Augmented by Self-Instruction Resources for CBT for Autism</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For mental health clinician participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Clinicians will regularly treat at least some youth with ASD within a recognized field&#xD;
        of practice (e.g., clinical psychology, counseling, marital and family therapy, social&#xD;
        work) and will serve youth with ASD referred by participating agencies.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For children/youth:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Youth is referred by a participating agency, including a contract with the treating&#xD;
             clinician to receive payment for the treatment by the agency or its proxy (i.e., not&#xD;
             as a private practice referral).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Youth will have a pre-existing clinical diagnosis of ASD made by an appropriate&#xD;
             licensed professional (e.g., clinical psychologist, developmental pediatrician).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The parent-reported Social Responsive Scale-2 (SRS-2; Constantino &amp; Gruber, 2012)&#xD;
             Total T-Score will be &gt; 60.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Youth will meet criteria for clinically significant emotion dysregulation symptoms as&#xD;
             defined by a minimum score of 18 on the Aberrant Behavior Checklist-2 Irritability&#xD;
             subscale (this is a standard entry criterion for many ASD clinical trials; Fung et&#xD;
             al., 2016).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Youth has a Vineland Adaptive Behavior Scales-3 Communication Composite Standard Score&#xD;
             &gt; 60.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. For participants presenting with severe comorbid symptomology (e.g., psychotic&#xD;
        symptoms), the comorbid conditions cannot be sufficiently severe to warrant immediate&#xD;
        treatment or require ongoing medication titration.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>14 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wood</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Wood</last_name>
    <phone>310-882-0537</phone>
    <email>meya@gseis.ucla.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Westside Regional Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Culver City</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90024</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Wood</last_name>
      <phone>310-882-0537</phone>
      <email>meya@gseis.ucla.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Naval Medical Center San Diego</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Wood</last_name>
      <phone>310-882-0537</phone>
      <email>meya@gseis.ucla.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://meya.ucla.edu</url>
    <description>Online repository of CBT practices used in the training/consultation protocol.</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wood JJ, Kendall PC, Wood KS, Kerns CM, Seltzer M, Small BJ, Lewin AB, Storch EA. Cognitive Behavioral Treatments for Anxiety in Children With Autism Spectrum Disorder: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Psychiatry. 2020 May 1;77(5):474-483. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2019.4160.</citation>
    <PMID>31755906</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wood JJ, Ehrenreich-May J, Alessandri M, Fujii C, Renno P, Laugeson E, Piacentini JC, De Nadai AS, Arnold E, Lewin AB, Murphy TK, Storch EA. Cognitive behavioral therapy for early adolescents with autism spectrum disorders and clinical anxiety: a randomized, controlled trial. Behav Ther. 2015 Jan;46(1):7-19. doi: 10.1016/j.beth.2014.01.002. Epub 2014 Jan 22.</citation>
    <PMID>25526831</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wood JJ, McLeod BD, Klebanoff S, Brookman-Frazee L. Toward the implementation of evidence-based interventions for youth with autism spectrum disorders in schools and community agencies. Behav Ther. 2015 Jan;46(1):83-95. doi: 10.1016/j.beth.2014.07.003. Epub 2014 Jul 30. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25526837</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lecavalier L, Wood JJ, Halladay AK, Jones NE, Aman MG, Cook EH, Handen BL, King BH, Pearson DA, Hallett V, Sullivan KA, Grondhuis S, Bishop SL, Horrigan JP, Dawson G, Scahill L. Measuring anxiety as a treatment endpoint in youth with autism spectrum disorder. J Autism Dev Disord. 2014 May;44(5):1128-43. doi: 10.1007/s10803-013-1974-9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24158679</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, Los Angeles</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jeffrey J. Wood</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>To comply with the Policy, we propose to make de-identified data, codebooks, documentation, and research protocols available under the auspices of the National Database for Autism Research (NDAR) (for data) and the PI's UCLA website (for codebooks, documentation, etc.).</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Datasets associated with manuscripts that are published during or following the grant period will be available once each manuscript is made available by the publisher. The final data set will be made available from Dr. Wood within 3 years after the end of all data collection activities. All datasets will be stored and made available for a minimum of 10 years or longer, depending on the extant NDAR policies.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>NDAR sets a universal policy for accessing its datasets. Other information (e.g., study protocol) will be freely available on the PI's website.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

