<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05039801</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-0265</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2021-09063</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2021-0265</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>national cancer institute</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05039801</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>IACS-6274 With or Without Pembrolizumab for the Treatment of Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1 Open-Label, Dose-Escalation and Dose-Expansion Study to Investigate the Safety, Pharmacokinetics, Pharmacodynamics and Anti-Tumor Activity of IACS-6274 as Monotherapy and in Combination in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I trial tests the safety, side effects, and best dose of IACS-6274 with or without&#xD;
      pembrolizumab in treating patients with solid tumors that have spread to other places in the&#xD;
      body (advanced). IACS-6274 may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes&#xD;
      needed for cell growth. Immunotherapy with monoclonal antibodies, such as pembrolizumab, may&#xD;
      help the body's immune system attack the cancer, and may interfere with the ability of tumor&#xD;
      cells to grow and spread. Giving IACS-6274 with or without pembrolizumab may help to control&#xD;
      the disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To assess the safety and tolerability of oral glutaminase inhibitor IPN60090 (IACS-6274)&#xD;
      as monotherapy (Part A) and in combination therapy with pembrolizumab (Part B).&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and the recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) of&#xD;
      IACS-6274 in combination therapy with pembrolizumab (Part B). (For Dose Escalation Only)&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To assess the preliminary antitumor activity of IACS-6274 as monotherapy (Part A) and in&#xD;
      combination with pembrolizumab (Part B) in patients with or without biomarker selected tumor&#xD;
      types.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To characterize the pharmacokinetics (PK) and pharmacodynamic (PD) profile of IACS-6274&#xD;
      as a monotherapy (Part A) and in combination with pembrolizumab (Part B).&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To evaluate biomarkers of patient stratification and correlate them with clinical&#xD;
      outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To collect biobank samples for potential future analysis of biomarkers (optional, informed&#xD;
      consent required).&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study of IACS-6274 followed by a dose-expansion study.&#xD;
      Patients are assigned to 1 of 2 parts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PART A: Patients receive IACS-6274 orally (PO) twice daily (BID) on days 1-21. Cycles repeat&#xD;
      every 21 days for 2 years in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PART B: Patients receive IACS-6274 PO BID on days 1-21 and pembrolizumab intravenously (IV)&#xD;
      over 30 minutes on day 1. Cycles repeat every 21 days for 2 years in the absence of disease&#xD;
      progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 30 days. Part B patients are&#xD;
      also followed up at 60 and 90 days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 9, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 29, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 29, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Will be assessed by the rate of dose limiting toxicities at each dose level in the dose escalation, and the rate of AEs and the rate of Grade 3 and higher AEs in the dose escalation and dose expansion. All AEs will be coded according to the latest version of Medical Dictionary for Regulatory Activities and National Cancer Institute-Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events version 5.0.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Endometrial Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Advanced Head and Neck Squamous Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Advanced Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Advanced Melanoma</condition>
  <condition>Advanced Ovarian Clear Cell Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Chondrosarcoma</condition>
  <condition>Clinical Stage III Cutaneous Melanoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Clinical Stage IV Cutaneous Melanoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage III Cutaneous Melanoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IIIA Cutaneous Melanoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IIIB Cutaneous Melanoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IIIC Cutaneous Melanoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IIID Cutaneous Melanoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Pathologic Stage IV Cutaneous Melanoma AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Endometrial Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Head and Neck Squamous Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory High Grade Ovarian Serous Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Melanoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Ovarian Clear Cell Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage III Ovarian Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage III Uterine Corpus Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA Ovarian Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA Uterine Corpus Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA1 Ovarian Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA2 Ovarian Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIB Ovarian Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIB Uterine Corpus Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIC Ovarian Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIC Uterine Corpus Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIC1 Uterine Corpus Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIC2 Uterine Corpus Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Ovarian Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Uterine Corpus Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVA Ovarian Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVA Uterine Corpus Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVB Ovarian Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVB Uterine Corpus Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part A (IACS-6274)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive IACS-6274 PO BID on days 1-21. Cycles repeat every 21 days for 2 years in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part B (IACS-6274, pembrolizumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive IACS-6274 PO BID on days 1-21 and pembrolizumab IV over 30 minutes on day 1. Cycles repeat every 21 days for 2 years in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Glutaminase Inhibitor IPN60090</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part A (IACS-6274)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part B (IACS-6274, pembrolizumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>IPN 60090</other_name>
    <other_name>IPN-60090</other_name>
    <other_name>IPN60090</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part B (IACS-6274, pembrolizumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Keytruda</other_name>
    <other_name>Lambrolizumab</other_name>
    <other_name>MK-3475</other_name>
    <other_name>SCH 900475</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provision of written informed consent prior to any study related procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients &gt;= 18 years of age at the time of study entry who agree to participate by&#xD;
             giving written informed consent prior to participation in any study related activities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically or cytologically confirmed advanced solid tumors, specifically,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Dose Escalation and Dose Expansion may include:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Patients with tumors with actionable KEAP1/NFE2L2/STK11/NF1 mutations&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Patients with low ASNS expression levels (high-grade serous ovarian&#xD;
                       carcinoma [HGSOC] or endometrial cancer)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Post-immunotherapy (IO) melanoma (minimum treatment duration of prior PD-1&#xD;
                       or PD-L1-containing regimen is 12 weeks [or equivalent of 2 response&#xD;
                       evaluations])&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Dose Escalation may also include:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Patients with post-platinum HNSCC&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Patients with chondrosarcoma&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Patients with ARID1A mutant clear cell ovarian cancer Note: all biomarker&#xD;
                       mutations/expression levels must be confirmed prior to study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have received at least one line of therapy for advanced stage disease&#xD;
             and be refractory or ineligible to available existing therapy(ies) known to provide&#xD;
             clinical benefit for their condition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with chemotherapy, radiotherapy, immunotherapy or any investigational&#xD;
             therapies must have been completed at least 3 weeks or at least five half-lives,&#xD;
             whichever is shorter, before the study drug administration, and all adverse events&#xD;
             (AEs) (excluding alopecia and peripheral neuropathy) have either returned to =&lt; grade&#xD;
             1 or stabilized&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fresh and/or archival tumor tissue from the biopsy obtained between the completion of&#xD;
             the most recent line of treatment until study entry must be available for mutation and&#xD;
             biomarker analysis. Patients should not be put at undue risk to obtain fresh tumor&#xD;
             biopsy. If available, archival tumor tissue from time of initial diagnosis will be&#xD;
             collected in addition to the most recent biopsy (archival and/or fresh)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable or non-measurable evaluable disease as defined per the Response Evaluation&#xD;
             Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version (v)1.1 (or immune-related RECIST [iRECIST]&#xD;
             for Part B only)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status =&lt; 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1500/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &gt;= 100,000/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine =&lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) and/or creatinine clearance &gt; 40&#xD;
             mL/min. Actual body weight should be used for calculating creatinine clearance using&#xD;
             the Cockroft-Gault equation (except for patients with body mass index &gt; 30 kg/m^2 when&#xD;
             the lean body weight should be used)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x ULN (with the exception of patients with known&#xD;
             Gilbert's syndrome: serum total bilirubin must be &lt; 3 x ULN in these patients)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase) and alanine&#xD;
             aminotransferase (serum glutamic pyruvic transaminase) =&lt; 2.5 x ULN or =&lt; 5 x ULN for&#xD;
             patients with liver metastases)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left ventricular ejection fraction &gt;= 50%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients are eligible to enter and participate in the study if they are of:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Non-childbearing potential (physiologically incapable of becoming pregnant),&#xD;
                  including any female who:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Has had a hysterectomy, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Has had a bilateral oophorectomy, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Has had a bilateral salpingectomy, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Is postmenopausal (total cessation of menses for &gt;= 2 years, or&#xD;
                       follicle-stimulating hormone &gt;= 50 IU/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Childbearing potential, but with a negative serum pregnancy test at screening&#xD;
                  (within 7 days of the first investigational medicinal product [IMP]&#xD;
                  administration), is not breastfeeding, and uses highly effective contraception at&#xD;
                  study entry and throughout the study until 90 days after the last administration.&#xD;
                  Highly effective contraceptive methods include:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Combined (estrogen and progestogen containing) hormonal contraception&#xD;
                       associated with inhibition of ovulation (for example oral, intravaginal,&#xD;
                       transdermal)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Progestogen-only hormonal contraception associated with inhibition of&#xD;
                       ovulation (for example oral, implantable, injectable)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Intrauterine device&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Intrauterine hormone-releasing system&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Bilateral tubal occlusion&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Male partner has had a vasectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male patients are eligible to enter and participate in the study if they agree to use&#xD;
             effective methods of contraception during the study treatment period and for at least&#xD;
             90 days after the last dose of investigational product&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior malignancy within the previous 2 years except for locally curable cancers that&#xD;
             have been cured, such as basal or squamous cell skin cancer, or carcinoma in situ of&#xD;
             the cervix, breast or bladder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known primary central malignancy or symptomatic central nervous system metastasis(es)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Note: Patients with stable, previously treated brain metastases may participate&#xD;
                  if neurologic symptoms have resolved, patients have been off steroids for at&#xD;
                  least 7 days, and there is no evidence of disease progression by imaging for at&#xD;
                  least 2 weeks before the first dose of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should be excluded if they have a condition requiring systemic treatment with&#xD;
             either corticosteroids (&gt; 10 mg daily prednisone equivalents) or other&#xD;
             immunosuppressive medications within 2 weeks of the first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled, significant intercurrent or recent illness including, but not limited&#xD;
             to, the following cardiac conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any unstable cardiac arrhythmia within 6 months prior to enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prolongation of the Fridericia corrected QT (QTcF) interval defined as &gt; 450 ms&#xD;
                  for males and &gt; 470 ms for females&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of any of the following cardiovascular conditions within 6 months of&#xD;
                  enrolment:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Cardiac angioplasty or stenting, myocardial infarction, unstable angina,&#xD;
                       coronary artery&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Bypass graft surgery, symptomatic peripheral vascular disease, class III or&#xD;
                       IV congestive heart failure, as defined by the New York Heart Association&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgical intervention within 28 days before study drug administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant acute or chronic infections&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any psychiatric condition that would prohibit the understanding or rendering of&#xD;
             informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with strong cytochrome P450 (CYP450) subtype 3A4 (CYP3A4) inducers&#xD;
             (including St John's wort) and inhibitors (including grapefruit juice) within 7 days&#xD;
             of the first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with strong CYP450 subtype 2D6 (CYP2D6) inhibitors within 7 days of the&#xD;
             first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiotherapy within 4 weeks prior to the start of study drug. Palliative radiotherapy&#xD;
             for symptomatic control is acceptable if completed at least 2 weeks prior to study&#xD;
             drug administration and no additional radiotherapy for the same lesion is planned&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Underlying medical conditions that, in the investigator's opinion, will make the&#xD;
             administration of study drug hazardous or obscure the interpretation of toxicity&#xD;
             determination or AEs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or&#xD;
             biological composition to any of the compounds in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known alcohol or drug abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Legal incapacity or limited legal capacity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to swallow oral medications (capsules and tablets) without chewing,&#xD;
             breaking, crushing, opening or otherwise altering the product formulation. Patients&#xD;
             should not have gastrointestinal illnesses that would preclude the absorption of&#xD;
             IACS-6274, which is an oral agent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unwilling to comply with protocol requirements related to the assigned part&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PART B (DOSE ESCALATION AND DOSE EXPANSION) SPECIFIC EXCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Autoimmune disease that might deteriorate when receiving an immune-stimulatory agent,&#xD;
             or immunodeficiencies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known severe hypersensitivity reactions to monoclonal antibodies, any history of&#xD;
             anaphylaxis, or uncontrolled asthma (that is, three or more features of partially&#xD;
             controlled asthma)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior organ transplantation, including allogeneic stem cell transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has received a live vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose of study&#xD;
             drug. Examples of live vaccines include, but are not limited to, the following:&#xD;
             measles, mumps, rubella, varicella/zoster (chicken pox), yellow fever, rabies,&#xD;
             Bacillus Calmette-Guerin and typhoid vaccine. Seasonal influenza vaccines for&#xD;
             injection are generally killed virus vaccines and are allowed; however, intranasal&#xD;
             influenza vaccines (e.g., FluMist) are live attenuated vaccines and are not allowed&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Timothy A Yap</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M D Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Timothy A. Yap</last_name>
      <phone>713-563-1930</phone>
      <email>tyap@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Timothy A. Yap</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Ovarian Epithelial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of Head and Neck</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Skin Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cystadenocarcinoma, Serous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Chondrosarcoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma, Clear Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

