<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05030350</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PH94B-CL030</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05030350</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Open-label Safety Trial of PH94B in Social Anxiety Disorder (SAD)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 3 Open-label Safety Trial of PH94B Nasal Spray in the Acute Treatment of Anxiety in Adult Subjects With Social Anxiety Disorder (SAD)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VistaGen Therapeutics, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VistaGen Therapeutics, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study evaluates the safety and tolerability of PH94B with repeated dosing over a period&#xD;
      of up to 12 months. Participating subjects will use PH94B up to 4 times a day when they&#xD;
      encounter anxiety-provoking situations in daily life. Safety and tolerability of PH94B (≤ 4&#xD;
      doses per day up to 12 months) will be assessed and summarized during monthly visits from&#xD;
      baseline (Visit 2) to end of treatment (Visit 14) in AEs, laboratory values, 12-lead ECGs,&#xD;
      physical examinations, and vital sign assessments following exposure to PH94B.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events and other safety measures</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome variable for the study is the change from Baseline (Visit 2) in AEs after the administration of PH94B prior to anxiety-provoking situations in daily life for subjects with SAD.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Liebowitz Social Anxiety Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of symptomatology of social anxiety disorder severity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Social Anxiety Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PH94B 3.2 micrograms</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>100 microliter nasal spray to each nostril up to four times a day as needed for acute anxiety</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PH94B</intervention_name>
    <description>Nasal spray</description>
    <arm_group_label>PH94B 3.2 micrograms</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Most but not all patients will enter the study following completion of Palisade-1&#xD;
        (NCT047548020) and Palisade-2 (NCT05011396).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male and female adults, 18 through 65 years of age, inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Women of childbearing potential must be able to commit to the consistent and correct&#xD;
             use of an effective method of birth control throughout the study, and must also have a&#xD;
             negative urine pregnancy test result at both Screening (Visit 1) (for subjects who&#xD;
             attend Visit 1) and Baseline (Visit 2), prior to IP administration. Effective methods&#xD;
             of contraception include: condoms with spermicide, diaphragm with spermicide, hormonal&#xD;
             contraceptive agents (oral, transdermal, or injectable), or implantable contraceptive&#xD;
             devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current diagnosis of social anxiety disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Clinician-rated HAM-D17 total score &lt; 18 at study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. LSAS score 50 or greater&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any history of bipolar disorder (I or II), schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder,&#xD;
             psychosis, anorexia or bulimia, autism-spectrum disorder, or obsessive-compulsive&#xD;
             disorder. Any other current Axis I disorder, other than SAD, which is the primary&#xD;
             focus of treatment. Note that subjects with concurrent Generalized Anxiety Disorder&#xD;
             are eligible for the study provided that Generalized Anxiety Disorder is not the&#xD;
             primary diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects who meet criteria for moderate or severe alcohol or substance use disorder&#xD;
             within the 1 year prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. In the opinion of the Investigator, the subject has a significant risk for suicidal&#xD;
             behavior during the course of their participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Clinically significant nasal pathology or history of significant nasal trauma, nasal&#xD;
             surgery, total anosmia, or nasal septum perforation that may have damaged the nasal&#xD;
             chemosensory epithelium.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. An acute or chronic condition, including an infectious illness, uncontrolled seasonal&#xD;
             allergies at the time of the study, or significant nasal congestion that potentially&#xD;
             could affect drug delivery to the nasal chemosensory epithelium.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects using the following psychotropic medications: anticonvulsants, mood&#xD;
             stabilizers, antipsychotic medications, gabapentin, pregabalin, opioids, naltrexone,&#xD;
             esketamine, and ketamine at enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Subjects using lower doses of atypical antipsychotics at Screening may be eligible&#xD;
             after discussion with the Medical Monitor (e.g., quetiapine &lt; 100 mg).&#xD;
&#xD;
             In general, subjects using antidepressants or buspirone can continue to receive these&#xD;
             provided that they have been taking them for a minimum of 2 months, and have been on a&#xD;
             stable dose for a minimum of 1 month.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Use of anxiolytics, such as benzodiazepines or unapproved treatments such as beta&#xD;
             blockers, within 30 days before study entry; concomitant use is prohibited during the&#xD;
             study. Subjects who have been taking benzodiazepines daily for 1 month or longer at&#xD;
             the time of Visit 1 are not eligible to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Use of any over-the-counter product, prescription product, or herbal preparation for&#xD;
             treatment of the symptoms of anxiety or social anxiety within 30 days before study&#xD;
             entry; concomitant use is prohibited during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects with clinically significant abnormalities in hematology, blood chemistry,&#xD;
             urinalysis, 12-lead ECG, or physical examination identified at the Screening visit or&#xD;
             Baseline visit that in the clinical judgment of the Investigator, could place the&#xD;
             subject at undue risk, interfere with study participation, or confound the results of&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jaakko Lappalainen, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>VistaGen Therapeutics</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Cherilyn Boller</last_name>
    <phone>1-860-200-6565</phone>
    <email>PalisadeLTSS@premier-research.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Phobia, Social</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

