<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05039515</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D-CA-60130-452</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-002858-24</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05039515</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Assess the Efficacy and Safety of 2 Dosage Regimens of Oral IPN60130 for the Treatment of Fibrodysplasia Ossificans Progressiva (FOP).</brief_title>
  <acronym>FALKON</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 2, Two-part, Placebo-controlled, Parallel-group, Double-blind Study to Assess the Efficacy and Safety of 2 Dosage Regimens of Oral IPN60130 for the Treatment of Fibrodysplasia Ossificans Progressiva in Male and Female Participants 5 Years of Age and Older.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Clementia Pharmaceuticals Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ipsen</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ipsen</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Fibrodysplasia Ossificans Progressiva (FOP) is a rare, severely disabling disease&#xD;
      characterized by the presence of bone in soft tissue where bone normally does not exist,&#xD;
      known as Heterotopic Ossification (HO). It is often associated with painful, recurrent&#xD;
      episodes of soft tissue swelling (flare-ups) that lead to abnormal stiffening and immobility&#xD;
      (ankyloses) of major joints with cumulative and irreversible loss of movement and disability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will evaluate the efficacy of 2 dosing regimens of IPN60130 in inhibiting new HO&#xD;
      volume compared with placebo (a dummy treatment) in adult and paediatric participants with&#xD;
      FOP. It will be assessed by a scan (provides internal images of the body) called low dose&#xD;
      Whole Body Computed Tomography (WBCT), excluding head.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults and participants 15 years of age or older are also eligible for a sub study to&#xD;
      evaluate HO lesions assessed by another type of scan, Fluorine-18-labelled natrium fluoride&#xD;
      Positron Emission Tomography-Computed Tomography ([18F]NaF PET-CT ).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Annualized change from baseline in HO volume as assessed by low-dose WBCT (excluding the head) in treated participants receiving IPN60130 compared with placebo.</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Adverse Events / Serious Adverse Events (AEs/SAE)</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline until the end of study (25 months)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in HO volume of new HO lesions as detected by WBCT in participants receiving IPN60130 compared with placebo recipients</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline up to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in number of HO lesions by WBCT in participants receiving IPN60130 compared with placebo recipients</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline up to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Flare-up rate and number of flare-up days in participants receiving IPN60130 compared with placebo recipients</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline up to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The number of body regions with new HO in participants receiving IPN60130 compared with placebo recipients</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline up to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in pain intensity over time using the Numeric pain rating scale (NRS) in participants ≥13 years old and Wong Baker Faces Pain Scale (FPS) in participants &lt;13 years old in participants receiving IPN60130 compared with placebo recipients</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline up to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of participants with any new HO in participants receiving IPN60130 compared with placebo recipients</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline up to 24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in HO volume as detected by WBCT in participants receiving IPN60130 compared with placebo recipients and with participants receiving the standard of care in the Natural history study (NHS)</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline up to 24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Fibrodysplasia Ossificans Progressiva</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IPN60130 high dosage</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral capsule, swallowed whole or sprinkled onto food, once daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IPN60130 low dosage</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral capsule, swallowed whole or sprinkled onto food, once daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral capsule, swallowed whole or sprinkled onto food, once daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>IPN60130</intervention_name>
    <description>Immediate-release capsule containing high dose of the drug substance.</description>
    <arm_group_label>IPN60130 high dosage</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>IPN60130</intervention_name>
    <description>Immediate-release capsule containing low dose of the drug substance.</description>
    <arm_group_label>IPN60130 low dosage</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo will be supplied as powder filled hard capsules</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Key Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written, signed, and dated informed subject/parent consent; and for subjects who are&#xD;
             minors, age-appropriate assent (performed according to local regulations).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must be clinically diagnosed with FOP, with the R206H ACVR1 mutation or&#xD;
             other FOP variants associated with progressive HO.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must have at least one flare-up in the preceding year of the screening&#xD;
             visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have participated in a prior clinical study using another&#xD;
             investigational product for the treatment of FOP may be enrolled after a washout of at&#xD;
             least 5 half-lives of the other investigational product. Participants with prior&#xD;
             treatment such as, but not limited to, imatinib, isotretinoin, or palovarotene may be&#xD;
             enrolled 30 days after discontinuation or after washout of at least 5 half-lives,&#xD;
             whichever is longer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must be able to perform pulmonary function tests adequately and reliably.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must be able to have an adequate echocardiography assessment at screening&#xD;
             for evaluation of left ventricular structure and function as defined by the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must be accessible for treatment and follow-up and be able to undergo all&#xD;
             study procedures. Participants living at distant locations from the investigational&#xD;
             site must be able and willing to travel to a site for the initial and all on-site&#xD;
             follow-up visits. Participants must be able to undergo low-dose WBCT (excluding head)&#xD;
             without sedation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight ≥10 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abstinent or using two highly effective forms of birth control. Females must also have&#xD;
             a negative blood or urine pregnancy test prior to administration of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Key Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with complete heart block and left bundle branch block on screening&#xD;
             electrocardiogram.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with screening echocardiography showing septal or left ventricular free&#xD;
             wall thickness &gt;12 mm for adult participants or a z-score &gt;3 compared with population&#xD;
             norms for children and adolescent participants or left ventricular ejection fraction&#xD;
             (LVEF) &lt;50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with severe mitral or tricuspid regurgitation on echocardiography at&#xD;
             screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with significant underlying lung disease requiring supplementary oxygen&#xD;
             or forced vital capacity &lt;35% of predicted at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with uncontrolled cardiovascular, hepatic, pulmonary, gastrointestinal,&#xD;
             endocrine, metabolic, ophthalmologic, immunologic, psychiatric, or another significant&#xD;
             disease as judged by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with severe hepatic impairment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant medications that are strong inhibitors (including grapefruit juice) or&#xD;
             inducers (including St John's Wort) of cytochrome P450 (CYP) 3A4 activity; or kinase&#xD;
             inhibitors such as imatinib.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior use in the past year and concomitant use of bisphosphonates.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent participation in another interventional clinical study, or a&#xD;
             noninterventional study with radiographic measures or invasive procedures (e.g.&#xD;
             collection of blood or tissue samples).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Amylase or lipase &gt;2× the upper limit of normal (ULN) or with a history of chronic&#xD;
             pancreatitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Elevated aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt;5×ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with hematologic abnormalities:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hgb&lt;10g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets&lt;75,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  WBC&lt;2000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants with coagulation test measurements outside of the normal range at&#xD;
                  screening.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ipsen Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Ipsen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ipsen Recruitment Enquiries</last_name>
    <phone>see email</phone>
    <email>clinical.trials@ipsen.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Myositis Ossificans</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Where patient data can be anonymised, Ipsen will share all individual participant data that underlie the results reported in the published journal article with qualified researchers who provide a valid research question. Study documents, such as the study protocol and clinical study report, are not always available.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data are available beginning 6 months and ending 5 years after the publication of the findings in a journal; after this time, only raw data may be available.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Proposals should be submitted to DataSharing@ipsen.com and will be assessed by a scientific review board.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

