<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05037435</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RTB 001/18</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05037435</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Immunological Efficacy of the Pentavalent Rotavirus Vaccine - Rota-V-Aid™ (Live Attenuated Oral, Freeze-dried) at Healthy Adults Aged 18 to 45 Years.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prospective, Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled Clinical Study of the Safety and Efficacy of the Vaccine for the Prevention of Pentavalent Live Rotavirus Infection in Healthy Subjects (Target Age of 18-45 Years Old).</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Limited Liability Company Pharm Aid</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Limited Liability Company Pharm Aid</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of the presented study was to evaluate the safety and immunological efficacy in&#xD;
      preventing the rotavirus infection within a cohort of healthy subjects (target age of 18-45&#xD;
      years old) by using the pentavalent rotavirus vaccine - Rota-V-Aid™ (live attenuated oral,&#xD;
      freeze-dried).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The clinical study named &quot;Prospective, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study of&#xD;
      safety and immunological efficacy for preventing a rotavirus infection pentavalent vaccine,&#xD;
      live attenuated at the healthy subjects at the age of 18-45 years&quot; was conducted in the&#xD;
      Russian Federation. The mentioned study was performed as per Protocol of clinical trial No.&#xD;
      RTB 001/18 (given by MOH RF exp June 7, 2018). All relevant requirements of the National&#xD;
      Legislative system and the international rules of conduct of clinical trials (ICH GCP).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study objective was to assess the safety and immunological efficacy for preventing a&#xD;
      rotavirus infection pentavalent rotavirus vaccine - Rota-V-Aid™ (live attenuated oral,&#xD;
      freeze-dried) at healthy adults aged 18 to 45 years for the subsequent vaccination of the&#xD;
      children's contingent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the achievement of a goal, it was necessary to solve the following problems:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Assessment of the vaccine's safety for preventing a rotavirus infection pentavalent live&#xD;
           compared to placebo at a single oral introduction to volunteers at the age of 18-45&#xD;
           years.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Immunological efficacy assessment for prevention of a rotavirus infection pentavalent&#xD;
           live in comparison with placebo at a single oral introduction to volunteers at the age&#xD;
           of 18-45 years&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 25, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 27, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 27, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective randomized double-blind placebo-controllable.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Titer (GMT) of antibody</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days post-Dose 1</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Seroconversion level</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days after Dose 1 of vaccine</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Seroconversion factor (The increase in the geometric mean antibody titer on day 28 compared to the initial level is expressed in the fold increase.).</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days post-Dose 1</time_frame>
    <description>The seroconversion factor after administration of the study vaccine was 1.20, after administration of placebo - 0.97.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency and expressiveness of AE /SAE.</measure>
    <time_frame>From the time of Dose 1 to 28 days</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Rotavirus Infections</condition>
  <condition>Rotavirus Vaccines</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The pentavalent rotavirus vaccine - Rota-V-Aid™ (live attenuated oral, freeze-dried)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Live attenuated bovine-human [UK] reassortant rotavirus vaccine manufactured by the Serum Institute of India, Limited (SIIL). The pentavalent vaccine contains rotavirus serotypes G1, G2, G3, G4, and G9 (≥5.6 log10 FFU/serotype/dose). The vaccine is lyophilized and supplied with 2.5 ml of citrate bicarbonate buffer added for reconstitution before oral administration.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Diluent is a sterile solution (Citrate Bicarbonate Buffer)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Same constituents as the active vaccine but without the viral antigens; manufactured by SIIL.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The pentavalent rotavirus vaccine (live attenuated oral, freeze-dried)</intervention_name>
    <description>Group 1 (20 participants) - received the pentavalent live vaccine to prevent rotavirus infection Single-use orally 2.5 ml (1 dose).</description>
    <arm_group_label>The pentavalent rotavirus vaccine - Rota-V-Aid™ (live attenuated oral, freeze-dried)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Rota-V-Aid™</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Group 2 (20 participants ) - received placebo orally once of 2.5 ml (1 dose).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Diluent is a sterile solution (Citrate Bicarbonate Buffer)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Diluent is a sterile solution (Citrate Bicarbonate Buffer)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The signed informed consent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Healthy participants, men's and females aged from 18 up to 45 years inclusive;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Readiness of participants and their sexual partners to use reliable methods of&#xD;
             contraception (a combination of at least two modes, including one barrier method, for&#xD;
             example, use of a spermicide and condom) from the moment of signing of the informed&#xD;
             consent (that is in 3 days before administration of drugs) and before the expiration&#xD;
             of 1 month after completion of participation in the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The verified diagnosis &quot;is healthy,&quot; established according to collecting the anamnesis&#xD;
             and physical inspection:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  absence in the anamnesis and at the time of screening clinically significant&#xD;
                  dysfunctions cardiovascular, respiratory, nervous, hemopoietic, endocrine,&#xD;
                  gastrointestinal systems, liver, and kidneys;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  absence of persistent infections (HIV, hepatitis B, C, syphilis);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  absence within 30 days before inclusion in the study of sharp, infectious&#xD;
                  diseases;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  absence of the mental disorders and any other states capable to affectability of&#xD;
                  the participant to follow requirements of the protocol;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  lack of complaints to the state of health within 30 days before inclusion in the&#xD;
                  study;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  hemodynamic indicators within norm: systolic arterial blood pressure - within 100&#xD;
                  - 130 mm Hg., diastolic arterial blood pressure - within 60 - 90 mm Hg;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The Body Mass Index (BMI) is in normal limits (≥18.5 kg/sq.m and ≤30 kg/sq.m);&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. There is a lack of instructions on alcohol abuse or narcotic dependence at the time of&#xD;
             inclusion in study or the anamnesis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The participant's Ability, according to the study, to fulfill the requirements of the&#xD;
             protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The severe vaccine-challenged reactions/complications connected with the previous&#xD;
             vaccination;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Allergic reactions to components of vaccine or any previous vaccination;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any carried-out vaccination less than in 2 months before the present study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. In the chronic anamnesis diseases of the digestive tract, causes intestinal&#xD;
             invagination, gastrointestinal pathology, surgical interventions on abdominal organs;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Clinically significant deviations of laboratory and tool indicators (including&#xD;
             standard pathological changes on the ECG) overstepping the bounds of the range of&#xD;
             normal values revealed on screening and capable of negatively impacting the safety of&#xD;
             participants of the volunteer in the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any diseases within four weeks preceding screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Presence of any oncological diseases (including in the anamnesis);&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any disease demands continuous therapy, including vegetable drugs or the expected&#xD;
             concurrent therapy during the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Donor blood donation (450 ml of blood or plasma and more) or loss of 500 or more ml of&#xD;
             blood in 3 months before the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Positive analysis on HIV, Hepatitis B and C, and syphilis (RW);&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Impossibility to give the written informed consent or to follow requirements of the&#xD;
             protocol;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Probability to refuse to follow the protocol's requirements, instructions and&#xD;
             restrictions; for example, unwillingness to cooperate, impossibility to return to&#xD;
             clinical center for the subsequent visits, and the probability not of completion of&#xD;
             participation in a clinical trial;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Participation in clinical trials of drugs less than in 3 months before the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Smoking more than ten cigarettes in a day;&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Drug addiction in the anamnesis. The positive analysis of urine on psychotropic and&#xD;
             narcotic substances, psychoactive medicines;&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Regular alcohol intake in many ˃10 units a week (to 1 unit of alcohol is equivalent to&#xD;
             ½ l of beer, 200 ml of wine, or 50 ml of hard liquors) or anamnestic data on&#xD;
             alcoholism. Alcohol intake within 48 hours before the Screening visit. Positive&#xD;
             respiratory test for alcohol on screening (breathalyzer);&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Observance of a special diet (for example, vegetarian, observance of a post, etc.) or&#xD;
             lifestyle (including work at night and extreme physical activities, such as sport or&#xD;
             raising of weights) which can interfere with carrying out the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. The study cannot include military personnel or employees law enforcement agencies&#xD;
             serving sentences in places of detention or being in custody;&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. The presence of conviction of the study is that the volunteer will not follow&#xD;
             procedures of the protocol;&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Use of any medicines, including OTC, vegetable medicines, dietary supplements, within&#xD;
             14 days before the study, according to the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Irina V. Feldblium, Dr. Sci</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Perm State Medical University named after Academician E.A. Wagner</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Perm State Medical University named after Academician E.A. Wagner</name>
      <address>
        <city>Perm</city>
        <zip>614990</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 31, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rotavirus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

