<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05037305</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>VUMCIRB:TBD</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05037305</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Knowledge and Attitudes Regarding Pharmacogenomics Testing Among Children With Chronic Disease and Pregnant Women</brief_title>
  <acronym>MPRINT</acronym>
  <official_title>Knowledge and Attitudes Regarding Pharmacogenomics Testing Among Children With Chronic Disease and Pregnant Women Before and After Receiving Pharmacogenomics Results Using a Community-Engaged Approach (MPRINT)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The field of pharmacogenomics has progressed from the discovery of genetic variants that&#xD;
      cause variable function of drug metabolism enzymes to a cornerstone of clinical precision&#xD;
      medicine. However, there are limited data supporting drug-gene associations for children and&#xD;
      for women during and after pregnancy. The unique physiology of childhood and pregnancy demand&#xD;
      validation of pharmacogenomic signals prior to clinical implementation. These knowledge gaps&#xD;
      are compounded for individuals from minority populations, who have been underrepresented and&#xD;
      thus underserved by genomic research and specifically pharmacogenomic studies. The primary&#xD;
      objective of this project is to advance research and support clinical implementation in&#xD;
      pharmacogenomics for children and pregnant women. This work will use a community engaged&#xD;
      approach to illuminate knowledge of, attitudes about, and priorities for pharmacogenomics.&#xD;
      The investigators will assess the knowledge and attitudes regarding pharmacogenomic testing&#xD;
      among diverse cohorts of children with chronic disease and pregnant women, before and after&#xD;
      receiving pharmacogenomic test results. This aim will begin with a Community Engagement&#xD;
      Studio to identify strategies to facilitate and enhance inclusion of children with chronic&#xD;
      health conditions, pregnant women, minorities, and those with disabilities in pharmacogenomic&#xD;
      research. The investigators will then perform surveys before and after pharmacogenomic&#xD;
      testing and return of results.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will follow a single-arm unblinded research design. Study inclusion criteria&#xD;
      include ability to provide a DNA sample for pharmacogenomic (PGx) testing and willingness to&#xD;
      receive the test results. Thus, all participants will have PGx testing, which the&#xD;
      investigators define as the intervention for this study. Participants will complete a survey&#xD;
      at study baseline, which will collect demographic information (age, race/ethnicity), contact&#xD;
      and alternative contact information, primary care physician information, socioeconomic&#xD;
      details (e.g. insurance information, education, occupation, marital status, and income)&#xD;
      health data (e.g. chronic conditions, personal and family history of genetic diseases) and&#xD;
      lifestyle data (e.g. smoking, drinking, and physical activity). Parents will complete&#xD;
      enrollment surveys on behalf of children. Basic health and pregnancy history will also be&#xD;
      collected for pregnant women. The survey regarding information and knowledge on PGx testing&#xD;
      will be administered at enrollment and again after return of PGx results. The investigators&#xD;
      will include additional questions in the follow-up survey specific to educational materials&#xD;
      provided after testing. The survey will capture the following core domains: 1) experience&#xD;
      with medications/side effects; 2) understanding of genetics and PGx; 3) impact of PGx with&#xD;
      relationships with healthcare professionals; 4) scenarios involving PGx-guided prescribing;&#xD;
      5) responses to PGx educational materials; 6) perceptions of the utility of PGx information.&#xD;
      Questions specific to perceptions and knowledge will be scored on a 5-point scale (e.g. 'very&#xD;
      important' to 'not at all important'; 'very likely' to 'not likely'). The investigators are&#xD;
      recruiting 250 women and 250 children with the goal of a final cohort of 200 for each group&#xD;
      for statistical analyses, thus allowing up to 20% drop out rate. The investigators will use&#xD;
      multivariate logistic or ordinal regression to determine the associations between survey&#xD;
      responses and demographic, clinical, and test result variables.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>All individuals in the Aim 1 cohort will be undergo pharmacogenomic testing, which will be performed in our CLIA-CAP certified clinical laboratory using the panel-based clinical pharmacogenomic assay used at Vanderbilt University Medical Center.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowledge gained after PGx testing</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to post-return of PGx results, approximately 2- 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To characterize knowledge gained after PGx testing, we will compare baseline and follow up survey results. We will also test if changes in responses from baseline to post-testing associate with demographic characteristics, clinical characteristics, and test results.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Attitudes surrounding PGx testing</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to post-return of PGx results, approximately 2-4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To characterize changes in attitudes after PGx testing, we will compare baseline and follow up survey results. We will also test if changes in responses from baseline to post-testing associate with demographic characteristics, clinical characteristics, and test results.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Pharmacogenomic Testing</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm One Pharmacogenetic Testing Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>All individuals in the &quot;Arm One Pharmacogenetic Testing Cohort&quot; will be undergo pharmacogenomic testing, which will be performed in our CLIA-CAP certified clinical laboratory using the panel-based clinical pharmacogenomic assay used at Vanderbilt University Medical Center.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pharmacogenomic Testing</intervention_name>
    <description>All individuals in the &quot;Arm One Pharmacogenetic Testing Cohort&quot; will be undergo pharmacogenomic testing, which will be performed in our CLIA-CAP certified clinical laboratory using the panel-based clinical pharmacogenomic assay used at Vanderbilt University Medical Center.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm One Pharmacogenetic Testing Cohort</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Maternal&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provide consent in English or Spanish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary care at VUMC&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult women aged 18 and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently pregnant 12 to 30 weeks gestational age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Completed or scheduled first prenatal visit at VUMC clinic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intent to deliver at VUMC or affiliate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees to receive findings from pharmacogenomic testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allow access their medical record&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stem cell or solid organ transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent transfusion within the previous 2 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to provide DNA sample for testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior pharmacogenomic testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women undergoing in vitro fertilization or assisted reproductive technologies&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pediatric&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provide consent (parent/guardian) and/or assent (child) in English or Spanish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary care or subspecialty care at VUMC&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 0 to 16&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parent (0-16 years) and child (12-16 years) agree for both parent and child to receive&#xD;
             findings from pharmacogenomic testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parent (0-16 years) and child (12-16 years) allow access their medical record&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a chronic health condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stem cell or solid organ transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent transfusion within the previous 2 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to provide DNA sample for testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior pharmacogenomic testing&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Adult pregnant women, and children (regardless of sex)</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 31, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sara Van Driest</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Pediatrics and Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>pharmacogenomic</keyword>
  <keyword>PGx</keyword>
  <keyword>pediatric</keyword>
  <keyword>maternal</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified datasets, including genomic data, will be made available upon request and review/approval of research purpose.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_time_frame>It will become available once any manuscripts are accepted for publication. It will be available for a reasonable amount of time.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Qualified Researchers</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

