<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05030129</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ORA 21051102</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05030129</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Single Blind Study of Ergoloid Mesylates, 5-HTP and the Combination in Adult Males With Fragile X Syndrome</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Exploratory Single Blind Study of Ergoloid Mesylates, 5-Hydroxytryptophan, and the Combination in Adult Males With Fragile X Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Elizabeth Berry-Kravis</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rush University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A preliminary assessment of the safety, tolerability and efficacy of Ergoloid mesylates (EM)&#xD;
      and 5-hydroxytryptophan (5-HTP) and the combination (EM + 5-HTP) compared to placebo in males&#xD;
      aged 18-45 years old with Fragile X Syndrome.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This single-center, Phase 2, single-blind, 4-period sequential study will obtain a&#xD;
      preliminary assessment of the effects of Ergoloid mesylates (EM) 1 mg TID and&#xD;
      5-hydroxytryptophan (5-HTP) 100 mg TID and the combination compared to a placebo period in&#xD;
      males aged 18-45 years old with Fragile X Syndrome. The study will consist of a Screening&#xD;
      period of up to 28 days prior to initial study drug administration, followed by four 4 week&#xD;
      single-blind treatment periods (up to 21 weeks total). The screening and baseline visits may&#xD;
      occur at the same time, provided the results of safety labs can be obtained. A final&#xD;
      follow-up visit or phone contact for safety is planned one week after the conclusion of&#xD;
      Period 4. Safety and tolerability assessments will include adverse event monitoring, vital&#xD;
      signs, blood chemistry and hematology, and urinalysis. Brief cognitive and behavioral&#xD;
      assessments will be performed during each clinic visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible participants will progress through each of 4 periods (arms) on study. The periods&#xD;
      are not listed sequentially here in order to preserve the single blind for participants.&#xD;
      Throughout all 4 periods, participants will take two identical capsules three times a day. If&#xD;
      only taking one over-encapsulated drug, they will take one over-encapsulated placebo pill&#xD;
      with the drug at each dose, and when in period 4 they will take two over-encapsulated placebo&#xD;
      pills at each dose.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 22, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 21, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the safety and tolerability of EM, 5-HTP, and EM + 5-HTP in fragile X syndrome.&#xD;
Safety and Tolerability Endpoints:&#xD;
● Adverse events as assessed at each visit by Clinical Trials Common Toxicity Criteria (CTCAE)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>KiTAP Executive Battery</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Computerized executive battery with assessments of alertness (reaction time), distractibility, go/nogo (impulsiveness), and flexibility</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Global Impression Severity</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Investigator rated (CGI-S) Standardized ranking scale with 7 rankings</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Global Impression Improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Investigator rated (CGI-I): Standardized ranking scale with 7 rankings</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Analog Scale (VAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Parent/caregiver-rated assessment of participant-specific behavioral anchors: Domains of daily functioning, anxiety/irritability and language.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Aberrant Behavior Checklist (ABC)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Parent/caregiver-rated scale with six subscales to assess irritability, social avoidance, lethargy, hyperactivity, inappropriate speech and social avoidance, using ABC-FX factoring system.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety, Depression, and Mood Scale (ADAMS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Parent/caregiver rated scale with a total score and five sub-scores to assess manic/hyperactive behavior, depressed mood, social avoidance, general anxiety, and obsessive/compulsive behavior.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>iBehavior ratings</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Smartphone app for tracking behavior in key domains of problem behavior in FXS</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vineland-3 Adaptive Behavior Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Clinician-administered standardized interview yielding adaptive behavior composite score and domain standard scores in domains of: communication (receptive, expressive, and written adaptive language functions), daily living skills (personal, domestic, and community skills), socialization (interpersonal relationships, play and leisure time, and coping abilities), and motor skills (gross and fine motor skills).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>NIH Toolbox Cognitive Battery Modified for Intellectual Disabilities (NIH-TCB)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Cognitive battery assessing different domains of cognition, administered using an iPad</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Event Related Potentials (ERP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Event Related Potentials (ERP)&#xD;
Resting state delta power (electrical activity in the brain) will be measured from an EEG (electroencephalogram)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Eye Tracking</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Eye Tracking = Measure of gaze aversion (social anxiety) and pupilometry (autonomic function) on computer based system</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Eye Tracking - Gaze Aversion</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The amount of time (in seconds) spent looking at, and away from, a visual image on a computer screen will be measured.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Eye Tracking - Pupilometry</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 21 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Measure of pupilometry (pupil size) on a computer based system. The pupil size, in millimeters, will be measured in response to a visual image on a computer screen.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Fragile X Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ergoloid mesylates (EM) and 5-hydroxytryptophan (5-HTP)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Ergoloid mesylates (EM) 1 mg three times daily and 5-hydroxytryptophan (5-HTP) 100 mg three times daily for 4 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>2 placebo capsules three times daily for 4 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ergoloid mesylates (EM) and placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Ergoloid mesylates (EM) 1 mg three times daily and 1 placebo capsule three times daily for 4 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>5-hydroxytryptophan (5-HTP) and placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>5-hydroxytryptophan (5-HTP) 100 mg three times daily and 1 placebo capsule three times daily for 4 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>5-Hydroxytryptophan / Vitamin B6</intervention_name>
    <description>5-hydroxytryptophan, also known as 5-HTP has a nutraceutical status and has never been approved as a drug for any indication, but as a dietary supplement has been used extensively for several disorders for many years such as in the therapy of depression, fibromyalgia, obesity, insomnia and chronic headache</description>
    <arm_group_label>5-hydroxytryptophan (5-HTP) and placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Ergoloid mesylates (EM) and 5-hydroxytryptophan (5-HTP)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ergoloid Mesylate</intervention_name>
    <description>Ergoloid Mesylates, trade name Hydergine, is a mixture of the methanesulfonate salts of three dihydrogenated ergot alkaloids, dihydroergocristine, dihydroergocornine, and alpha- and beta-dihydroergocryptine. Ergot alkaloids are dopamine agonists which activate dopamine receptors (in the basal ganglia and other parts of the brain involved in motor function) and a prolactin inhibitor. Ergot is a strong vasoconstrictor and thus helps to reduce bleeding by narrowing of the blood vessels.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ergoloid mesylates (EM) and 5-hydroxytryptophan (5-HTP)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Ergoloid mesylates (EM) and placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo capsules</description>
    <arm_group_label>5-hydroxytryptophan (5-HTP) and placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Ergoloid mesylates (EM) and placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male aged 18 to 45 years, inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participant has Fragile X Syndrome with a molecular genetic confirmation of the full&#xD;
             Fragile X Mental Retardation (FMR1) mutation (≥200 CGG repeats).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current treatment with no more than 3 prescribed psychotropic medications.&#xD;
             Anti-epileptic medications are permitted and are not counted as psychotropic&#xD;
             medications if they are used for treatment of seizures. Anti-epileptics for other&#xD;
             indications, such as the treatment of mood disorders, count towards the limit of&#xD;
             permitted medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Permitted concomitant psychotropic medications must be at a stable dose and dosing&#xD;
             regimen for at least 2 weeks prior to Screening and must remain stable during the&#xD;
             period between Screening and the commencement of study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Anti-epileptic medications must be at a stable dose and dosing regimen for 12 weeks&#xD;
             prior to Screening and must remain stable during the period between Screening and the&#xD;
             commencement of study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participants with a history of seizure disorder who are currently receiving treatment&#xD;
             with anti-epileptics must have been seizure-free for 3 months preceding screening, or&#xD;
             must be seizure-free for 3 years if not currently receiving anti-epileptics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Behavioral and therapy treatments/interventions must be stable for 4 weeks prior to&#xD;
             Screening and must remain stable during the period between Screening and the&#xD;
             commencement of study medication, and throughout the study. Minor changes in hours or&#xD;
             times of therapy that are not considered clinically significant will not be&#xD;
             exclusionary. Changes in therapies provided through a school program, due to school&#xD;
             vacations, are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Participant must be willing to practice barrier methods of contraception while on&#xD;
             study, if sexually active. Abstinence is also considered a reasonable form of birth&#xD;
             control in this study population.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Participant has a parent, legal authorized guardian or consistent caregiver.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Participant and caregiver are able to attend the clinic regularly and reliably.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Participant is able to swallow capsules.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. For participants who are not their own legal guardian, participant's parent/legal&#xD;
             authorized guardian is able to understand and sign an informed consent form to&#xD;
             participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. If participant is his own legal guardian, he can understand and sign informed consent&#xD;
             to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. If participant is not their own legal guardian, the participant provides assent for&#xD;
             participation in the study, if the participant has the cognitive ability to provide&#xD;
             assent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of, or current cardiovascular, renal, hepatic, respiratory, gastrointestinal,&#xD;
             psychiatric, neurologic, cerebrovascular, or other systemic disease that would place&#xD;
             the participant at risk or potentially interfere with the interpretation of the&#xD;
             safety, tolerability, or efficacy of the study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Common diseases such as mild hypertension, well-controlled type 2 diabetes mellitus&#xD;
             (hemoglobin A1C [Hgb A1C] &lt;6.5%), etc. are allowed per the investigator's judgment as&#xD;
             long as they are stable and controlled by medical therapy that is constant for at&#xD;
             least 4 weeks before randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Clinically significant abnormalities, in the investigator's judgment, in safety&#xD;
             laboratory tests, vital signs, as measured during Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of substance abuse within the past year, according to investigator assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Use of CYP3A4 inhibitors, beta-blockers, MAO inhibitors or triptans at any time during&#xD;
             participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Significant hearing or visual impairment that may affect the participant's ability to&#xD;
             complete the test procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Concurrent major psychiatric condition (e.g., Major Depressive Disorder, Schizophrenia&#xD;
             or Bipolar Disorder) as diagnosed by the investigator. Participants with additional&#xD;
             diagnosis of Autism Spectrum Disorder or Anxiety Disorder will be allowed as these are&#xD;
             characteristics of FXS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Participant has active diseases that would interfere with participation, such as&#xD;
             acquired immunodeficiency disorder, hepatitis C, hepatitis B, or tuberculosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Participant is planning to commence psychotherapy or cognitive behavior therapy (CBT)&#xD;
             during the period of the study or had begun psychotherapy or CBT within 4 weeks prior&#xD;
             to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Participant has participated in another clinical trial within the 30 days preceding&#xD;
             Screening.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elizabeth Berry-Kravis, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rush University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kimberleigh M Sharp, B.S.</last_name>
    <phone>312.942.2815</phone>
    <email>kimberleigh_sharp@rush.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rush University Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Elizabeth Berry-Kravis</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor, Department of Pediatrics, Neurological Sciences, Biochemistry</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fragile X Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vitamin B 6</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pyridoxal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pyridoxine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ergoloid Mesylates</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>5-Hydroxytryptophan</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dihydroergotoxine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

