<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05031312</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>03112019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05031312</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Inferior Oblique Myectomy Versus Anterior and Nasal Transposition of Its Tendon for Treatment of Superior Oblique Muscle Palsy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Inferior Oblique Myectomy Versus Anterior and Nasal Transposition of Its Tendon for Treatment of Superior Oblique Muscle Palsy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Research Institute of Ophthalmology, Egypt</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Research Institute of Ophthalmology, Egypt</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This Study aims at comparing the safety and efficacy of inferior oblique myectomy to anterior&#xD;
      and nasal transposition of inferior oblique as two treatment options of superior oblique&#xD;
      palsy regarding ocular alignment , alphabetical pattern correction , comitance and limitation&#xD;
      of ocular motility&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Superior oblique palsy is one of the most common causes of vertical ocular muscle palsy. It&#xD;
      may be congenital or acquired with over-elevation of the affected eye in primary position&#xD;
      that increases in contralateral gaze and with ipsilateral head tilt . Torsional and vertical&#xD;
      diplopia may occur resulting in compensatory head tilt .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Bilateral superior oblique palsy is approximately 29%-38% of cases of superior oblique palsy.&#xD;
      It is a rare congenital or acquired ocular motility disorder. It can be symmetrical or&#xD;
      asymmetrical .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Superior oblique palsy can be treated by different types of surgeries including superior&#xD;
      oblique strengthening by tucking of its tendon, contralateral inferior rectus muscle&#xD;
      recession, recession of ipsilateral superior rectus muscle or inferior oblique weakening by&#xD;
      disinsertion , myectomy , recession and anterior transposition .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Superior oblique tucking is an efficient and safe procedure for treatment of superior oblique&#xD;
      palsy with vertical deviation less than 15 prism diopter in the primary position and&#xD;
      remarkable superior oblique under action. The superior oblique forced duction test is the&#xD;
      most important for planning surgery .This procedure may cause iatrogenic post-operative Brown&#xD;
      syndrome .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recession of the ipsilateral superior rectus muscle reduces the upward force elevating the&#xD;
      hypertropic eye. Recession of the contralateral inferior rectus muscle is another option that&#xD;
      reduces the force shifting the contralateral eye downward to match the position of the other&#xD;
      hypertropic eye due to superior oblique muscle palsy .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inferior oblique disinsertion is one of inferior oblique muscle weakening procedures with&#xD;
      high efficacy when used simultaneously with superior rectus recession to control large&#xD;
      vertical deviations in superior oblique palsy with contracture of superior rectus muscle .&#xD;
      This may carry a high risk of postoperative overcorrection .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inferior oblique recession is effective in weakening of its action and treatment of superior&#xD;
      oblique palsy. Inferior oblique myectomy is more effective than recession in improving&#xD;
      hyper-elevation in primary gaze specially in those patients with small to moderate&#xD;
      preoperative hyperopia .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inferior oblique myectomy temporal to the inferior rectus muscle is the most popular&#xD;
      procedure to treat inferior oblique over action and reduce vertical deviation .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inferior oblique anterior transposition was first described at (1980) to correct both&#xD;
      excyclotorsion and hypertropia in superior oblique palsy presenting with inferior oblique&#xD;
      over action but this may be complicated by post-operative limited elevation . At 1992 -2001&#xD;
      antero-nasal transposition of inferior oblique was described to overcome these problems by&#xD;
      converting inferior oblique muscle from an elevator and extorted muscle to depressor in&#xD;
      adduction and intorted muscle . This makes it one of the surgical options for inferior&#xD;
      oblique weakening in superior oblique palsy with reduction of antielevation complications&#xD;
      associated with anterior inferior oblique transposition .&#xD;
&#xD;
      The retrospective studies were done between 2012-2017 and for 6 months postoperative follow&#xD;
      up that have reported postoperative inferior oblique over action rates of 1.7%- 5% following&#xD;
      myectomy, 4% residual inferior oblique overaction was detected in recession in contrast to&#xD;
      only 2% residual over action in the eyes that had inferior oblique anterior transposition&#xD;
      with only 4% antielevation syndrome developed but with orthotropia in the primary position&#xD;
      and no further surgery was performed .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 29, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>prospective comparative simple randomized study of 30 cases of superior oblique palsy divided in to two groups (A) and (B) Group A will include 15 cases who will undergo inferior oblique anterior and nasal transposition and group B will include 15 cases who will undergo inferior oblique myectomy .</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Inferior oblique Myectomy versus Anterior and Nasal transposition of its tendon for treatment of Superior oblique muscle palsy</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>30 participants ,15 participants of them were included in anterior nasal transposition ,15 participants were included in myectomy group with assessment of pre and postoperative vertical deviation with prism diopter , V pattern with prism diopter , torsion with degree , palpebral fissure with millimeter and grading over or underaction of inferior oblique by numbers from1 to 4</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Superior Oblique Palsy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>inferior oblique anterior nasal transposition</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group A for inferior oblique anterior nasal transposition 2mmx2mm posterior and nasal to inferior rectus insertion to control vertical deviation especially large angle vertical deviation and V pattern with more potent postoperative effect in unilateral and bilateral cases</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>inferior oblique myectomy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group B for inferior oblique myectomy to control vertical deviation but not of large angle which lead to residual inferior oblique overaction</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>inferior oblique weakening</intervention_name>
    <description>inferior oblique myectomy versus inferior oblique anterior nasal transposition in superior oblique palsy treatment</description>
    <arm_group_label>inferior oblique anterior nasal transposition</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>inferior oblique myectomy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with superior oblique palsy (unilateral or bilateral) with no age restriction&#xD;
             from males and females cases .&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
&#xD;
        The following patients will be excluded:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with previous cyclo-vertical muscle surgeries.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Connective tissue diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Previous orbital surgery.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elsayed Mohamed Eltoukhi, prof dr</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>RIO</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mohammad Othman Abd El Khaleq, Lecturer</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Beni-suef University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sameh Galal Taher, Lecturer</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>RIO</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Institute of Ophthalmomogy</name>
      <address>
        <city>Giza</city>
        <state>El Haram</state>
        <zip>12556</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Clifford L, Roos J, Dahlmann-Noor A, Vivian AJ. Surgical management of superior oblique paresis using inferior oblique anterior transposition. J AAPOS. 2015 Oct;19(5):406-9. doi: 10.1016/j.jaapos.2015.07.280.</citation>
    <PMID>26486020</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chang MY, Coleman AL, Tseng VL, Demer JL. Surgical interventions for vertical strabismus in superior oblique palsy. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017 Nov 27;11:CD012447. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD012447.pub2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29178265</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Merino PS, Rojas PL, Gómez De Liaño PS, Fukumitsu HM, Yáñez JM. Bilateral superior oblique palsy: etiology and therapeutic options. Eur J Ophthalmol. 2014 Mar-Apr;24(2):147-52. doi: 10.5301/ejo.5000362. Epub 2013 Sep 5.</citation>
    <PMID>24030536</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Li Y, Zhao K. Superior oblique tucking for treatment of superior oblique palsy. J Pediatr Ophthalmol Strabismus. 2014 Jul 1;51(4):249-54. doi: 10.3928/01913913-20140527-01. Epub 2014 Jun 3.</citation>
    <PMID>24893352</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Özkan SB, Akyuz Unsal AI, Kagnici DB. The efficacy of superior rectus recession with simultaneous inferior oblique disinsertion on superior oblique palsy with superior rectus contracture. Strabismus. 2019 Mar;27(1):16-23. doi: 10.1080/09273972.2018.1553986. Epub 2018 Dec 7.</citation>
    <PMID>30522394</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bahl RS, Marcotty A, Rychwalski PJ, Traboulsi EI. Comparison of inferior oblique myectomy to recession for the treatment of superior oblique palsy. Br J Ophthalmol. 2013 Feb;97(2):184-8. doi: 10.1136/bjophthalmol-2012-301485. Epub 2012 Nov 30.</citation>
    <PMID>23203704</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shipman T, Burke J. Unilateral inferior oblique muscle myectomy and recession in the treatment of inferior oblique muscle overaction: a longitudinal study. Eye (Lond). 2003 Nov;17(9):1013-8.</citation>
    <PMID>14704751</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Saxena R, Sharma M, Singh D, Sharma P. Anterior and nasal transposition of inferior oblique muscle in cases of superior oblique palsy. J AAPOS. 2017 Aug;21(4):282-285. doi: 10.1016/j.jaapos.2017.05.026. Epub 2017 Jul 14.</citation>
    <PMID>28713055</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ozsoy E, Gunduz A, Ozturk E. Inferior Oblique Muscle Overaction: Clinical Features and Surgical Management. J Ophthalmol. 2019 Jul 17;2019:9713189. doi: 10.1155/2019/9713189. eCollection 2019.</citation>
    <PMID>31396413</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>myectomy</keyword>
  <keyword>superior oblique palsy</keyword>
  <keyword>inferior oblique overaction</keyword>
  <keyword>anterior nasal transposition</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Paralysis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

