<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05120271</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>B1030-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05120271</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>BOXR1030 T Cells in Subjects With Advanced GPC3-Positive Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>A First-in-Human, Phase 1/2, Dose Escalation Study of BOXR1030 T Cells in Subjects With Advanced GPC3-Positive Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>SOTIO, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>SOTIO Biotech</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>SOTIO Biotech</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a first-in-human (FIH), Phase 1, open-label, multicenter study to assess safety and&#xD;
      determine the recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D) of BOXR1030 administration after&#xD;
      lymphodepleting chemotherapy (LD chemotherapy) in subjects with glypican-3 positive (GPC3+)&#xD;
      advanced solid tumors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a first-in-human (FIH), Phase 1, open-label, multicenter study to assess safety and&#xD;
      determine the recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D) of BOXR1030 administration after&#xD;
      lymphodepleting chemotherapy (LD chemotherapy) in subjects with glypican-3 positive (GPC3+)&#xD;
      advanced solid tumors. Refer to the Study Schema for a diagram of the study flow. After&#xD;
      signing informed consent and completing all screening assessments, eligible subjects will&#xD;
      undergo leukapheresis to obtain T cells for BOXR1030 manufacturing. Subjects will receive a&#xD;
      7-day LD chemotherapy regimen with fludarabine and cyclophosphamide, administered according&#xD;
      to institutional standard practice for these drugs at this dosage, including inpatient&#xD;
      administration as appropriate. Subjects must be hospitalized for BOXR1030 administration and&#xD;
      will remain hospitalized for 10 days after the infusion. If at least 2 cohorts complete the&#xD;
      dose-limiting toxicity (DLT) assessment period with no DLTs and no severe/delayed events of&#xD;
      cytokine release syndrome (CRS) or immune effector cell-associated neurotoxicity syndrome&#xD;
      (ICANS), the Sponsor may allow subjects in subsequent cohorts to be discharged earlier, with&#xD;
      daily follow-up clinic visits. For 28 days after BOXR1030 administration, all subjects must&#xD;
      stay within a distance that requires no more than 2 hours of travel to the study site. During&#xD;
      the Post-treatment Evaluation Period (6 months after BOXR1030 administration), study visits&#xD;
      will occur daily for the first week, twice in the second week, and then at Weeks 3, 4, 6, and&#xD;
      Months 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6. Safety (targeted physical examination, adverse event assessment,&#xD;
      and clinical labs) will be evaluated and samples will be collected for endpoint analyses. For&#xD;
      28 days after BOXR1030 administration, subjects will be required to monitor their temperature&#xD;
      and complete neurological evaluation via the immune effector cell-associated encephalopathy&#xD;
      (ICE) assessment tool every day (to be administered by a caregiver at home on non-clinic&#xD;
      days). At regular intervals, antitumor activity will be assessed per RECIST Version 1.1 and&#xD;
      iRECIST criteria. After 6 months of follow-up from BOXR1030 administration, subjects will&#xD;
      enter the Long-term Follow-up Period for a total duration of 15 years after BOXR1030 dosing.&#xD;
      Study visits are scheduled every 3 months from Month 9 to Month 24, every 6 months thereafter&#xD;
      until Year 5, and then annually through Year 15. Long-term follow-up assessments will focus&#xD;
      on long-term safety and disease status.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2039</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose limiting toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Safety</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Tolerability evaluation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment emergent adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence rate</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse event of special interest</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence rate</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Efficacy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">98</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Lung</condition>
  <condition>Merkel Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Liposarcoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>GPC3 positive solid tumors</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>One time i.v. administration of BOXR1030 after completion of cyclophosphamide and fludarabine lymphodepleting chemotherapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CAR-GPC3 T Cells</intervention_name>
    <description>Three dose levels each with lymphodepleting chemotherapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>GPC3 positive solid tumors</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BOXR1030</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Aged 18 to 80 years at time of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able to provide a recent tumor specimen taken since the time of the subject's most&#xD;
             recent systemic anticancer therapy, for GPC3 expression assessment by IHC.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Histologically confirmed advanced unresectable or metastatic hepatocellular carcinoma&#xD;
             (HCC), squamous cell carcinoma (SCC) of the lung, liposarcoma, or Merkel cell&#xD;
             carcinoma (MCC) with GPC3 overexpression by IHC. Subjects must consent to IHC testing&#xD;
             in a separate informed consent. Note: Tumor samples will be sent to a central&#xD;
             laboratory for GPC3 expression analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Documentation of disease progression or refractory disease or intolerance to prior&#xD;
             lines of standard-of-care (SOC) therapies. Patients with tumors with genetic&#xD;
             alterations and mutations (eg, breast cancer gene [BRCA], epidermal growth factor&#xD;
             receptor [EGFR] mutations, and anaplastic lymphoma kinase [ALK] translocation) who&#xD;
             have approved targeted therapies available for their cancer will need to have been&#xD;
             treated with such approved therapies or refused such approved targeted therapy for&#xD;
             their cancer prior to enrolling in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Life expectancy &gt;16 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Have adequate organ/renal function&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) ≥50% by multiple-gated acquisition (MUGA)&#xD;
             scan or echocardiogram (ECHO)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Eastern Cooperative Group performance status of 0 to 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. For subjects with HCC:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Child-Pugh Score of A&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No fibrolamellar carcinoma or mixed hepatocellular cholangiocarcinoma histology&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No moderate or severe ascites&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. A minimum of 2 sites of disease, including at least 1 site that is measurable by&#xD;
             RECIST Version 1.1 criteria to ensure sufficient disease for response assessment. At&#xD;
             least 1 of the other lesions must be considered adequate for protocol-required tumor&#xD;
             biopsy. Consider prioritization of percutaneous lesions that are palpable, or guided&#xD;
             by imaging if necessary, and exclude biopsies of any lesions that are in proximity to&#xD;
             vital visceral, cardio-pulmonary, or any neurovascular structures. A single site of&#xD;
             disease is considered adequate to allow for response assessment and protocol-required&#xD;
             tumor biopsies if it measures at least 2 cm in the shortest axis).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Adequate wash-out of prior systemic therapy for underlying malignancy, relative to&#xD;
             leukapheresis:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Last dose of any antineoplastic treatment must be at least 2 weeks before&#xD;
                  leukapheresis.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Last dose of any investigational agent must be at least 3 half-lives of the&#xD;
                  treatment, or 28 days, before leukapheresis (whichever is shorter). Adequate&#xD;
                  wash-out of prior systemic therapy for underlying malignancy, relative to LD&#xD;
                  chemotherapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The last dose of systemic nitrosourea or systemic mitomycin-C must be at least 6&#xD;
                  weeks before the first dose of LD chemotherapy in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  For all other for systemic cytotoxic chemotherapy, the wash-out must be the&#xD;
                  duration of a full cycle of that therapy. For example, if the prior therapy is&#xD;
                  given in 3-week cycles, there must be at least 3 weeks between the last dose of&#xD;
                  that therapy and the first dose of LD chemotherapy in this study. If the prior&#xD;
                  therapy is administered more frequently than every 2 weeks, a minimum 2-week&#xD;
                  wash-out is required.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  For biologic therapy (eg, antibodies) the wash-out must be either the duration of&#xD;
                  the biologic agent dosing interval, or 3 weeks, whichever is shorter.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  For small molecule therapies, the wash-out must be 5 half-lives of the drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  For any investigational agent, the wash-out must be 3 half-lives of the&#xD;
                  investigational agent, or 4 weeks, whichever is shorter.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note: Local radiation of lesions is allowed if indicated for palliation; locally&#xD;
             treated lesions will be considered non-target lesions. Hormone ablation is also&#xD;
             allowed as clinically indicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subjects or their legally acceptable representative must be able and willing to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Provide IRB/IEC-approved written informed consent in accordance with regulatory&#xD;
                  and institutional guidelines. This must be obtained before the performance of any&#xD;
                  protocol related procedures that are not part of normal patient care.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Comply with the study protocol and with the planned biopsy procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Willing and able to commit to study assessments and visit schedule, including&#xD;
             availability of a caregiver to conduct daily neurological assessments for 28 days&#xD;
             after BOXR1030 administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. For women of childbearing potential (defined as physiologically capable of becoming&#xD;
             pregnant), confirmation of a negative serum pregnancy test and agreement to use of&#xD;
             highly effective contraception per Clinical Trials Facilitation and Coordination Group&#xD;
             (CTFG) criteria from screening through the first 12 months after BOXR1030&#xD;
             administration. For men with partners of childbearing potential, agreement to use&#xD;
             effective barrier contraception from screening through the first 12 months after&#xD;
             BOXR1030 administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Prior treatment with adoptive cell therapy (eg, CAR T-cell therapy, natural killer&#xD;
             cell therapy, engineered T-cell receptor therapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of allogenic hematopoietic stem cell transplant (HSCT).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Untreated central nervous system (CNS) tumors or brain metastasis. Patients are&#xD;
             eligible if CNS metastases are asymptomatic and have been treated and patients have&#xD;
             neurologically returned to baseline (residual signs or symptoms related to the CNS&#xD;
             treatment are permitted). Imaging obtained for the purpose of CNS metastases&#xD;
             management performed within 28 days prior to Day 1 must document radiographic&#xD;
             stability of CNS lesions and be performed after completion of any CNS directed&#xD;
             therapy. CNS evaluation for asymptomatic patients is not required for the study.&#xD;
             Patients with leptomeningeal metastases are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients who have not recovered to ≤ Grade 1 or baseline from all AEs due to previous&#xD;
             therapies (patients with ≤ Grade 2 neuropathy that has been stable for at least 4&#xD;
             weeks or ≤ Grade 2 endocrine-related AEs that has been stable for at least 4 weeks on&#xD;
             replacement therapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Planned use of any antineoplastic treatment or investigational agent from the time of&#xD;
             the first dose of LD chemotherapy through the end of study participation, except for&#xD;
             allowed local radiation of lesions for palliation (to be considered non-target lesions&#xD;
             after treatment) and hormone ablation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Uncontrolled or life-threatening symptomatic concomitant disease including clinically&#xD;
             significant gastrointestinal bleeding or pulmonary hemorrhage within 4 weeks before&#xD;
             screening, known symptomatic human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) positive with an&#xD;
             acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS)-defining opportunistic infection within the&#xD;
             last year, or a current CD4 count &lt;350 cells/uL, symptomatic active hepatitis B or C&#xD;
             checked at screening, or active tuberculosis. Patients with HIV are eligible if:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  They have received antiretroviral therapy (ART) as clinically indicated for at&#xD;
                  least 4 weeks prior to starting study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  They continue on ART as clinically indicated while enrolled on study&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CD4 counts and viral load are monitored per standard of care by a local health&#xD;
                  care provider&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Has undergone a major surgery within 3 weeks of starting study treatment or has&#xD;
             inadequate healing or recovery from complications of surgery prior to starting study&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Has received prior radiotherapy within 2 weeks of start of study treatment. Subjects&#xD;
             must have recovered from all radiation-related toxicities, not require&#xD;
             corticosteroids, and not have had severe radiation pneumonitis. A 1-week wash-out is&#xD;
             permitted for palliative radiation (≤2 weeks of radiotherapy) to non-CNS disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Potentially life-threatening second malignancy requiring systemic treatment within the&#xD;
             last 3 years (ie, patients with a history of prior malignancy are eligible if&#xD;
             treatment was completed at least 3 years before entering the Treatment Period and the&#xD;
             patient has no evidence of disease) or which would impede evaluation of treatment&#xD;
             response. Hormone ablation therapy is allowed within the last 3 years. Patients with&#xD;
             history of prior early stage basal/squamous cell skin cancer or non-invasive or in&#xD;
             situ cancers that have undergone definitive treatment at any time are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Clinically significant (ie, active) cardiovascular disease: cerebral vascular&#xD;
             accident/stroke (&lt;6 months prior to enrollment), myocardial infarction (&lt;6 months&#xD;
             prior to enrollment), unstable angina, congestive heart failure (≥ New York Heart&#xD;
             Association Classification Class II), or the presence of any condition that can&#xD;
             increase proarrhythmic risk (eg, hypokalemia, bradycardia, heart block) including any&#xD;
             new, unstable, or serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring medication, or other baseline&#xD;
             arrhythmia that might interfere with interpretation of electrocardiograms (ECGs) on&#xD;
             study (eg, bundle branch block). Patients with QTcF &gt;450 msec for males and &gt;470 msec&#xD;
             for females on screening ECG are excluded. Any patients with a bundle branch block&#xD;
             will be excluded with QTcF &gt;450 msec. Males who are on stable doses of concomitant&#xD;
             medication with known prolongation of QTcF (eg, selective serotonin re-uptake&#xD;
             inhibitor antidepressants) will only be excluded for QTcF &gt;470 msec.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Has an active infection requiring systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. A woman of child-bearing potential (WOCBP) who has a positive pregnancy test prior to&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Is breastfeeding or expecting to conceive or father children within the projected&#xD;
             duration of the study, starting with the Screening Visit through 6 months after the&#xD;
             last dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Unable to receive any of the agents used in this study due to history of severe&#xD;
             immediate hypersensitivity reaction (eg, hypersensitivity to dimethyl sulfoxide&#xD;
             [DMSO]).&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Known allergy or contraindication to any of the LD chemotherapy or prophylaxis&#xD;
             medications required during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Any other significant co-morbid disease or condition which, in the judgment of the&#xD;
             Investigator, would put the subject at undue risk (eg, cirrhotic liver disease).&#xD;
&#xD;
             -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Glen J Weiss, MD, MBA</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>SOTIO, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rachael Alvarado</last_name>
    <phone>617-904-7600</phone>
    <email>alvarado@sotio.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Merkel Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liposarcoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

