<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05124587</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021.su</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05124587</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prediction for Critical Outcomes of Patients With COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Development and External Validation of a Prediction Model for Critical Outcomes of Patients With Confirmed COVID-19 in the Hospital Setting Based on Demographic Characteristics, Medical Conditions and Oral Health</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Academic Centre for Dentistry in Amsterdam</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Academic Centre for Dentistry Amsterdam (ACTA)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Amsterdam Medical Center (AMC)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Academic Centre for Dentistry in Amsterdam</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study aims to develop and externally validate a prediction model for the critical&#xD;
      outcomes of COVID-19 patients using predictors which can be easily obtained in clinical&#xD;
      practice, including patients' demographic characteristics, self-reported medical conditions,&#xD;
      and oral health.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background The novel coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic has presented an important&#xD;
      and urgent threat to global health since its outbreak in December 2019. The COVID-19 does not&#xD;
      only affect the respiratory tract, but also other organs in human body including lungs,&#xD;
      liver, kidney, heart, vessels, and other organs (1). Respiratory failure and acute&#xD;
      respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) are the most common serious complications of COVID-19&#xD;
      infection (2). The crude mortality rates (CMRs) of COVID-19 varies in different locations,&#xD;
      which ranges from 37.0/100,000 to 167.6/100,000 in several European countries up to 30th&#xD;
      August 2020 (3). The in-hospital mortality of COVID-19 was reported to be 17.1% based on 33&#xD;
      studies from 13,398 patients (4), and it was 2.9 times higher than that of influenza based on&#xD;
      the French national administrative database (5). It was reported that 26% of the COVID-19&#xD;
      patients admitted to ICU with severe status and 31% of the patients who admitted to ICU died&#xD;
      based on 37 studies from 24,983 patients (6).&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are several risk factors on patients' demographic characteristics and underlying&#xD;
      medical conditions which were shown be associated with the critical outcomes of COVID-19 (7).&#xD;
      In addition, poor oral health, in particular periodontitis, was also shown to be associated&#xD;
      with the critical outcomes of COVID-19 (8). Marouf et al. showed that COVID-19 patients with&#xD;
      periodontitis had 8 times higher odds of death and 3.5 times higher odds of ICU admission&#xD;
      than those without periodontitis based on a case-control study (9). This may be because&#xD;
      periodontal disease could enhance cytokine release via altered microflora, expression of&#xD;
      multiple viral receptors, bacterial superinfection, and aspiration of periodontal pathogens&#xD;
      (10). The increased production of pro-inflammatory cytokine, which is referred to as cytokine&#xD;
      storm, is the foremost cause of the adverse events of COVID-19 (10).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Because of the high contagiousness, high ICU admission rate, and high mortality of COVID-19,&#xD;
      it has led to tremendous increases in the demand for hospital beds and shortage of medical&#xD;
      equipment. Therefore, there is an urgent need for a pragmatic risk stratification tool that&#xD;
      allows the early identification of the COVID-19 patients who are likely to be at highest risk&#xD;
      of ICU admission and death (11). This can help clinicians and policymakers make the decisions&#xD;
      on the management and optimize resource allocation. A recent review identified multiple&#xD;
      prediction models which have been developed for prediction of prognosis of COVID-19 patients&#xD;
      (12). Those prediction models varied in their predictors and performance of the models. A&#xD;
      large number of prediction models reflected difficulties in their application in the rapid&#xD;
      risk stratification for general COVID-19 patients at their first intake in hospitals because&#xD;
      some predictors cannot be easily obtained without professional devices or lab tests, such as&#xD;
      C reactive protein, peripheral oxygen saturation, and urea level. Many prediction models&#xD;
      showed moderate performance in aspects of discrimination and calibration, and no benefit to&#xD;
      clinical decision making (12). In addition, the dental variables were not considered the&#xD;
      potential predictors in the previously developed models.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, the aim of the present study is to develop and externally validate a prediction&#xD;
      model for the critical outcomes of COVID-19 patients using predictors which can be easily&#xD;
      obtained in clinical practice, including patients' demographic characteristics, self-reported&#xD;
      medical conditions, and oral health.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials and Methods Participants We include hospitalized patients and outpatients from the&#xD;
      Isala Hospital (Zwolle, the Netherlands) with confirmed COVID-19 who visited the Department&#xD;
      of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery (OMFS) between March 2020 and May 2021, if they have had a&#xD;
      dental panoramic radiograph (OPG), obtained up to a maximum of 5 years until the end of the&#xD;
      current study. The patients are used to develop the prediction model (derivation cohort).&#xD;
&#xD;
      We also include the hospitalized patients and outpatients from Noordwest Ziekenhuis (NWZ)&#xD;
      (Alkmaar, the Netherlands) with confirmed COVID-19 to externally validate the prediction&#xD;
      model (validation cohort).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential predictors&#xD;
&#xD;
      The potential predictors include patients' demographic characteristics, self-reported medical&#xD;
      conditions, and oral health. All the potential predictors are collected at baseline. The&#xD;
      potential predictors are presented below:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Demographic characteristics&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Gender&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Age&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  BMI&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Smoking&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hypercholesterolemia&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  COPD&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  CVD&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Chronic kidney disease&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  OSAS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dental variables (based on OPG)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Number of teeth&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Number of dental implants&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome (endpoint) The endpoint of the study is the presence or absence of the critical&#xD;
      outcomes of COVID-19 (dichotomized). The course and outcome of the COVID-19 is classified&#xD;
      into (1) ambulatory; (2) hospitalized; (3) ICU admission or death based on the WHO Clinical&#xD;
      Progression Scale (13). In the study, the critical outcomes are defined as ICU admission or&#xD;
      death, while the non-critical outcomes are defined that patients are ambulatory or&#xD;
      hospitalized without ICU admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis The prediction modes will be developed and externally validated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      References&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Wang X, Fang X, Cai Z, et al. Comorbid Chronic Diseases and Acute Organ Injuries Are&#xD;
           Strongly Correlated with Disease Severity and Mortality among COVID-19 Patients: A&#xD;
           Systemic Review and Meta-Analysis. Research (Wash D C) 2020; 2402961.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. SeyedAlinaghi S, Afsahi AM, MohsseniPour M, et al. Late Complications of COVID-19; a&#xD;
           Systematic Review of Current Evidence. Arch Acad Emerg Med 2021; 9: e14.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Villani L, McKee M, Cascini F, et al. Comparison of deaths rates for COVID-19 across&#xD;
           Europe during the first wave of the COVID-19 pandemic. Front Public Health 2020; 8:&#xD;
           620416.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Macedo A, Gonçalves N, Febra C. COVID-19 fatality rates in hospitalized patients:&#xD;
           systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Epidemiol 2021; 57: 14-21.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Piroth L, Cottenet J, Mariet AS, et al. Comparison of the characteristics, morbidity,&#xD;
           and mortality of COVID-19 and seasonal influenza: a nationwide, population-based&#xD;
           retrospective cohort study. Lancet Respir Med 2021; 9: 251-259.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Abate SM, Ali SA, Mantfardo B, et al. Rate of intensive care unit admission and outcomes&#xD;
           among patients with coronavirus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One 2020;&#xD;
           15: e0235653.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Kim HJ, Hwang H, Hong H, et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of regional risk&#xD;
           factors for critical outcomes of COVID-19 during early phase of the pandemic. Sci Rep&#xD;
           2021; 11: 9784.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Botros N, Iyer P, Ojcius DM. Is there an association between oral health and severity of&#xD;
           COVID-19 complications? Biomed J 2020; 43: 325-327.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Marouf N, Cai W, Said KN, et al. Association between periodontitis and severity of&#xD;
           COVID-19 infection: a case-control study. J Clin Periodontol 2021; 48: 483-491.&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Sukumar K, Tadepalli A. Nexus between COVID-19 and periodontal disease. J Int Med Res&#xD;
           2021; 49: 3000605211002695.&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Knight SR, Ho A, Pius R, et al. Risk stratification of patients admitted to hospital&#xD;
           with covid-19 using the ISARIC WHO Clinical characterization protocol: development and&#xD;
           validation of the 4C mortality score. BMJ 2020; 370: m3339.&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Wynants L, Calster BV, Collins GS, et al. Prediction models for diagnosis and prognosis&#xD;
           of covid-19: systematic review and critical appraisal. BMJ 2020; 369: m1328.&#xD;
&#xD;
       13. WHO Working Group on the Clinical Characterisation and Management of COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
           A minimal common outcome measure set for COVID-19 clinical research. Lancet Infect Dis&#xD;
           2020; 20: e192-e197.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Critical outcomes of COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>March 2020 and May 2021</time_frame>
    <description>The critical outcomes include death, and ICU admission</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Prediction Model</condition>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <condition>Oral Health</condition>
  <condition>External Validation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with confirmed COVID-19 in the hospital setting</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No intervention group</intervention_name>
    <description>No intervention group</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with confirmed COVID-19 in the hospital setting</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The patients were diagnosed as COVID-19 from the Isala Hospital (Zwolle, the Netherlands)&#xD;
        or from Noordwest Ziekenhuis (NWZ) (Alkmaar, the Netherlands).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who had a diagnosis of COVID-19 in the hospitals who visited the Department&#xD;
             of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery (OMFS) between March 2020 and May 2021, if they have&#xD;
             had a dental panoramic radiograph (OPG), obtained up to a maximum of 5 years until the&#xD;
             end of the current study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Noordwest Ziekenhuis (NWZ)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Alkmaar</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Isala Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Zwolle</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 17, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Academic Centre for Dentistry in Amsterdam</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Naichuan Su</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

