<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05123391</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>210406002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05123391</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Randomized Pilot Study of Radiosurgery for the Treatment of Non-metastatic Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Technical Feasibility of a Randomized Pilot Study of Radiosurgery for the Treatment of Non-metastatic Prostate Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pontificia Universidad Catolica de Chile</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pontificia Universidad Catolica de Chile</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, interventional pilot study to evaluate the feasibility of randomizing&#xD;
      patients diagnosed with prostate cancer to different treatment schemes according to their&#xD;
      risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with a diagnosis of prostate adenocarcinoma (confirmed by biopsy), without signs of&#xD;
      metastasis outside the pelvis in the staging study and without prior radiotherapy (RT) to the&#xD;
      pelvic region will be recruited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The definition of risk group from the international guide National Comprehensive Cancer&#xD;
      Network will be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Low risk&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Favorable intermediate risk&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Unfavorable intermediate risk&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  High risk The use of hormonal blocking will be at the discretion of each treating&#xD;
           physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The radiotherapy simulation will be carried out according to the institutional protocol for&#xD;
      the treatment of prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to the risk group of the patients, the following randomization will be carried out:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Low / intermediate favorable risk: Patients will be randomized to receive SBRT to&#xD;
           prostate 36.25 Gy in 5 fractions, alternate days or weekly, with VMAT (technique and 6&#xD;
           Mega-voltage (MV) X-rays vs to SBRT to prostate 26 Gy in 2 fractions, 1 weekly fraction,&#xD;
           with VMAT technique and 6 Mv X-rays. The volumes to be treated, ¨Clinical target volume¨&#xD;
           (CTV) will be defined as the prostate, according to the consensus of the Radiation&#xD;
           Therapy Oncology Group (RTOG).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Intermediate unfavorable risk and high risk: Patients will be randomized to receive SBRT&#xD;
           to the prostate and seminal vesicles, 36.25 Gy in 5 fractions, alternate days or weekly,&#xD;
           with VMAT technique and 6 MV X-rays vs SBRT to pelvis scheme of 25 Gy in 5 fractions&#xD;
           with simultaneous integrated boost up to 36.25 to the prostate and seminal vesicles,&#xD;
           with the same technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with positive pelvic node: Will be randomized to moderate hypofractionated RT ,&#xD;
           completing a dose of 44 Gy in 20 fractions to the pelvis with a simultaneous integrated&#xD;
           boost up to 54-60 Gy in 20 fractions to metastatic lymphadenopathy and prostate with&#xD;
           seminal vesicles, completing 60 Gy to prostate and seminal vesicles or to ultra&#xD;
           hypofractionated RT to the prostate and macroscopic lymphadenopathy to 35 and 30-35 Gy&#xD;
           respectively and 25 Gy in 5 fractions to the elective nodal areas.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prostate cancer is the most common non-cutaneous neoplasm in men both worldwide and in Chile,&#xD;
      being the third cause of death in our country. Radiation therapy (RT) is a well-validated&#xD;
      curative treatment alternative for prostate cancer, generally being combined with androgen&#xD;
      deprivation therapy in intermediate and high risk patients. Dose escalation of RT improves&#xD;
      event-free survival and the need for new therapies in the future (continuous androgen&#xD;
      deprivation). This dose escalation strategy involves long-term treatments (7 to 8 weeks) with&#xD;
      high operational cost for the patient (stays, transportation, etc.) and radiotherapy&#xD;
      services.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypofractionated RT (reduction of treatment fractions) has shown a similar safety profile and&#xD;
      oncological results equivalent to dose escalation in several phase III studies, allowing the&#xD;
      total treatment time to be reduced to 4-5 weeks and thus be a more convenient treatment for&#xD;
      patients and the radiotherapy department. In the same way, radiosurgery or stereotaxic body&#xD;
      radiotherapy (SBRT), is a highly conformed RT technique that significantly reduces the total&#xD;
      treatment time (1-2 weeks of treatment). In recent years, the safety and efficacy of SBRT in&#xD;
      low- and intermediate-risk prostate cancer has been proven in phase III studies; and in&#xD;
      high-risk patients, its low toxicity profile and good biochemical control have been&#xD;
      demonstrated in a systematic review. Since this radiotherapy technique has recently been&#xD;
      introduced into clinical practice, there are different approaches in relation to the number&#xD;
      of fractions used and volumes to be treated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A pilot study was designed to evaluate the technical feasibility of implementing the&#xD;
      randomization of patients who are candidates for radiosurgery between schemes previously used&#xD;
      in the literature according to their risk and stage: 2 vs 5 fractions in low / intermediate&#xD;
      risk patients include or not pelvic treatment in high-risk patients and a moderate&#xD;
      hypofractionated treatment regimen of 20 vs 5 fractions in cN1 or higher patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a prospective, interventional pilot study to evaluate the feasibility of randomizing&#xD;
      patients diagnosed with prostate cancer to different treatment schemes according to their&#xD;
      risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with a diagnosis of prostate adenocarcinoma (confirmed by biopsy), without signs of&#xD;
      metastasis outside the pelvis in the staging study and without prior RT to the pelvic region&#xD;
      will be recruited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The definition of risk group from the international guide National Comprehensive Cancer&#xD;
      Network will be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Low risk&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Favorable intermediate risk&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Unfavorable intermediate risk&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  High risk&#xD;
&#xD;
      The use of hormonal blocking will be at the discretion of each treating physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The radiotherapy simulation will be carried out according to the institutional protocol for&#xD;
      the treatment of prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to the risk group of the patients, the following randomization will be carried out:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Low / intermediate favorable risk: Patients will be randomized to receive SBRT to&#xD;
           prostate 36.25 Gy in 5 fractions, alternate days or weekly, with Volumetric modulated&#xD;
           arc therapy technique (VMAT) and 6 Mv X-rays vs to SBRT to prostate 26 Gy in 2&#xD;
           fractions, 1 weekly fraction, with VMAT technique and 6 Mv X-rays. The volumes to be&#xD;
           treated, ¨clinical target volume¨ (CTV) will be defined as the prostate, according to&#xD;
           the consensus of the RTOG.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Intermediate unfavorable risk and high risk: Patients will be randomized to receive SBRT&#xD;
           to the prostate and seminal vesicles, 36.25 Gy in 5 fractions, alternate days or weekly,&#xD;
           with VMAT technique and 6 Megavolts MV X-rays vs SBRT to pelvis scheme of 25 Gy in 5&#xD;
           fractions with simultaneous integrated boost up to 36.25 to the prostate and seminal&#xD;
           vesicles, with the same technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with positive regional pelvic nodes: Patients will be randomized to moderate&#xD;
           hypofractionated RT, completing a dose of 44 Gy in 20 fractions to the pelvis with a&#xD;
           simultaneous integrated boost up to 54-60 Gy in 20 fractions to metastatic&#xD;
           lymphadenopathy and prostate with seminal vesicles, completing 60 Gy to prostate and&#xD;
           seminal vesicles or to ultra-hypofractionated RT to the prostate and macroscopic&#xD;
           lymphadenopathy to 35 and 30-35 Gy respectively and 25 Gy in 5 fractions to the elective&#xD;
           nodal areas.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Contouring of the prostate, seminal vesicles and pelvis will be performed according to the&#xD;
      consensus of the NRG Oncology Group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The treatment will be delivered at the Radiotherapy Service of the Cancer Center, in the a&#xD;
      linear accelerator unit with daily verification images.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before starting treatment and during follow ups urinary symptoms will be assessed by the&#xD;
      International Prostate Symptom Score (IPSS) scale, and the The National Cancer Institute&#xD;
      Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) and quality of life with &quot;The Expanded&#xD;
      Prostate Cancer Index Composite &quot;v2.0 (EPIC 2.0), and the European Organisation for Research&#xD;
      and Treatment of Cancer (EORTC) quality of life questionnaire-30 (QLQ-30 and QLQ-PR25). The&#xD;
      patient will be monitored weekly during the delivery of radiation therapy to assess acute&#xD;
      toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The last day of radiotherapy will be counted as day zero, and the patient will be monitored&#xD;
      after 30 days, then every 6 months with IPSS, CTCAE, EPIC, QLQ-30, QLQ-PR25 and prostate&#xD;
      specific antigen (PSA) according to the follow-up protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A randomization feasibility trial was designed for each of the 3 groups of patients, assigned&#xD;
      1: 1 for different interventions in each group. The CONSORT recommendations and the Lewis et&#xD;
      al method were followed to calculate the sample size and define the feasibility objectives,&#xD;
      respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three key objectives were defined to assess the feasibility of the trial: recruitment&#xD;
      acceptance (Percentages of selected patients recruited), treatment fidelity, and patient&#xD;
      retention (follow-up). An exact 1-tailed binomial test was used with 5% significance and 80%&#xD;
      power.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The feasibility criteria will correspond to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Recruitment: At least 80% (green indicator) of eligible patients must be recruited, the&#xD;
           trial will not be feasible if recruitment uptake is less than or equal to 40% (red&#xD;
           indicator).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Treatment fidelity: A high level of treatment fidelity is required with 80% or more&#xD;
           (green indicator) of patients receiving the treatment plan without major protocol&#xD;
           deviations, if less than 40% of patients comply with this indicator (red indicator) the&#xD;
           test will not be feasible.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Follow-up: At least 80% (green indicator) of the patients must remain in follow-up to&#xD;
           meet feasibility, if 40% or less (red indicator) comply with retention, the trial will&#xD;
           not be feasible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For this feasibility study a sample size of 30 patients is calculated (5 for each branch of&#xD;
      the protocol).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This sample size calculation and feasibility criteria will be used for each of the 3 groups&#xD;
      of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the case an indicator in the red zone the study will stop, in the case all the indicators&#xD;
      are in green, a follow up study will be carried out, in the case any indicator is yellow&#xD;
      (between 80% and 40%), the pertinent corrections will be made to proceed to a further study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 22, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 22, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 22, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recruitment</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of screened patients eligible recruited</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment protocol fidelity</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of recruited patients receiving treatment according to protocol</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Follow up</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of recruited patients effectively followed according to protocol</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Biochemical control</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Failure defined according Phoenix definition (rise by 2 ng/mL or more above the nadir PSA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline In Quality Of Life (QoL) Total Score As Assessed By The Global Health Domain Of The European Organization Of Research And Treatment Of Cancer (EORTC)-Quality Of Life Questionnaire (QLQ)-C30</measure>
    <time_frame>6,12 and 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>The EORTC QLQ-C30 core measurement was used to capture distal outcomes, including physical, social functioning, and overall health-related quality of life. The questionnaire incorporates 30 questions comprising nine multi-item scales: 5 functional scales (physical, role, cognitive, emotional, and social); 3 symptom scales (fatigue, pain, and nausea and vomiting); and a global health and quality of life scale. All raw domain scores are linearly transformed to a 0-100 scale. The global health and quality of life domain is presented. An increase in activity or functioning scores indicates improvement (higher/healthier level of functioning) and a decrease in symptom scores indicates improvement (lower level of symptoms/problems)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline In QoL Total Score As Assessed By The EORTC-QLQ-PR25 Sexual Activity And Functioning And Hormonal-Treatment-Related Symptom Subdomains.</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 12 and 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Subscales for assessment of hormonal treatment-related symptoms (6 items) and sexual activity and function (6 items) from the EORTC-QLQ-PR25 25-item prostate cancer module of the EORTC are presented. Questions used 4 point scale (1 'Not at all' to 4 'Very much'). All raw domain scores are linearly transformed to a 0-100 scale. An increase in activity or functioning scores indicates improvement (higher/healthier level of functioning) and a decrease in symptom scores indicates improvement (lower level of symptoms/problems).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostatic Neoplasms</condition>
  <condition>Radiosurgery</condition>
  <condition>Quality of Life</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Low-Intermediate favorable risk 5 Fraction SBRT arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>36.25 Gy in 5 fractions to the prostate weekly or every other day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Low-Intermediate favorable risk 2 Fraction SBRT arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>26 Gy in 2 fractions to the prostate</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intermediate unfavorable-high risk prostate only SBRT arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>36.25 Gy in 5 fractions to the prostate and seminal vesicles base, weekly or every other day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intermediate unfavorable-high risk prostate and pelvis SBRT arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>25 Gy in 5 fractions to the elective pelvic nodes and simultaneous integrated boost to 36.25 Gy in 5 fractions to the prostate and seminal vesicles base, weekly</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pelvic node positive moderate hypofractionated radiotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>44 Gy in 20 daily fractions to the elective pelvic nodes and simultaneous integrated boost to 60 Gy to the prostate and seminal vesicles base and 54 Gy to positive lymph nodes</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pelvic node positive moderate ultra-hypofractionated radiotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>25 Gy in 5 fractions to the elective pelvic nodes and simultaneous integrated boost to 36.25 Gy in 5 fractions to the prostate and seminal vesicles base and to 30 Gy to positive lymph nodes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>External beam image guided radiotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Volumetric modulated arc therapy (VMAT)-Image-guided radiation therapy (IGRT)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intermediate unfavorable-high risk prostate and pelvis SBRT arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Intermediate unfavorable-high risk prostate only SBRT arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Low-Intermediate favorable risk 2 Fraction SBRT arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Low-Intermediate favorable risk 5 Fraction SBRT arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pelvic node positive moderate hypofractionated radiotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pelvic node positive moderate ultra-hypofractionated radiotherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histology confirmed prostate cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Disease confined to the pelvis by imaging CT (CT scan of chest, abdomen and pelvis and&#xD;
             bone scan or prostate specific membrane antigen positron emission tomography&#xD;
             (PET-PSMA) if required according to local guidelines)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance 0-1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eligible for curative radiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metastasis beyond the pelvis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Poor performance ECOG 2-4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cannot follow directions to prepare for simulation (bladder filling and rectal&#xD;
             emptying)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tomas Merino, MD</last_name>
    <phone>56-223543346</phone>
    <email>tmerino@med.puc.cl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pontificia Universidad Catolica de Chile</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santiago</city>
        <state>Metropolitana</state>
        <country>Chile</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tomas Merino, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+5623542000</phone>
      <phone_ext>6832</phone_ext>
      <email>tmerino@med.puc.cl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Chile</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

