<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05121506</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19GBHG</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05121506</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Investigate the Bioavailability and Skin Absorption of CBD and THC From GT4 Technology in Healthy Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Single-arm Open-label Study to Investigate the Bioavailability and Skin Absorption of CBD and THC From GT4 Technology in Healthy Adults</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Gefion Canada Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>KGK Science Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Gefion Canada Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The bioavailability of cannabinoids differs greatly for different routes of administration.&#xD;
      When applied topically to the skin, they are absorbed through the skin or hair follicles&#xD;
      while interacting with receptors to provide localized effects. To gain more information on&#xD;
      the potential of this route of administration in therapeutic applications, this open-label&#xD;
      study will investigate the skin absorption and bioavailability of CBD and THC delivered&#xD;
      trans-dermally.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The global use of cannabis for both recreational and medical purposes has deep historical&#xD;
      origins. Medicinal cannabis has traditionally been used to treat nausea, inflammation,&#xD;
      vomiting and pain. The use of cannabis is widespread, with over 147 million people worldwide&#xD;
      consuming cannabis annually ). While cannabis regulations for recreational use have&#xD;
      traditionally followed the prohibitionist model, Canadian legalization is expected to loosen&#xD;
      the barriers to access and research of its potential medicinal and therapeutic benefits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cannabidiol (CBD) and Δ9-tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) are two naturally occurring&#xD;
      phytocannabinoids found in cannabis. THC is the main psychoactive compound of cannabis and&#xD;
      gives users a distinguished &quot;high&quot; feeling, whereas CBD studies have shown it does not have&#xD;
      any mind-altering effects. Differences in molecular interactions and structural properties&#xD;
      are responsible for the varied pharmacological effects of THC and CBD. Both Δ9-THC and CBD&#xD;
      exert their effects by interacting with the receptors of the endocannabinoid system (ECS),&#xD;
      CB1 and CB2, with varying affinities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The ECS plays an integral role in regulatory functions implicated in health and disease as&#xD;
      well as in downregulating stress signals that cause pain and inflammation. Endocannabinoid&#xD;
      receptors are ubiquitous in the body, and due to their extensive presence, the ECS is&#xD;
      referred to as a 'bridge between mind and body. Cutaneously, the role of the ECS is to&#xD;
      regulate skin cell proliferation, survival, and differentiation. CB1 receptors are found&#xD;
      mainly in the brain and central nervous system and are involved in coordination, movement,&#xD;
      pain, memory and mood, whereas CB2 receptors are found mainly in peripheral organs and are&#xD;
      linked with reducing inflammation, pain and tissue damage. Differential activation of CB1 and&#xD;
      CB2 receptors, whether individually or simultaneously, could lead to varied physiological&#xD;
      effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The differences in neurological outcomes between THC and CBD may be linked to their&#xD;
      contrasting interactions with the CB1 receptor. THC is a potential partial agonist of the CB1&#xD;
      receptor, and it produces its effects through direct binding. CBD, on the other hand, is a&#xD;
      negative allosteric modulator of CB1 and it induces a conformational change to inhibit other&#xD;
      agonists from binding. The binding of CB1 receptors is also responsible for the&#xD;
      antinociceptive activity of THC, which makes it an effective analgesic agent. In addition,&#xD;
      THC has been shown to improve food intake and weight gain in wasting conditions such as&#xD;
      cancer, Crohn's disease and AIDS, as well as in the treatment of glaucoma, nausea, multiple&#xD;
      sclerosis, epilepsy and inflammation in a series of preclinical and clinical studies. CBD, on&#xD;
      the other hand, shows immense therapeutic potential without the psychoactive effects of THC.&#xD;
      It has shown promise in the treatment of anxiety, epilepsy, schizophrenia, Parkinson's&#xD;
      disease, Alzheimer's disease, multiple sclerosis and sleep management. Studies have shown&#xD;
      that CBD and THC acting together can be more potent than their individual effects. Oral&#xD;
      supplementation of THC alone is not as effective as their combination, which has been shown&#xD;
      to significantly relieve neuropathic pain. CBD can also lower the psychoactive effects of THC&#xD;
      and thus produce their combined benefits by enhancing THC tolerability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The bioavailability of cannabinoids differs immensely for different routes of administration.&#xD;
      When taken orally, CBD and THC are digested in the stomach and intestines. Further the CBD&#xD;
      and THC will undergo first-pass metabolism after digestion. When taken sublingually, they&#xD;
      bypass first-pass metabolism, which increases their bioavailabilities. When inhaled, CBD and&#xD;
      THC are immediately absorbed through the lungs resulting in a faster response and higher&#xD;
      bioavailability in comparison with oral products. When applied topically to the skin, they&#xD;
      are absorbed through the epidermis or hair follicles while interacting with receptors to&#xD;
      provide localized effects. A common route of administration for recreational purposes is&#xD;
      inhalation through smoking as it yields very high concentrations rapidly, but this is not&#xD;
      ideal due to risks such as toxicity and loss of activity through combustion. To take&#xD;
      advantage of the lungs' efficient drug delivery and avoid the harm associated with smoking,&#xD;
      inhalation can be achieved via aerosolization or vaporization. Systemically, the&#xD;
      bioavailability of inhaled CBD using these two methods has been reported to be 31%, and the&#xD;
      peak plasma concentration was reached within 10 minutes. The terminal half-life of CBD&#xD;
      following inhalation was found to be 27-35 hours, following intravenous injection it was&#xD;
      18-33 hours and following oral administration it was 2-5 days. The terminal half-life of THC&#xD;
      after inhalation was found to be 21-31 hours and following intravenous injection it was 24&#xD;
      hours. Bioavailability of oral CBD was found to be around 6%, and bioavailability for oral&#xD;
      THC was shown to be 4-12%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The pharmacokinetics of CBD and THC after transdermal administration have not been&#xD;
      extensively studied. When applied with the GT4 technology, the CBD and THC are expected to be&#xD;
      absorbed through the stratum corneum and other epidermal layers, the basement membrane and&#xD;
      into the dermis rapidly. Once in the dermis CBD and THC can enter the capillary bed aided by&#xD;
      increased blood flow and then the systemic circulation. In addition to avoiding the negative&#xD;
      effects of inhalation, transdermal administration is superior to oral ingestion as this route&#xD;
      provides a way to avoid gastrointestinal involvement and first pass metabolism. Further,&#xD;
      transdermal delivery may generate more constant plasma levels. It can also be designed for&#xD;
      targeted delivery where the IP and specific tissues within the cutaneous ECS can interact.&#xD;
      Pharmaceuticals with the GT4 technology have had over 1,000 prescriptions filled in the&#xD;
      United States to deliver 10% gabapentin and 5% naproxen sodium for treatment of severe&#xD;
      muscular skeletal pain. This technology has allowed physicians to treat severe pain without&#xD;
      or with significantly less opioids. To date, no adverse events have been reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this open-label study is to investigate the bioavailability and skin&#xD;
      absorption of CBD and THC delivered using GT4 technology in a healthy adult population.&#xD;
      Participants will be healthy men and women between the ages of 25-65 and will be occasional&#xD;
      cannabis users. They will have used cannabis at least once in the past 6 months and 4 times&#xD;
      in their lifetime but no more than 3 times per week. Participants must have experienced&#xD;
      psychotropic effects related to cannabis without having severe adverse events. In the area of&#xD;
      application, participants must not have received laser hair removal, shaved, or waxed within&#xD;
      14 days or have any acute or chronic skin diseases or dermatological conditions to avoid&#xD;
      interfering with the test product. Participants must not be using medicinal cannabis. They&#xD;
      must not be receiving any treatments that may confound results, such as prescribed&#xD;
      medications, over-the-counter medications, supplements, and food/drinks that will interact&#xD;
      with the test product or that contain CBD and THC. Based on the short half lives of CBD and&#xD;
      THC, recreational users must refrain from cannabis for 48 hours. The inclusion and exclusion&#xD;
      criteria in this study ensure a homogeneous population of participants who are healthy,&#xD;
      stable, and have no comorbidities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the curve to the last measured timepoint (AUCT) for CBD metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>The AUCT will be calculated using the trapezoid approximation. Time points assessed for AUC0-12 h: pre-dose (T = 0 h) and post-dose at 10, 20, 30, 45 min and 1, 1.5, 2, 2.5, 3, 4, 5, 6, 8 and 12 h.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the curve to the last measured timepoint (AUCT) for THC metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>The AUCT will be calculated using the trapezoid approximation. Time points assessed for AUC0-12 h: pre-dose (T = 0 h) and post-dose at 10, 20, 30, 45 min and 1, 1.5, 2, 2.5, 3, 4, 5, 6, 8 and 12 h. This parameter will be presented for each metabolite, for each study participant.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum concentration (Cmax) for CBD metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Peak concentration (Cmax) will be determined directly from the concentration-time curve.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum concentration (Cmax) for THC metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Peak concentration (Cmax) will be determined directly from the concentration-time curve.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to maximum concentration (Tmax) for CBD metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Time to peak concentration (Tmax) will be determined directly from the concentration-time curve.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to maximum concentration (Tmax) for THC metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Time to peak concentration (Tmax) will be determined directly from the concentration-time curve.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the curve to infinity (AUCI) for CBD metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>The area under the curve to infinity AUCI will be calculated by AUCT + CT/ λ, where CT is the last quantifiable concentration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the curve to infinity (AUCI) for THC metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>The area under the curve to infinity AUCI will be calculated by AUCT + CT/ λ, where CT is the last quantifiable concentration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal elimination rate constant (λ or ke) for CBD metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal disposition rate constant (λ) will be calculated as the slope of points on the terminal log-linear end of the concentration versus time curve.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal elimination rate constant (λ or ke) for THC metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal disposition rate constant (λ) will be calculated as the slope of points on the terminal log-linear end of the concentration versus time curve.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal half-life (t1/2) for CBD metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal half-life (t1/2) will be calculated as ln(2)/λ = 0.693/λ.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal half-life (t1/2) for THC metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal half-life (t1/2) will be calculated as ln(2)/λ = 0.693/λ.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absorption rate constant (ka) for CBD metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>The absorption rate constant (ka) will be calculated using the feathering method.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absorption rate constant (ka) for THC metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>The absorption rate constant (ka) will be calculated using the feathering method.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of pre-emergent and post-emergent adverse events (AEs) following a single dose of CBD and THC from GT4 technology</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period and follow-up call at 7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of pre-emergent and post-emergent adverse events will be determined to calculate the incidence. Adverse events will be recorded during the 12 h in-clinic visit and during a follow-up phone call (7 days)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Aspartate Aminotransferase at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Aspartate Aminotransferase at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Alanine Aminotransferase at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Alanine Aminotransferase at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Alkaline Phosphatase at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Alkaline Phosphatase at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Total Bilirubin at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Total Bilirubin at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Creatinine at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Creatinine at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Estimated Glomerular Filtration Rate (eGFR) at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in eGFR at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in random glucose at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in random glucose at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in sodium levels at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in sodium levels at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in potassium levels at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in potassium levels at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in chloride levels at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in chloride levels at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in White Blood Cell Count (WBC) at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in WBC at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in amount of Neutrophils at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in amount of Neutrophils at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in amount of Lymphocytes at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in amount of Lymphocytes at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in amount of Monocytes at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in amount of Monocytes at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in amount of Eosinophils at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in amount of Eosinophils at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in amount of Basophils at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in amount of Basophils at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Red Blood Cell Count (RBC) at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Red Blood Cell Count (RBC) at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hemoglobin levels at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in hemoglobin levels at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematocrit levels at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in hematocrit levels at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in platelet count at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in platelet count at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Mean Corpuscular Volume (MCV) at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in MCV at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in mean corpuscular hemoglobin (MCH) at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in MCH at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in mean corpuscular hemoglobin concentration (MCHC) at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in MCHC at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in red cell distribution width (RDW) at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Change in RDW at 12-h post dose following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC will be compared to baseline.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Psychoactive Assessment following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Psychoactive Assessment as administered at post-dose at 10, 20, 30, 45 min and 1, 1.5, 2, 2.5, 3, 4, 5, 6, 8 and 12 h.&#xD;
The &quot;Psychoactive Assessment&quot; will be administered just before each post-dose blood draw with the following questions:&#xD;
Are you experiencing a &quot;high&quot; feeling?&#xD;
On a scale of 1 (least) to 10 (most), how intense is that feeling?&#xD;
Is this &quot;high&quot; feeling (other than intensity) different than past high experiences? If yes, please describe.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the curve to the last measured timepoint (AUCT) for Cannabinol (CBN) metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>The AUCT will be calculated using the trapezoid approximation. Time points assessed for AUC0-12 h: pre-dose (T = 0 h) and post-dose at 10, 20, 30, 45 min and 1, 1.5, 2, 2.5, 3, 4, 5, 6, 8 and 12 h.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum concentration (Cmax) for Cannabinol (CBN) metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Peak concentration (Cmax) will be determined directly from the concentration-time curve.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Time to maximum concentration (Tmax) for Cannabinol (CBN) metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Time to peak concentration (Tmax) will be determined directly from the concentration-time curve.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the curve to infinity (AUCI) for Cannabinol (CBN) metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>The area under the curve to infinity AUCI will be calculated by AUCT + CT/ λ, where CT is the last quantifiable concentration.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal elimination rate constant (λ or ke) for Cannabinol (CBN) metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal disposition rate constant (λ) will be calculated as the slope of points on the terminal log-linear end of the concentration versus time curve.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal half-life (t1/2) for Cannabinol (CBN) metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal half-life (t1/2) will be calculated as ln(2)/λ = 0.693/λ.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Absorption rate constant (ka) for for Cannabinol (CBN) metabolite following acute topical administration using GT4 technology of CBD and THC</measure>
    <time_frame>12-hour study period</time_frame>
    <description>The absorption rate constant (ka) will be calculated using the feathering method.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">18</enrollment>
  <condition>Bioavailability of CBD and THC</condition>
  <condition>Skin Absorption of CBD and THC</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CBD and THC with GT4 technology</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CBD and THC with GT4 technology</intervention_name>
    <description>A single topical dose of CBD and THC will be administered with GT4 technology. The material will be provided in a single use pre-filled syringe.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CBD and THC with GT4 technology</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy males and females between 25-65 years of age at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Body Mass Index (BMI) from 18.5 to 29.9 kg/m2, inclusive&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Occasional users of cannabis: Have consumed cannabis products at least once in the&#xD;
             past 6 months and at least 4 times in their lifetime but no more than 3 times per week&#xD;
             and not within 48 hours of Visit 2 and have experienced psychotropic effects without&#xD;
             severe adverse events (short term paranoia, belligerence, extreme hallucinations)&#xD;
             requiring medical interventions. Eligibility will be determined on a case by case&#xD;
             basis by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Female participant is not of child bearing potential, which is defined as females who&#xD;
             have undergone a sterilization procedure (e.g. hysterectomy, bilateral oophorectomy,&#xD;
             bilateral tubal ligation, complete endometrial ablation) or have undergone natural&#xD;
             menopause (have not had menses for &gt; 1 year) OR&#xD;
&#xD;
             Females of childbearing potential must agree to abstain from heterosexual intercourse&#xD;
             or use two methods of contraception for 30 days prior to first treatment and for 30&#xD;
             days after the treatment. Subjects must have a negative urine pregnancy test result at&#xD;
             screening and baseline. All hormonal birth control must have been in use for a minimum&#xD;
             of three months. Acceptable methods of birth control include:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Hormonal contraceptives including oral contraceptives, hormone birth control&#xD;
                  patch (Ortho Evra), vaginal contraceptive ring (NuvaRing), injectable&#xD;
                  contraceptives (Depo-Provera, Lunelle), or hormone implant (Norplant System)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Double-barrier method&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Intrauterine devices&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Non-heterosexual lifestyle or agrees to use contraception if planning on changing&#xD;
                  to heterosexual partner(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Vasectomy of partner at least 6- months prior to screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. A male participant with sexual partners who are not pregnant or do not fit the&#xD;
             criteria as indicated above in number 4 must meet the following criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participant is unlikely to procreate, defined as surgically sterile (i.e. has&#xD;
                  undergone vasectomy, it must be at least 6 months since the surgery)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participant agrees to use of the accepted contraceptive regimens from first drug&#xD;
                  administration until 30 days after the drug administration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  An acceptable method of contraception includes one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Abstinence from heterosexual intercourse&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Condom with spermicide&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Agrees to avoid alcohol intake 48 h prior to visit 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Agrees to avoid tobacco or nicotine-containing products 96 hours prior to visit 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Healthy as determined by medical history and laboratory results, as assessed by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Agrees to complete all study related procedures and assessments&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Agrees to provide information of two adult contacts to be reached in the event of&#xD;
             transportation requirements from the clinic to their home after the study visits&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Provides voluntary, written informed consent to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Women who are pregnant, breast feeding, or planning to become pregnant during the&#xD;
             course of the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Allergy or sensitivity to investigational product's active or inactive ingredients&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Acute or chronic skin disease (i.e. atopic dermatitis, eczema, rosacea, psoriasis) or&#xD;
             dermatological conditions (open wounds, scars, sunburns, moles) in the proposed area&#xD;
             of application that would interfere with the application and absorption of the test&#xD;
             product&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Shaving, waxing or laser hair removal of the planned study treatment application area&#xD;
             within 14 days prior to baseline. Tattoos on the planned study application area.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Current use of prescribed medication containing the ingredients in the IP&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Current use of over-the-counter medications, supplements, and foods/drinks containing&#xD;
             the ingredients in the IP unless willing to washout&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Prescribed or OTC medication, supplements, or food/drinks that will interact with the&#xD;
             investigational product&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Positive drug of abuse test at baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of alcohol and/or drug abuse or substance dependence within the last 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. High alcohol intake (average of &gt;2 standard drinks per day)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Self-reported serious psychological disorder(s) diagnosis e.g. schizophrenia, bipolar&#xD;
             disorder, depression, PTSD, sleep disorder that, in the QI's opinion, could interfere&#xD;
             with study participation. History of suicidal ideation, attempts and/or behaviour.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. History of psychosis in immediate family including schizophrenia and affective&#xD;
             psychosis&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Cancer, except basal cell skin carcinoma completely excised with no chemotherapy or&#xD;
             radiation with a follow up that is negative. Volunteers with cancer in full remission&#xD;
             for more than five years after diagnosis are acceptable&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Major surgery in the past 3 months or individuals who have planned surgery during the&#xD;
             course of the trial. Participants with minor surgery will be considered on a&#xD;
             case-by-case basis by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Unstable hypertension. Treatment on a stable dose of medication for at least 3 months&#xD;
             will be considered by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Self-reported cardiovascular disease. Participants with no significant cardiovascular&#xD;
             event in the past 1 year and who are on stable medication may be included after&#xD;
             assessment by the QI on a case-by-case basis&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Individuals with an autoimmune disease or who are immune-compromised&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Positive laboratory results for HIV, Hepatitis B or C as assessed at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Type I or Type II diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Current or history of significant liver disease or dysfunction that in the opinion of&#xD;
             the QI may impact study outcomes or participant safety&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. History of or current diagnosis with kidney diseases as assessed by the QI on a&#xD;
             case-by-case basis, with the exception of history of kidney stones symptom-free for 6&#xD;
             months&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Self-reported current or pre-existing thyroid condition. Treatment on a stable dose&#xD;
             medication for over 6 months will be reviewed on a case-by-case basis by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Self- reported blood/bleeding disorder as assessed by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Clinically significant abnormal laboratory results at screening as determined by the&#xD;
             QI&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Blood donation 30 days prior to screening, during the study, or a planned donation&#xD;
             within 30-days of the last study visit&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Participation in other clinical research trials 30 days prior to enrollment will be&#xD;
             assessed on a case-by-case basis by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. Individuals who are unable to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
         28. Any other condition or lifestyle factor, that, in the opinion of the QI may adversely&#xD;
             affect the participant's ability to complete the study or its measures or pose&#xD;
             significant risk to the participant&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David Crowley, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>KGK Science Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mal Evans, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>519-438-9374</phone>
    <phone_ext>239</phone_ext>
    <email>mevans@kgkscience.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CBD</keyword>
  <keyword>THC</keyword>
  <keyword>GT4 Technology</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

