<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05124054</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>QoR-15</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05124054</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Validity and Reliability of the Turkish Version of the Quality of Recovery-15 (QoR-15) Questionnaire</brief_title>
  <official_title>Turkish Version of the Quality of Recovery-15 (QoR-15) Questionnaire</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Selcuk University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Selcuk University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Postoperative recovery is a complex process influenced by various factors such as patients,&#xD;
      surgical methods and anesthetic properties. Such factors can be accompanied by many negative&#xD;
      situations. Previous studies evaluating recovery following anesthesia primarily evaluated the&#xD;
      incidence of morbidity, mortality, adverse anesthesia-related outcomes, and changes in vital&#xD;
      signs (1-4). These parameters are important, but the quality of recovery of patients has been&#xD;
      neglected in most studies. Therefore, various patient-reported outcome measurement scales and&#xD;
      tools have been developed (1,3-8). One of these scales is Stark et al. It is the QoR-15&#xD;
      questionnaire developed by in 2013 (4). QoR-15 aims to assess the quality of early recovery&#xD;
      and emotional health of patients after surgery (4,6). It is a 15-item questionnaire assessing&#xD;
      the patient's emotional state, physical comfort, psychological support, physical independence&#xD;
      and pain. This one-page QoR-15 questionnaire has been shown to be highly valid and reliable&#xD;
      in patients who have undergone general surgery (4).&#xD;
&#xD;
      QoR-15 has been verified and translated into many languages such as Japanese, French,&#xD;
      Portuguese, Chinese, Swedish (13-17). It was reported in a systemic review that all&#xD;
      translated versions of the QoR-15 had sufficient validity and reliability to assess the&#xD;
      quality of postoperative recovery (19). However, an official Turkish version of the QoR-15&#xD;
      has not yet been developed or approved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study was to develop the Turkish version of the QoR-15 (QoR-15T) and to&#xD;
      evaluate its validity, reliability and responsiveness for Turkish-speaking patients receiving&#xD;
      general anaesthesia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 4, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 24, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Crossover</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>to evaluate the feasibility, reliability, validity, and responsiveness of the QoR-15T after surgery.</measure>
    <time_frame>5 min</time_frame>
    <description>The QoR-15, a measurement tool to evaluate postoperative recovery in patients, consists of 15 items including pain, nausea, vomiting, and self-care status [9]. For each item, the patient is asked to express their status scoring from 0 to 10; therefore, the total score ranges from 0 to 150 points, with higher scores indicating better postoperative recovery. QoR-15 has been verified and translated into many languages such as Japanese, French, Portuguese, Chinese, Swedish.&#xD;
All translated versions of the QoR-15 were reported in a systemic review to have sufficient validity and reliability to assess the quality of postoperative recovery.The aim of this study is to develop the Turkish version of the QoR-15 (QoR-15T) and evaluate its validity, reliability and responsiveness for Turkish speaking patients receiving general anesthesia.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">177</enrollment>
  <condition>to Evaluate the Feasibility, Reliability, Validity, and Responsiveness of the QoR-15T</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients between the ages of 18 and 65 who will undergo elective surgery and who is native&#xD;
        Turkish speaker&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  native turkish speaker&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  scheduled elective surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  with cognitive impairment,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) physical condition IV or higher,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with psychiatric disorders,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of alcohol or any other substance abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients expected to need postoperative mechanical ventilation (eg, cardiovascular&#xD;
             surgery requiring cardiopulmonary bypass, microvascular reconstruction surgery for&#xD;
             oral and maxillofacial cancer, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are thought to be unable to answer the questionnaire due to a change in&#xD;
             mental status or the need for sedation during the postoperative evaluation,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who develop major complications after surgery&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Selcuk University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>EMİNE ASLANLAR</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

