<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05121012</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1920/15</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05121012</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Synaptic Loss in Multiple System Atrophy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Molecular Imaging of Synaptic Loss in Multiple System Atrophy (MSA)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Exeter</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Exeter</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this study the investigators would like to investigate the degree of damage of the&#xD;
      synapses, an important part of the neurons vital for the communications between neurons, in&#xD;
      Multiple System Atrophy (MSA).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Multiple System Atrophy (MSA) is a chronic and progressive neurological disease, for which&#xD;
      unfortunately there is no cure yet. It is known from pathological studies that the synapses&#xD;
      (the terminal parts of the neurons) are affected in this disease, but the investigators don't&#xD;
      know how, and how much this happens. An imaging tool called Positron Emission Tomography&#xD;
      (PET) can study the integrity of the synapses by the use of a dedicated tracer, called&#xD;
      [11C]UCB-J. In this study the investigators would like to study how, and how early, the&#xD;
      synapse deteriorate in patients with MSA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For this study, patients with the MSA-P form of disease will be enrolled. Participants will&#xD;
      be asked to undergo a clinical visit with questionnaires and scales for motor and cognitive&#xD;
      symptoms. Then, participants will come for a [11C]UCB-J PET scan, a [18F]FDG PET scan, to&#xD;
      check the metabolism of the brain, and a MRI scan, to help the analysis of the PET. The&#xD;
      participants will also be asked to perform a Lumbar puncture for a cerebrospinal fluid draw.&#xD;
      This procedure will be optional.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results will help in understanding better the mechanisms underlying this disease and open&#xD;
      new avenues for its treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To measure the magnitude of longitudinal within-group change in [11C]UCB-J volume of distribution in MSA-P</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>[11C]UCB-J is a marker of synaptic damage in MSA-P</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression of brain glucose metabolism in MSA-P</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Brain glucose metabolism is assessed with serial [18F]FDG PET scans at baseline and after 12-month follow-up.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate differences in MRI structural, microstructural, molecular, and functional parameters in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic Resonance Imaging change in Magnetization Prepared Rapid Acquisition Gradient Echo [MPRAGE]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate differences in MRI structural, microstructural, molecular, and functional parameters in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic Resonance Imaging change Fast Gray Matter Acquisition T1 Inversion Recovery [FGATIR]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate differences in MRI structural, microstructural, molecular, and functional parameters in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic Resonance Imaging change in Susceptibility Weighted Imaging [SWI]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate differences in MRI structural, microstructural, molecular, and functional parameters in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic Resonance Imaging change in Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping [QSM]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate differences in MRI structural, microstructural, molecular, and functional parameters in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic Resonance Imaging change in Diffusion Tensor Imaging [DTI]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate differences in MRI structural, microstructural, molecular, and functional parameters in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic Resonance Imaging change in Neuromelanin-MRI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate differences in MRI structural, microstructural, molecular, and functional parameters in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic Resonance Imaging change in Arterial Spin Labelling [ASL]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate differences in MRI structural, microstructural, molecular, and functional parameters in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic Resonance Imaging change in resting state functional MRI [rs-fMRI]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate differences in MRI structural, microstructural, molecular, and functional parameters in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic Resonance Imaging change in Neurite Orientation Dispersion and Density Imaging [NODDI]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and the grading scale UMSARS</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and the staging scale Hoehn and Yahr</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and the screening cognitive measure MoCA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and the ability scale Schwab &amp; England</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and the quality of life scale MSA QoL</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and the autonomic symptoms scale COMPASS-31</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and the balance scale ABC-16</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and the depression scale BDI-II</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and the depression scale HDRS</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and the sleep scale RBD-SQ</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and the behavioural scale NPI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and the cognitive battery CANTAB</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and blood biomarkers related to neuroinflammation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate correlations between synaptic density, regional brain glucose metabolism, and clinical measures in MSA patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between imaging measures and CSF biomarkers related to neuroinflammation and misfolded proteins deposition</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple System Atrophy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with MSA-P</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Study procedures</intervention_name>
    <description>All participants will undergo a collection of demographic data, a neurological examination and administration of clinical scales relevant for MSA-P. All participants will undergo a collection of venous blood sample for routine analyses.&#xD;
Participants will undergo one PET scan with the tracer [11C]UCB-J, and one PET scan with the tracer [18F]FDG. All participants will also undergo one MRI scan.&#xD;
Participants will also undergo one lumbar puncture (optional).&#xD;
All procedures will be performed at baseline and after one-year follow-up.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Venous blood will be collected for analysis of inflammatory biomarkers (including CRP, IL-6,&#xD;
      IL-1b, TNF, ferritin, ESR) and for storage in biobanks for future ethically approved studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) will be collected for analysis of cell count and for biomarkers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with a diagnosis of MSA-P&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female, aged 45-70 at the time of informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. A female subject is eligible to participate if she is (i) of non-childbearing&#xD;
             potential, defined as pre-menopausal females with a documented tubal ligation or&#xD;
             hysterectomy, or postmenopausal defined as 12 months of spontaneous amenorrhea or (ii)&#xD;
             of childbearing potential but not pregnant (as determined by urinary pregnancy test on&#xD;
             screening and on each study day), is not lactating and is willing to use one of the&#xD;
             contraception methods listed below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Combined (estrogen and progesterone containing) hormonal contraception associated&#xD;
                  with initiation of ovulation( oral, intravaginal, or transdermal);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Progesterone-only hormonal contraception associated with inhibition of ovulation&#xD;
                  (oral, injectable, implantable);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intrauterine device;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intrauterine hormone releasing system;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilateral tubal occlusion;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Vasectomized partner;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Sexual abstinence.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Male subject with a female partner of child-bearing potential must use one of the&#xD;
             following contraceptive methods for 90 days after each dose of radiotracer:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Condom plus partner use of a highly effective contraceptive (see point above) OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Abstinence&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects must understand the nature of the study and be able to provide signed and&#xD;
             dated written informed consent in accordance with local regulations before the conduct&#xD;
             of any study-related procedures. They must be able and willing to participate in all&#xD;
             scheduled evaluations, abide by all study restrictions, and complete all required&#xD;
             tests and procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Must have anticipated survival of ≥3 years (in the opinion of the Investigator).&#xD;
&#xD;
             Must be able to walk unassisted for at least 10 meters (approximately 30 feet). In the&#xD;
             opinion of the investigator, the subject must be considered likely to comply with the&#xD;
             study protocol and to have high probability of completing the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Have received at least one shot of the SARS-CoV2 vaccination, unless deemed medically&#xD;
             unsuitable to receive vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Meet criteria for diagnosis of probable or possible MSA-P&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Medical treatment of MSA and co-morbid medical conditions must be stable for at least&#xD;
             30 days prior to screening and between screening and baseline PET scan. Intermittently&#xD;
             administered treatment may be considered stable if the dose and dosing frequency have&#xD;
             been unchanged for the greater of 30 days or three dosing intervals (e.g. a treatment&#xD;
             given once a month must be at a stable dose and dosing frequency for 3 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. For inclusion in optional CSF sampling, written informed consent must be provided,&#xD;
             either by separate signed and dated written informed consent or by specific written&#xD;
             acknowledgement on the main study informed consent form, according to local procedure.&#xD;
             Failure to participate in optional CSF sampling will have no influence on the&#xD;
             subject's ability to participate in the main study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of other neurological disorders or intracranial co-morbidities, such as&#xD;
             stroke, haemorrhage, space-occupying lesions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Presence of any clinically significant medical condition (including cardiovascular,&#xD;
             respiratory, cerebrovascular, hematological, hepatic, renal, gastrointestinal, or&#xD;
             other disease) that, based on the judgement of the investigator, is clinically&#xD;
             unstable, is likely to deteriorate during the course of the study, could put the&#xD;
             patient at risk because of participation in the study, could affect the subject's&#xD;
             ability to complete the study, or could influence the study results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Presence of cognitive dysfunction (defined as MoCA score &lt;25).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Presence of any of the following MRI contraindications: pacemaker; cardiac&#xD;
             defibrillator; spinal cord or vagus nerve stimulator; aneurysm clip; artificial heart&#xD;
             valve; recent coronary or carotid stent; ear implant; CSF shunt; other implanted&#xD;
             medical device (e.g. Swan-Ganz catheter, insulin pump); or metal fragments or foreign&#xD;
             objects in the eyes, skin, or body. If the principal investigator considers the&#xD;
             presence of any of the above not to be a contraindication to MRI in a given subject,&#xD;
             the investigator may obtain approval from the medical monitor based on a discussion of&#xD;
             the case.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Negative modified Allen test in both hands.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of claustrophobia or back pain that makes prolonged laying on the MRI or PET&#xD;
             scanner intolerable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Pregnancy, lactation, or, if female of childbearing potential, positive urine β-hCG at&#xD;
             screening or prior to PET scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Use of drugs acting on SV2A such as antiepileptics (e.g. levetiracetam or&#xD;
             brivaracetam).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of brain surgery for parkinsonism or stem cell treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Clinically significant blood clotting or bleeding disorder, including clinically&#xD;
             significant abnormal findings in laboratory assessments of coagulation or hematology.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Current or recent history of alcohol or drug abuse / dependence (except nicotine&#xD;
             dependence).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. History of cancer within the last 5 years, with the exception of nonmetastatic basal&#xD;
             cell carcinoma of the skin.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Any clinically important abnormality, as determined by the investigator, on physical&#xD;
             examination or vital signs, ECG, or clinical laboratory test results other than&#xD;
             abnormality due to a stable, well-controlled medical condition; or any abnormality&#xD;
             that could be detrimental to the subject or could compromise the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Presence of supranuclear gaze palsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Severe-to-complete dependence on caregivers (score &gt;3 on UMSARS Part IV, Global&#xD;
             Disability), severe impairment of swallowing (score ≥3 on UMSARS Part I, Question 2),&#xD;
             or frequent falls (score ≥3 on UMSARS Part I, Question 8) at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) ≥ 6.5% at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Uncontrolled/poorly controlled diabetes mellitus.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For subjects participating in optional CSF sampling:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any spinal malformation or other aspects (e.g. tattoos) / clinical findings (e.g.&#xD;
             papilledema) that may complicate or contraindicate lumbar puncture, as judged by the&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Neoplasm or other space-occupying intracranial lesion on MRI.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marios Politis, MD MSc PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Exeter</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Edoardo R. de Natale, MD MSc Ph.D</last_name>
    <phone>07503741242</phone>
    <email>e.de-natale@exeter.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Heather Wilson, MSc Ph.D</last_name>
    <email>h.wilson4@exeter.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Exeter</name>
      <address>
        <city>Exeter</city>
        <zip>SE16 7RJ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Edoardo R de Natale, MD MSc PhD</last_name>
      <phone>07503741242</phone>
      <email>e.de-natale@exeter.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Neurodegeneration</keyword>
  <keyword>Positron Emission Tomography</keyword>
  <keyword>Multiple System Atrophy</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple System Atrophy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Shy-Drager Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Atrophy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

