<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05121948</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HC366-FCP2111</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05121948</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of HC-7366 to Establish the Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD) and Recommended Phase 2 Dose (RP2D)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Open-label, Phase 1a/b Study of HC-7366 in Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>HiberCell, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Covance</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>HiberCell, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a first in human, multicenter, open label, Phase 1a/b dose escalation and dose&#xD;
      expansion study to establish the maximum tolerated dose (MTD), recommended Phase 2 dose&#xD;
      (RP2D), and evaluate the safety and tolerability of QD oral dosing of HC 7366 in a dose&#xD;
      escalating fashion in subjects with advanced solid tumors. Up to 36 subjects will be enrolled&#xD;
      into the Phase 1a dose escalation part of the study. Every effort will be made to ensure&#xD;
      approximately 50% of all subjects enrolled in this study will be subjects with the tumors of&#xD;
      special interest such as squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck (SCCHN), colorectal&#xD;
      cancer (CRC), non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC), and transitional cell carcinoma of the&#xD;
      bladder (TCC). Subjects with other solid tumor types are also eligible provided study&#xD;
      selection criteria are met and they do not exceed 50% of all enrolled subjects. The study&#xD;
      will be conducted in the United States at approximately 3 to 5 sites. This Phase 1a/b study&#xD;
      will follow a traditional 3+3 design. The starting dose level will be 10 mg QD, escalating to&#xD;
      20, 40, 75, 125, and 150 mg QD as safety allows. All doses are to be administered in the&#xD;
      fasting state with water at least 1 hour before food or at least 2 hours after food. The&#xD;
      Phase 1b dose expansion part will involve cohort expansion at up to 2 dose levels selected&#xD;
      from the dose escalation data by the safety monitoring committee (SMC), to obtain additional&#xD;
      safety and preliminary efficacy information. Each cohort in Phase 1b will enroll 15 subjects.&#xD;
      The study will be expanded into a Phase 2 study via protocol amendment which will then assess&#xD;
      the dose and tumor type(s) selected in Phase 1a/b as the most appropriate for further&#xD;
      clinical development. Subjects will be dosed until unacceptable toxicity, disease progression&#xD;
      per immune-related Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (iRECIST), discontinuation of&#xD;
      treatment for other protocol allowed reason (eg, subject refusal), any other administrative&#xD;
      reasons, or after 2 years of treatment, whichever occurs first. For scheduling purposes,&#xD;
      dosing will occur in 3 week cycles and computed tomography (CT) scans will be conducted once&#xD;
      every 6 weeks with the first postbaseline scan after 6 weeks of dosing (precycle 3).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Subjects are to spend Cycle 1/Day 1 (C1D1) in the clinic followed by an overnight stay for&#xD;
      safety monitoring and PK sampling. Subjects will be hospitalized for administration of the&#xD;
      first 2 doses: C1D1 and Cycle 1/Day 2 (C1D2) (as local coronavirus disease 19 restrictions&#xD;
      allow). After the initial hospital stay at the start of study, subjects will be seen in&#xD;
      outpatient clinic on Days 8, 15, and 21 of Cycle 1 and thereafter, on the first day of each&#xD;
      cycle for physical and laboratory assessments, adverse event (AE) and dosing compliance&#xD;
      monitoring, and PK C3-C6; the End of Treatment visit will also be in person in outpatient&#xD;
      clinic. An overnight stay for Cycle 1/Day 21 (C1D21) to C2D1 is optional. Subjects who&#xD;
      discontinue before the first postbaseline CT scan for reasons other than disease progression,&#xD;
      a treatment-related AE, or dose limiting toxicity (DLT) prior to completion of the DLT&#xD;
      evaluation period will be replaced to ensure an adequate safety assessment at each dose&#xD;
      level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each subject will be treated for a maximum of 2 years and followed for a maximum of 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Six dose-escalation levels are planned starting with 10 mg QD, escalating to 20, 40, 75, 125,&#xD;
      and 150 mg QD. Dose escalation will follow a traditional 3+3 design. A minimum of 3 subjects&#xD;
      will be enrolled in each cohort sequentially, with expansion to 6 subjects in each cohort as&#xD;
      needed to determine the DLT. For each cohort, the first subject is a sentinel subject.&#xD;
      Sentinel subjects will be dosed and followed for 4 days to assess safety and tolerability. If&#xD;
      deemed safe and well tolerated, the remainder of the cohort (N=2) will be enrolled. If none&#xD;
      of the first 3 subjects in a cohort experiences a study treatment related DLT during the&#xD;
      first 21 days (DLT evaluation period), the next cohort may be enrolled. Before applying the&#xD;
      dose escalation rules, 3 subjects in a given dose level must have received a minimum of 75%&#xD;
      of the planned dose and have been evaluated for toxicity, unless one or more subjects&#xD;
      experiences a DLT within the first 21 days. If the first 3 DLT evaluable subjects within a&#xD;
      cohort experience no DLTs during the DLT evaluation period, the next cohort may enroll. In&#xD;
      the case a subject does not receive a minimum of 75% of the planned dose, for any reason&#xD;
      other than a DLT (ie, lost to follow-up), the subject may be replaced. DLT's will be reviewed&#xD;
      by the Safety Monitoring Committee (SMC) when the planned number of subjects complete their&#xD;
      DLT observation period using the dose-escalation rules. If the MTD is not reached even at the&#xD;
      maximum dose level (150 mg QD is well tolerated), a higher dose level may be evaluated based&#xD;
      on the SMC recommendations after a comprehensive review of the safety, PK, and efficacy data&#xD;
      generated from the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determination of MTD of HC-7366</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 18 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
    <description>When orally administered once daily in a dose escalating fashion in subjects with selected, advanced solid tumors</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determination of Recommended Phase 2 dose of HC-7366</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 18 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
    <description>When orally administered once daily in a dose escalating fashion in subjects with selected, advanced solid tumors</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of dose-limiting toxicities (DLTs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 18 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence and severity of treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs) and treatment related TEAEs according to National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (NCI CTCAE) v 5.0</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 18 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of TEAEs leading to premature discontinuation</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 18 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of laboratory abnormalities, based on NCI CTCAE grades of hematology, serum chemistry, and urinalysis test results</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 18 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of abnormalities observed in 12 lead ECG parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 18 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of abnormalities observed in vital signs measurements</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 18 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve from time 0 until last measurable concentration (AUC 0-last)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve from time 0 to 24 hours postdose (AUC 0-24)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve from time 0 extrapolated to infinity (AUC 0-∞)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve over a dosing interval (AUC 0-t)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak plasma concentration (Cmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time of the maximum observed plasma concentration (tmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent total clearance (CL/F) of plasma concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent volume of distribution during the terminal phase (Vz/F) of plasma concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent terminal elimination half life (t1/2) of plasma concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accumulation ratio based on AUC 0-t (ARAUC) of plasma concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Linearity ratio (LR) of plasma concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate (ORR) to HC-7366 using iRECIST</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response (DOR) to HC-7366 using iRECIST</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to treatment failure (TTF)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS) using iRECIST</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 months of last patient enrolled</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>8</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">66</enrollment>
  <condition>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of Head and Neck</condition>
  <condition>Colo-rectal Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Non Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Transitional Cell Carcinoma of the Bladder</condition>
  <condition>Other Solid Tumors</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1a Cohort 1 - 10 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>10 mg capsules of HC-7366 administered orally once a day in the fasting state with water at least 1 hour before food or at least 2 hours after food of each 3-week treatment cycle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1a Cohort 2 - 20 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>20 mg capsules of HC-7366 administered orally once a day in the fasting state with water at least 1 hour before food or at least 2 hours after food of each 3-week treatment cycle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1a Cohort 3 - 40 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>40 mg capsules of HC-7366 administered orally once a day in the fasting state with water at least 1 hour before food or at least 2 hours after food of each 3-week treatment cycle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1a Cohort 4 - 75 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>75 mg capsules of HC-7366 administered orally once a day in the fasting state with water at least 1 hour before food or at least 2 hours after food of each 3-week treatment cycle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1a Cohort 5 - 125 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>125 mg capsules of HC-7366 administered orally once a day in the fasting state with water at least 1 hour before food or at least 2 hours after food of each 3-week treatment cycle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1a Cohort 6 - 150 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>150 mg capsules of HC-7366 administered orally once a day in the fasting state with water at least 1 hour before food or at least 2 hours after food of each 3-week treatment cycle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1b Cohort 7 - Dose 1 Chosen for Expansion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>XX mg capsules of HC-7366 administered orally once a day in the fasting state with water at least 1 hour before food or at least 2 hours after food of each 3-week treatment cycle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1b Cohort 8 - Dose 2 Chosen for Expansion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>XX mg capsules of HC-7366 administered orally once a day in the fasting state with water at least 1 hour before food or at least 2 hours after food of each 3-week treatment cycle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HC-7366</intervention_name>
    <description>HC-7366 drug product is an immediate release capsule formulation of HC-7366 potassium salt monohydrate (HC-7366-K) in a hard gelatin capsule for oral administration. Each capsule contains HC-7366-K monohydrate (the active ingredient), lactose monohydrate, microcrystalline cellulose, croscarmellose sodium, colloidal silicon dioxide, and magnesium stearate. Capsules are supplied in 3 strengths: 10, 25, and 100 mg HC-7366 free acid equivalent.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1a Cohort 1 - 10 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1a Cohort 2 - 20 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1a Cohort 3 - 40 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1a Cohort 4 - 75 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1a Cohort 5 - 125 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1a Cohort 6 - 150 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1b Cohort 7 - Dose 1 Chosen for Expansion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1b Cohort 8 - Dose 2 Chosen for Expansion</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>HC-7366-K</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Have a signed an informed consent form prior to any study specific procedures or&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Be ≥18 years of age (male or female) at the time of consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have 1 of the following tumor types with qualifying characteristics, and have received&#xD;
             at least 1 and no more than 5 prior lines of therapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. SCCHN&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. CRC&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. NSCLC&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. TCC&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Other solid tumors (eg, carcinoma of unknown primary) with the exception of&#xD;
                  rapidly progressing neoplasms (eg, pancreatic cancer, glioblastoma,&#xD;
                  hepatocellular carcinoma). Note: Subjects do not need to have progressed through&#xD;
                  all possible available therapies with known clinical benefit for their respective&#xD;
                  cancers to participate in this study. Note: Subjects with SCCHN, CRC, NSCLC, and&#xD;
                  TCC are a priority and should constitute as a whole, at least 50% of the enrolled&#xD;
                  population. Enrollment of all others will be capped when reaching a combined 50%,&#xD;
                  in order to maintain 18 slots for subjects with SCCHN, CRC, NSCLC, and TCC.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Have at least 1 radiologically measurable lesion as per Response Evaluation Criteria&#xD;
             in Solid Tumors (RECIST) v 1.1 defined as a lesion that is at least 10 mm in longest&#xD;
             diameter or lymph node that is at least 15 mm in short axis imaged by CT scan or&#xD;
             magnetic resonance imaging and obtained by imaging within 28 days prior to study&#xD;
             treatment. Tumor lesions situated in a previously irradiated area are considered&#xD;
             measurable if progression has been demonstrated in such lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Have resolution of all previous treatment related toxicities to Grade 1 severity or&#xD;
             lower, except for stable sensory neuropathy (≤Grade 2) and alopecia. If the subject&#xD;
             received major surgery or radiation therapy of &gt;30 Gy, they must have recovered from&#xD;
             the toxicity and/or complications from the intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. If subjects were previously treated with immune checkpoint inhibitors, at least 4&#xD;
             weeks must have elapsed since the last dose, and toxicities resolved as above&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects must have at least one biopsiable lesion at baseline. Biopsies in this&#xD;
             clinical study will conform to American Society of Clinical Oncology's Ethical&#xD;
             Framework for Including Research Biopsies in Oncology Clinical Trials. Provided there&#xD;
             are suitable and accessible lesions, no biopsy contraindications, minimal risk of&#xD;
             complications and a positive informed decision, subjects are willing to provide fresh&#xD;
             tissue for biomarker analysis, and, based on the adequacy of the tissue sample&#xD;
             quality, for assessment of biomarker status. Two biopsies will be necessary: at&#xD;
             baseline (within 15 days prior to study Day 1) and at the time of the first response&#xD;
             assessment CT scan at Cycle 3/Day 1 (+7 days). Newly obtained biopsy specimens are&#xD;
             preferred to archived samples and formalin fixed, paraffin embedded block specimens&#xD;
             are preferred to slides&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Have Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status of 0 or 1 and sustained&#xD;
             between screening and initiation of dosing on Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Have no swallowing difficulties that would prevent compliance with oral dosing&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Have not experienced &gt;10% body weight loss in the previous 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Have a serum albumin level &gt;3 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Have life expectancy of 3 months or greater as determined by the treating physician&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Have adequate organ function on Day 1, as defined by meeting all of the following&#xD;
             criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Total bilirubin ≤1.5 × upper limit of normal (ULN) OR direct bilirubin ≤ULN for&#xD;
                  subjects with total bilirubin levels &gt;1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Aspartate aminotransferase and alanine aminotransferase ≤2.5 × ULN or ≤5 × ULN&#xD;
                  for subjects with known hepatic metastases&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Have adequate renal function on Day 1, as defined by creatinine ≤1.5 × ULN and&#xD;
             creatinine clearance ≥60 mL/min, as per the below Cockcroft Gault formula&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Have adequate hematologic function on Day 1, as defined by meeting all of the&#xD;
             following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Hemoglobin ≥9 g/dL (uncorrected by red blood cell transfusion or erythropoietin&#xD;
                  support)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Absolute neutrophil count ≥1.5 × 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Platelet count ≥100 × 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Have adequate coagulation function on Day 1, as defined by either of the following&#xD;
             criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. International normalized ratio (INR) &lt;1.5 × ULN OR for subjects receiving&#xD;
                  warfarin or low molecular weight heparin, the subject must, in the investigator's&#xD;
                  opinion, be clinically stable with no evidence of active bleeding while receiving&#xD;
                  anticoagulant therapy. The INR for these subjects may exceed 1.5 × ULN if that is&#xD;
                  the goal of anticoagulant therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Activated partial thromboplastin time &lt;1.5 × ULN unless subject is receiving&#xD;
                  anticoagulant therapy, provided prothrombin time or partial thromboplastin time&#xD;
                  is within therapeutic range of intended use of anticoagulants&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Have normal or adequately controlled pan-endocrine function (pituitary, adrenal,&#xD;
             thyroid, pancreatic, gonadal). Subjects on hormonal supplementation must be stable at&#xD;
             their treatment doses&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative urine or serum&#xD;
             pregnancy test within 72 hours prior to receiving the first dose of study medication.&#xD;
             If the urine test is positive or cannot be confirmed as negative, a serum pregnancy&#xD;
             test will be required&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Female subjects of childbearing potential must be willing to use an adequate form of&#xD;
             contraception from the signing of the ICF until 90 days after the last dose of study&#xD;
             medication&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Female subjects must agree not to breastfeed and not to donate ova starting at&#xD;
             screening and throughout the study treatment, and for 90 days after the final&#xD;
             administration of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Male subjects with a pregnant or breastfeeding partner(s) must agree to remain&#xD;
             abstinent or use a condom for the duration of the pregnancy or for the time their&#xD;
             partner is breastfeeding throughout the study treatment and for 90 days after the&#xD;
             final administration of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Male subjects must not donate sperm during the treatment period and for at least 90&#xD;
             days after the final administration of the study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Male subjects with female partner(s) of child bearing potential must agree to use a&#xD;
             condom with spermicide during the treatment period and for at least 90 days after the&#xD;
             final administration of the study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Be willing and have the ability to comply with scheduled visits (including&#xD;
             geographical proximity), treatment plans, laboratory tests, and other study&#xD;
             procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Had prior chemotherapy, targeted small molecule therapy, or radiation therapy within 2&#xD;
             weeks prior to the first dose of study treatment or who has not recovered from adverse&#xD;
             reactions due to a previously administered agent or major surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Is currently participating and receiving study therapy or has participated in a study&#xD;
             of an investigational agent and received study therapy or used an investigational&#xD;
             device within 4 weeks of the first dose of treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Has a diagnosis of immunodeficiency or receiving systemic steroid therapy or any other&#xD;
             form of immunosuppressive therapy within 7 days prior to the first dose of study&#xD;
             treatment. The use of physiologic doses of corticosteroids may be approved after&#xD;
             consultation with the sponsor&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Has known history of active tuberculosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Has known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) (HIV 1/2 antibodies)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Has known active hepatitis B (eg, hepatitis B surface antigen reactive) or hepatitis C&#xD;
             (eg, hepatitis C virus ribonucleic acid [RNA] [qualitative]) infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Has been diagnosed with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection&#xD;
             confirmed by real time polymerase chain reaction (PCR) test as per the local&#xD;
             guidelines at screening and positive by PCR within 7 days prior to the first dose of&#xD;
             study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Has a history of clinically severe autoimmune disease, or history of organ transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Has a history of retinitis or photosensitive skin disorders including (but not limited&#xD;
             to) erythema multiforme, atopic eczema, psoriasis, viral exanthemata, pemphigus, and&#xD;
             dermatitis herpetiformis&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Has known additional malignancy that is progressing or required active treatment&#xD;
             within the previous 5 years. Exceptions include basal cell carcinoma or squamous cell&#xD;
             carcinoma of the skin that has undergone potentially curative therapy, superficial&#xD;
             bladder cancer, or in situ cervical cancer. Subjects with other malignancies are&#xD;
             eligible if they were cured by surgery alone or surgery plus radiotherapy and have&#xD;
             been continuously disease free for at least 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Has known active central nervous system metastases and/or carcinomatous meningitis.&#xD;
             Subjects with previously treated brain metastases may participate provided they are&#xD;
             stable (without evidence of disease progression by imaging for at least 4 weeks prior&#xD;
             to the first dose of study treatment and any neurologic symptoms have returned to&#xD;
             baseline), have no evidence of new or enlarging brain metastases, and are not using&#xD;
             systemic steroids for at least 7 days prior to study treatment. This exception does&#xD;
             not include carcinomatous meningitis which is excluded regardless of clinical&#xD;
             stability&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Has a history of interstitial lung disease, pneumonitis within 12 months prior to&#xD;
             screening, or current pneumonitis&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Has an active infection requiring systemic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Has a history or current evidence of any condition, therapy, or laboratory abnormality&#xD;
             that might confound the results of the study, interfere with the subject's&#xD;
             participation for the full duration of the study, or is not in the best interest of&#xD;
             the subject to participate, in the opinion of the treating investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Has a clinically significant cardiovascular disease such as unstable angina,&#xD;
             myocardial infarction, or acute coronary syndrome, symptomatic or uncontrolled&#xD;
             arrhythmia, congestive heart failure, baseline electrocardiogram (ECG) abnormalities,&#xD;
             including, but not limited to, QTc prolongation to greater than 470 ms, or any Class&#xD;
             III or IV cardiac disease as defined by the New York Heart Association Functional&#xD;
             Classification&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Has overt or latent disorders of the exocrine pancreas (such as acute or chronic&#xD;
             pancreatitis of any etiology) or chronic (including autoimmune) gastrointestinal&#xD;
             disorders such as Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis, rheumatoid arthritis, lupus,&#xD;
             scleroderma, Sjogren's syndrome, and polyarteritis nodosa&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Has a known psychiatric or substance abuse disorder(s) that would interfere with&#xD;
             informed consent or cooperation with the requirements of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Is pregnant or breastfeeding or expecting to conceive children within the projected&#xD;
             duration of the study, starting with the screening visit through 90 days after the&#xD;
             final administration of the study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Is a first degree relative of the investigator, staff, or study sponsor.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jose Iglesias, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Consultant Chief Medical Officer for HiberCell, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Viviana Cecinato, MPharm</last_name>
    <phone>708-295-1226</phone>
    <email>viviana.cecinato@labcorp.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Holly J. Brems</last_name>
    <phone>816-260-2097</phone>
    <email>holly.brems@labcorp.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SCCHN</keyword>
  <keyword>CRC</keyword>
  <keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
  <keyword>TCC</keyword>
  <keyword>Phase 1</keyword>
  <keyword>First in human</keyword>
  <keyword>HC-7366</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Transitional Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of Head and Neck</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

