<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04253782</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2000028548</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01CE002989-01</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2000027149</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04253782</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SafetyNet Program for Opioid Use Disorder (OUD)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multi-Tiered Safety Net Following Naloxone Resuscitation From Opioid Overdose</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The principal aim of this study is to determine whether a novel biopsychosocial intervention&#xD;
      following opioid overdose (OD) affects 1) the frequency of secondary opioid OD events and 2)&#xD;
      the proportion of individuals who remain engaged in treatment for opioid use disorder (OUD)&#xD;
      or are in remission at 30 days and at 180 days post intervention. Remission is defined as&#xD;
      engagement in daily medication-assisted therapy (MAT)-typically buprenorphine/naloxone (BUP)&#xD;
      or methadone- and/or a recovery capital score of ≥ 27.5. The intervention principally&#xD;
      involves connecting OUD-affected individuals with community resources, including BUP-, other&#xD;
      MAT-, and education-related services. To carry out the intervention, an addiction recovery&#xD;
      coach and an appropriately trained health educator paramedic (research assistant) will form a&#xD;
      Team and perform follow-up visits (electronically/remotely and/or by phone and/or in person,&#xD;
      when appropriate) after a participant has experienced at least 1 opioid OD requiring naloxone&#xD;
      resuscitation. Our hypothesis is that the intervention will decrease subsequent OD events and&#xD;
      increase the likelihood of remission. To evaluate this hypothesis, data will be collected&#xD;
      from self-report and from EPIC, Yale New Haven Hospital's medical record system. The&#xD;
      secondary aim is to determine whether the intervention affects 1) the frequency of&#xD;
      positive-urine tests for opioids and 2) the frequency and proportion of subjects&#xD;
      self-reporting opioid use. Our hypothesis is that this intervention will decrease both. Data&#xD;
      from the entire cohort will be compared in aggregate with patients who were started on BUP in&#xD;
      the ED over the same time period and with historic controls.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Scientific premise for proposed project. Buprenorphine/naloxone-based (BUP) treatment for&#xD;
      opioid use disorder (OUD). It is known that medication-assisted therapy (MAT) of opioid use&#xD;
      disorder (OUD) with buprenorphine/naloxone (BUP) is associated with decreased risk of opioid&#xD;
      overdose, improved engagement in treatment at 30 days, and less self-reported opioid use&#xD;
      compared with those who receive only a brief negotiated interview (BNI) or referral for&#xD;
      counselling. As a result of previous research, patients in Yale's Emergency Department (ED)&#xD;
      who are successfully resuscitated with naloxone following an opioid overdose are routinely&#xD;
      screened using the Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI) for OUD. Those who&#xD;
      screen positive for moderate to severe OUD are offered initiation of BUP treatment in the ED,&#xD;
      with outpatient primary care clinic referral for ongoing medical monitoring and treatment. At&#xD;
      the time of the ED visit, however, fewer than half of these patients will consent to&#xD;
      initiation of BUP. Those who decline are offered overdose education and naloxone (OEN) by ED&#xD;
      staff. A safety net that includes tailored linkage plans to effectively engage opioid&#xD;
      overdose survivors with BUP, intensive psychosocial support, and follow-up counseling in the&#xD;
      community is needed. To gain a better understanding of the motivations of those who decline&#xD;
      the offer of BUP, research from Yale's Department of Emergency Medicine purposively sampled&#xD;
      16 opioid overdose survivors who agreed to participate in a qualitative study looking at&#xD;
      their knowledge and understanding of OUD (unpublished). Predominant themes included the&#xD;
      following: ambivalence regarding the effectiveness of treatment for OUD, concerns about&#xD;
      concurrent social supports such as housing and mental health services; lack of appreciation&#xD;
      for the risks associated with OUD (even with multiple prior overdoses); strong, but abstract,&#xD;
      desire to discontinue use of opioids, despite refusal of treatment; and limited understanding&#xD;
      of how to prevent or emergently manage overdoses. These perceptions from the patient&#xD;
      population with OUD declining treatment directly informed the current study and its proposed&#xD;
      research strategy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Peer support and recovery in OUD. In 2012, the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services&#xD;
      Administration (SAMHSA) established a working definition of recovery from mental health and&#xD;
      substance use disorders: a process of change through which individuals improve their health&#xD;
      and wellness, live self-directed lives, and strive to reach their full potential. The&#xD;
      definition identifies 4 dimensions that support recovery: 1) health, including both&#xD;
      management of the disease and decision making associated with physical and emotional&#xD;
      wellbeing; 2) home, e.g., a stable place to live; 3) purpose, e.g., meaningful daily&#xD;
      activities; and 4) community, e.g., supportive relationships and social networks. One of the&#xD;
      interrelated guiding principles of recovery promulgated by SAMHSA is peer support. Peer&#xD;
      recovery support services are delivered by persons who have common life experiences with&#xD;
      those they are serving. Since 1998, SAMHSA has sponsored Recovery Community Services grant&#xD;
      programs, and in 2002 the program changed its focus to emphasize the use of peers for&#xD;
      recovery support services. This funding now targets recovery community statewide networks.&#xD;
      The Connecticut Community for Addiction Recovery (CCAR) was established in 1998, with initial&#xD;
      funding by the State's Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services and one of the&#xD;
      original SAMHSA grants. Since then, it has grown to its current size with a staff of 28,&#xD;
      recovery centers located in major cities, an ED recovery coach program, and 308 volunteers&#xD;
      who donated 28,841 hours in 2017 alone. CCAR recovery coaches are peer experts; many have&#xD;
      been in recovery themselves. They have experiential knowledge and training. More&#xD;
      specifically, CCAR describes a recovery coach as a motivator who exhibits bold faith in an/a&#xD;
      individual/family's capacity for change, and who encourages and celebrates achievement. The&#xD;
      recovery coach is an ally and confidant who genuinely cares, listens, and can be trusted with&#xD;
      confidences, as well as a truth teller who provides a consistent source of honest feedback&#xD;
      regarding self-destructive patterns of thinking, feeling, and acting. He or she is also a&#xD;
      role model and mentor who offers his/her life as living proof of the transformative power of&#xD;
      recovery and provides stage-appropriate recovery education and advice. The recovery coach is&#xD;
      trained to serve as a problem solver who identifies and helps remove personal and&#xD;
      environmental obstacles to recovery. He or she serves as a resource broker, linking&#xD;
      individuals/families to formal and indigenous resources such as sober housing,&#xD;
      recovery-conducive employment, health and social services, and other recovery support. The&#xD;
      recovery coach advocates by helping individuals and families navigate service systems for&#xD;
      access, responsiveness, and protection of rights. The recovery coaches may also be community&#xD;
      organizers to help develop and expand available recovery support resources, lifestyle&#xD;
      consultants to assist individuals/families to develop sobriety-based rituals of daily living,&#xD;
      and friends, providing companionship. Coaches receive training at the CCAR Recovery Coach&#xD;
      Academy, a 5-day intensive training program that focuses on providing individuals with the&#xD;
      necessary skills to mentor, support, and guide any person who would like to enter or sustain&#xD;
      long-term recovery from addiction. At this training, prospective CCAR recovery coaches learn&#xD;
      about the roles and functions of a recovery coach, core values and guiding principles of&#xD;
      recovery, relationship enhancement and crafting skills, appropriate attitudes about&#xD;
      self-disclosure, stages of recovery, addressing stigma, awareness of culture, power and&#xD;
      privilege, and addressing ethical and boundary issues. This Academy also teaches how to&#xD;
      practice newly acquired skills. CCAR recovery coaches' style of treatment is generally&#xD;
      informal, and they assist the individual affected by OUD in focusing on what he or she can do&#xD;
      at the present time to facilitate recovery in the future, in addition to helping these&#xD;
      individuals connect with community resources. Reports suggest that fostering a supportive and&#xD;
      positive treatment environment is critical.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Community treatment of OUD. Some small studies and anecdotal successes have been reported in&#xD;
      a variety of settings when community health educators were included in programs to assist&#xD;
      patients with OUD. Most of the available reports are in emergency medical services (EMS)&#xD;
      trade journals, organization newsletters, public news releases, and other &quot;gray&quot; literature.&#xD;
      For example, a Fairfield County, Ohio initiative called Project FORT (Fairfield Overdose&#xD;
      Response Team) dispatches a community paramedic and a law enforcement officer to meet with&#xD;
      patients after opioid overdoses. This is a community outreach model program that contacts&#xD;
      patients, within 1-3 days of overdose, and assists them with getting into treatment&#xD;
      facilities, which are aimed primarily at abstinence. With no reports of formal outcomes, as&#xD;
      of December, 2017, Project FORT had piloted 12 patients. Of these, 1 was known to be in an&#xD;
      inpatient treatment program, and another had been admitted to the hospital for opioid&#xD;
      withdrawal then discharged to inpatient treatment. The Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of&#xD;
      Public Health is collaborating with Baltimore City Fire Department's paramedics and the&#xD;
      Behavioral Health System of Baltimore in a program that trains the paramedics to perform a&#xD;
      screening test for OUD, followed by a BNI after responding to opioid overdoses. At the time&#xD;
      of their report, patients with OUD were being referred by the paramedics to a community-based&#xD;
      research center within the Bloomberg School for counseling, motivation, and discussion of&#xD;
      barriers to treatment. HIV (+) patients were preferentially referred to a medical facility&#xD;
      for treatment with BUP along with management of their HIV disease. Their longer-term plan was&#xD;
      to eventually transport clinically stable patients after overdose directly to a sobering&#xD;
      center, similar to the protocol used in the City of San Francisco. Although the patients&#xD;
      referred by the paramedics to the community-based research center are randomized to one of 2&#xD;
      different treatment arms, there have been no reports of the effectiveness of the paramedics&#xD;
      in this role. In a Palm Beach, FL community paramedicine program loosely based on previous&#xD;
      work at Yale, consented patients are started on BUP in the ED after an overdose. But&#xD;
      community paramedics deliver the ensuing daily doses to the patients at home for the first&#xD;
      week of therapy. These medics are accompanied by peer recovery specialists who work with the&#xD;
      patient on support systems for longer term recovery. Although no outcomes data are available&#xD;
      for this program, it involves a rapid taper off of BUP early in the treatment regimen. In&#xD;
      most other studies, early discontinuation of BUP is associated with poorer short- and&#xD;
      long-term outcomes, and increased risk of nonfatal and fatal overdoses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Paramedic Referrals for Increased Independence and Decreased Disability in the Elderly&#xD;
      (PRIDE) program at Yale. Findings from the Department of Emergency Medicine previously&#xD;
      demonstrated that 1/3 of all seniors who activated the local 9-1-1 system due to inability to&#xD;
      get up after a fall at home would activate 9-1-1 again within the ensuing 30 days.&#xD;
      Furthermore, 2/3 of all calls to EMS for a &quot;lift assist&quot; were repeat calls to the same&#xD;
      address within the previous 30 days. By addressing some of the factors contributing to the&#xD;
      risk of falling, and by improving access to community medical resources based on individuals'&#xD;
      needs, many unplanned healthcare encounters likely could be prevented, while keeping&#xD;
      participants safely in their homes. Thus, a collaborative program between research paramedics&#xD;
      and home healthcare nurses was established. The program was funded by a Health Care&#xD;
      Innovations Award from the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services in 2014. The overarching&#xD;
      goal of Paramedic Referrals for Increased Independence and Decreased Disability in the&#xD;
      Elderly (PRIDE) was to help older individuals to live independently, while decreasing&#xD;
      requirements for unplanned utilization of EMS, EDs, and hospitalization. To be eligible to&#xD;
      participate in PRIDE, seniors must have fallen in the past or felt that they were at risk for&#xD;
      falling, resided within a 15-town area in South-Central Connecticut, and resided at home or&#xD;
      in an assisted-living facility. The program's intervention involved home visits by the PRIDE&#xD;
      Team. Health-educator paramedics, as research assistants, and nurses recorded results of&#xD;
      balance and other agility tests, participants' medications, vital signs, and performed safety&#xD;
      assessments of the living space. The home healthcare nurses evaluated gait, posture,&#xD;
      cardiovascular health and medications, requirements for durable medical equipment, and&#xD;
      ongoing care needs, such as physical or occupational therapy. All participant data were&#xD;
      entered into a Health Insurance Portability and Accountability (HIPAA)-compliant, encrypted&#xD;
      database: Research Electronic Data Capture (REDCap). Additionally, if needed, staff set up&#xD;
      appointments with the participant's primary care provider, and a free ride in a medically&#xD;
      appropriate vehicle to and from the appointment was included. Subsequent unplanned healthcare&#xD;
      utilization was tracked using the electronic medical record system at Yale New Haven Hospital&#xD;
      (YNHH). PRIDE operated from 2014-2018 and enrolled greater than 5,600 participants. Data&#xD;
      (currently unpublished) to date demonstrate that there are significantly fewer ED visits and&#xD;
      less EMS utilization among those who received PRIDE services, compared with participants who&#xD;
      enrolled but declined visits by PRIDE staff. These data suggest that PRIDE's intervention was&#xD;
      effective in decreasing unplanned healthcare utilization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Proposed adaptation of PRIDE to serve persons with OUD. We propose to adapt the PRIDE program&#xD;
      infrastructure to provide a safety net for patients who 1) have been resuscitated from an&#xD;
      opioid overdose with naloxone, 2) have screened positive for OUD using the MINI, and 3)&#xD;
      refused to initiate treatment with BUP in the ED, if offered. We may also include and accept&#xD;
      referrals from CCAR, Project Alcohol &amp; Substance Abuse Services, Education, and Referral to&#xD;
      Treatment (ASSERT) (whose recruiters work in the YNHH EDs), staff working in the Yale EDs and&#xD;
      with American Medical Response (AMR) units, and a Community Health Care Van. For this&#xD;
      program, the composition of the field teams will be changed, pairing recovery coaches from&#xD;
      CCAR with experienced PRIDE research paramedics, to form RCP Teams. For those affected by&#xD;
      moderate-severe OUD, we expect that engaging with the RCP Teams will create a more robust&#xD;
      linkage of care with community resources and treatment options. Importantly, these Teams will&#xD;
      motivate interest in treatment, facilitate access to BUP or methadone or equivalent, assist&#xD;
      with other community-based recovery strategies, help address acute psychosocial issues, and&#xD;
      provide ongoing education and counselling. The requirements for these capabilities were&#xD;
      derived from our previous qualitative studies of persons with OUD who declined ED-initiated&#xD;
      treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research plan. To date, there is no standard of care for individuals with OUD who have&#xD;
      overdosed on opioids, have been resuscitated by naloxone, and have refused BUP treatment. As&#xD;
      noted previously, YNHH typically will send home these individuals with OEN kits. However,&#xD;
      follow-up care remains variable. Hence, this research seeks to determine whether individuals&#xD;
      with OUD might benefit significantly from a novel, Team-based intervention encouraging&#xD;
      biopsychosocial and medical interventions. First, this work will assess whether a novel&#xD;
      biopsychosocial intervention following OD affects 1) the frequency of secondary opioid OD&#xD;
      events and 2) the proportion of individuals who remain engaged in treatment for OUD or are in&#xD;
      remission within 30 and 180 days post intervention. Remission may be defined as engagement in&#xD;
      daily medication-assisted therapy-typically buprenorphine/naloxone (BUP) or methadone- and/or&#xD;
      a recovery capital score of ≥ 27.5. The study's hypothesis is that the intervention by the&#xD;
      RCP team will decrease subsequent OD events and increase the likelihood of remission. This&#xD;
      work also seeks to determine whether the intervention affects 1) the frequency of&#xD;
      positive-urine tests for opioids and 2) the frequency and proportion of subjects&#xD;
      self-reporting opioid use. The hypothesis is that the intervention will decrease both. The&#xD;
      study plan is as follows: To prepare for the intervention, health educators and key study&#xD;
      staff are required to attend 12 hours of in-person training, which is to take place over 2&#xD;
      days, to learn about best practices assessing those with OUD. One of the co-principal&#xD;
      investigators (co-PIs) of this study, along with CCAR staff, will teach. Sessions will&#xD;
      include training to conduct a BNI and a brief assessment of recovery capital (BARC-10)&#xD;
      interview. Training also will prepare all staff to respectfully ask questions about potential&#xD;
      overdose events and the possibility of creating and/or implementing a wellness plan. After&#xD;
      resuscitation from opioid overdose by naloxone individuals in the EDs at the York St. and&#xD;
      Chapel St. campuses of YNHH will be screened by ED providers for OUD using a MINI. This is an&#xD;
      evidence-supported, standard practice at Yale. Upon screening positive for OUD, individuals&#xD;
      should be offered BUP treatment by staff. Those who screen positive for OUD, but who decline&#xD;
      BUP, will be offered overdose and naloxone kits. In addition, the study Team will approach&#xD;
      these individuals to ask whether they might be interested in research participation. If the&#xD;
      patient were to express interest, then the study Team members would set up an appointment&#xD;
      (remotely/electronically and/or by phone and/or in person, if appropriate) to meet at a time&#xD;
      and place of the prospective/ participant's choosing. Depending on preference informed&#xD;
      consent may be obtained in the ED or at the first outpatient visit. In addition, individuals&#xD;
      from CCAR may refer interested individuals to study participation, providing that at some&#xD;
      time in the previous 7 days they had overdosed on opioids, were resuscitated by naloxone, and&#xD;
      screened positive for OUD in a YNHH ED. After consent and study initiation, either at the&#xD;
      hospital or later, the Team will perform a BNI- whose goal is to employ motivational&#xD;
      techniques to help those with substance misuse consider their reasons for wanting to address&#xD;
      dependency. The Team will perform psychosocial and medical evaluations. The Team will also&#xD;
      enter all data into a secured, encrypted database, REDCap. Approximately 30 days after&#xD;
      consent, the Team will schedule Meeting 1 with participants. During this time, the Team will&#xD;
      collect and enter data into REDCap based on discussions with and evaluations of participants.&#xD;
      During Meeting 2, which should occur no more than 180 days after consent, the Team will also&#xD;
      collect and enter data into REDCap based on discussions with and evaluations of participants.&#xD;
      The study team will also enter data from participants' medical records at all time intervals.&#xD;
      Because of the COVID-19 outbreak, at the time of this writing (07/25/2020), many follow-up&#xD;
      visits will occur remotely/electronically, using HIPAA-compliant software + data bases,&#xD;
      and/or by phone. However, on a case-by-case basis, in-person follow up visits are permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data from the entire cohort will be compared in aggregate with patients who were started on&#xD;
      BUP in the ED over the same time period and with historic controls.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Study personnel (recovery coaches + health educators) will form teams and meet (mostly remotely/electronically and/or by phone) with participants, who will select one of three options that may help with opioid misuse:&#xD;
treatment with buprenorphine/naloxone (BUP),&#xD;
methadone maintenance, intensive outpatient, or residential treatments, or&#xD;
education only. Throughout the study, participants may switch to any other option.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of positive urine tests at 30 days (chart review)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of positive urine tests at 30 days after intervention (data obtained via chart review)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of positive urine tests at 180 days (chart review)</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of positive urine tests at 180 days after intervention (data obtained via chart review)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of positive urine tests within 30 days (self-report)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of positive urine tests within 30 days after intervention (data obtained via self-report)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of positive urine tests within 180 days (self-report)</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of positive urine tests within 180 days after intervention (data obtained via self-report)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of positive urine tests at 30 days (chart review)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of positive urine tests at 30 days after intervention (data obtained via chart review)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of positive urine tests at 180 days (chart review)</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of positive urine tests at 180 days after intervention (data obtained via chart review)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of positive urine tests within 30 days (self-report)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of positive urine tests within 30 days after intervention (data obtained via chart review)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of positive urine tests within 180 days (self-report)</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of positive urine tests within 180 days after intervention (data obtained via self-report)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Opioid-Use Disorder (OUD)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Team Intervention Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Recovery coaches and trained health educators will team together and meet with participants (remotely/electronically and/or by phone or in person, when appropriate) at least twice and for a maximum of 7 times. This includes access to mediation-assisted therapy, trained mental healthcare providers, and educational resources.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Team Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>The Team will meet with participants (remotely/electronically and/or by phone) and will ask that they select one of three options that may help with opioid addiction:&#xD;
treatment with buprenorphine/naloxone (BUP),&#xD;
inpatient, 12-step, or methadone regimens, or&#xD;
education only (materials provided by the CT Community for Addiction Recovery (CCAR)).&#xD;
Throughout the study, participants may switch to any other option.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Team Intervention Arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. ≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Screen positive for opioid use disorder (OUD)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Screen positive for OUD using the mini international neuropsychiatric interview (MINI)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. At least 1 opioid overdose requiring resuscitation by naloxone or equivalent&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. No non-opioid overdose explanation for decreased level of consciousness, miosis, or&#xD;
             decreased respiratory rate&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Positive for OUD using a health questionnaire containing questions about prescription&#xD;
             opioid and heroin use&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Not in a critically ill state at the time of consent (e.g., not actively suicidal,&#xD;
             psychotic, septic, nor cardiac arrest; nor any combination; nor equivalent)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. 3., 4., &amp; 6. (in III. Inclusion criteria) must have occurred within ≤7 days&#xD;
             (inclusive) from the date of consent if the prospective participant were discharged&#xD;
             from the hospital or equivalent treatment facility&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Not homicidal&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Able to self-consent to program/study participation&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Permanent residence is not a long-term care facility&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. No simultaneous enrollment in another study whose principal investigator (PI) or co-PI&#xD;
             is a faculty member in the Department of Emergency Medicine at the Yale School of&#xD;
             Medicine&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Not prescribed opioids for acute pain, chronic pain, or palliative care without OUD&#xD;
             diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Not stably enrolled in opioid agonist treatment for OUD at the time of the ED visit&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Neither in police custody nor incarcerated nor both; nor equivalent; *parolees and&#xD;
             those on probation may be enrolled incidentally, but are not the target population of&#xD;
             this work&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Refused buprenorphine/naloxone (BUP), if offered&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Has a valid mailing address or P.O. box&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Able to answer questions electronically/remotely, by phone, or by any combination of&#xD;
             these technologies&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. &lt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Screen negative for OUD&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Screen negative for OUD using the mini international neuropsychiatric interview (MINI)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. No evidence of documented opioid overdose requiring resuscitation by naloxone or&#xD;
             equivalent&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Non-opioid overdose explanation for decreased level of consciousness, miosis, or&#xD;
             decreased respiratory rate&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Negative for OUD using a health questionnaire containing questions about prescription&#xD;
             opioid and heroin use&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. In a critically ill state (e.g., actively suicidal, psychotic, septic, or in cardiac&#xD;
             arrest; any combination; or equivalent) at the time of consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. 3., 4., &amp; 6. (in III. Inclusion criteria) have occurred &gt;7 days (exclusive) from the&#xD;
             date of consent if the prospective participant were discharged from the hospital or&#xD;
             equivalent treatment facility&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Homicidal&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Unable to self-consent to program/study participation&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Permanent resident of a long-term care facility&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Simultaneous enrollment in another study whose principal investigator (PI) or co-PI is&#xD;
             a faculty member in the Department of Emergency Medicine&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Prescribed opioids for acute pain, chronic pain, or palliative care without OUD&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Stably enrolled in opioid agonist treatment or other medication-assisted therapy for&#xD;
             OUD at the time of consent&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. In police custody and/or incarcerated or equivalent; *parolees and those on probation&#xD;
             may be enrolled incidentally, but are not the target population of this work&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. On BUP treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. No valid mailing address or P.O. box&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Unable to answer questions electronically/remotely, by phone, or by any combination of&#xD;
             these technologies&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>130 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Daniel Joseph, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale University School of Medicine, Yale New Haven Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Daniel Joseph, MD</last_name>
    <phone>1(203)785-4404</phone>
    <email>daniel.joseph@yale.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Carolyn Brokowski, PhD (in prog)</last_name>
    <phone>1(860)874-6249</phone>
    <email>carolyn.brokowski@yale.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale New Haven Hospital, 20 York Street</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06510</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carolyn E Brokowski, ALM, MSc, PhD (in prog)</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale New Haven Hospital, Saint Raphael Campus, 1450 Chapel Street</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06511</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carolyn Brokowski, ALM, MSc, PhD (in prog.)</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>D'Onofrio G, O'Connor PG, Pantalon MV, Chawarski MC, Busch SH, Owens PH, Bernstein SL, Fiellin DA. Emergency department-initiated buprenorphine/naloxone treatment for opioid dependence: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2015 Apr 28;313(16):1636-44. doi: 10.1001/jama.2015.3474.</citation>
    <PMID>25919527</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dugosh K, Abraham A, Seymour B, McLoyd K, Chalk M, Festinger D. A Systematic Review on the Use of Psychosocial Interventions in Conjunction With Medications for the Treatment of Opioid Addiction. J Addict Med. 2016 Mar-Apr;10(2):93-103. doi: 10.1097/ADM.0000000000000193. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26808307</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Amorim P, Lecrubier Y, Weiller E, Hergueta T, Sheehan D. DSM-IH-R Psychotic Disorders: procedural validity of the Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI). Concordance and causes for discordance with the CIDI. Eur Psychiatry. 1998;13(1):26-34. doi: 10.1016/S0924-9338(97)86748-X.</citation>
    <PMID>19698595</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sheehan DV, Lecrubier Y, Sheehan KH, Amorim P, Janavs J, Weiller E, Hergueta T, Baker R, Dunbar GC. The Mini-International Neuropsychiatric Interview (M.I.N.I.): the development and validation of a structured diagnostic psychiatric interview for DSM-IV and ICD-10. J Clin Psychiatry. 1998;59 Suppl 20:22-33;quiz 34-57. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>9881538</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration. SAMHSA's working definition of recovery: 10 guiding principles of recovery. 2012. PEP12-RECDEF https://store.samhsa.gov/system/files/pep12-recdef.pdf (Accessed 1/27/2020)</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA). What are peer recovery support services? US Department of Health and Human Services; HHS Publication SMA 09-4454. http://www.samhsa.gov/recovery/peer-support-social-inclusion (Accessed 01/27/2020)</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kaplan l, Nugent C, Baker M, Clark HW, Veysey BM. Introduction: The recovery community services program. Alcoholism Treatment Quarterly 28: 244-255, 2010.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>CONNECTICUT COMMUNITY FOR ADDICTION RECOVERY (CCAR). What is a recovery coach? https://addictionrecoverytraining.org/recovery-coach-academy/ (Accessed 01/27/2020)</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>CONNECTICUT COMMUNITY FOR ADDICTION RECOVERY (CCAR). Recovery Coach Academy © https://addictionrecoverytraining.org/recovery-coach-academy/ (Accessed 01/27/2020)</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Capozzi J. Heroin epidemic: As deaths rise, program a 'glimmer of hope' for life. myPalmBeachPost. https://www.palmbeachpost.com/news/heroin-epidemic-deaths-rise-program-glimmer-hope-for-life/c8ITU5Q2lJbVFfEjSZKwpK/ (Accessed 01/27/2020)</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tracy K, Wallace SP. Benefits of peer support groups in the treatment of addiction. Subst Abuse Rehabil. 2016 Sep 29;7:143-154. eCollection 2016. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27729825</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hayes M. Fairfield County program targets opioid addiction. This Week Community News; Dec 12, 2017. http://www.thisweeknews.com/news/20171212/fairfield-county-program-targets-opioid-addiction (Accessed 01/27/2020)</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rienzi G. Johns Hopkins pilots study on EMS treatment of substance abusers. Johns Hopkins University Gazette. Sept-Oct 2014. https://hub.jhu.edu/gazette/2014/september-october/focus-baltimore-city-ems/ (Accessed 01/27/2020)</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cone DC, Ahern J, Lee CH, Baker D, Murphy T, Bogucki S. A descriptive study of the &quot;lift-assist&quot; call. Prehosp Emerg Care. 2013 Jan-Mar;17(1):51-6. doi: 10.3109/10903127.2012.717168. Epub 2012 Sep 12.</citation>
    <PMID>22971148</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yale University Section of EMS. Yale PRIDE. http://www.pride-ems.org/myself/ (Accessed 01/27/2020)</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Boscarino JA, Kirchner HL, Pitcavage JM, Nadipelli VR, Ronquest NA, Fitzpatrick MH, Han JJ. Factors associated with opioid overdose: a 10-year retrospective study of patients in a large integrated health care system. Subst Abuse Rehabil. 2016 Sep 16;7:131-141. eCollection 2016.</citation>
    <PMID>27695382</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Community Healthcare</keyword>
  <keyword>Emergency Medicine</keyword>
  <keyword>Addiction Recovery</keyword>
  <keyword>Substance Misuse</keyword>
  <keyword>Opioid Overdose</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Opioid-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

