<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04252859</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HCI128055</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04252859</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>[18F]Fluoroestradiol-PET/CT Imaging of Invasive Lobular Carcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>[18F]Fluoroestradiol-PET/CT Imaging of Invasive Lobular Carcinoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Utah</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Utah</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      FES PET/CT imaging for invasive lobular cancer&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      According to the National Comprehensive Cancer Network (NCCN) 2018 guidelines FDG-PET/CT may&#xD;
      be performed as an alternative to a contrast-enhanced CT of the chest, abdomen and pelvis and&#xD;
      Tc-99m MDP bone scan for evaluation of distant metastatic disease in newly diagnosed stage&#xD;
      III breast cancer patients. FDG-PET/CT is usually not obtained for stage I or stage II breast&#xD;
      cancer patients. Prior studies have demonstrated FDG-PET/CT can identify sites of unsuspected&#xD;
      metastatic disease in newly diagnosed breast cancer patients thereby altering treatment&#xD;
      decisions given that palliative management is typical for stage IV disease, whereas&#xD;
      neoadjuvant therapy followed by surgery and postoperative radiation may be considered for&#xD;
      stage II and operable stage III disease. These guidelines consider invasive breast cancer as&#xD;
      a single entity and do not consider whether tailoring imaging techniques for subtypes of&#xD;
      breast cancer may be beneficial. However, prior research suggests that FDG-PET/CT may be more&#xD;
      appropriate as an alternative to CT and bone scan for patients with invasive ductal carcinoma&#xD;
      (IDC) rather than invasive lobular carcinoma (ILC) as FDG demonstrates comparatively reduced&#xD;
      sensitivity for ILC metastases. Compared to IDC, ILC is more often occult on mammography,&#xD;
      ultrasound, and FDG-PET/CT; which is of importance for clinical management as ILC is more&#xD;
      often multifocal and bilateral compared to IDC. Clinical breast examination also has lower&#xD;
      sensitivity for detection of ILC compared to IDC, even for large tumors, as ILC may be&#xD;
      indistinguishable from normal breast tissue on palpation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A prior study evaluating systemic staging of newly diagnosed patients with stage I-III&#xD;
      invasive breast cancer found that FDG-PET/CT is 1.98 times less likely to reveal unsuspected&#xD;
      distant metastatic disease for women with ILC compared to IDC. In this study, all IDC&#xD;
      metastases demonstrated FDG avidity whereas 25% of ILC metastases (3 of 12) were not FDG&#xD;
      avid. Detection of local axillary metastatic disease on FDG-PET/CT was also lower for ILC (0&#xD;
      of 146 patients) compared to IDC (7 of 89 patients) despite data from the Surveillance,&#xD;
      Epidemiology and End Results (SEER) database demonstrating similar rates for lymph node&#xD;
      metastases between IDC and ILC. Another study evaluating FDG-PET/CT for the diagnosis of&#xD;
      primary breast cancer found that the false negative rate for detection of ILC by FDG was 65%&#xD;
      (15 of 23 cases) compared to 23% for IDC (23 of 97 cases) when matching for tumors of the&#xD;
      same size. A final study reported a false negative rate of FDG for ILC detection of 13% (2 of&#xD;
      15 patients). Mechanistically, ILC may not take up FDG as avidly as IDC due to lower tumor&#xD;
      microvascularity, cellular density, proliferation rate, and number of GLUT transporters. ILC&#xD;
      osseous metastatic disease is also more frequently occult on FDG-PET/CT compared to IDC as&#xD;
      ILC osseous metastases are more frequently sclerotic, whereas FDG-PET/CT is more sensitive&#xD;
      for lytic osseous metastases. Sclerotic ILC osseous metastases also may be indistinguishable&#xD;
      from benign bone islands on CT at initial staging, thereby necessitating biopsy or imaging&#xD;
      follow-up for confirmation of osseous metastatic disease. Improved imaging strategies for&#xD;
      primary and metastatic ILC are therefore warranted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Multiple studies have proven the efficacy of FES-PET/CT for imaging evaluation of ER+&#xD;
      invasive breast malignancy (evaluating both IDC and ILC together, with the large majority of&#xD;
      cases comprising IDC) but, to our knowledge, no prior study has focused FES-PET/CT evaluation&#xD;
      only to cases of ILC, nor have prior studies compared FES-PET/CT directly with FDG-PET/CT for&#xD;
      evaluation of newly diagnosed ILC. Given that all prior studies on FES-PET/CT have grouped a&#xD;
      small number of ILC cases with a larger number of IDC cases, the imaging performance of&#xD;
      FES-PET/CT specifically for ILC is unknown. ILC demonstrates higher rates of ER positivity&#xD;
      than IDC with prior studies showing greater than 90% positivity for cases of ILC. Data from&#xD;
      the SEER database also shows ILC demonstrates higher overall expression of ER than IDC (ILC&#xD;
      95% positive for ER, n=17,503 vs IDC 74% positive for ER, n=172,379). FES-PET/CT may&#xD;
      therefore be suitable for imaging evaluation of a high proportion of patients with ILC.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 11, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 4, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 4, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Positive detection rate of invasive lobular carcinoma (ILC)</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of imaging</time_frame>
    <description>Hypothesize that FES-PET/CT will detect at least 80% of histologically proven primary ILC estrogen receptor positive (ER+) tumors.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of estrogen receptor positive (ER+) ILC that does not demonstrate positive FES uptake</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of imaging</time_frame>
    <description>FES-PET/CT concordance with ER status from biopsy and presence of inter-tumoral ER heterogeneity. Focal uptake above background with SUV max of 1.5 or greater</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of estrogen receptor negative (ER-) ILC that does demonstrate positive FES uptake</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of imaging</time_frame>
    <description>FES-PET/CT concordance with ER status from biopsy and presence of inter-tumoral ER heterogeneity. Focal uptake above background with SUV max of 1.5 or greater</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of same-patient (inter-tumoral) heterogeneous FES uptake</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of imaging</time_frame>
    <description>FES-PET/CT concordance with ER status from biopsy and presence of inter-tumoral ER heterogeneity. Focal uptake above background with SUV max of 1.5 or greater. Presence of FES uptake with SUV max of 1.5 or greater in some but not all biopsy proven or suspected metastatic lesions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the rate of discordant uptake (FES positive/FDG negative or FES negative/FDG positive)</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of imaging</time_frame>
    <description>Differences between FDG- and FES PET/CT uptake. Discordant uptake will be evaluated for biopsy proven primary, any proven or suspected local nodal (axillary, intramammary, internal mammary, supraclavicular) and any proven or suspected distant metastatic lesions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the correlation of lesion uptake between FES and FDG.</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of imaging</time_frame>
    <description>Differences between FDG- and FES PET/CT uptake for cases with both FDG- and FES-PET/CT imaging,</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">19</enrollment>
  <condition>Invasive Lobular Breast Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>All Participants</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>One session of [18F]FES PET/CT Imaging</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>[18F]Fluoroestradiol (FES) PET/CT</intervention_name>
    <description>[18F]Fluoroestradiol (FES) PET/CT for invasive lobular carcinoma (ILC)</description>
    <arm_group_label>All Participants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults aged 18 years or greater&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients or legal guardians are willing and able to sign a written informed&#xD;
             consent and HIPAA authorization in accordance with local and institutional guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed invasive lobular carcinoma within the past 12 weeks confirmed&#xD;
             from biopsy of primary tumor or metastasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is willing to have their clinical records reviewed for at least 24 months&#xD;
             after enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known allergic or hypersensitivity reactions to previously administered&#xD;
             radiopharmaceuticals. Patients with significant drug or other allergies or autoimmune&#xD;
             diseases may be enrolled at the Investigator's discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who require monitored anesthesia for PET/CT scanning.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are too claustrophobic to undergo PET/CT scanning.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or current breast feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patient that is medically unstable defined as patient requiring inpatient&#xD;
             hospitalization or needing evaluation at an acute care or urgent care facility at time&#xD;
             of imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing treatment with estrogen receptor agonists (such as fulvestrant and&#xD;
             tamoxifen) within 5 weeks of the FES-PET/CT scan. (Note that aromatase inhibitors and&#xD;
             luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone agonists do not affect ER expression, or binding&#xD;
             of FES to ER, and do not need to be discontinued or considered for inclusion or&#xD;
             exclusion of patients).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who have had the site(s) of biopsy proven invasive lobular carcinoma&#xD;
             surgically resected.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Matthew Covington, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Huntsman Cancer Institute/ University of Utah</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Huntsman Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84112</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Lobular</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

