<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04253457</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>259336</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04253457</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The SToICAL Study - The Soft Tissue Injection of Corticosteroid And Local Anaesthetic Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>SToICAL</acronym>
  <official_title>The Soft Tissue Injection of Corticosteroid And Local Anaesthetic Study - A Single Site, Non-inferiority Randomised Control Trial Evaluating Pain After Soft Tissue Corticosteroid Injections With and Without Local Anaesthetic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital Plymouth NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital Plymouth NHS Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Some hand conditions can be treated with a steroid injection. Some doctors mix the steroid&#xD;
      with local anaesthetic in the hope that the patient will experience less pain after the&#xD;
      injection. Some doctors do not do this. It is not known if adding local anaesthetic to the&#xD;
      steroid improves patient's pain after the injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall aim of the study is to see whether using local anaesthetic in the steroid&#xD;
      injection makes a difference to patients' pain. If the study shows that using local&#xD;
      anaesthetic improves patients' pain then the investigators should continue using it. If not,&#xD;
      the investigators should stop giving patients unnecessary medication, which would also save&#xD;
      the NHS time and money.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is a single site, patient and assessor blinded, non-inferiority randomised control&#xD;
      trial of patients with a clinical diagnosis of trigger finger, de Quervains tenosynovitis or&#xD;
      carpal tunnel syndrome, treated with a corticosteroid injection co-administered with or&#xD;
      without local anaesthetic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim is to determine whether pain experienced during the 24 hours after a corticosteroid&#xD;
      injection to the hand and wrist is no worse than (not inferior to) the pain experienced after&#xD;
      a corticosteroid and local anaesthetic injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome is to investigate whether there is a difference in pain VAS scores at&#xD;
      1-hour after a corticosteroid injection for trigger finger, de Quervains tenosynovitis or&#xD;
      carpal tunnel syndrome co-administered with or without local anaesthetic. Secondary outcomes&#xD;
      look at differences in pain VAS scores within the first 24-hours after the injection, at the&#xD;
      time of the injection and enquires about effects on hand function.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients attending elective hand and wrist outpatient clinics at the University Hospitals&#xD;
      Plymouth NHS Trust with a clinical diagnosis of trigger finger, de Quervains tenosynovitis&#xD;
      and carpal tunnel syndrome will be screen for eligibility for recruitment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients over the age 18 years old with a clinical diagnosis of trigger finger, de&#xD;
      Quervains tenosynovitis or carpal tunnel syndrome and who are able to give written informed&#xD;
      consent for treatment will be included. Patients will be excluded if they have had previous&#xD;
      surgery or corticosteroid injection for the condition being treated at the site considered&#xD;
      for injection. A previous corticosteroid injection elsewhere in the hand does not exclude a&#xD;
      patient from the trial. Those who are pregnant, breast-feeding or who have a history of&#xD;
      hypersensitivity to corticosteroid or local anaesthetic will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will run for a 12-month period or until 100 patients have been recruited to the&#xD;
      trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Suspended</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    COVID-19&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 26, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 26, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 26, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain visual analog scale scores at 1 hour</measure>
    <time_frame>1 hour</time_frame>
    <description>Investigate whether there is a difference in pain visual analog scale scores (where 0 is no pain and 10 is the worst pain possible) at 1-hour after a corticosteroid injection for trigger finger, de Quervains tenosynovitis or carpal tunnel syndrome co-administered with or without local anaesthetic.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain visual analog scale scores during 24 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Investigate whether there is a difference in pain visual analog scale scores (where 0 is no pain and 10 is the worst pain possible) during the 24-hours after a corticosteroid injection for trigger finger, de Quervains tenosynovitis or carpal tunnel syndrome co-administered with or without local anaesthetic.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain visual analog scale score at the time of injection</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediate</time_frame>
    <description>Investigate whether there is a difference in the pain visual analog scale scores (where 0 is no pain and 10 is the worst pain possible) at the time of the corticosteroid injection for trigger finger, de Quervains tenosynovitis or carpal tunnel syndrome co-administered with or without local anaesthetic.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain and functional loss</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Investigate the difference in the additional analgesia required and in the functional use of the hand during the first 3 hours following a corticosteroid injection for trigger finger, de Quervains tenosynovitis or carpal tunnel syndrome co-administered with or without local anaesthetic.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Carpal Tunnel Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>De Quervains Tenosynovitis</condition>
  <condition>Trigger Finger</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Corticosteroid injection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single injection of 1ml of triamcinolone (40mg/1ml)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Corticosteroid and local anaesthetic injection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single injection of 1ml of triamcinolone (40mg/1ml) + 1ml 1% Lidocaine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>1ml of triamcinolone (40mg/1ml)</intervention_name>
    <description>Single injection of 1ml of triamcinolone (40mg/1ml)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Corticosteroid and local anaesthetic injection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Corticosteroid injection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female ages &gt;/= 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A clinical diagnosis of trigger finger, de Quervains tenosynovitis or carpal tunnel&#xD;
             syndrome made by a consultant physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with corticosteroid injection is recommended by the doctor and agreed by the&#xD;
             patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is willing and able to give informed consent for participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous surgery for the condition being treated at the desired location of injection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous steroid injection for the condition being treated at the desired location of&#xD;
             injection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical suspicion of local or systematic sepsis or infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hypersensitivity to the corticosteroid or local anaesthetic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast-feeding females&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to understand and complete self-report questionnaires written in English&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Charles Gozzard, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospitals Plymouth NHS Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospitals Plymouth NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Plymouth</city>
        <state>Devon</state>
        <zip>PL6 8DH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 31, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 31, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pain VAS Score</keyword>
  <keyword>Corticosteroid injection</keyword>
  <keyword>Local anaesthetic</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Trigger Finger Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tenosynovitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>De Quervain Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carpal Tunnel Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Triamcinolone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 7, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/57/NCT04253457/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 7, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/57/NCT04253457/ICF_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

