<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03867357</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1653</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03867357</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intramuscular Mechanisms of Androgen Deprivation-related Sarcopenia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Intramuscular Mechanisms of Androgen Deprivation-related Sarcopenia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Seattle Institute for Biomedical and Clinical Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United States Department of Defense</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Washington</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Seattle Institute for Biomedical and Clinical Research</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Prostate cancer (PCa) is the most common cancer among men and is even more common in the&#xD;
      military and veteran population. For patients with advanced prostate cancer, the most common&#xD;
      treatment includes lowering the levels of the hormone testosterone as much as possible. This&#xD;
      is called &quot;androgen deprivation therapy&quot; or &quot;ADT&quot;. Unfortunately, ADT also causes patients to&#xD;
      be fatigued, weak and to loose muscle. This is often referred to as &quot;sarcopenia&quot; and it leads&#xD;
      to falls, poor quality of life and higher risk of death. Currently, there is no treatment for&#xD;
      sarcopenia because the investigators do not understand the mechanisms that cause it. The&#xD;
      mitochondria is the part of the cells responsible for providing energy to muscles but to this&#xD;
      date the investigators do not know if it is affected in prostate cancer patients with&#xD;
      sarcopenia due to ADT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall goal of this proposal is to establish if the mitochondria is responsible for&#xD;
      sarcopenia in patients with prostate cancer receiving ADT. The investigators will measure&#xD;
      mitochondrial function, muscle mass and strength, and feelings of fatigue and quality of life&#xD;
      in patients with prostate cancer before starting and after 6 months of ADT.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Prostate cancer (PCa) is the most common cancer among men. Androgen deprivation therapy (ADT)&#xD;
      is the standard treatment for advanced and metastatic PCa and nearly 400,000 men remain on&#xD;
      androgen deprivation therapy (ADT) for advanced PCa in the U.S. Unfortunately, ADT also&#xD;
      induces a decrease in muscle mass and function, known as sarcopenia, a condition that leads&#xD;
      to decreased endurance, increased fatigue, falls, poor health-related quality of life&#xD;
      (HR-QOL) and increased mortality. The mechanisms underlying the development of ADT-induced&#xD;
      sarcopenia are incompletely understood and remain a significant barrier to the development of&#xD;
      therapies for this condition. Mitochondria play an essential role in generating the adenosine&#xD;
      triphosphate (ATP) needed for muscle contraction and abnormalities in mitochondria function&#xD;
      have been reported in animal models of sarcopenia. The extent to which mitochondrial&#xD;
      dysfunction mediates ADT-induced sarcopenia and muscle dysfunction is not known.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall goal of this proposal is to establish the role of mitochondrial dysfunction on&#xD;
      ADT-induced sarcopenia in patients with PCa. The investigators hypothesize that ADT in men&#xD;
      with PCa will induce mitochondrial dysfunction leading to sarcopenia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Improving scientific understanding of the mechanisms underlying sarcopenia following ADT will&#xD;
      enable investigators to develop new treatments and novel biomarkers for this disease. Given&#xD;
      that there are no available therapies for sarcopenia, this is clinically very relevant. The&#xD;
      near-term impact of this proposal will be to elucidate the extent to which mitochondrial&#xD;
      dysfunction mediates the development of sarcopenia in veterans and non-veterans with prostate&#xD;
      cancer undergoing ADT, and to evaluate the potential for these measurements at baseline to&#xD;
      serve as early predictors of disease. The outcomes that will be directly attributed to the&#xD;
      results of the proposed research include baseline and changes in muscle mass and performance,&#xD;
      in-vivo and ex-vivo mitochondrial function, and patient reported outcomes (PROs) including&#xD;
      fatigue and HR-QOL. The investigators expect that these efforts will have a major impact on&#xD;
      the goal of reducing morbidity associated with prostate cancer, and improving HR-QOL by&#xD;
      filling the gap in the knowledge of the mechanisms causing ADT-induced sarcopenia in PCa. The&#xD;
      mechanisms identified in this grant will be the target of future interventional clinical&#xD;
      trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The proposed project will address one of the PCRP overarching challenges and focus areas:&#xD;
      &quot;Survivorship including psychosocial impact on the patient&quot;. If the investigators prove the&#xD;
      hypothesis that mitochondrial dysfunction plays a significant role in the development of&#xD;
      sarcopenia, fatigue and poor HR-QOL in veterans and non-veterans with prostate cancer, the&#xD;
      multidisciplinary team that has been assembled will build on these findings and test&#xD;
      interventions currently undergoing clinical development to target mitochondria dysfunction in&#xD;
      this population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 7, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Lean body mass (LBM) change</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in LBM (kg) measured by X-ray densitometry (DEXA).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Lean body mass (LBM) change</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in LBM (kg) measured by X-ray densitometry (DEXA).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Body composition change</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Lean body mass and fat mass (kg) measured by dual energy x-ray absorptiometry (DEXA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Muscle strength change</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Hand grip strength (kg)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Muscle strength change</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Stair climb power (seconds)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Aerobic capacity change</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>VO2 max</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Daily physical activity change</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Actigraphy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Skeletal muscle mitochondrial function (in vivo)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic resonance spectroscopy (MRS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Skeletal muscle mitochondrial function (ex vivo)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Oxygen consumption rate (OCR)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality-of-life change</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>EORTC Quality of Life Questionnaire (EORTC QLQ-C30)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality-of-life change</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Expanded Prostate Cancer Index Composite (EPIC) questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality-of-life change</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-Prostate questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Degree of androgen deprivation</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Total and free testosterone levels in blood draw samples</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Androgen Deprivation Therapy</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>GnRH agonist</intervention_name>
    <description>Zoladex is a gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist, or GnRH-A. It is an implant that is injected under the skin (subcutaneously). The implant gradually dissolves and releases the drug over the time between injections. There are two dosages of Zoladex: Zoladex 10.8 mg, which is injected once every 3 months, and Zoladex 3.6 mg, which is injected once a month.</description>
    <other_name>Zoladex, Goserelin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Plasma, muscle samples&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Male Veteran patients presenting with advanced or metastatic PCa eligible for ADT in the&#xD;
        Urology clinic at the Veterans Affairs Puget Sound Health Care System.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically, cytologically, or image based documented advanced or metastatic PCa&#xD;
             initiating ADT with expected continuous treatment for a minimum of 6 months and&#xD;
             willing/able to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to provide written informed consent prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Liver disease (AST or ALT equal or more than 3x normal levels);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal failure (creatinine equal or more than 2.5 mg/dL);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Untreated thyroid disease, class III-IV CHF, AIDS;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other cancer diagnosed within the past five years other than non-melanoma skin cancer;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe COPD requiring use of home O2;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic, uncontrolled hypertension as judged by the Investigator (i.e., Baseline SBP&#xD;
             &gt;150 mm Hg, DBP &gt;90 mm Hg) or a SBP &gt; 150 mm Hg or DBP &gt; 95 mm Hg at the time of&#xD;
             screening or baseline;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An active, uncontrolled infection or cardiovascular disease including a recent&#xD;
             myocardial infarction (MI), cerebrovascular accident (CVA), arrhythmias or unstable&#xD;
             angina (&lt; 6 months);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus (as defined by a HbA1c equal or more than 9%);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Underlying muscular or neuromuscular disorder or neurologic deficit contributing to&#xD;
             sarcopenia;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Enrolled in a clinical trial involving an investigational product or non-approved use&#xD;
             of a drug/device or concurrently enrolled in medical research not scientifically or&#xD;
             medically compatible with this study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use (within one month) of testosterone, high dose steroids (20mg of&#xD;
             prednisone/day for more than 1 month), or megestrol treatment for cancer within the&#xD;
             previous 3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous treatment with ADT other than oral anti-androgen at initiation of ADT;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metal implants in the right limbs (non-MRI compatible metal stents, titanium&#xD;
             pins/markers, etc.) or implanted cardiac pacemaker or other implanted non-MRI&#xD;
             compatible cardiac device (e.g., stent);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of vascular problems (DVT, etc.)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jose M Garcia, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Veterans Affairs Puget Sound Health Care System, University of Washington</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jonathan Lee, BS</last_name>
    <phone>2062775087</phone>
    <phone_ext>65087</phone_ext>
    <email>Jonathan.Lee3@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lindsey Anderson, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>2062776719</phone>
    <phone_ext>66719</phone_ext>
    <email>Lindsey.Anderson5@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Veterans Affairs Puget Sound Health Care System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98108</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jonathan Lee, BS</last_name>
      <phone>206-277-5087</phone>
      <phone_ext>65087</phone_ext>
      <email>Jonathan.Lee3@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Lindsey Anderson, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>2062776719</phone>
      <phone_ext>66719</phone_ext>
      <email>Lindsey.Anderson5@va.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jose M Garcia, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shanely RA, Zwetsloot KA, Triplett NT, Meaney MP, Farris GE, Nieman DC. Human skeletal muscle biopsy procedures using the modified Bergström technique. J Vis Exp. 2014 Sep 10;(91):51812. doi: 10.3791/51812.</citation>
    <PMID>25285722</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 26, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 5, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 8, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Androgen deprivation therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Prostate cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Sarcopenia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sarcopenia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Goserelin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 17, 2019</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/57/NCT03867357/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

