<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02161341</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R1146/48/2014</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2014/520/A</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02161341</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ocular Surface Microbiome in Dry Eye Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Exploratory Study on the Ocular Surface Microbiome and Correlation to Clinical Parameters</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Singapore National Eye Centre</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Singapore National Eye Centre</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The ocular surface is the first line of defence of the eye, it is therefore where external&#xD;
      threats are sensed, and potential insults neutralised. Over the course of evolution, various&#xD;
      microbes, especially bacteriae, have come to colonise the ocular surface as commensals. The&#xD;
      commensals have a role to maintain the homeostasis of the ocular surface. 1 The innate&#xD;
      immunity of the ocular surface is very active, and consists of active mechanisms to suppress&#xD;
      inflammation 2. For example, there exist macrophages, dendritic cells, suppressor cells,&#xD;
      regulatory cells, B cells, IgA, lysozyme, anti-microbial peptides and barriers against&#xD;
      external agents. The normal commensals of the ocular surface maintain a basal level of&#xD;
      activation of innate defence by stimulating the pattern recognition receptors on ocular&#xD;
      surface epithelial cells. This normal composition of microbes is important since inflammation&#xD;
      and infection will result if there is introduction of a pathogenic strain that overcomes the&#xD;
      flora, or if a dominant strain secretes excessively immunogenic products, such as the&#xD;
      exotoxin A of Staphylococcus which triggers marginal keratitis, a form of type IV&#xD;
      hypersensitivity. The flora load of microbiome could also influence tear function as a higher&#xD;
      flora load was found to be associated with increased mucin degradation 3 and reduced globet&#xD;
      cell densitiy 4. Previous studies [I'm not sure which studies these are] at SERI/SNEC also&#xD;
      point to the importance of microbes. For example, in dry eye patients, there is increased&#xD;
      lysophospholipids in the tear, and this may contribute to inflammatory mediators such as&#xD;
      arachidonic acid and other metabolites. The lysophospholipids are formed by phospholipase A2&#xD;
      reactions, and the latter may be microbial in origin. Since dry eye is a known inflammatory&#xD;
      disease of the ocular surface, this is one way that microbes can contribute to the pathology.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The ocular surface is the first line of defense of the eye, it is therefore where external&#xD;
      threats are sensed, and potential insults neutralised. Over the course of evolution, various&#xD;
      microbes, especially bacteriae, have come to colonise the ocular surface as commensals. The&#xD;
      commensals have a role to maintain the homeostasis of the ocular surface. 1 The innate&#xD;
      immunity of the ocular surface is very active, and consists of active mechanisms to suppress&#xD;
      inflammation 2. For example, there exist macrophages, dendritic cells, suppressor cells,&#xD;
      regulatory cells, B cells, IgA, lysozyme, anti-microbial peptides and barriers against&#xD;
      external agents. The normal commensals of the ocular surface maintain a basal level of&#xD;
      activation of innate defence by stimulating the pattern recognition receptors on ocular&#xD;
      surface epithelial cells. This normal composition of microbes is important since inflammation&#xD;
      and infection will result if there is introduction of a pathogenic strain that overcomes the&#xD;
      flora, or if a dominant strain secretes excessively immunogenic products, such as the&#xD;
      exotoxin A of Staphylococcus which triggers marginal keratitis, a form of type IV&#xD;
      hypersensitivity. The flora load of microbiome could also influence tear function as a higher&#xD;
      flora load was found to be associated with increased mucin degradation 3 and reduced globet&#xD;
      cell densitiy 4. Previous studies [I'm not sure which studies these are] at SERI/SNEC also&#xD;
      point to the importance of microbes. For example, in dry eye patients, there is increased&#xD;
      lysophospholipids in the tear, and this may contribute to inflammatory mediators such as&#xD;
      arachidonic acid and other metabolites. The lysophospholipids are formed by phospholipase A2&#xD;
      reactions, and the latter may be microbial in origin. Since dry eye is a known inflammatory&#xD;
      disease of the ocular surface, this is one way that microbes can contribute to the pathology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The microbiome is the sum total of the microbe found in a body location. In the eye the&#xD;
      microbiome can be investigated non-invasively because of the accessible location of the&#xD;
      ocular surface. Despite the importance of the ocular surface microbiome, understanding of&#xD;
      this topic is very superficial and largely based on culture methods5-10. This can be&#xD;
      misleading because some of the microbes are not so amenable to routine cell cultures and&#xD;
      their presence may be undetected or their representation under-estimated 11. Recently&#xD;
      developed metagenomics sequencing, compared to cultures, are advantageous to get an un-biased&#xD;
      view of microbiome11.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three prior studies have evaluated the microbiome profiles of the ocular surface with&#xD;
      metagenomics sequencing of 16s rRNA 4, 12 13. Differences in microbiome were observed between&#xD;
      subjects with dry eyes or blepharitis, and healthy subjects. Moreover, a much greater&#xD;
      diversity of ocular flora was discovered compared to results based on bacterial culture.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The school of chemical and environmental life science at Nanyang Technological University has&#xD;
      evaluated the microbiomes using such techniques. The basis of this is that prokaryotic&#xD;
      organisms have unique DNA signatures which can typically characterise the species of origin,&#xD;
      and the relative prevalence of the organisms of different species can be deduced from the&#xD;
      relative abundance of the different DNA detected. The global human microbiome project seeks&#xD;
      to understand the microbiome in different parts of the human body. This is best understood in&#xD;
      the intestine, but publications on the ocular surface have yet to emerge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently our collaborators have been found that 3 bacteria dominated the ocular surface of&#xD;
      the eye. These are Klebsiella pneumoniae, Pseudoalteromonas agarivorans and Lactobacillus&#xD;
      rhamnosus. This dominance of 3 types of bacteria was unexpected, since the dominant view of&#xD;
      ocular surface commensals is that coagulase negative Staphylococcus dominates, followed by&#xD;
      Staphylococcus aureus and Streptococcus, with less gram negative bacteria, and some&#xD;
      Propionibacter spp 11. Among the 3 species, Klebsiella pneumonia is a known gram negative&#xD;
      pathogen that can cause infectious keratitis, and in some cases endophthalmitis. The roles of&#xD;
      Pseudoalteromonas and Lactobacillus are entirely unknown. The former is a non-pathogenic free&#xD;
      living gram negative bacteria known to be present in marine settings. Surprisingly the high&#xD;
      levels of the 3 predominant bacteria are relatively constant among the 3 human participants,&#xD;
      suggesting a certain amount of uniformity in the colonisation of the ocular surface by major&#xD;
      bacteria microbes in non-diseased individuals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The ocular surface microbiome can be studied by sterile swapping of the inferior fornix of&#xD;
      the conjunctiva followed by homogenisation and extraction of DNA. The presence of bacteria&#xD;
      DNA does not inform on the function of the microbes, since even dead and non-proliferating&#xD;
      organisms have remnant DNA. The technique of collecting samples can also yield RNA, and from&#xD;
      reverse transcription PCR, it is possible to determine the presence of specific microbial&#xD;
      transcripts that are found in the ocular surface. Furthermore, our collaborators from Nanyang&#xD;
      Polytechnic have pioneered MALDI TOF mass spectrometry techniques that allow the&#xD;
      characterisation of bacterial proteomes, based on identification of unique bacterial peptide&#xD;
      sequences. Together, these techniques of bacteria transcript and protein investigations&#xD;
      permit evaluation of the gene expression and to some extent, functional status of the&#xD;
      bacteria discovered. This would be extremely important in the case of microbes that have not&#xD;
      been previously discovered on the ocular surface.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Apart from the obvious academic and scientific advance, this project also has medical&#xD;
      implications and potential new Intellectual property for commercial applications. First,&#xD;
      understanding of the microbiome is the first step to treat certain types of diseases such as&#xD;
      marginal keratitis and unusual infectious keratitis. It suggests how the immune system can be&#xD;
      manipulated for treatment. Secondly, prevention of diseases and inflammation may be achieved&#xD;
      by probiotic administration of living microbes to colonise the ocular surface. Third, the&#xD;
      study may lead to new techniques and assays that identify microbes and their components which&#xD;
      can be developed into clinical diagnostic assays.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We have some industry collaborators who are interested to partner us to develop some of these&#xD;
      ideas.&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
      We aim to conduct an exploratory study to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Determine the composition of the bacterial microbiome of the human ocular surface in&#xD;
           normal volunteers and dry eye patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Determine the bacterial gene expression (bacterial transcripts) found in the human&#xD;
           ocular surface.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Characterise any feature of the microbiome that may be linked to clinical&#xD;
           characteristics such as age, status of tearfilm, Meibomian gland dysfunction, exposure&#xD;
           to environmental stimulation such as smoking, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2. EXPECTED RIKS AND BENEFITS Expected risks No potential problems are expected for this&#xD;
      study. However, there will be some slight discomfort during the collection of microbiome from&#xD;
      the lower conjunctival fornix. Non-preservative tetracaine will be given to the patient to&#xD;
      minimise any discomfort. There will also be some slight discomfort during the Schimers I&#xD;
      test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential benefits With greater understanding of the presence of various microbiome in the&#xD;
      ocular surface, we can gain further insight into the complex process taking place.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3. STUDY POPULATION 3.1. List the number and nature of subjects to be enrolled. 90 subjects&#xD;
      will be recruited from SNEC dry eye clinic and general clinic serviced by the Principal&#xD;
      Investigator. 45 subjects without dry eye symptoms will be recruited as normal controls and&#xD;
      45 subjects with symptomatic dry eye will be recruited as dry eye subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.2. Criteria for Recruitment and Recruitment Process&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To recruit normal controls- All the 8 questions on dry eye symptoms must be clear of dry&#xD;
           eye symptoms during the pre-screening stage. (Appendix 1) Questionnaire modified after&#xD;
           Schein et al.,1997. To recruit dry eye subjects- At least one out of the 8 questions on&#xD;
           dry eye symptoms must be ≥ grade 3&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Subjects meet all the inclusion criteria listed below.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Clear of exclusion criteria. Permission would be sought from the attending doctors&#xD;
           before subjects are being recruited. Eligible subjects will be counselled on the study&#xD;
           by study coordinator. If the subject is interested, the study coordinator will then&#xD;
           accompany the subject to SERI level 5 for the relevant assessments. Informed written&#xD;
           consent will be obtained from all participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.3. Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject must meet all of the inclusion criteria to participate in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Subjects must be 21 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Willing to perform all the eye examinations in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.4. Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
      All subjects meeting any of the exclusion criteria at baseline will be excluded from&#xD;
      participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Known history of thyroid disorders (diagnosed by physician).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Known history of Sjogren syndrome or rheumatoid arthritis (diagnosed by physician).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. No ocular surgery within the last 3 months and LASIK within 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Ocular surface diseases such as pterygium, or obvious lid/orbital disease with&#xD;
           lagophthalmos.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Any other specified reason as determined by clinical investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      4. STUDY DESIGN AND PROCEDURES/METHODOLOGY&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Observational -Cross sectional study&#xD;
&#xD;
      No. of visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
      There will only be 1 visit in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Duration of Study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Collection of Medical history and Dry Eye Questionnaire There will be some questionnaire&#xD;
      which consists of medical history and a standard set of dry eye questionnaires which&#xD;
      identifies factors such as contact lens use, smoking, occupation and etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Non-Invasive Tear Break-Up Time (OCULUS K5M) Non-Invasive Tear Break-Up Time is measured&#xD;
      non-invasively and fully automatically using OCULUS K5M. The new infrared illumination is not&#xD;
      visible to the human eye. This prevents glare during the examination. Patient will sit&#xD;
      comfortably in front of the instrument and blink freely while fixing on a target directly&#xD;
      ahead. Once the participant is ready, they will be instructed to blink twice and refrain from&#xD;
      blinking. Keratograph 5M is fully automated and it will capture any break or distortion in&#xD;
      the image and the time of the break will be noted. Three readings will be taken for each eye&#xD;
      to get the average value.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conjunctiva redness (OCULUS K5M) Conjunctiva redness will be assessed using OCULUS K5M.&#xD;
      Patient will sit comfortably in front of the instrument while fixing on a target directly&#xD;
      ahead. Imaged will be captured and an overview display of conjunctiva redness will be&#xD;
      evaluated by &quot;JENVIS Grading Scale&quot;. JENVIS scale range from 0 to 4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Redness value Definition 0 No findings, eg. Babies or infants&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Single injections, standard value for adults&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Mild diffuse injections&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Severe local injections&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Severe diffuse injections&#xD;
&#xD;
      Collection of microbiome Two specimens of microbiome will be collected from both eyes. First:&#xD;
      a drop of non-preserved tetracaine will be instilled into the conjunctival fornix. After the&#xD;
      stinging sensation has resolved, a sterile cotton swap will be used to collect the microbes&#xD;
      from the lower conjunctival fornix using a gentle rolling action (up to 8 strokes). The&#xD;
      procedure is then repeated for the opposite eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These swaps will then be soaked in DNA/RNA Shield (Zymo) reagent and immediately homogenised&#xD;
      for 1 minute, stop at 30 seconds, and keep on ice for 1 minute, and homogenized for another&#xD;
      30 seconds. Homogenised samples will be stored at 4°C. This ensures an optimal and sufficient&#xD;
      DNA/RNA yield for our purpose. Subsequent nucleic acid extraction, PCR, sequencing, and&#xD;
      bioinformatics procedures will be performed by our collaborators.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Storage: intended to be analysed within a year, not more than 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Corneal fluorescein staining (OCULUS K5M) A drop of normal saline will be instilled on the&#xD;
      fluorescein strip (Fluorets) then shaken off so that no visible drop remains. The subject is&#xD;
      asked to look up before the introduction of the fluoret to the inferior conjunctival fornix&#xD;
      on the right then left eye. Corneal fluorescein staining will be imaged by Keratograph 5M.&#xD;
      Scoring system will be based on CCLRU. Briefly, there will be 5 corneal zones. The staining&#xD;
      scale is 0-4, with 0.5 unit steps in each of the zones. Lastly, a picture of the fluorescein&#xD;
      stained cornea will be taken.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Schirmers I test This will be done with the standard strips currently used at SERI (5 mm wide&#xD;
      with a notch for folding) (Schirmer Tear Test Strips, Clement Clarke International, UK). No&#xD;
      prior anesthetic will be used. The strips will be positioned over the inferior temporal half&#xD;
      of the lower lid margin in both eyes at the same time. The study participant will be asked to&#xD;
      close their eyes. Any excessive irritation signs will be noted. The extent of the wetting in&#xD;
      each strip will be recorded after 5 minutes of testing. The strip will be collected and&#xD;
      stored in 1.5ml eppendorf tubes at -80˚C until further analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>bacterial microbiome</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the composition of the bacterial microbiome of the human ocular surface in normal volunteers and dry eye patients</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gene expression</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the bacterial gene expression (bacterial transcripts) found in the human ocular surface.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical characteristic</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Characterise any feature of the microbiome that may be linked to clinical characteristics such as age, status of tearfilm, Meibomian gland dysfunction, exposure to environmental stimulation such as smoking, etc</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">82</enrollment>
  <condition>Dry Eye</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Microbiome swab will be collected from the inferior fornix of the lower eyelids to determine&#xD;
      composition of the bacterial microbiome of the human ocular surface in normal volunteers and&#xD;
      dry eye patients&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Dry eye patients and healthy normal volunteers&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must be 21 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to perform all the eye examinations in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of thyroid disorders (diagnosed by physician).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of Sjogren syndrome or rheumatoid arthritis (diagnosed by physician).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No ocular surgery within the last 3 months and LASIK within 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ocular surface diseases such as pterygium, or obvious lid/orbital disease with&#xD;
             lagophthalmos.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other specified reason as determined by clinical investigator.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Singapore Eye Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Singapore</city>
        <zip>168751</zip>
        <country>Singapore</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Singapore</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 9, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 9, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 11, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 29, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 29, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 31, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Singapore National Eye Centre</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Louis Tong</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinician-Scientist, Senior Consultant</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Bacterial microbiome</keyword>
  <keyword>Gene expression</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dry Eye Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Keratoconjunctivitis Sicca</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

