<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04434560</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00103812</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>CA184-583</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04434560</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neoadjuvant Immunotherapy in Brain Metastases</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Trial of Surgery and Stereotactic Radiosurgery With Neoadjuvant Nivolumab and Ipilimumab in Patients With Surgically-resectable, Solid Tumor Brain Metastases</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sarah Sammons, MD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bristol-Myers Squibb</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Duke University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Duke University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this phase 2 study is to assess the feasibility and efficacy of neoadjuvant&#xD;
      immunotherapy in patients with previously untreated, surgically-resectable, solid tumor brain&#xD;
      metastases. The primary objectives of this study are to 1) assess the feasibility of&#xD;
      neoadjuvant ipilimumab and nivolumab treatment before surgery and stereotactic radiosurgery&#xD;
      (SRS) in patients with solid tumor brain metastases as measured by the proportion of patients&#xD;
      who have their surgery delayed or surgery never occurs, and 2) demonstrate that neoadjuvant&#xD;
      immunotherapy will increase proliferation of circulating T-cells compared to baseline&#xD;
      measurements. Exploratory objectives include describing patient progression free survival and&#xD;
      overall survival, time to local and distant intracranial progression, and the rate of&#xD;
      radiation necrosis. The rate of radionecrosis will also be explored, as immune expression&#xD;
      profiles.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Forty patients planned for standard of care resection of at least one solid tumor brain&#xD;
      metastasis will be enrolled onto the study after providing informed consent. Primary tumor&#xD;
      histology types are restricted to those known to extracranially respond to immunotherapy, and&#xD;
      will include, but not be limited to, squamous non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC),&#xD;
      non-squamous NSCLC without known anaplastic lymphoma kinase (ALK), epidermal growth factor&#xD;
      receptor (EGFR), and ROS mutation, renal cell carcinoma (RCC), melanoma, and triple negative&#xD;
      breast cancer (TNBC) that is programmed death-ligand 1 positive (PD-L1 +). All participants&#xD;
      will receive neoadjuvant immunotherapy and will receive a single infusion of nivolumab at a&#xD;
      dose of 3 mg/kg and ipilimumab at a dose of 1 mg/kg 7 days (±3 days) prior to surgical&#xD;
      resection of their metastases. Approximately three weeks after resection, patients in will&#xD;
      then receive SRS per standard of care guidelines. Patients will be followed for 18 months&#xD;
      after initiating study treatment. Up to 20 participants will be recruited and treated. Blood&#xD;
      will be collected periodically during the study for correlative assessments.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Poor enrollment&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 4, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 17, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 17, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients that receive neoadjuvant ipilimumab and nivolumab prior to surgery and SRS</measure>
    <time_frame>10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients who have their surgery delayed by more than 4 days or surgery never occurs as a direct or indirect result of ipilimumab and nivolumab treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proliferation of circulating T-cells</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Mean fold-change between baseline and day 1 in Ki67 levels.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1</enrollment>
  <condition>Brain Metastases, Adult</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Neoadjuvant Immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive a single dose of neoadjuvant nivolumab and ipilimumab 7 days (± 3 days) prior to surgical resection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nivolumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Nivolumab will be given at the FDA-approved dose of 3 mg/kg.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Neoadjuvant Immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Opdivo</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ipilimumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Ipilimumab will be given at the FDA-approved dose of 1 mg/kg.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Neoadjuvant Immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Yervoy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Patients must have at least 1 previously untreated, solid tumor brain metastases&#xD;
             that are ≤4 cm in the largest direction. At least one of the metastases must be&#xD;
             surgically resectable. All metastases must be planned for treatment with SRS. Primary&#xD;
             tumor histology must be one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Squamous NSCLC&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Non-squamous NSCLC without known ALK, EGFR, and ROS mutation&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. RCC&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Urothelial carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Ovarian carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Melanoma&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Triple negative breast cancer that is PD-L1 positive&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Other solid tumor histologies may be eligible at the discretion of the PI if they&#xD;
                  are known to respond to immunotherapy containing regimens.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  2. Patient must be asymptomatic or minimally symptomatic, requiring the equivalent of&#xD;
             ≤ 4 mg dexamethasone daily for at least 7 days prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  3. Patient or partner(s) meets one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Non-childbearing potential (i.e. not sexually active, physiologically incapable&#xD;
                  of becoming pregnant, including any female who is post-menopausal or surgically&#xD;
                  sterile, or any male who has had a vasectomy). Surgically sterile females are&#xD;
                  defined as those with a documented hysterectomy and/or bilateral oophorectomy or&#xD;
                  tubal ligation. Postmenopausal for purposes of this study is defined as 1 year&#xD;
                  without menses.; or&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Childbearing potential and agrees to use one of the following methods of birth&#xD;
                  control: approved hormonal contraceptives (e.g. birth control pills, patches,&#xD;
                  implants, or infusions), an intrauterine device, or a barrier method of&#xD;
                  contraception (e.g. a condom or diaphragm) used with spermicide.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  4. Age ≥ 18 years of age at the time of entry into the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  5. Karnofsky Performance Score (KPS) ≥ 70&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  6. Prothrombin and Partial Thromboplastin Times ≤ 1.2 x normal prior to resection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  7. Neutrophil count ≥ 1000 prior to resection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  8. Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dl prior to resection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  9. Platelet count ≥ 100,000/µl unsupported is necessary for eligibility on the study;&#xD;
             however, because of risks of intracranial hemorrhage during resection, platelet count&#xD;
             ≥ 125,000/µl is required for the patient to undergo resection, which can be attained&#xD;
             with the help of platelet transfusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  10. Creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN prior to resection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  11. A signed informed consent form approved by the Institutional Review Board (IRB)&#xD;
             will be required for patient enrollment into the study. Patients must be able to read&#xD;
             and understand the informed consent document and must sign the informed consent&#xD;
             indicating that they are aware of the investigational nature of this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  12. Ability to undergo MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Females who are pregnant or breast-feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  2. Patients with an impending, life-threatening cerebral herniation syndrome, based on&#xD;
             the assessment of the study neurosurgeons or their designate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  3. Patients with severe, active co-morbidity, defined as follow:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients with an active infection requiring intravenous treatment or having an&#xD;
                  unexplained febrile illness (Tmax &gt; 99.5°F/37.5°C)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patients with known immunosuppressive disease or known uncontrolled human&#xD;
                  immunodeficiency virus infection&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Patients with unstable or severe intercurrent medical conditions such as severe&#xD;
                  heart disease (New York Heart Association Class 3 or 4)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  4. Patients who have not recovered from the toxic effects of prior chemo- and/or&#xD;
             radiation therapy. Guidelines for this recovery period are dependent upon the specific&#xD;
             therapeutic agent being used:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  5. Patients must not have received immunotherapy within 3 months prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  6. Patients with prior, unrelated malignancy requiring current active treatment in the&#xD;
             last 3 years with the exception of cervical carcinoma in situ and adequately treated&#xD;
             basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  7. Patients with a known history of hypersensitivity to nivolumab, or any components&#xD;
             of nivolumab&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  8. Patients with a known history of hypersensitivity to ipilimumab, or any components&#xD;
             of ipilimumab&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  9. Patients with active autoimmune disease requiring systemic immunomodulatory&#xD;
             treatment within the past 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  10. History and/or confirmed pneumonitis, or extensive bilateral lung disease on high&#xD;
             resolution/spiral CT scan.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sarah Sammons, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Duke University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://tischbraintumorcenter.duke.edu/</url>
    <description>The Preston Robert Tisch Brain Tumor Center</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.dukehealth.org/clinical-trials</url>
    <description>Duke Health</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 12, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Duke University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sarah Sammons, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pro00103812</keyword>
  <keyword>Sammons</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-small-cell lung carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Renal cell carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Urothelial carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Melanoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Ovarian carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Triple negative breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Solid tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>Brain metastases</keyword>
  <keyword>Nivolumab</keyword>
  <keyword>Ipilimumab</keyword>
  <keyword>Opdivo</keyword>
  <keyword>Yervoy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Second Primary</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ipilimumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

