<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02784288</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UMCC 2015.126</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>HUM00105447</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02784288</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase II Treatment Stratification Trial Using Neck Dissection-Driven Selection to Improve Quality of Life for Low Risk Patients With HPV+ Oropharyngeal Squamous Cell Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Treatment Stratification Trial Using Neck Dissection-Driven Selection to Improve Quality of Life for Low Risk Patients With HPV+ Oropharyngeal Squamous Cell Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Michigan Rogel Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Michigan Rogel Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Investigators will determine whether a treatment paradigm of up-front neck dissection, to&#xD;
      more accurately pathologically stage patients, minimizing the number of treatment modalities&#xD;
      in patients with low risk oropharyngeal squamous cell carcinoma, can improve quality of life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      After enrollment, all patients will undergo neck dissection and primary site biopsy.&#xD;
      Pathology will be reviewed, and patients will proceed into one of three standard-of-care&#xD;
      (SOC) treatment groups. The treatments themselves are not the focus of this study; the focus&#xD;
      of this study is quality of life in this population, after a pathology-based treatment plan,&#xD;
      to assess the utility of the investigational &quot;neck dissection first&quot; paradigm. The SOC&#xD;
      treatment plans are as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patients with a single lymph node that measures less than six centimeters, have no&#xD;
           extracapsular extension in the lymph node, and have no perineural or perivascular&#xD;
           invasion of the primary biopsy will undergo transoral surgery of the primary site.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Patients who have 2 positive nodes with no extracapsular extension, or have perineural&#xD;
           or perivascular invasion of the primary biopsy will undergo radiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Patients who have extracapsular extension in any number of lymph nodes or in those&#xD;
           patients in whom negative margins are unable to be obtained after the completion of&#xD;
           transoral surgery will undergo chemoradiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of therapy (surgical, radiation, or combined modality) patients will be&#xD;
      followed closely on an outpatient basis including regular exams, quality of life&#xD;
      questionnaires, and interval surveillance imaging as clinically indicated. Swallowing&#xD;
      function will also be addressed by videofluoroscopy one year after completion of therapy.&#xD;
      Blood/plasma and oral rinses for correlative studies will be collected at 3-month intervals&#xD;
      during 3 years of follow up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study was initially registered as if it were an inter-group comparison; however, the&#xD;
      original and consistent intent has been to determine whether a treatment paradigm of neck&#xD;
      dissection guided staging as a whole can minimize the number of standard treatment methods&#xD;
      used, leading to improved quality of life in low risk patients with HPV+ oropharyngeal&#xD;
      squamous cell cancer. Though certain groups are expected to need multimodal definitive&#xD;
      treatment downstream of the experimental &quot;neck dissection first&quot; paradigm, the population&#xD;
      must be assessed as one group in this trial to assess the utility of the paradigm.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 31, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 10, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Median change in Quality of Life (QOL) from baseline to 12 months post treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 Months post-treatment (up to approximately 15 months post neck dissection)</time_frame>
    <description>Four QOL instruments will be administered: the University of Washington Quality of Life (UWQOL), University of Michigan Head and Neck Quality of Life Instrument (HN-QOL), the University of Michigan Voice Related Quality of Life Measure (V-RQOL), and the FACT Head and Neck (version 4) (FACT H&amp;N). Results of each of the 4 surveys will be reported in separate rows in the results table. The difference in scores from baseline to 12 months after completion of study treatment is calculated for each participant, with the median across all participants reported for each survey.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact of neck dissection on shoulder function using the Neck Dissection Impairment Index</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years post-treatment (up to approximately 27 months post neck dissection)</time_frame>
    <description>The neck dissection impairment index will be scored and summarized for all patients who receive neck dissection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median change in Quality of Life (QOL) from baseline to 24 months post treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years post-treatment (up to approximately 27 months post neck dissection)</time_frame>
    <description>Four QOL instruments will be administered: the University of Washington Quality of Life (UWQOL), University of Michigan Head and Neck Quality of Life Instrument (HN-QOL), the University of Michigan Voice Related Quality of Life Measure (V-RQOL), and the FACT Head and Neck (version 4) (FACT H&amp;N). Results of each of the 4 surveys will be reported in separate rows in the results table. The difference in scores from baseline to 24 months after completion of study treatment is calculated for each participant, with the median across all participants reported for each survey.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Specific Survival (DSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Years</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients alive at 3 years from date of neck dissection. Death from OPSCC (Oropharyngeal Squamous Cell Cancer) will be considered an event for DSS. Death from other causes will be censored at time of death.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Years</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients alive and free of disease persistence, progression or recurrence at 3 years from the date of completion of study treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Years</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients alive at 3 years from date of neck dissection. Death from any cause will be considered an event for overall survival.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Financial Toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>University of Michigan (UM) Financial and Work survey, scored per UM guidelines</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Financial Toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Comprehensive Score for Financial Toxicity (COST), scored according to Functional Assessment of Chronic Illness Therapy (FACIT) guidelines.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">34</enrollment>
  <condition>Oropharyngeal Squamous Cell Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Neck Dissection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients undergo up-front neck dissection of the cervical lymph nodes to determine stratification into one of three standard-of-care treatment groups: transoral surgery of the primary site, radiation or chemoradiation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Neck Dissection</intervention_name>
    <description>All patients will undergo neck dissection of the cervical lymph nodes</description>
    <arm_group_label>Neck Dissection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard-of-Care (SOC) Transoral Surgery of Primary Site</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients with a single lymph node that measures less than six centimeters, have no extracapsular extension in the lymph node, and have no perineural or perivascular invasion of the primary biopsy will undergo transoral surgery of the primary site.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Neck Dissection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SOC Radiation</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients who have 2 positive nodes with no extracapsular extension, or have perineural or perivascular invasion of the primary biopsy will undergo radiation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Neck Dissection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SOC Carboplatin</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients who have extracapsular extension in any number of lymph nodes or in those patients in whom negative margins are unable to be obtained after the completion of transoral surgery will undergo chemoradiation (Radiation, Carboplatin and Paclitaxel).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Neck Dissection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SOC Paclitaxel</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients who have extracapsular extension in any number of lymph nodes or in those patients in whom negative margins are unable to be obtained after the completion of transoral surgery will undergo chemoradiation (Radiation, Carboplatin and Paclitaxel).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Neck Dissection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Videofluoroscopy</intervention_name>
    <description>All patients undergo a videofluoroscopy procedure one year after completion of therapy to assess swallowing function.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Neck Dissection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have pathologically-confirmed, previously untreated, p16-positive&#xD;
             oropharyngeal squamous cell carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have pretreatment neck and chest imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tumors must be potentially surgically resectable via a transoral approach, at the&#xD;
             discretion of the treating surgeon&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with T stage T1-3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with N stage N0-N2c&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status: an attempt to quantify&#xD;
             cancer patients' general well-being and activities of daily life. The score ranges&#xD;
             from 0 to 5 where 0 is asymptomatic and 5 is death.) Performance status 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients are adults (Age &gt;18)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must agree to biospecimen submission for tissue and serum processing and&#xD;
             storage for secondary biomarker studies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must give documented informed consent to participate in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth&#xD;
             control) prior to study entry, for the duration of chemoradiation (treatment) and for&#xD;
             3 months after discontinuing treatment. Women of childbearing potential must have a&#xD;
             negative serum or urine pregnancy test within 3 days prior to starting treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child-bearing potential, unless they are using highly effective methods of&#xD;
             contraception during dosing and for 30 days after study treatment. Women not of&#xD;
             childbearing potential will be defined as all women older than age 50 and anovulatory&#xD;
             for 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexually active males must use a condom during intercourse while receiving&#xD;
             chemoradiation and for 90 days after stopping treatment and should not father a child&#xD;
             in this period. A condom is required to be used also by vasectomized men in order to&#xD;
             prevent delivery of the drug via seminal fluid. Likewise, male subjects should not&#xD;
             donate sperm during the time they are receiving chemoradiation and for 90 days after&#xD;
             stopping treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior head and neck radiation or prior chemotherapy for HNSCC (Head and Neck Squamous&#xD;
             Cell Carcinoma)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with T4 disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with N3 disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  FNA evidence of squamous cell carcinoma involving 3 or more lymph nodes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with matted lymph nodes, defined as three nodes abutting one another with&#xD;
             loss of intervening fat plane that is a replaced with radiologic evidence of&#xD;
             extracapsular spread&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with an outside primary site biopsy showing perineural or perivascular&#xD;
             invasion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented evidence of distant metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients residing in prison.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Class 3 or 4 cardiac disease as defined by the New York Heart Association Functional&#xD;
             Classification&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unstable angina or a history of myocardial ischemia within prior 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any of the following laboratory values at baseline:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt; 1,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets &lt; 75,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin &lt; 9.0 gm/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Calculated or measured creatinine clearance (method determined by the prescribing&#xD;
                  physicians) &lt; 50 ml/min&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilirubin &gt; 1.5 x ULN (Upper Limit of Normal), except for patients with known&#xD;
                  Gilbert syndrome who are excluded if total bilirubin &gt; 3.0 x ULN or direct&#xD;
                  bilirubin &gt; 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate transaminase (AST) &gt; 3.0 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine transaminase (ALT) &gt; 3.0 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or breastfeeding female.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other severe, acute, or chronic medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory&#xD;
             abnormality that may increase the risk associated with study participation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Paul Swiecicki, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Michigan Rogel Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Michigan Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 24, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 24, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 27, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <disposition_first_submitted>June 28, 2021</disposition_first_submitted>
  <disposition_first_submitted_qc>June 28, 2021</disposition_first_submitted_qc>
  <disposition_first_posted type="Actual">June 30, 2021</disposition_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>head and neck neoplasms</keyword>
  <keyword>HPV</keyword>
  <keyword>human papilloma virus</keyword>
  <keyword>de-escalation</keyword>
  <keyword>low-risk</keyword>
  <keyword>oropharyngeal cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted, but a results disposition has been submitted           -->
</clinical_study>

