<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04909827</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PED 20-6D</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04909827</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>3D-printed Endocrowns Versus Prefabricated Zirconia Crowns in Pulpally-treated Primary Molars</brief_title>
  <official_title>3D-printed Endocrowns Versus Prefabricated Zirconia Crowns for the Restoration of Pulpally-treated Primary Molars ; In-Vivo and In-Vitro Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ain Shams University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ain Shams University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aim of the study :&#xD;
&#xD;
      to compare between 3D printed microfilled hybrid composite endocrowns and prefabricated&#xD;
      zirconia crowns for restoring pulpally treated primary molars regarding the following&#xD;
      aspects: In Vivo aspects Patient satisfaction&#xD;
&#xD;
      *The esthetic, functional and biological performance according to FDI clinical criteria. At&#xD;
      3, 6 and 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Vitro aspects:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Marginal gap.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Fracture resistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study methodology:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is a combined randomized clinical trial and in vitro study .The study will be&#xD;
      conducted at the Department of Pediatric Dentistry and Dental Public Health, Faculty of&#xD;
      Dentistry,&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ain Shams University as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In vivo comparison of the clinical performance of 3D printed Endocrowns versus prefabricated&#xD;
      zirconia crowns regarding esthetic, functional and biological performance according to FDI&#xD;
      clinical criteria. In vitro evaluation of the marginal gap and fracture resistance of both&#xD;
      types of restorations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Procedure:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In-vivo Phase:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of thirty primary mandibular molars in healthy subjects will be selected from the&#xD;
      Pediatric Dentistry and Dental Public Health outpatient clinic, Faculty of Dentistry, Ain&#xD;
      Shams University. Randomization The molars will be assigned to one of the 2 groups using a&#xD;
      generated computer list Allocation The molars will be allocated to the groups via a third&#xD;
      party not involved with the study They will have the generated list and inform the allocation&#xD;
      accordingly Blinding Is not possible due to the obvious difference between the 2 Pulpotomy&#xD;
      procedure for both groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Local anesthesia will be administered.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Teeth will be isolated by a Rubber Dam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Teeth will undergo pulpotomy procedure' as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Caries will be removed using a large size 4 round bur, mounted onto a high speed hand piece&#xD;
      with constant coolant. All access cavity walls are to be flared to allow complete exposure of&#xD;
      the pulp chamber, and easy undisturbed access to the canals, followed by removal of all the&#xD;
      soft pulpal tissue tags by a sharp spoon shaped excavator. Bleeding will be controlled using&#xD;
      moist cotton pellet with gentle pressure. Formocresol will be applied through a cotton pellet&#xD;
      for 5 mins, for fixation. The pulp chamber will be filled with reinforced zinc oxide and&#xD;
      eugenol ( that will be mixed according to manufacturer s instructions. A 0.5 mm layer of&#xD;
      Resin modified glass ionomer is then applied to the cavity floor and light cured for 40 secs,&#xD;
      to isolate the zinc oxide eugenol paste, and block unwanted undercuts Analgesics will be&#xD;
      prescribed to the patient to be taken when needed&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention :group A:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The cavities will be prepared so as to receive endocrowns:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Occlusal preparation: achieved by drilling, 2mm depth grooves using diamond stone as&#xD;
           guides for reduction of the occlusal surface. axial preparation: using a 7 degree taper&#xD;
           diamond stone, eliminating undercuts in the access cavity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. impression for the preparation is taken using putty and light poly vinyl siloxane&#xD;
           material&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Light cured temporary filling will be placed in the cavity as temporisation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. The impression will be sent to the lab and the patient is dismissed&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. The preparation will be optically scanned in the lab and the restoration will be&#xD;
           digitally designed using computer designing software.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. The restoration will be printed using 3D printer using microfilled hybrid composite&#xD;
           material.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. During the second visit the temporary is removed the restoration is cemented by self&#xD;
           adhesive resin after etching and bonding the cavity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control Group B:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Crown reduction:&#xD;
&#xD;
           reduction will be performed on the occlusal surface disregarding the occlusal anatomy&#xD;
           using a flame stone or a wheel stone, to perform occlusal clearance. Then reduction will&#xD;
           be performed on the mesial, distal, buccal and lingual surfaces of the tooth to&#xD;
           compensate for the thickness of the zirconia crowns. Reduction will first be performed&#xD;
           using fine needle stone to free the contact from the adjacent teeth then followed by&#xD;
           reduction of the other surfaces using a diamond stone. Roundation of the line angles&#xD;
           will be performed&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Zirconia crowns that match the size of the tooth will be selected putting into&#xD;
           consideration that no undercuts should be present to avoid crown fracture.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. . After checking the size of the crowns, it will be removed, drie d and cemented on the&#xD;
           tooth using (3M™ ESPE™ KETAC™ CEM) that will be mixed according to manufacturer's&#xD;
           instructions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Pressure will be applied on the crown, and any excess cement will be removed after it&#xD;
           hardens. All children and parents will be give n strict oral hygiene instructions and&#xD;
           dietary instructions Teeth not included in the study will be scheduled for dental&#xD;
           treatment in the Department of Pediatric Dentistry, Faculty of Dentistry, Ain Shams&#xD;
           University. Outcome measurement&#xD;
&#xD;
      Esthetic functional biological criteria will be evaluated in the following order:&#xD;
&#xD;
      After cementation evaluation: patients will be evaluated according to FDI criteria as&#xD;
      previously mentioned,.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Vitro phase:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All soft tissue debris will be removed by a hand scaler and teeth will be disinfect ed, and&#xD;
      then stored in distilled water at 4 degrees Celsius until the start of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The molars will undergo pulpotomy procedures and filled as previously described. The molars&#xD;
      will be randomly divided into two groups Group A: Will receive 3D printed Endocrowns Group B:&#xD;
      Will receive prefabricated zirconia crowns The specimens will be embedded perpendicularly in&#xD;
      Polyvinyl chloride ( cubes with the occlusal surface parallel to the ground using acrylic&#xD;
      resin extending 2mm b elow the cemento enamel junction. The following will be measured:&#xD;
      Marginal gap Precementation measurements of the cervical vertical marginal discrepancies will&#xD;
      be performed before cementation. For each specimen, four stereomicrographs will be captured&#xD;
      by a stereomicroscope (Wild 400, Switzerland) at a 32× magnification. Images will then be&#xD;
      transferred to the computer software for image analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fracture Resistance:&#xD;
&#xD;
      An axial loading condition through the functional cusp will be defined in the mechanical&#xD;
      failure description. Failure to fracture strength will be tested with a universal testing&#xD;
      machine at a 0.5 mm/sec crosshead speed. Application of a round end vertical loading tip on&#xD;
      the occlusal third of a specimen fixed into a loading apparatus as functional loading&#xD;
      simulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Management:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient information will be gathered and stored in the patient examination chart of the&#xD;
      outpatient clinic, Department of Pediatric Dentistry, faculty of Dentistry, Ain Shams&#xD;
      University. All information will be kept as a hard copy and as an electronic one as well.&#xD;
      Patient information will be guarded as co nfidential information that should never be&#xD;
      revealed at all times. This file will remain with the investigator during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All data will be tabulated, summarized and statistically analyzed using software SPSS&#xD;
      (Statistical Packages for Social Sciences. 3 and 6 months evaluation: evaluation of the&#xD;
      previous criteria.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A total of thirty primary mandibular molars in healthy subjects will be selected.&#xD;
The molars will be randomly assigned equally into two treatment groups&#xD;
Group A: 3D printed microfilled hybrid composite Endocrowns&#xD;
Group B: pr efabricated zirconia crowns Pulpotomy</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>clinical performance</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Federation Dentaire international clinical assessment scale. Minimum value is 1 and highest value is 11. Higher values mean worst outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>patient satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>A structured patient satisfaction questionnaire with a 3 points likert scale question.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Pulpotomy</condition>
  <condition>Tooth Restoration</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>group A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>3D printed microfilled hybrid composite Endocrowns</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>group B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>prefabricated zirconia crowns</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>3D-printed endocrown</intervention_name>
    <description>pulpotomy and restoration with 3D-printed microfilled hybrid composite endocrown</description>
    <arm_group_label>group A</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Zirconia crown</intervention_name>
    <description>pulpotomy and restoration with prefabricated zirconia crown</description>
    <arm_group_label>group B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Having at least one vital primary molar with deep carious lesion indicated for&#xD;
             pulpotomy or pulpectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The anticipated exfoliation date of the selected primary teeth has to be more than 12&#xD;
             months from the date of the study start.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Children who are uncooperative needing sedatin or general anasthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Children who are physically or mentally disabled or having any medical condition that&#xD;
             will complicate the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        e) Teeth of poor prognosis due to th e presence of an abscess or a sinus, mobility,&#xD;
        advanced bone or root resorption.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>7 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mariem O Wassel, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Ainshams university</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lamia H Yassin, MDs</last_name>
    <phone>01005293169</phone>
    <phone_ext>02</phone_ext>
    <email>limo9381@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 30, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ain Shams University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lamia Hussein</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>3D-printing</keyword>
  <keyword>Endocrown</keyword>
  <keyword>zirconia crown</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

