<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04907578</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY21040124</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04907578</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Thromboelastography (TEG) In the Intrauterine Growth Restriction (IUGR) Neonatal Population by Gestational Age</brief_title>
  <official_title>Thromboelastography (TEG) In the Intrauterine Growth Restriction (IUGR) Neonatal Population by Gestational Age</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Pittsburgh</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pittsburgh</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators aim to improve the understanding of TEG in this population in an effort to&#xD;
      improve outcomes in a population at high risk in both the presence and absence of blood&#xD;
      product transfusions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators plan to 1.) examine dynamic hemostasis as measured by TEG in the&#xD;
      intrauterine growth restriction (IUGR) neonatal population due to a high risk of requiring&#xD;
      blood transfusions, 2.) determine the influence of gestational age on TEG in this population,&#xD;
      and 3.) examine the utility of TEG as a tool for identifying coagulopathy in IUGR neonates.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that thromboelastography parameters will change with&#xD;
      gestational age in the IUGR population in a manner similar to non-IUGR populations and that&#xD;
      neonatal comorbidities, maternal factors, and socioeconomic status will influence TEG values;&#xD;
      TEG is likely a useful marker of dynamic hemostasis in this neonatal subpopulation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Study will not commence&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 12, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 12, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 12, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dynamic hemostasis measured by Thromboelastography (TEG) in intrauterine growth restriction (IUGR) neonatal population verse non-IUGR populations</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Discarded blood specimens (1-2 mL of placental umbilical vein blood following umbilical cord clamping) will be needed to perform TEG analysis, in duplicate when possible, immediately following the live birth of a viable neonate. The output of the TEG will include maximum amplitude (mm), which is a reflection of clot strength and a function of the maximum dynamic properties of fibrin and platelet bonding and correlates to platelet function.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clot formation measured by Thromboelastography (TEG) in intrauterine growth restriction (IUGR) neonatal population verse non-IUGR populations</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Discarded blood specimens (1-2 mL of placental umbilical vein blood following umbilical cord clamping) will be needed to perform TEG analysis, in duplicate when possible, immediately following the live birth of a viable neonate. The output of the TEG will include R time (min), which represents a period of latency from start to initial fibrin formation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of clot formation measured by Thromboelastography (TEG) in intrauterine growth restriction (IUGR) neonatal population verse non-IUGR populations</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Discarded blood specimens (1-2 mL of placental umbilical vein blood following umbilical cord clamping) will be needed to perform TEG analysis, in duplicate when possible, immediately following the live birth of a viable neonate. The output of the TEG will include α-Angle (degree), which measures the speed at which fibrin build-up and cross-linking takes place, assesses the rate of clot formation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Intrauterine Growth Restriction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>postpartum full term neonates</arm_group_label>
    <description>immediate postpartum full term neonates with no intrauterine growth restricted</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>intrauterine growth restricted neonates</arm_group_label>
    <description>preterm or full-term intrauterine growth restricted neonates</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      The investigators plan to collect discarded blood specimens (1-2 mL of placental umbilical&#xD;
      vein blood following umbilical cord clamping) in order to perform TEG analysis, in duplicate&#xD;
      when possible, immediately following the live birth of a viable neonate. No additional&#xD;
      specimens will be collected for this study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants will be recruited from Magee-Womens Hospital&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants included for medical record data and blood sample collection will be:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neonates diagnosed with intrauterine growth restriction, defined as a weight below the&#xD;
             estimated 10th percentile and accordingly identified as such in any peripartum&#xD;
             evaluation AND&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  May have additional comorbidities AND&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Full term IUGR neonates will be have a gestational age of 37 weeks or greater OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preterm IUGR neonates will have a gestational age less than 37 weeks OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preterm IUGR neonates will have a gestational age less than 37 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants included for medical record review data collection ONLY will be:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Mothers of eligible neonates&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Constitutionally (familial) low birth weight, i.e. small for gestational age, babies&#xD;
             OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Born to women with life threatening coexisting morbidities (this may include severe&#xD;
             pre-eclampsia, diabetes or suspected infections including HIV or herpes) OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neonates with an abnormal delivery or perinatal course including:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Fetal demise, death in the first week after birth, neonatal encephalopathy, meconium&#xD;
        aspiration, and physical birth injuries (fractures and brachial plexus injuries)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jonathan H. Waters, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UPMC Magee-Womens Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Waters JH. The role of viscoelastic testing in the management of the parturient. Transfusion. 2020 Oct;60 Suppl 6:S70-S74. doi: 10.1111/trf.15928. Epub 2020 Jun 22. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32567712</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sayce AC, Neal MD, Leeper CM. Viscoelastic monitoring in trauma resuscitation. Transfusion. 2020 Oct;60 Suppl 6:S33-S51. doi: 10.1111/trf.16074.</citation>
    <PMID>33089933</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jonathan H. Waters</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Thromboelastography</keyword>
  <keyword>Intrauterine Growth Restriction</keyword>
  <keyword>Neonate</keyword>
  <keyword>Gestational age</keyword>
  <keyword>hemostasis</keyword>
  <keyword>coagulopathy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fetal Growth Retardation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

