<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04905693</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RIN-PF-302</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04905693</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Extension Study of Inhaled Treprostinil in Subjects With Fibrotic Lung Disease</brief_title>
  <acronym>TETON-OLE</acronym>
  <official_title>An Open-label Extension Study of Inhaled Treprostinil in Subjects With Fibrotic Lung Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>United Therapeutics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>United Therapeutics</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Study RIN-PF-302 is designed to evaluate the long-term safety and tolerability of inhaled&#xD;
      treprostinil in subjects with fibrotic lung disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study RIN-PF-302 is a Phase 3, multicenter, open-label extension (OLE) study for eligible&#xD;
      subjects who completed Study RIN-PF-301 to evaluate the long-term safety and tolerability of&#xD;
      inhaled treprostinil in subjects with fibrotic lung disease. Following OLE entry, subjects&#xD;
      will return at Week 4, Week 12, and every 12 weeks thereafter through Week 108. Study visits&#xD;
      will continue until each subject reaches the Week 108 Visit or until inhaled treprostinil&#xD;
      becomes commercially available for fibrotic lung disease (whichever is sooner).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Efficacy assessments will include spirometry (forced expiratory volume in 1 second [FEV1] and&#xD;
      forced vital capacity [FVC]), time to clinical worsening, time to first acute exacerbation of&#xD;
      underlying lung disease, overall survival, King's Brief Interstitial Lung Disease (K-BILD)&#xD;
      Questionnaire, plasma N-terminal pro-brain natriuretic peptide (NT-proBNP) concentration,&#xD;
      supplemental oxygen use, diffusion capacity of lungs for carbon monoxide (DLCO), and&#xD;
      evaluation of biomarkers (for subjects who consent). Safety assessments will include&#xD;
      monitoring for the development of adverse events (AEs)/serious adverse events (SAEs), vital&#xD;
      signs, clinical laboratory parameters, and electrocardiogram (ECG) parameters. In addition,&#xD;
      up to 24 eligible subjects may participate in a PK substudy to evaluate the systemic exposure&#xD;
      of treprostinil after inhaled administration.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Open-label Extension</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Long-term safety and tolerability of inhaled treprostinil in subjects with fibrotic lung disease</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 108</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of AEs and SAEs, incidence of abnormal clinical laboratory parameters, abnormal vital signs, and abnormal 12-lead ECGs</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">396</enrollment>
  <condition>Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</condition>
  <condition>Interstitial Lung Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Inhaled Treprostinil</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treprostinil inhalation solution (0.6 mg/mL) delivered via an ultrasonic nebulizer which emits a dose of approximately 6 mcg per breath. Inhaled QID and titrated to a target of 15 breaths QID or until the subject reaches their maximum clinically tolerated dose.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Inhaled Treprostinil</intervention_name>
    <description>Inhaled Treprostinil (6 mcg/breath) administered QID</description>
    <arm_group_label>Inhaled Treprostinil</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Tyvaso</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Treprostinil Ultrasonic Nebulizer</intervention_name>
    <description>Treprostinil ultrasonic nebulizer which emits a dose of approximately 6 mcg per breath.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Inhaled Treprostinil</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject gives voluntary informed consent to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The subject participated in Study RIN-PF-301 and remained on study drug and completed&#xD;
             all scheduled study visits or was enrolled in Study RIN-PF-301 at the time that the&#xD;
             study or study subject was discontinued by the Sponsor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Women of childbearing potential must be non-pregnant (as confirmed by a urine&#xD;
             pregnancy test at Screening and Baseline) and non-lactating, and will abstain from&#xD;
             intercourse (when it is in line with their preferred and usual lifestyle) or use 2&#xD;
             medically acceptable, highly effective forms of contraception for the duration of the&#xD;
             study, and at least 30 days after discontinuing study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Males with a partner of childbearing potential must use a condom for the duration of&#xD;
             treatment and for at least 48 hours after discontinuing study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. In the opinion of the Investigator, the subject is able to communicate effectively&#xD;
             with study personnel, and is considered reliable, willing, and likely to be&#xD;
             cooperative with protocol requirements, including attending all study visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject is pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. In the opinion of the Investigator, enrollment in Study RIN-PF-302 would represent a&#xD;
             risk to the subject's overall health.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>United Therapeutics Global Medical Information</last_name>
    <phone>919-485-8350</phone>
    <email>clinicaltrials@unither.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Treprostinil</keyword>
  <keyword>IPF</keyword>
  <keyword>ILD</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Fibrosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Interstitial</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Treprostinil</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

