<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04909034</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MB103CLAS08</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04909034</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Potential Efficacy of MS-20 In Combination With Pembrolizumab for the Treatment of NSCLC</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Placebo Controlled Study to Evaluate the Safety and Potential Efficacy of MS-20 In Combination With Pembrolizumab for the Treatment of Non-Small-Cell Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Microbio Co Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Microbio Co Ltd</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      MS-20 was approved as the first oral cancer adjuvant new drug indicated for ameliorating&#xD;
      fatigue and appetite loss associated with cancer chemotherapy via reshaping human gut&#xD;
      ecosystem and restoring immunity. MS-20 has also been shown to be anti-PD-1 booster by&#xD;
      activating tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes (TILs) in mice cancer models, particularly&#xD;
      promoting migration of TILs into tumors and increasing the amount of TILs inside tumors.&#xD;
      Therefore, this study is designed to explore the safety and relationship between gut&#xD;
      microbiome and potential clinical outcomes in NSCLC patients under combination therapy with&#xD;
      pembrolizumab and MS-20.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 20, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The incidence of treatment-emergent adverse event (TEAE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>48 week</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed according to RECIST v1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>48 week</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed according to RECIST v1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Control Rate (DCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>48 week</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed according to RECIST v1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Response (DOR)</measure>
    <time_frame>48 week</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed according to RECIST v1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes from baseline in the composition, abundance and variability of gut microbiota after IP treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>12, 24, 48 week</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes from baseline of absolute proportion of (Tc, CD3+CD8+),( Th, CD3+CD4+), Th1/Th2/Th17, Treg, and MDSC. Relative proportion of CD4+/CD8+ cells, and CD8+/Treg cells</measure>
    <time_frame>12, 24, 48 week</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes form baseline of (Tc, CD3+CD8+), (Th, CD3+CD4+), Th1/Th2/Th17, Treg, and MDSC cell number</measure>
    <time_frame>12, 24, 48 week</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>NSCLC Stage IV</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MS-20 oral solution</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral Solution 8 c.c per day divided twice daily (BID) for 48 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral Solution 8 c.c per day divided twice daily (BID) for 48 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MS-20</intervention_name>
    <description>Fermented soybean extract MicrSoy-20(MS-20), which uses a variety of lactic acid bacteria and yeasts to metabolize organic soybeans</description>
    <arm_group_label>MS-20 oral solution</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Chemo young</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral solution without active ingredients</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female subjects who are over 20 years old (inclusive) at the time of signing&#xD;
             the informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The subject is diagnosed pathologically or cytologically with non-small cell lung&#xD;
             cancer(NSCLC).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. According to the 8th edition of the American Joint Committee on Cancer [AJCC], it is&#xD;
             classified as metastatic stage IV NSCLC.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The subject with metastatic non-small cell lung cancer whose EGFR/ALK/ROS 1 tumor gene&#xD;
             is wild type.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. At least one measurable lesion per RECIST v 1.1 criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The subject whose biomarker performance: The PD-L1 performance detected by Dako 22C3&#xD;
             or Ventana SP263 and other third-level in vitro diagnostic medical devices (class III)&#xD;
             must meet tumor proportion scores (TPS) ≥ 50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. The life expectancy is not less than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The subject whose liver and kidney functions must meet all of the following&#xD;
             conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Liver function: aspartate aminotransferase (AST) value &lt; 2.5 x ULN, alanine&#xD;
                  aminotransferase(ALT) value &lt; 2.5 x ULN and total bilirubin (T-bilirubin) value &lt;&#xD;
                  1.5 x ULN. For the subjects who have liver metastases, total bilirubin value&#xD;
                  should be &lt; 5 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Kidney function: Serum creatinine value &lt; 1.5 x ULN. If subject's serum&#xD;
                  creatinine value is ≥ 1.5 x ULN, his/her creatinine clearance value should be &gt;&#xD;
                  40 mL/min based on Cockcroft and Gault formula.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subject, if a female of child-bearing potential, must agree to completely abstain from&#xD;
             sexual intercourse or be willing to use appropriate methods of contraception (e.g.,&#xD;
             Intra-uterine device or contraceptives) during the study. 【The definition of&#xD;
             infertile：(1) Being menopause for more than 1 year；(2) Surgery for permanent&#xD;
             contraception (e.g., abdominal tubal sterilization, bilateral Salpingo-Oophorectomy,&#xD;
             and tubectomy)；(3) Congenital structural abnormalities.】&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subject, if male, agrees not to donate sperm, be willing to avoid sexual intercourse&#xD;
             or use appropriate contraception method (e.g., using a condom) during the study&#xD;
             treatment period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subject is active and capable to communicate with site staff, willing to be in&#xD;
             compliance with the following two items based on investigator's judgment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        (1) To complete return visits and study examination per the study protocol. (2) To collect&#xD;
        stool specimens at home, refrigerate and deliver the sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Presence of any symptomatic central nervous system metastasis or leptomeningeal&#xD;
             metastasis which has not been treated or is under disease progression. For subjects&#xD;
             with brain metastasis who have been treated and confirmed as stable per radiology&#xD;
             diagnosis, which means no evidence of disease progression based on repeated CT scan&#xD;
             with at least a 4-week window period (Note: The repeated angiography should be within&#xD;
             the study screening period and before receiving the investigational drug), could be&#xD;
             enrolled if his/her clinical condition is stable and not using steroid treatment for&#xD;
             at least 14 days before study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Presence of any other malignant tumor. Unless the subject had completed radical&#xD;
             treatment without any disease recurrence for at least 3 years. (Those who have&#xD;
             successfully undergone radical resection or have received possible curative treatments&#xD;
             for basal cell carcinoma, superficial bladder cancer, squamous-cell carcinoma,&#xD;
             cervical intraepithelial neoplasia or other carcinoma in situ are not limited)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Presence of any autoimmune disease which requires systemic treatment within the past 2&#xD;
             years. Hormone replacement therapy (for example, insulin or physiological replacement&#xD;
             of corticosteroid due to adrenal or pituitary disorders, etc.) is allowed and not&#xD;
             considered as systemic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Have had any transplantation of allogeneic cells, tissue, or solid organ.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) is positive or hepatitis B virus (HBV) DNA viral&#xD;
             load is ≥500 IU/mL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Hepatitis C virus (HCV) antibody is positive and hepatitis C virus (HCV) ribonucleic&#xD;
             acid(RNA) is also positive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject has non-infectious pneumonia history which requires systemic steroids or who&#xD;
             currently have interstitial pneumonia or interstitial pneumonitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Presence of any severe cardiac dysfunction, Class III-IV of chronic heart failure&#xD;
             based on New York Heart Association (NYHA) Functional Classification, which includes&#xD;
             symptomatic coronary artery disease and severe ventricular arrhythmia; Presence of any&#xD;
             myocardial infarction, unstable or poorly controlled angina within 6months before&#xD;
             subject screening visit (V0).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Have any gastrointestinal history or surgery which the investigator believes may&#xD;
             affect the absorption of the oral investigational product.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Enterocutaneous or non- enterocutaneous fistula which is defined as Grade 3 or above&#xD;
             based on Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE, also known as Common&#xD;
             Toxicity Criteria).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Currently presence of inflammatory bowel disease or gastric ulcer.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Have not yet recovered from major surgery or complications before subject screening&#xD;
             visit(V0).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. History of active tuberculosis (TB, Mycobacterium tuberculosis).&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Presence of any mental disease or drug abuse disorder that may interfere with&#xD;
             subject's ability for being compliant with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Active infection which requires systemic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Allergies to soy products, severe allergies to antibody therapy, or known allergies or&#xD;
             intolerances to any component of pembrolizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Have previously received systemic chemotherapy or other targeted or biological&#xD;
             anti-tumor treatments for metastatic NSCLC.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Have received anti-PD-1, anti-PD-L1, or anti-PD-L2 drug therapy within 3 years before&#xD;
             the screening visit (V0) or act on another drug treatment that stimulates signals or&#xD;
             synergistically inhibits T cell receptors (e.g. CTLA-4, OX 40, CD137).&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Received radiotherapy within the 14 days before receiving the investigational drug or&#xD;
             received pulmonary radiotherapy&gt; 30 Gy within 6 months before receiving the&#xD;
             investigational drug (the subject must recover from all radiation-related toxicities&#xD;
             to grade 1 or below, without corticosteroid therapy and radiation pneumonia has never&#xD;
             occurred).&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Diagnosed with immunodeficiency or are receiving any form of immunosuppressive&#xD;
             therapy, systemic steroids (allowed to use up to 10 mg Prednisone or equivalent&#xD;
             steroids per day) within 7 days before receiving the investigational drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Those who have received live-virus vaccines within 30 days before receiving the&#xD;
             investigational drug or are expected to receive live-virus vaccines during the study&#xD;
             period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Have used antibacterial drugs including antibiotics and synthetic drugs (such as&#xD;
             sulfonamides, quinolones), antifungal or antiviral drugs (not including topical&#xD;
             medication) within the 14 days before receiving the investigational drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Use probiotics and prebiotics-related products within 14 days before receiving the&#xD;
             investigational drug. (e.g., yogurt drink, yogurt, Yakult, probiotic fermented&#xD;
             beverages, Wakamoto tablets, Shin Biofermin S tablets, inulin, oligosaccharide&#xD;
             products, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Those who have had gastrointestinal infection and diarrhea within the 14 days before&#xD;
             receiving the investigational drug (soft or watery stools more than three times within&#xD;
             24 hours).&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Women who are pregnant, breastfeeding, or expect to breastfeed during the study&#xD;
             period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. Currently participating in clinical trials of other investigational product&#xD;
             treatments, medical devices, health foods, or cosmetics.&#xD;
&#xD;
         28. Subjects who judged by the investigator to be unsuitable to participate in the trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amy Lee</last_name>
    <phone>+886-2-2655-8558</phone>
    <email>mbclinical@microbio.com.tw</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Taipei Medical University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <zip>110</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Han-Pin KUO, MD</last_name>
      <email>q8828@tmu.edu.tw</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Taipei Municipal Wanfang Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <zip>116</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ministry of Health and Welfare Shuang-Ho Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <zip>235</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kang-Yun Lee, MD</last_name>
      <email>13258@s.tmu.edu.tw</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
  <keyword>MS-20</keyword>
  <keyword>Add-on</keyword>
  <keyword>pembrolizumab</keyword>
  <keyword>metastatic</keyword>
  <keyword>microbiome</keyword>
  <keyword>microbiota</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

