<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04900467</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APHP210605</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2021-002174-52</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04900467</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Compare Immunological Efficacy of a Vaccine Regimen Combining Two Covid19 mRNA Vaccines (Pfizer-BioNTech and Moderna) With That of a Homologous Vaccination of Each Covid19 mRNA Vaccine</brief_title>
  <acronym>ARNCOMBI</acronym>
  <official_title>Multicenter, Randomized, Open-label Trial Comparing the Immunological Efficacy of a Vaccine Regimen Combining Two Covid19 mRNA Vaccines (Pfizer-BioNTech and Moderna) With That of a Homologous Vaccination of Each Covid19 mRNA Vaccine: Non-inferiority Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>COVIREIVAC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      As part of the COVID 19 vaccine campaign, the two mRNA vaccines, BNT162b2 (COMIRNATY®) and&#xD;
      mRNA-1273 COVID-19 vaccine Moderna, are administered in two doses in subjects without a&#xD;
      history of SARS-CoV-2 infection . In accordance with the marketing authorization for&#xD;
      vaccines, HAS recommends that subjects who have received one dose of an mRNA vaccine receive&#xD;
      a second dose of the same vaccine with an interval between the 2 doses of 4 to 6 weeks. These&#xD;
      two vaccines are based on very similar technologies but were developed independently. Given&#xD;
      the similarities between these two vaccines, the choice between the two, for the moment, is&#xD;
      based solely on the availability of doses and on logistical constraints. Since April 14, the&#xD;
      interval between the two doses of the mRNA vaccines is 42 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      WHO has announced that in the absence of available data, vaccine interchangeability cannot be&#xD;
      recommended. However, to facilitate the organization of the vaccination campaign and allow&#xD;
      faster vaccination of the population, it would be desirable to be able to use either one or&#xD;
      the other mRNA vaccine for the 2nd dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to be able to recommend the interchangeability of the 2 mRNA vaccines, it is&#xD;
      proposed to evaluate the immunogenicity of a scheme combining the two Covid 19 mRNA vaccines&#xD;
      (i.e. a 2nd dose of vaccine with the Moderna vaccine after a first dose of the Pfizer vaccine&#xD;
      or 2nd dose of Pfizer vaccine after a first dose of Moderna vaccine) compared to that of a&#xD;
      standard vaccination schedule with two doses of the same Covid 19 mRNA vaccine.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Covid 19 has infected more than 132 million people around the world&#xD;
      (https://covid19.who.int/, data from 04/07/21). In record time, effective vaccines were&#xD;
      developed allowing the start of the vaccination campaign less than a year after the outbreak&#xD;
      was declared by WHO.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date, more than 604 million vaccine doses have been administered worldwide&#xD;
      (https://covid19.who.int/, data from 04/07/21).&#xD;
&#xD;
      On December 21, 2020, the first mRNA vaccine developed by Pfizer and BioNTech obtained a&#xD;
      marketing authorization (conditional AMM) in Europe for the active immunization of people 16&#xD;
      years of age and over to prevent Covid-19 due to SARS -CoV-2. Then, on January 6, 2021&#xD;
      Moderna in turn obtained a conditional Marketing Authorization for the indication of active&#xD;
      immunization to prevent Covid-19 due to SARS-CoV-2 in subjects 18 years of age and over.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In France, more than 7 million injections have been performed with the Pfizer / BioNTech&#xD;
      vaccine and more than 617,000 doses of the Moderna vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The two mRNA vaccines, BNT162b2 (COMIRNATY®) from Pfizer / BioNTech and mRNA-1273 COVID-19&#xD;
      vaccine Moderna, are given on a two-dose schedule in subjects without a history of SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      infection. In accordance with the AMM for vaccines, HAS recommends that subjects who have&#xD;
      received one dose of an mRNA vaccine receive a second dose of the same vaccine. The&#xD;
      recommended interval between the 2 doses is 4 to 6 weeks. These two vaccines are based on&#xD;
      very similar technologies but were developed independently. Given the similarities between&#xD;
      these two vaccines, the choice between the two, for the moment, is based solely on the&#xD;
      availability of doses and on logistical constraints.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since 14 April, the interval between the two doses of mRNA vaccines is 42 days. In order to&#xD;
      facilitate the organisation of the vaccination campaign and to enable the population to be&#xD;
      vaccinated more quickly, it would seem desirable to be able to use either COVID 19 RNA&#xD;
      vaccine for the 2nd vaccine dose. However, the WHO has announced that, in the absence of&#xD;
      available data, the interchangeability of vaccines cannot be recommended.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to be able to recommend the interchangeability of the 2 mRNA vaccines, the ARN Combi&#xD;
      trial aims to compare the immunogenicity of a standard vaccine regimen (second dose of the&#xD;
      same Covid 19 mRNA vaccine) to that of a regimen combining the two Covid 19 mRNA vaccines&#xD;
      (i.e. either a 2nd dose of vaccine with Moderna vaccine after a first dose of Pfizer vaccine&#xD;
      or a 2nd dose of Pfizer vaccine after a first dose of Moderna vaccine)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 28, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-Spike IgG titer</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Anti-Spike IgG titer measured by ELISA and neutralising antibodies to European SARS-CoV-2 and SARS-CoV-2 variants 28 days after the second injection.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Any adverse events, local and systemic reactions occurring up to 180 days (6 months) after the second injection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">418</enrollment>
  <condition>Adult Who Received a First Dose of an mRNA Vaccine (Pfizer-BioNTech or Moderna) and Need to Receive a Second Dose</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pfizer-Pfizer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pfizer-Pfizer Length of use : 1 day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pfizer-Moderna</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pfizer-Moderna Length of use : 1 day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Moderna- Moderna</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Moderna- Moderna Length of use : 1 day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Moderna - Pfizer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Moderna - Pfizer Length of use : 1 day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pfizer</intervention_name>
    <description>BNT162b2 (Comirnaty®), Pfizer/BioNTech, mARN vaccine,</description>
    <arm_group_label>Moderna - Pfizer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pfizer-Moderna</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pfizer-Pfizer</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Moderna</intervention_name>
    <description>mRNA-1273, COVID-19 Vaccine Moderna, mARN vaccine, administrated by intramuscular</description>
    <arm_group_label>Moderna - Pfizer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Moderna- Moderna</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pfizer-Moderna</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Having received a first dose of one of the two mRNA vaccines (Pfizer-BioNTech or&#xD;
             Moderna) as recommended.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. For whom a 2nd dose of mRNA vaccine is planned within 4 to 6 weeks (according to the&#xD;
             recommendations of the HAS and the ANSM).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Without a history of SARS-CoV-2 infection (negative PCR, negative antigen test or&#xD;
             negative chest CT or SARS-CoV-2 serology)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Healthy or in stable health if pre-existing medical history. Stable health is defined&#xD;
             as an existing disease that has not required a significant change in treatment or&#xD;
             hospitalisation for worsening in the 3 months prior to inclusion, and for which&#xD;
             neither a significant change in treatment or hospitalisation for worsening of the&#xD;
             disease is envisaged in the near future&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Able to understand and comply with the research procedures as judged by the&#xD;
             investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Informed consent signed by the participant and the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Person affiliated to a social security scheme.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of SARS-CoV-2 infection at the inclusion visit or between the 2 vaccine doses&#xD;
             (documented by positive PCR, positive antigen test or positive chest CT or positive&#xD;
             SARS-CoV-2 serology.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Acute febrile infection (body temperature ≥ 38.0°C) within the previous 72 hours&#xD;
             and/or with symptoms suggestive of COVID-19 or case contact within the last 14 days&#xD;
             prior to the inclusion visit. Sick or febrile subjects may be re-invited for a new&#xD;
             inclusion visit during the inclusion period when they no longer have these symptoms)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Immunosuppressive medications such as corticosteroids at a dosage &gt; 10 mg prednisone&#xD;
             equivalent/day (excluding topical preparations and inhalers) within 3 months prior to&#xD;
             inclusion or within 6 months for chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Treatment with immunoglobulin or other blood product within 3 months prior to&#xD;
             inclusion or with planned administration of immunoglobulin or blood product before the&#xD;
             end of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Known HIV, HCV or HBV infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any immunosuppressive condition, such as cancer, that may reduce the immune response.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The use of experimental Ig, experimental monoclonal antibodies or convalescent serum&#xD;
             is not permitted during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Participation in any other research involving humans (Jardé 1 or Jardé 2) within 4&#xD;
             weeks prior to the inclusion visit&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Person subject to a legal protection measure (guardianship, curatorship or safeguard&#xD;
             measure).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of severe adverse reactions after vaccine administration including&#xD;
             anaphylactic reaction and associated symptoms such as rash, difficulty breathing,&#xD;
             angiodema and abdominal pain, or a history of allergic reaction that may be&#xD;
             exacerbated by a component of the SARS-COV-2 vaccine at the time of the first vaccine&#xD;
             injection&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Participant who has been vaccinated against BCG in the previous year.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Having received a vaccination within 4 weeks prior to the first injection or scheduled&#xD;
             to receive a licensed vaccine 4 weeks after the last injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. History of severe allergic manifestations&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Any bleeding disorder considered to be a contraindication to intramuscular injection&#xD;
             or having had a phlebotomy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Odile LAUNAY</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Cécile JANSSEN</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre Hospitalier Annecy Genevois</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CIC 1417 Cochin-Pasteur</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75679</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 21, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 21, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID 19</keyword>
  <keyword>mRNA vaccines</keyword>
  <keyword>Immunology</keyword>
  <keyword>mRNA-1273</keyword>
  <keyword>BNT162b2</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

