<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04908670</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-30</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04908670</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of the Effect of Spine Grade I and II Manipulation and a PNE Video on Brainwaves: Pilot Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Low-grade Spinal Oscillations Compared to a Pain Neuroscience Education Video on Electroencephalogram (EEG) Brain Activity on Individuals With Chronic Spine Pain: Pilot Study. WITH CHRONIC SPINE PAIN: PILOT STUDY</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Florida Gulf Coast University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Florida Gulf Coast University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the effect of the use of a pain neuroscience&#xD;
      educational video instruction on brainwave activity and compare this to the effects of a&#xD;
      grade I &amp; II PA spinal oscillations of the spine using EEG in individuals with chronic pain.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This quasi-experimental pilot study compared differences in brainwave activity in subjects&#xD;
      with chronic spinal pain following PA spinal oscillations and after viewing a 5-minute pain&#xD;
      neuroscience educational video.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this within subject's design all subjects were given the two interventions on two&#xD;
      different days. To prevent the order of the intervention to influence the study results the&#xD;
      subjects were randomized into two different groups, A and B. Group A received PA spinal&#xD;
      oscillations on their first visit and. Group B's underwent the opposite and watched a pain&#xD;
      neuroscience education video on their first visit and received PA spinal oscillations on&#xD;
      their first visit. Both sessions and interventions were lead and performed by the Doctor of&#xD;
      Physical Therapy student under the direct supervision of the lead physical therapist, who is&#xD;
      manually trained and holds a Cranio-Facial Certification. In order to standardize the&#xD;
      location of the PA spinal oscillation intervention so brain activity and response can be&#xD;
      properly compared, C7, T4 and L4 were identified and marked with a pen prior to any measures.&#xD;
      Identification of L4 was achieved by placing hands on the subject's iliac crests with thumbs&#xD;
      pointing toward one another. Keeping hands straight and parallel to the floor, thumbs will&#xD;
      move medially, landing on L4.25 To identify C7, the subject was taken through cervical&#xD;
      extension, where C6 will disappear and C7 remains in place.26 Once C7 was located, the&#xD;
      spinous processes were palpated and counted until the level of T4, which was marked. Various&#xD;
      factors can affect the reliability of this process, such as subject obesity, therapist&#xD;
      experience, and anatomical differences.25 Studies show reliability for this method to be&#xD;
      low.25,26 However, these studies, as with most, use a small sample size and only using one&#xD;
      palpatory landmark for each level examined.25,26 To standardize variables, the methods above&#xD;
      were used in conjunction with palpation of surrounding vertebrae. To measure brain wave&#xD;
      activity during this study the 14-lead Emotiv EPOC portable EEG headset was used. Each&#xD;
      participant wore the headset throughout the measurement and was in a seated position. After&#xD;
      the EEG headset was placed properly and connection with the system had been appropriately&#xD;
      established the subjects remained seated in a quiet room for three minutes to accommodate to&#xD;
      the room environment before the first EEG measurement. After this, a 1-minute EEG recording&#xD;
      was taken. This measurement served as the participant's baseline measurement. Group A&#xD;
      subjects then received a grade I &amp; II spinal oscillations of three identified segments (C7,&#xD;
      T4, and L4), 1 minute per segment for a total of 3 minutes. Directly following this a second&#xD;
      1-minute EEG recording was taken. On the subsequent visit, group A again underwent the&#xD;
      three-minute seated accommodation period with the EEG headset on, followed by a 1 minute&#xD;
      baseline EEG measurement prior to watching a 5 minute pain neuroscience educational video&#xD;
      Understanding Pain in less than 5 minutes, and what to do about it!&#xD;
      https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C_3phB93rvI. A 1-minute EEG recording was taken during the&#xD;
      first minute of the video and again during the last minute of the video. Immediately after&#xD;
      watching the pain neuroscience educational video a 1-minute EEG recording was taken. The&#xD;
      measurement protocol for group B was the same, but in reversed order. They watched the pain&#xD;
      neuroscience educational video at their first visit and the PA spinal oscillations on their&#xD;
      next visit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 29, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Half of the group was assigned randomly to receive intervention 1 and during the second visit intervention 2. The other half received intervention 2 first followed by intervention 1 on subsequent visit</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participant and clinician providing the manipulation on the spine were blinded to the EEG measures</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>EEG power in alpha, delta, gamma, and theta waves</measure>
    <time_frame>4- 10 seconds measures of all wave bands in one session measures</time_frame>
    <description>alpha, delta, gamma, and theta waves brain wave measures</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Pain</condition>
  <condition>Manipulation</condition>
  <condition>Psychologic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PNE group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>5 minute video :Understanding Pain in less than 5 minutes, and what to do about it! https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C_3phB93rvI.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Manipulation group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>PA grade I-II oscillation on C7, T4 and L4</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Understanding Pain in less than 5 minutes, and what to do about it! https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C_3phB93rvI</intervention_name>
    <description>Watching pain neuroscience education video</description>
    <arm_group_label>Manipulation group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>PNE group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PA manipulation</intervention_name>
    <description>Low grade PA manipulation on the cervical, thoracic and lumbar spine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Manipulation group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>PNE group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects in this study were males and female between the ages of 20 to 65 years with&#xD;
        chronic lower back pain (&gt; 3 months). Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        were not meeting the age requirement having pain less than three months having conditions&#xD;
        that would be a contraindication for the grade I-II PA spinal oscillations Those with known&#xD;
        neurological conditions making EEG measures unreliable.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Integrated therapy Practice PC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Merrillville</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46410</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Florida Gulf Coast University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Rob Sillevis,</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pain neuroscience education</keyword>
  <keyword>EEG</keyword>
  <keyword>Spinal manipulation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

