<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04904575</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LOCAL2020-GL01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04904575</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Erector Spinae Plane Block in Lumbar Spinal Fusion</brief_title>
  <acronym>MERFUSION</acronym>
  <official_title>Erector Spinae Plane Block in Lumbar Spinal Fusion : Double-blind, Randomized Controlled Trial.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Clinique Saint Jean, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Clinique Saint Jean, France</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to observe or not a reduction in the consumption of morphine within&#xD;
      72 hours of the realization of an erector spinae plane block when preparing for a lumbar&#xD;
      spinal fusion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Posterior lumbar spine surgery is surgery described by patients as painful. For this type of&#xD;
      surgery, lumbar spinal fusion, especially because of greater exposure, is more painful than&#xD;
      simple surgeries to release the lumbar canal or to cure a herniated disc. However, the&#xD;
      improvement of implants and techniques, as well as the change in the habits of surgeons,&#xD;
      means that this lumbar spinal is on the increase (+ 65%). The management of postoperative&#xD;
      pain is a priority for anesthesiologic teams with a goal to improved rehabilitation after&#xD;
      surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Multimodal analgesia, already recognized for other surgeries, is one of the keys to success,&#xD;
      combining oral analgesics and regional local anesthetics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The recourse to the realization of a erector spinae plane block was described for the first&#xD;
      time in 2016, it is described as not presenting any particular risk, simple to apply and&#xD;
      having a satisfactory analgesia action. However, this process is little described in the&#xD;
      context of spine surgery and even less in the context of randomized controlled trials. On the&#xD;
      other hand, no study has evaluated the effectiveness of spinal block as part of an Enhanced&#xD;
      Rehabilitation After Surgery (RAAC) program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the Clinique Saint Jean Sud de France, the management of spine surgeries is part of an&#xD;
      Improved Rehabilitation After Surgery (RAAC) process. Patients benefit from multidisciplinary&#xD;
      preoperative information and perioperative management promoting early mobilization and&#xD;
      postoperative rehabilitation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It seemed relevant to carry out a randomized, controlled, double-blind study to evaluate the&#xD;
      consumption of postoperative morphine during the 72 hours following a lumbar spinal fusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The studied process will be the realization of a ultrasound guided erector spinae plane&#xD;
      block.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The realization of the erector spinae plane block is carried out as part of lumbar spinal&#xD;
      fusion surgery on 1 or 2 levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As part of this study, 130 patients will be randomized into 2 arms: one arm receiving the&#xD;
      anesthetic and another arm receiving the placebo. As the study is double blind, both arms&#xD;
      will benefit from the same procedure. Patients in the block arm will receive an injection of&#xD;
      levobupivacaine 2.5 mg / ml while the patients in the placebo arm will receive an injection&#xD;
      of physiological saline (NaCL 0,9%) in the same proportions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data necessary for this study will be collected directly from the patient and from his&#xD;
      medical file according to the following schedule: 3h, 4h, 6h, 9h, 12h, 18h, 24h, 36h, 48h,&#xD;
      72h and 1 month after realization of the erector spinae plane block.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 3, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Consumption of postoperative morphine within 72 hours of the operation.</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Digital visual scale to assess pain of patient within 72 hours of the operation.</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Numeric scale numbered from 0 to 10. 0 : no pain, 10: worst pain possible</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Onset of nausea and vomiting within 72 hours of the operation.</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Onset of nausea/ vomiting or taking an anti-vomiting treatment within 72 hours of the operation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Onset of complication within 30 days of the intervention.</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Walking perimeter measurement by the physiotherapist during the 72 hours following the intervention.</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of the maximum distance traveled without stopping in meter with or without assistance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">130</enrollment>
  <condition>Lumbar Spinal Fusion</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Block</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The &quot;Block&quot; group will be made up of patients who will benefit from an injection of levobupivacaine for the realization of the erector spinae plane block.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The &quot;placebo&quot; group corresponds to the reference group, that is to say that it will consist of patients who will benefit from an injection of physiological serum for the realization of the erector spinae plane block.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Erector spinae plane block</intervention_name>
    <description>Procedure : After installing the sleeping patient and identifying the surgical level by the surgeon, the anesthetist will perform the erector spinae plane block. The anesthetist performs an ultrasound to view the spine and erector muscles and identifies the transverse processes of the vertebra involved in the surgery. Once the location has been made, the anesthetist injects the anesthetic product under ultrasound control between the erector muscle of the spine and its anterior fascia, the trajectory of the needle being thus visualized throughout the procedure. The anesthetist bilaterally injects 3ml/kg of solution with a maximum of 30ml injected.&#xD;
Drug : Levobupivacaïne 2,5mg/ml.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Block</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Erector spinae plane block</intervention_name>
    <description>Procedure : After installing the sleeping patient and identifying the surgical level by the surgeon, the anesthetist will perform the erector spinae plane block. The anesthetist performs an ultrasound to view the spine and erector muscles and identifies the transverse processes of the vertebra involved in the surgery. Once the location has been made, the anesthetist injects the anesthetic product under ultrasound control between the erector muscle of the spine and its anterior fascia, the trajectory of the needle being thus visualized throughout the procedure. The anesthetist bilaterally injects 3ml/kg of solution with a maximum of 30ml injected.&#xD;
Drug : NaCL 0,9%.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with medical insurance.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who received information about study and signes a consent to participate in&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major patient requiring a lumbar spinal fusion surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with an ASA score of 1, 2 or 3.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minor patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with morphine intolerance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with allergy to local anesthetics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient consuming morphine for more than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient scheduled for cancer surgery or trauma surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient participating in another interventional study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with history of lumbar spinal fusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient requiring lumbar surgery without arthrodesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient requiring lumbar surgery with inter-lamar or inter-epineal stabilization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient refusing to sign the consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient for whom it is impossible to give informed information.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient under the protection of justice, under curatorship or under tutorship.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Guillaume LONJON, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Clinique Saint Jean, Saint Jean de Védas</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Julie SOULIER</last_name>
    <phone>04 67 61 20 71</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>julie.soulier@capsante.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinique Saint Jean</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint-Jean-de-Védas</city>
        <zip>34430</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Julie SOULIER</last_name>
      <phone>04 67 61 20 71</phone>
      <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
      <email>julie.soulier@capsante.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Guillaume LONJON, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Aurélien BONNAL, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chen K, Wang L, Ning M, Dou L, Li W, Li Y. Evaluation of ultrasound-guided lateral thoracolumbar interfascial plane block for postoperative analgesia in lumbar spine fusion surgery: a prospective, randomized, and controlled clinical trial. PeerJ. 2019 Oct 28;7:e7967. doi: 10.7717/peerj.7967. eCollection 2019.</citation>
    <PMID>31681518</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ren Z, Li Z, Li S, Sheng L, Xu D, Chen X, Wu WKK, Chan MTV, Ho J. Local infiltration with cocktail analgesics during 2 level lumbar spinal fusion surgery: Study protocol of a randomized controlled trial. Medicine (Baltimore). 2019 May;98(19):e15526. doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000015526.</citation>
    <PMID>31083198</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Breebaart MB, Van Aken D, De Fré O, Sermeus L, Kamerling N, de Jong L, Michielsen J, Roelant E, Saldien V, Versyck B. A prospective randomized double-blind trial of the efficacy of a bilateral lumbar erector spinae block on the 24h morphine consumption after posterior lumbar inter-body fusion surgery. Trials. 2019 Jul 17;20(1):441. doi: 10.1186/s13063-019-3541-y.</citation>
    <PMID>31315670</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Forero M, Adhikary SD, Lopez H, Tsui C, Chin KJ. The Erector Spinae Plane Block: A Novel Analgesic Technique in Thoracic Neuropathic Pain. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2016 Sep-Oct;41(5):621-7. doi: 10.1097/AAP.0000000000000451.</citation>
    <PMID>27501016</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Qiu Y, Zhang TJ, Hua Z. Erector Spinae Plane Block for Lumbar Spinal Surgery: A Systematic Review. J Pain Res. 2020 Jul 1;13:1611-1619. doi: 10.2147/JPR.S256205. eCollection 2020. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32669870</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ince I, Atalay C, Ozmen O, Ozturk V, Hassan M, Aksoy M, Calikoglu C. Comparison of ultrasound-guided thoracolumbar interfascial plane block versus wound infiltration for postoperative analgesia after single-level discectomy. J Clin Anesth. 2019 Sep;56:113-114. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinane.2019.01.017. Epub 2019 Feb 8.</citation>
    <PMID>30743153</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cesur S, Yayik AM, Ozturk F, Ahiskalioglu A. Ultrasound-guided Low Thoracic Erector Spinae Plane Block for Effective Postoperative Analgesia after Lumbar Surgery: Report of Five Cases. Cureus. 2018 Nov 16;10(11):e3603. doi: 10.7759/cureus.3603.</citation>
    <PMID>30680264</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mathiesen O, Dahl B, Thomsen BA, Kitter B, Sonne N, Dahl JB, Kehlet H. A comprehensive multimodal pain treatment reduces opioid consumption after multilevel spine surgery. Eur Spine J. 2013 Sep;22(9):2089-96. doi: 10.1007/s00586-013-2826-1. Epub 2013 May 17.</citation>
    <PMID>23681498</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Davies AF, Segar EP, Murdoch J, Wright DE, Wilson IH. Epidural infusion or combined femoral and sciatic nerve blocks as perioperative analgesia for knee arthroplasty. Br J Anaesth. 2004 Sep;93(3):368-74. Epub 2004 Jul 9.</citation>
    <PMID>15247111</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Benyahia NM, Verster A, Saldien V, Breebaart M, Sermeus L, Vercauteren M. Regional anaesthesia and postoperative analgesia techniques for spine surgery - a review. Rom J Anaesth Intensive Care. 2015 Apr;22(1):25-33.</citation>
    <PMID>28913452</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tsui BCH, Fonseca A, Munshey F, McFadyen G, Caruso TJ. The erector spinae plane (ESP) block: A pooled review of 242 cases. J Clin Anesth. 2019 Mar;53:29-34. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinane.2018.09.036. Epub 2018 Oct 3. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30292068</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kendall MC, Alves L, Traill LL, De Oliveira GS. The effect of ultrasound-guided erector spinae plane block on postsurgical pain: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. BMC Anesthesiol. 2020 May 1;20(1):99. doi: 10.1186/s12871-020-01016-8.</citation>
    <PMID>32357842</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nielsen RV, Fomsgaard JS, Dahl JB, Mathiesen O. Insufficient pain management after spine surgery. Dan Med J. 2014 May;61(5):A4835.</citation>
    <PMID>24814741</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gerbershagen HJ, Aduckathil S, van Wijck AJ, Peelen LM, Kalkman CJ, Meissner W. Pain intensity on the first day after surgery: a prospective cohort study comparing 179 surgical procedures. Anesthesiology. 2013 Apr;118(4):934-44. doi: 10.1097/ALN.0b013e31828866b3.</citation>
    <PMID>23392233</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 17, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Erector spinae plane block</keyword>
  <keyword>consumption of morphine</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

