<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04906447</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-0124</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1UG3AT011265-01</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04906447</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Hybrid Effectiveness-Implementation Trial of Guided Relaxation and Acupuncture for Chronic Sickle Cell Disease Pain</brief_title>
  <acronym>GRACE</acronym>
  <official_title>Hybrid Effectiveness-Implementation Trial of Guided Relaxation and Acupuncture for Chronic Sickle Cell Disease Pain</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Illinois at Chicago</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Florida</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Duke University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health (NCCIH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Illinois at Chicago</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators will conduct a hybrid type 1 effectiveness implementation trial to assess&#xD;
      the effectiveness of acupuncture and guided relaxation on 360 people with Sickle Cell Disease&#xD;
      (SCD), while observing and gathering information on implementation in three health systems:&#xD;
      University of Illinois Hospital &amp; Health Sciences System, University of Florida Health, and&#xD;
      Duke University Health Systems. Each serves a large population with SCD, uses EPIC as their&#xD;
      electronic health record, and has a Clinical and Translational Science Award (CTSA), which&#xD;
      will help speed the translation of discovery into improved patient care. During the UH3&#xD;
      Implementation Phase, the 3-arm, 3-site randomized controlled trial will follow a&#xD;
      quantitative modified SMART design, a pragmatic trial that evaluates adaptive interventions&#xD;
      where the guided relaxation and acupuncture interventions respond to patients'&#xD;
      characteristics and evolving pain status. The investigators rely on the Consolidated&#xD;
      Framework for Implementation Research (CFIR) to plan, execute, and evaluate associated&#xD;
      implementation processes. The use of complementary and integrative health (CIH) therapies by&#xD;
      those with SCD to reduce pain and opioid use, to help enable them to better cope with their&#xD;
      pain, is well known, but there are few studies that evaluate the effectiveness of these&#xD;
      therapies, and none that also evaluates the implementation across multiple health care&#xD;
      systems and patient populations as this study will.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1: Determine the effectiveness of guided relaxation and acupuncture as compared to usual&#xD;
      care in decreasing pain and opioid use for SCD patients. Hypothesis: At 6-weeks, SCD patients&#xD;
      randomized to either CIH intervention will have a greater decrease in pain, opioid use,&#xD;
      sleep, anxiety, depressive symptoms, and pain catastrophizing compared to SCD patients&#xD;
      randomized to usual care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2: Identify the best adaptive intervention for improved outcomes by documenting outcomes&#xD;
      among adaptive intervention sequences: (1) initiate guided relaxation and switch to&#xD;
      acupuncture for non-responders at midpoint; (2) initiate guided relaxation and continue with&#xD;
      guided relaxation for non-responders at midpoint; (3) initiate acupuncture and switch to&#xD;
      guided relaxation for non-responders at midpoint or (4) initiate acupuncture and continue&#xD;
      with acupuncture for non-responders at midpoint.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 3: Explore differences in response to the adaptive interventions by age and sex.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 4: Identify implementation facilitators, challenges, and solutions for structures and&#xD;
      processes that contribute to the seamless integration of CIH therapies into the 3 health&#xD;
      systems by conducting individual interviews with participants in the intervention group who&#xD;
      responded to the intervention and those who did not. The investigators will also conduct&#xD;
      focus groups with hospital personnel at 4 timepoints.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS Pain Interference</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Scores range from 4-20; higher scores indicate that pain is interfering with daily activities more</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain, Enjoyment of Life and General Activity scale (PEG)</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>0-10 rating on pain intensity, enjoyment of life and general activity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS Physical Function</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>4-20 rating on the impact of pain on ability to perform normal activities; higher scores indicate greater impact of pain on physical function</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Generalised Anxiety Disorder Questionnaire (GAD-7)</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Measure of Anxiety with scores ranging from 0-21. Higher scores indicate higher levels of anxiety.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Health Questionnaire Depression Scale (PHQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>0-24 rating of depression. 10 or greater total is considered major depression, 20 or more is severe major depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS sleep disturbance 8a</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>8-40 rating with higher scores indicating greater severity of sleep disturbance</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep duration</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Hours a participant has slept</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Catastrophizing Scale (PCS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>0-52 scale with higher scores indicating more catastrophizing thoughts are present</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient's Global Impression of Change (PGIC)</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>1-7 scale with higher scores indicating more improvement in pain from the patient's perspective</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tobacco, Alcohol, Prescription medication, and other Substance use (TAPS1)</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>1-20 scale with higher score relating to more frequent substance use over the past 12 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gastrointestinal Constipation 9a</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>9-45 scale with higher scores indicating more severe constipation symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">366</enrollment>
  <condition>Sickle Cell Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomized to the control arm will receive usual care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Acupuncture</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Acupuncture treatments twice a week for five weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Guided Relaxation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Daily use of a guided relaxation app for 6 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Guided Relaxation</intervention_name>
    <description>Guided relaxation uses the mind to reduce pain, promote well-being, and improve physical function. Guided relaxation is a state of concentration and focused attention that gives people more control over their pain experience and its impact and an increased sense of well-being.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Guided Relaxation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acupuncture</intervention_name>
    <description>Acupuncture is a body-based therapy that includes the insertion of thin needles at strategic points on the body that has been proven effective for reducing pain.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Acupuncture</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of sickle cell disease based on hemoglobin electrophoresis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provision of signed and dated informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to speak and understand English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic pain defined as a response of &quot;Most days&quot; or &quot;Every day&quot; to the question, &quot;In&#xD;
             the past 3 months, how often have you had pain?&quot; (Answer options: Never, Some days,&#xD;
             Most days, Every day)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current pain interference using the general activity question from PEG, score ≥3 on&#xD;
             0-10 scale&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has had a stem cell transplant for sickle cell disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A known diagnosis of moderate or severe opioid use disorder by Diagnostic and&#xD;
             Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders-5 criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current incarceration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are on a chronic transfusion/exchange program&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition that the investigator considers precludes participation in the&#xD;
             clinical trial&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ardith Doorenbos, PhD, RN, FAAN</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Illinois at Chicago</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ardith Doorenbos, PhD, RN, FAAN</last_name>
    <phone>312-996-2817</phone>
    <email>ardith@uic.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Victoria deMartelly, MPH</last_name>
    <email>vdemar2@uic.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Florida</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32610</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Miriam Ezenwa, PhD, RN, FAAN</last_name>
      <email>moezenwa@ufl.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Illinois at Chicago</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ardith Doorenbos, PhD, RN, FAAN</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>22710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nirmish Shah, MD</last_name>
      <email>nirmish.shah@duke.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Illinois at Chicago</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ardith Doorenbos</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor in the Department of Biobehavioral Health Science, College of Nursing</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>We will publish our results in open-source manuscripts that will be available to the public. Electronic copies of publications will be deposited in PubMed Central with proper tagging of metadata to ensure online discoverability and accessibility within four weeks of acceptance by a journal. To the extent feasible, Underlying Primary Data will be shared simultaneously with the publication and made immediately accessible through release under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 Generic License or an equivalent license, or otherwise dedicated to the public domain. Before submitting Underlying Primary Data, we will work with our Institutional Review Board (IRB) and Data Safety and Monitoring Board to assess the informed consent materials and to determine whether the Underlying Primary Data may be shared as contemplated in this policy.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data will be shared within one year of the completion of the study.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>The data and associated documentation will be made available to users only under a data-sharing agreement that provides for (a) a commitment to using the data only for research purposes and not to identify any individual patient; (b) a commitment to securing the data using appropriate computer technology; and (c) a commitment to destroying or returning the data after analyses are completed. Such a data-use agreement will be executed through the PIs and the University of Illinois at Chicago College of Nursing. The database can then be accessed via our secure website, in a format that can be used by a variety of statistical software packages. We will make our data and results publicly available (predominately online), so that they can easily be found.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

