<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04900181</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>271816</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04900181</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Analysis of the Cost-Effectiveness of Same-day Discharge Surgery for Primary Total Hip Arthroplasty</brief_title>
  <official_title>Analysis of the Cost-Effectiveness of Same-day Discharge Surgery for Primary Total Hip Arthroplasty: A Pragmatic Randomized Controlled Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Wuhan Union Hospital, China</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Wuhan Union Hospital, China</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Total hip arthroplasty (THA) causes a great medical burden globally, and the same-day&#xD;
      discharge (SDD) method has previously been considered to be cost saving. However, a standard&#xD;
      cost-effectiveness analysis (CEA) in a randomized controlled trial (RCT) is needed to&#xD;
      evaluated the benefits of SDD when performing THA from the perspective of both economic and&#xD;
      clinical outcomes. So the objective is to evaluate the cost-effectiveness of SDD for hip&#xD;
      replacement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This was a single center, pragmatic RCT with a 6-month follow up. Eighty-four participants&#xD;
      who met the inclusion criteria were randomized to either the SDD group or the inpatient group&#xD;
      (42 per group). Outcomes were assessed by an independent orthopedist who was not in the&#xD;
      surgical team, using the Oxford Hip Score (OHS), EuroQol 5D (EQ-5D) and 36-Item Short-From&#xD;
      Health Survey (SF-36) scores at the baseline and the 6-month follow up. All interviews were&#xD;
      conducted face to face. All the cost information was collected both from payment receipts and&#xD;
      insurance reimbursement records.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This was a prospective RCT. Patients qualified for inclusion in the study if they met the&#xD;
      following criteria: undergoing unilateral primary THA; having the ability to understand the&#xD;
      relevant treatment process; aged between 18 and 75 years; a body mass index (BMI) ≤ 40 kg/m2;&#xD;
      hemoglobin ≥ 12g/dL; American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) physical status&#xD;
      classification of I or II; and no ongoing infection or blood coagulation disorders. Those&#xD;
      with a history of coronary artery disease, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease,&#xD;
      arrhythmias, or untreated obstructive sleep apnea were excluded. Eligible individuals who&#xD;
      gave informed consent were randomly assigned (1:1) to an inpatient THA group or an SDD THA&#xD;
      group. SDD-THA was defined as admission, surgery, and discharge within 24 hours, whereas the&#xD;
      inpatients stayed in hospital for more than one day. Randomization occurred at the individual&#xD;
      level and was performed by an independent statistician, utilizing an automatic&#xD;
      computer-generated table of random numbers. Preoperatively, patients undergoing SDD-THA and&#xD;
      their families received information in the form of teaching booklets and a teaching class&#xD;
      conducted by a bedside clinician, which included the protocol, matters needing attention,&#xD;
      exercise training, and home-based rehabilitation. All operations were performed by the same&#xD;
      surgical team through a posterolateral approach. Standardized general anesthesia was&#xD;
      administered by low-dose bupivacaine, to allow early postoperative patient mobilization.&#xD;
      Celebrex 400 mg PO was used as routine analgesia before surgery. Cefazolin (1.0 g) and&#xD;
      Tranexamic Acid (0.4 g) were administered 30 min prior to skin incision. A uniform&#xD;
      perioperative multimodal pain management protocol was established by cocktail periarticular&#xD;
      injection before wound closure, which consisted of Flurbiprofen axetil (50 mg) and&#xD;
      Ropivacaine (200 mg). Patients in both groups accepted the same postoperative protocols. To&#xD;
      avoid venous thromboembolism (VTE), all participants were encouraged to perform ankle pumping&#xD;
      and quadriceps-setting exercises immediately. Additionally, patients were encouraged to get&#xD;
      out of bed and ambulate progressively with assistance under the guidance of the bedside&#xD;
      clinician.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>the Oxford Hip Score</measure>
    <time_frame>six months</time_frame>
    <description>the Oxford Hip Score consists of 12 questions reflecting the different aspects of hip function. Each question was scored from 0 to 4, with 4 representing the best outcome or least symptoms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>the quality-adjusted life years</measure>
    <time_frame>six months</time_frame>
    <description>the quality-adjusted life years was calculated as the outcome in cost utility analysis, as proposed by the CHEERS and CEA guidelines. The values of QALYs were estimated by EQ-5D . The EQ-5D was administered at baseline and at the 6-month follow-up. The EQ-5D is divided into five aspects (mobility, self-care, usual activities, discomfort, depression) to evaluate patients' health state, and each consists of three levels. The score for the EQ-5D ranges from -0.59 to 1.00, with a higher score indicating a better quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">84</enrollment>
  <condition>Hip Arthropathy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>the same-day discharge surgery</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in the the same-day discharge surgery group were admitted to hospital, operated and discharged within 24 hour</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>inpatient surgery</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in inpatient surgery follow routine procedures and do not need to be discharged on the same day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>the same-day discharge surgery</intervention_name>
    <description>the same-day discharge surgery is the procedure in which the patient is admitted, operated and discharged within 24 hours.</description>
    <arm_group_label>the same-day discharge surgery</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  undergoing unilateral primary THA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  having the ability to understand the relevant treatment process&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  aged between 18 and 75 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a body mass index (BMI) ≤ 40 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hemoglobin ≥ 12g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) physical status classification of I or II&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no ongoing infection or blood coagulation disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  with a history of coronary artery disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic obstructive pulmonary disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  arrhythmias&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  untreated obstructive sleep apnea&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hongtao Tian, doctor</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Wuhan Union Hospital, China</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hongtao Tian, doctor</last_name>
    <phone>18627171618</phone>
    <email>tianhongtao@vip.163.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wuhan Union Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wuhan</city>
        <state>Hubei</state>
        <zip>430000</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hongtao Tian, doctor</last_name>
      <phone>18627171618</phone>
      <email>tianhongtao@vip.163.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/</url>
    <description>The link of citation</description>
  </link>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kurtz SM, Ong KL, Lau E, Bozic KJ. Impact of the economic downturn on total joint replacement demand in the United States: updated projections to 2021. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2014 Apr 16;96(8):624-30. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.M.00285.</citation>
    <PMID>24740658</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Molloy IB, Martin BI, Moschetti WE, Jevsevar DS. Effects of the Length of Stay on the Cost of Total Knee and Total Hip Arthroplasty from 2002 to 2013. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2017 Mar 1;99(5):402-407. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.16.00019.</citation>
    <PMID>28244911</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Navathe AS, Troxel AB, Liao JM, Nan N, Zhu J, Zhong W, Emanuel EJ. Cost of Joint Replacement Using Bundled Payment Models. JAMA Intern Med. 2017 Feb 1;177(2):214-222. doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2016.8263.</citation>
    <PMID>28055062</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Doran JP, Zabinski SJ. Bundled payment initiatives for Medicare and non-Medicare total joint arthroplasty patients at a community hospital: bundles in the real world. J Arthroplasty. 2015 Mar;30(3):353-5. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2015.01.035. Epub 2015 Jan 23.</citation>
    <PMID>25680450</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Zeng JQ. The pilot results of 47 148 cases of BJ-DRGs-based payment in China. Int J Health Plann Manage. 2019 Oct;34(4):1386-1398. doi: 10.1002/hpm.2818. Epub 2019 Jul 8.</citation>
    <PMID>31286577</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>same-day discharge surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>total hip arthropathy</keyword>
  <keyword>cost effectiveness</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Joint Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

