<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04909567</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RCT: OPTIMIZATION: 2021:9</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04909567</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Optimization of Patients' Physical and Mental Status Prior to Colorectal Cancer Surgery</brief_title>
  <acronym>OPT</acronym>
  <official_title>Optimization of Patients' Physical and Mental Status Prior to Colorectal Cancer Surgery -a Randomized Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Karolinska Institutet</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Karolinska Institutet</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Colorectal cancer is one of the most common cancers globally. A majority are operated on for&#xD;
      the purpose of cure. Complications after surgery are common, involve long length of stay and&#xD;
      increase the risk of later recurrence of cancer. Optimization of physical and mental function&#xD;
      before surgery can reduce the risk of complications and provide a faster recovery. However, a&#xD;
      standardized form for how optimization should be performed does not exist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Danderyd Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden, we are starting up an optimization center where&#xD;
      patients are offered optimizing measures while waiting for surgery. This form of structured&#xD;
      treatment has not been studied before and we therefore want to investigate outcomes in a&#xD;
      randomized study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients with colorectal cancer who are being examined for surgery are offered&#xD;
      participation in the study. Randomization of 518 patients in to either an intervention group&#xD;
      where the patients; are optimized for concomitant diseases, treated for malnutrition and&#xD;
      overconsumption of alcohol and tobacco, undergoes an exercise program and receives&#xD;
      psychosocial support before surgery, or a control group where patients are prepared for&#xD;
      surgery according to current routines. Primary outcome is the difference in severe&#xD;
      complications between the groups. Secondary outcome is difference in length of stay as well&#xD;
      as fitness and mental well-being before and 30 days after the operation.If optimization&#xD;
      before surgery reduces complications and shortens length of stay, the model can also be used&#xD;
      by other operating specialties. This may result in a great improvement for the healthcare in&#xD;
      general.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A randomized controlled, unblinded study with block stratification for surgical procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention arm:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients in the intervention group will be treated in an &quot;optimization center&quot; which&#xD;
      constitutes its own physical location at the hospital and functions as a day care unit&#xD;
      staffed with doctors, contact nurses, physiotherapists, ERAS nurses and dietitians. An expert&#xD;
      team of cardiologists, physiologists, renal physicians and endocrinologists are attached to&#xD;
      the unit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Day 1. (2-12 weeks before the operation). Multipel testing: Clinical status, ASA score, NSQIP&#xD;
      score. Alcohol and Smoke score tests. Nutritional score. 6 minute walk test. Psychiatric&#xD;
      score tests. If mortality risk &gt;5% according to NSQIP, low performance on walk test, chair&#xD;
      stand test. ASA 3-4, HbA1c &gt;50 for non diabetics, &gt;60 for diabetics or (GFR &lt;45) = special&#xD;
      attention from the expert team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Day 2 until one week before surgery:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Home exercise 5 days / week. Organised (physiotherapist) exercise 2 days / week. Dietprogram&#xD;
      with close follow-up. Psychosocial support. Smoking and alcohol cessation program&#xD;
&#xD;
      The week before surgery: The same tests as day 1. 30 days posted: The same tests as day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Controlarm: The same tests as for the intervention group, day 1, the week before surgery and&#xD;
      30 days post. No interventions during the period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The international ERAS database will be used to record data in the study. Consecutive&#xD;
      registration of over 300 perioperative variables on each individual patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Examples of these variables are basic patient characteristics, preoperative variables such as&#xD;
      information before surgery, laxation, nutrition, fluid intake, anemia and glucose&#xD;
      optimization. Intraoperative variables such as body temperature, fluid supply, anesthesia&#xD;
      method, bleeding, operation time and gastric tube. Postoperative variables such as catheter&#xD;
      removal, nutrition, mobilization, nausea, paralytic ileus, specified complications,&#xD;
      reoperations and length of stay after surgery. Compliance with the ERAS protocol will be&#xD;
      registered.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized controlled study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Serious complications</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Can preoperative optimization change the proportion of serious complications after surgery (defined according to Clavien 3b-5) in intervention vs. control arm.&#xD;
) in intervention vs. control arm</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reoperations</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Change of proportion of reoperations in intervention vs. control arm</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of stay (LOS)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Change of LOS (days) in intervention vs. control arm</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Working capacity</measure>
    <time_frame>2-12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change of walking distance (meter) in intervention vs. control arm (6 minute walk test)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Weight loss</measure>
    <time_frame>2-12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change of weight loss (kg) in intervention vs. control arm</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Psychosocial status</measure>
    <time_frame>2-12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change of points in Hospital and Anxiety scale (HAD) in intervention vs. control arm</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">518</enrollment>
  <condition>Complication,Postoperative</condition>
  <condition>ERAS</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Optimisation:&#xD;
Diet, organised exercise, psychosocial support</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Current standard preparation before surgery</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Optimisation</intervention_name>
    <description>Defined optimisation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients, 18 years or older, with strong suspicion of colorectal cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with dementia with severe cognitive impairment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ulf Gustafsson, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Karolinska Institutet</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Klas Pekkari, MD, PhD,</last_name>
    <phone>46707799817</phone>
    <email>klas.pekkari@sll.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Helene Vibom, nurse</last_name>
    <phone>Danderyd</phone>
    <email>helene.vibom@sll.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Karolinska Institutet</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ulf Oskar Gustafsson, MD, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Surgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ERAS</keyword>
  <keyword>RCT</keyword>
  <keyword>Optimisation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Postoperative Complications</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data Availability Statement&#xD;
Due to Swedish legal restrictions and the current ethical approval for the study, data is not publicly available to share, but the research group can provide descriptive data in table form.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

