<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04901273</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PRP-o65</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04901273</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Homologous PRP vs Placebo in Knee Osteoarthritis in Over 65 Years Old Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Homologous PRP Versus Placebo in the Infiltrative Treatment of Knee Osteoarthritis in Over 65 Years Old Patients.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istituto Ortopedico Rizzoli</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istituto Ortopedico Rizzoli</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the study is to compare the 6 months clinical outcome of the treatment with a&#xD;
      single injection of Homologous PRP versus single injection of placebo (saline solution) in&#xD;
      the infiltrative treatment of knee osteoarthritis in over 65 years old patients. The&#xD;
      evaluation will be performed through clinical, subjective and objective assessments.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      204 patients affected by knee osteoarthritis will be included in a double-blinded RCT with&#xD;
      possibility ,after 6 months, to cross-over from control arm ( saline solution ) to the&#xD;
      treatment arm (Homologous PRP). Patients will be followed-up with clinical evaluation at 1,3&#xD;
      and 6 months. During the follow-up visits ,will be evaluated the inflammatory status of the&#xD;
      knee by thermographic assessment. Patients in the treatment arm (Homologous PRP) will be&#xD;
      followed for an additional 6 months (up to 12 months of follow-up). After 6 months, patients&#xD;
      in the control arm have the possibility to cross-over into the treatment arm, in which case&#xD;
      they will be followed for an additional 12 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The study is a double-blinded RCT with possibility ,after 6 months, to cross-over from control arm (saline solution ) to the treatment arm (Homologous PRP). After 6 months, patients in the control arm have the possibility to cross-over into the treatment arm, in which case they will be followed for an additional 12 months.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>This is a double-blind randomized controlled trial with 1:1 allocation. Patient blinding will be provided during the injection treatment.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>KOOS-Pain Score</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months FU</time_frame>
    <description>KOOS-Pain Score is referred to a subscale of pain composed by 9 items. The score range considerate is 0-100.The score uses a 5-point Likert scale and each question is assigned a score from 0 to 4, where 0 indicates &quot;no pain&quot; and 4 &quot;severe level of pain&quot;.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>KOOS Score</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 1 month, 3 months, 6 and 12 months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>KOOS SCORE consists of 5 subscales and covers: pain (9 items), symptoms (7 items, two of which are related to stiffness), functions and activities of daily living (17 items), physical function, sports and leisure activities (5 items) and quality of life in relation to the knee (4 items).&#xD;
Each question is scored from 0 to 4, where 0 indicates &quot;no difficulty&quot; and 4 &quot;severe difficulty. Score range 0-100 for each subscale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>IKDC-Subjective Score</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 1 month, 3 months, 6 and 12 months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>This is a subjective, knee-specific rating scale that is considered one of the most reliable assessment tools in the evaluation of knee pathologies. All questions examines 3 categories: symptoms, sports activity, and knee function.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Analogue Scale (VAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 1 month, 3 months, 6 and 12 months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>VAS is a visual analogue scale consisting of a range scale (10 cm length), the ends of which correspond to &quot;no pain&quot; and &quot;the strongest pain imaginable&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EQ-VAS</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 1 month, 3 months, 6 and 12 months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>EQ-VAS Is a visual analog scale that has a range of scores from 0 (worst imaginable health condition) to 100 (best imaginable health condition).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EQ-5D (EuroQoL) Current Health Assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 1 month, 3 months, 6 and 12 months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>EQ-5D is useful to evaluate the quality life of the patients</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tegner Activity Level Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 1 month, 3 months, 6 and 12 months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Tegner activity level scale allows to know the level of physical activity carried out by the patients. All patients will indicate the type of sporting activity performed and its frequency.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective parameters- Range of Motion</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 1 month, 3 months, 6 and 12 months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the Range of Motion for comparative analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Acceptable Symptom State (PASS)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 1 month, 3 months, 6 and 12 months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>A tool to assess patient satisfaction in consideration of their current degree of pain, function, and daily activity. Patients can express if their state of health will be satisfying, answering &quot;yes&quot; or &quot;no.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective parameters - Circumferences</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 1 month, 3 months, 6 and 12 months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Bilateral trans- and supra- patellar circumferences measurement for comparative analysis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">204</enrollment>
  <condition>Knee Osteoarthritis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Homologous PRP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group of patients will be treated with single intra-articular injection of Homologous PRP. At the 6-month follow-up visit, the patient will be informed about the treatment received.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Saline solution</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group of patients will be treated with single intra-articular injection of saline solution (placebo). At the 6-month follow-up visit, patients will be informed about the treatment received. Patients of this group can cross-over to the treatment arm after 6 months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Homologous PRP injections</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will be treated with a single injection of Homologous PRP (5 ml) in the knee joint affected by osteoarthritis.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Homologous PRP</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo injection (saline solution)</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will be treated with a single injections of saline solution (5 ml) in the knee joint affected by osteoarthritis</description>
    <arm_group_label>Saline solution</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Unilateral involvement;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Signs and symptoms of degenerative pathology of the knee cartilage;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Radiographic or MRI signs of degenerative pathology of the knee cartilage&#xD;
             (Kellgren-Lawrence 1-4 grades);&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Ability and consent of patients to actively participate in clinical follow-up;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Signature of informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients undergoing knee surgery within the previous 12 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with malignant neoplasms;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with rheumatic diseases;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with diabetes;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients with hematologic diseases (coagulopathies);&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with metabolic disorders of the thyroid gland;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients abusing alcoholic beverages, drugs or medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Body Mass Index &gt; 35&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alessandro Di Martino, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Istituto Ortopedico Rizzoli</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Roberta Licciardi, Msc</last_name>
    <phone>0516366567</phone>
    <email>roberta.licciardi@ior.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Alessandro Di Martino, MD</last_name>
    <email>alessandro.dimartino@ior.it</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Di Martino A, Di Matteo B, Papio T, Tentoni F, Selleri F, Cenacchi A, Kon E, Filardo G. Platelet-Rich Plasma Versus Hyaluronic Acid Injections for the Treatment of Knee Osteoarthritis: Results at 5 Years of a Double-Blind, Randomized Controlled Trial. Am J Sports Med. 2019 Feb;47(2):347-354. doi: 10.1177/0363546518814532. Epub 2018 Dec 13.</citation>
    <PMID>30545242</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Filardo G, Kon E, Pereira Ruiz MT, Vaccaro F, Guitaldi R, Di Martino A, Cenacchi A, Fornasari PM, Marcacci M. Platelet-rich plasma intra-articular injections for cartilage degeneration and osteoarthritis: single- versus double-spinning approach. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2012 Oct;20(10):2082-91. Epub 2011 Dec 28.</citation>
    <PMID>22203046</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Braun HJ, Kim HJ, Chu CR, Dragoo JL. The effect of platelet-rich plasma formulations and blood products on human synoviocytes: implications for intra-articular injury and therapy. Am J Sports Med. 2014 May;42(5):1204-10. doi: 10.1177/0363546514525593. Epub 2014 Mar 14.</citation>
    <PMID>24634448</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cavallo C, Filardo G, Mariani E, Kon E, Marcacci M, Pereira Ruiz MT, Facchini A, Grigolo B. Comparison of platelet-rich plasma formulations for cartilage healing: an in vitro study. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2014 Mar 5;96(5):423-9. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.M.00726.</citation>
    <PMID>24599205</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Everts PA, Knape JT, Weibrich G, Schönberger JP, Hoffmann J, Overdevest EP, Box HA, van Zundert A. Platelet-rich plasma and platelet gel: a review. J Extra Corpor Technol. 2006 Jun;38(2):174-87. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16921694</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 17, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>knee</keyword>
  <keyword>knee osteoarthritis</keyword>
  <keyword>PRP</keyword>
  <keyword>Homologous PRP</keyword>
  <keyword>PRP injections</keyword>
  <keyword>injection treatment</keyword>
  <keyword>Randomized controlled trial</keyword>
  <keyword>osteoarthritis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

