<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02761694</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>4440-001</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>ARQ 751-101</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02761694</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Vevorisertib (ARQ 751) (4440-001) as a Single Agent or in Combination With Other Anti-Cancer Agents, in Solid Tumors With PIK3CA / AKT / PTEN Mutations</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1b Study of ARQ 751 as a Single Agent or in Combination With Other Anti-Cancer Agents in Adult Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors With PIK3CA / AKT / PTEN Mutations</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>ArQule, Inc. (a wholly owned subsidiary of Merck Sharp and Dohme, a subsidiary of Merck &amp; Co., Inc.)</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>ArQule, Inc. (a wholly owned subsidiary of Merck Sharp and Dohme, a subsidiary of Merck &amp; Co., Inc.)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      An open-label, Phase 1b, study of vevorisertib as a single agent or in combination with other&#xD;
      anti-cancer agents, in subjects with advanced solid tumors with PIK3CA / AKT / PTEN&#xD;
      mutations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      AKT inhibitor may decrease or arrest growth of cancer cells that depends on the presence of a&#xD;
      protein called AKT. A number of genes, namely, PIK3CA, AKT and PTEN, may cause the AKT to&#xD;
      behave abnormally, so by blocking the action of these genes on AKT with the drug like&#xD;
      vevorisertib, the cancer spread may be stopped or slowed down. Paclitaxel and fulvestrant are&#xD;
      standard anticancer agents, paclitaxel is given to destroy cancer cells and fulvestrant to&#xD;
      lower the amount of estrogen the body makes. Vevorisertib in combination with paclitaxel or&#xD;
      fulvestrant may potentiate effect of a single therapy in tumors driven by PIK3CA/AKT/PTEN&#xD;
      mutations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Business Reasons&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 26, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 10, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 10, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events graded using National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (NCI CTCAE) guidelines v4.03</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The incidence of adverse events will be assessed as a measure of the safety and tolerability profile of vevorisertib</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the peak plasma concentration (Cmax) of the pharmacokinetic (PK) profile of vevorisertib</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 Day 1 (C1D1) (each cycle is 28 days) (time [t]=0,1,2,4,6,8 hours [h]), C1D2 (t=0), and C1D15 (t=0,1,2 h), C2D1 (t=0,1,2,4,6,8 h), C2D2 (t=0), C3D1 (t=0,1,2 h), C4D1 (t=0,1,2 h)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the area under the plasma concentration vs. time curve (AUC) of the pharmacokinetic (PK) profile of vevorisertib</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 Day 1 (C1D1) (each cycle is 28 days) (time [t]=0,1,2,4,6,8 hours [h]), C1D2 (t=0), and C1D15 (t=0,1,2 h), C2D1 (t=0,1,2,4,6,8 h), C2D2 (t=0), C3D1 (t=0,1,2 h), C4D1 (t=0,1,2 h)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the half life of vevorisertib of the pharmacokinetic (PK) profile of vevorisertib</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 Day 1 (C1D1) (each cycle is 28 days) (time [t]=0,1,2,4,6,8 hours [h]), C1D2 (t=0), and C1D15 (t=0,1,2 h), C2D1 (t=0,1,2,4,6,8 h), C2D2 (t=0), C3D1 (t=0,1,2 h), C4D1 (t=0,1,2 h)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess changes in serum glucose, insulin and cell-free ctDNA, to determine pharmacodynamic activity of vevorisertib</measure>
    <time_frame>Blood samples are collected on Day 1 of Cycles 1, 2, and 3 (each cycle is 28 days) and at the End of Treatment visit, which may occur at up to 24 weeks after the first dose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and/or the recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D) of vevorisertib as single agent and when given in combination with other anti-cancer treatments.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to the first 28 days (1 cycle) of therapy</time_frame>
    <description>MTD is defined as the dose level at which no more than one out of six subjects has an observable dose limiting toxicity (DLT)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate tumor response assessed by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) v1.1 after treatment with vevorisertib</measure>
    <time_frame>Tumor assessments will be performed at Baseline, every eight weeks (e.g., Cycle 3 Day 1, Cycle 5 Day 1, etc), and at the End of Treatment visit, which may occur at up to 24 weeks after the first dose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">77</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Solid Tumors</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vevorisertib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive vevorisertib orally every day. Subjects will receive treatment with vevorisertib until unacceptable toxicity, disease progression (clinical or radiological), or another of the discontinuation criteria is documented. It is expected that most subjects will receive between one and six cycles of vevorisertib for a treatment period of 4 to 24 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vevorisertib and Fulvestrant</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Vevorisertib will be administered orally every day (QD) of a 28-day cycle in combination with fulvestrant, which will be administered intramuscularly on Days 1 &amp; 15 of Cycle 1 and Day 1 of all subsequent cycles. The combination treatment will continue until progression of disease (clinical or radiological), unacceptable toxicity, or another of the discontinuation criteria is documented.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vevorisertib and Paclitaxel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Vevorisertib will be administered orally every day of a 28-day cycle in combination with paclitaxel, which will be administered intravenously on Days 1, 8 &amp; 15 of each cycle. The combination treatment will continue until progression of disease (clinical or radiological), unacceptable toxicity, or another of the discontinuation criteria is documented.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vevorisertib</intervention_name>
    <description>During dose escalation, subjects received vevorisertib orally every day at dose levels specified for the respective dose cohort for a 28-day cycle During dose expansion, subjects will receive vevorisertib orally at 75mg every day on a 28-day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vevorisertib</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ARQ 751</other_name>
    <other_name>4440-001</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vevorisertib and Fulvestrant</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will receive vevorisertib orally every day at dose levels specified for the respective dose cohort for a 28-day cycle in combination with fulvestrant (500 mg administered intramuscularly) on Days 1 &amp; 15 of Cycle 1 and Day 1 on all subsequent cycles for each 28-day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vevorisertib and Fulvestrant</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Faslodex</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vevorisertib and Paclitaxel</intervention_name>
    <description>Vevorisertib will be administered every day orally at dose levels specified for the respective dose cohort for a 28-day cycle in combination with an intravenous (IV) infusion of paclitaxel (80 mg/m2), once a week on Day 1, 8 &amp;15 for three consecutive weeks followed by one week off of each 28-day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vevorisertib and Paclitaxel</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Taxol</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Signed written informed consent granted prior to initiation of any study-specific&#xD;
             procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. 18 years of age and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Histologically and/or cytologically documented diagnosis of a selected tumor type that&#xD;
             is locally advanced, inoperable, metastatic or recurrent (including but not restricted&#xD;
             to breast cancer, TNBC [triple negative]; HR-positive [HR+]/HER2-negative [HER2-] or&#xD;
             endometrial cancer)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Documented AKT genetic alterations or known actionable PIK3CA/PTEN mutations by&#xD;
             genetic testing&#xD;
&#xD;
             • Subjects with tumors with PTEN null/PTEN loss-of-function mutations are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. For combination arms; subjects should be eligible for paclitaxel or fulvestrant&#xD;
             therapy as per Investigator assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Failure to respond to standard systemic therapy, or for whom standard or curative&#xD;
             systemic therapy does not exist or is not tolerable&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subjects in single agent arm (with AKT genetic alterations) and subjects in dose&#xD;
                  escalation cohorts of combination therapy arms should have at least one line of&#xD;
                  standard systemic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subjects in single agent arm (with PIK3CA/PTEN actionable mutations) and subjects&#xD;
                  in the expansion cohorts of combination therapy arms should have no more than 3&#xD;
                  prior systemic regimens for the advanced disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Neoadjuvant and adjuvant chemotherapy are considered one regimen if they are a&#xD;
                  continuation of the same regimen with interval debulking surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If the subject is refractory or has disease progression within 6 months after&#xD;
                  completion of the adjuvant treatment, then the adjuvant treatment should be&#xD;
                  considered as the line of treatment rather than an adjuvant therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Endocrine (hormonal) therapy does not count toward total lines of therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Maintenance therapy is considered part of the preceding regimen if one or more of&#xD;
                  the same drugs are continued&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Has at least one measurable target lesion according to RECIST v. 1.1&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) ≤ 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Adequate organ function as indicated by the following laboratory values. (All&#xD;
             laboratory tests must be obtained within 14 days prior to the first dose of study&#xD;
             treatment):&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Hematological&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.5 x 10⁹/L&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Platelet count (Plt) ≥ 100 x 10⁹/L&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Hemoglobin (Hb) ≥ 9 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  International normalized ratio (INR) 0.8 to upper limit of normal (ULN) or ≤&#xD;
                       3 for subjects receiving anticoagulant therapy such as Coumadin or heparin&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Renal&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN or calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 60&#xD;
                       mL/min/1.73 m2 for subjects with serum creatinine levels &gt; 1.5 x&#xD;
                       institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Hepatic&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≤ 3 x&#xD;
                       ULN or ≤ 5 x ULN for subjects with known liver metastases&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Metabolic&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c) ≤ 8% (≤ 64 mmol/mol)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. If a subject is currently receiving bisphosphonates or any other drug for treatment of&#xD;
             osteoporosis, treatment-induced bone loss and metastases to bone, the subject must&#xD;
             have received the bisphosphonates for at least four weeks prior to the first dose of&#xD;
             study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
             • Initiation of bisphosphonates or similar agents during the study may be allowed&#xD;
             provided the subject completes the first cycle of treatment without any dose limiting&#xD;
             toxicity (DLT) and the Investigator rules out tumor progression&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Male or female subjects of child-producing potential must agree to use adequate&#xD;
             contraception, including double-barrier contraceptive measures, oral contraception, or&#xD;
             avoidance of intercourse during the study and for 90 days after the last dose of study&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test. &quot;Women of&#xD;
             childbearing potential&quot; is defined as sexually mature women who have not undergone a&#xD;
             hysterectomy or who have not been naturally postmenopausal for at least 12 consecutive&#xD;
             months prior to the first dose of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Anti-cancer therapy, such as chemotherapy, immunotherapy, hormonal therapy, targeted&#xD;
             therapy, or investigational agents within five half-lives or four weeks, whichever is&#xD;
             shorter, prior to administration of the first dose of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  To be eligible for study treatment, toxicity from prior treatment(s) must recover&#xD;
                  to Grade ≤ 1, except for alopecia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Concurrent systemic high-dose corticosteroids (in dosing exceeding 10 mg QD of&#xD;
                  prednisone equivalent) when used intermittently in an antiemetic regimen, for&#xD;
                  central nervous system (CNS) metastases management, or as a part of the&#xD;
                  premedication regimen are allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Radiation therapy within four weeks, or palliative radiation therapy within two weeks,&#xD;
             prior to administration of the first dose of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  To be eligible for study treatment, radiation therapy-related toxicity must&#xD;
                  recover to Grade ≤ 1 prior to administration of the first dose of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Concurrent palliative radiotherapy for local pain-control or prevention of&#xD;
                  fracture (for known bone metastases) may be allowed provided the subject&#xD;
                  completes the first cycle of treatment, does not meet criteria of progressive&#xD;
                  disease, and treated lesions will not be included in the target/non-target lesion&#xD;
                  assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Major surgical procedure within four weeks prior to administration of the first dose&#xD;
             of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
             • To be eligible for the study treatment, all surgical wounds must be fully healed,&#xD;
             and any surgery-related adverse events must recover to Grade ≤ 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Unable or unwilling to swallow the complete daily dose of vevorisertib&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Previous treatment with&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AKT inhibitors (e.g., ARQ 092, MK-2206, GSK2141795, AZD5363; prior treatment with&#xD;
                  PI3K or mTOR inhibitor are allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prior taxane therapy for the advanced, metastatic disease (for subjects&#xD;
                  considered for vevorisertib +paclitaxel combination arm only)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Known prior allergic reaction to or severe intolerance of paclitaxel or fulvestrant.&#xD;
             Intolerance is defined as a serious adverse event, a grade 3 or 4 AE per CTCAE v.4.03,&#xD;
             or permanent treatment discontinuation&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of Type 1 diabetes mellitus or Type 2 diabetes mellitus requiring regular&#xD;
             medication (other than oral hypoglycemic agents) or fasting glucose ≥ 160 mg/dL at&#xD;
             Screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Significant gastrointestinal disorder(s) that could, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             Investigator, interfere with the absorption, metabolism, or excretion of vevorisertib&#xD;
             (e.g., inflammatory bowel disease, Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis, extensive&#xD;
             gastric resection)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Known untreated or active CNS metastases and/or carcinomatous meningitis&#xD;
&#xD;
             • To be eligible for the study treatment, subjects must have stable disease ≥ 1 month,&#xD;
             confirmed by magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) or computed tomography (CT) scan, and&#xD;
             have CNS metastases well controlled by low-dose steroids, anti-epileptics, or other&#xD;
             symptom-relieving medications&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of myocardial infarction (MI) or New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class II-IV&#xD;
             congestive heart failure within 6 months of the administration of the first dose of&#xD;
             study treatment (MI occurring &gt; 6 months of the first dose of study treatment will be&#xD;
             permitted); Grade 2 or worse conduction defect (e.g., right or left bundle branch&#xD;
             block)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. A heart rate corrected QT (QTc) interval ≥ 480 msec, using the Fridericia's formula&#xD;
             QTcF&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt;50% as determined by Multiple Gated&#xD;
             Acquisition (MUGA) scan or echocardiogram (ECHO) in subjects who received prior&#xD;
             treatment with anthracyclines&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled illness not related to cancer and/or social&#xD;
             situation that would limit compliance with study requirements, including but not&#xD;
             limited to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Psychiatric illness, substance abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ongoing or active known infection, including human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)&#xD;
                  infection, hepatitis B or C virus&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Significant pulmonary dysfunction, including pneumonitis, interstitial lung&#xD;
                  disease (ILD), idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, cystic fibrosis, severe COPD&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Peripheral neuropathy grade ≥2 (vevorisertib+paclitaxel combination arm)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bleeding diathesis, thrombocytopenia or coagulation disorders&#xD;
                  (vevorisertib+fulvestrant combination arm)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Thrombotic/coagulation disorders within 6 months prior to the first dose of study&#xD;
                  treatment unless stable on anticoagulation for &gt; 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Active or history of other malignancy other than the current cancer within 2 years of&#xD;
             the first dose of study treatment, with the exception of carcinoma in-situ of the&#xD;
             cervix, basal cell carcinoma, and superficial bladder tumors curatively treated&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Blood transfusion or administration of growth factors within 5 days prior to a blood&#xD;
             draw being used to confirm eligibility&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Comprehensive Cancer Centers of Nevada</name>
      <address>
        <city>Las Vegas</city>
        <state>Nevada</state>
        <zip>89169</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stephenson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oklahoma City</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <zip>73104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Charleston Hematology Oncology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charleston</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29414</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Sarah Cannon Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37203</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mary Crowley Cancer Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75230</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 29, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 3, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 4, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>AKT1</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT2</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT3</keyword>
  <keyword>PI3K</keyword>
  <keyword>solid tumors</keyword>
  <keyword>cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>ARQ 751</keyword>
  <keyword>ArQule</keyword>
  <keyword>PTEN</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fulvestrant</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>http://engagezone.msd.com/doc/ProcedureAccessClinicalTrialData.pdf</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>http://engagezone.msd.com/ds_documentation.php</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

