<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02762682</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Its12pgi</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02762682</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Vitamin B12 Status in Children With Infantile Tremor Syndrome and Pre Infantile Tremor Syndrome</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Study of Vitamin B12 Status in Children With Infantile Tremor Syndrome and Pre Infantile Tremor Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
      • To describe the vitamin B12 status in children with infantile tremor syndrome(ITS) and Pre&#xD;
      ITS&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To study the vitamin B12 status in mothers of children with infantile tremor syndrome&#xD;
           (ITS) and Pre ITS&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To study the blood levels of folate in children with infantile tremor syndrome (includes&#xD;
           Pre ITS) and their mothers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Materials and methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY SETTING: Hospital based study (Advanced Pediatrics Centre, PGIMER) STUDY PERIOD: July&#xD;
      2015 to December 2016 STUDY DESIGN: Cross sectional, Observational Enrolment criteria&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria (cases)&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Either sex, age less than 3 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Clinical diagnosis of Infantile Tremor Syndrome as evidenced by the following features:&#xD;
&#xD;
      [Developmental delay or regression WITH history of exclusive or predominant breast feeding&#xD;
      WITH two or more of the following; skin pigmentation, hair depigmentation, tremors] ITS:1 and&#xD;
      2 plus tremors PreITS:1 and 2 without tremors Exclusion criteria (cases)&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Parents refusing consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Later confirmation of an alternative diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Patient has received oral or injectable Vitamin B12 in the past 6 months Controls (C)-&#xD;
           Normally developing children&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Inclusion criteria Developmentally normal child not suffering from any acute or&#xD;
                chronic neurological illness&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
      1.Parent/individual refusing consent 2.Patient has received oral or injectable Vitamin B12 in&#xD;
      the past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
      PLAN OF THE STUDY All consecutive patients who present in Pediatric Emergency and OPD in&#xD;
      Advanced pediatric Centre with suspected Infantile tremor syndrome will be screened for&#xD;
      inclusion in the study. Those found eligible would be included after an informed consent.&#xD;
      Baseline clinical and demographic profile will be recorded on a proforma..The study aims at&#xD;
      assessment of vitamin B12 status in children with ITS. The various manifestations of the&#xD;
      syndrome, the presentations, the clinical picture, the development profile, various&#xD;
      haematological and biochemical markers would be studied in a detailed manner and recorded on&#xD;
      a proforma (annexure).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first section of the proforma is targeted at the clinical picture of the disease. The&#xD;
      presenting features will be recorded. The presenting complaints which can be anything ranging&#xD;
      from an episode of upper respiratory tract infection to an apparently healthy child&#xD;
      presenting with delayed milestones. A brief history of the development milestones achieved&#xD;
      under gross motor, fine motor, language and social milestones is important and form a basis&#xD;
      for screening the developmentally delayed children .A feeding history will be taken and is&#xD;
      important as this disease is more frequently seen in children who are&#xD;
      exclusively/predominantly breastfed. A detailed examination of the child would be done and&#xD;
      the findings recorded. Skin and hair changes are very classical of this disease and hence&#xD;
      will be to be studied and recorded in detail. A neurological examination will be done to&#xD;
      study the neurological status of the children and presence of any extrapyramidal symptoms.&#xD;
      Hematological indices will be recorded. Plasma Vitamin B 12, folate, homocysteine levels will&#xD;
      be studied.Urine methylmalonic acid along with TMS/GCMS will also be done as a part of this&#xD;
      project. Other investigations will be done as per case profile. Any other investigation if&#xD;
      done for the case as a part of the treatment or diagnostic evaluation like liver function&#xD;
      tests, renal function tests , EEG, CT, MRI will also be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The second section of the proforma consists of assessment of health and nutritional status of&#xD;
      the mother. It aims at establishing any direct relation between the maternal health and&#xD;
      development of ITS like picture in their children. Mother's dietary history will be taken to&#xD;
      find out whether the maternal diet is lacking in Vitamin B12 and folate. A targeted&#xD;
      neurological examination will be done to look for neurological manifestations of vitamin B12&#xD;
      deficiency in form of posterior column tract sensation and presence of peripheral neuropathy.&#xD;
      A lab estimation of maternal Vitamin B12,folate and homocysteine levels will also be done and&#xD;
      recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood samples: Sampling would be done along with routine sampling as far as possible to avoid&#xD;
      additional pricks to the child. Plasma would be immediately separated and stored and tested&#xD;
      for Vitamin B12 ,homocysteine, methylmalonic acid and folate levels. This blood would be&#xD;
      taken from sample already taken for other tests to be done in the child. Confidentiality of&#xD;
      records would be maintained. The study is purely observational and will not influence the&#xD;
      management of the child. Though as a standard policy all children with ITS would receive&#xD;
      Vitamin B12, folate and other supplements and diet counseling will be done.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood TMS-acylcarnitine and propionylcarnitine along with evaluation of urine methyl malonic&#xD;
      acid as a part of GCMS will also be studied in cases and controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mother's blood samples will also be taken after explaining to them the entire aims and&#xD;
      objectives of the study and taking full free voluntary informed consent from them. This would&#xD;
      also benefit the mothers in a way because those identified with a deficiency will be given&#xD;
      supplements to overcome the deficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control samples will be taken from children of the same age group admitted for some other&#xD;
      ailment. A 2 ml sample will be taken from sample already drawn for other tests to be done in&#xD;
      the child. The controls also stand to be benefitted because all children found deficient will&#xD;
      be advised Vitamin B12 and folate supplementation immediately.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vitamin B12 and folate levels will also be studied in the mothers of the 50 controls. All&#xD;
      mothers found deficient will be advised Vitamin B12 and folate.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>vitamin b12 status in children with ITS and preITS</measure>
    <time_frame>July 2015 to December 2016</time_frame>
    <description>The blood levels of vitamin B-12 and folate would be expressed as mean ± 2 SD or median (range) and will be compared between the children (with infantile tremor syndrome) and their mothers with controls.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>vitamin B12 Status in mothers of children with ITS and preITS folate status in these children and their mothers</measure>
    <time_frame>July 2015 to December 2016</time_frame>
    <description>The blood levels of folate would be expressed as mean ± 2 SD or median (range) and will be compared between the children (with infantile tremor syndrome) and their mothers with controls</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">93</enrollment>
  <condition>Infant Nutrition Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CASES OF ITS AND PRE ITS</arm_group_label>
    <description>Either sex, age less than 3 years&#xD;
Clinical diagnosis of Infantile Tremor Syndrome as evidenced by the following features:&#xD;
[Developmental delay or regression WITH history of exclusive or predominant breast feeding WITH two or more of the following; skin pigmentation, hair depigmentation, tremors] ITS:1 and 2 plus tremors PreITS:1 and 2 without tremors</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HEALTHY CONTROLS</arm_group_label>
    <description>Developmentally normal child not suffering from any acute or chronic neurological illness</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      serum samples&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Hospital based study (Advanced Pediatrics Centre, PGIMER) all cases of infantile tremor&#xD;
        syndrome (ITS) and pre ITS presenting to APC during the study period&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inclusion criteria (cases)&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Either sex, age less than 3 years&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Clinical diagnosis of Infantile Tremor Syndrome as evidenced by the following&#xD;
                  features:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  [Developmental delay or regression WITH history of exclusive or predominant&#xD;
                  breast feeding WITH two or more of the following; skin pigmentation, hair&#xD;
                  depigmentation, tremors] ITS:1 and 2 plus tremors PreITS:1 and 2 without tremors&#xD;
&#xD;
                  Controls (C)- Normally developing children&#xD;
&#xD;
                  • Inclusion criteria Developmentally normal child not suffering from any acute or&#xD;
                  chronic neurological illness&#xD;
&#xD;
                  Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  Exclusion criteria (cases)&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Parents refusing consent&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Later confirmation of an alternative diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Patient has received oral or injectable Vitamin B12 in the past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Exclusion criteria(controls)&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Parent/individual refusing consent&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patient has received oral or injectable Vitamin B12 in the past 6 months&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>3 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Naveen Sankhyan, MBBS,MD,DM</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>PGIMER Chandigarh</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>PGIMER</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chandigarh</city>
        <zip>160012</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 3, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 3, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 5, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 27, 2016</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 27, 2016</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 28, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Chaudhary Himanshi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Junior resident</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tremor</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nutrition Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infant Nutrition Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

