<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00697580</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>5R01HD033064</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>5R01HD033064</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00697580</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Strength and Nutrition Outcomes for Latino Adolescents</brief_title>
  <acronym>SANO LA</acronym>
  <official_title>Intra-Abdominal Fat and Risk of Disease in Adolescents</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Southern California</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Southern California</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      We are conducting an intervention study to examine the effects of a 16-week exercise and diet&#xD;
      interventions on prevention of disease, specifically type 2 diabetes and heart disease, in&#xD;
      Latino youth. Eighty overweight Latino boys and girls will be recruited and placed in one of&#xD;
      the following intervention groups: 1) Control Group (delayed intervention), 2) Dietary&#xD;
      Education Group (nutrition education focused on reducing sugar &amp; soda, increased fiber &amp;&#xD;
      whole grain intake), 3) Combination of Strength Training (twice/week for 60 min, progressive&#xD;
      increases in exercise volume and intensity) + Dietary Education (nutrition education focused&#xD;
      on reducing sugar &amp; soda, increased fiber &amp; whole grain intake) or 4) Combination of Circuit&#xD;
      Training (twice/week for 60 min, aerobic + strength training exercises) + Dietary Education&#xD;
      (same as above). We will assess which intervention group has the most effects on health&#xD;
      parameters such as weight, body composition, and insulin related measures.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The overall historical goal of this grant has been to examine the determinants of insulin&#xD;
      resistance in children, especially the role of total fat and visceral fat during pubertal&#xD;
      development in &quot;high risk&quot; minority children. Our previous longitudinal work has provided the&#xD;
      platform to propose a new intervention phase of this research. This new emphasis is justified&#xD;
      based on the magnitude of the pediatric obesity problem, particularly in susceptible ethnic&#xD;
      groups, and the need to design and test novel interventions to reduce not just obesity, but&#xD;
      the profound insulin resistance that we have observed in overweight minority children.&#xD;
      Insulin resistance is thought to be central (and perhaps causative) to several metabolic&#xD;
      abnormalities associated with type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular disease. Thus, interventions&#xD;
      aimed at improving insulin resistance in susceptible children could be an effective means in&#xD;
      the primary prevention of type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall objective of this proposal is therefore to conduct a randomized controlled study&#xD;
      to examine the effects of 16-week exercise and diet interventions on insulin sensitivity,&#xD;
      insulin secretion, beta-cell function, and body fat distribution. Overweight Hispanic boys&#xD;
      and girls (n=80) will be recruited and randomized to one of the following interventions:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ø Control (delayed intervention) Ø Modification of carbohydrate intake (reduced sugar &amp; soda,&#xD;
      increased fiber &amp; whole grain intake) using an individualized healthy exchange system and&#xD;
      motivational interviewing Ø Strength training + modification of carbohydrate intake Ø Circuit&#xD;
      Training + modification of carbohydrate intake&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will provide new information on the effects of these interventions on primary&#xD;
      outcomes at the level of body composition (total lean and fat mass, visceral fat,&#xD;
      intramyocellular fat and liver fat) and insulin related measures (insulin secretion &amp;&#xD;
      sensitivity and beta-cell function). The hypotheses are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. All interventions will have separate and independent effects on improving insulin&#xD;
           resistance&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Strength training will improve insulin resistance by re-distribution of body fat (lower&#xD;
           visceral fat, intramyocellular lipid and liver fat)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Carbohydrate modification will improve insulin secretion and beta-cell function&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Circuit training will have similar improvements in insulin resistance and have more&#xD;
           improvements on adiposity compared to the strength training group.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. The aforementioned effects on insulin dynamics will be independent of any effects of&#xD;
           either intervention on weight loss or loss in whole body fat.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall rationale for these interventions is based on three main factors. First,&#xD;
      preliminary data are presented in overweight Hispanic boys showing that 16-weeks of strength&#xD;
      training significantly improves insulin sensitivity in the absence of a reduction in total&#xD;
      body fat and in the absence of any dietary intervention. Second, preliminary data suggests&#xD;
      that overweight Hispanic children consume high levels of simple sugar, and low levels of&#xD;
      fiber and complex carbohydrates, and data from the literature suggests that modification of&#xD;
      carbohydrate consumption (reduced sugar, increased fiber &amp; whole grain) can improve glucose&#xD;
      control independent of body composition. Third we provide new preliminary data showing that&#xD;
      the only dietary variable associated with insulin dynamics in overweight Hispanic children&#xD;
      was high sugar intake which was associated with poor beta-cell function.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We have chosen to focus on Hispanic children because they are an understudied, high-risk&#xD;
      population, and display significant obesity-related metabolic abnormalities probably&#xD;
      emanating from profound insulin resistance (see preliminary data). In support of the&#xD;
      feasibility of our proposal, we have developed extensive expertise in recruiting and&#xD;
      retaining research volunteers from the large Hispanic population of East Los Angeles, we have&#xD;
      an experienced multi-disciplinary group of investigators, and the University of Southern&#xD;
      California has the necessary clinical research infrastructure to tackle this project. If our&#xD;
      hypotheses are borne out, it will provide evidence for the incorporation of strength training&#xD;
      and more specific and individualized dietary recommendations in the prevention and management&#xD;
      of obesity, type 2 diabetes, and cardiovascular risk in overweight Hispanic youth.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 2007</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2007</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>insulin sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>post intervention (week 16)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>adiposity</measure>
    <time_frame>post-intervention (week 16)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">104</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <condition>Type 2 Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Risk</condition>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control (C)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nutrition (N)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Strength Training &amp; Nutrition (ST + N)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Circuit Training &amp; Nutrition (CT + N)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nutrition</intervention_name>
    <description>Nutrition classes for 1 hour &amp; 30 minutes once a week for 16 weeks + motivational interviewing (4 individual sessions)</description>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Strength Training &amp; Nutrition</intervention_name>
    <description>Strength Training twice a week for 1 hour a day for 16 weeks + Nutrition once a week for 1 hour &amp; 30 minutes for 16 weeks + motivational interviewing (4 individual &amp; 4 group sessions)</description>
    <arm_group_label>3</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Circuit Training &amp; Nutrition</intervention_name>
    <description>Circuit Training twice a week for 1 hour a day for 16 weeks + Nutrition once a week for 1 hour &amp; 30 minutes for 16 weeks + motivational interviewing (4 individual &amp; 4 group sessions)</description>
    <arm_group_label>4</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Overweight (age- &amp; sex-specific body mass index ≥ 85th percentile based on CDC BMI&#xD;
             growth charts [US Department of Health and Human Services, 2000], calculated by Epi&#xD;
             Info Software, version 3.3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Latino (both sets of grandparents must be of Latino heritage as defined by&#xD;
             self-report; limited to Latinos to maintain a homogeneous sample and because Latinos&#xD;
             are at increased risk of insulin resistance and type 2 diabetes.) If the participant&#xD;
             or the parent is unsure of the country of origin of all 4 grandparents they will be&#xD;
             excluded from the study. The participants and their families are not asked whether or&#xD;
             not their grandparents are undocumented immigrants.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presently taking medication(s) or diagnosed with any syndrome or disease that could&#xD;
             influence dietary intake, exercise ability, body composition and fat distribution, or&#xD;
             insulin action and secretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previously diagnosed with any major illness since birth (e.g. severe intrauterine&#xD;
             growth retardation, chronic birth asphyxia, cancer).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children will not be eligible for participation if they have any diagnostic criteria&#xD;
             for diabetes including polyuria, polydipsia with or without unexplained weight loss,&#xD;
             fasting plasma glucose &gt; 126 mg/dl, or a 2-hour plasma glucose &gt;200 mg/dL during an&#xD;
             oral glucose tolerance test. Children will also be excluded if they test positive for&#xD;
             diabetes-related auto-antibodies, including ICA512 and GAD. Children testing positive&#xD;
             for type 2 diabetes will be referred for treatment. Children with impaired glucose&#xD;
             tolerance (fasting glucose &gt;110 mg/dL or 2-hour glucose &gt;140 mg/dl during an OGTT)&#xD;
             and/or conditions associated with insulin resistance (e.g. acanthosis nigricans,&#xD;
             hypertension, dyslipidemia, PCOS) will be eligible, as long as they are not receiving&#xD;
             treatment and meet other eligibility criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who are involved in any weight training, exercise, nutrition, or weight&#xD;
             loss program or have been in the past 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants that do not follow the rules and guidelines of appropriate conduct during&#xD;
             participation, i.e., disruptive behavior, derogatory or racist comments, or any acts&#xD;
             of physical violence towards study staff or other participants, and use of illegal&#xD;
             substances. The principal investigator Dr. Michael Goran will decide if this conduct&#xD;
             warrants exclusion or removal from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy test comes out positive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children who live further than 20 miles away from the General Clinic Research Center&#xD;
             (GCRC).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  We can terminate participation if the child fails to follow the rules and guidelines&#xD;
             of appropriate behavior and conduct during participation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael I Goran, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Southern California</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Veronica Atkins Lifestyle Intervention Laboratory</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90033-9073</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 11, 2008</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 11, 2008</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 16, 2008</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 29, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 29, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Southern California</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michael I. Goran</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Obesity</keyword>
  <keyword>Type 2 Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiovascular risk</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Latino</keyword>
  <keyword>Adolescents</keyword>
  <keyword>Strength Training</keyword>
  <keyword>Circuit Training</keyword>
  <keyword>Nutrition</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

