<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02438527</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20151136</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02438527</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Flowchart-Assisted Resuscitation. Standard CPR vs. Chest Compressions Only: What Happened to the Quality?</brief_title>
  <official_title>Flowchart-Assisted Resuscitation. Standard CPR vs. Chest Compressions Only: What Happened to the Quality?</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical University of Vienna</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of Vienna</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      ABSTRACT&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      More than two thirds of sudden cardiac arrests are witnessed by bystanders. Bystander&#xD;
      cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) doubles survival from cardiac arrest. Importantly, even&#xD;
      in witnessed cardiac arrests only 20% of the bystanders commence basic life support. Common&#xD;
      reasons for not commencing include panicking and the perceived inability to perform CPR&#xD;
      correctly. A meta-analysis could demonstrate that a simplification of the algorithm&#xD;
      (compression-only dispatcher-assisted bystander CPR) led to a 22% increase in&#xD;
      survival-to-hospital discharge. A recently published trial of the research group could&#xD;
      demonstrate that the presence of a flowchart has a positive effect on the quality of BLS&#xD;
      while at the same time increasing the rescuers' confidence. Nonetheless, performing CPR is&#xD;
      exhausting. Previous publications have emphasized increasing fatigue with the duration of CPR&#xD;
      efforts in both, standard and chest compressions-only CPR. Consequently, we wanted to test&#xD;
      the hypothesis that chest compressions (CC) are delivered more correctly regarding the depth&#xD;
      when utilizing the standard BLS algorithm with the aid of a flowchart as compared to the CC&#xD;
      only algorithm utilizing an adapted CPR flowchart in a manikin resuscitation model.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      After consent of the Research Ethics Board of Medical University of Vienna and obtaining&#xD;
      written informed consent of the participants, 84 medically untrained laypersons will be&#xD;
      randomised to perform flow-chart assisted CPR for 300s following standard CPR guidelines or&#xD;
      CC only CPR. The primary outcome parameter will be the total number of CC achieving the&#xD;
      correct depth of 50-60mm. Secondary outcome parameters will be hands-off time, the total&#xD;
      number of CC, and the compression rate. The total number of delivered rescue breaths, tidal&#xD;
      volume, and time to deliver these will also be evaluated. Furthermore, the subjective point&#xD;
      of exhaustion affecting the CPR quality, the reason for discontinuation of CPR if stopped&#xD;
      within the 300sec. period and the exhaustion at the end of the CPR measures will be&#xD;
      evaluated.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Design The investigation will be conducted as a prospective, randomized controlled&#xD;
      study performed by the Department of Anaesthesia, General Intensive Care and Pain Management,&#xD;
      Medical University of Vienna, Austria, according to the Good Scientific Practise guidelines&#xD;
      of the Medical University of Vienna. The data collection will be conducted in cooperation&#xD;
      with the Training Centre of St. John Ambulance, Vienna, Austria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population Eligible are all volunteers of ≥18 years of age of non-medical profession,&#xD;
      irrespective of gender. Exclusion criteria are professional medical training (nurses, medical&#xD;
      doctors, physiotherapists, ergotherepeuts, emergency medical technician or equivalent),&#xD;
      pregnancy (as by verbal response at the time of recruitment), and parallel participation in a&#xD;
      clinical trial, or physical impairment or illness prohibiting physical effort.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Withdrawal and replacement of subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects must be withdrawn under the following circumstances:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  at their own request&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  if the subject violates the conditions laid out in the consent form/information sheet or&#xD;
           disregards instructions by the study personnel&#xD;
&#xD;
      In all cases, the reasons why subjects are withdrawn must be recorded in detail in the case&#xD;
      report form. Should the study be discontinued prematurely, all study materials (completed,&#xD;
      partially completed and empty case report forms) will be retained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects who do not complete the study according to protocol will be replaced. The data from&#xD;
      the replaced subjects will be eligible for analysis of the conducted trial periods and for&#xD;
      safety variables.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample Size In order to detect a clinically important difference of 20% in compression depth&#xD;
      with a power of 0.8 and a significance level set at 0.05, the sample size calculation yielded&#xD;
      a total needed number of participants at 74. Since a drop out rate of approx. 10% must be&#xD;
      expected 84 participants will be recruited. Data regarding compression depth utilizing&#xD;
      standard CPR techniques in a manikin model (43±12mm) were provided by a previous publication&#xD;
      and used to estimate the sample size [Rössler et al. 2013]&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome parameters:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome is total number of CC achieving the correct depth of 50-60mm in five&#xD;
      minutes of manikin CPR. With this the authors want to test the hypothesis that chest&#xD;
      compressions are delivered more correctly regarding the depth when utilizing the standard BLS&#xD;
      algorithm with the aid of a flowchart as compared to the CC only algorithm utilizing an&#xD;
      adapted BLS flowchart in a manikin resuscitation model. The secondary outcome parameter is&#xD;
      hands-off time (HOT), which is defined as the sum of total time elapsed during the 300sec. of&#xD;
      BLS in which no chest compressions are provided. This includes the pre-compression interval&#xD;
      where the initial steps of BLS are performed as well as all interruptions of the CC, e.g. in&#xD;
      order to ventilate or pause due to any other reason including exhaustion. Furthermore, the&#xD;
      total number of CC, and the compression rate will be evaluated. The total number of delivered&#xD;
      rescue breaths, tidal volume, and time to deliver these will also be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Furthermore, questions regarding following points will be raised: &quot;During CPR and without&#xD;
      stopping your actions, please tell us &quot;NOW&quot; when you perceive your fatigue is affecting the&#xD;
      quality of the life support performed&quot;, &quot;How exhausted are you now (question raised directly&#xD;
      after discontinuing the CPR) [McDonald et al. 2013] (Lickert Like Scale 1-10). If a&#xD;
      participant choses to abort resuscitation attempts the open ended question &quot;Why did you&#xD;
      discontinue the resuscitation attempts?&quot; will be raised.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data management and calculations Data will be described as absolute frequencies and&#xD;
      percentages for categorical data and using mean and standard deviations (SD) for normally&#xD;
      distributed data. All tests for p-values are two-sided and p≤0.05 will be regarded to be&#xD;
      statistically significant. Students t-test and chi-sqare test will be used as appropriate. As&#xD;
      it is common practice, results of Likert-like scales will be treated as interval-measures and&#xD;
      thereby analysed by using parametric tests [Norman et al. 2010, Cariio et al. 2008]. Local&#xD;
      data management will be done using Microsoft Excel for Mac (Microsoft Corporation, USA) and R&#xD;
      for Mac (R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, Austria) for statistical analysis.&#xD;
      [R_Development_Core_Team 2009] Graphics will be created using PraphPad Prism for Mac&#xD;
      (GraphPad Software Inc., La Jolla, USA).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description of study days Volunteers will be invited to participate in the trial by the study&#xD;
      personnel. Recruitment will be conducted at a Training Centre of St. John ambulance, Vienna,&#xD;
      Austria, before the starts of the lessons. After giving written informed consent,&#xD;
      participants will be randomized using a web based randomization program (www.random.org) and&#xD;
      allocated to perform standard CPR or CC only. The randomization for group allocation will be&#xD;
      kept in opaque and sealed envelopes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The evaluation will be performed with an independent investigator using a computer attached&#xD;
      Resusci-Anne Skillreporter by Laerdal-Medical® and the Laerdal Skillreporter Software with&#xD;
      Segstat (Version 2.3.0, Laerdal Medical, Stavanger, Norway).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants will be asked to perform BLS for five minutes on a manikin. The participants&#xD;
      will then be asked to undertake any action they deem necessary to rescue the person simulated&#xD;
      by the resuscitation manikin. Participants will not be informed about the underlying&#xD;
      hypothesis or the outcome parameters. The room will be prepared to minimise outside&#xD;
      interruptions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additionally, participants will be instructed to indicate the point in time during CPR when&#xD;
      they feel that their fatigue is affecting the quality of the life support performed. (&quot;During&#xD;
      CPR and without stopping your actions, please tell us &quot;NOW&quot; when you perceive your fatigue is&#xD;
      affecting the quality of the life support performed.)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in both groups will receive one of the charts right at the beginning of the&#xD;
      scenario with the information that &quot;this chart will provide information on how to perform&#xD;
      CPR&quot; and with the start of the clock further instructions regarding is content. Both groups&#xD;
      will not receive any further introduction or support. At the beginning of the scenario, the&#xD;
      manikin will be positioned in a supine position on the floor. There will be no clock visible&#xD;
      for the participant while performing CPR. An investigator is acting as bystander able to call&#xD;
      the emergency medical service or to be sent to look for an automated external defibrillator&#xD;
      (which will not be available in the scenario). Nonetheless, the investigator is instructed&#xD;
      not to provide any information on how to perform CPR and does not physically take part in the&#xD;
      primary check, CC, or mouth-to-mouth ventilations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data of steps performed or left out will be documented in hardcopy on the case report form by&#xD;
      an investigator and the exact times and details of chest compressions and ventilations will&#xD;
      be documented electronically (Laerdal Skillreporter Software with Segstat (Version 2.3.0,&#xD;
      Laerdal Medical, Stavanger, Norway)). Checklists of necessary steps will be created based on&#xD;
      the ERC BLS Guidelines 2010 in the same manner as published previously [Roessler et al. 2007,&#xD;
      Koster et al. 2010].&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the five-minute period has ended, the participants will be informed that the emergency&#xD;
      medical service is now taking over and that they can stop performing CPR. Directly&#xD;
      thereafter, they will be asked the following questions &quot;How exhausted are you now on a scale&#xD;
      from 1 to 10, where 1 indicates no exhaustion at all and 10 maximum exhaustion?&quot; (Lickert&#xD;
      Like 1-10). If a participant choses to abort resuscitation attempts before the five minutes&#xD;
      are over, the open-ended question &quot;Why did you discontinue the resuscitation attempts?&quot; will&#xD;
      be raised.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Risk/benefit assessment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Apart from physical strain such as muscle pain or abrasion on the palm of the hand or knee&#xD;
      after delivering chest compressions, there is no direct risk as the consequence of&#xD;
      participation in the trial. To ensure participants added value, detailed information about&#xD;
      the ERC CPR algorithm will be given after data collection. This information included written&#xD;
      material on the 2010 CPR guidelines, or the 2015 CPR guidelines when available.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 15, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>total number of CC achieving the correct depth of 50-60mm.</measure>
    <time_frame>5min. CPR</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>hands-off time</measure>
    <time_frame>5min CPR</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>the total number of CC</measure>
    <time_frame>5min CPR</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>compression rate</measure>
    <time_frame>5min CPR</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">84</enrollment>
  <condition>CPR Guidelines</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Chest Compressions Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>After recruitment and consenting, volunteers in the &quot;chest compressions only&quot; arm will receive a chart with a description of Basic Life Support without mouth to mouth ventilations. The participants will be asked to perform Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation according to the chart for a period of 5minutes on a manikin in a simulated cardiac arrest scenario.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard CPR</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>After recruitment and consenting, volunteers in the &quot;standard CPR&quot; arm will receive a chart with a description of Basic Life Support. The participants will be asked to perform Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation according to the chart (including the initial check, chest compressions and mouth to mouth ventilations) for a period of 5minutes on a manikin in a simulated cardiac arrest scenario.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Chart for CPR guidance</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Chest Compressions Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Standard CPR</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        ≥18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  professional medical training (nurses, medical doctors, physiotherapists,&#xD;
             ergotherepeuts, emergency medical technician or equivalent)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy (as by verbal response at the time of recruitment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  parallel participation in a clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  physical impairment or illness prohibiting physical effort.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>December 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 29, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 5, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 8, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 13, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 13, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Medical University of Vienna</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Bernhard Roessler</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PD Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

