<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00296478</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FE999913 2004-02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00296478</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Multi-Center, Randomized, Open-Label, Parallel Group Study of a Vaginal Micronized Progesterone Tablet (Endometrin®) Compared to Crinone 8% Vaginal Gel in Female Patients Undergoing In-Vitro Fertilization (IVF)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Multi-Center, Randomized, Open-Label, Parallel Group Study of a Vaginal Micronized Progesterone Tablet (Endometrin®) Compared to Crinone 8% Vaginal Gel in Female Patients Undergoing In-Vitro Fertilization (IVF)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ferring Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ferring Pharmaceuticals</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This multicenter, randomized, open-label study will be performed in approximately 990 healthy&#xD;
      females undergoing IVF. Each study center will follow their study center standard practice&#xD;
      for IVF unless otherwise noted in this protocol. The study centers will be provided with the&#xD;
      medications for down regulation, stimulation and ovulation induction. The subjects will be&#xD;
      randomized to study medication on the day of oocyte retrieval or the day following and will&#xD;
      continue treatment for up to 10 weeks. The subjects with a confirmed pregnancy will be&#xD;
      required to return to the clinic several times during the course of the 10 week treatment&#xD;
      period for serum pregnancy tests and transvaginal ultrasounds to monitor the pregnancy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This multicenter, randomized, open-label study will be performed in approximately 990 healthy&#xD;
      females undergoing IVF. Each study center will follow their study center standard practice&#xD;
      for IVF unless otherwise noted in this protocol. The study centers will be provided with the&#xD;
      medications for down regulation, stimulation and ovulation induction. The subjects will be&#xD;
      randomized to study medication on the day of oocyte retrieval or the day following and will&#xD;
      continue treatment for up to 10 weeks. The subjects with a confirmed pregnancy will be&#xD;
      required to return to the clinic several times during the course of the 10 week treatment&#xD;
      period for serum pregnancy tests and transvaginal ultrasounds to monitor the pregnancy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 2006</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2006</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ongoing pregnancy.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Biochemical pregnancy, clinical pregnancy, pregnancy outcome.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1211</enrollment>
  <condition>Fertility</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Endometrin 100mg BID</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Endometrin 100mg TID</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Crinone</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Endometrin</intervention_name>
    <description>Endometrin 100mg BID x 10weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Endometrin</intervention_name>
    <description>Endometrin 100mg TID x 10weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Crinone</intervention_name>
    <description>Crinone QD x 10weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>3</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pre-menopausal females between the ages of 18 and 42 years Non-smokers. For females&#xD;
             who are past smokers, they must have stopped tobacco usage for at least 3 months prior&#xD;
             to baseline visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Early follicular phase (day 2-4) FSH (follicle stimulating hormone) less than or equal&#xD;
             to 15 IU/L and Estradiol within normal limits&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. LH (luteinizing hormone), PRL (prolactin), T (testosterone), DHEA-S&#xD;
             (dehydroepiandrosterone sulfate) and TSH (thyroid-stimulating hormone), within the&#xD;
             normal limits for the clinical laboratory, or considered not clinically significant by&#xD;
             the investigator within 6 months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Negative serum hepatitis B surface antigen, hepatitis C antibody, HIV antibody, and&#xD;
             rapid plasma reagin tests within 3 months prior to screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Seropositive for rubella and varicella and ABO grouping and Rho (D) typing prior to&#xD;
             screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Documented history of infertility (eg, unable to conceive for at least one year or for&#xD;
             6 months for women ≥38 years of age or bilateral tubal occlusion or absence).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Male partner with recent (within 6 months prior to screening) semen analysis showing&#xD;
             normalcy adequate for IVF by standard WHO and/or Kruger criteria. Donor sperm may be&#xD;
             used, if indicated, provided that it meets standard WHO criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Normal Transvaginal ultrasound at screening (or within 14 days of screening) with&#xD;
             presence of both at least ovaries without evidence of clinically significant&#xD;
             abnormality consistent with findings adequate for ART with respect to uterus and&#xD;
             adnexa (no hydrosalpinx or clinically relevant uterine fibroids).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. At least one cycle with no fertility medication prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Hysterosalpingography, hysteroscopy, or sonohysterogram documenting a normal uterine&#xD;
             cavity.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Negative pregnancy test on the day of pituitary down regulation (prior to&#xD;
             administration of GnRH agonist).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Signed informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Requires Donor oocyte or embryo recipient; gestational or surrogate carrier&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Undergoing blastomer biopsy and other experimental ART procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Inadequate number of oocytes defined as fewer than 3 oocytes retrieved in the study&#xD;
             cycle&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Presence of any clinically relevant systemic disease (eg, insulin-dependent diabetes&#xD;
             mellitus).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Surgical or medical condition which in the judgment of the Investigator or Sponsor may&#xD;
             interfere with absorption, distribution, metabolism, or excretion of the drugs to be&#xD;
             used.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects with a body mass index (BMI) of greater than 34 at time of Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Previous IVF or ART failure due to related to either a sperm/fertilization problem&#xD;
             which resulted in unsuccessful fertilization or an ART with a poor response to&#xD;
             gonadotropins. Poor response is defined as development of less than 2 mature follicles&#xD;
             or history of 2 previous cycle cancellations prior to oocyte retrieval due to poor&#xD;
             response.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Presence of abnormal uterine bleeding of undetermined origin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Current or recent substance abuse, including alcohol and tobacco. (Note: Patients who&#xD;
             stopped tobacco usage at least 3 months prior to screening visit would be allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of chemotherapy (except for gestational conditions) or radiotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Currently breast feeding, pregnant or contraindication to pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Refusal or inability to comply with the requirements of the Protocol for any reason,&#xD;
             including scheduled clinic visits and laboratory tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. For male partner, obvious leukospermia (&gt; 2 million WBC/mL) or signs of infection in&#xD;
             semen sample within past 2 months of pituitary down regulation; if either of these&#xD;
             conditions exists, male should be treated with antibiotics and retested prior to his&#xD;
             partner's pituitary down regulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Documented intolerance or allergy to any of the medications used including the study&#xD;
             medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Participation in any experimental drug study within 60 days prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Use of any of the following medications during the pretreatment and treatment phase:&#xD;
             hormonal drug products (use of oral contraceptives during down regulation is allowed),&#xD;
             progesterone creams, hydrocortisone and other steroid drug products, and fertility&#xD;
             modifiers such as insulin sensitizers.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. History of recurrent pregnancy loss defined as 3 or more spontaneous miscarriages&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>42 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Clinical Development Support</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Ferring Pharmaceuticals</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>May 2011</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 23, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 27, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 18, 2011</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 18, 2011</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 19, 2011</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Clinical Development Support</name_title>
    <organization>Ferring Pharmaceuticals</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Progesterone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

