<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02129543</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20080899</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2019-08554</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02129543</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Immune Reconstitution in Stem Cell Transplant Recipients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Collection of Peripheral Blood Samples From Donors and Recipients of Blood and Marrow Transplants for Laboratory Research in Immune Reconstitution</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Miami</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Miami</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This specimen collection lab protocol will allow the investigators to prospectively study&#xD;
      immune reconstitution in patients being treated for hematologic disorders and immune factors&#xD;
      affecting graft versus host disease in stem-cell transplant (SCT) patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 15, 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of Immune Reconstitution in Study Participants</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The rate of immune reconstitution in study participants treated for hematologic disorders and malignancies including SCT donors and recipients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>T cell subsets derived from samples for participants receiving stem cell therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Identification of the T cell subsets derived from samples from participants receiving stem cell therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immune status of responders and non-responders to CAR-T therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Immune status as determined via the examination of genomic profiles of responders vs non-responders to CAR-T therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">700</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: Treatment for Malignancy/Failure Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants in this group will be those who are undergoing treatment for hematologic malignancy or bone marrow failure state.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: Standard-of-Care SCT Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants in this group will be cancer participants being treated with standard of care stem cell therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C: Adoptive T Cell Therapy Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants in this group will be participants being treated with adoptive T cell therapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm D: Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants without cancer for studies of immunophenotype and immunologic function.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Blood Draw</intervention_name>
    <description>Whole blood samples will be collected from study subjects for immune cell and plasma analysis per protocol.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: Treatment for Malignancy/Failure Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: Standard-of-Care SCT Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C: Adoptive T Cell Therapy Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm D: Control Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood Samples Marrow Samples&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        -  Arm A: All patients undergoing treatment for hematologic malignancy or bone marrow&#xD;
             failure state.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arm B: All cancer patients being treated with standard-of-care SCT will be studied.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arm C: All patients being treated with adoptive T cell therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arm D: Patients without cancer for studies of immunophenotype and immunologic function&#xD;
             as a control for cancer patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Arms will include subjects ranging in age from late adolescence to approximately age 75;&#xD;
        regardless of gender or ethnicity.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arm A: The study population will include subjects selected from all patients&#xD;
             presenting to the clinical services of the Division of Hematology or Transplantation&#xD;
             and Cellular Therapy. As a result, this group will consist of a diverse assortment&#xD;
             including subjects ranging in age from late adolescence to approximately age 75;&#xD;
             individuals of both sexes; and a wide variety of ethnic backgrounds. T h i s will&#xD;
             include patients with a broad range of hematologic malignancies and bone marrow&#xD;
             failure states. We will attempt to study a broad range of patients and not exclude&#xD;
             subjects on the basis of sex, ethnicity, age, or disease status in order to derive a&#xD;
             more complete understanding of variables important in immune reconstitution. It is&#xD;
             expected that up to 10 patients each month may be eligible for this study. Up to 200&#xD;
             patients may be enrolled in this arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arm B: The study population will include subjects selected from all patients&#xD;
             presenting to the clinical services of the Transplantation and Cellular Therapy&#xD;
             Program as donors or recipients for SCT or cellular therapy. As a result, this group&#xD;
             will consist of a diverse assortment including subjects ranging in age from late&#xD;
             adolescence to approximately age 75; individuals of both sexes; and a wide variety of&#xD;
             ethnic backgrounds. All donors will have been cleared for clinical marrow or&#xD;
             peripheral blood stem cell donation, and will be expected to be generally healthy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Recipients will include patients with a broad range of malignancies and will be&#xD;
                  among those selected as clinically fit to undergo SCT. Pregnant women will not be&#xD;
                  included among recipients, but may be present among donor subjects unless&#xD;
                  contraindicated for clinical purposes. For purposes of optimizing specific&#xD;
                  laboratory assays, subjects may be chosen on the basis of known serologic status&#xD;
                  (e.g., those with a history of positive lgG indicating a history of infection&#xD;
                  with cytomegalovirus-CMV, for assays of CMV-specific T cell function). While it&#xD;
                  may not be possible to study each patient presenting as a SCT recipient or donor,&#xD;
                  we will attempt to study a broad range of patients and not exclude subjects on&#xD;
                  the basis of sex, ethnicity, age, or disease status in order to derive a more&#xD;
                  complete understanding of variables important in immune reconstitution following&#xD;
                  SCT. It is expected that up to 6 patients each month may be eligible for this&#xD;
                  study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arm C: The study population will include patients undergoing CAR T therapy. This group&#xD;
             of patients will include subjects ranging in age from late adolescence and adults of&#xD;
             all ages, individuals of both sexes, and a wide variety of ethnic backgrounds. It is&#xD;
             expected that up to 6 patients each month may be eligible for this arm of the study&#xD;
             and up to 100 patients may be enrolled in the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Age &gt; 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Enrollment for treatment with Anti-tumor T cells including either CARs,&#xD;
                  TCR-transgenic, TILs, or Tregs, or DLI&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. White Blood Cell count &gt; 100 k/uL&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Patients will be screened based on their enrollment and planned treatment&#xD;
                       with T cells. Up to 1 month prior to conditioning chemotherapy baseline&#xD;
                       samples will be collected, which can be pre-infusion product or samples&#xD;
                       collected when patients are classified as having Grade 0-2 CRS or Grade 0-2&#xD;
                       Neurotoxicity. Post T cell infusion samples will be collected and this study&#xD;
                       will include fresh, noncryopreserved CSF, and/or BM, and/or blood and/or&#xD;
                       serum obtained from 300 patients treated with adoptively transferred T&#xD;
                       cells. Patient PHI information will be stored on a password-protected&#xD;
                       computer and the database file will be password protected to maximize&#xD;
                       security of PHI. This file will be accessible by the study investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arm D: The goal of this aim is to study groups of subjects to understand immune&#xD;
             function in individuals without cancer, as a reference group for studies of patients&#xD;
             with cancer (including those receiving hematopoietic cell transplants and immune&#xD;
             effector cell therapies). We also expect that these studies will have value&#xD;
             independently to derive an understanding of protective human immunity in patients&#xD;
             without cancer, but in relation to pathogen-specific immunity. This includes immunity&#xD;
             to chronic viral infections (e.g., the herpesviruses that include CMV, EBV, HHV-6 and&#xD;
             VZV), to epidemic and pandemic viruses (e.g., seasonal influenza, SARS-CoV-2) and to&#xD;
             other pathogens (e.g., measles) that are important targets of antiviral immunity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arms A, B, D: There are no exclusion criteria for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arm C:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Prior diagnosis of acquired (eg. HIV/AIDS) or congenital immune deficiencies.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Autoimmune disease requiring disease modifying agent or corticosteroids &lt;2 years&#xD;
                  prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Treatment with an immune-modulatory agent (excludes steroids) within 1 day prior&#xD;
                  to T cell infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Krishna V Komanduri, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Miami</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Krishna V Komanduri, MD</last_name>
    <phone>305-243-6356</phone>
    <email>kkomanduri@med.miami.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Miami</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33136</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Krishna Komaduri, MD</last_name>
      <phone>305-243-6356</phone>
      <email>kkomanduri@med.miami.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Krishna Komaduri, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Eric Wieder, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 30, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 30, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 2, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SCT</keyword>
  <keyword>Stem Cell Transplantation</keyword>
  <keyword>Stem Cell Transplant</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

