<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02122185</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB13-1235</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2014-00860</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>IRB13-1235</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02122185</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Metformin and Chemotherapy in Treating Patients With Stage III-IV Ovarian, Fallopian Tube, or Primary Peritoneal Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Placebo Controlled Phase II Trial of Metformin in Conjunction With Chemotherapy Followed by Metformin Maintenance Therapy in Advanced Stage Ovarian, Fallopian Tube and Primary Peritoneal Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Chicago</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Chicago</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This randomized phase II trial studies how well metformin hydrochloride and combination&#xD;
      chemotherapy works in treating patients with stage III-IV ovarian, fallopian tube, or primary&#xD;
      peritoneal cancer. Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as carboplatin, paclitaxel and docetaxel,&#xD;
      work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells, by&#xD;
      stopping them from dividing, or by stopping them from spreading. Metformin hydrochloride may&#xD;
      help carboplatin, paclitaxel and docetaxel work better by making tumor cells more sensitive&#xD;
      to the drugs. Studying samples of blood and tissue in the laboratory from patients receiving&#xD;
      metformin hydrochloride may help doctors learn more about the effects of metformin&#xD;
      hydrochloride on cells. It may also help doctors understand how well patients respond to&#xD;
      treatment. Giving metformin hydrochloride together with combination chemotherapy may kill&#xD;
      more tumor cells.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine if the addition of metformin to standard adjuvant or neoadjuvant chemotherapy&#xD;
      plus extended metformin (metformin hydrochloride) beyond standard chemotherapy increases&#xD;
      progression free survival when compared to 6 cycles of standard chemotherapy alone in&#xD;
      non-diabetic subjects with stage III (with any gross residual disease) or stage IV ovarian,&#xD;
      primary peritoneal, or fallopian tube carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine whether the addition of metformin to standard chemotherapy plus extended&#xD;
      metformin beyond standard chemotherapy increases the time to biochemical progression when&#xD;
      compared to chemotherapy alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To compare biochemical (cancer antigen [CA]-125) response rates in the two arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To describe and compare toxicities in the two arms. IV. To compare overall survival in&#xD;
      both arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TERTIARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To elucidate metformin's molecular mechanism of action in ovarian, fallopian tube or&#xD;
      primary peritoneal cancer by: determining whether metformin's anti-cancer effects are&#xD;
      mediated by systemic metabolic changes, a direct effect on tumor cells, or both, and testing&#xD;
      the metabolic and proteomic alterations induced in biospecimens from non-diabetic patients&#xD;
      prospectively treated with standard chemotherapy in conjunction with metformin compared to&#xD;
      placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive a standard chemotherapy regimen at the discretion of the treating physician.&#xD;
      Regimens include either paclitaxel intravenously (IV) over 2-3 hours and carboplatin IV over&#xD;
      30-60 minutes on day 1; docetaxel IV over 1 hour on and carboplatin IV over 30-60 minutes on&#xD;
      day 1; or paclitaxel IV over 1 hour on days 1, 8, and 15, and carboplatin IV over 30-60&#xD;
      minutes on day 1. Treatment repeats every 21 days for up to 6 courses. Patients are&#xD;
      randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM I: Patients receive metformin hydrochloride orally (PO) twice daily (BID) and standard&#xD;
      chemotherapy regimen as above for 6 courses. Treatment for metformin hydrochloride continues&#xD;
      for up to 2 years in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM II: Patients receive placebo PO BID and standard chemotherapy regimen as above for 6&#xD;
      courses. Treatment for placebo continues for up to 2 years in the absence of disease&#xD;
      progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 2 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Suspended</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Enrollment halted for planned interim analysis.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 25, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 25, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 25, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival (PFS) evaluated using the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version (v)1.1 and Gynecological Cancer Intergroup (GCIG) criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>Time from randomization until disease progression or death from any cause, assessed up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Kaplan-Meier curves will be generated and the metformin and placebo groups compared using a logrank test stratified by initial treatment (primary debulking surgery or neoadjuvant therapy). A one-sided alpha level of 0.15 will be used to determine statistical significance. Median PFS and associated 90% confidence interval will be estimated using the method described in Brookmeyer and Crowley. A Cox regression model will also be fit to assess and adjust for the effects of the stratification factor and other baseline covariates (for example, age, ECOG performance status).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to biochemical (CA-125) progression using GCIG criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Analyzed using Kaplan-Meier curves, stratified logrank test, and Cox regression modeling. CA-125 response rates in the subgroup of patients with elevated CA-125 at entry (i.e., &gt; institutional ULN) will be compared between the two treatment arms using a chi-square test.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Analyzed using Kaplan-Meier curves, stratified logrank test, and Cox regression modeling.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events, graded according to the National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events version 4.0</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events will be summarized by type, grade, and attribution. Treatment group comparisons will be performed using chi-square or Fisher's exact test.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">160</enrollment>
  <condition>Brenner Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Ascites</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Pleural Effusion</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Clear Cell Cystadenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Endometrioid Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Mixed Epithelial Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Serous Cystadenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Undifferentiated Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Fallopian Tube Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Ovarian Epithelial Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Ovarian Germ Cell Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Primary Peritoneal Cavity Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA Fallopian Tube Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA Ovarian Epithelial Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA Ovarian Germ Cell Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA Primary Peritoneal Cavity Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIB Fallopian Tube Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIB Ovarian Epithelial Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIB Ovarian Germ Cell Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIB Primary Peritoneal Cavity Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIC Fallopian Tube Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIC Ovarian Epithelial Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIC Ovarian Germ Cell Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIC Primary Peritoneal Cavity Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Fallopian Tube Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Ovarian Epithelial Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Ovarian Germ Cell Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Primary Peritoneal Cavity Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Metformin plus chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive metformin hydrochloride PO BID and standard chemotherapy for 6 -8 cycles. Treatment with metformin hydrochloride continues for up to 2 years in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo plus chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive placebo PO BID and standard chemotherapy for 6 -8 cycles. Treatment with placebo continues for up to 2 years in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>metformin hydrochloride</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Metformin plus chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Glucophage</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo plus chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PLCB</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Chemotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will received standard chemotherapy (6-8 cycles). Specific regimen to be given is at the discretion of their treating physician.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Metformin plus chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo plus chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA FOR PRE-REGISTRATION&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A reasonable suspicion of ovarian cancer by the treating oncologist is required,&#xD;
             evidenced by abdominal carcinomatosis, omental caking, pleural effusions or ascites&#xD;
             AND an elevated CA125 &gt; 250 OR CA125:carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) ratio &gt; 25 OR&#xD;
             CA125 =&lt; 250 with no evidence of gastrointestinal (GI) cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status =&lt; 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Leukocytes &gt;= 3,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,500/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &gt;= 100,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; upper normal institutional limits (except for patients with&#xD;
             Gilbert's disease who are eligible despite elevated serum bilirubin level)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase&#xD;
             [SGOT])/alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase [SGPT])&#xD;
             =&lt; 2.0 × institutional upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine =&lt; institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) OR creatinine clearance &gt;= 60&#xD;
             mL/min/1.73 m^2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood glucose =&lt; 126 mg/dL fasting or =&lt; 140 mg/dL nonfasting&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed written pre-registration informed consent document&#xD;
&#xD;
        ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA FOR REGISTRATION:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed carcinoma consistent with ovarian, fallopian tube, or primary&#xD;
             peritoneal carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects undergoing primary debulking surgery must have stage III or IV disease and&#xD;
             have undergone surgery to include, at a minimum, removal of the uterus, ovaries and&#xD;
             fallopian tubes; these patients may be optimally debulked (less than 1 cm residual&#xD;
             disease) but must have grossly visible macroscopic residual disease OR be suboptimally&#xD;
             debulked&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects for whom neoadjuvant chemotherapy followed by interval cytoreductive surgery&#xD;
             is planned must have fine needle aspirate (FNA) or other cytology showing&#xD;
             adenocarcinoma OR core biopsies OR surgically directed biopsies showing adenocarcinoma&#xD;
             AND CA125 over 250 OR CA125:CEA ratio &gt; 25 OR CA =&lt; 250 with no evidence of GI cancer;&#xD;
             they should have presumed stage III or IV disease, generally based on abdominal&#xD;
             carcinomatosis, omental caking, pleural effusions or ascites&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject and her physician must agree to six cycles or up to 8 cycles of one of the&#xD;
             standard of care regimens allowed on this protocol; these regimens (starting dosage)&#xD;
             include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        If &lt; 70 years old:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IV paclitaxel 175 mg/m^2 and carboplatin area under the curve (AUC) 5-6 every 21 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IV docetaxel 75 mg/m^2 and carboplatin AUC 5-6 every 21 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IV paclitaxel 80 mg/m^2 day 1, 8, and 15 and carboplatin AUC 5-6 day 1 every 21 days&#xD;
&#xD;
        If 70 years or older:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IV paclitaxel 135 mg/m^2 plus IV carboplatin AUC 5 plus optional G-CSF every 21 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IV paclitaxel 60 mg/m^2 day 1, 8, 15 plus IV carboplatin AUC 5 every 21 days (Day 15&#xD;
             paclitaxel optional)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IV paclitaxel 60 mg/m^2 plus IV carboplatin AUC 2 day 1, 8, and 15 every 21 days&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ECOG performance status =&lt; 2&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Leukocytes &gt;= 3,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,500/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  platelets &gt;= 100,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  total bilirubin =&lt; upper normal institutional limits (except for patients with&#xD;
                  Gilbert's disease who are eligible despite elevated serum bilirubin level)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST(SGOT)/ALT(SGPT) =&lt; 2.0 × institutional upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  creatinine =&lt; OR institutional ULN OR creatinine clearance &gt;= 60 mL/min/1.73 m^2&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  blood glucose =&lt; 126 mg/dL fasting or =&lt; 140 mg/dL nonfasting&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  women of child-bearing potential must agree to use an effective method of birth&#xD;
                  control on trial, as the safety of metformin in pregnancy has not been&#xD;
                  established; an effective method of birth control includes surgical sterilization&#xD;
                  of woman or her partner, abstinence, or two barrier methods (e.g. condom plus&#xD;
                  diaphragm); hormonal methods of birth control are not permitted on this study&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent&#xD;
                  document&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA FOR PRE-REGISTRATION&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with known diabetes and those taking metformin, sulfonylureas,&#xD;
             thiazolidinediones or insulin for any reason&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are receiving any other investigational agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with comorbidities that would limit their two year survival for reasons other&#xD;
             than ovarian cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent active invasive malignancy or one previously diagnosed with a greater than&#xD;
             30% chance of recurrence in the next two years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to metformin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must not have conditions associated with increased risk of&#xD;
             metformin-associated lactic acidosis, including New York Heart Association class III&#xD;
             or IV congestive heart failure, history of acidosis of any type, alcoholic liver&#xD;
             disease, or habitual intake of 3 or more alcoholic beverages per day&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             major infection, unstable angina pectoris, or psychiatric illness/social situations&#xD;
             that would limit compliance with study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or nursing women&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA FOR REGISTRATION:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mucinous adenocarcinoma, borderline tumors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects who will undergo intraperitoneal chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects receiving neoadjuvant chemotherapy for whom interval debulking surgery&#xD;
             (assuming adequate response to therapy) is not planned&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects receiving chemotherapy regimens not specified in the inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects should not be participating in other clinical trials of interventions&#xD;
             designed to reduce risk of ovarian cancer recurrence or plan to receive off -protocol&#xD;
             maintenance therapy (e.g. paclitaxel or bevacizumab)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects with known diabetes, fasting glucose over 126 mg/dL or random glucose over&#xD;
             140 mg/dL and those taking metformin, sulfonylureas, thiazolidenediones or insulin for&#xD;
             any reason&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who are receiving any other investigational agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects with comorbidities which would lead to a clinical expectation that they will&#xD;
             not survive two years for reasons other than ovarian cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  concurrent active invasive malignancy or one previously diagnosed with a greater than&#xD;
             30% chance of recurrence in the next two years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to metformin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects must not have conditions associated with increased risk of&#xD;
             metformin-associated lactic acidosis, including New York Heart Association class III&#xD;
             or IV congestive heart failure, history of acidosis of any type, alcoholic liver&#xD;
             disease, or habitual intake of 3 or more alcoholic beverages per day&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with&#xD;
             study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnant or nursing women&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Seiko Yamada</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Chicago</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35233</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mitchell Cancer Institute - University of South Alabama</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mobile</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>36604</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City of Hope</name>
      <address>
        <city>Duarte</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NCH Medical Group- Northwest Community Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Arlington Heights</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60005</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rush University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Chicago</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60637</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Decatur Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Decatur</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>62526</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NorthShore University HealthSystem</name>
      <address>
        <city>Evanston</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ingalls Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Harvey</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60426</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 22, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 23, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 24, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Germ Cell and Embryonal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Ovarian Epithelial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peritoneal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Germinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pleural Effusion, Malignant</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Endometrioid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cystadenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cystadenocarcinoma, Serous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brenner Tumor</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pleural Effusion</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ascites</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

