<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02127203</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UDDS-Perio-03-2014</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02127203</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Nitro-oxidative Stress in Periodontitis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Assessment of Nitro - Oxidative Stress in Periodontal Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Damascus University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Damascus University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Periodontitis is a chronic inflammatory disease whose etio-pathogencity is not fully&#xD;
      understood yet. Reactive oxygen species (ROS) and reactive nitrogen species (RNS) are&#xD;
      involved in physiological and pathological processes. Nitro-oxidative stress has been&#xD;
      implicated in Periodontitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to assess the levels of ROS and RNS in serum and gingival crevicular&#xD;
      fluid (GCF) samples taken from periodontitis (chronic and aggressive) patients and healthy&#xD;
      controls. Subsequently, correlating these levels with the severity of periodontal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eighty subjects will be invited to participate in this study. Patients will be allocated into&#xD;
      four groups (20 patients each). The biochemical parameters that will be investigated are&#xD;
      Malondialdehyde (MDA) (using TBRSA assay) as a marker of oxidative stress and (NO- level&#xD;
      using Griess reagent) as a marker of nitrosative stress.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Teeth and their supporting periodontal structures are of great importance in good oral&#xD;
      health. Periodontitis is an inflammatory disease of the periodontium which affects the&#xD;
      supporting tissues of the teeth. The disease is multifaceted and its etio-pathogenecity is&#xD;
      still not fully understood and therefore the treatment of different types of periodontal&#xD;
      disease can be very difficult. Numerous risk factors have been implicated in the disease&#xD;
      process including risk determinants and risk indicators. Most recently, strong body of&#xD;
      evidence has accumulated to support a role for reactive oxygen (ROS) and nitrogen species&#xD;
      (RNS) either as trigger agents or more frequently, aggravators of the primary lesions in&#xD;
      periodontitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Oxygen and nitrogen reactive species are involved in a large number of physiological and&#xD;
      pathological processes. ROS generated by monocytes and neutrophyles during inflammation are&#xD;
      important aggression factors in the periodontal tissues. ROS play an important role in&#xD;
      activation of osteoclasts and in bone resorption.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Oxidative stress is a condition arising when there is a serious imbalance between the levels&#xD;
      of free radicals in a cell and its antioxidant defenses in favor of the former. Thus, tissue&#xD;
      damage can result when antioxidant systems are unable to counteract the free radicals actions&#xD;
      efficiently. Inflammation when stimulated by bacterial pathogens, host cells release&#xD;
      proinflammatory cytokines (IL-1α, IL-6, IL-8, and tumor necrosis factor-α) as part of immune&#xD;
      response. These cytokines recruit polymorphonuclear cells (PMNs) that play a major role in&#xD;
      the etiology of periodontal disease by producing proteolytic enzymes, such as elastase and O2&#xD;
      (molecular oxygen) by the oxidative burst.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a recent study, Abou Sulaiman &amp; Shehadeh found that serum total antioxidant capacity (TAS)&#xD;
      was lower in non-smokers Syrian patients with chronic periodontitis compared to healthy&#xD;
      controls. Also, they reported that periodontal treatment restored TAS levels to normal levels&#xD;
      similar to healthy controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to assess the levels of ROS and RNS in serum and gingival crevicular&#xD;
      fluid (GCF) samples taken from periodontitis patients (chronic and aggressive) and healthy&#xD;
      controls. Subsequently, correlating these levels with severity of periodontal disease in&#xD;
      Syrian patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials and methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of 80 subjects will be invited to participate in this study from the patients&#xD;
      referred to the Department of Periodontology, Faculty of Dentistry, University of Damascus.&#xD;
      The study has been approved by our local Review Board. Subjects will be recruited according&#xD;
      to specific inclusion criteria after completion of medical and dental history questionnaires.&#xD;
      Patients will sign a consent form after being advised about the nature of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The selection of patients will be made according of the criteria approved by the 1999&#xD;
      international world workshop for a classification system of periodontal diseases and&#xD;
      conditions using five clinical parameters and full mouth or panoramic radiographs for&#xD;
      diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be allocated into four groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Chronic Periodontitis group (ChP): comprise 20 patients aged &gt; 45 years and have&#xD;
           presence of ≥2 non-adjacent sites per quadrant that were not first molars or incisors,&#xD;
           with probing depth (PD) ≥5 mm, which bleed on gentle probing. The demonstrated&#xD;
           radiographic bone loss ≥30% of the root length, patient with poor oral hygiene, the&#xD;
           amount of accumulated plaque commensurate with the amount of clinical attachment level&#xD;
           (CAL)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Resistant Control group (R): comprise 20 age-sex matched patients who are &gt; 45 years&#xD;
           exhibit no signs of periodontal disease as determined by the absence of the evidence of&#xD;
           interproximal (CAL ≤ 1mm), PD &gt; 3 mm at any site, whole-mouth bleeding scores &lt;10% and&#xD;
           have no clinical signs of gingival inflammation .&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Aggressive Periodontitis group (AgP): comprise 20 patients who are aged &lt; 35 years and&#xD;
           diagnosed with rapid attachment loss with periodontal pocket depth (PD) &gt; 4 mm around at&#xD;
           least three teeth other than the first molars and incisors. Rapid bone destruction&#xD;
           (&gt;50%bone loss at diseased sites). Weak relationship between dental plaque and the&#xD;
           severity of gingival inflammation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Young Control group (YC): comprise 20 age- and sex matched patients who are &lt; 35 years&#xD;
           and exhibit no signs of periodontal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical measurements:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A standard periodontal probe will be used for recording periodontal indices at six sites per&#xD;
      tooth. The examined clinical parameters include bleeding on probing (BOP), plaque index (PI),&#xD;
      clinical attachment loss (CAL) and periodontal pocket depth (PPD) and gingival index (GI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Collection of samples&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be asked to refrain from brushing within 1 hour of sampling. (GCF) samples will&#xD;
      be obtained using standard paper strips (Periocol strips, Oraflow, NY, USA). 6 samples from&#xD;
      each individual (mesiofacial, distopalatal) sites from each examined tooth (incisor, premolar&#xD;
      and molar) in the maxilla (Chapple et al. 2002). Strips will be put in PBS Buffer solution&#xD;
      for 30 minutes then extracted and stored under liquid nitrogen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Venous blood samples will be collected from the antecubital fossa and stored in lithium&#xD;
      heparin tubes and allowed to stand for 30 minutes before being centrifuged at 1000 ×g for 30&#xD;
      minutes, samples will be aliquoted into cryogenic vials and will be stored under liquid&#xD;
      nitrogen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laboratory studies:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  TBARS assay (HPLC) will be used to assess the malondialdihyde levels as a marker of&#xD;
           oxidative stress.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Griess reagent to assess nitric oxide levels as a marker of nitrosative stress.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Nitric oxide levels in serum and gingival cervicular fluid</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 hours after the collection of the serum and gingival fluid</time_frame>
    <description>Griess reagent to assess nitric oxide levels as a marker of nitrosative stress.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Malondialdihyide levels in serum and gingival cervicular fluid</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 24 hours after the collection of the serum and gingival fluid</time_frame>
    <description>TBARS assay (HPLC) will be used to assess the malondialdihyde levels as a marker of oxidative stress.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bleeding on Probing (BOP)</measure>
    <time_frame>One time assessment once sample recruitment has completed. This outcome will be assessed within one week before treatment provision</time_frame>
    <description>A standard periodontal probe will be used for recording periodontal indices at six sites per tooth. The examined clinical parameters include bleeding on probing (BOP)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plaque Index (PI)</measure>
    <time_frame>One time assessment once sample recruitment has completed. This outcome will be assessed within one week before treatment provision</time_frame>
    <description>A standard periodontal probe will be used for recording periodontal indices at six sites per tooth.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Attachment Loss (CAL)</measure>
    <time_frame>One time assessment once sample recruitment has completed. This outcome will be assessed within one week before treatment provision</time_frame>
    <description>A standard periodontal probe will be used for recording periodontal indices at six sites per tooth.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Periodontal Pocket Depth (PPD)</measure>
    <time_frame>One time assessment once sample recruitment has completed. This outcome will be assessed within one week before treatment provision</time_frame>
    <description>A standard periodontal probe will be used for recording periodontal indices at six sites per tooth.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gingival Index (GI).</measure>
    <time_frame>One time assessment once sample recruitment has completed. This outcome will be assessed within one week before treatment provision</time_frame>
    <description>A standard periodontal probe will be used for recording periodontal indices at six sites per tooth.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Periodontitis</condition>
  <condition>Aggressive Periodontitis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Chronic Periodontitis group (ChP)</arm_group_label>
    <description>20 patients aged &gt; 45 years and have presence of ≥2 non-adjacent sites per quadrant that were not first molars or incisors, with probing depth (PD) ≥5 mm, which bleed on gentle probing. The demonstrated radiographic bone loss ≥30% of the root length, patient with poor oral hygiene, the amount of accumulated plaque commensurate with the amount of clinical attachment level (CAL)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Resistant Control group (R)</arm_group_label>
    <description>20 age-sex matched patients who are &gt; 45 years exhibit no signs of periodontal disease as determined by the absence of the evidence of interproximal (CAL ≤ 1mm), PD &gt; 3 mm at any site, whole-mouth bleeding scores &lt;10% and have no clinical signs of gingival inflammation .</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Aggressive Periodontitis group (AgP)</arm_group_label>
    <description>20 patients who are aged &lt; 35 years and diagnosed with rapid attachment loss with periodontal pocket depth (PD) &gt; 4 mm around at least three teeth other than the first molars and incisors. Rapid bone destruction (&gt;50%bone loss at diseased sites). Weak relationship between dental plaque and the severity of gingival inflammation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Young Control group (YC)</arm_group_label>
    <description>20 age- and sex matched patients who are &lt; 35 years and exhibit no signs of periodontal disease.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        A total of 80 subjects will be invited to participate in this study from the patients&#xD;
        referred to the Department of Periodontology, Faculty of Dentistry, University of Damascus.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The study has been pproved by our local Review Board. Subjects will be recruited according&#xD;
        to specific inclusion criteria after completion of medical and dental history&#xD;
        questionnaires. Patients will sign a consent form after being advised about the nature of&#xD;
        the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The selection of patients will be made according of the criteria approved by the 1999&#xD;
        international world workshop for a classification system of periodontal diseases and&#xD;
        conditions (Armitage 1999) using five clinical parameters and full mouth or panoramic&#xD;
        radiographs for diagnosis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients of Syrian descent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemically healthy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have at least 20 teeth&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Periodontal treatment during the last three months,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of major systemic diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consumption of anti oxidant supplements, antibiotics, anti inflammatory or any other&#xD;
             drugs in the last three months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smoking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alcohol consumption&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant and lactating women.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Abeer Alasadi, DDS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>MSc student, Department of Periodontology, University of Damascus Dental School</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ali Abou Sulaiman, DDS MSc Phd</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Senior Lecturer in Periodontics, University of Damascus Dental School, Damascus</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Francoise Qarabit, BSc MSc PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Senior Lecturer in Chemistry, Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Sciences, University of Damascus, Baramkeh, Damascus, Syria</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Periodontics, University of Damascus Dental School</name>
      <address>
        <city>Damascus</city>
        <zip>DM20AM18</zip>
        <country>Syrian Arab Republic</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Syrian Arab Republic</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Abou Sulaiman AE, Shehadeh RM. Assessment of total antioxidant capacity and the use of vitamin C in the treatment of non-smokers with chronic periodontitis. J Periodontol. 2010 Nov;81(11):1547-54. doi: 10.1902/jop.2010.100173. Epub 2010 Jun 22.</citation>
    <PMID>20569170</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Armitage GC. Development of a classification system for periodontal diseases and conditions. Ann Periodontol. 1999 Dec;4(1):1-6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>10863370</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chapple IL, Matthews JB. The role of reactive oxygen and antioxidant species in periodontal tissue destruction. Periodontol 2000. 2007;43:160-232. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17214840</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Halliwell B. Reactive oxygen species in living systems: source, biochemistry, and role in human disease. Am J Med. 1991 Sep 30;91(3C):14S-22S. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>1928205</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kinane DF. Causation and pathogenesis of periodontal disease. Periodontol 2000. 2001;25:8-20. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11155179</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sies H. Oxidative stress: oxidants and antioxidants. Exp Physiol. 1997 Mar;82(2):291-5. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>9129943</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wactawski-Wende J. Periodontal diseases and osteoporosis: association and mechanisms. Ann Periodontol. 2001 Dec;6(1):197-208. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11887465</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 25, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 28, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 30, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 2, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 2, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">October 5, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>oxidative stress</keyword>
  <keyword>periodontal disease</keyword>
  <keyword>nitric oxide</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Periodontal Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Chronic Periodontitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Aggressive Periodontitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

