<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02121639</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RHMCAN0935</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02121639</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Open Label Phase I/Randomised,Double Blind Phase II Study in mCRPC of AZD5363 In Combination With DP Chemotherapy</brief_title>
  <acronym>ProCAID</acronym>
  <official_title>An Open Label Phase I/Randomised, Double Blind Phase II Study in Metastatic Castration Resistant Prostate Cancer of AZD5363 In Combination With Docetaxel and Prednisolone Chemotherapy (ProCAID)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital Southampton NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cancer Research UK</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital Southampton NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the ProCAID study is to determine if the addition of the AKT inhibitor AZD5363 to&#xD;
      docetaxel and prednisolone (DP) prolongs progression free survival (PFS) in Metastatic&#xD;
      castration resistant prostate cancer to a degree worthy of further investigation&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 29, 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 8, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase I:Determination of a suitable dose of AZD5363</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Phase I:Determination of a suitable dose of AZD5363 using a 4 days on/3 days off continuous schedule, in combination with Docetaxol and prednisolone chemotherapy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Phase II: Progression free survival (PFS) in patients receiving AZD5363 versus placebo when combined with Docetaxol and prednisolone chemotherapy (DP) in metastic castration resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase I: Safety and tolerability profiles</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Phase I: Safety and tolerability profiles using Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 4.03</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase I: AZD5363 pharmacokinetics Area Under Curve (AUC) Time Frame: predose, 2, 4, 8, 24,144 hours post-dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Phase I: AZD5363 pharmacokinetics in combination with Docetaxol and prednisolone chemotherapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Bone Pain</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Phase II: Bone pain changes using the brief pain inventory</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Progression Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Phase II: Progression Free Survival excluding biochemical (Prostate Specific Antigen - PSA) alone progression</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Biochemical (PSA) response rates according to PCWG2 criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Phase II: Biochemical (Prostate Specific Antigen - PSA) response rates according to Prostate Cancer Working Gourp (PCWG2) criteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Safety and tolerability profiles using CTCAE version 4.03</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Phase II: Safety and tolerability profiles using Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 4.03</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">168</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AZD5363</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>AZD5363</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AZD5363</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>AZD5363</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Histologically or cytologically proven mCRPC with documented metastases (measurable or&#xD;
             evaluable disease is acceptable) now eligible for treatment with docetaxel&#xD;
             chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Disease progression since the last change in therapy defined by one or more of the&#xD;
             following according to the Prostate Cancer Working Group (PCWG2) criteria (J Clin&#xD;
             Oncol 2008;26:1148-1159):&#xD;
&#xD;
             i. PSA progression as defined by the prostate cancer working group (2) (PCWG2)&#xD;
             criteria (Scher et al. 2008 J Clin Oncol. 26; 1148). This must be based on a series of&#xD;
             at least 3 readings at least 7 days apart. The 3rd reading must be &gt;= 2ng/ml. In the&#xD;
             event where an intermediate reading is lower than a previous reading, then the patient&#xD;
             will still be eligible (ie. the 3 readings do not need to be consecutive). The first&#xD;
             of the three readings must have been obtained after commencing the previous systemic&#xD;
             therapy, or, in the case of androgen receptor antagonists, after discontinuing.&#xD;
&#xD;
             ii. Radiographic progression of nodal or visceral metastases as defined by RECIST&#xD;
             version 1.1 (Eur J Cancer 2009;45:228). See Appendix 5 iii. The appearance of two or&#xD;
             more new bony metastases&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Serum testosterone &lt;1.7 nmol/L (ongoing LHRH analogue or antagonist therapy is&#xD;
             permitted to maintain a castrate state)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Discontinuation of prior therapies for prostate cancer ≥ 4 weeks prior to commencing&#xD;
             study treatment (with the exception of an LHRH agonist or antagonist where required&#xD;
             for ongoing testosterone suppression)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. No current anti-androgen withdrawal response from bicalutamide or flutamide.&#xD;
             Consistent with PCWG2 guidelines, investigators should evaluate patients to exclude&#xD;
             withdrawal response for 6 weeks after stopping bicalutamide or flutamide.&#xD;
             Investigators need not wait to assess for withdrawal response in patients who did not&#xD;
             respond, or who showed a PSA decline for ≤ 3 months, after bicalutamide or flutamide&#xD;
             was administered as a second-line or later intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. ECOG performance status 0 or 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Hb ≥ 9g/dL; platelets ≥ 100 x 109/L; neutrophils ≥ 1.5 x109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Bilirubin ≤ ULN ; ALT and AST ≤ 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Sodium and potassium within the normal range for the site&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Able to swallow study drugs (without crushing/opening in the case of AZD5363)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Life expectancy &gt; 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Aged 18 years or over&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Provision of written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Previous treatment with cytotoxic chemotherapy for castrate resistant prostate cancer.&#xD;
             Patients may have received previous docetaxel for up to 6 cycles given in the 'hormone&#xD;
             sensitive setting' or ongoing bisphosphonates or denosumab. There are no restrictions&#xD;
             on prior use of second generation hormonal therapies e.g. abiraterone, enzalutamide as&#xD;
             long as they have been discontinued ≥ 2 weeks prior to commencing study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Prior malignancy with an estimated ≥ 30% chance of relapse within 2 years following&#xD;
             curative treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Previously identified brain metastases, or spinal cord compression unless treated with&#xD;
             full functional recovery&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prior radiotherapy to &gt; 30% of bone marrow&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Administration of an investigational agent within 30 days of first dose of study&#xD;
             medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients will be excluded with any of:&#xD;
&#xD;
             i. Diabetes mellitus type I ii. Fasting plasma glucose [fasting is defined as no&#xD;
             calorific intake for at least 8 hours] of either ≥ 7.0mmol/L (126 mg/dL) for those&#xD;
             patients without a pre-existing diagnosis of Type 2 diabetes mellitus or ≥ 9.3 mmol/L&#xD;
             (167mg/dL) for those patients with a pre-existing diagnosis of Type 2 diabetes&#xD;
             mellitus iii. Glycosylated haemoglobin (HbA1C) ≥8.0% (63.9 mmol/mol) iv. Requirement&#xD;
             for insulin for routine diabetic management and control v. Requirement for more than&#xD;
             two oral hypoglycaemic medications for routine diabetic management and control.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Malabsorption syndrome, previous gastrointestinal surgery, or other gastrointestinal&#xD;
             condition that may affect drug absorption&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Coronary artery bypass graft, angioplasty, vascular stent, myocardial infarction,&#xD;
             angina pectoris or congestive heart failure (NYHA ≥ grade 2) within the last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Abnormal echocardiogram or MUGA (LVEF should be normal according to the criteria used&#xD;
             within the treating institution&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Uncontrolled hypotension (systolic blood pressure &lt;90 mmHg and/or diastolic blood&#xD;
             pressure &lt;50 mmHg)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. QTc interval of &gt;480 msec at two or more time points within a 24 hour period&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Proteinuria (either 3+ on dipstick analysis or &gt;500 mg/24 hours) or creatinine &gt;1.5 x&#xD;
             ULN concurrent with creatinine clearance &lt;50 mL/min (assessed as per local practice&#xD;
             e.g. by Cockcroft and Gault estimation)&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Exposure to potent inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A4 or CYP2D6 or substrates of CYP3A4&#xD;
             within 2 weeks before the first dose of study treatment (3 weeks for St John's Wort)&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Unresolved toxicity ≥ grade 2 (except alopecia) from previous cancer therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Patients with a partner of child-bearing potential who are not using a highly&#xD;
             effective method of contraception, who are unwilling to use condoms during the study&#xD;
             and for 30 days after the last dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Known hypersensitivity to AZD5363, its excipients, or drugs in its class&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Previous exposure to agents with the following mechanisms of action:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  inhibition of AKT (e.g., MK2206, GDC0068, GSK2110183, GSK2141795)any inhibitor&#xD;
                  with PI3K pharmacology (e.g., GDC0941, XL147, BKM120, PX866, BYL719, AMG319,&#xD;
                  GDC0032, INK1117, INK119)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  any compound with mixed PI3K and mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) kinase&#xD;
                  pharmacology (e.g., BEZ235, GDC0980, PF04691502, PF05212384, GSK2126458, XL765)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  or any mTOR kinase inhibitor (e.g., AZD8055, AZD2014, OSI027, INK128) Note: Do&#xD;
                  not exclude patients previously treated with a rapalogue (allosteric inhibitor of&#xD;
                  mTOR; mTORC1 complex inhibitor) - including temisirolimus (Torisel; Pfizer),&#xD;
                  everolimus (Affinitor; Novartis), ridoforolimus (Ariad).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Southampton General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Southampton</city>
        <state>Hampshire</state>
        <zip>SO16 6YD</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 16, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 22, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 23, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Metastatic Castration Resistant Prostate Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>AZD5363</keyword>
  <keyword>Docetaxel</keyword>
  <keyword>Prednisolone</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

