<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04800978</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ESR-18-14325</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04800978</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Combination of Durvalumab and BVAC-C in Patients With HPV 16 or 18 Positive Cervical Cancer Failure to First-Line Platinum-based Chemotherapy</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open Label, Single Arm, Safety Lead-in, Multicenter, Investigator Initiated Trial of Combination of Durvalumab , An Immune Checkpoint Inhibitor, and BVAC-C, A Cell-based Immunotherapeutic Vaccine, in Patients With HPV 16 or 18 Positive Cervical Cancer Failure to First-Line Platinum-based Chemotherapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Samsung Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Asan Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Seoul National University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Seoul National University Bundang Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Severance Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Center, Korea</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Samsung Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an exploratory, open label, multi-center trial to evaluate the safety and efficacy of&#xD;
      combination of durvalumab with BVAC-C in patients with cervical cancer refractory to or&#xD;
      relapse after platinum-based first-line chemotherapy with safety lead-in phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study consists of 2 parts: part A, a safety lead-in phase, and part B, an exploratory&#xD;
      safety and efficacy evaluation phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part A will be conducted as a 3+3 dose escalation manner, and part B will be conducted as a&#xD;
      non-randomized single arm study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      •Part A: Open-labeled; 3+3 dose-escalation; Multi-center; safety lead-in phase&#xD;
&#xD;
      •Part B: Open-labeled; Non-randomized, Single arm; Multi-center, efficacy evaluation phase&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 14, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>•Part A: Open-labeled; 3+3 dose-escalation; Multi-center; safety lead-in phase&#xD;
•Part B: Open-labeled; Non-randomized, Single arm; Multi-center, efficacy evaluation phase</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A : Dose-limiting toxicities(DLTs)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 11 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The primary objective of the part A is to assess the maximum tolerable dose of BVAC-C combined with durvalumab 1500 mg as defined by dose-limiting toxicities (DLTs), and to find the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) that can be safely used for Part B (single arm phase II).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part B : Evaluate the safety and clinical efficacy, as measured by 6-month PFS rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 Months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary objective of the part B is to evaluate the safety and clinical efficacy, as measured by 6-month PFS rate, of the combination therapy of durvalumab and BVAC-C in patients with HPV 16 or 18 positive cervical cancer recurrent after or refractory to first-line platinum-based chemotherapy +/-bevacizumab.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Best overall response rate(BORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>12~24 Months</time_frame>
    <description>• To evaluate the response to the combination therapy as measured by best overall response rate (BORR), 12-month and 24-month disease control rate (DCR), 12-month and-24 month progression free survival (PFS) rate and 12-month and 24-month overall survival (OS) rate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease control rate(DCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>12~24 Months</time_frame>
    <description>• To evaluate the response to the combination therapy as measured by best overall response rate (BORR), 12-month and 24-month disease control rate (DCR), 12-month and-24 month progression free survival (PFS) rate and 12-month and 24-month overall survival (OS) rate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival (PFS) rate</measure>
    <time_frame>12~24 Months</time_frame>
    <description>• To evaluate the response to the combination therapy as measured by best overall response rate (BORR), 12-month and 24-month disease control rate (DCR), 12-month and-24 month progression free survival (PFS) rate and 12-month and 24-month overall survival (OS) rate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS) rate</measure>
    <time_frame>12~24 Months</time_frame>
    <description>• To evaluate the response to the combination therapy as measured by best overall response rate (BORR), 12-month and 24-month disease control rate (DCR), 12-month and-24 month progression free survival (PFS) rate and 12-month and 24-month overall survival (OS) rate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse event(AE)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 99 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>• To evaluate the safety of combination therapy of durvalumab and BVAC-C as measured by adverse events (AE), adverse events of special interest (AESI), vital signs, physical examination, safety laboratory tests, including change of lymphocyte subsets from baseline, plasma cytokine level</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events rate of special interest(AESI)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 99 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>• To evaluate the safety of combination therapy of durvalumab and BVAC-C as measured by adverse events (AE), adverse events of special interest (AESI), vital signs, physical examination, safety laboratory tests, including change of lymphocyte subsets from baseline, plasma cytokine level</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Programmed death-ligand 1(PD-L1)</measure>
    <time_frame>1-2 day</time_frame>
    <description>PD-L1 expression level</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Tumor mutational burden(TMB)</measure>
    <time_frame>1-2 day</time_frame>
    <description>TBM is a biomarker that can predict the response of PD-L1 to treatment.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of Tumor infiltrating lymphocytes(TIL)</measure>
    <time_frame>1-2 day</time_frame>
    <description>Cancers with a DNA repair gene deficiency repair (dMMR) mechanism undergo changes very frequently and accumulate mutations in monomorphic microsatellites (short tandem repeats). And is prone to mismatch errors.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Immune gene expression profile(RNA)</measure>
    <time_frame>1-2 day</time_frame>
    <description>We studied immune cell expression profiles for various cancer immune characteristics and confirmed significant differences in OS.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Serum cytokine level(multiplex cytokine assay)</measure>
    <time_frame>1-2 day</time_frame>
    <description>Immune cells secrete various cytokines that induce subsequent activation of the immune system. It is worth confirming that BVAC-C can increase blood cytokines.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>T cells (ELISPOT)</measure>
    <time_frame>1-2 day</time_frame>
    <description>ELISA (The enzyme-linked immunospot) can quantify the cell-mediated immune response with a sensitive technique that can detect cells that produce cytokines at the single cell level. This method of analysis allows for rapid, reproducible, and infrequent direct counting of antigen-specific T cells.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>HPV types</measure>
    <time_frame>1-2 day</time_frame>
    <description>Biopsy samples will be continuously evaluated to search for biomarkers other than immune profiles and gene signatures that can predict responsiveness to concomitant administration.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">37</enrollment>
  <condition>Cervical Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BVAC-C+Durvalumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>• Part A: The primary objective of the part A is to assess the maximum tolerable dose of BVAC-C combined with durvalumab 1500 mg as defined by dose-limiting toxicities (DLTs), and to find the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) that can be safely used for Part B (single arm phase II).&#xD;
• Part B: The primary objective of the part B is to evaluate the safety and clinical efficacy, as measured by 6-month PFS rate, of the combination therapy of durvalumab and BVAC-C in patients with HPV 16 or 18 positive cervical cancer recurrent after or refractory to first-line platinum-based chemotherapy +/-bevacizumab.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BAVC-C+Durvalumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Durvalumab Durvalumab will be supplied in glass vials containing 500 mg of liquid solution at a concentration of 50 mg/mL for infusion after dilution.&#xD;
BVAC-C BVAC-C will be supplied in cyclic olefin co-polymer vials containing 1x10⁸ cells of suspension at a concentration of 5x10⁷ cells/mL infusion</description>
    <arm_group_label>BVAC-C+Durvalumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capable of giving signed informed consent which includes compliance with the&#xD;
             requirements and restrictions listed in the informed consent form (ICF) and in this&#xD;
             protocol. Written informed consent and any locally required authorization obtained&#xD;
             from the patient/legal representative prior to performing any protocol-related&#xD;
             procedures, including screening evaluations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and ability to provide blood and tumor tissue samples&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed HPV 16/18-positive cervical carcinoma (squamous cell&#xD;
             carcinoma; adenocarcinoma, adenosquamous carcinoma)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior primary therapy with radical surgery, radical surgery followed by radiotherapy&#xD;
             (+/- chemo), chemotherapy, or primary concurrent chemoradiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cervical cancer recurrent after or refractory to only 1 prior first-line&#xD;
             platinum-based chemotherapy +/- bevacizumab.Measurable disease per Response Evaluation&#xD;
             Criteria in Solid Tumors, version 1.1 (RECIST v1.1)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status of 0-1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have a life expectancy of at least 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 18 years at time of study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight &gt;30 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate normal organ and marrow function as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Haemoglobin ≥9.0 g/dL (Note: The use of transfusion or other intervention to&#xD;
                  achieve Hgb ≥ 9.0 g/dl is acceptable)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt; 1.5x10³per mm³&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count ≥75x10⁹/L (≥75,000 per mm³)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum bilirubin ≤1.5 x institutional upper limit of normal (ULN). This will not&#xD;
                  apply to patients with confirmed Gilbert's syndrome, who will be allowed only in&#xD;
                  consultation with their physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST (SGOT)/ALT (SGPT) ≤2.5 x institutional upper limit of normal unless liver&#xD;
                  metastases are present, in which case it must be ≤5x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Measured creatinine clearance (CL) &gt;40 mL/min or Calculated creatinine CL&gt;40&#xD;
                  mL/min by the Cockcroft-Gault formula (Cockcroft and Gault 1976) or by 24-hour&#xD;
                  urine collection for determination of creatinine clearance:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If the patient is not in status post hysterectomy, women who are of child-bearing&#xD;
             potential willing to use effective methods of contraception including oral&#xD;
             contraceptives, intrauterine device, diaphragm with spermicides, and/or abstinence.&#xD;
             Women of childbearing potential who have a negative serum pregnancy test and must&#xD;
             agree to practice effective birth control throughout their participation in the&#xD;
             treatment phase of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of post-menopausal status or negative urinary or serum pregnancy test for&#xD;
             female pre-menopausal patients. Women will be considered post-menopausal if they have&#xD;
             been amenorrheic for 12 months without an alternative medical cause. The following&#xD;
             age-specific requirements apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women &lt;50 years of age would be considered post-menopausal if they have been&#xD;
                  amenorrheic for 12 months or more following cessation of exogenous hormonal&#xD;
                  treatments and if they have luteinizing hormone and follicle-stimulating hormone&#xD;
                  levels in the post-menopausal range for the institution or underwent surgical&#xD;
                  sterilization (bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women ≥50 years of age would be considered post-menopausal if they have been&#xD;
                  amenorrheic for 12 months or more following cessation of all exogenous hormonal&#xD;
                  treatments, had radiation-induced menopause with last menses &gt;1 year ago, had&#xD;
                  chemotherapy-induced menopause with last menses &gt;1 year ago, or underwent&#xD;
                  surgical sterilization (bilateral oophorectomy, bilateral salpingectomy or&#xD;
                  hysterectomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Status post hysterectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is willing and able to comply with the protocol for the duration of the study&#xD;
             including undergoing treatment and scheduled visits and examinations including follow&#xD;
             up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in another clinical study with an investigational product during the&#xD;
             last 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent enrollment in another clinical study, unless it is an observational&#xD;
             (non-interventional) clinical study or during the follow-up period of an&#xD;
             interventional study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of the last dose of anticancer therapy (chemotherapy, immunotherapy, endocrine&#xD;
             therapy, targeted therapy, biologic therapy, tumor embolization, monoclonal&#xD;
             antibodies) 4 weeks prior to the first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any unresolved toxicity NCI CTCAE Grade ≥2 from previous anticancer therapy with the&#xD;
             exception of alopecia, vitiligo, and the laboratory values defined in the inclusion&#xD;
             criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with Grade ≥2 neuropathy will be evaluated on a case-by-case basis after&#xD;
                  consultation with the Study Physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with irreversible toxicity not reasonably expected to be exacerbated by&#xD;
                  treatment with durvalumab may be included only after consultation with the Study&#xD;
                  Physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any concurrent chemotherapy, IP, biologic, or hormonal therapy for cancer treatment.&#xD;
             Concurrent use of hormonal therapy for non-cancer-related conditions (e.g., hormone&#xD;
             replacement therapy) is acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiotherapy treatment to more than 30% of the bone marrow or with a wide field of&#xD;
             radiation within 4 weeks of the first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgical procedure (as defined by the Investigator) within 28 days prior to the&#xD;
             first dose of IP. Note: Local surgery of isolated lesions for palliative intent is&#xD;
             acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allogenic organ transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active or prior documented autoimmune or inflammatory disorders (including&#xD;
             inflammatory bowel disease [e.g., colitis or Crohn's disease], diverticulitis [with&#xD;
             the exception of diverticulosis], systemic lupus erythematosus, Sarcoidosis syndrome,&#xD;
             or Wegener syndrome [granulomatosis with polyangiitis, Graves' disease, rheumatoid&#xD;
             arthritis, hypophysitis, uveitis, etc]). The following are exceptions to this&#xD;
             criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with vitiligo or alopecia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with hypothyroidism (e.g., following Hashimoto syndrome) stable on&#xD;
                  hormone replacement&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any chronic skin condition that does not require systemic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients without active disease in the last 5 years may be included but only&#xD;
                  after consultation with the study physician&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with celiac disease controlled by diet alone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness, including but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, uncontrolled hypertension, unstable&#xD;
             angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, interstitial lung disease, serious chronic&#xD;
             gastrointestinal conditions associated with diarrhea, or psychiatric illness/social&#xD;
             situations that would limit compliance with study requirement, substantially increase&#xD;
             risk of incurring AEs or compromise the ability of the patient to give written&#xD;
             informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of another primary malignancy except for&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Malignancy treated with curative intent and with no known active disease ≥5 years&#xD;
                  before the first dose of IP and of low potential risk for recurrence&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adequately treated non-melanoma skin cancer or lentigo maligna without evidence&#xD;
                  of disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adequately treated carcinoma in situ without evidence of disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of leptomeningeal carcinomatosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Brain metastases or spinal cord compression. Patients with suspected brain metastases&#xD;
             at screening should have an MRI (preferred) or CT each preferably with IV contrast of&#xD;
             the brain prior to study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other epithelial tumors (except for adenosquamous carcinoma) defined by WHO&#xD;
             histological classification (including neuroendocrine tumors and undifferentiated&#xD;
             carcinoma)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-epithelial cervical tumors defined by WHO histological classification: mesenchymal&#xD;
             tumors and tumor-like conditions; mixed epithelial and mesenchymal tumors; germ cell&#xD;
             tumors; lymphoid and myeloid tumors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of active primary immunodeficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection including tuberculosis (clinical evaluation that includes clinical&#xD;
             history, physical examination and radiographic findings, and TB testing in line with&#xD;
             local practice), hepatitis B (known positive HBV surface antigen (HBsAg) result),&#xD;
             hepatitis C. Patients with a past or resolved HBV infection (defined as the presence&#xD;
             of hepatitis B core antibody [anti-HBc] and absence of HBsAg) are eligible. Patients&#xD;
             positive for hepatitis C (HCV) antibody are eligible only if polymerase chain reaction&#xD;
             is negative for HCV RNA.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or prior use of immunosuppressive medication within 14 days before the first&#xD;
             dose of any investigational products (BVAC-C or durvalumab). The following are&#xD;
             exceptions to this criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intranasal, inhaled, topical steroids, or local steroid injections (e.g., intra&#xD;
                  articular injection)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Systemic corticosteroids at physiologic doses not to exceed 10 mg/day of&#xD;
                  prednisone or its equivalent&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Steroids as premedication for hypersensitivity reactions (e.g., CT scan&#xD;
                  premedication)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of live attenuated vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose of IP. Note:&#xD;
             Patients, if enrolled, should not receive live vaccine whilst receiving IP and up to&#xD;
             30 days after the last dose of IP.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding or male or female patients of&#xD;
             reproductive potential who are not willing to employ effective birth control from&#xD;
             screening to 90 days after the last dose of durvalumab monotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy or hypersensitivity to any of the study drugs or any of the study drug&#xD;
             excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior randomization or treatment in a previous durvalumab clinical study regardless of&#xD;
             treatment arm assignment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior therapy with any anti-PD-1 or anti-PD-L1 inhibitor including durvalumab&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recurrent/refractory cervical cancer amenable to curative local therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known severe ischemic heart disease, severe arrythmia and other clinically significant&#xD;
             cardiac disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Judgment by the investigator that the patient is unsuitable to participate in the&#xD;
             study and the patient is unlikely to comply with study procedures, restrictions and&#xD;
             requirements.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>ByoungGie Kim</last_name>
    <phone>+82-02-3410-3513</phone>
    <email>bgkim@skku.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>BVAC-C</keyword>
  <keyword>Durvalumab</keyword>
  <keyword>Cervical cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Durvalumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

