<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04803435</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>36793220300000071</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04803435</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Telemedicine and Face-to-face Consultations Diagnostic Accuracy Comparison in Gastrointestinal Infection Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Telemedicine Evaluation of Immunocompetent Adult Patients With Symptoms Suggestive of Acute Gastrointestinal Infection Compared With Face-to-face Medical Consultation in an Emergency Department: a Randomized Study of Diagnostic Accuracy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital Israelita Albert Einstein</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital Israelita Albert Einstein</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Acute gastroenterocolitis (GECA) in healthy adults is a frequent cause of looking for medical&#xD;
      care in emergency care units and most cases are aimed at etiology viral infection or food&#xD;
      toxin, being generally self-limited with good prognosis and only need for treatment with&#xD;
      behavioral measures and use of medications for relief symptomatic. Anamnesis is the main&#xD;
      resource for the diagnosis and stratification of GECA severity and is infrequent alterations&#xD;
      of physical examination and complementary examinations without association with symptoms of&#xD;
      alert. Telemedicine has become a resource that allows easier and faster access to medical&#xD;
      evaluation, with low cost and rational use of resources. Virtual emergency care is part of&#xD;
      Hospital Israelita Albert Einstein (HIAE) institutional routine and there is a large number&#xD;
      of consultations whose final diagnosis was GECA. It is not known whether the accuracy of&#xD;
      diagnosis of GECA by telemedicine is not inferior to the diagnosis by face-to-face&#xD;
      evaluation, considered the Golden pattern. The aim of the study is compare the diagnostic&#xD;
      accuracy of GECA by telemedicine with that of face-to-face care. It is a prospective&#xD;
      randomized study with a population of adult patients who sought in person the screening of&#xD;
      the Morumbi Emergency Care Unit of HIAE with symptoms suggestive of GECA (diarrhea with or&#xD;
      without other symptoms of the digestive tract and infectious). Patients whose screening will&#xD;
      be excluded of nursing directed for immediate evaluation in the emergency room and patients&#xD;
      with dysfunctions organisms or immunosuppression. Patients who accept and sign the informed&#xD;
      consent form will be randomized into 2 groups: A) immediate face-to-face evaluation; B)&#xD;
      evaluation initially by telemedicine and sequentially at face-to-face evaluation. In both&#xD;
      cases, the ICD diagnostics will be compiled and grouped according to clinical significance&#xD;
      and will be the primary outcome of the study. Service time, exams requested, guidelines,&#xD;
      prescription and destination will also be analyzed. Patients and doctors who undergoing group&#xD;
      B assessment will be blinded to the telemedicine assessment data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The face-to-face assessment will be carried out by the local UPA medical and assistance team&#xD;
      and the assessment by telemedicine by the fixed medical team of the HIAE service responsible&#xD;
      for urgency / emergency. Both in face-to-face evaluation, as well as telemedicine, clinical&#xD;
      data, final diagnosis, destination, total time of care, guidance and prescription will be&#xD;
      computed. In the face-to-face evaluation, complementary exams and medications received in&#xD;
      situ were computed. Final diagnoses will receive nomenclature according to the International&#xD;
      Statistical Classification of Diseases and Problems Health-Related - ICD 10 (institutional&#xD;
      medical record requirement - Cerner) and will be grouped according to equivalence of&#xD;
      syndromic diagnosis. The diagnosis of the face-to-face assessment is made according to&#xD;
      protocols based on extensive medical literature and approved by the institutional clinical&#xD;
      staff, being representative of current medical practice and will be considered the gold&#xD;
      standard diagnosis. Patients evaluated by telemedicine will be blinded to the diagnosis,&#xD;
      recommended destination, guidelines and prescription performed by the medical team. UPA&#xD;
      doctors will be blind to the doctor's assessment telemedicine and telemedicine doctors will&#xD;
      not have access to the data obtained in the screening.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of telemedicine diagnosis of adult patients with symptoms compatible with acute gastrointestinal infection</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The patient will be evaluated by telemedicine and / or face-to-face consultation and at the end will receive the diagnosis, which will be assigned the ICD code. At the end, these ICDs will be grouped by the same clinical significance and will be compared between the two consultation methods (telemedicine versus face-to-face consultation).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time of medical care</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of time (minutes) of medical care between telemedicine and face-to-face consultation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of indication for complementary exams</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of rate (porcentage) of indication for complementary exams between telemedicine and face-to-face consultation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Types of requested exams</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of types of requested exams (porcentage) between telemedicine and face-to-face consultation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Guidelines follow-up</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of guidelines follow-up (porcentage) between telemedicine and face-to-face consultation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Medical prescription</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of medical prescription after completion of the service between telemedicine and face-to-face consultation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proposed destination after completion of the service</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of proposed destination (percentage of discharge or hospitalization) after completion of the service between telemedicine and face-to-face consultation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Gastrointestinal Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Adult patients with acute gastrointestinal infection - telemedicine before face-to-face evaluation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adult patients who sought in person the screening of the Morumbi Emergency Care Unit of HIAE with symptoms suggestive of GECA (diarrhea with or without other symptoms of the digestive tract and infectious) who have undergone telemedicine consultation before face-to-face evaluation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Adult patients with acute gastrointestinal infection - only face-to-face evaluation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adult patients who sought in person the screening of the Morumbi Emergency Care Unit of HIAE with symptoms suggestive of GECA (diarrhea with or without other symptoms of the digestive tract and infectious) who have only face-to-face evaluation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Telemedicine Consultation</intervention_name>
    <description>Brief telemedicine consultation, blindedto subsequent face-to-face evaluation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Adult patients with acute gastrointestinal infection - telemedicine before face-to-face evaluation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Face-to-face Consultation</intervention_name>
    <description>Direct face-to-face evaluation (without telemedicine consultation before).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Adult patients with acute gastrointestinal infection - only face-to-face evaluation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Adult patients with acute gastrointestinal infection - telemedicine before face-to-face evaluation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age&gt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptoms present less than 7 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Without the use of antibiotics in last 30 days prior to the onset of symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No trips abroad in the last 15 days prior to the onset of symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of more than three episodes of watery diarrhea in the last 24 hours with or&#xD;
             without symptoms related to the infection (fever 38oC, chills, sweating, myalgia,&#xD;
             vomiting) that motivated / were looking for the Emergency Care Unit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signature of informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Return to the Emergency Care Unit due to maintenance or aggravation of the complaint&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age&gt; 65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of chronic gastrointestinal diseases, gastritis with or without&#xD;
             gastroesophageal reflux disease, previous diverticulitis, previous abdominal surgery,&#xD;
             chronic colitis, inflammatory bowel diseases, food intolerances (gluten, lactose)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous diagnosis of congestive heart failure, HIV / AIDS, active cancer, type I&#xD;
             diabetes mellitus, use of any immunosuppressant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diarrhea chronic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with emergency room criteria by the nursing evaluation of the triage.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eduardo HS Cordioli, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Telemedicine Department, Hospital Israelita Albert Einstein, Sao Paulo, Brazil</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tarso AD Accorsi, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+55 11 2151 2773</phone>
    <email>tarsoa@einstein.br</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diarrhea</keyword>
  <keyword>Telemedicine</keyword>
  <keyword>Emergency Medical Services</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

