<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04801719</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FNBKRNM0002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04801719</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Endoluminal Radiofrequency Ablation for the Treatment of Malignant Biliary Stenosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Endoluminal Radiofrequency Ablation of Tumors Affecting the Bile Ducts</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Brno University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Brno University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The rationale of the study is to explore the safety and efficacy of endoluminal&#xD;
      radiofrequency ablation prior metal stent insertion in patiens with malignant biliary&#xD;
      stenosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this randomized study was to analyze survival rate in patients with malignant&#xD;
      biliary obstruction treated with metal stent insertion with or without previous endoluminal&#xD;
      radiofrequency ablation (RFA). Secondary endpoint was to analyze metal stent patency rate and&#xD;
      survival rate in the subgroup of infiltrative hilar cholangiocarcinomas standardly treated by&#xD;
      brachytherapy and metal stenting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients underwent percutaneous cholangiography followed by transhepatic drainage, all&#xD;
      patients underwent histopathologic verification of the stenosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomised patients in selected arm received endoluminal RFA by 8F catheter (Habib™ EndoHPB;&#xD;
      EMcision Ltd., London, UK) before stenting procedure. Repeated ablations were processed&#xD;
      through stenotic areas (10W, 90-120s, Rita 1500, Angiodynamics Ltd), all drained biliary&#xD;
      tracts were used for introducing catheter and performance of ablation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In experimental group ablation procedure was followed with uncovered self-expandable metal&#xD;
      stent insertion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Brachytherapy procedure (performed in case of cholangiocarcinoma as institutional treatment&#xD;
      standard) was performed through 5F applicator by after loading system of iridium radiation&#xD;
      source (HDR brachytherapy, applicator temporarily placed into a drain for 3-4 days).&#xD;
      Prescribed dose was 15-24Gy at distance of 1.0cm in 3-4 fractions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analyzed characteristics:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific therapeutic procedures e.g. systemic chemotherapy, brachytherapy indicated by&#xD;
      multidisciplinary tumor board were recorded. Laboratory tests were evaluated withing 24 hours&#xD;
      before and after the RFA (AMS, INR, APTT, GMT, total bilirubin, ALP, ALT, AST). The time of&#xD;
      initial diagnosis, drainage procedures, ablation and stenting were referred to patient&#xD;
      survival. Patients underwent repeated ambulatory follow-up in 3months period (dedicated&#xD;
      ultrasound performed by interventional radiologist, in case of bilirubin and obstructive&#xD;
      enzymes elevation intensified follow up was performed). Patients time of death was gathered&#xD;
      from record of central database of insured persons or from hospital information system.&#xD;
      Procedural complications were graded in consensus by interventional radiologists and&#xD;
      oncologist according to Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary stent patency:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stent patency was defined as the duration from the insertion of the stent until the date of&#xD;
      closure. If the cause of death was directly related to stent failure, the date of death was&#xD;
      defined as time of stent closure. If no stent failure occurred (i.e. the absence of increased&#xD;
      total serum bilirubin levels or the absence of dilation of intrahepatic bile ducts on CT or&#xD;
      US examination even if total serum bilirubin level was increased), stent patency was&#xD;
      considered as censored at the date of death or at the end of the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analyses were performed using IBM SPSS Statistics 23 (IBM Corporation, Armonk, NY, USA).&#xD;
      Basic characteristics were summarized by absolute and relative frequencies and compared using&#xD;
      Fisher's exact test (categorical variables), continuous characteristics compared using the&#xD;
      Mann-Whitney test. Survival parameters were evaluated by Kaplan-Meier methodology,&#xD;
      differences in survival were evaluated by log-rank test. Relationships between survival&#xD;
      parameters and endoluminal biliary pathway ablation prior to stent insertion were modelled&#xD;
      using one-dimensional Cox regression models and described using a risk ratio (HR) of 95% CI&#xD;
      for HR and a p-value corresponding to the relevant regression coefficient. The level of&#xD;
      statistical significance in all analyses was set at α = 0.05.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 4, 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Two study arms with histologically proven malignant biliary stenosis treated either by endoluminal radiofrequency ablation with subsequent metal stent insertion or metal stent insertion only.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Stent patency</measure>
    <time_frame>up to month 36 or death of the patient</time_frame>
    <description>Analysis of metal stent patency since insertion in both study arms (measured in months, Kaplan-Meier estimate).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>up to month 36 or death of the patient</time_frame>
    <description>Analysis of overall survival since the diagnosis, initial drainage, and metal stent insertion in both study arms (measured in months, Kaplan-Meier estimate).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complications of endoluminal RFA of biliary tract</measure>
    <time_frame>up to day 30</time_frame>
    <description>Procedural complications were graded in consensus by interventional radiologists and oncologist according to Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events v4.0.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">76</enrollment>
  <condition>Radiofrequency Ablation</condition>
  <condition>Biliary Tract Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stent Complication</condition>
  <condition>Brachytherapy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental arm - endoluminal RFA</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>standard treatment protocol for malignant biliary stenosis + endoluminal RFA prior metal stent insertion</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>standard treatment protocol for malignant biliary stenosis which includes metal stent insertion</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Habib™ EndoHPB; Boston Scientific, US; former EMcision Ltd., UK</intervention_name>
    <description>Randomised patients in selected arm received endoluminal RFA by 8F catheter (Habib™ EndoHPB; Boston Scientific, US; former EMcision Ltd., UK) before stenting procedure. Repeated ablations were processed through stenotic areas of bile ducts (10W, 90-120s, Rita 1500, Angiodynamics Ltd), all drained biliary tracts were used for introducing catheter and performance of ablation. Ablation procedure was followed with uncovered self-expandable metal stent insertion.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental arm - endoluminal RFA</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  histologically verified malignant stenosis of bile ducts&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  indication of implantation of SEMS by multidisciplinary indication committee&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  life expectancy of less than 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky performance status of &lt;80%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history or concomitant treatment with intraarterial oncologic therapies (eg, hepatic&#xD;
             arterial infusion, chemoembolization)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ongoing infections resistant to antibiotic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  clinical or biochemical signs of liver or renal failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  INR ≥ 1.3, serum albumin ≤ 35 g/l, haemoglobin ≤ 100 g/l, serum creatinine ≥ 200μmol/l&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tomáš Andrašina, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Brno University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brno University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brno</city>
        <zip>62500</zip>
        <country>Czechia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Czechia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Brno University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Tomas Andrasina</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Tomáš Andrašina, MD, PhD; Assistant professor, Head of Non-vascular interventions and Computed Tomography of the Department of Radiology and Nuclear Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Biliary Tract Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

