<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04802122</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>INTUSEVO</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04802122</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Induction of Anesthesia With Sevoflurane Preserving Spontaneous Breathing: Cardiorespiratory Effects.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparative Assessment of Intubating Conditions and Cardiorespiratory Effects of Sevoflurane Induction and Intubation.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Aristotle University Of Thessaloniki</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Aristotle University Of Thessaloniki</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Airway management is of outmost importance in the perioperative period. One of the main&#xD;
      questions while making a plan for airway management is whether spontaneous ventilation should&#xD;
      be maintained or not. Induction of anesthesia with Sevoflurane is a conventional technique&#xD;
      that preserves spontaneous ventilation. It is used especially in non-collaborating patients&#xD;
      or when other pharmaceutical agents or sophisticated airway management equipment is out of&#xD;
      reach.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inhalational induction of anesthesia with Sevoflurane is well studied. However, there are few&#xD;
      studies investigating the effects of Sevoflurane on induction and intubating conditions, on&#xD;
      cardiopulmonary physiology, on emergence conditions, when it is used as one and only agent to&#xD;
      achieve induction of anesthesia, intubation and maintenance of anesthesia in adult patients.&#xD;
      There is also no consensus on the appropriate duration of the inhalational induction or other&#xD;
      criteria to guarantee successful intubation conditions, since most studies investigate&#xD;
      Sevoflurane administration until induction of anesthesia and not until intubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      From all the above, it appears that there are a few gaps in the management of patients who&#xD;
      are to be intubated with Sevoflurane only, without the use of any other anesthetic agents.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Preoperatively, the study protocol-mandated baseline data will be recorded: gender, age, body&#xD;
      weight, body mass index, body surface area, ASA-PS, type of surgery. The airway assessment&#xD;
      will include Mallampati score, thyromental distance, cervical spine mobility, upper lip bite&#xD;
      test, mouth opening, micrognathia, protruding incisors, beard, denture, snoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be randomly allocated into one of two groups: the S group was to be intubated&#xD;
      after inhalational anesthesia with Sevoflurane only and maintenance of anesthesia with&#xD;
      Sevoflurane 1MAC. The P group will receive standard anesthesia induction with propofol&#xD;
      1,5mg/Kg, fentanyl 2mcg/Kg, rocuronium 0,5mg/Kg, while anesthesia will be maintained by&#xD;
      sevoflurane.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before induction of anesthesia, we will record baseline data including BIS, SpO2, heart rate,&#xD;
      invasive blood pressure, cardiac output, stroke volume, stroke volume variation, respiratory&#xD;
      rate, and arterial blood gas sample recordings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During induction of anesthesia, the following data will be recorded: BIS, SpO2, heart rate,&#xD;
      invasive blood pressure, cardiac output, stroke volume, stroke volume variation, respiratory&#xD;
      rate, recordings from arterial blood gas sample, induction to anesthesia conditions (limb&#xD;
      movement, cough, salivation, laryngospasm, and apnea), respiratory rate, tidal volume, minute&#xD;
      volume, end-tidal CO2, the concentration of sevoflurane (inhaled, exhaled), peak inspiratory&#xD;
      pressure, mean inspiratory pressure, dynamic respiratory compliance. In the S group, these&#xD;
      data will be recorded again five minutes after the induction to anesthesia commencement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During intubation, we will record BIS, SpO2, heart rate, blood pressure, cardiac output,&#xD;
      stroke volume, stroke volume variation, intubating conditions (jaw relaxation, vocal cord&#xD;
      position, vocal cord movement, limb movement, bucking), Cormack-Lehane grade, duration of&#xD;
      intubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After intubation we will register: BIS, SpO2, heart rate, invasive blood pressure, cardiac&#xD;
      output, stroke volume, stroke volume variation, respiratory rate, recordings from arterial&#xD;
      blood gas sample, respiratory rate, tidal volume, minute volume, end-tidal CO2, the&#xD;
      concentration of sevoflurane (inhaled, exhaled), peak inspiratory pressure, mean inspiratory&#xD;
      pressure, dynamic respiratory compliance, were recorded. Patients having abolished&#xD;
      spontaneous breathing will be set on the IMV mode of ventilation receiving tidal volume&#xD;
      8ml/Kg, 10 breaths/min, PEEP=5cmH2O, I: E=1:2, Plateau time 30%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Upon the end of the surgical stimuli the following parameters will be registered: BIS, blood&#xD;
      pressure, heart rate, SpO2, stroke volume, stroke volume variation, cardiac output, etCO2,&#xD;
      respiratory rate, sevoflurane concentration (exhaled, inhaled), peak inspiratory pressure,&#xD;
      mean inspiratory pressure, dynamic compliance, time of establishing spontaneous breathing,&#xD;
      time of extubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      BIS, blood pressure, heart rate, SpO2, stroke volume, stroke volume variation, cardiac&#xD;
      output, etCO2, the respiratory rate will be recorded 5 and 10 minutes respectively&#xD;
      post-extubation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 14, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 13, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intubating conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>10 minutes after induction to anesthesia commencement with sevoflurane or 5 minutes after induction to anesthesia with propofol plus fentanyl and muscle relaxant</time_frame>
    <description>Modification of intubating conditions assessed by Cormack-Lehane classification system after induction to anesthesia with sevoflurane (without muscle relaxants) or standard induction to anesthesia involving propofol supplemented by fentanyl and muscle relaxant.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiac output compromise</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 10 minutes after induction to anesthesia commencement with sevoflurane or 5 minutes after induction to anesthesia with propofol plus fentanyl and muscle relaxant</time_frame>
    <description>Cardiac index reduction defined CI &lt; 2.2 L/min/m2 after induction to anesthesia with sevoflurane (without muscle relaxants) or standard induction to anesthesia involving propofol supplemented by fentanyl and muscle relaxant.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hypercapnia</measure>
    <time_frame>1 minute after intubation</time_frame>
    <description>The occurrence of hypercapnia defined as carbon dioxide partial pressure &gt; 45 mmHg in arterial blood gas sample after induction to anesthesia with sevoflurane (without muscle relaxants) or standard induction to anesthesia involving propofol supplemented by fentanyl and muscle relaxant.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hypotension</measure>
    <time_frame>Within10 minutes after induction to anesthesia commencement with sevoflurane or 5 minutes after induction to anesthesia with propofol plus fentanyl and muscle relaxant</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of hypotension defined as systemic arterial pressure &lt; 90mmHg after induction to anesthesia with sevoflurane (without muscle relaxants) or standard induction to anesthesia involving propofol supplemented by fentanyl and muscle relaxant.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Anesthesia Intubation Complication</condition>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Complication</condition>
  <condition>Intubation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sevoflurane group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in this group will receive Sevoflurane 8% / O2 100% with the vital capacity breathing method (vital capacity induction, VCI) for induction to anesthesia and to facilitate endotracheal intubation (without the use of muscle relaxant) and thereafter Sevoflurane 1 MAC will be used for maintenance of anesthesia plus muscle relaxant until study completion.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Propofol group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in this group will receive a standard anesthesia induction involving Propofol 1,5mg/Kg, supplemented by fentanyl 2mcg/Kg and rocuronium 0,5mg/Kg and O2 100% for induction to anesthesia and to facilitate endotracheal intubation and thereafter Sevoflurane 1 MAC will be used for maintenance of anesthesia.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sevoflurane inhalant product</intervention_name>
    <description>Sevoflurane 8% / O2 100% with the vital capacity breathing method (vital capacity induction, VCI) will be used for induction to anesthesia and facilitate endotracheal intubation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sevoflurane group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Sevoflurane</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Propofol Fresenius</intervention_name>
    <description>Propofol 1,5mg/Kg, supplemented by fentanyl 2mcg/Kg and rocuronium 0,5mg/Kg and O2 100% will be for induction to anesthesia and facilitate endotracheal intubation. .</description>
    <arm_group_label>Propofol group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Propofol</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;18 and &lt; 71 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA-PS 1-3 (American Society of Anesthesiologists Physical Status classification)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  General anesthesia for abdominal surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Elective cases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Urgent/emergency surgeries&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI&lt;18.5 or BMI&gt;34.9&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intraabdominal hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gastroesophageal reflex&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Liver or renal failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  intracranial hypertension&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Vasilios Grosomanidis</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Aristotle University Of Thessaloniki</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AHEPA University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Thessaloniki</city>
        <zip>54636</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Aristotle University Of Thessaloniki</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Georgia Tsaousi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>inhalational</keyword>
  <keyword>sevoflurane</keyword>
  <keyword>cardiovascular</keyword>
  <keyword>induction</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Propofol</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sevoflurane</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

