<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04807738</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1983/21+4772/21 (G-21-02)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04807738</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Virtual Reality in Physical Therapy in Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
  <acronym>VIREMS</acronym>
  <official_title>Effect of Neuroproprioceptive &quot;Facilitation, Inhibition&quot; Physical Therapy Using Virtual Reality on Upper Limb Mobility and Postural Stability in Multiple Sclerosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Charles University, Czech Republic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Charles University, Czech Republic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The randomized controlled trial is aimed to study the efficacy of virtual reality (VR) and&#xD;
      its impact on upper limb function and postural stability in people with mild to severe&#xD;
      multiple sclerosis (pwMS). The conceptual idea is to compare two kinds of neuroproprioceptive&#xD;
      &quot;facilitation and inhibition&quot; physical therapy, first in a real environment and second in&#xD;
      virtual reality, in out-patient therapy that will be held in 15 hourly therapies, 2x a week&#xD;
      in a period of two months. The efficacy will be assessed by a blinded independent clinical&#xD;
      examiner using clinical examination and questionnaire survey before and in a week following&#xD;
      the therapeutic intervention. The main focus is on upper limb gross and fine motor skills,&#xD;
      trunk stability and stability, and sit to stand stability.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In 60 - 75% of people with multiple sclerosis (MS) an upper limb mobility dysfunction&#xD;
      (unilateral or bilateral manual dexterity, sensibility impairment, tremor) is present,&#xD;
      resulting in reduced participation in activities of daily living.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physiotherapy has a crucial impact on upper limb mobility, although there are many approaches&#xD;
      applied (exercise/strengthening exercise, endurance training, sensory training,&#xD;
      constraint-induced movement therapy, robotic rehabilitation therapy, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Virtual reality is an innovative technological concept using game mechanisms that facilitate&#xD;
      concentration and motivation in task performance. Current research implies that VR is a safe&#xD;
      and effective method in gait and balance//stability rehabilitation therapy and with less&#xD;
      evidence, for upper limb mobility improvement. It is expected that a greater therapeutic&#xD;
      effect is a result of multifactorial sense stimulation and dopamine centres in the brain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A pilot project showed that virtual reality without the prompt feedback of a physiotherapist&#xD;
      is not more effective than standard therapy. A new therapeutic software using virtual reality&#xD;
      spontaneously motivating the patient for movement realization was developed in cooperation&#xD;
      with the Department of informatics and computer science Faculty of applied sciences&#xD;
      University West Bohemia. Accurate execution of neuroproprioceptive &quot;facilitation and&#xD;
      inhibition techniques&quot; physical therapy combining key principles from proprioceptive&#xD;
      neuromuscular stabilization (PNS) and motor program activating therapy (MPAT), ensures a&#xD;
      present physiotherapist. These principles have shown the effect in therapy in pwMS.&#xD;
      Participants will be randomized into two arms of the study, both implementing&#xD;
      neuroproprioceptive &quot;facilitation and inhibition&quot; physical therapy, first in a real&#xD;
      environment and second in VR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators expect that VR intervention shall improve upper limb motor functions, trunk&#xD;
      muscles coordination, improve the performance of activities of daily living and quality of&#xD;
      life in pwMS more than identical therapy not using VR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The effect of both interventions will be assessed using validated tests for clinical&#xD;
      examination- Five times Sit to Stand test (5STS), Nine Hole Peg Test (9HPT), Hand Grip&#xD;
      Strength (HGS), Box and Block Test (BNB), accelerometer for tremor examination. Validated&#xD;
      questionnaires will be used, specifically the Multiple Sclerosis Impact Scale (MSIS-29),&#xD;
      EQ-5D-3L health questionnaire, Visual Analogue Scale, and a questionnaire dealing with&#xD;
      individual virtual reality intervention evaluation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A randomized controlled trial. 110 outpatients will be randomized into two interventional groups, one with face-to-face individual neuroproprioceptive &quot;facilitation and inhibition&quot; physical therapy combining key principles of proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation (PNF) and motor program activating therapy (MPAT). The second arm will place the same therapy, but virtual reality environment. Participants of both groups - active comparator and virtual reality interventional group will undergo 15 hourly therapies, twice a week in a time range of two months. Before and in a week following the last therapy, all participants will be examined by a blinded independent clinician.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>All participants of the study will undergo a clinical examination including a questionnaire survey, led by a blinded independent examiner, who will not have access to intervention documentation. The examiner will see each patient twice, before the first intervention and in follow-up examination in a week following the last therapy. The examiner will be prohibited to talk about the therapy attended. The patients will be informed about the character of the examination and the importance of the most objectivity possible. All therapists can apply both interventions, therefore masking is more efficient.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Nine Hole Peg Test (9HPT) - change pre/post intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-assessment (baseline testing), Post-assessment (immediately in a week following the last procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>The NHPT requires participants to repeatedly place and then remove nine pegs into nine holes, one at a time, as quickly as possible. Lower number (quicker time) means better result.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Box and Block Test (BNB) - change pre/post intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-assessment (baseline testing), Post-assessment (immediately in a week following the last procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>The Box and Block Test tests gross manual dexterity. This test consists of moving, one by one, the maximum number of blocks from one compartment of a box to another of equal size, originally, within 60 seconds. A lower number (quicker time) means better result.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Five times Sit to Stand test (5STS) -change pre/post intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-assessment (baseline testing), Post-assessment (immediately in a week following the last procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>The test assesses time when people stand and sit repeatedly five times. The lower the time to complete the test the better the outcome of the test.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hand Grip Strength (HGS) -change pre/post intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-assessment (baseline testing), Post-assessment (immediately in a week following the last procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Jamar Hydraulic Hand Dynamometer measures isometric grip force and strength. The higher value, the better function (higher strength).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency for which the smoothed power spectral density is maximal (fMAX)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-assessment (baseline testing), Post-assessment (immediately in a week following the last procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>The spectral characteristic of postural tremor measured by the 3-axis accelerometer and 3-axis gyroscope chip (Motion Tracking sensor MPU-6050) - lower value, lower tremor.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Power of the signal in band from f1 to f2 (Pf1-f2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-assessment (baseline testing), Post-assessment (immediately in a week following the last procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>The spectral characteristic of postural tremor measured by the 3-axis accelerometer and 3-axis gyroscope chip (Motion Tracking sensor MPU-6050) - lower value, lower tremor.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Multiple Sclerosis Impact Scale (MSIS-29) - change pre/post intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-assessment (baseline testing), Post-assessment (immediately in a week following the last procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>A 29-item self-report measure with 20 items associated with a physical scale and 9 items with a psychological scale. Items ask about the impact of MS on a day-to-day life in the past two weeks. All items have 5 response options: 1 &quot;not at all&quot; to 5&quot; extremely&quot;. Each of the two scales is scored by summing the responses across items, then converting to a 0-100 scale where 100 indicates the greater impact of the disease on daily function (worse health).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EQ-5D-3L-health questionnaire - change pre/post intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-assessment (baseline testing), Post-assessment (immediately in a week following the last procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Descriptive system for health-related quality of life states in adults, consisting of five dimensions (Mobility, Self-care, Usual activities, Pain &amp; discomfort, Anxiety &amp; depression), each of which has three severity levels that are described by statements appropriate to that dimension. A higher number means a worse quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">110</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Neuroproprioceptive &quot;facilitation and inhibition&quot;</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>ARM 1 - Neuroproprioceptive &quot;facilitation and inhibition&quot; physical therapy combining key principles of proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation (PNF) and motor program activating therapy (MPAT), with former positive probative evidence on MS and are recommended for MS intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Neuroproprioceptive &quot;facilitation and inhibition&quot; in virtual reality</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>ARM 2. Experimental group, neuroproprioceptive &quot;facilitation and inhibition&quot; physical therapy combining key principles of proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation (PNF) and motor program activating therapy (MPAT) through virtual reality and software inducing and motivating for movement according to principles of proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation (PNF) and motor program activating therapy (MPAT). We believe that the VR environment might lead to better results due to greater motivation effect, novelty effect, entertainment effect, as well as activating the reward system. We believe the VR might enhance the activation of mirror neurons, it might also activate proprioception. The present physiotherapist is to ensure proper execution of the tasks. The correlation of the two arms of the study should indicate, whether virtual reality and the software used are as effective, or more effective in sustaining the hand motor function and axial stability, than traditionally led therapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Neuroproprioceptive &quot;facilitation and inhibition&quot; in virtual reality</intervention_name>
    <description>The 110 outpatients will be randomized into groups: First arm, individual neuroproprioceptive &quot;facilitation and inhibition&quot; physical therapy combining key principles of proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation (PNF) and motor program activating therapy (MPAT) in a real environment and the second arm, the same therapy in virtual reality environment. All participants will undergo 15 sessions, 60 minutes each, twice a week in a period of two months.&#xD;
The therapy in a second, interventional group, uses virtual reality and new software that was developed specifically for inducing and motivating for movement according to principles of proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation (PNF) and motor program activating therapy (MPAT). The software allows immediate feedback and moreover, movement is corrected by a present therapist. Evaluation of speed and performance quality might be extracted from the software of virtual reality.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Neuroproprioceptive &quot;facilitation and inhibition&quot; in virtual reality</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Neuroproprioceptive &quot;facilitation and inhibition&quot;</intervention_name>
    <description>The first arm of the study will consist of a physiotherapeutic approach based on neurophysiological principles using proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation (PNF) and motor program activating therapy (MPAT) approaches. MPAT makes use of particular motor patterns that evolve in postural control development. The repetition of activated programs, a set of stimuli, applied to change the posture with anatomical centration of the joint under various conditions in leading to better support of postural stabilization while seated, while getting up, stepping forward, and standing, in order to teach the patients to use the acquired motor skills automatically in daily life. PNF is a method used for learning effective movement patterns with high biomechanical effectiveness based on repetitive stimulation of cooperating alfa-motoneurons and proprioceptors in muscle, tendons and joint capsules. Therapy will be individualized and led in the standard face-to-face regiment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Neuroproprioceptive &quot;facilitation and inhibition&quot;</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The inclusion criteria comprise of a definite diagnosis of multiple sclerosis, EDSS&#xD;
             score ≥ 2 a ≤ 7 ((10); determined by neurologist), no history of relapse, no history&#xD;
             of change in disease-modifying treatment, no history of corticosteroid therapy in the&#xD;
             past three months prior to recruitment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The exclusion criteria include other factors influencing mobility (history of stroke,&#xD;
             pregnancy, traumatic injury of limb/s. Severe cardiovascular or orthopedic&#xD;
             dysfunction, impaired cognitive functions in the course of examination and/or&#xD;
             consecutive therapy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kamila Rasova, as.prof.Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Clinic of rheumatology and rehabilitation,Third medical faculty CU and Faculty Thomayer Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Barbora Miznerova, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>+420776480210</phone>
    <email>blahutovabarbora@seznam.cz</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kamila Rasova, as.prof.Dr.</last_name>
    <phone>+420604511416</phone>
    <email>kamila.rasova@lf3.cuni.cz</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of neurology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Prague</city>
        <zip>100 00</zip>
        <country>Czechia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ivana Stetkarova, prof MD PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+420197170</phone>
      <email>ivana.stetkarova@fnkv.cz</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Deparment of revmatology and rehabilitation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Prague</city>
        <zip>140 59</zip>
        <country>Czechia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tom Philipp, M.D., Ph.D.</last_name>
      <phone>+420737273589</phone>
      <email>tom.philipp@ftn.cz</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Czechia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Charles University, Czech Republic</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kamila Řasová</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>assoc. prof. PhDr.Kamila Řasová, Ph.D.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>multiple sclerosis</keyword>
  <keyword>virtual reality</keyword>
  <keyword>hand dexterity</keyword>
  <keyword>postural stability</keyword>
  <keyword>physical therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>coordination</keyword>
  <keyword>upper limb fine motor skills</keyword>
  <keyword>motor programme activating therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>neuroproprioceptive &quot;facilitation, inhibition&quot;</keyword>
  <keyword>postural control</keyword>
  <keyword>functional recovery</keyword>
  <keyword>Demyelinating Autoimmune Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Autoimmune Diseases of the Nervous System</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All data sharing terms and conditions and the nature of the relationship between the study and new user will be contained in a Data-sharing Agreement that will be issued and sighed before any data are handed out. The de-identification process for each patient is to ensure anonymization of individual patient's data, in order to be able to share IPD within the terms of participant's consent and ethics committee approval.&#xD;
The study policy on sharing defines the terms of privileged use by the study team. The research team requires to be appropriately notified and acknowledged in publications and other outputs of the transferred data (or analyses conducted by the study on the new users' behalf). The Data-sharing agreement will comprehend arrangements for data destruction or secure archiving.&#xD;
It is planned that the data will be placed into an online repository (to be specified later).</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The IPD will be made available from 3-months months following the first publication of findings based on the data until 3 years following the first publication.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>The datasets will be prepared and might be reachable on a request. The study team formally reviews access requests for proposals. The data on an exclusive basis will be made available for third party use/ the new user, which can range from direct provision of data, data analysis collaboration, and/or scientific collaboration. Also, the requester is to state the purpose for which the data are to be used.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

