<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04803474</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NL65814.078.18</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04803474</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Turner And Klinefelter Treatment Target Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>TAKTT</acronym>
  <official_title>Turner And Klinefelter Treatment Target Study. Improving Endocrine Treatment by Linking Biochemical Parameters to Morbidity and Quality of Life in Patients With Turner and Klinefelter Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>dr. Laura C. G. de Graaff-Herder</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Erasmus Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Rationale: Health related Quality of life (HRQoL) is impaired in patients with Turner and&#xD;
      Klinefelter syndrome (TS and KS). It is unknown what the optimal endocrine treatment target&#xD;
      values are that maximize HRQoL in patients with these syndromes. Therefore the relation&#xD;
      between HRQoL and biochemical parameters will be studied in large cohorts of patients with TS&#xD;
      and KS. This information will give essential insight that will help to improve endocrine&#xD;
      treatment and HRQoL in these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research objectives: To explore the relationship between biochemical parameters and HRQoL in&#xD;
      patients with TS and KS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: Biochemical parameters are related to HRQoL in patients with TS and KS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: Cross-sectional, observational, multicentre study Study population: Patients&#xD;
      with KS or TS, 18 years or older Methods and procedures: To measure fatigue the Checklist&#xD;
      Individual Strength (CIS-20) will be used, for QoL the 5-level EQ-5D (EQ-5D-L5) will be used&#xD;
      and for stress the Perceived Stress Scale (PSS) and hair cortisol levels. For patients with&#xD;
      KS the anxiety scale from the Liebowitz social anxiety scale (LSAS) will be used to measure&#xD;
      social anxiety. To measure the long-term exposure to testosterone in KS patients,&#xD;
      testosterone concentrations in hair will be measured. For patients with KS, all questions&#xD;
      from the questionnaires will be discussed orally during a visit to the outpatients clinic.&#xD;
      One extra tube of blood and a strand of hair will be collected during routine blood&#xD;
      withdrawal. All other variables are already part of the standard patient care and are&#xD;
      available in patient records. For patients with TS all information including the&#xD;
      questionnaires and laboratory values is already available and will be collected from clinical&#xD;
      records.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main study parameters/endpoints: The relationship between different hormonal parameters and&#xD;
      HRQoL as measured by questionnaires. The main hormonal parameter that will be investigated in&#xD;
      KS is testosterone in hair. For patients with Turner syndrome, free thyroxine (FT4), thyroid&#xD;
      stimulating hormone (TSH) and liver enzymes, which have already been collected, will be&#xD;
      investigated. The relationships between the EQ-5D-L5 score and testosterone in hair (in&#xD;
      patients with KS) and thyroid hormone status (in patients with TS) are the primary outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Rationale: Health related Quality of life (HRQoL) is impaired in patients with Turner and&#xD;
      Klinefelter syndrome (TS and KS). It is unknown what the optimal endocrine treatment target&#xD;
      values are that maximize HRQoL in patients with these syndromes. Therefore the relation&#xD;
      between HRQoL and biochemical parameters will be studied in large cohorts of patients with TS&#xD;
      and KS. This information will give essential insight that will help to improve endocrine&#xD;
      treatment and HRQoL in these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research objectives: To explore the relationship between biochemical parameters and HRQoL in&#xD;
      patients with TS and KS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: Biochemical parameters are related to HRQoL in patients with TS and KS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: Cross-sectional, observational, multicentre study&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population: Patients with KS or TS, 18 years or older Methods and procedures: To&#xD;
      measure fatigue the Checklist Individual Strength (CIS-20) will be used, for QoL the 5-level&#xD;
      EQ-5D (EQ-5D-L5) will be used and for stress the Perceived Stress Scale (PSS) and hair&#xD;
      cortisol levels. For patients with KS the anxiety scale from the Liebowitz social anxiety&#xD;
      scale (LSAS) will be used to measure social anxiety. To measure the long-term exposure to&#xD;
      testosterone in KS patients, testosterone concentrations in hair will be measured. For&#xD;
      patients with KS, all questions from the questionnaires will be discussed orally during a&#xD;
      visit to the outpatients clinic. One extra tube of blood and a strand of hair will be&#xD;
      collected during routine blood withdrawal. All other variables are already part of the&#xD;
      standard patient care and are available in patient records. For patients with TS all&#xD;
      information including the questionnaires and laboratory values is already available and will&#xD;
      be collected from clinical records.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main study parameters/endpoints: The relationship between different hormonal parameters and&#xD;
      HRQoL as measured by questionnaires. The main hormonal parameter that will be investigated in&#xD;
      KS is testosterone in hair. For patients with Turner syndrome, free thyroxine (FT4), thyroid&#xD;
      stimulating hormone (TSH) and liver enzymes, which have already been collected, will be&#xD;
      investigated. The relationships between the EQ-5D-L5 score and testosterone in hair (in&#xD;
      patients with KS) and thyroid hormone status (in patients with TS) are the primary outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To explore the relationship between thyroid hormone status* and QoL as measured by the&#xD;
      EQ-5D-5L in patients with TS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To explore the relationship between testosterone concentrations in hair and QoL as measured&#xD;
      by the EQ-5D-5L in patients with KS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objective(s):&#xD;
&#xD;
      For TS:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The relationship between thyroid hormone status* and the CIS-20 and PSS scores. The&#xD;
      relationship between liver enzymes** and the EQ-5D-5L, CIS-20 and PSS scores.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The relationship between hair cortisol levels and the EQ-5D-5L, CIS-20 and PSS scores.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For KS:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The relationship between testosterone concentrations in hair and the CIS-20, LSAS and PSS&#xD;
      scores.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The relationship between hair cortisol levels and the EQ-5D-5L, CIS-20, LSAS and PSS scores.&#xD;
&#xD;
      *Variable that consists of the following 6 categories:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Overt hyperthyroidism (FT4&gt;25pmol/L and TSH&lt;0,4mU/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Overt hypothyroidism (FT4 &lt;11 pmol/L and TSH &gt;4,3 mU/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Subclinical hypothyroidism with TSH &lt;10mU/L (FT4 11-25 pmol/L and TSH 4,3-10mU/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Subclinical hypothyroidism with TSH &gt;10mU/L (FT4 11-25 pmol/L and TSH &gt; 10mU/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Subclinical hyperthyroidism (FT4 11-25 pmol/L and TSH &lt;0,4 mU/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Euthyroidism (FT4 11-25 pmol/L and TSH 0,4- 4,3 mU/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  aspartate aminotransferase (ASAT), alanine aminotransferase (ALAT), alkaline&#xD;
                phosphatase (ALP), gamma-glutamyl transpeptidase (GGT), bilirubin, lactate&#xD;
                dehydrogenase (LDH)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      2. STUDY DESIGN This is study is a multicentre cross-sectional cohort study with the Erasmus&#xD;
      Medical Centre (EMC), the VU University Medical Centre (VUmc) and the Amsterdam Medical&#xD;
      Centre (AMC) as contributing centres. The duration of the study is 26 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following data will be collected: laboratory values, fatigue scores, HRQoL scores,&#xD;
      stress-scores, date of birth, age at diagnosis, height, weight, use of medication, genetic&#xD;
      background, comorbidities. All information is already available in clinical records for&#xD;
      patients with TS. For patients with KS information on HRQoL, fatigue and stress scores needs&#xD;
      to be collected. A strand of hair to measure long-term testosterone and cortisol levels in&#xD;
      hair and an extra tube of blood for storage will also be collected. This tube of blood could&#xD;
      later be used to determine CAGn polymorphism in the androgen receptor, see paragraph below.&#xD;
      Patients with KS visit an endocrinologist at the outpatients clinic of the AMC, VUmc or the&#xD;
      EMC every one or two years and will be asked all questions of the questionnaires right after&#xD;
      their appointment with the endocrinologist. The executive researcher will be present at the&#xD;
      outpatients clinic to obtain informed consent and ask all questions. All laboratory values&#xD;
      needed are routinely assessed at every visit for standard patient care and will be collected&#xD;
      from clinical records afterwards.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.1 Laboratory values&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laboratory outcomes:&#xD;
&#xD;
      For KS: luteinizing hormone (LH), follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH), testosterone in blood&#xD;
      and testosterone and cortisol levels in hair.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For TS: thyroid stimulating hormone (TSH), free T4 (fT4) and liver enzymes: aspartate&#xD;
      aminotransferase (ASAT), alanine aminotransferase (ALAT), alkaline phosphatase (ALP),&#xD;
      gamma-glutamyl transpeptidase (GGT), bilirubin, lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) and cortisol&#xD;
      levels in hair.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.2 Genotype The classic form of KS, which is present in the 80-90 % of the cases, is defined&#xD;
      by a 47,XXY karyotype. Higher-grade aneuploidies (e.g. 48,XXXY or 48,XXYY), structurally&#xD;
      abnormal X chromosome (e.g. 47,iXq,Y) or mosaicisms (e.g. 47,XXY/46,XY) make up the remaining&#xD;
      10-20 % of cases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The most common genetic background in TS patients is a 45,X karyotype, which is present in&#xD;
      approximately 60% of TS patients. Around 20% of cases of TS are caused by a mosaicism&#xD;
      45X/46,XX and structural abnormalities chromosome X explain the last 20%. (26) As genetic&#xD;
      background influences phenotype, information on karyotype from clinical records will be&#xD;
      collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.3 Questionnaires Checklist Individual Strength (CIS-20) To measure fatigue the Checklist&#xD;
      Individual Strength (CIS-20) will be used. The CIS-20 consists of 20 questions that measure&#xD;
      the amount of fatigue experienced by the subject during the last two weeks. The subject has&#xD;
      to indicate on a 7 point Likertscale to what extent each statement applies to him or her. The&#xD;
      CIS-20 consists of 4 subscales: subjective fatigue (8 questions), concentration (5&#xD;
      questions), motivation (4 questions) and activity (3 questions). The CIS-20 questionnaire has&#xD;
      been validated in several populations and has proven to be a valid and reliable questionnaire&#xD;
      for the assessment of fatigue. Utilization of the CIS-20 questionnaire is free, as long a&#xD;
      reference to two articles is included in the publication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5-level EQ-5D (EQ-5D-L5) To assess HRQoL the EQ-5D-L5 questionnaire will be used. This&#xD;
      questionnaire consists of two components: the EQ-5D descriptive system and the EQ visual&#xD;
      analogue scale (EQ VAS). In the descriptive system the patient is asked to rate how many&#xD;
      problems he or she experiences in the following five dimensions: mobility, self-care, usual&#xD;
      activities, pain/discomfort and anxiety/depression. The scores for these five dimensions can&#xD;
      be combined to get a number that describes the health state of the respondent. The EQ VAS is&#xD;
      also a measure of health outcome. The patient is asked to indicate on a visual analogue scale&#xD;
      how good he or she thinks his or her health is. References values for the Dutch general&#xD;
      population are available.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Perceived Stress Scale (PSS) To measure stress the PSS questionnaire will be used. The PSS&#xD;
      consists of 10 questions that measure the degree of stress experienced by a subject after or&#xD;
      during certain events during the preceding month. The PSS has proven to be a valid measure&#xD;
      for perceived stress with good psychometric properties.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Liebowitz social anxiety scale (LSAS) To measure social anxiety in patients with Klinefelter&#xD;
      syndrome, the LSAS will be used. The LSAS is widely used to measure social anxiety. It&#xD;
      consists of two subscales: the scale for anxiety and for avoidance. Respondents are asked to&#xD;
      rate their level of fear and avoidance in 24 social situations. Research shows good&#xD;
      psychometric properties. Only the scale for anxiety will be used to minimize the burden for&#xD;
      the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.4 Androgen receptor CAGn polymorphism A study by Zitzmann et al. showed an association&#xD;
      between androgen receptor CAG repeats and androgen action. KS men with a shorter CAGn length&#xD;
      seem to have less gynecomastia, bigger testis and higher bone density. When KS men with a&#xD;
      shorter CAGn length receive testosterone replacement therapy, they show a better suppression&#xD;
      of LH levels, prostate growth and higher haemoglobin concentrations. However, a more recent&#xD;
      study by Valente et al. showed no relevant clinical differences in KS patients due to CAGn&#xD;
      length variation on the androgen receptor. Therefore it is currently unclear whether CAG&#xD;
      repeats are of clinical importance. Blood samples (buffy coat) will be collected and stored&#xD;
      to be able to measure androgen receptor CAG repeats when the role of these CAGn polymorphisms&#xD;
      has been clarified.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nature and extent of the burden and risks associated with participation, benefit and group&#xD;
      relatedness:&#xD;
&#xD;
      For patients with KS: There are no risks associated with participation. All measurements will&#xD;
      take place right after a planned visit at the outpatients clinic. All subjects with KS need&#xD;
      to answer questions from four questionnaires, which will take about 30 minutes (including&#xD;
      collection of informed consent). The biochemical parameters measured are already routinely&#xD;
      assessed during the visits to the outpatients clinic. Only one extra tube of blood will be&#xD;
      collected and stored. Blood will be collected during blood withdrawal for the assessment of&#xD;
      laboratory values needed for standard care. One strand of hair will also be collected.The&#xD;
      burden is therefore minimal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For patients with TS: For patients with TS all information is already available. Therefore&#xD;
      there will not be any burden or risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is no direct benefit for the participants, but all patients with KS and TS could&#xD;
      benefit from better hormonal treatment in the future due to the results of this study. When&#xD;
      the questionnaires indicate severe psychological problems, psychological care will be&#xD;
      offered.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The relationship between thyroid hormone status* and QoL as measured by the EQ-5D-5L in patients with TS.</measure>
    <time_frame>At study entry (cross-sectional study). There is just one visit per patient. The total study has an approximately duration of 3-4 years.</time_frame>
    <description>thyroid hormone status is a variable that consists of the following 6 categories:&#xD;
Overt hyperthyroidism (FT4&gt;25pmol/L and TSH&lt;0,4mU/L)&#xD;
Overt hypothyroidism (FT4 &lt;11 pmol/L and TSH &gt;4,3 mU/L)&#xD;
Subclinical hypothyroidism with TSH &lt;10mU/L (FT4 11-25 pmol/L and TSH 4,3-10mU/L)&#xD;
Subclinical hypothyroidism with TSH &gt;10mU/L (FT4 11-25 pmol/L and TSH &gt; 10mU/L)&#xD;
Subclinical hyperthyroidism (FT4 11-25 pmol/L and TSH &lt;0,4 mU/L)&#xD;
Euthyroidism (FT4 11-25 pmol/L and TSH 0,4- 4,3 mU/L)&#xD;
The range of the EQ-5D-5L is from 0 to 100. A higher score means a better outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The relationship between testosterone concentrations in hair and QoL as measured by the EQ-5D-5L in patients with KS.</measure>
    <time_frame>At study entry (cross-sectional study). There is just one visit per patient. The total study has an approximately duration of 3-4 years.</time_frame>
    <description>The range of the EQ-5D-5L is from 0 to 100. A higher score means a better outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">370</enrollment>
  <condition>Klinefelter Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Turner Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Klinefelter</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with Klinefelter syndrome</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Turner</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patient with Turner syndrome</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Measurement of blood values, questionnaire scores and measurements of hormone levels in hair</intervention_name>
    <description>Measurement of blood values, questionnaire scores and measurements of hormone levels in hair</description>
    <arm_group_label>Klinefelter</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Turner</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients with KS and TS of 18 years or older that visit the outpatients clinic of the&#xD;
        EMC, AMC or the VUmc will be included. Approximately 120 KS and 250 TS patients are&#xD;
        intended to be included.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Klinefelter or Turner syndrome as confirmed by genetic testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sufficient knowledge of the Dutch language to complete the questionnaires&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  KS: Patients not under treatment in the EMC, AMC or VUmc or no planned visits during&#xD;
             the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  TS: No laboratory values or no questionnaires available in patient records&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe psychiatric or neurologic disorders or other reasons for inability to complete&#xD;
             the questionnaires as assessed by the treating physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure to obtain informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Laura de Graaff, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine - Endocrinology, Erasmus MC, Rotterdam, the Netherlands</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Laura de Graaff, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+31618843010</phone>
    <email>l.degraaff@erasmusmc.nl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Erasmus Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rotterdam</city>
        <state>Zuid-Holland</state>
        <zip>3015 GD</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Laura CG de Graaff, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+31618843010</phone>
      <email>l.degraaff@erasmusmc.nl</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sabine E Hannema</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Erasmus Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>dr. Laura C. G. de Graaff-Herder</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Turner Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gonadal Dysgenesis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Klinefelter Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data available upon reasonable request</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

