<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04806191</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2019/104</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04806191</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Simple and Evidence-based Examination and Treatment of Shoulder Pain in General Practice</brief_title>
  <acronym>EASIER</acronym>
  <official_title>Making Shoulder Pain Simple in General Practice-implementing an Evidenced Based Guideline for Shoulder Pain, a Hybrid Design Cluster Randomised Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Oslo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Helse Fonna</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Oslo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Previous research suggests that general practitioners find handling patients with shoulder&#xD;
      pain difficult and that the current care for shoulder pain is not in line with the best&#xD;
      available evidence (1).This project aims to assess the effectiveness, costs and&#xD;
      implementation of an evidence-based guideline for shoulder pain in general practice.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A simplified and evidence-based algorithm for examination and treatment of patients with&#xD;
      shoulder pain will be developed and implemented in general practice. The purpose is to&#xD;
      improve quality of care and provide GPs with a simplified and efficient tool to handle&#xD;
      patients with common shoulder- related pain. The study is a stepped-wedge, cluster-randomized&#xD;
      trial with a hybrid design including a effectiveness, cost and implementation assessment of a&#xD;
      guideline-based intervention in clinical practice (2). General practitioners in Norway will&#xD;
      be recruited and the GP offices will be randomized to the time of crossover from current&#xD;
      treatment as usual (TAU) to the implementation of the intervention. The intervention is a&#xD;
      tailored strategy that includes workshops for general practitioners covering information and&#xD;
      access to a decision support tool, an education program where the general practitioner learn&#xD;
      an evidence-based approach to shoulder pain and access to patient information materials.&#xD;
      Outcomes will be measured at patient and GP levels, using self-report questionnaires, focus&#xD;
      group interviews and register based data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 11, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Stepped wedge randomized study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Outcome assessor will be blinded for treatment allocation. Randomization will be done after recruitment of GPs. GPs and study coordinators and outcome evaluators will be blinded to the allocation sequence with only the allocation of the next GP surgery being revealed by randomization list holder approximately 6 weeks before each intervention implementation point.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Shoulder Pain and Disability Index (SPADI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from 0 to 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>13 item patient reported questionnaire on shoulder pain and disability. (0 = no pain or shoulder disability, 100 = worst pain and disability).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>the EuroQol quality of life measure (EQ5D-5L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from 0 weeks to 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Health related quality of life ((0 (death) - 1.0 (perfect health))</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient reported quality of care index (treatment according to the guideline intervention)</measure>
    <time_frame>0 week (after 1. visit to general practitioner)</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported content of treatment measured on six items according to treatment prescribed by the GP measured on 5-item Likert scales. Sum score above 18 points regarded as consultation of high quality according to guideline intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Global patient perceived effect of treatment outcome (GPE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 6,12 and 52 weeks. Primary analysis of interest is at 12 weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>1 item (7-point) ( 0 = worse than ever, 7 =I have become completely well)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Brief illness perception questionnaire (BIPQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0, 6, 12, 52 weeks, Primary time point of interest is 12 weeks and analysing changescore from 0 to 12 weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>Illness perception 0-80 where a higher score reflects a more threatening view of the illness</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Pain self-efficacy questionnaire (PSEQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0, 6, 12, 52 weeks, primary time point of interest is 12 weeks analysing change score from 0 to 12 weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>Self efficacy for pain 0-60 where higher score reflects higher self efficacy for pain.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Work disability patient reported</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0, 6, 12, 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Sick leave reported as whole days away from work</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Örebro Musculoskeletal Pain Screening Questionnaire (Short)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Psychosocial, prognostic factors for musculoskeletal pain. The total score will range between 1 and 100, with a score &gt;50 indicating higher estimated risk for future work disability</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Pateint reported frequency of therapy due to shoulder pain in primary and secondary health care</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0, 6, 12, 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Reported number of consultations by GPs, specialists (orthopeds, rheumatologists, physiatrists or neurologists), physiotherapists, chiropractists and alternative therapists, injections and surgery.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient reported frequency of use of supplemental investigations in primary and secondary health care.</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0, 6, 12, 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of investigations; blood tests and radiology (Projectional radiograph, CT, MRI)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient reported direct economical expences due to shoulder pain</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0, 6, 12, 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported use of medication reported as type of medication and frequency last week</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient reported indirect economical expences due to shoulder pain; travel distance to therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0, 6, 12, 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported travel distance to therapy measured in km</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient reported indirect economical expences due to shoulder pain; time away for therapy measured in hours</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0, 6, 12, 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported time away for therapy measured in hours</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient reported indirect economical expences due to shoulder pain; time away for work measured in hours.</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0, 6, 12, 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported time away from work measured in hours</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient reported indirect economical expences due to shoulder pain; production loss.</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0, 6, 12, 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported production loss measured as patient estimated per cent production loss due to shoulder pain. A higher number means a higher loss of production.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Work disability from the Norwegian Labour and Welfare Administration registry</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Registry data</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Global patient perceived satisfaction with treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 6, 12, 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>1 item (5-point Likert scale); 0=dissatisfied, 5=very satisfied</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient experience questionnaire (PEQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>4 subscales (communication, emotions, outcome, barriers) with 4 items measured on 4 or 7 point Likert scales. A high score represents a good communication experience, positive emotions, positive consultation outcome, no communication barriers.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Shoulder Outcome Expectancies</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0 week, 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>1 item measured on a 7-point Likert scale. A higher score indicate higher patient perceived outcome expectancy.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient interview (qualitative)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative interview with selected patients, feasibility/ barriers and facilitators</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Implementation process assesment tool (IPAT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 2 weeks, 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of the implementation process from the perspective of the GPs</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>GPs self-efficacy for handling patients with shoulder pain according to guideline care</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0 week, 2 weeks,12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>9 items measured on 6-point Likert scales analysing change in individual items and sum score before and 12 weeks after educational outreach. A higher score indicates higher self-efficacy</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>GPs global perceived satisfaction with workshop (GP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 0 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>10 item measured on 5-point Likert scales concerning satisfaction with the different topics and content of the work shop.We will analyze individual items. A higher score indicate higher satisfaction.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>GPs global perceived satisfaction, benefit, usability and frequency of use of the intervention (GP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>4 item measured on 5-point Likert scales. We will analyze individual items. A higher score indicate higher satisfaction, benefit, usability and frequency of use of the intervention.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>GPs use of the intervention in daily practice; degree of simplifying shoulder evaluation and treatment, recommending exercises, information and patient involvement (GP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>4 items measured on 7-point Likert scales. We will analyze individual items. A higher score indicate higher degree of use in daily practice and a higher degree of simplifying shoulder evaluation and treatment, recommending exercises, information and patient involvement.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>GP focus groups</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative interview with selected GPs, feasibility/ barriers and facilitators</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">250</enrollment>
  <condition>Shoulder Pain</condition>
  <condition>Frozen Shoulder</condition>
  <condition>Rotator Cuff Tendinosis</condition>
  <condition>Myalgia</condition>
  <condition>Rotator Cuff Impingement Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Rotator Cuff Tear or Rupture, Not Specified as Traumatic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be assessed by GPs who have attended an outreach workshop and trained at using an evidence based strategy for shoulder examination and treatment. GPs will have access to a decision support tool and patients is offered a tailored information package for self management.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual (TAU)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The participants enrolled in the control period will receive treatment as offered in general practice.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Evidence based treatment strategy</intervention_name>
    <description>Evidence-based clinical examination and treatment plan</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Targeted patient information package</intervention_name>
    <description>GPs will in cooperation with the patients tailor a information package targeted to the patients needs regarding their clinical shoulder diagnosis and individual implications and needs (Pain, sleep, exercises etc.).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Treatment as usual (TAU)</intervention_name>
    <description>Usual care as provided by the GP</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual (TAU)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pain in the shoulder region&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Above 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to fill in self-report questionnaires or do not understand Norwegian&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute injury with clinical suspicion of fracture, luxation of shoulder joints or large&#xD;
             tendon ruptures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical suspicion of referred pain to the shoulder area from other organs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signs of inflammatory joint disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspicion of malignant disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptoms and signs of cervical radiculopathy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Niels G Juel, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of General practice, University of Oslo</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Stein J Pedersen, MD</last_name>
    <phone>90162213</phone>
    <phone_ext>+47</phone_ext>
    <email>s.j.pedersen@medisin.uio.no</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ole M Ekeberg, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>91745757</phone>
    <phone_ext>+47</phone_ext>
    <email>omae@helse-fonna.no</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Research and innovation, Helse Fonna, Norway</name>
      <address>
        <city>Haugesund</city>
        <state>Vestland</state>
        <zip>5504</zip>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ole M Ekeberg, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>91745757</phone>
      <phone_ext>+47</phone_ext>
      <email>omae@helse-fonna.no</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Eva Biringer, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>97156593</phone>
      <phone_ext>+47</phone_ext>
      <email>eva.kristin.hope.aaker.biringer@helse-fonna.no</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of General Practice, University of Oslo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oslo</city>
        <zip>0450</zip>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Stein J Pedersen, MD</last_name>
      <phone>90162213</phone>
      <phone_ext>+47</phone_ext>
      <email>s.j.pedersen@medisin.uio.no</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Niels G Juel, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>92443113</phone>
      <phone_ext>+47</phone_ext>
      <email>UXNGJU@ous-hf.no</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Norway</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Curran GM, Bauer M, Mittman B, Pyne JM, Stetler C. Effectiveness-implementation hybrid designs: combining elements of clinical effectiveness and implementation research to enhance public health impact. Med Care. 2012 Mar;50(3):217-26. doi: 10.1097/MLR.0b013e3182408812.</citation>
    <PMID>22310560</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Artus M, van der Windt DA, Afolabi EK, Buchbinder R, Chesterton LS, Hall A, Roddy E, Foster NE. Management of shoulder pain by UK general practitioners (GPs): a national survey. BMJ Open. 2017 Jun 21;7(6):e015711. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2016-015711.</citation>
    <PMID>28637737</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 3, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Oslo</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Niels Gunnar JUEL</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD. PhD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>General practice</keyword>
  <keyword>Implementation</keyword>
  <keyword>Guideline</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Shoulder Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bursitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myalgia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tendinopathy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Shoulder Impingement Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rupture</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rotator Cuff Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

