<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04801576</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EPuizina</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04801576</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>In Vivo Assessment of Geno- and Cytotoxicity of Fluoridated Toothpastes and Mouthrinses on Buccal Epithelial Cells</brief_title>
  <official_title>In Vivo Assessment of Geno- and Cytotoxicity of Fluoridated Toothpastes and Mouthrinses on Human Buccal Epithelial Cells</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Split, School of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Split, School of Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Buccal cells represent the first barrier to the oral hygiene products' potential toxic&#xD;
      effect. The usual concentration of fluoride in toothpastes is 1000/1100 parts per million&#xD;
      (ppm F); toothpastes with higher (1500 ppm F) and lower than conventional fluoride levels&#xD;
      (around 500 ppm F) are available in many countries. Toothpastes containing higher&#xD;
      concentrations of fluoride confer greater protection against caries but at the same time the&#xD;
      fluoride is able to induce harmful effects on oral mucosa cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study would include around 40 participants, aged between 20 and 65, divided in two&#xD;
      groups. Each group will use fluoride free toothpaste for 28 days, than afterwards group B&#xD;
      will get toothpastes (each for 28 days) with no fluoride, 1045 ppm F and 1450 ppm F used&#xD;
      together with mouthrinse containing 450 ppm F, while the group A will have everything the&#xD;
      same except the mouthrinse that will contain no fluoride - a placebo mouthrinse.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Every 28 days buccal cells samples would be collected from each participant and a Buccal&#xD;
      micronucleus cytome assay would be performed according to Nature protocols: Thomas et all.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study would be to assess the possible cumulative effect of together use of&#xD;
      fluoridated toothpastes and mouthrinses, since population worldwide uses them together&#xD;
      without any exact studies about toxicity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 21, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients with treatment-related cytotoxic and genotoxic events in buccal cells assessed by buccal cytome micronucleus assay.</measure>
    <time_frame>112 days (4 periods of 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Method used is Buccal Micronucleus Cytome (BMCyt) assay as minimally invasive method for studying DNA damage, chromosomal instability, cell death and the regenerative potential of human buccal mucosal tissue. This is one of the current established methods for buccal cell collection using a small-headed toothbrush, the generation of a single-cell suspension, slide preparation using cytocentrifugation, fixation and staining using Feulgen and Light Green for both bright field and fluorescence microscopic analysis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>DNA Damage</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo mouthrinse</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group that uses just toothpaste without fluoride for 28 days; toothpaste without flouride and mouthrinse without flouride for 28 days; toothpaste with 1050 ppm F and mouthrinse without flouride for 28 days; toothpaste with 1450 ppm F and mouthrinse without flouride for 28 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fluoride in mouthrinses</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group that uses just toothpaste without fluoride for 28 days; toothpaste without flouride and mouthrinse with 450 ppm F for 28 days; toothpaste with 1050 ppm F and mouthrinse with 450 ppm F for 28 days; toothpaste with 1450 ppm F and mouthrinse with 450 ppm F for 28 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Flouride in mouthrinses</intervention_name>
    <description>Custom made toothpastes and mouthrinses that do or do not contain flouride as sodium fluoride in different concentrations.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Fluoride in mouthrinses</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo mouthrinse</intervention_name>
    <description>Mouthrinses without flouride</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo mouthrinse</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  healthy subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a sufficient level of education to understand the procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients not younger than 18 and not older than 65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  non-smokers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients without exposure to any x-ray examination in last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects with use of any medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects that use alcohol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects with oral lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects with history of chronic health conditions&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ema Puizina Mladinić, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>00385955749644</phone>
    <email>e.puizina@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Split School of medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Split</city>
        <zip>21000</zip>
        <country>Croatia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ema Puizina Mladinić, M.D.</last_name>
      <phone>0955749644</phone>
      <email>e.puizina@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Croatia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tadin A, Gavic L, Govic T, Galic N, Zorica Vladislavic N, Zeljezic D. In vivo evaluation of fluoride and sodium lauryl sulphate in toothpaste on buccal epithelial cells toxicity. Acta Odontol Scand. 2019 Jul;77(5):386-393. doi: 10.1080/00016357.2019.1577988. Epub 2019 Feb 20. Erratum in: Acta Odontol Scand. 2019 Aug;77(6):483.</citation>
    <PMID>30784350</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tadin A, Gavic L, Zeravica A, Ugrin K, Galic N, Zeljezic D. Assessment of cytotoxic and genotoxic effects of conventional and whitening kinds of toothpaste on oral mucosa cells. Acta Odontol Scand. 2018 Jan;76(1):64-70. doi: 10.1080/00016357.2017.1384567. Epub 2017 Sep 29.</citation>
    <PMID>28959909</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tadin A, Marovic D, Galic N, Kovacic I, Zeljezic D. Composite-induced toxicity in human gingival and pulp fibroblast cells. Acta Odontol Scand. 2014 May;72(4):304-11. doi: 10.3109/00016357.2013.824607. Epub 2013 Aug 22.</citation>
    <PMID>23964631</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ribeiro DA, Cardoso CM, Yujra VQ, DE Barros Viana M, Aguiar O Jr, Pisani LP, Oshima CTF. Fluoride Induces Apoptosis in Mammalian Cells: In Vitro and In Vivo Studies. Anticancer Res. 2017 Sep;37(9):4767-4777. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28870895</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Thomas P, Holland N, Bolognesi C, Kirsch-Volders M, Bonassi S, Zeiger E, Knasmueller S, Fenech M. Buccal micronucleus cytome assay. Nat Protoc. 2009;4(6):825-37. doi: 10.1038/nprot.2009.53. Epub 2009 May 7.</citation>
    <PMID>19444240</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Split, School of Medicine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ema Puizina Mladinić, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

