<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04808076</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LinkoepingU2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04808076</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Idiopathic Normal Pressure Hydrocephalus: Focus on Imaging and Clinical Symptoms.</brief_title>
  <acronym>LiNPH</acronym>
  <official_title>Advanced MR-methods, Protein Levels in Cerebrospinal Fluid, Gait Analysis and Symptoms in Patients With Idiopathic Normal Pressure Hydrocephalus.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Linkoeping University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Linkoeping University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      LiNPH is a prospective single center clinical and radiological study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Fifty consecutive patients with idiopathic Normal Pressure Hydrocephalus (iNPH) diagnosed&#xD;
      according to the American-European iNPH guidelines from 2005, are going to be recruited from&#xD;
      the outpatient clinic at the Department of Neurology, University Hospital, Linköping, Sweden.&#xD;
      All patients are going to undergo a primary evaluation and examination by a neurologist&#xD;
      followed by a CT or/and a MRI of the brain. On MRI there should be symmetrical communicating&#xD;
      ventricular enlargement without cortical infarcts or other lesions of clinical importance,&#xD;
      except lacunar infarcts (&lt;1 cm3), the Evans ratio should be ≥ 0.3 and the corpus callosum&#xD;
      angle should be between 50o to 90o. The temporal horns and third ventricle should be&#xD;
      relatively enlarged. Mild to moderate cortical atrophy and subcortical white matter&#xD;
      hyper-intensity will be allowed. The motor function will be assessed by a physiotherapist&#xD;
      using the following tests: time needed for a 10-meter (m) walk in steps (w10ms) and 10-m walk&#xD;
      in time (w10mt) at a self-selected speed and with their usual walking aid, timed up and go&#xD;
      test in seconds (TUGt) and steps (TUGs), which is a timed test for standing up from chair,&#xD;
      walking 3 m, turning and walking back to the chair and sitting down. An occupational&#xD;
      therapist will perform cognitive testing with Mini Mental State Examination (MMSE). A&#xD;
      CSF-tap-test will be performed at the Neurology outpatient department, at around 10:00 pm, in&#xD;
      all patients. For the CSF-TT the patients will lie in a recumbent position, and under sterile&#xD;
      conditions by using a 10 ml subcutaneous Xylocaine dose as pain prevention, the investigators&#xD;
      will applicate a spinal needle 18Gx3.50&quot;x1.2mmx90mm. Once CSF is obtained, a spinal fluid&#xD;
      manometer (Optidynamic, Mediplast, Italy) will be connected to measure the CSF pressure in cm&#xD;
      H2O. The lumbar pressure will be measured during a period of almost one minute for avoiding&#xD;
      artificially elevated levels. All patients will be relaxed and have their neck to a neutral&#xD;
      position and their legs extended. Lumbar pressure will be measured before the CSF-TT. The CSF&#xD;
      will be analyzed for: cells, lactate, albumin, isoelectric focusing, antibodies against&#xD;
      Borrelia Burgdofferi, NFL, t-tau, p-tau, β-amyloid 42/40, β-amyloid and GFAP. After a&#xD;
      multidisciplinary round the investigators will decide who is suitable for a&#xD;
      ventriculoperitoneal shunt. All probable/possible iNPH patients, included in the study, will&#xD;
      undergo a preoperative Tracted-Based Spatial Statistics (TBSS) and Diffusion Tensor Imaging&#xD;
      (DTI) investigation one to two days before the operation. All included in this study patients&#xD;
      will undergo the same work-up almost 3 months after the shunt surgery inclusive the TBSS and&#xD;
      DTI. All patients will meet a neurosurgeon once after the operation for possible shunt valve&#xD;
      adjustment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, 50 volunteer healthy control subjects (HI) over the age of 60 will be recruited.&#xD;
      All HI will undergo examination by a neurologist, DTI,TBSS and answer questionnaires included&#xD;
      in the study. The controls are recruited from relatives, University Hospital employees and&#xD;
      friends of the research group through advertising and personal inquiries. Exclusion criteria&#xD;
      are observable gait disorder, diagnosed dementia, obvious gait / balance disorder for other&#xD;
      reasons, occurrence of claustrophobia, implants that make MRI examination impossible and&#xD;
      neurological disorder that is detected in connection with MRI examination and urinary&#xD;
      catheter and / or uro- / intestinal stomia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Another part of this project is a qualitative questionnaire based single center prospective&#xD;
      study. All LiNPH patients and HI are going to answer three questionnaires ( ICIQ-UI, Bowel&#xD;
      function Questionnaire, Wexners FI) regarding gastrointestinal and urinary symptoms and the&#xD;
      investigators are going to correlate them with clinical data before and after the shunt&#xD;
      surgery. The aim of this study is to identify if fecal incontinence is a new unknown symptom&#xD;
      in iNPH patients. The secondary aim of this study is to correlate DTI and TBSS data with&#xD;
      urinary- and fecal-incontinence symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary aim of this study is to distinguish between reversible and irreversible changes&#xD;
      in iNPH. To establish a new technique in investigation of patients with iNPH and early&#xD;
      identify this group. A significant correlation between DTI results in one or more brain areas&#xD;
      with the iNPH-results will give the investigators the opportunity to use a specific DTI&#xD;
      protocol to easier identify iNPH-patients who will have positive results with a shunt&#xD;
      operation. The investigators also aim to compare manual-DTI MRI and TBSS-based MRI results&#xD;
      before and after shunt surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 12, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>INPH patients and Healthy Individuals.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>White Matter Changes in Idiopathic Normal Pressure Hydrocephalus: A Diffusion Tensor Imaging Study.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Franctional Anisotropi and Apparent Diffusion Coefficient changes before and 3 months after the shunt surgery and correlation with clinical data. All data will be compared with results from the Healthy individual group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gastrointestinal and urinary symptoms in idiopathic Normal Pressure Hydrocephalus.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>By using questionnaires possible gastrointestinal and urinary symptoms are going to be characterized, check existence and correlate with Diffusion Tensor Imaging data. Statistically control of differences with the Healthy Individual group.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Tract-based spatial statistics and diffusion tensor imaging in patients with idiopathic Normal Pressure Hydrocephalus.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Analysis of data from both techniques and statistical analysis to find which method could be more suitable in patients with idiopathic Normal Pressure Hydrocephalus.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Fecal Incontinence With Fecal Urgency</condition>
  <condition>Urine Incontinence</condition>
  <condition>Diffusion Tensor Imaging</condition>
  <condition>Leukoencephalopathies</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>iNPH patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Shunt operation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Individuals</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Healthy individuals without any neurological disease.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Shunt surgery</intervention_name>
    <description>Shunt operation</description>
    <arm_group_label>iNPH patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: Patients fulfilling the clinical and radiological criteria for a&#xD;
        possible or probable iNPH diagnosis, according to the American-European Guidelines from&#xD;
        2005.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: Patients unable to understand instructions with an MMSE lower than 17,&#xD;
        claustrophobia or implant which makes the participation in MRI studies unable.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Fredrik Lundin, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Neurology and Department of Biomedical and Clinical Sciences, Linköping University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andreas Eleftheriou, MD, PhDc</last_name>
    <phone>+46733993945</phone>
    <email>andelef2002@yahoo.gr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Fredrik Lundin, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+46704782816</phone>
    <email>fredrik.lundin@regionostergotland.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of Linköping</name>
      <address>
        <city>Linköping</city>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andreas Eleftheriou</last_name>
      <phone>+46733993945</phone>
      <email>andelef2002@yahoo.gr</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Fredrik Lundin</last_name>
      <phone>+46704782816</phone>
      <email>fredrik.lundin@regionostergotland.se</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eleftheriou A, Blystad I, Tisell A, Gasslander J, Lundin F. Publisher Correction: Indication of Thalamo-Cortical Circuit Dysfunction in Idiopathic Normal Pressure Hydrocephalus: A Diffusion Tensor Imaging Study. Sci Rep. 2020 Jul 16;10(1):12014. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-69149-x.</citation>
    <PMID>32678296</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Keong NC, Pena A, Price SJ, Czosnyka M, Czosnyka Z, DeVito EE, Housden CR, Sahakian BJ, Pickard JD. Diffusion tensor imaging profiles reveal specific neural tract distortion in normal pressure hydrocephalus. PLoS One. 2017 Aug 17;12(8):e0181624. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0181624. eCollection 2017.</citation>
    <PMID>28817574</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Siasios I, Kapsalaki EZ, Fountas KN, Fotiadou A, Dorsch A, Vakharia K, Pollina J, Dimopoulos V. The role of diffusion tensor imaging and fractional anisotropy in the evaluation of patients with idiopathic normal pressure hydrocephalus: a literature review. Neurosurg Focus. 2016 Sep;41(3):E12. doi: 10.3171/2016.6.FOCUS16192. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27581308</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nakanishi A, Fukunaga I, Hori M, Masutani Y, Takaaki H, Miyajima M, Aoki S. Microstructural changes of the corticospinal tract in idiopathic normal pressure hydrocephalus: a comparison of diffusion tensor and diffusional kurtosis imaging. Neuroradiology. 2013 Aug;55(8):971-976. doi: 10.1007/s00234-013-1201-6. Epub 2013 Jun 2.</citation>
    <PMID>23728069</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ege S. [Management of urinary incontinence in a geriatric rehabilitation department : Global urinary incontinence assessment incorporating the International Consultation on Incontinence Questionnare - Urinary Incontinence Short Form (ICIQ-UI SF)]. Z Gerontol Geriatr. 2018 Apr;51(3):301-313. doi: 10.1007/s00391-016-1173-3. Epub 2017 Feb 8. German.</citation>
    <PMID>28180932</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Marmarou A, Black P, Bergsneider M, Klinge P, Relkin N; International NPH Consultant Group. Guidelines for management of idiopathic normal pressure hydrocephalus: progress to date. Acta Neurochir Suppl. 2005;95:237-40.</citation>
    <PMID>16463856</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ishikawa M, Hashimoto M, Kuwana N, Mori E, Miyake H, Wachi A, Takeuchi T, Kazui H, Koyama H. Guidelines for management of idiopathic normal pressure hydrocephalus. Neurol Med Chir (Tokyo). 2008;48 Suppl:S1-23.</citation>
    <PMID>18408356</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Linkoeping University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Fredrik Lundin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Senior Officer, MD, PhD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Tract-Based Spatial Statistics</keyword>
  <keyword>DTI</keyword>
  <keyword>fecal incontinence</keyword>
  <keyword>urine incontinence</keyword>
  <keyword>whiter matter changes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fecal Incontinence</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hydrocephalus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hydrocephalus, Normal Pressure</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukoencephalopathies</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Enuresis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

