<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04804059</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APX001-104</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04804059</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Assess the Mass Balance Recovery and Metabolite Profile &amp; Identification of [14C]-APX001 in Healthy Males</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open Label, Single-Dose, Single-Period Study Designed to Assess the Mass Balance Recovery, Metabolite Profile and Metabolite Identification of [14C]-APX001 in Healthy Male Subjects After Oral and Intravenous Dosing</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pfizer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pfizer</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a single-center, open-label, non-randomized, single dose study in healthy male&#xD;
      subjects. It was planned to enroll 2 cohorts of 5 subjects (10 subjects in total), with the&#xD;
      target of achieving data in 4 evaluable subjects per cohort. Five subjects were to receive a&#xD;
      single oral dose of APX001 and not more than (NMT) 3.1 megabecquerel (MBq) (84.0 microcurie&#xD;
      [μCi]) 14C in the fed state. Five subjects were to receive a single IV administration&#xD;
      containing APX001 and NMT 3.4 MBq (93.0 μCi) 14C in the fed state.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 17, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 26, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 26, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mass balance recovery as measured by mass unit equiv/g after a single oral or single intravenous (IV) dose of carbon-14 (14C)-labelled APX001 ([14C]-APX001).</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Profiling of metabolites of [14C]-APX001 in plasma and excreta.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma, urine and feces samples from subjects dosed with [14C]-APX001 were analyzed using high resolution, accurate mass liquid chromatography tandem mass spectrometry (LC-MS/MS) with in-line fraction collection and off-line counting to obtain [14C]-radiochromatographic profiles and provide information on the nature of the radioactive components present, including chemical structure identification.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Elimination pathway of [14C]-APX001 following a single oral or single IV dose of [14C]-APX001.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Amount of radioactivity recovered from urine and feces over time was measured by liquid scintillation counting (LSC) and expressed as a percentage of administered radioactivity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Extent of distribution of total radioactivity into blood cells following a single oral or single IV dose of [14C]-APX001.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Amount of radioactivity in whole blood over time was quantified by LSC and expressed in ng equivalents free drug/g.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Fungal Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>[14C]-APX001 Oral Solution</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>[14C]-APX001 Solution for Infusion</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>[14C]-APX001 Oral Solution</intervention_name>
    <description>Total dose containing NMT 3.1 MBq (84.0 µCi) 14C</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort A</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>[14C]-APX001 Solution for Infusion</intervention_name>
    <description>Total dose containing NMT 3.4 MBq (93.0 µCi) 14C</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy males&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Aged 30 to 65 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Body mass index (BMI) of 18.0 to 32.0 kg/m2 or, if outside the range, considered not&#xD;
             clinically significant by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Good state of health (mentally and physically) as indicated by a comprehensive&#xD;
             clinical assessment (detailed medical history and a complete physical examination)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Must have been willing and able to communicate and participate in the whole study&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Must have had regular bowel movements (i.e. average stool production of ≥1 and&#xD;
&#xD;
             ≤3 stools per day)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Must have provided written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Must have adhered to the contraception requirements defined in Section 9.4 of the&#xD;
             protocol (Appendix 16.1.1)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects who had received any IMP in a clinical research study within the previous 3&#xD;
             months or a similar 14C radioactive clinical trial within the previous 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects who were study site employees, or immediate family members of a study site or&#xD;
             sponsor employee&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects who had previously been enrolled in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of any drug or alcohol abuse in the past 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Regular alcohol consumption in males &gt;21 units per week (1 unit = ½ pint beer, or a 25&#xD;
             mL shot of 40% spirit, 1.5 to 2 units = 125 mL glass of wine, depending on type)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Current smokers and those who had smoked within the last 12 months. A breath carbon&#xD;
             monoxide (CO) reading of greater than 10 ppm at screening and admission&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Current users of e-cigarettes and nicotine replacement products and those who had used&#xD;
             these products within the last 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Radiation exposure, including that from the present study, excluding background&#xD;
             radiation but including diagnostic x-rays and other medical exposures, exceeded 5&#xD;
             millisieverts (mSv) in the last 12 months or 10 mSv in the last 5 years. No&#xD;
             occupationally exposed worker, as defined in the Ionising Radiation Regulations 2017,&#xD;
             was to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects who did not have suitable veins for multiple venipunctures/cannulation as&#xD;
             assessed by the investigator at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Clinically significant abnormality on electrocardiogram (ECG) as judged by the&#xD;
             investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Clinically significant abnormal biochemistry, hematology or urinalysis at screening as&#xD;
             judged by the investigator (laboratory parameters are listed in Appendix 1 of the&#xD;
             protocol, Appendix 16.1.1)&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Positive drugs of abuse test result (drugs of abuse tests are listed in Appendix 1 of&#xD;
             the protocol, Appendix 16.1.1)&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Positive hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg), hepatitis C virus antibody (HCV Ab) or&#xD;
             human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) results&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Evidence of renal impairment at screening, as indicated by an estimated creatinine&#xD;
             clearance of &lt;80 mL/min using the Cockcroft-Gault equation&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. History of clinically significant cardiovascular, renal, hepatic, chronic respiratory&#xD;
             or gastrointestinal (GI) disease, neurological or psychiatric disorder, as judged by&#xD;
             the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Serious adverse reaction or serious hypersensitivity to any drug or the formulation&#xD;
             excipients&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Presence or history of clinically significant allergy requiring treatment, as judged&#xD;
             by the investigator. Hayfever was allowed unless it was active&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Donation or loss of greater than 400 mL of blood within the previous 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Subjects who were taking, or had taken, any prescribed or over-the-counter drug (other&#xD;
             than 4 g per day paracetamol) or herbal remedies in the 14 days before IMP&#xD;
             administration (see Section 11.4 of the protocol, Appendix 16.1.1). Exceptions may&#xD;
             have applied on a case by case basis, if considered not to interfere with the&#xD;
             objectives of the study, as agreed by the PI and sponsor's medical monitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Failure to satisfy the investigator of fitness to participate for any other reason&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pfizer CT.gov Call Center</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Pfizer</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Quotient Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ruddington</city>
        <state>Nottingham</state>
        <zip>NG11 6JS</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 1, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 15, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 18, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mycoses</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

