<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04805164</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>69HCL20_0065</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-A02299-30</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04805164</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of the Efficiency of the Bone Substitute Cerament-G Locally Delivering Gentamicin in the Treatment of Chronic Osteomyelitis of Long Bones</brief_title>
  <acronym>CONVICTION</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Efficiency of the Bone Substitute Cerament-G Locally Delivering Gentamicin in the Treatment of Chronic Osteomyelitis of Long Bones: Randomized Multicentre Study in the CRIOAc Network - CONVICTION Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospices Civils de Lyon</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospices Civils de Lyon</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic osteomyelitis is a serious osteoarticular infection that most often occurs in the&#xD;
      long bones (tibia, femur, humerus), responsible for significant morbidity with risk of&#xD;
      fracture and amputation. It is due to the presence of bacteria in the bone marrow, sometimes&#xD;
      responsible for an intraosseous abscess.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chronic osteomyelitis can have a hematogenous or more often exogenous origin, after trauma or&#xD;
      surgery. The bacteria involved have the ability to modify their metabolism and involve&#xD;
      persistence mechanisms (such as biofilm) making them difficult to eradicate. The treatment of&#xD;
      chronic osteomyelitis requires surgery, i.e. corticotomy, which means opening of the bone&#xD;
      cortex to perform an endomedullary curettage to identify the bacteria, remove any&#xD;
      sequestration (bone fragments to which the bacteria adhere as biofilm) and reduce the&#xD;
      bacterial inoculum. At the same time, or at a second stage, a skin and soft tissue/muscle&#xD;
      flap may be required, especially in patients with long-standing disease with embrittlement&#xD;
      and adhesion of the skin and soft tissue to the underlying bone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post-operatively, the patient receives a probabilistic systemic antibiotic therapy and then a&#xD;
      systemic antibiotic therapy targeted on the identified germ, for a period of 3 months. The&#xD;
      effectiveness of these antibiotics is based on their ability to penetrate bone tissue.&#xD;
      Despite the progress made in both antibiotics and surgical treatments, the probability of&#xD;
      failure (recurrence of infection) is around 20%, and has unfortunately remained stable for&#xD;
      more than 20 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cerament-G (BONESUPPORT AB Laboratory, Sweden), a synthetic bone substitute composed of&#xD;
      hydroxyapatite, calcium sulphate, and gentamicin, fills the &quot;dead space&quot; formed during&#xD;
      surgery, prevents infection of this blood-filled cavity, and promotes bone regeneration&#xD;
      within this space (limiting the risk of fracture in the medium and long term). Cerament-G&#xD;
      also delivers locally very high doses of gentamicin (concentration of 17.5 mg/mL in the&#xD;
      device) for several weeks. Gentamicine is a broad-spectrum bactericidal antibiotic effective&#xD;
      against the vast majority of bacteria involved in osteoarticular infections. It provides&#xD;
      effective local antibiotic therapy through wide exposure and prolonged concentrations during&#xD;
      several weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date, there is no other bone substitute with antibiotics available in France. Two&#xD;
      prospective studies have shown that Cerament-G reduces the number of infectious recurrences&#xD;
      (about 5%).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This innovation is available in France but at a high price (between 2,500 and 4,000 euros)&#xD;
      and is not currently reimbursed. However, the use of this product would make it possible to&#xD;
      improve the health and quality of life of patients while avoiding certain consumption of&#xD;
      resources.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incremental Cost-Utility Ratio (ICUR) between the two treatments strategies for chronic long bone osteomyelitis</measure>
    <time_frame>At 24 months (M24)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrence of bone infection</measure>
    <time_frame>At 24 months (M24)</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with at least one recurrence of infection on the studied bone and time to recurrence. The Event Validation Committee will confirm the recurrence of infection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intraoperative and Postoperative complications</measure>
    <time_frame>From inclusion to 24 months (M24)</time_frame>
    <description>Number and types of intraoperative and postoperative complications up to 24 months (including fracture) according to CTCAE and Clavien-Dindo classifications; and proportion of patients with at least one complication during follow-up</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Repeated surgeries for complication</measure>
    <time_frame>From first surgery to 24 months (M24)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of repeat surgeries for complication up to 24 months; and proportion of patients who had at least one repeat surgery for complication during follow-up</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients with amputations</measure>
    <time_frame>At 24 months (M24)</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with amputation of the area containing the bone studied.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bone healing and bone remodelling/consolidation</measure>
    <time_frame>At 12 months (M12)</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with bone healing and proportion of patients with bone remodelling/consolidation, assessed from a standard radiograph (confirmed by the Event Validation Committee).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serious Adverse Events (SAEs) attributable to systemic antibiotic therapy.</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 3 months of the first intervention (M3)</time_frame>
    <description>Number and types of serious adverse events (SAEs) attributable to systemic antibiotic therapy following the first intervention; and proportion of patients with at least one SAE attributable to this systemic antibiotic therapy; within 3 months of the first intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acute renal failure</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 3 months of the first procedure (M3)</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with acute renal failure within 3 months of the first procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events related to the use of Cerament-G</measure>
    <time_frame>At 24 months (M24)</time_frame>
    <description>Cost of both strategies estimated at 24 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Real cost</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months (M24)</time_frame>
    <description>Real cost associated of a corticotomy procedure using Cerament-G</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Estimated utility</measure>
    <time_frame>At inclusion, at Week 4/Week 6, Month 3, Month 6, Month12, Month 18 and Month 24 (usual follow-up visits) as well as after each repeat surgery according to the same schedule</time_frame>
    <description>Estimated utility measured with the EQ-5D (EuroQol Group-5 dimensions) questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Estimated incremental cost-effectiveness ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>At 24 months (M24)</time_frame>
    <description>Estimated incremental cost-effectiveness ratio with no recurrence of infection as efficacy endpoint</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Budgetary impact analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months (M24)</time_frame>
    <description>Budgetary impact analysis carried out from the perspective of the French Health Insurance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">220</enrollment>
  <condition>Osteomyelitis Chronic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Innovative strategy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>usual medical and surgical care with corticotomy and use of a bone substitute (Cerament-G) delivering gentamicin locally (± skin and soft-tissue/muscle flap) and antibiotic therapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Reference strategy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Medico-surgical usual care with corticotomy (± skin and soft-tissue/muscle flap), and antibiotic therapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Corticotomy and use of the bone substitute : Cerament-G device.</intervention_name>
    <description>Corticotomy and Cerament-G device</description>
    <arm_group_label>Innovative strategy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Corticotomy</intervention_name>
    <description>Corticotomy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Reference strategy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with suspected chronic osteomyelitis (stage III of the Cierny-Mader&#xD;
             classification) of a long bone of the tibia, femur or humerus, at the diaphysis,&#xD;
             metaphysis or epiphysis, defined as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Supposed inoculation &gt; 3 months ;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  At least one of the following clinical signs at the suspected infected site:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Spontaneous or supporting pain ;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Presence of fistula;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Presence of serous or purulent flow;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Presence of bone exposure;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Local Inflammation;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Fever in the absence of any other explanation.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  At least one of the following radiological signs at the suspected infected site:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Bone reshaping with osteolysis or periosteal apposition;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Presence of intramedullary abscess (if MRI performed);&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Presence of a fistulous pathway to the intramedullary (if MRI performed);&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Presence of bone sequestration visible on CT scan (if CT scan performed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient in whom conventional surgical treatment of chronic osteomyelitis is possible,&#xD;
             with decortication and corticotomy with endomedullary curettage (to eradicate bone&#xD;
             sequestrums, reduce the inoculum, and identify the bacterium(s) involved) and&#xD;
             secondary intramedullary residual cavity;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient in whom 3 months of systemic antibiotic therapy post-operatively are planned;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If osteosynthetic material is present in the infection site, this material should be&#xD;
             considered preoperatively as completely removable during chronic osteomyelitis&#xD;
             surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient in whom a direct closure without tension is possible, or in whom a skin and&#xD;
             soft-tissue/muscle flap can be performed within 15 days after the initial surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female patient between 18 and 80 years of age;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who has given written informed consent to participate in the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Geographically stable patient;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient able to comply with follow-up visits, protocol schedule and therapeutic&#xD;
             treatment, according to investigator's judgement;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Affiliated patient or beneficiary of a social security system&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute hematogenic osteomyelitis (Cierny-Mader stage I) ;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cortical osteitis (Cierny-Mader stage II);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Septic pseudoarthrosis (Cierny-Mader stage IV);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient requiring an estimated skin and soft-tissue/muscle flap that cannot be done&#xD;
             within 15 days after surgery for the treatment of chronic osteomyelitis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Woman who is pregnant, nursing or who is considering becoming pregnant during the&#xD;
             study period;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient participating in another interventional study that could interfere with it;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient known to have hypersensitivity to aminoglycosides (especially gentamicin),&#xD;
             sulfites (including calcium sulfate) or calcium hydroxyapatite;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to the use of Cerament-G: severe myasthenia (class IV or higher&#xD;
             according to the MGFA classification), , severe renal insufficiency (creatinine&#xD;
             clearance &lt;30 mL/min according to the Cockcroft-Gault formula, or GFR &lt; 30&#xD;
             ml/min/1.73² according to the CKD-EPI or MDRDs equation or, dialysis patient),&#xD;
             pre-existing disorders of calcium metabolism (total plasma calcium (or total corrected&#xD;
             plasma calcium according to albuminemia) outside normal laboratory values);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with endocrine or metabolic disorders known to affect osteogenesis (e.g.,&#xD;
             Paget's disease, renal osteodystrophy, hyperthyroidism, parathyroid disorder,&#xD;
             Ehler-Danlos syndrome, osteogenesis imperfecta);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with one or more untreated malignant cancers, or undergoing radiotherapy or&#xD;
             chemotherapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patient protected by law, under guardianship or trusteeship.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tristan FERRY</last_name>
    <phone>+33 4 72 07 24 81</phone>
    <email>tristan.ferry@chu-lyon.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 18, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Bone infection</keyword>
  <keyword>chronic osteomyelitis</keyword>
  <keyword>bone substitute</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Osteomyelitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

