<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04808778</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>190203</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04808778</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Stroke Prevention in Young Adults With Sickle Cell Anemia</brief_title>
  <acronym>SPIYA</acronym>
  <official_title>Stroke Prevention in Young Adults With Sickle Cell Anemia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Aminu Kano Teaching Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Sickle cell disease (SCD) is the most common genetic disease, affecting about 25 million&#xD;
      people worldwide. Approximately 150,000 Nigerian children are born each year with sickle cell&#xD;
      disease (SCD), making it the country with the largest burden of SCD in the world. Recent&#xD;
      advancements in care for children with SCA have translated into improved survival of children&#xD;
      in both high and low-resource settings. However, more complications of SCD are seen in those&#xD;
      who survive to adulthood. Silent cerebral infarcts (SCI) and strokes are among the most&#xD;
      devastating complications of SCD, affecting 40% and 10% of children, respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall goal of this study is to extend the Investigator's successful capacity-building&#xD;
      effort in the assessment of neurological morbidity in children with SCD living in northern&#xD;
      Nigeria (Kano) to young adults with SCD living in the same region. About 50% of all adults&#xD;
      with SCD live in Nigeria. Despite the high prevalence of SCD in Africa, the neurological&#xD;
      morbidity is not well characterized, limiting opportunities for primary and secondary stroke&#xD;
      prevention strategies. At least 50% of young adults with sickle cell anemia (SCA), the most&#xD;
      severe form of the disease, will have SCIs and an estimated 10% will have strokes, based on&#xD;
      studies in high-resource settings. In high-resource settings, screening for abnormal&#xD;
      transcranial Doppler (TCD) velocities in children with SCA, coupled with regular blood&#xD;
      transfusion has resulted in a 92% reduction of relative risk for strokes. Despite this&#xD;
      effective strategy, regular blood transfusion therapy does not seem sustainable in&#xD;
      sub-Saharan Africa due to shortages and the risk of transfusion transmissible infections.&#xD;
      Additionally, there is a lack of evidence-based stroke prevention strategies in young adults&#xD;
      with SCA, either in the high-income or in low-resource settings. Based on the foregoing, the&#xD;
      Investigators propose to determine the prevalence of neurological injury (overt stroke,&#xD;
      transient ischemic attacks, and silent cerebral infarcts) in young adults at the transition&#xD;
      age from 16-25 years. The Investigators will also, for the first time, assess conventional&#xD;
      risk factors of stroke in the general population to determine whether a different prevention&#xD;
      strategy is required to reduce the incidence of neurological injury in this high-risk&#xD;
      population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Investigator's global hypothesis, to be tested eventually in an NIH-funded phase III&#xD;
      controlled trial, is that hydroxyurea at a fixed moderate dose of 20 mg/kg is safe and&#xD;
      effective for primary and secondary stroke prevention in young adults with SCA. Prior to&#xD;
      testing this global hypothesis, the Investigators must develop a multi-disciplinary team that&#xD;
      provides medical care for young adults with SCD and establish the clinical epidemiology of&#xD;
      neurological morbidity in this distinct age group. Building upon the existing research&#xD;
      platforms of ongoing NINDS-funded primary stroke prevention trials in Nigeria, the&#xD;
      Investigators are uniquely positioned to extend their stroke assessment and treatment to the&#xD;
      next sequential age group, young adults with SCA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The immediate goals of this project are 1) to estimate the prevalence of neurological&#xD;
      morbidity in young adults with SCA (R21 application to NIH); 2) to establish a prospective&#xD;
      cohort of young adults to determine the incidence of neurological morbidity, and 3) to&#xD;
      determine the safety and feasibility of fixed moderate dose of hydroxyurea therapy for&#xD;
      prevention of further neurological disease in young adults with SCA in Nigeria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The leadership of the current pediatric primary and secondary stroke prevention trials&#xD;
      (NCT01801423, NCT02560935, NCT02675790) in Nigeria will apply a similar effective strategy&#xD;
      used in the Investigator's previous pediatric NINDS-R21 and current pediatric NINDS-R01 to&#xD;
      estimate the prevalence and incidence of neurological morbidity in young adults with SCA.&#xD;
      Young adults with SCA have different stroke risk factors than children less than 16 years of&#xD;
      age with SCA, including risk factors for stroke seen in the general population resulting in&#xD;
      the need for age and disease-specific evidence-based management for primary and secondary&#xD;
      stroke prevention strategies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      the Investigators propose to enroll 350 participants with SCA between 16-25 years of age. The&#xD;
      Investigators believe this sample size is sufficient to estimate the prevalence of stroke and&#xD;
      SCI. This cohort will be followed for 12-18 months to determine the short-term incidence of&#xD;
      strokes and SCI. The Investigators do not intend to calculate a precise incidence of these&#xD;
      neurological injuries due to the short duration of the follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For young adults with SCIs, strokes, and elevated TCD measurements (based on the pediatric&#xD;
      threshold of abnormal ≥200 cm/s in the middle cerebral artery or terminal portion of the&#xD;
      internal carotid) the Investigators will initially offer regular blood transfusion therapy as&#xD;
      standard care. If they refuse, the Investigators will offer a dose of 20 mg/kg/day of&#xD;
      hydroxyurea for at least one year of therapy. The hydroxyurea will be supplied free of charge&#xD;
      with monthly follow-up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 17, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2029</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2029</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The prevalence of neurological morbidity in young adults with sickle cell anemia neurological examinations and MRA/MRI</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>To estimate the prevalence of neurological morbidity including SCIs, strokes, and cerebral vasculopathy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The prevalence of neurological morbidity in young adults with sickle cell anemia utilizing Transcranial Doppler (TCD) measurement</measure>
    <time_frame>2 year</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of patients with abnormal TCD velocity (&gt; 200 cm/s)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Conventional risk factors of stroke</measure>
    <time_frame>2 year</time_frame>
    <description>We will also screen the participants for conventional risk factors of stroke (hypertension, smoking, diabetes, obesity, renal disease, cardiomyopathy, and atrial fibrillation).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Long-term incidence of neurological morbidity in young adults with sickle cell anemia</measure>
    <time_frame>10 years</time_frame>
    <description>For this purpose, we will determine the long-term incidence rates of initial and recurrent infarcts in young adults with sickle cell anemia with repeat magnetic resonance imaging and magnetic resonance angiography (MRI/MRA), and transcranial Doppler (TCD) measurements, and neurological examinations ~ 1 to 1.5 years for at least 10 years after baseline evaluations.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Preliminary data for safety and feasibility of hydroxyurea therapy in young adults with sickle cell anemia</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>To collect the preliminary data necessary to establish a safety and feasibility study for fixed moderate dose hydroxyurea treatment (~ 20 mg/kg/day) of neurological morbidity in young adults with sickle cell anemia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">350</enrollment>
  <condition>Sickle Cell Disease</condition>
  <condition>Sickle Cell Anemia</condition>
  <condition>Stroke, Ischemic</condition>
  <condition>Silent Stroke</condition>
  <condition>Silent Cerebral Infarct</condition>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Participants with sickle cell anemia identified with neurological morbidity</arm_group_label>
    <description>Successful completion of screening procedures inclusive of 1.) Cerebral blood flow velocity greater than or equal to 200 cm/sec measured twice or 2.) At least one measurement greater than or equal to 220 cm/sec in the middle cerebral artery or 3.) Two TCD measurements above 190 cm/sec within a three-month interval;&#xD;
MRI showing cerebral infarcts with or without (based on Silent Cerebral Infarct Trial (SIT) criteria) neurological deficits on standard neurological examination;&#xD;
Informed consent from a participant (&gt; 18 years) or parent/legal guardian for participants (&lt; 18 years) and assent of the participant completed;&#xD;
Acceptance of hydroxyurea therapy for one year as standard care. After one year of therapy, the participant will have the option to continue therapy with follow-up visits to monitor adherence to therapy with his or her care provider.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Participants with sickle cell anemia identified to be without neurological morbidity</arm_group_label>
    <description>Successful completion of screening procedures inclusive of cerebral blood flow velocity less than or equal to 199 cm/sec in the middle cerebral artery;&#xD;
Normal MRI and MRA;&#xD;
No focal neurological deficit on standard neurological examination;&#xD;
Informed consent from a participant (&gt; 18 years), or parent/legal guardian for participants (&lt; 18 years) and assent from the participant;&#xD;
Agreement to be followed for at least one year in the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hydroxyurea therapy per standard care</intervention_name>
    <description>Moderate-dose of 20mg/kg/day</description>
    <arm_group_label>Participants with sickle cell anemia identified with neurological morbidity</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Hydrea</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        A total of 350 participants with sickle cell anemia between 16 through 25 years of age&#xD;
        living in northern Nigeria receiving care at the Aminu Kano Teaching Hospital in Kano&#xD;
        Nigeria.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with hemoglobin S-S or Sβ0 thalassemia confirmed by hemoglobin&#xD;
             electrophoresis or High-Performance Liquid Chromatography (HPLC);&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participant is 16 through 25 years of age;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Informed consent from participants above 18 years, and informed consent from a parent&#xD;
             or legal guardian and assent of participants aged &lt; 18 years (assessment can take&#xD;
             place up until the 26th birthday);&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participant resides within an hour driving distance from the medical center to&#xD;
             facilitate weekly phone calls between the scheduled monthly clinic visits;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participant is willing to be enrolled and followed for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Young adults with co-morbidities that may have an impact on neurological status, such&#xD;
             as epilepsy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Young adults enrolled in clinical trials upon entry;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participants with an implanted defibrillator or certain other implanted electronic or&#xD;
             metallic devices contraindicated for MRI;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Young adults with known HIV diagnosis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any other condition or chronic illness, which in the opinion of the site's Principal&#xD;
             Investigator (PI) makes participation ill-advised or unsafe.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>26 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael R DeBaun, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Michael R DeBaun, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>(615) 936-1762</phone>
    <email>m.debaun@vumc.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Djamila L Ghafuri, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <email>djamila.labib@vumc.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37232-9000</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michael R. DeBaun, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>615-875-3040</phone>
      <phone_ext>5-3040</phone_ext>
      <email>m.debaun@vumc.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Djamila L Ghafuri, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <email>djamila.labib@vumc.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aminu Kano Teaching Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kano</city>
        <country>Nigeria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jamil Galadanci, MS</last_name>
      <phone>+2348035993379</phone>
      <email>jamilgaladanci@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jamil Galadanci, MS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Nigeria</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 17, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michael DeBaun</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor, Vice Chair for Clinical and Translational Research</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>sickle cell anemia</keyword>
  <keyword>stroke prevention</keyword>
  <keyword>low-resource setting</keyword>
  <keyword>silent cerebral infarct</keyword>
  <keyword>northern Nigeria</keyword>
  <keyword>young adults</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ischemic Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cerebral Infarction</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hydroxyurea</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

