<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04802161</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCI-2021-01961</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2021-01961</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>10434</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>10434</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>UM1CA186712</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04802161</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparing the Addition of an Anti-Cancer Drug, Pomalidomide, to the Usual Chemotherapy Treatment (CPX-351) in Newly Diagnosed Acute Myeloid Leukemia With Myelodysplastic Syndrome-Related Changes</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized Phase 2 Study of CPX-351 + Pomalidomide Versus CPX-351 in Newly Diagnosed AML With MDS-Related Changes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase II trial studies the effect of adding pomalidomide to usual chemotherapy treatment&#xD;
      (CPX-351) in treating patients with newly diagnosed acute leukemia with myelodysplastic&#xD;
      syndrome-related changes. Pomalidomide may stop the growth of blood vessels, stimulate the&#xD;
      immune system, and kill cancer cells. Chemotherapy drugs, such as CPX-351, work in different&#xD;
      ways to stop the growth of cancer cells, either by killing the cells, by stopping them from&#xD;
      dividing, or by stopping them from spreading. Adding pomalidomide to chemotherapy treatment&#xD;
      with CPX-351 may be effective in improving some treatment outcomes in patients with newly&#xD;
      diagnosed acute leukemia with myelodysplastic syndrome-related changes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To compare the rate of overall complete response (CR)/complete response with incomplete&#xD;
      hematologic recovery (CRi) with liposome-encapsulated daunorubicin-cytarabine (CPX-351) +&#xD;
      pomalidomide versus CPX-351 alone in newly diagnosed scute myeloid leukemia (AML) with&#xD;
      preexisting myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS), chronic myelomonocytic leukemia (CMML), or&#xD;
      myeloproliferative neoplasm (MPN); therapy-related AML (t-AML); or AML with&#xD;
      myelodysplasia-related changes (MRC) based on cytogenetics or morphologic dysplasia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate and compare rates of CR (full hematologic recovery) between CPX-351 +&#xD;
      pomalidomide versus CPX-351 alone in newly diagnosed AML with preexisting MDS, CMML or MPN,&#xD;
      t-AML or AML with MRC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To evaluate and compare toxicities (including treatment-related mortality) of CPX-351 +&#xD;
      pomalidomide versus CPX-351 alone in newly diagnosed AML with preexisting MDS, CMML or MPN,&#xD;
      t-AML, or AML with MRC based on cytogenetics or morphologic dysplasia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To detect and compare the presence of minimal residual disease (MRD) by flow cytometry&#xD;
      in those who achieve CR/CRi with CPX-351 + pomalidomide versus CPX-351 alone in newly&#xD;
      diagnosed AML with preexisting MDS, CMML or MPN, t-AML, or AML with MRC based on cytogenetics&#xD;
      or morphologic dysplasia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To compare median event-free survival (EFS) of CPX-351 + pomalidomide versus CPX-351&#xD;
      alone in newly diagnosed AML with preexisting MDS, CMML or MPN, t-AML, or AML with MRC based&#xD;
      on cytogenetics or morphologic dysplasia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      V. To compare median overall survival (OS) of CPX-351 + pomalidomide versus CPX-351 alone in&#xD;
      newly diagnosed AML with preexisting MDS, CMML or MPN, t-AML, or AML with MRC based on&#xD;
      cytogenetics or morphologic dysplasia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VI. To compare median and 2-year disease-free survival (DFS) after CR/CRi with CPX-351 +&#xD;
      pomalidomide versus CPX-351 alone in newly diagnosed AML with preexisting MDS, CMML or MPN,&#xD;
      t-AML, or AML with MRC based on cytogenetics or morphologic dysplasia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VII. To compare rates of allogeneic stem cell transplant (SCT) after CPX-351 + pomalidomide&#xD;
      versus CPX-351 alone in newly diagnosed AML with preexisting MDS, CMML or MPN, t-AML, or AML&#xD;
      with MRC based on cytogenetics or morphologic dysplasia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To assess for molecular biomarkers, Aiolos expression, and immune correlates of response&#xD;
      with CPX-351 + pomalidomide versus CPX-351 alone in newly diagnosed AML with preexisting MDS,&#xD;
      CMML or MPN, t-AML, or AML with MRC based on cytogenetics or morphologic dysplasia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To assess for differences in MRD by molecular based platforms in CPX-351 + pomalidomide&#xD;
      versus CPX-351 alone in newly diagnosed AML with preexisting MDS, CMML or MPN, t-AML, or AML&#xD;
      with MRC based on cytogenetics or morphologic dysplasia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM A:&#xD;
&#xD;
      INDUCTION: Patients receive liposome-encapsulated daunorubicin-cytarabine intravenously (IV)&#xD;
      over 90 minutes on days 1, 3, and 5 and then pomalidomide orally (PO) once daily (QD)&#xD;
      beginning between days 21-30 for 21 days in the absence of disease progression or&#xD;
      unacceptable toxicity. Patients who do not respond, may receive a second cycle of&#xD;
      liposome-encapsulated daunorubicin-cytarabine IV over 90 minutes on days 1 and 3 in the&#xD;
      absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CONSOLIDATION: Patients who achieve CR/CRi receive liposome-encapsulated&#xD;
      daunorubicin-cytarabine IV over 90 minutes on days 1 and 3. Treatment repeats every 21 days&#xD;
      for 2 cycles in the absence of disease progression and unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM B:&#xD;
&#xD;
      INDUCTION: Patients receive liposome-encapsulated daunorubicin-cytarabine intravenously (IV)&#xD;
      over 90 minutes on days 1, 3, and 5 in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable&#xD;
      toxicity. Patients who do not respond, may receive a second cycle of liposome-encapsulated&#xD;
      daunorubicin-cytarabine IV over 90 minutes on days 1 and 3 in the absence of disease&#xD;
      progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CONSOLIDATION: Patients who achieve CR/CRi receive liposome-encapsulated&#xD;
      daunorubicin-cytarabine IV over 90 minutes on days 1 and 3. Treatment repeats every 21 days&#xD;
      for 2 cycles in the absence of disease progression and unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 30 days, then up to 5&#xD;
      years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Suspended</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Other - Clinical hold&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 16, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of complete response (CR)/complete response with incomplete hematologic recovery (CRi)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days after last dose</time_frame>
    <description>Will be assessed by Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version (v.) 5.0 and compared descriptively between Arms A and B.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete response (CR) without minimal residual disease (MRD)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will assess CR without MRD by flow cytometry via Hematologics, Inc. compare descriptively between Arms A and B.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Event-free survival (EFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From day 1 of liposome-encapsulated daunorubicin-cytarabine (CPX-351) until no response is achieved, relapse or death, assessed up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be compared between Arms A and B.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From randomization until death or last follow-up, assessed up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be compared between Arms A and B.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of allogeneic stem cell transplantation</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be compared between Arms A and B.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">78</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Myeloid Leukemia</condition>
  <condition>Acute Myeloid Leukemia With Multilineage Dysplasia</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Myelomonocytic Leukemia</condition>
  <condition>Myelodysplastic Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Myeloproliferative Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Therapy-Related Acute Myeloid Leukemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A (CPX-351, pomalidomide)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>INDUCTION: Patients receive liposome-encapsulated daunorubicin-cytarabine IV over 90 minutes on days 1, 3, and 5 and then pomalidomide PO QD beginning between days 21-30 for 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients who do not respond, may receive a second cycle of liposome-encapsulated daunorubicin-cytarabine IV over 90 minutes on days 1 and 3 in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
CONSOLIDATION: Patients who achieve CR/CRi receive liposome-encapsulated daunorubicin-cytarabine IV over 90 minutes on days 1 and 3. Treatment repeats every 21 days for 2 cycles in the absence of disease progression and unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B (CPX-351)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>INDUCTION: Patients receive liposome-encapsulated daunorubicin-cytarabine intravenously (IV) over 90 minutes on days 1, 3, and 5 in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients who do not respond, may receive a second cycle of liposome-encapsulated daunorubicin-cytarabine IV over 90 minutes on days 1 and 3 in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
CONSOLIDATION: Patients who achieve CR/CRi receive liposome-encapsulated daunorubicin-cytarabine IV over 90 minutes on days 1 and 3. Treatment repeats every 21 days for 2 cycles in the absence of disease progression and unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Liposome-encapsulated Daunorubicin-Cytarabine</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A (CPX-351, pomalidomide)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B (CPX-351)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CPX-351</other_name>
    <other_name>Cytarabine-Daunorubicin Liposome for Injection</other_name>
    <other_name>Daunorubicin and Cytarabine (Liposomal)</other_name>
    <other_name>Liposomal AraC-Daunorubicin CPX-351</other_name>
    <other_name>Liposomal Cytarabine-Daunorubicin</other_name>
    <other_name>Liposome-encapsulated Combination of Daunorubicin and Cytarabine</other_name>
    <other_name>Vyxeos</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pomalidomide</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A (CPX-351, pomalidomide)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B (CPX-351)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>4-Aminothalidomide</other_name>
    <other_name>Actimid</other_name>
    <other_name>CC-4047</other_name>
    <other_name>Imnovid</other_name>
    <other_name>Pomalyst</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pathological confirmation of AML as defined by histologic, morphologic, or cytological&#xD;
             evidence/confirmation of &gt;= 20% blasts in bone marrow aspirate and/or biopsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must meet criteria for t-AML or AML with MRC as defined by one of the following&#xD;
             features:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Therapy-related AML (AML derived from prior chemotherapy or radiation therapy)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AML originating from prior hematologic malignancy (MDS, CMML, or MPN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  World Health Organization (WHO)-defined AML with MRC which is defined by meeting&#xD;
                  one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Morphologic detection of multilineage dysplasia defined as &gt;= 50% dysplastic&#xD;
                       cells in at least 2 lineages from bone marrow aspirate and/or biopsy without&#xD;
                       NPM1 or biallelic CEBPA mutations&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  One of the following cytogenetic abnormalities:&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  Complex karyotype (3 or more chromosomal abnormalities)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  -7/del(7q)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  Del(5q)/t(5q)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  i(17q)/t(17p)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  -13/del(13q)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  Del(11q)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  Del(12p)/t(12p)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  idicX(q13)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  t(11;16)(q23.3;p13.3)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  t(3;21)(q26.2;q22.1)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  t(1;3)(p36.3;q21.2)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  t(2;11)(p21;q23.3)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  t(5;12)(q32;p13.2)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  t(5;7)(q32;q11.2)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  t(5;17)(q32;p13.2)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  t(5;10)(q32;q21.2)&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  t(3;5)(q25.3;q35.1)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No prior treatment for AML other than cytoreductive doses of hydroxyurea or&#xD;
             leukapheresis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;= 18 and =&lt; 75 years on day of signing informed consent are eligible who are&#xD;
             planned for intensive chemotherapy. Because no dosing or adverse event data are&#xD;
             currently available on the use of pomalidomide in combination with CPX-351 in patients&#xD;
             &lt; 18 years of age, children are excluded from this study. Patients &gt; 75 years are not&#xD;
             candidates for intensive chemotherapy with CPX-351&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0-2 (Karnofsky &gt;= 60%)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) unless due to&#xD;
             leukemic infiltration, Gilbert's Syndrome, or hemolysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (serum glutamic-oxaloacetic transaminase&#xD;
             [SGOT])/alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase [SGPT[)&#xD;
             =&lt; 5 x institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine &gt;= 30 ml/min creatinine clearance by Cockcroft-gault&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &gt;= 50%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-infected patients on effective anti-retroviral&#xD;
             therapy with undetectable viral load within 6 months are eligible for this trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For patients with evidence of chronic hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection, the HBV viral&#xD;
             load must be undetectable on suppressive therapy, if indicated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection must have been treated&#xD;
             and cured with undetectable HCV viral load. For patients with HCV infection who are&#xD;
             currently on treatment, they are eligible if they have an undetectable HCV viral load&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known history or current symptoms of cardiac disease, or history of&#xD;
             treatment with cardiotoxic agents, should have a clinical risk assessment of cardiac&#xD;
             function using the New York Heart Association Functional Classification. To be&#xD;
             eligible for this trial, patients should be class 2B or better&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of childbearing potential (FCBP), defined as a female who: 1) has reached&#xD;
             menarche at some point, 2) has not undergone a hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy;&#xD;
             or 3) has not been naturally postmenopausal for at least 24 consecutive months (i.e.,&#xD;
             has had menses at any time in the preceding 24 consecutive months) must have a&#xD;
             negative pregnancy test 72 hours prior to the start of study therapy. For FCBPs in Arm&#xD;
             A, they must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test with a sensitivity of at&#xD;
             least 25 mIU/mL within 10 - 14 days prior to and again within 24 hours of starting&#xD;
             pomalidomide and must either commit to continued abstinence from heterosexual&#xD;
             intercourse or begin TWO acceptable methods of birth control, one highly effective&#xD;
             method and one additional effective method AT THE SAME TIME, at least 28 days before&#xD;
             starting pomalidomide. FCBP must also agree to ongoing pregnancy testing. Men must&#xD;
             agree to use a latex condom during sexual contact with a FCBP even if they have had a&#xD;
             vasectomy. All patients must be counseled at a minimum of every 28 days about&#xD;
             pregnancy precautions and risks of fetal exposure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
             Participants with impaired decision-making capacity (IDMC) who have a&#xD;
             legally-authorized representative (LAR) and/or family member available will also be&#xD;
             eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with Wilson's Disease or Copper-related metabolic disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute blast count &gt; 30 x 10^9/L (cytoreduction with leukapheresis, hydroxyurea, or&#xD;
             cyclophosphamide can be used to achieve absolute blast count &lt; 30 x 10^9/L prior to&#xD;
             day 1 of treatment). If cyclophosphamide is used for cytoreduction, day 1 of treatment&#xD;
             should occur 7 +/- 2 days after cyclophosphamide administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cumulative daunorubicin lifetime exposure &gt; 330 mg/m^2 and &gt; 180 mg/m^2 with prior&#xD;
             mediastinal radiation therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known active central nervous system leukemia should be excluded from&#xD;
             this clinical trial because they often develop progressive neurologic dysfunction that&#xD;
             would confound the evaluation of neurologic and other adverse events. Patients&#xD;
             receiving intrathecal chemotherapy prophylaxis should receive pomalidomide &gt;= 3 days&#xD;
             after administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, active&#xD;
             and uncontrolled infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina&#xD;
             pectoris, and cardiac arrhythmia. Patients with infection under active treatment and&#xD;
             controlled with antibiotics are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known additional malignancy (with the exception of prior hematologic malignancies that&#xD;
             have transformed to AML) that is active and/or progressive requiring treatment;&#xD;
             exceptions include basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, in situ cervical cancer or&#xD;
             patients receiving maintenance treatments without active disease (for example,&#xD;
             hormonal therapy for breast cancer or prostate cancer or other adjuvant chemotherapy&#xD;
             approaches). Anti-cancer therapy as above should be discontinued &gt; 72 hours prior to&#xD;
             Day 1 of treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with&#xD;
             study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of prior allogeneic stem cell transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Administration of any therapy for MDS, CMML, or MPN (conventional or unconventional)&#xD;
             must be completed by 2 weeks prior to treatment with CPX-351. Use of strong CYP1A2&#xD;
             inhibitors should be avoided&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are receiving any other investigational agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to pomalidomide (e.g. lenalidomide, thalidomide) or CPX-351 or their&#xD;
             excipients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Development of erythema nodosum if characterized by a desquamating rash while taking&#xD;
             thalidomide, lenalidomide, or similar drugs in the past&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women are excluded from this study because pomalidomide is an&#xD;
             immunomodulatory agent with the potential for teratogenic or abortifacient effects.&#xD;
             Because there is an unknown but potential risk for adverse events in nursing infants&#xD;
             secondary to treatment of the mother with pomalidomide, breastfeeding should be&#xD;
             discontinued if the mother is treated with pomalidomide. These potential risks may&#xD;
             also apply to other agents used in this study. Women of childbearing potential must be&#xD;
             willing to undergo pregnancy testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other medical condition that in the opinion of investigator would place patient at&#xD;
             increased risk for toxicity during pomalidomide treatment (i.e. history of recurrent&#xD;
             or serious thromboembolic events such as massive pulmonary embolism)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joshua F Zeidner</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ohio State University Comprehensive Cancer Center LAO</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ohio State University Comprehensive Cancer Center LAO</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelomonocytic, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelomonocytic, Juvenile</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myeloproliferative Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cytarabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Daunorubicin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pomalidomide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>NCI is committed to sharing data in accordance with NIH policy. For more details on how clinical trial data is shared, access the link to the NIH data sharing policy page.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://grants.nih.gov/policy/sharing.htm</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

