<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04804163</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>QYFYEC 2020-012-02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04804163</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Research on the Effectiveness and Safety of Remote Control of Domestic Surgical Robot System for Urinary Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Research on the Effectiveness and Safety of Remote Surgery of Domestic Surgical Robot System for Urinary System Diseases</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      One-arm clinical trial was adopted in this study. The surgeon performed remote urological&#xD;
      surgery for patients through domestically produced &quot;MicroHand&quot; surgical robot system&#xD;
      (Shandong Weigao Co., Ltd). The &quot;MicroHand&quot; surgical robot system consists of two physically&#xD;
      separated subsystems named the &quot;surgeon console&quot; and &quot;patient side cart&quot;. The surgeon console&#xD;
      includes a stereo image viewer, two master manipulators, a control panel and several foot&#xD;
      pedals. The patient side cart includes a passive arm that can slide in the up-down direction&#xD;
      and be adjusted forward and backward, a swivel head that can rotate around the vertical axis,&#xD;
      and three slave arms (one for the endoscopic camera and the other two for surgical&#xD;
      instruments). The surgeon console (based in Qingdao) takes the surgeon's input and translates&#xD;
      manipulation into a control signal. After network transmission, the patient side cart (based&#xD;
      in other cities in Shandong Province) translates the control signal into actual instrument&#xD;
      manipulation. The 3D images captured by the endoscopic camera were simultaneously sent back&#xD;
      to the screen of the surgeon console as visual feedback. Data between the surgeon console and&#xD;
      the patient side cart were transmitted through a 5G network. The safety and effectiveness of&#xD;
      the robotic system in remote clinical diagnosis and treatment were verified by the main&#xD;
      judgment criterion and secondary judgment criterion. Thirty patients with urinary diseases&#xD;
      are planned to enroll in the clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main judgment criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The robot-assisted telesurgery did not transfer to other types of surgery, such as open&#xD;
      surgery or normal robot-assisted surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary judgment criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
      operative time, blood loss, postoperative pain, preoperative adjusting time and&#xD;
      hospitalization time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient enrollment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This trial aims to explore the safety and effectiveness of the domestically produced robotic&#xD;
      system in remote clinical diagnosis and treatment through 5G network. Thirty patients are&#xD;
      planned to enroll in the clinical trial, including 15 patients with adreanl tumor, 5 patients&#xD;
      with nonfunctional kidney and 10 patients with renal cell carcinoma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objective： This clinical trial aims to evaluate the efficacy and safety of telesurgery for&#xD;
      patients with tumors of the urinary system using Chinese independently developed &quot;MicroHand&quot;&#xD;
      Surgical Robot System through 5G network.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Content： One-arm clinical trial was adopted in this study. The product was domestically&#xD;
      produced &quot;MicroHand&quot; surgical robot system (Shandong Weigao Co., Ltd). Before entering the&#xD;
      clinical study, the patients were fully informed and the written informed consent were&#xD;
      signed. According to the inclusion criteria and exclusion criteria, the researchers will&#xD;
      conduct a detailed screening to determine whether the patients are suitable for the clinical&#xD;
      study. Telesurgery would be conducted for patients who met the inclusion criteria using&#xD;
      &quot;MicroHand&quot; surgical robot system. Data between the surgeon console and the patient side cart&#xD;
      were transmitted through a 5G network. The safety and efficacy of the robotic system in&#xD;
      remote clinical diagnosis and treatment were verified according to the main judgment&#xD;
      criterion and secondary judgment criterion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background：With the combination of robotic and network communication technology, telesurgery&#xD;
      has become a reality. On the one hand, telesurgery can conserve and optimize medical&#xD;
      resources, providing high-quality medical services to unbalanced areas, such as rural areas,&#xD;
      stricken areas and battlefields. On the other hand, telesurgery can reduce the time spent by&#xD;
      patients waiting for treatment and thus prevent diseases from worsening.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The unbalanced distribution of medical resources has been a prominent problem in China. In&#xD;
      addition, the vast territory and relatively lower medical distribution ratio per capita make&#xD;
      it difficult for patients to receive timely and high-quality treatment, especially those in&#xD;
      remote and underdeveloped areas. Therefore, telesurgery is more significant in China. In&#xD;
      recent years, surgical robot systems and network communication technology have experienced&#xD;
      breakthroughs. The operation systems of the da Vinci robot in America, the REVO-I robot in&#xD;
      South Korea and the ALF-X robot in Italy are more flexible and intelligent, performing well&#xD;
      in surgical procedures. The &quot;Micro Hand S&quot; system robot, independently developed in China,&#xD;
      represets a new generation of surgical robot systems. In addition to the flexible and&#xD;
      intelligent characteristics of traditional robots, the robot has a series of advantages, such&#xD;
      as a clear interface, light weight, low cost in terms of use and maintenance, and strong&#xD;
      equipment compatibility. After preliminary experiments, the domestically produced robot has&#xD;
      been successfully applied in clinical surgery. Meanwhile, in the field of network&#xD;
      communication, the emerging 5G mobile communication technology (the 5th generation of&#xD;
      wireless systems, 5G technology for short) is the latest generation of cellular mobile&#xD;
      communication technology. 5G technology is also an extension of 4G (LTE-A or WiMax), 3G (UMTS&#xD;
      or LTE) and 2G (GSM) technology. 5G technology has a high data rate, low latency, high&#xD;
      throughput, equipment connection on a large scale, low cost and low energy consumption. The&#xD;
      emergence of 5G technology offers more opportunities for the prevalence of telesurgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In September 2020, our research group carried out the first 5G remote telesurgery using the&#xD;
      &quot;Micro Hand S&quot; system robot and a 5G network between Qingdao, Shandong Province, and Xixiu,&#xD;
      Guizhou Province, in September 2019 in China (the network communication distance was nearly&#xD;
      3000 km). Specifically, the investigators conducted radical cystectomy on a male patient. The&#xD;
      5G network (Plan A) was used throughout the operation, with an average total delay of 254ms&#xD;
      (including an average round-trip delay of 104ms and a packet loss rate of 0%). The operation&#xD;
      time was about 5 hours, the intraoperative bleeding was about 200ml, and no intraoperative&#xD;
      complications occurred. The patient recovered smoothly after the operation and was discharged&#xD;
      on the 18th day. The investigators demonstrated that ultra-remote laparoscopic telesurgery&#xD;
      can be performed safely and smoothly under the 5G network using domestically produced&#xD;
      equipment. On such basis, our research group planned to carry out this clinical trial with&#xD;
      more patients to evaluate the efficacy and safety of telesurgery for patients with tumors of&#xD;
      the urinary system using Chinese independently developed &quot;MicroHand&quot; Surgical Robot System&#xD;
      through 5G network.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Introduction of the &quot;MicroHand&quot; surgical robot： The &quot;MicroHand&quot; surgical robot system&#xD;
      consists of two physically separated subsystems named the &quot;surgeon console&quot; and &quot;patient side&#xD;
      cart&quot;. The surgeon console includes a stereo image viewer, two master manipulators, a control&#xD;
      panel and several foot pedals. The patient side cart includes a passive arm that can slide in&#xD;
      the up-down direction and be adjusted forward and backward, a swivel head that can rotate&#xD;
      around the vertical axis, and three slave arms (one for the endoscopic camera and the other&#xD;
      two for surgical instruments). The surgeon console (based in Qingdao) takes the surgeon's&#xD;
      input and translates manipulation into a control signal. After network transmission, the&#xD;
      patient side cart (based in Anshun) translates the control signal into actual instrument&#xD;
      manipulation. The 3D images captured by the endoscopic camera were simultaneously sent back&#xD;
      to the screen of the surgeon console as visual feedback.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Steps of the procedure：&#xD;
&#xD;
      ① The surgeon console was placed in Qingdao, Shangdong Province, while the patient side cart&#xD;
      was placed in other cities in Shandong Province.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ② Connections between the surgeon console and the patient side cart were established through&#xD;
      a public 5G wireless network. Special 5G customer premise equipment (CPE) was used as a&#xD;
      signal repeater station and amplifier. Upload and download speed will be tested as network&#xD;
      bandwidth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ③ After general anesthesia, the supine position was maintained, the surgical area was&#xD;
      disinfected, and pneumoperitoneum was established from the left side of the umbilicus by&#xD;
      using a Veress needle. Then, trocars were inserted, and slave arms were delivered. Slave arm&#xD;
      A was equipped with robotic grasp pliers, and Slave arm C was equipped with an ultrasonic&#xD;
      scalpel (bipolar pliers or electrocautery). Robot-assisted telesurgeries, including&#xD;
      adrenalectomy and nephrectomy, were performed by a surgeon from the departments of urology.&#xD;
      The surgeon in Qingdao performed the dissection and coagulation of the target organs, while&#xD;
      assistants in other cities performed exposure of structures and clip application. Trocar&#xD;
      placement and position of the patients were also adjusted in each telesurgery by the&#xD;
      assistants if necessary. After completion of the dissection, the target organs were removed&#xD;
      by the assistant bedside. Then the pneumoperitoneum was exsufflated and the incisions were&#xD;
      closed. Intraoperative network latencies and vital signs were monitored constantly. The&#xD;
      master-slave manipulation consistency was assessed subjectively. The operative time, blood&#xD;
      loss and complications were recorded.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>success rate of the telesurgery</measure>
    <time_frame>after the study is completed, up to 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>The success of the telesurgery is the robot-assisted telesurgery did not transfer to other types of surgery， such as open surgery or normal robot-assisted surgery. The number of the success divided by the total number is the success rate.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>operative time</measure>
    <time_frame>after the procedure is completed, all data will be collected within 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>duration of each surgery</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>blood loss</measure>
    <time_frame>after the procedure is completed, all data will be collected within 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>blood loss of each surgery</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>latency time</measure>
    <time_frame>during the whole procedure, all data will be collected within 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Mechanical response delay of the robot, endoscope imaging and image processing delay plus video codec delay equals the total delay.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>from admission to discharge for each patients, all data will be collected within 5 months</time_frame>
    <description>time from admission to discharge</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Renal Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Adrenal Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Nonfunctioning Kidney</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Upper urinary tract disease group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with upper urinary diseases (renal cell carcinoma, adrenal tumor and nonfunctioning kidney) will be treated by telesurgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>telesurgery by domestic robot</intervention_name>
    <description>telesurgery of the upper urinary disease by domestic robot</description>
    <arm_group_label>Upper urinary tract disease group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA class I-III&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI: 18-30Kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  adrenal tumors that need adrenalectomy (hormonally active or grow more than 1cm during&#xD;
             annual evaluation； other benign adrenal tumors)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with Robson Stage I or II renal cell carcinoma that need radical nephrectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with nonfunctioning kidney that need radical nephrectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  women during pregnancy or lactation period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with uncontrolled hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with a history of epilepsy or psychosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with severe cardiovascular disease (NYHA, grade III-IV)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with cerebrovascular disease (CVD)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with other diseases that cannot tolerate surgery&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Qingdao</city>
        <state>Shandong</state>
        <zip>266003</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Haitao Niu, MD</last_name>
      <phone>18661803117</phone>
      <email>niuht0532@126.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nguan C, Miller B, Patel R, Luke PP, Schlachta CM. Pre-clinical remote telesurgery trial of a da Vinci telesurgery prototype. Int J Med Robot. 2008 Dec;4(4):304-9. doi: 10.1002/rcs.210.</citation>
    <PMID>18803341</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sterbis JR, Hanly EJ, Herman BC, Marohn MR, Broderick TJ, Shih SP, Harnett B, Doarn C, Schenkman NS. Transcontinental telesurgical nephrectomy using the da Vinci robot in a porcine model. Urology. 2008 May;71(5):971-3. doi: 10.1016/j.urology.2007.11.027. Epub 2008 Mar 4.</citation>
    <PMID>18295861</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Clayman RV. Transatlantic robot-assisted telesurgery. J Urol. 2002 Aug;168(2):873-4.</citation>
    <PMID>12136861</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Marescaux J, Leroy J, Rubino F, Smith M, Vix M, Simone M, Mutter D. Transcontinental robot-assisted remote telesurgery: feasibility and potential applications. Ann Surg. 2002 Apr;235(4):487-92.</citation>
    <PMID>11923603</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Garcia P, Rosen J, Kapoor C, Noakes M, Elbert G, Treat M, Ganous T, Hanson M, Manak J, Hasser C, Rohler D, Satava R. Trauma Pod: a semi-automated telerobotic surgical system. Int J Med Robot. 2009 Jun;5(2):136-46. doi: 10.1002/rcs.238.</citation>
    <PMID>19222048</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lefranc M, Peltier J. Evaluation of the ROSA™ Spine robot for minimally invasive surgical procedures. Expert Rev Med Devices. 2016 Oct;13(10):899-906. Epub 2016 Sep 30.</citation>
    <PMID>27649314</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Abdel Raheem A, Troya IS, Kim DK, Kim SH, Won PD, Joon PS, Hyun GS, Rha KH. Robot-assisted Fallopian tube transection and anastomosis using the new REVO-I robotic surgical system: feasibility in a chronic porcine model. BJU Int. 2016 Oct;118(4):604-9. doi: 10.1111/bju.13517. Epub 2016 May 26.</citation>
    <PMID>27123543</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fanfani F, Monterossi G, Fagotti A, Rossitto C, Gueli Alletti S, Costantini B, Gallotta V, Selvaggi L, Restaino S, Scambia G. The new robotic TELELAP ALF-X in gynecological surgery: single-center experience. Surg Endosc. 2016 Jan;30(1):215-21. doi: 10.1007/s00464-015-4187-9. Epub 2015 Apr 4.</citation>
    <PMID>25840895</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Moglia A, Ferrari V, Morelli L, Ferrari M, Mosca F, Cuschieri A. A Systematic Review of Virtual Reality Simulators for Robot-assisted Surgery. Eur Urol. 2016 Jun;69(6):1065-80. doi: 10.1016/j.eururo.2015.09.021. Epub 2015 Oct 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26433570</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yi B, Wang G, Li J, Jiang J, Son Z, Su H, Zhu S, Wang S. Domestically produced Chinese minimally invasive surgical robot system &quot;Micro Hand S&quot; is applied to clinical surgery preliminarily in China. Surg Endosc. 2017 Jan;31(1):487-493. doi: 10.1007/s00464-016-4945-3. Epub 2016 May 18.</citation>
    <PMID>27194259</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yi B, Wang G, Li J, Jiang J, Son Z, Su H, Zhu S. The first clinical use of domestically produced Chinese minimally invasive surgical robot system &quot;Micro Hand S&quot;. Surg Endosc. 2016 Jun;30(6):2649-55. doi: 10.1007/s00464-015-4506-1. Epub 2015 Aug 21.</citation>
    <PMID>26293795</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 15, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 18, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Haitao Niu, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor Haitao Niu (the department of Urology)</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adrenal Gland Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

