<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00571311</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>080032</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>08-CC-0032</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00571311</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Parental Permission and Adolescent Assent and Decision-Making in Clinical Research</brief_title>
  <official_title>Parental Permission and Adolescent Assent and Decision Making in Clinical Research</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will evaluate how adolescents enrolled in clinical research and their parents:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Understood the study information presented before they agreed to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Made decisions about enrolling in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Experienced the process of assent and consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Perceive the experience of participating in research&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will determine how adolescents and their parents evaluate risk and benefit, what&#xD;
      information they use in making their research enrollment decisions, and how these decisions&#xD;
      are made.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In recent years the medical community and the federal government have increasingly recognized&#xD;
      the need to conduct pediatric research. Several initiatives have resulted in an expanding&#xD;
      number of studies that include children. With more pediatric research comes the need to&#xD;
      ensure that protections for the rights and safety of children enrolled in research are&#xD;
      performing well.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adolescent patients between 13 and 18 years of age who are enrolled in a research study at&#xD;
      the NIH involving cancer, diabetes mellitus, vaccines, obesity, bipolar disorder, and HIV, as&#xD;
      well as healthy adolescent controls, may be eligible. One parent of each adolescent also&#xD;
      participates.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants are interviewed at the NIH Clinical Center. Each interview will last about 30&#xD;
      minutes and consists of questions in the following areas:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Demographics (age, sex, ethnicity, education, socioeconomic status, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Brief medical history of the adolescent&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Experience and satisfaction with the parental permission/assent process&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Motivations for participating in clinical research&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Decision-making process&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Willingness to accept certain types and levels of hypothetical risks in a study,&#xD;
           including those of side effects and invasive procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Willingness to enroll with different chances of possible benefit&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Comparison with other activities&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  General understanding of research&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to better understand how adolescents enrolled in clinical research and their&#xD;
      parents understood the study information presented, made decisions about enrolling,&#xD;
      experienced the process of assent and consent, and perceive the experience of participating&#xD;
      in research. Interviews will be conducted with adolescents participating in clinical research&#xD;
      and with one of their parents. Adolescents with a number of disorders including cancer,&#xD;
      chronic diseases, bipolar disorder, obesity, and HIV, as well as healthy controls who are&#xD;
      enrolled in NIH intramural protocols will be interviewed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 10, 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date>March 12, 2018</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Actual">356</enrollment>
  <condition>Adolescents</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria- Adolescent:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 13 to 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Currently enrolled in clinical research.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Gave assent to participate in the primary study within the previous 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Physically and cognitively able and willing to participate in a 30-minute interview.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Able to understand and speak English or Spanish.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria- Parents:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Parent of an eligible adolescent&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Physically and cognitively able and willing to participate in a 30 minute interview.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Gave permission for their child to participate in the primary study within the&#xD;
             previous 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Able to understand and speak English or Spanish&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christine Grady, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Burke TM, Abramovitch R, Zlotkin S. Children's understanding of the risks and benefits associated with research. J Med Ethics. 2005 Dec;31(12):715-20.</citation>
    <PMID>16319237</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brody JL, Scherer DG, Annett RD, Pearson-Bish M. Voluntary assent in biomedical research with adolescents: a comparison of parent and adolescent views. Ethics Behav. 2003;13(1):79-95.</citation>
    <PMID>14552306</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brody JL, Annett RD, Scherer DG, Perryman ML, Cofrin KM. Comparisons of adolescent and parent willingness to participate in minimal and above-minimal risk pediatric asthma research protocols. J Adolesc Health. 2005 Sep;37(3):229-35.</citation>
    <PMID>16109343</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 12, 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 11, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 11, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 12, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 8, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 8, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 9, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Assent</keyword>
  <keyword>Adolescent</keyword>
  <keyword>Informed Consent</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

