<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00880659</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2009-004</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00880659</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Bangladesh Secondary Transmission Handwashing Protocol</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prevention of Secondary Transmission of Human Influenza by Promoting Handwashing With Soap: The Bangladesh Interruption of Secondary Transmission of Influenza Study (BISTIS)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangladesh</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>State University of New York at Buffalo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangladesh</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The next influenza pandemic is expected to spread rapidly in resource-poor settings.&#xD;
      Influenza viruses spread from human-to-human via large respiratory droplets. Transmission via&#xD;
      large-particle respiratory droplets is believed to be mediated by close contact between&#xD;
      infected and susceptible persons or contact with droplet-contaminated fomites. Close contact&#xD;
      between infected and susceptible persons may consist of skin-to-skin contact (e.g., via&#xD;
      hands) or inhalation of respiratory droplets (e.g., due to talking, coughing, or sneezing by&#xD;
      the infected person). Airborne transmission, which is expected to result in transmission over&#xD;
      long distances (&gt;1 meter) and which would be mediated by ventilation, is believed to be&#xD;
      uncommon. Therefore, the greatest risk of transmission from personal contact comes from those&#xD;
      people who are closest to an index case, such as contacts living in the same household. There&#xD;
      are, to date, no published estimates of the secondary attack ratio of influenza among&#xD;
      household contacts of index case-patients in low-income countries. Moreover, the&#xD;
      investigators do not have data on the risk factors for secondary transmission of influenza&#xD;
      from index case-patients to their household contacts. There is some data for the benefits of&#xD;
      promoting handwashing with soap on the risk of all-cause acute respiratory illness among&#xD;
      children &lt; 15 years old in a resource-poor setting in Pakistan. But, the investigators do not&#xD;
      have evidence that promoting handwashing with soap will acutely reduce the risk of secondary&#xD;
      transmission. Therefore, the investigators propose to conduct a study in rural Bangladesh to&#xD;
      assess the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The secondary attack ratio of influenza among household contacts of an index&#xD;
           case-patient with influenza&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The risk factors for secondary transmission of influenza from an index case-patient to&#xD;
           household contacts&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The impact of promoting handwashing with soap on the risk of secondary transmission of&#xD;
           influenza from an index case-patient to household contacts&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The impact of handwashing promotion on handwashing behavior six months after&#xD;
           intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The impact of handwashing promotion on the prevalence of respiratory infections,&#xD;
           diarrhea and influenza&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BISTIS builds on hospital-based surveillance for Influenza virus infection, which is ongoing&#xD;
      in hospitals around Bangladesh, as part of the Hospital-based Influenza Surveillance (HBIS)&#xD;
      and Surveillance for the Epidemiology of Influenza in Bangladesh (SEIB) projects. We intend&#xD;
      to recruit patients identified at the Jahurul Islam Medical College Hospital in Kishoregonj,&#xD;
      Bangladesh, where both HBIS and SEIB are in place. In this hospital 80% of all the patients&#xD;
      who present with influenza-like illness (ILI) to the outpatient departments of Medicine and&#xD;
      Pediatrics are from three upazillas of Kishorgonj district: Bajitpur, Kuliar char and&#xD;
      Kotiadi. The distances of these three upazillas are within 30 minutes travel time from&#xD;
      Jahurul Islam Medical College Hospital (one way) and hence these upazillas will serve as the&#xD;
      primary catchment areas for BISTIS. The table below illustrates the number of ILI cases&#xD;
      identified through HBIS and SEIB study at Jahurul Islam Medical College Hospital in 2008 and&#xD;
      also the number and proportion among them who were tested PCR positive for influenza virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      n.b., most influenza-positive specimens were collected between May and September in 2007 and&#xD;
      2008&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will also enroll patients who present to two local upazilla health complexes (UHCs), one&#xD;
      in Bajitpur and one in Kuliar Char. These local health complexes see numerous patients a day&#xD;
      from the rural areas surrounding the clinic. Patients who present to these clinics are more&#xD;
      likely to have symptom onset within 24 hours of presentation then those patients who seek&#xD;
      care at JIMCH, since patients may only want to go to the hospital if their illness has been&#xD;
      severe and prolonged over several days. Some studies on the impact of handwashing promotion&#xD;
      have found that the intervention is effective if delivered within 36 hours of the index&#xD;
      case-patient's symptom onset; therefore, the UHC sites are appropriate for enrollment of&#xD;
      patients for BISTIS in addition to enrollment at JIMCH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lastly, we will recruit patients from pharmacies within the catchment areas mentioned above.&#xD;
      By collaborating with local pharmacists, we intend on further increasing our enrollment&#xD;
      numbers. Patients who present to local pharmacists are likely to have symptom onset within 24&#xD;
      hours of their visit to the pharmacist and are also more likely to be the primary case within&#xD;
      their bari.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 1: To measure the secondary attack ratio (SAR) of influenza viruses among&#xD;
      household contacts of index cases with influenza, in a rural setting in Bangladesh&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods for Specific Aim 1&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specimen collection and processing A trained study physician will procure a nasal swab and an&#xD;
      oropharyngeal swab from consenting index case-patients meeting the inclusion criteria above&#xD;
      using a standardized method. At the Jahurul Islam Medical College Hospital, the nasal and&#xD;
      oropharyngeal swabs will both be placed into a single tube containing viral transport media&#xD;
      (VTM). An aliquot of the VTM will then be tested for Influenza A and B by the trained&#xD;
      physician or nurse using a rapid antigen detection test (QuickVue® Influenza A + B). If the&#xD;
      QuickVue® result is positive for Influenza A or Influenza B, the remaining VTM will be kept&#xD;
      at 4°C. All VTM will be transported to the ICDDR,B virology laboratory in Dhaka on a weekly&#xD;
      basis. At the ICDDR,B virology laboratory, RT-PCR testing for Influenza A (H1N1), Influenza A&#xD;
      ( H3N2), and Influenza B will be carried out. If Influenza A H1N1 and A H3N2 are both&#xD;
      negative, RT-PCR testing for Influenza A H5N1 will be performed. If the QuickVue® result is&#xD;
      negative for both Influenza A and Influenza B, the patient will be informed of the result and&#xD;
      thanked for participating in the study. The VTM will be discarded using appropriate infection&#xD;
      control procedures, unless the patient is also participating in the ongoing HBIS or SEIB (in&#xD;
      which case the remaining specimen will be processed like other surveillance specimens).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enumeration of bari contacts and questionnaire administration Illness tracking among bari&#xD;
      contacts Illness tracking will be carried out on each day for 10 days until after resolution&#xD;
      of the index case-patient's illness. Resolution will be defined as the lack of fever, cough,&#xD;
      and sore throat for at least 24 hours preceding the FRA's daily illness tracking visit. Thus,&#xD;
      if the index case-patient's illness resolves on day 4 after enrollment, illness tracking will&#xD;
      continue until day 14 after enrollment. The FRA will visit the patient's home and record&#xD;
      information regarding the presence or absence of ILI and SARI symptoms in each household&#xD;
      contact using an individual illness tracking form (appendix 9a8a and 9b8b - illness tracking&#xD;
      form, ages ≥ 5 and &lt; 5). For the purposes of screening household contacts for influenza, we&#xD;
      will alter the age-specific case definition for children, based on data from urban&#xD;
      Bangladesh, which demonstrates that fever and rhinorrhea are the most predictive factors for&#xD;
      influenza in children &lt; 5 years old (WA Brooks, ICDDR,B, personal communication).&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a household contact meets the age-specific case definition and does NOT have any danger&#xD;
      signs, the FRA will obtain written informed consent for specimen collection (appendix 2-&#xD;
      specimen collection from household contact for adult &gt; 18 years old, (appendix 3 - specimen&#xD;
      collection from household contact for child &lt; 18 years old). The FRA will alert the medical&#xD;
      officer, who will visit the home with the FRA no later than the following day in order to&#xD;
      collect nasal and oropharyngeal swabs from the ill household contact. She will immediately&#xD;
      place both swabs into VTM, which will then be placed into a cool box, containing ice and a&#xD;
      thermometer to ensure temperatures &lt; 40 C.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All specimens collected in the field will be placed in a cool box and transported to the&#xD;
      ICDDR,B laboratory within 72 hours. At the ICDDR,B virology laboratory, all specimens for&#xD;
      household contacts will be tested using RT-PCR for Influenza A (H1N1), A (H3N2), and&#xD;
      Influenza B (and A (H5N1) if appropriate).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Illness tracking among household contacts will continue in each household until the 10th full&#xD;
      day following the resolution of the index case-patient's symptoms, irrespective of whether&#xD;
      any household contact develops illness or not.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 2: To test the efficacy of a handwashing promotion intervention for prevention&#xD;
      of intrahousehold transmission of influenza virus&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods for Specific Aim 2&#xD;
&#xD;
      To address this specific aim, we will conduct a randomized controlled trial. Households of&#xD;
      index case-patients with influenza-like illness who are recruited at Jahurul Islam Medical&#xD;
      College Hospital the UHCs or the local pharmacies will be randomized to the intervention&#xD;
      group or the routine practices group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The two groups will be defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Intervention Households: intensive promotion of handwashing with soap, and provision of&#xD;
           facilitating tools, to the index-case-patient and all available household contacts&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Routine practices Households: continuation of the household's usual handwashing and&#xD;
           respiratory hygiene practices group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For promotion of handwashing with soap to intervention households, Field Intervention&#xD;
      Specialists (FIS) will be trained to carry out a structured intervention that will follow&#xD;
      constructs of Social Cognitive Theory (SCT). SCT addresses the reciprocal interaction between&#xD;
      individuals, their environment, and health behaviors. Given that intervention will occur at&#xD;
      the bari level, group-mediated constructs such as observational learning and reinforcements&#xD;
      are highly relevant. FISs will visit the intervention households on a daily basis for 10 days&#xD;
      after the resolution of the index case-patient's illness in order to encourage handwashing&#xD;
      with soap at the recommended times. Routine practices households will also be exposed to the&#xD;
      intervention, but only upon completion of the study. As noted above, under Specific Aim 1, an&#xD;
      FRA will visit the home of the index case-patient daily for 10 days after the resolution of&#xD;
      the index case-patient's symptoms in order to record age-specific case defining symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific aim 3: To identify risk factors, other than handwashing with soap, for&#xD;
      intrahousehold transmission of influenza in a rural setting in Bangladesh.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods for Specific Aim 3&#xD;
&#xD;
      To address Specific Aim 3, we will conduct a nested cohort study to assess risk factors for&#xD;
      intrahousehold transmission of influenza viruses. Here, the cohort under investigation is the&#xD;
      routine practices group, as defined under Specific Aim 2. All data required to address this&#xD;
      Specific Aim 3 will have been collected as part of the data collection described above under&#xD;
      Specific Aim 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A case will be defined as: RT-PCR confirmed Influenza virus infection (A or B) in a household&#xD;
      contact of an RT-PCR confirmed Influenza virus infection (A or B) index case-patient during&#xD;
      10 days of follow-up after resolution of the index case-patient's symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific aim 4: To assess whether exposure to the BISTIS intervention results in sustained&#xD;
      improvements in handwashing behavior.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods for Specific Aim 4&#xD;
&#xD;
      To address Specific Aim 4, we will visit each bari that was enrolled in the intervention&#xD;
      study 4 - 7 months after illness tracking is complete. The FRA will measure handwashing&#xD;
      behavior at the bari. We will complete a structured observation of the bari's common&#xD;
      handwashing behaviors. One or two months after the initial follow-up visit, the FRA will&#xD;
      return to the bari and once again collect the same information on the handwashing behavior&#xD;
      but will also provide soap to the bari. The FRA will collect the soap two days later. Data&#xD;
      from the soap will be used to calculate the number of soap use events in the bari. In total&#xD;
      an FRA will visit the household a total of three times, two visits for data collection and&#xD;
      one visit to collect the soap.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific aim 5: To assess if exposure to the BISTIS intervention results in a reduced risk of&#xD;
      respiratory infections, diarrhea, and influenza.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods for Specific Aim 5&#xD;
&#xD;
      The measurements of the health outcomes will be done in two different ways. At the first&#xD;
      visit, after the handwashing behavior information is collected, the FRA will record whether&#xD;
      each member of the bari has had symptoms of fever, cough, sore throat, difficulty breathing,&#xD;
      respiratory illness or diarrhea in the previous 48 hours. At the third visit, in April 2010,&#xD;
      the FRA will record mobile phone numbers of two or three bari members. The FRA will identify&#xD;
      a key informant, who will be able to provide information regarding fever in any bari member.&#xD;
      The FRA will phone the bari once each week during the influenza season and speak with the key&#xD;
      informant once per week to assess whether any bari member has had fever during the previous&#xD;
      24 hours. If any member is reported to have a fever, we will dispatch an MO or lab/medical&#xD;
      technician to the bari to obtain nasopharyngeal swab from that member for flu testing by PCR.&#xD;
      A case will be defined as: RT-PCR confirmed Influenza virus infection (A or B).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To test the efficacy of a handwashing promotion intervention for prevention of intrahousehold transmission of influenza virus in a rural setting in Bangladesh</measure>
    <time_frame>17 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To measure the secondary attack ratio of influenza among household contacts of influenza-infected persons in a rural setting in Bangladesh influenza-infected persons in a rural setting in Bangladesh</measure>
    <time_frame>17 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">6600</enrollment>
  <condition>Human Influenza</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Promotion of handwashing with soap and maintenance of a fully stocked handwashing station.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Practice of routine handwashing among the household members</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Soap</intervention_name>
    <description>Promotion of handwashing with soap</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons ≥ 5 years old: Influenza-like illness (ILI), defined as history of fever and&#xD;
             either cough or sore throat with fever onset within the previous 24 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons &lt; 5 years old: any child with acute fever with onset within the previous 24&#xD;
             hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Return to home within 24 hours of presentation to Upazilla Health Complex, Jahurul&#xD;
             Islam Medical College Hospital or the local pharmacies; i.e., the index case cannot be&#xD;
             admitted for treatment. If admitted, the patient would not be eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No fever in any bari resident during the 7 days preceding the patient's presentation&#xD;
             to hospital (see definition below)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least two persons (in addition to the index case-patient) who intend to reside in&#xD;
             the bari during the subsequent 20 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residence within 30 minutes travel time (one-way) from the Upazilla Health Complex or&#xD;
             Jahurul Islam Medical College Hospital or the local pharmacy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eduardo Azziz-Baumgartner, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangladesh</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pavani K. Ram</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kishoreganj</city>
        <country>Bangladesh</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Bangladesh</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2010</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 11, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 13, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 14, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 29, 2010</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 29, 2010</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 30, 2010</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Pavani K. Ram</name_title>
    <organization>Department of Social and Preventive Medicine</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Influenza</keyword>
  <keyword>secondary transmission</keyword>
  <keyword>handwashing</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

