<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02084888</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SCAAR-CTO-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02084888</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prognostic Impact of Chronic Total Occlusions</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prognostic Impact of Chronic Total Occlusions - A Report From the Swedish Coronary Angiography and Angioplasty Registry (SCAAR)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Sweden</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Sweden</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the prognostic impact of the presence of chronic&#xD;
      total occlusions (CTO) of the coronary arteries in patients undergoing coronary angiography&#xD;
      and PCI.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The SCAAR registry&#xD;
&#xD;
      The SCAAR registry was established in 1999 and is a part of the national SWEDEHEART registry.&#xD;
      The registry gathers data on all consecutive patients from all hospitals that perform&#xD;
      coronary angiography and PCI in Sweden. The information about clinical characteristics and&#xD;
      procedural details is entered into the registry immediately after the procedure by the PCI&#xD;
      physician after the review of clinical information. SCAAR is independent of commercial&#xD;
      funding and is sponsored by the Swedish Health Authorities only. The technology has been&#xD;
      developed and administered by the Uppsala Clinical Research Center, Uppsala, Sweden. Since&#xD;
      2001, it has a web-based case-report platform with automatic data surveillance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study population consisted of all consecutive patients that underwent coronary&#xD;
      angiography or PCI in Sweden who were registered between 2005 to 2012 in Swedish Coronary&#xD;
      Angiography and Angioplasty Registry (SCAAR).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Definitions&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators defined CTO as 100% luminal diameter stenosis and the absence of antegrade&#xD;
      flow known or assumed to be ≥3 months duration. Coronary artery disease (CAD) was defined as&#xD;
      a luminal narrowing ≥50% on angiography. Procedural success after PCI treatment of the&#xD;
      coronary lesion is defined as residual stenosis &lt; 50%, decreased grade of stenosis after&#xD;
      intervention by at least 20%, TIMI flow ≥ II and no serious complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study cohort&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study was based on patients who underwent diagnostic coronary angiography and were&#xD;
      registered in SCAAR during the period 2005 to January 2012. Only patients who were diagnosed&#xD;
      with significant coronary artery disease were included in the analyses. A CTO patient was&#xD;
      identified based on the available information about the percentage of luminal stenosis at the&#xD;
      level of coronary segments that was introduced in 2005. From this date onwards, the&#xD;
      information derived from a diagnostic coronary angiogram can also be used to determine if a&#xD;
      coronary segment was totally occluded. In order to differentiate between acute and chronic&#xD;
      occlusions, we excluded patients who underwent a procedure for ACS in whom the 100% occlusion&#xD;
      was located in the same coronary artery as the culprit vessel. Furthermore, we excluded&#xD;
      patients who underwent a procedure in the same vessel within the previous 3 months. The&#xD;
      patients with previous coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) surgery were excluded from&#xD;
      analysis as the patency of the graft could not be determined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Validation&#xD;
&#xD;
      Validation of the CTO definition was performed in a subgroup of 955 patients from one&#xD;
      university hospital (Sahlgrenska University Hospital) and from three county hospitals (Norra&#xD;
      Älvsborgs Hospital, Borås Hospital, Skövde Hospital). This subgroup represents 5.7% of all&#xD;
      identified CTO patients in SCAAR in the study period. The patients were randomly selected by&#xD;
      means of random number generator. The validation procedure was conducted by a panel&#xD;
      consisting of five experienced interventional cardiologists. The panelists examined&#xD;
      individual coronary angiograms according to a monitoring plan defined in advance. Each&#xD;
      angiogram was evaluated in regard to whether the patient had previous CABG, whether the&#xD;
      treated occlusion was ≥3 months old and whether 100% segmental stenosis on angiogram was an&#xD;
      occlusion ≥3 months old. The results from the validation procedure were then compared to the&#xD;
      data entered in SCAAR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Differences in baseline characteristics between the groups were tested with the χ2 test for&#xD;
      categorical variables while Mann-Whitney U test and Kruskal-Wallis test were used for&#xD;
      comparison of continuous non-normally distributed variables. Shapiro-Wilks test was used as a&#xD;
      test for normal distribution. Statistical significance was defined as a P-value &lt;0.05. The&#xD;
      primary outcome was all-cause mortality. Unadjusted survival was examined using a&#xD;
      Kaplan-Meier survival curve and the log-rank test. To evaluate the association between&#xD;
      presence of CTO and mortality, multivariable-adjusted hazard ratios (HR) were calculated&#xD;
      using Cox proportional-hazards regression models. All tests were two-sided. The potential&#xD;
      confounders such as; age, gender, diabete, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, smoking status,&#xD;
      previous PCI, previous MI, extent of CAD, indication, puncture site, any complication,&#xD;
      primary treatment decision, were all entered into the model. We prespecified six subgroup&#xD;
      analyses for the following patient categories: indication for angiography and PCI (stable&#xD;
      angina, UA/non-STEMI, STEMI and other) severity of CAD (one-, two-, three-vessel and left&#xD;
      main disease) age, gender, diabetes and calendar year. The possible effect modification of&#xD;
      CTO on risk of dying in the subgroups was analyzed by means of interaction test. Age was&#xD;
      examined in the interaction with CTO both as a continuous as well as factorial variable&#xD;
      consisting of four different age groups namely &lt;59, 60-69, 70-79 and &gt;80 years. The&#xD;
      assumption of proportional hazards for each covariate was reviewed separately by the means of&#xD;
      log-minus-log survival plots and by formal test based on scaled Schoenfeld residuals.&#xD;
      Possible multicollinearity between the variables in the model was assessed by calculation of&#xD;
      variance inflation factor. The database was scrutinized for missing data. A number of&#xD;
      variables listed above were associated with missing data. In addition to the complete case&#xD;
      analysis, we applied multiple imputation method to estimate the missing data and performed&#xD;
      Cox proportional hazards regression with the imputed data set under the assumption that&#xD;
      missing data are missing at random. The imputation protocol consisted of the chain-equation&#xD;
      method with a predictive-mean matching algorithm using the same covariates as in the main&#xD;
      analysis with 20 imputed data sets with addition of cumulative hazard and event indicator.&#xD;
      Cumulative hazard was estimated with the Nelson-Aalen's test. Due to hierarchical structure&#xD;
      of SCAAR with clustering of patients within hospitals causing violation of assumption of&#xD;
      independency between the patients, we applied multilevel modeling with shared frailty Cox&#xD;
      proportional-hazards regression to adjust for the clustering effect. This was the primary&#xD;
      model. The secondary model was based on complete-case analysis. All analyses were performed&#xD;
      using Stata software (version 13.1, StataCorp, College Station, Texas, USA). The imputation&#xD;
      procedure and subsequent Cox proportional hazards regression estimation was performed&#xD;
      according to the Rubin's protocol.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>3 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>All cause Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">91154</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronary Artery Disease</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Total Occlusions</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study is based on all patients who underwent diagnostic coronary angiography and were&#xD;
        registered in SCAAR during the period 2005 to January 2012 . Only patients who were&#xD;
        diagnosed with significant coronary artery disease were included in the analyses.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with angiographic diagnosis of significant CAD registered in SCAAR between&#xD;
             January 2005 and january 2012&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous CABG surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Missing data on coronary anatomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who underwent a procedure for ACS in whom the 100% occlusion was located in&#xD;
             the same coronary artery as the culprit vessel&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who underwent a procedure in the same vessel within the previous 3 months&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Truls Råmunddal, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Sweden</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elmir Omerovic, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Sweden</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sahlgrenska University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gothenburg</city>
        <zip>41345</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 10, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 11, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 12, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 11, 2014</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 11, 2014</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 12, 2014</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Sweden</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Truls Råmunddal</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Senior consultant cardiologist, Director of the catheterization laboratory</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

