<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02088866</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>515576</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02088866</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Commercial Lidocaine Patch as a Treatment for Ear-ringing</brief_title>
  <official_title>Transdermal Lidocaine as a Treatment for Tinnitus</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, Davis</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Davis</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this investigation is to evaluate if topically applied lidocaine, in the form&#xD;
      of lidocaine patches, reduces the burden of chronic subjective tinnitus in a consistent and&#xD;
      measurable way.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Potential research participants will be recruited from the UC Davis Otolaryngology clinic.&#xD;
      For this investigation, the investigators will be using the Tinnitus Functional Index, a&#xD;
      standardized and validated survey for the impact of tinnitus on an individual's life. The&#xD;
      study design will be an unblinded, quasi-experimental protocol to ascertain if transdermal&#xD;
      lidocaine can reduce subjective tinnitus. This initial investigation will be studying the&#xD;
      efficacy of 5% transdermal lidocaine patches in the treatment of tinnitus. Transdermal&#xD;
      lidocaine is currently approved by the FDA for the treatment of post-herpetic neuralgia, but&#xD;
      it is used off label for a wide assortment of conditions. The investigators will be following&#xD;
      the guidelines used for the general use of transdermal lidocaine and will remain within the&#xD;
      dosing approved by the FDA. The investigators intend to sequentially recruit 44 participants&#xD;
      for this study, in the order that they present to the UC Davis Otolaryngology clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SUBJECTS Eligible subjects are greater than 18 years of age and have had at least a history&#xD;
      of chronic subjective tinnitus. Prior to enrollment, all potential subjects will be screened&#xD;
      to see if they meet the inclusion and exclusion criteria as listed in Section 6. Once&#xD;
      inclusion and exclusion criteria have been evaluated, appropriate participants will undergo&#xD;
      the informed consent process. Following informed consent, all selected participants will&#xD;
      undergo a full history and physical exam. We will not be performing a pre-enrollment EKG, as&#xD;
      it is not required for the general use of transdermal lidocaine. Each subject will have had&#xD;
      an audiogram performed as standard of care for evaluation and management of chronic tinnitus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MATERIALS AND APPLICATION This investigation will utilize the UC Davis Otolaryngology clinic&#xD;
      and its resource within for this investigation. TFI surveys will be provided for the&#xD;
      participants. The drug used in this investigation will be 5% lidocaine patches (Endo&#xD;
      Pharmaceuticals and Actavis Pharmaceuticals). Study drug will be prescribed by a physician in&#xD;
      the Department of the Otolaryngology at UC Davis, to be filled at the pharmacy of the&#xD;
      participant's choosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The transdermal lidocaine patches will be administered to the participant's torso, either the&#xD;
      upper back or chest, at his or her preference. If an individual is so slight of build that he&#xD;
      or she can not apply three patches to either his upper chest or upper back, then other&#xD;
      locations will be considered, including low back, buttocks, and thighs. Patches will be&#xD;
      applied first thing in the morning to these areas daily, and kept on for twelve hours.&#xD;
      Following patch removal at night, the patient will undergo a twelve hour drug recess off of&#xD;
      the transdermal lidocaine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All relevant patient information including symptoms checklists, results of TFI, and other&#xD;
      important patient care information will be recorded in the UC Davis Electronic Medical Record&#xD;
      (EMR) for each encounter under the appropriate encounter subheading. These recording will be&#xD;
      done in accordance with UC Davis Policies and Procedures manual Chapter 320, Section 10&#xD;
      Records and Archives: Records Management Program, as well as UC Davis Health Center's Code of&#xD;
      Conduct, specifically referring to Standards 6, Creation and Retention of an Accurate Patient&#xD;
      and Institutional Record, and 14, Clinical Research. The patient data will also be transposed&#xD;
      into a REDCap database for patient tracking, evaluation, and analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY VISITS After the completion of the informed consent, each individual will be asked to&#xD;
      complete the tinnitus functional index. If he or she does not have a baseline audiogram on&#xD;
      record, they will be referred to the Audiology Clinic for this in accordance with standard of&#xD;
      care for tinnitus. Using a previously created dot phrase in the EMR, the results of the TFI&#xD;
      and the symptom checklist will be recorded into the participant's health record. Following&#xD;
      completion of the tinnitus functional index, each participant will be prescribed thirty&#xD;
      transdermal lidocaine patches, so that one patch can be applied daily for 12 hours, as&#xD;
      indicated by the manufacturer. The participant will be asked to follow-up in 4 weeks by&#xD;
      phone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All subjects will be enrolled sequentially and assigned a schedule that works best with his&#xD;
      or her ability to follow-up. As such, for this pilot study there will not be any cohort&#xD;
      assignment outside of the treatment group. Each participant will continue with either the&#xD;
      baseline dosage or an increased dosage based upon his or her response and tolerance to the&#xD;
      drug. For this quasi-experimental model, we will not be using controls and will compare final&#xD;
      results to baseline measurements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After one month of treatment, the participant will be called by the research team. During&#xD;
      this telephone call, the participant will first be asked if he or she would like to&#xD;
      withdrawal from the study. This individual will then be asked to voice any and all concerns&#xD;
      he or she may have up to that point in the study. During these calls, the participant will be&#xD;
      asked the same questions he or she answered during the initial visit, including those of the&#xD;
      TFI and the symptoms checklist. These results will be recorded in the EMR as a phone&#xD;
      interaction, using the previously developed dot phrases. At the time of the call, the&#xD;
      participant will be asked how many patches he or she has remaining from the previous month.&#xD;
      These left over patches will be recorded as well in the EMR. At the conclusion of this first&#xD;
      follow-up call, the participant will either continue the baseline dosage or have dosing&#xD;
      increased to two transdermal lidocaine patches. These patches will again be applied to the&#xD;
      upper back or shoulder 12 hours of each day. Patch application techniques will be similar to&#xD;
      that of the first patch, but if he or she has any concerns about application of the patches&#xD;
      he or she can ask the research team at any time for advice or guidance. We anticipate this&#xD;
      follow-up call will take 30 minutes or less.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of this second 4 week period, 8 total study weeks, the participant will again be&#xD;
      called by the research team and asked questions in a similar manner to the first follow-up&#xD;
      phone call. During this telephone encounter, the patient will be asked if he or she would&#xD;
      like to withdrawal from the study, and /or if he or she has any concerns. The participant&#xD;
      will then be asked the same questions he or she answered during the initial visit, including&#xD;
      the TFI and the symptoms checklist. The results will again be recorded in the EMR as a phone&#xD;
      interaction, using the previously developed dot phrases. At the time of the call, the&#xD;
      participant will be asked how many patches he or she has remaining from the previous month.&#xD;
      These left over patches will be recorded as well in the EMR. At the conclusion of this&#xD;
      follow-up call, the participant will have the opportunity to continue current therapy, or to&#xD;
      increase his or her current regimen by a patch. This change would increase the total dose to&#xD;
      either 2 or 3 transdermal lidocaine patches based upon his or her previous therapy. The&#xD;
      patches will again be applied to the upper back or shoulder 12 hours of each day. Patch&#xD;
      application techniques will be similar to that of the first patch, but if he or she has any&#xD;
      concerns about application of the patches he or she can ask the research team at any time for&#xD;
      advice or guidance. We anticipate this follow-up call will take 30 minutes or less.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following the third month of the study, 12 total study weeks, the participant will be asked&#xD;
      to follow up in the UC Davis Otolaryngology clinic, and he or she will be seen in one of the&#xD;
      clinical suites. The participant will have the opportunity to voice any concerns he or she&#xD;
      may have with the trial. At this visits the participant will be asked again to complete the&#xD;
      TFI, a symptoms checklist, report the number of patches he or she used over the previous&#xD;
      month, and to undergo a focused physical examination of his or her head, neck, and&#xD;
      cardiovascular system. The results of these questionnaires and exams will be recorded in the&#xD;
      EMR. Following these repeat evaluations, the participant's results of the TFI will be&#xD;
      reviewed. After reviewing these results, the participant will have the opportunity to&#xD;
      continue the most effective dose of the medication for him or her, based on his or her&#xD;
      symptoms and side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The above protocol will be followed unless the participant develops toxic effects of the&#xD;
      lidocaine patches including but not limited to palpitations, chest pain, irregular heart beat&#xD;
      (as diagnosed by either his or her primary care physician or other health care provider),&#xD;
      severe allergic reactions, severe vestibular symptoms including severe dizziness, intractable&#xD;
      nausea, or blurred vision. In such an occurrence the participant will be removed from the&#xD;
      study. If a participant develops these or other concerning symptoms, they will be immediately&#xD;
      referred to the emergency room for evaluation and treatment. The onset of these symptoms as&#xD;
      well as the dosing at which they were experienced will be recorded for statistical analysis.&#xD;
      A participant may also be removed from the study if they have an adverse event unrelated to&#xD;
      the study including hospitalization for major illness or injury. The data that he or she&#xD;
      contributed up until removal from the study will remain within the study and be evaluated on&#xD;
      an intent to treat basis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the participant has an adverse event following the increase of the dose of transdermal&#xD;
      lidocaine he or she will be presented with two options. If he or she previously tolerated a&#xD;
      lower dosage of the transdermal lidocaine, and would like to return to that dose, following&#xD;
      the adverse event, he or she will have the option of returning to that regimen. He or she&#xD;
      will also be presented with the option of treatment cessation following their adverse event.&#xD;
      Their decision will be recorded and their data treated accordingly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A participant will be informed of his or her results from the survey at his or her request,&#xD;
      as well as at the completion of the third month of follow-up. The results will be reviewed by&#xD;
      one of the investigators with the participant, allowing adequate time for interpretation and&#xD;
      questions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data will be stored in three locations. The participant's informed consent documents will&#xD;
      be scanned into the EMR, the participant will be asked to keep a copy of these forms, and we&#xD;
      will keep the original hard copy forms in a secured drawer in the back of the Otolaryngology&#xD;
      clinic, away from clinical activity. The participant will be asked to fill out paper copies&#xD;
      of the TFI, and symptom checklist at the final clinical appointment, and these will be&#xD;
      immediately transposed into the EMR. Once transposed, the paper copies of the TFI and symptom&#xD;
      checklist will disposed of in secure shredding bins. All data will be stored in the REDCap&#xD;
      database and available to only to the investigating team.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tinnitus Functional Index (TFI) change at 4 week intervals up to a maximum time frame of 12 weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of enrollment and every 4 weeks thereafter up to a maximum time frame of 12 weeks from date of enrollment.</time_frame>
    <description>The primary study endpoint is change in tinnitus tolerance based on the tinnitus functional index. TFI will be measured at initial appointment and will be measured again at 4±1 weeks for any change in outcome, then again at 8±1 weeks for any subsequent change to outcome, and finally at 12±1 weeks follow-up for any subsequent change to outcome, up to a maximum time frame of 12 weeks from date of enrollment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Tinnitus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Transdermal Lidocaine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients will be in this arm. This arm will be the transdermal lidocaine group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Transdermal Lidocaine</intervention_name>
    <description>The intervention will use 5% commercially available transdermal lidocaine in clinical practice for the treatment of tinnitus. This dose will be tailored to patient preference.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Transdermal Lidocaine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>5% Commercially Available Transdermal Lidocaine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of chronic subjective tinnitus that cannot be attributed to vascular,&#xD;
             neurologic, neoplastic or traumatic causes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capable of self-applying the lidocaine patches&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of heart disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of irregular heartbeat&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior MI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous exposure to lidocaine as a treatment for tinnitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An allergy to adhesives&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to lidocaine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking medications, herbal remedies and supplements that may interact with lidocaine,&#xD;
             including but not limited to antivirals, benzodiazepines, and St. John's Wart&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known liver disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known kidney disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults who do not speak English,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults who cannot consent for him or herself&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who intend to become pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nursing mothers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prisoners&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Daniel C O'Brien, B.S.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University of California Davis Department of Medical Education</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rodney Diaz, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California Davis Department of Otolaryngology - Head and Neck Surgery</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UC Davis Department of Otolaryngology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95817</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 11, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 13, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 17, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 24, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 24, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 30, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Tinnitus</keyword>
  <keyword>Otolaryngology</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tinnitus</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Final data was inconclusive</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

