<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01707056</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2011-338</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01707056</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Coffee on the Absorption of Thyroid Hormone in Patients With Thyroid Carcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Coffee Consumption on the Intestinal Absorption of Levothyroxine Thyroid Hormone Replacement in Patients With Thyroid Carcinoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medstar Health Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Georgetown University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medstar Health Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate whether taking thyroid hormone medication with&#xD;
      beverages other than water, decreases absorption of the medication by the intestine.&#xD;
      Specifically we are interested in whether coffee, coffee with milk, or black tea affects how&#xD;
      thyroid medication is absorbed by the body. Previous studies have suggested that taking&#xD;
      thyroid hormone with coffee may interfere with the ability to absorb thyroid medicine. Given&#xD;
      that many patients take their thyroid medicine with beverages other than water, and&#xD;
      specifically with coffee or tea, understanding whether and how much coffee or tea may&#xD;
      decrease thyroid hormone absorption is important for clinical practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will help determine the safest and most effective way for adults to take their&#xD;
      thyroid medication and will guide medical practitioners in how to counsel their patients when&#xD;
      they prescribe thyroid hormone.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Previous studies have suggested that taking thyroid replacement therapy with coffee&#xD;
      potentially hinders its absorption. We already know that food especially a fiber-rich diet,&#xD;
      cholestyramine resin, aluminum containing antacids, activated charcoal, and certain herbal&#xD;
      remedies among others interfere with the ability to absorb thyroid medicine. These findings&#xD;
      have prompted providers to advise patients to take their levothyroxine on an empty stomach in&#xD;
      the morning. However, many patients take their thyroid medicine with their morning cup of&#xD;
      coffee prior to eating breakfast. A small study has shown that Italian espresso coffee can&#xD;
      decrease the absorption of levothyroxine, but the effect of American style coffee is not&#xD;
      known. Given that the intestinal absorption of levothyroxine can be hindered by multiple&#xD;
      substances and coffee is the most commonly consumed beverage worldwide, it is important to&#xD;
      investigate what effect coffee may have on thyroid hormone absorption and thyroid function&#xD;
      tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Using methods similar to those used in previous studies, this study will measure thyroid&#xD;
      function tests in approximately 10-20 subjects (18-60 years of age) over a 6 hour period of&#xD;
      time after taking their thyroid medication with the specified study beverage for a 6 week&#xD;
      period. Subjects will be randomized to water, black coffee, coffee with milk, and black tea&#xD;
      as four specified study beverages, with water serving as the control beverage. Each subject&#xD;
      will be recruited to participate with each study beverage for a 6 week period of time in a&#xD;
      total of four consecutive 6 week periods. Blood draws will occur at the end of each 6 week&#xD;
      period on test days 1, 2, 3, and 4. The coffee will represent the most common household&#xD;
      coffee brand, Folgers. Thyroid function tests with each beverage will be compared to thyroid&#xD;
      function tests with water to determine if thyroid medication absorption is impaired by&#xD;
      coffee, coffee with milk, or tea.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will help determine the safest and most efficacious way for adults to take their&#xD;
      thyroid medication and will guide medical practitioners in how to counsel their patients when&#xD;
      they prescribe thyroid replacement therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in TSH (thyrotropin-stimulating-hormone) with each beverage type</measure>
    <time_frame>6 hours</time_frame>
    <description>change in TSH over 6 hours&#xD;
peak change in TSH over 6 hours</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in TSH with various beverages</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if taking Synthroid for 6 weeks with each of the prescribed study beverages results in a different baseline TSH, reflecting altered absorption of levothyroxine with each particular beverage.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total T4 with each beverage type</measure>
    <time_frame>6 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Change in total T4 over 6 hours&#xD;
Peak change in total T4 over 6 hours&#xD;
area under the curve (AUC) for total T4</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in free T4 with each beverage type</measure>
    <time_frame>6 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Change in free T4 over 6 hours&#xD;
Peak change in free T4 over 6 hours&#xD;
area under the curve (AUC) for free T4</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total T3 with each beverage type</measure>
    <time_frame>6 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Change in total T3 over 6 hours&#xD;
Peak change in total T3 over 6 hours&#xD;
area under the curve (AUC) for total T3</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Thyroid Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Hypothyroidism</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Black coffee</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Synthroid will be administered with 12 ounces of black coffee for a period of 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Coffee with Milk</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Synthroid will be administered with 12 ounces of coffee and 2 ounces of 2% milk for a period of 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Black Tea</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Synthroid will be administered with 12 ounces of black Lipton tea for a period of 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Water</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Synthroid will be administered with 12 ounces of water for a period of 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Black Coffee</intervention_name>
    <description>Taking Synthroid with 12 ounces of black coffee for 6 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Black coffee</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Coffee with Milk</intervention_name>
    <description>Taking Synthroid with 12 ounces of black coffee and 2 ounces of 2% milk for a period of 6 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Coffee with Milk</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Black Tea</intervention_name>
    <description>Taking Synthroid with 12 ounces of black tea for a period of 6 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Black Tea</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Water</intervention_name>
    <description>Taking Synthroid with water for a period of 6 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Water</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - patients with thyroid carcinoma after standard care of treatment on stable dose of&#xD;
        Synthroid with a detectable baseline TSH&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undetectable baseline TSH&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not willing to drink coffee, coffee with milk, or black tea&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age less than 18 or greater than 60 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking generic thyroid hormone (levothyroxine) and not brand-name Synthroid&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dose of thyroid medication has been recently changed (less than 3 months ago)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently receiving treatment for gastroesophageal reflux disease, gastritis, stomach&#xD;
             or intestinal cancer, inflammatory bowel disease, or H. pylori&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking cholestyramine resin, colestipol hydrochloride, sucralfate, iron sulphate,&#xD;
             aluminum containing antacids, activated charcoal, raloxifene, and herbal remedies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of previous gastric or small intestine surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of kidney or liver disease, congestive heart failure, anemia, biliary&#xD;
             disease, pancreatitis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dorota Krajewski, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Medstar</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Georgetown University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20007</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington Hospital Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MedStar St. Mary's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leonardtown</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20650</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Benvenga S, Bartolone L, Pappalardo MA, Russo A, Lapa D, Giorgianni G, Saraceno G, Trimarchi F. Altered intestinal absorption of L-thyroxine caused by coffee. Thyroid. 2008 Mar;18(3):293-301. doi: 10.1089/thy.2007.0222.</citation>
    <PMID>18341376</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 5, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 12, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 15, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>levothyroxine</keyword>
  <keyword>synthroid</keyword>
  <keyword>coffee</keyword>
  <keyword>absorption</keyword>
  <keyword>tea</keyword>
  <keyword>thyroid carcinoma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thyroid Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thyroid Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypothyroidism</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

