<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03267251</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UNewMexico</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03267251</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Engaging Patients and Providers in Collaborative Communication on HPV Vaccination (EPICC-HPV)</brief_title>
  <acronym>EPICC-HPV</acronym>
  <official_title>Engaging Patients and Providers in Collaborative Communication on HPV Vaccination (EPICC-HPV)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of New Mexico</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Klein Buendel, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of New Mexico</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Vaccination against Human Papillomavirus is recommended for adolescent females by the&#xD;
      Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices (ACIP), physicians, and many medical&#xD;
      organizations, yet uptake of HPV vaccines remains very low. CDC data reveal that in 2013 only&#xD;
      44.3% of 13-17 year old females in New Mexico (and 37.6% nationwide) had completed the 3-dose&#xD;
      HPV vaccine series. These data reveal the uptake of the HPV vaccines is unacceptably low,&#xD;
      thereby diminishing its ability to provide population-level protection against the HPV types&#xD;
      known to cause cervical, vaginal, and vulvar cancers in women, oropharyngeal and anal cancers&#xD;
      in men and women, and penile cancers in men. The danger of very low vaccination rates is that&#xD;
      adolescents of all ages will continue to be vulnerable to HPV and the associated cancer&#xD;
      risks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite recommendations for HPV, parents continue to have concerns about HPV vaccination.&#xD;
      Clinicians often lack a clear frame for discussions about HPV vaccination with parents, so&#xD;
      much so that recent research indicates that pediatricians' discussions with parents about&#xD;
      vaccinations in general often take the form of bargaining, e.g., &quot;since this may be too early&#xD;
      for the vaccination, can we delay the vaccination schedule?&quot; Effective messaging is needed to&#xD;
      close a knowledge gap among parents around HPV and HPV vaccines, improve communication and&#xD;
      shared decision-making about HPV vaccination between adolescent girls' parents and&#xD;
      physicians, and ultimately prompt uptake of HPV vaccines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This project will employ a web-based intervention on HPV as a way to improve knowledge,&#xD;
      communication and shared decision-making about HPV vaccination for 11-13 year old girls and&#xD;
      their parents. A clinic-based comparative effectiveness randomized trial will be used to&#xD;
      examine the impact of the website on vaccine-related outcomes and vaccine uptake. New Mexico&#xD;
      pediatric clinics will be randomly assigned to either the usual care clinic-based&#xD;
      communication about HPV vaccination or to usual care plus web-based dissemination.&#xD;
      Assessments of vaccine-related outcomes, including shared decision-making between girls,&#xD;
      parents and physicians, will be assessed at baseline, 3 months, and 9 months and vaccine&#xD;
      uptake and dose adherence will be abstracted from clinic vaccine records at 9 months. An&#xD;
      effective web-based resource should increase parents' knowledge, intentions and motivations&#xD;
      to vaccinate&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Uptake of the Human Papillomavirus (HPV) vaccines in the U.S. remains very low. (RQ-1) The&#xD;
      quadrivalent HPV vaccine has been routinely recommended for adolescent females by the&#xD;
      Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention&#xD;
      (CDC) reports that in 2013, the uptake of HPV vaccines (all three doses) was 37.6% for&#xD;
      females (ages 13-17 years). The Healthy People 2020 target for vaccination coverage of&#xD;
      adolescent females aged 13-15 years is 80.0% for ≥3 doses of HPV, far above current national&#xD;
      rates for HPV vaccine uptake. In New Mexico, the 3-dose completion rate for HPV vaccination&#xD;
      for females ages 13-17 is currently 44.3%. However, for girls in the recommended early age&#xD;
      vaccination range (11-13), a recent estimate provided by the New Mexico Dept. of Public&#xD;
      Health Vaccination Program reveals that in 2012 approximately 7% of 11-12 year old New Mexico&#xD;
      adolescent girls completed all 3 doses of HPV vaccine, and in 2013 approximately 9% had&#xD;
      completed all 3 doses. In the simplest terms, the uptake of the HPV vaccines is unacceptably&#xD;
      low, diminishing its ability to confer population-level protection against the HPV types&#xD;
      known to cause cervical, vaginal, and vulvar cancers in women, oropharyngeal and anal cancers&#xD;
      in men and women, and penile cancers in men. The danger given the very low vaccination rates&#xD;
      reported above is that a significant proportion of adolescents of all ages will not receive&#xD;
      the HPV vaccine and continue to be vulnerable to HPV and the associated cancer risks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physicians' views of and recommendations for HPV vaccination and parents' perceptions of the&#xD;
      HPV vaccines predict HPV vaccine uptake. Despite convincing data on the safety and&#xD;
      effectiveness of the vaccines, and a wide variety of medical organizations recommending them,&#xD;
      parents continue to have concerns about HPV vaccination. The pattern of vaccine uptake also&#xD;
      increases the risk of vaccine-related health disparity across gender and ethnic groups. While&#xD;
      minority youth are more likely to begin vaccination programs, they are significantly less&#xD;
      likely to complete vaccination programs for reasons that remain in debate. As a result,&#xD;
      minority youth lack adequate protection from preventable illnesses. This is particularly&#xD;
      problematic as such deficits can build into larger medical consequences later in life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Diffusion of Innovations theory (DI) provides a framework for explaining vaccine uptake. DI&#xD;
      is a theory that seeks to explain how, what, and why new ideas (e.g., vaccines) are spread&#xD;
      through different populations at different rates. One tenet of DI is that effective messaging&#xD;
      is necessary for the diffusion of a new innovation, and there is a lack of effective&#xD;
      messaging to parents to close the knowledge gap about HPV vaccines, resulting in poor uptake.&#xD;
      Both the CDC and the President's Cancer Advisory Board call for the development of effective&#xD;
      and accessible messaging to improve decision-making around adolescent vaccination,&#xD;
      particularly for the HPV vaccines. Effective messaging is especially important to reach&#xD;
      minority groups who experience health disparities, especially to parents for whom English may&#xD;
      not be the first language. Because parents drive the decision-making around vaccine uptake,&#xD;
      messaging should be focused on them, but should include adolescents as well. Clinicians also&#xD;
      often lack a clear frame for discussions about HPV vaccination with parents. The topic of&#xD;
      vaccines is a polarizing one for many physicians and their patients (parents and children).&#xD;
      Physicians often find their expertise and recommendations being accepted by parents for&#xD;
      certain areas of their child's care (e.g., diet, seatbelt use), but not others. Providers are&#xD;
      using many strategies in response, but think few are effective. Very little research has been&#xD;
      conducted on clinic interventions that improve vaccine uptake, or on interventions that would&#xD;
      help physicians effectively frame HPV vaccination discussion with parents. With the recent&#xD;
      approval of the new 9-valent vaccine (Gardasil 9), a further premium is placed on effective&#xD;
      communication between parents and physicians communicating about HPV vaccines. The focus in&#xD;
      this project is to employ a developed and efficacious digital intervention on HPV messaging&#xD;
      (GoHealthyGirls.org) as a way to improve the communication and shared decision-making about&#xD;
      HPV vaccination between girls' parents and pediatricians. An effective web-based resource in&#xD;
      pediatric and family practice clinics should increase parents' knowledge, intentions and&#xD;
      motivations to vaccinate, enhance pediatrician-parent shared decision making for HPV&#xD;
      vaccination, and increase HPV vaccination rates.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A clinic-based comparative effectiveness randomized trial will be used to examine the impact&#xD;
      of the GoHealthyGirls website on vaccine-related outcomes and vaccine uptake. Pediatric&#xD;
      clinics within established health care networks in New Mexico will be randomly assigned to&#xD;
      either the usual care clinic-based communication about HPV vaccination (UC) or to usual care&#xD;
      plus web-based dissemination (UC+GHG). Assessments of vaccine-related outcomes, including&#xD;
      shared decision making between parents and physicians, will be assessed at baseline, 3&#xD;
      months, and 9 months. Vaccine uptake and dose adherence will be abstracted from clinic&#xD;
      vaccine records. Comparative effectiveness, sensitivity analysis, and heterogeneity of&#xD;
      treatment effects analyses are planned. An extensive parent and stakeholder engagement plan&#xD;
      will be utilized, and includes an Adolescent HPV Immunization Advocacy Coalition that will&#xD;
      involve parents across New Mexico, and an Adolescent HPV Immunization Expert Advisory Board&#xD;
      that will involve clinicians, vaccine experts and researchers in New Mexico. Quarterly&#xD;
      meetings of these groups will review project plans, protocols, and processes, and link the&#xD;
      project to the communities and population of New Mexico.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 28, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This research project will compare usual care clinic-based communication about HPV vaccination (UC) to usual care plus web-based dissemination (UC+GHG) of information on HPV vaccination to parents and adolescent girls using a pair-matched group-randomized pretest-posttest design protocol. Pediatric/family practice clinics in New Mexico (n=30 clinics) will be pair-mated and one clinic per pair will be randomized to UC+GHG condition via the website, GoHealthyGirls.org. The remaining clinic will continue to receive UC only. Assessment protocols will be conducted at pretest, 3-month follow-up, and 9-month follow-up points, measuring knowledge, compatibility and relative advantage principles in DI, shared decision making, and vaccine adoption by girls. Thus, the proposed trial design will be a 2 (UC v. UC+GHG) intervention x 3 (level of time - pretest vs. 3-month follow-up vs. 9-month follow-up) mixed factorial design with participants nested within clinics.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Vaccine Adoption</measure>
    <time_frame>9-month follow up</time_frame>
    <description>Shot records of initial and second HPV vaccination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parental HPV vaccination knowledge - questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3-month and 9-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of HPV-related knowledge among parents, developed by Perez, et al.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Shared decision-making (SDM-Q9) questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>3-month and 9-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of Shared Decision Making, developed by Kriston, et al.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physician-Patient Communication questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>3-month and 9-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Satisfaction of communication between healthcare provider and parent, developed by Street, et al.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1800</enrollment>
  <condition>Vaccine Decision Making</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Clinic communication - HPV Vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard Usual and Customary HPV Information - CDC pamphlet</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care and Web App on HPV Vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Usual Care and Web app on HPV Vaccine: Vacteens Web app for mobile devices</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vacteens Web app for mobile devices</intervention_name>
    <description>The Web app provides parents of young adolescent girls (ages 11-14) accurate information about HPV Vaccination, and a number of tools to aid informed decision making.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care and Web App on HPV Vaccine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard Usual and Customary HPV Information - CDC pamphlet</intervention_name>
    <description>The usual communication about HPV Vaccination in clinics is for parents to be issued the CDC pamphlet on HPV Vaccination.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Clinic communication - HPV Vaccine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parent of an adolescent girl ages 11-14, adolescent girl has not yet received HPV&#xD;
             vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  adolescent girl has received HPV vaccination&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>26 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>William Lawrence, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Patient Centered Outcomes Research Organization</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>William G Woodall, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>505-925-2316</phone>
    <email>gwoodall@unm.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Marita Brooks, BS</last_name>
    <phone>505-925-2312</phone>
    <email>maritab@unm.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>August 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 24, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 28, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 28, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 28, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Vaccine Decision Making</keyword>
  <keyword>Public Health</keyword>
  <keyword>Health Communication</keyword>
  <keyword>Digital Interventions</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>No plan at this time.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

