<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03269487</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>v1 01.04.2015</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03269487</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PERFECTED WP2: Implementing Optimised Hospital Care</brief_title>
  <acronym>PERFECTED</acronym>
  <official_title>PERFECTED WP2: Implementing the Optimisation of Hospital Care Delivery to Older Adults by NHS Staff Via Action Research</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of East Anglia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of East Anglia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is part of the 5-year long (2013-18) PERFECTED (Peri-operative Enhanced Recovery&#xD;
      hip-fracture Care of paTiEnts with Dementia) National Institute for Health Research (NIHR)&#xD;
      funded research programme.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PERFECTED's aim is to develop and pilot an evidence-based intervention to improve the&#xD;
      hospital care of patients living with dementia who have fractured their hip. This protocol&#xD;
      relates to Work Package 2 (WP2) of PERFECTED only.&#xD;
&#xD;
      By working collaboratively with local clinicians and stakeholders, an action research&#xD;
      (plan-do-study-act) approach will be used to generate knowledge to understand how to best&#xD;
      implement the intervention (PERFECTED Enhanced Recovery Pathway), which was developed from&#xD;
      learning and research undertaken as part of Work Package 1. During the current study the&#xD;
      PERFECTED Enhanced Recovery Pathway (ERP) will be used to optimise care on three&#xD;
      ortho-geriatric wards for 12 months. These wards are located in Norfolk, Nottinghamshire and&#xD;
      Yorkshire. The sole participants are NHS personnel delivering care on selected wards.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection activities (observations, in-field interviews, documentary analysis and&#xD;
      quantitative data generated from the PERFECTED ERP implementation checklist) will determine&#xD;
      the staff training and cultural changes required to implement and maximise adherence to the&#xD;
      PERFECTED ERP. Simultaneously, enabling the identification and exploration of areas of&#xD;
      optimised, satisfactory and sub-optimal care. By working in partnership within and across the&#xD;
      partner wards, action plans to address sub-optimal care will be generated, implemented and&#xD;
      reviewed. Findings will inform the best ways to optimise care via the implementation of the&#xD;
      PERFECTED ERP. Knowledge generated during this study will be used to develop an ERP and staff&#xD;
      training manual. This will aid implementation of the intervention arm of a latter Cluster&#xD;
      Randomised Control Trial (Work Package 3), ensuring the PERFECTED ERP can be utilised in the&#xD;
      real world.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As part of PERFECTED's commitment to Public Patient Involvement (PPI), lay researchers will&#xD;
      be trained to assist with qualitative research activities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 1, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 1, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Day</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PERFECT-ER</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement toolkit</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">270</enrollment>
  <condition>Implementation of Enhanced Recovery Pathway</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthcare professionals in partner sites</arm_group_label>
    <description>NHS employee or student nurse involved in the delivery of care to patients on partner wards in which the PERFECTED ERP is being implemented.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Sole participant group for this study are NHS employees involved in care delivery on&#xD;
        partner hospital wards.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  NHS employee or student nurse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Involved in the delivery of care to patients on partner wards in which the PERFECTED&#xD;
             ERP is being implemented&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        * None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 1, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 30, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 30, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 30, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

