<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02302963</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>17725</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1DP3DK101055</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02302963</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>USS Virginia Closed-Loop Versus SAP Therapy for Hypoglycemia Reduction in T1D</brief_title>
  <official_title>Unified Safety System (USS) Virginia Closed-Loop Versus Sensor Augmented Pump Therapy for Hypoglycemia Reduction in Type 1 Diabetes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Virginia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Stanford University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>TypeZero Technologies, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Virginia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, controlled trial of Unified Safety System (USS) Virginia closed-loop&#xD;
      versus sensor-augmented pump (SAP) therapy for hypoglycemia prevention in subjects with type&#xD;
      1 diabetes and hypoglycemia unawareness and/or risk for hypoglycemia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness of the control system in reducing&#xD;
      hypoglycemia by comparing, in a randomized study, 24 hour control with USS Virginia versus&#xD;
      sensor augmented pump (SAP) therapy in subjects with type 1 diabetes and hypoglycemia&#xD;
      unawareness and/or risk for hypoglycemia. We will also evaluate the effectiveness of the&#xD;
      control system to improve hypoglycemia counterregulation, hypoglycemia awareness, and overall&#xD;
      glycemic control. To achieve this goal, we will conduct pre- and post-intervention inpatient&#xD;
      assessments of hypoglycemia counterregulation and symptom awareness. Subjects randomized to&#xD;
      USS Virginia will participate in two training visits at a monitored outpatient setting for&#xD;
      the step-wise deployment of the cell phone based Artificial Pancreas (AP) System at home. The&#xD;
      first training visit includes training on the study pump and AP System followed by 1 week use&#xD;
      of AP System at home in Pump mode. The second training visit includes additional training on&#xD;
      USS Virginia+AP System and confirmation of independent use by the subject followed by 4 week&#xD;
      use of the AP System at home in Closed Loop mode. Subjects randomized to sensor-augmented&#xD;
      pump therapy will complete 5 weeks of CGM with the home pump.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction in hypoglycemia during closed loop control (assessed by Low Blood Glucose Index [LBGI])</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
    <description>Reduction in hypoglycemia during the study on USS Virginia versus Sensor Augmented Pump (SAP) as assessed by Low Blood Glucose Index (LBGI) from Continuous Glucose Monitoring (CGM) during 1 week of baseline blinded use versus during the last week of intervention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">85</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AP System (DiAs or inControl) with USS Virginia</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subject will complete an 8-hour inpatient assessment of hypoglycemia counterregulation. Subject will then proceed through 7 weeks of training and use of the AP System with USS Virginia and study pump. The inpatient testing will be repeated after wearing the AP System at home.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sensor-Augmented Pump Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subject will complete an 8-hour inpatient assessment of hypoglycemia counterregulation. Subject will then wear a continuous glucose monitor and their own insulin pump at home for 5 weeks. The inpatient testing will be repeated at the completion of the 5 weeks at home.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AP System (DiAs or inControl) with USS Virginia</intervention_name>
    <description>Subject will participate in two 24-hour study insulin pump and AP System training sessions. At the conclusion of each training session, subject will wear the equipment at home for a total of 5 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>AP System (DiAs or inControl) with USS Virginia</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sensor-Augmented Pump Therapy (placebo)</intervention_name>
    <description>Subject will participate in 5 weeks use of CGM and personal insulin pump at home.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sensor-Augmented Pump Therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Clinical diagnosis of type 1 diabetes for at least 1 year. For an individual to be enrolled&#xD;
        at least one criterion from each list must be met:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Criteria for documented hyperglycemia (at least 1 must be met):&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Fasting glucose ≥126 mg/dL (confirmed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Two-hour oral glucose tolerance test (OGTT) glucose ≥200 mg/dL (confirmed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. HbA1c ≥6.5% (confirmed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Random glucose ≥200 mg/dL with symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. No data at diagnosis is available but the participant has a convincing history of&#xD;
             hyperglycemia consistent with diabetes or in the opinion of the investigator&#xD;
             participant has history consistent with type 1 diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Criteria for requiring insulin at diagnosis (at least 1 must be met):&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participant required insulin at diagnosis and continually thereafter&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participant did not start insulin at diagnosis but upon investigator review likely&#xD;
             needed insulin (significant hyperglycemia that did not respond to oral agents) and did&#xD;
             require insulin eventually and used continually&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participant required insulin at diagnosis but continued to be hyperglycemic, had&#xD;
             positive islet cell antibodies - consistent with latent autoimmune diabetes in adults&#xD;
             (LADA) and did require insulin eventually and used continually thereafter&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Use of insulin for the last 12 months or more&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Use of an insulin infusion pump for the last 6 months or longer&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Age 12-70 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HbA1c &lt;10.0% as measured with DCA2000 or equivalent device; if HbA1c &lt;6.0% then&#xD;
                  total daily insulin must be ≥0.5 U/kg&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Risk of hypoglycemia or hypoglycemia unawareness as defined by any of the&#xD;
                  following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clarke Hypoglycemia Perception Awareness questionnaire score of ≥4.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Average Daily Risk Range (ADRR) &gt;40 as assessed from Self-Monitoring Blood&#xD;
                  Glucose (SMBG) readings from the prior month. Subject must have a glucometer that&#xD;
                  can be downloaded for this assessment. The subjects may alternatively provide a&#xD;
                  spreadsheet of their past 30 days of blood glucose values.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Low Blood Glucose Index (LBGI) &gt;2.5 as assessed from SMBG from the prior month or&#xD;
                  LBGI &gt;1.1 as assessed from 1 week of CGM readings from the prior three weeks.&#xD;
                  Subject must have a glucometer or CGM that can be downloaded for this assessment.&#xD;
                  For the glucometer data, the subjects may alternatively provide a spreadsheet of&#xD;
                  their past 30 days of blood glucose values.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subject reports no recognition of hypoglycemia until the glucose is &lt;60 mg/dL and&#xD;
                  no adrenergic symptoms at glucose of 60 mg/dL (shakiness, palpitations,&#xD;
                  diaphoresis).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Able to speak and read English and use basic technology such as a cell phone.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Currently using an insulin-to-carbohydrate ratio to calculate meal bolus sizes.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Access to Internet or cell phone service in the subject's local environment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Willingness to maintain uninterrupted availability via personal cell phone at all&#xD;
                  times during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Willingness to perform SMBG testing 4-6 times daily (before meals, about 2 hours&#xD;
                  after meals and at bedtime, before driving, before exercise, and as indicated)&#xD;
                  during the interventional phases of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Living with a diabetes care partner ≥18 years old who meets the following&#xD;
                  inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Committed to potentially (if randomized to DiAs) participating in all training&#xD;
                  activities involving DiAs components and emergency procedures,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Knowledgeable at all times of the participant's location during the day when&#xD;
                  closed loop is in use,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Committed to maintaining uninterrupted availability via personal cell phone,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Being present and available to provide assistance when the closed loop system is&#xD;
                  being used at night,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Able to speak and read English and use basic technology such as a cell phone, and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absence of known medical condition that in the judgment of the investigator might&#xD;
                  interfere with the completion of the protocol such as the following examples:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Inpatient psychiatric treatment in the past 6 months,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current or recent abuse of alcohol or recreational drugs by history&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A recent injury to body or limb, muscular disorder, use of any medication, any&#xD;
                  carcinogenic disease, or other significant medical disorder if that injury,&#xD;
                  medication, or disease in the judgment of the investigator will affect the&#xD;
                  completion of the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The presence of any of the following is an exclusion for the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Admission for diabetic ketoacidosis in the 12 months prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Severe hypoglycemia resulting in seizure or loss of consciousness in the 3 months&#xD;
             prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Hematocrit less that the lower limit of normal for the assay.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pregnancy, breast-feeding, or intention of becoming pregnant over time of study&#xD;
             procedures; If female and sexually active, must agree to use a form of contraception&#xD;
             to prevent pregnancy while a participant in the study. A negative urine pregnancy test&#xD;
             will be required for all premenopausal women who are not surgically sterile. Subjects&#xD;
             who become pregnant will be discontinued from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Conditions which may increase the risk of induced hypoglycemia such as: known coronary&#xD;
             artery disease, congestive heart failure, history of any cardiac arrhythmia (benign&#xD;
             premature atrial contractions and premature ventricular contractions allowed), history&#xD;
             of seizure disorder, history of cerebrovascular event or transient ischemic attack,&#xD;
             hypoglycemia-induced migraine within the last 6 months, or neurological disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Cystic fibrosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. A known medical condition that in the judgment of the investigator might interfere&#xD;
             with the completion of the protocol such as the following examples:&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Inpatient psychiatric treatment in the past 6 months for either the subject or the&#xD;
             subject's diabetes care partner&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Presence of a known adrenal disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Abnormal liver function tests (transaminase &gt;3 times the upper limit of normal);&#xD;
             testing required for subjects taking medications known to affect liver function or&#xD;
             with diseases known to affect liver function&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Abnormal renal function test results (estimated Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &lt;60&#xD;
             mL/min/1.73m2); testing required for subjects with diabetes duration of greater than 5&#xD;
             years post onset of puberty&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Active gastroparesis&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. If on antihypertensive, thyroid, anti-depressant or lipid lowering medication, lack of&#xD;
             stability on the medication for the past 2 months prior to enrollment in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Uncontrolled thyroid disease (TSH undetectable or &gt;10 mIU/L); testing required within&#xD;
             3 months prior to admission for subjects with a goiter, positive antibodies, or who&#xD;
             are on thyroid hormone replacement, and within one year otherwise&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Current or recent abuse of alcohol or recreational drugs by patient history&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Infectious process not anticipated to resolve prior to study procedures (e.g.&#xD;
             meningitis, pneumonia, osteomyelitis)&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Any skin condition in the area of insertion that prevents safe sensor or pump&#xD;
             placement (e.g. bad sunburn, pre-existing dermatitis, intertrigo, psoriasis, extensive&#xD;
             scarring, cellulitis)&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Diagnosed with celiac disease and not currently following a gluten free diet&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A recent injury to body or limb, muscular disorder, use of any medication, any&#xD;
                  carcinogenic disease, or other significant medical disorder if that injury,&#xD;
                  medication, or disease in the judgment of the investigator will affect the&#xD;
                  completion of the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current use of any of the following drugs and supplements:&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Any medication being taken to lower blood glucose, such as Pramlintide, Metformin,&#xD;
             Glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) Analogs such as Liraglutide, and nutraceuticals&#xD;
             intended to lower blood glucose&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Beta blockers&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Oral glucocorticoids&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Pseudoephedrine&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Any other medication that the investigator believes is a contraindications to the&#xD;
             subject's participation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Stacey M. Anderson, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UVA Center for Diabetes Technology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bruce Buckingham, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Stanford University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stanford</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94305</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Virginia Center for Diabetes Technology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlottesville</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>22903</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://doi.org/10.1089/dia.2019.0018</url>
    <description>Hybrid Closed-Loop Control Is Safe and Effective for People with Type 1 Diabetes Who Are at Moderate to High Risk for Hypoglycemia</description>
  </link>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Anderson SM, Buckingham BA, Breton MD, Robic JL, Barnett CL, Wakeman CA, Oliveri MC, Brown SA, Ly TT, Clinton PK, Hsu LJ, Kingman RS, Norlander LM, Loebner SE, Reuschel-DiVirglio S, Kovatchev BP. Hybrid Closed-Loop Control Is Safe and Effective for People with Type 1 Diabetes Who Are at Moderate to High Risk for Hypoglycemia. Diabetes Technol Ther. 2019 Jun;21(6):356-363. doi: 10.1089/dia.2019.0018. Epub 2019 May 16.</citation>
    <PMID>31095423</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>July 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 24, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 26, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 27, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 22, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 22, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 24, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Virginia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Stacey Anderson</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Medical Director, Center for Diabetes Technology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1 (T1DM)</keyword>
  <keyword>Diabetes Assistant (DiAs)</keyword>
  <keyword>Artificial Pancreas (AP) System</keyword>
  <keyword>Closed-Loop Control (CLC)</keyword>
  <keyword>Unified Safety System (USS) Virginia</keyword>
  <keyword>Sensor Augmented Pump (SAP)</keyword>
  <keyword>Low Blood Glucose Index (LBGI)</keyword>
  <keyword>Continuous Glucose Monitor (CGM)</keyword>
  <keyword>inControl Diabetes Management Platform</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypoglycemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>NIH's Data Sharing Policy on sharing research resources for research purposes to the scientific community will be followed. Data will be stored in a Data Archive Database includes CGM-insulin delivery time series, meal content, boluses, &amp; exercise will be deidentified &amp; retrievable only by subject ID number. The data's real value lies in their precise time stamps - each reading is coded by date &amp; time which makes possible the data to be related to the subjects' daily routine. Individual patterns of demographic &amp; insulin treatment parameters leave open a remote possibility of deductive disclosure of subjects with unusual characteristics. Data can be made available only under a Data-Sharing Agreement that includes: (1) a commitment to using the data only for research purposes &amp; not to identify participants; (2) a commitment to securing the data using appropriate computer technology; &amp; (3) a commitment to destroying or returning the data after analyses are completed.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

