<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01137409</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0811004420</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01137409</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Detecting Heart Disease Using First Pass Imaging With Gated SPECT Perfusion</brief_title>
  <official_title>Detecting Heart Disease Using First Pass Imaging With Gated SPECT Perfusion</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Astellas Pharma US, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to determine if stress first pass imaging in conjunction with a&#xD;
      nuclear scan will improve the sensitivity for detecting heart disease. This study will also&#xD;
      test the usefulness of a nuclear medicine camera, CDLCAM One Pass Angiography system.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this clinical trial, patients with suspected or previously diagnosed coronary artery&#xD;
      disease who are clinically referred for either a treadmill exercise stress/rest SPECT study&#xD;
      or a vasodilatation stress/rest SPECT study will be considered for this protocol. The&#xD;
      vasodilation study may be either adenosine or regadenosin. In addition to the stress study, a&#xD;
      stress/rest echocardiography study and first pass image will also be obtained. The reason to&#xD;
      include echocardiography is to provide an independent measurement of the ejection fraction&#xD;
      during pharmacological stress for comparison to the ejection fraction from the first pass&#xD;
      study and from the ECG-gated SPECT study performed at rest. This will evaluate the added&#xD;
      value of calculation of stress left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) over gated SPECT&#xD;
      resting EF. This information will also assist in evaluating LV dysfunction following&#xD;
      induction of pharmacological stress Nuclear imaging compared with echocardiographic stress&#xD;
      EF, established imaging modalities for assessment of coronary heart disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will include two ECHO imaging sessions and two SPECT imaging sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will undergo a resting first pass image during the administration 99mTc-tetrofosmin;&#xD;
      and a resting ECHO study at an appropriate imaging time. The resting ECHO will also be used&#xD;
      to assess patient imaging window quality and to optimize equipment settings for subsequent&#xD;
      stress images. A rest gated-SPECT image will be acquired at the appropriate imaging time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patient will then undergo a standard vasodilation stress infusion. A first pass image&#xD;
      will be obtained during the administration of 99mTc-tetrofosmin. An ECHO will be obtained&#xD;
      prior to the completion of the infusion. A gated-SPECT study will then be performed at the&#xD;
      appropriate imaging time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tetrofosmin ECG-gated SPECT Imaging:&#xD;
&#xD;
      One hundred patients will be enrolled in the vasodilation stress/rest ECG-gated SPECT&#xD;
      myocardial perfusion imaging group. Imaging time for each session will vary from one and a&#xD;
      half to three hours. A one or two day imaging protocol can be utilized. Depending on what&#xD;
      imaging session is done first (rest or stress), a &quot;one-day&quot; protocol consists of having the&#xD;
      first dose of 99mTc-Tetrofosmin as a low dose of 10-15mCi. The second dose will be the high&#xD;
      dose of 20-40mCi depending on the patient's weight. In the &quot;two-day&quot; protocol, patients will&#xD;
      receive a high dose of 99mTc-Tetrofosmin for both imaging sessions. The dose given will&#xD;
      depend on the patient's weight.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rest Imaging:&#xD;
&#xD;
      If venous access is not already established, the standard universal precautions and 18-20&#xD;
      gauge catheter equipped with a 3-way stopcock will be inserted preferably in the antecubital&#xD;
      vein. The patient will be injected with the appropriate amount of 99mTc-Tetrofosmin. The&#xD;
      first pass image will be acquired during the injection (see first pass protocol). An Early&#xD;
      resting gated-SPECT imaging and an ECHO will be done at 15 minutes and then repeated at 60&#xD;
      minutes (see ECHO protocol).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adenosine Imaging:&#xD;
&#xD;
      If venous access is not already established, the standard universal precautions and 18-20&#xD;
      gauge catheter equipped with a 3-way stopcock will be inserted preferably in the antecubital&#xD;
      vein. Patients will receive an infusion of adenosine at a rate of 140ug/kg/min. After 1.5&#xD;
      minutes of adenosine infusion, the appropriate dose of 99mTc-Tetrofosmin will be injected and&#xD;
      adenosine infusion will continue for 4.5 additional minutes, in compliance with the standard&#xD;
      6-minute infusion protocol and current ASNC guidelines. The first pass image will be acquired&#xD;
      during the injection (see first pass protocol). Blood pressure and heart rate will be&#xD;
      documented every minute. 12 lead ECG will be obtained at baseline and printed once a minute.&#xD;
      There will be continuous monitoring of ECG and symptoms throughout the infusion. The ECHO&#xD;
      will be acquired at 2.5 min of adenosine infusion (see ECHO protocol). An Early resting&#xD;
      gated-SPECT imaging and an ECHO will be done at 15 minutes post infusion and then repeated at&#xD;
      60 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Test Termination End Points (standard criteria)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Symptomatic hypotension, bradycardia or high degree AV Block&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Severe shortness of breath or wheezing&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Completion of protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ST Segment depression &gt;2mm (horizontal or downsloping)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Angina&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Life threatening arrhythmia&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Subject requests to stop&#xD;
&#xD;
      Regadenoson Imaging:&#xD;
&#xD;
      If venous access is not already established, the standard universal precautions and 18-20&#xD;
      gauge catheter equipped with a 3-way stopcock will be inserted preferably in the antecubital&#xD;
      vein.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will receive an infusion of Regadenoson (0.4 mg regadenoson) by rapid intravenous&#xD;
      injection; followed immediately by 5 ml saline flush. 20-40 seconds after the saline flush&#xD;
      Tetrofosmin is injected and a first pass image is done.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will receive an infusion of Regadenoson at a rate of (0.4 mg regadenoson). After 1.5&#xD;
      minutes of Regadenoson infusion, the appropriate dose of 99mTc-Tetrofosmin will be injected&#xD;
      and Regadenoson infusion will continue for 4.5 additional minutes, in compliance with the&#xD;
      standard 6-minute infusion protocol and current ASNC guidelines. The first pass image will be&#xD;
      acquired during the injection (see first pass protocol). Blood pressure and heart rate will&#xD;
      be documented every minute. 12 lead ECG will be obtained at baseline and printed once a&#xD;
      minute. There will be continuous monitoring of ECG and symptoms throughout the infusion. The&#xD;
      ECHO will be acquired at 2.5 min of Regadenoson infusion (see ECHO protocol). An Early&#xD;
      resting gated-SPECT imaging and an ECHO will be done at 15 minutes post infusion and then&#xD;
      repeated at 60 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Test Termination End Points (standard criteria)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Symptomatic hypotension, bradycardia or high degree AV Block&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Severe shortness of breath or wheezing&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Completion of protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ST Segment depression &gt;2mm (horizontal or downsloping)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Angina&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Life threatening arrhythmia&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Subject requests to stop&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treadmill Exercise (Stress) Imaging:&#xD;
&#xD;
      If venous access is not already established, the standard universal precautions and 18-20&#xD;
      gauge catheter equipped with a 3-way stopcock will be inserted preferably in the antecubital&#xD;
      vein. Patients will follow a preset treadmill protocol. ECG's will be continuously monitored&#xD;
      during exercise and are printed out for each stage of exercise. Patients will be injected&#xD;
      with the appropriate amount of 99mTc-Tetrofosmin. The first pass image will be acquired&#xD;
      during the injection (see first pass protocol). Due to logistical difficulties, the ECHO will&#xD;
      not be performed for this imaging session.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Test Termination End Points (standard criteria)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Severe Fatigue&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ST segment depression or elevation &gt;2mm (horizontal or downsloping)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Severe Angina&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Severe Shortness of breath/ wheezing&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Significant drop (20mmHG) in blood pressure&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Significant elevation of blood pressure:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Systolic :&gt; 220mmHG&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Diastolic :&gt; 120mmHG&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Severe lower extremity discomfort&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Signs of severe peripheral circulatory insufficiency: lightheadedness, nausea, pallor&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Onset of second or third degree AV Block&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ventricular Tachycardia&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Symptomatic SVT&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient request to stop&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Completion of Protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  For a Nuclear Imaging Study, patient should reach 85% of age predicted maximum heart&#xD;
           rate prior to the injection of radioisotope (220-age). Once target is reached then the&#xD;
           isotope is injected and patient should exercise for 2 more minutes post injection&#xD;
&#xD;
      Echocardiography Imaging:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Instrument settings will be optimized to ensure the best delineation of the endocardial&#xD;
      borders of the left ventricle. Rest ECHO will be obtained in the standard protocol for both&#xD;
      imaging groups. Patients in the adenosine vasodilatation stress group will have an ECHO&#xD;
      during the infusion of adenosine in the standard views. Patients in the exercise stress group&#xD;
      will have an ECHO immediately after exercise in the standard views. Patients in both groups&#xD;
      will have an ECHO 15 minutes and 60 minutes after stress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2D and 3D- Echocardiography Views&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary views:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Apical four chamber 2D view (2D and color tissue Doppler)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Apical two chamber 2D view (2D and color tissue Doppler)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Apical 3D view&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary 2D views:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Parasternal short axis at base, mid and apex of LV (2D and color tissue Doppler)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Parasternal long axis&#xD;
&#xD;
      First Pass Radionuclide Angiography:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients are prepped as outlined previously including IV placement. For the resting image,&#xD;
      patients are connected to the camera gate device for continuous registration of the ECG.&#xD;
      Patients will be placed against the face of the camera to begin isotope infusion. The camera&#xD;
      will detect the presence of the isotope within the SVC and initiate recording of the data;&#xD;
      real time acquisition progress will be displayed on the computer screen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the acquisition for the treadmill exercise image, patients will be connected to the&#xD;
      camera gate device for continuous registration of the ECG. Patients are placed against the&#xD;
      face of the camera. The height of the camera is set to the patient and &quot;Treadmill tracking&quot;&#xD;
      is set to the &quot;ON&quot; position. At peak exercise, the isotope is injected. The camera will&#xD;
      detect the presence of the isotope within the SVC and initiate recording of the data; real&#xD;
      time acquisition progress is displayed on the computer screen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During acquisition for the adenosine vasodilatation image, patients are connected to the&#xD;
      camera gate device for continuous registration of the ECG. Patients are placed against the&#xD;
      face of the camera. The isotope is infused at 1.5 minutes of adenosine infusion. The camera&#xD;
      will detect the presence of the isotope within the SVC and initiate recording of the data;&#xD;
      real time acquisition progress is displayed on the computer screen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The total image time for the first pass study is 30 seconds.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2010</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine if stress first pass imaging in conjunction with gated SPECT, with or with out low level exercise,will improve the sensitivity for detecting ischemic heart disease</measure>
    <time_frame>First pass imaging done in conjunction with SPECT study</time_frame>
    <description>First pass imaging will be done in conjunction with the clinically indicated SPECT study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine if first pass imaging provides a more reproducible approach for evaluation of both rest and stress global LV function over gated SPECT perfusion imaging compared with 3D echocardiography</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately following administration of regadenoson.</time_frame>
    <description>Echocardiography will be done immediately following the administration of regadenoson.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Ischemic Heart Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Suspected or Diagnosed with Coronary artery disease</arm_group_label>
    <description>All patients with suspected or previously diagnosed coronary artery disease</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients with suspected or previously diagnosed coronary artery disease that are&#xD;
        clinically referred for either a treadmill exercise stress/rest SPECT study or an adenosine&#xD;
        vasodilatation stress/rest SPECT study will be considered for this protocol. Efforts will&#xD;
        be made to enroll equal numbers of men and women for this clinical study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males and females age 18 through 80 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients who are: surgically sterile (hysterectomy or bilateral tubule&#xD;
             libation), at least one year post-menopausal, or have a negative pregnancy test on the&#xD;
             day of treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient consumed food/beverage/medication containing caffeine/methylxanthines up to 12&#xD;
             hours prior to infusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exacerbation of COPD, Asthma (actively wheezing)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sinus node dysfunction in absence of pacemaker&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of Aggrenox (ASA/Dipyridamole), Pentoxifylline (Trental) , or oral Dipyridamole&#xD;
             (Persantine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Atrial fibrillation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant/breast feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non English speaking patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is allergic or intolerant to aminophylline, regadenoson&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has a history of known or suspected bronchospastic lung disease [e.g., asthma,&#xD;
             wheezing, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD, etc.)]&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with first degree or second degree AV block&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Albert Sinusas, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale New Haven Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06510</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 3, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 3, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 4, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 19, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 19, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 20, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

