<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01132898</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>100118</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10-CC-0118</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01132898</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Long-term Clinical Correlates of Traumatic Brain Injury</brief_title>
  <official_title>Long Term Clinical Correlates of TBI: Imaging, Biomarkers, and Clinical Phenotyping Parameters</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Center for Neuroscience and Regenerative Medicine (CNRM)</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United States Department of Defense</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Traumatic brain injury may have a range of effects, from severe and permanent disability to&#xD;
      more subtle functional and cognitive deficits that often go undetected during initial&#xD;
      treatment. To improve treatments and therapies and to provide a uniform quality of care,&#xD;
      researchers are interested in developing more standardized criteria for diagnosing and&#xD;
      classifying different types of traumatic brain injury. By identifying imaging and other&#xD;
      indicators immediately after the injury and during the initial treatment phrase, researchers&#xD;
      hope to better understand the nature and effects of acute traumatic brain injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To study the natural history of traumatic brain injury by examining the changes in brain&#xD;
      scans, blood samples, and brain function over 5 years after a the injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Individuals between 18 and 70 years of age who have had a traumatic brain injury within the&#xD;
      past 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This study will include about eight visits to the NIH Clinical Center over 5 years.&#xD;
           Participants will have four visits in the first year, and one visit each year for the&#xD;
           following 4 years. Each visit will take between 1 and 4 days, and participants will be&#xD;
           in the outpatient clinic for about 8 hours each day of the visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At each study visit, participants will have some or all of the following tests:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Medical history and physical examination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood and urine tests&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Questionnaires and assessments of thinking and memory, which may be spoken aloud,&#xD;
           written down, or entered into a computer&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Imaging scans, such as magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) or positron emission&#xD;
           tomography/computed tomography (PET/CT).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This study does not provide treatment and does not replace any current therapies.&#xD;
           However, participants who are eligible for other National Institutes of Health studies&#xD;
           may be referred to these studies by researchers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective is to contribute to the understanding of non-penetrating traumatic&#xD;
      brain injury (TBI) through the description of the relationships between neuroimaging,&#xD;
      hematological, and extensive functional/cognitive phenotyping measures. We will generate&#xD;
      natural history data for cohort-based comparisons and to serve as the basis for future&#xD;
      hypothesis-driven protocols. In addition, we will create and test a series of new taxonomies&#xD;
      to describe TBI severity and predict outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three hundred adult subjects with a clinical diagnosis of non-penetrating TBI (mild, moderate&#xD;
      and severe) will be enrolled. Subjects will be recruited from NIH, affiliated&#xD;
      hospitals/clinics, and in the community. One hundred adult healthy volunteers without a&#xD;
      history of TBI will be seen for comparison. Additionally, a select group of up to 115 US&#xD;
      government associated personnel experiencing TBI-like symptoms arising after possible&#xD;
      exposure to a non-natural energy source, will be studied (select exposure group). This select&#xD;
      group will require a separate age and sex matched group of 115 unaffected volunteers.&#xD;
      Participants (100) who are not able to travel to the NIH Clinical Center to participate in&#xD;
      the Select Exposure Group study can complete study tests and questionnaires remotely, and&#xD;
      have biospecimens sent to our lab for analysis, as part of the remote select exposure samples&#xD;
      group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a natural history study following a prospective cohort of subjects with a clinical&#xD;
      diagnosis of non-penetrating traumatic brain injury with a cross-sectional sub-study.&#xD;
      Subjects will be enrolled in the prospective cohort within one year of their head injury and&#xD;
      then followed periodically for five years, with neuroimaging, including Magnetic Resonance&#xD;
      Imaging (MRI), hematological, and extensive functional/cognitive phenotyping measures.&#xD;
      Subjects will be enrolled in the cross-sectional sub-study within five years of their head&#xD;
      injury and may be evaluated with MRI, hematological, and functional/cognitive measures&#xD;
      usually within a single visit. However, procedures may be scheduled during multiple visits,&#xD;
      depending on the number of procedures performed. Study participants may be offered standard&#xD;
      of care rehabilitation therapies provided at no cost by Investigators and supervised by Dr.&#xD;
      Chan. Tests will be subject to investigator discretion and subject willingness to participate&#xD;
      in evaluation. After first MRI, future MRI s will be obtained based on subject willingness&#xD;
      and investigator discretion from findings on previous imaging. Subjects will be stratified&#xD;
      according to findings into cohorts for comparison. Subjects will not be treated with&#xD;
      experimental therapies as part of the research study. This study will provide direct benefit&#xD;
      to subjects as they will receive sensitive neuro-imaging and clinical testing that may have&#xD;
      diagnostic value and rehabilitation therapies that might not be provided to them in the&#xD;
      community. In addition to the TBI patient group, a longitudinal control group comprised of&#xD;
      healthy volunteers will be collected. The control group participants may complete the&#xD;
      Neuroimaging (MRI without gadolinium), hematological and functional/cognitive phenotyping&#xD;
      measures as the TBI patient population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The prospective select exposure group of US government associated personnel will be followed&#xD;
      periodically for a total of six years. Subjects may complete neuroimaging, including Magnetic&#xD;
      Resonance Imaging (MRI), hematological, and extensive functional/cognitive, auditory,&#xD;
      vestibular, and oculomotor phenotyping measures. In addition to the select exposure group, a&#xD;
      longitudinal control group comprised of unaffected volunteers matched to this group will be&#xD;
      collected. The control group participants will complete the same Neuroimaging (MRI without&#xD;
      gadolinium), hematological and functional/cognitive phenotyping measures as the select&#xD;
      exposure patient population. Additionally, if a select exposure matched control participant&#xD;
      is subsequently exposed, they may enroll into the select exposure group arm of the study for&#xD;
      pre and post exposure analysis. Participants who are unable to travel to the NIH Clinical&#xD;
      Center to participate can remote consent, answer questionnaires remotely via telephone or&#xD;
      electronic communication methods, and have biospecimens sent to our lab for analysis.&#xD;
      Participants enrolled in the any arm of the study who are unable to travel to NIH for any&#xD;
      study visit may be asked to answer questions electronically (telephone, email,&#xD;
      videoconferencing if within the US, etc) to allow for some data collection to occur at each&#xD;
      time point.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome Measures&#xD;
&#xD;
      A variety of outcome measures will be used including MRI, to include Diffusion Tensor Imaging&#xD;
      (DTI), Dynamic Susceptibility Contrast (DSC), and functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging&#xD;
      (fMRI), high field 7T MRI. In addition, extensive and sensitive clinical phenotyping will be&#xD;
      performed to assess functional and cognitive impairment, including auditory, vestibular, and&#xD;
      oculomotor testing, and quality of life assessments. Blood and saliva (buccal cells may be&#xD;
      collected in lieu of whole blood for subjects unwilling or unable to provide blood draw) may&#xD;
      also be collected and sent to a biorepository for future analysis if subject agrees to&#xD;
      participation in sample collection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 31, 2011</start_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary outcome measure will be to observe changes in the TBI Common Data Elements over time.</measure>
    <time_frame>30, 90, 180 days post injury, then annually out to 5 years.</time_frame>
    <description>See NINDS Common Data Elements for TBI</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in other clinical phenotyping measures over time</measure>
    <time_frame>30, 90, 180 days post injury, then annually out to 5 years.</time_frame>
    <description>Comprehensive clinical phenotyping assessments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>6</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">560</enrollment>
  <condition>Traumatic Brain Injury</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>cross-sectional TBI</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants with a mild, moderate, or severe Traumatic Brain Injury enrolled within 5 years from injury. Seen at only one visit.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HV</arm_group_label>
    <description>Healthy Volunteer with no history of TBI</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective TBI</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants with a mild, moderate, or severe Traumatic Brain Injury enrolled within 1 year from injury.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Remote Select Exposure Samples</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants who are unable to travel to the NIH Clinical Center to participate can remote consent, answer questionnaires remotely, and have biospecimens sent to our lab for analysis.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Select Exposure Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>US government associated personnel experiencing TBI-like symptoms arising after possible exposure to a non-natural energy source</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Select Exposure Matched Unaffected</arm_group_label>
    <description>a longitudinal control group comprised of unaffected volunteers matched to the Select Exposure group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Three hundred adult subjects with a clinical diagnosis of non-penetration TBI will be&#xD;
        enrolled. Recruitment will occur from NIH, affiliated hospitals/clinics in the community as&#xD;
        well as local practioners offices. One hundred healthy volunteers without a history of TBI&#xD;
        will be recruited to compare outcomes to TBI participants. A select exposure group of up to&#xD;
        96 US government associated personnel experiencing TBI-like symptoms arising after possible&#xD;
        exposure to a non-natural energy source will be studied. An age and sex matched cohort of&#xD;
        non TBI healthy volunteers will be recruited for comparison (n=96). One hundred&#xD;
        participants who are unable to travel to the NIH Clinical Center to participate but would&#xD;
        like to participate in the study can answer questionnaires remotely, and have biospecimens&#xD;
        sent to our lab for analysis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects eligible for participation in the TBI prospective cohort must meet the following&#xD;
        inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of non-penetrating mild, moderate, or severe TBI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Injury occurred less than one year before enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 years of age and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide informed consent or with a legally-authorized representative able to&#xD;
             provide consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects eligible for participation in the cross-sectional sub-study must meet the&#xD;
        following inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of non-penetrating mild, moderate, or severe TBI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Injury occurred less than five years before enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 years of age and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide informed consent or with a legally-authorized representative able to&#xD;
             provide consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects eligible for participation in the healthy volunteer control group must meet the&#xD;
        following inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to lie flat for up to 2 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Good general medical and psychological health based on History and Physical (H&amp;P)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects eligible for participation in the Select Exposure Matched Unaffected volunteer&#xD;
        control group must meet the following inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to lie flat for up to 2 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Good general medical and psychological health based on History and Physical (H&amp;P)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects eligible for participation in the Select Exposure Matched Unaffected volunteer&#xD;
        control group must meet the following inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Good general medical and psychological health based on History and Physical (H&amp;P)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects eligible for participation in the Remote Select Exposure Samples cohort must meet&#xD;
        the following inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        --Referral from US State Department, Department of Health and Human Services or other&#xD;
        governmental entity based on their assessment of symptomatology and potential exposure (may&#xD;
        include, for example, abnormal auditory sensations and subsequent oculomotor, vestibular,&#xD;
        and cognitive symptoms)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 years of age and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide informed consent (telephone or electronic signature)&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects are not eligible for participation in the prospective cohort if any of the&#xD;
        following conditions exist:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to MRI scanning including certain metal implants or devices such as:&#xD;
             cardiac pacemaker, insulin infusion pump, implanted drug infusion device, cochlear,&#xD;
             otologic, or ear implant, transdermal medication patch (Nitroglycerine) that cannot be&#xD;
             removed for the study, body piercing(s), bone/joint pin, screw, nail, plate, wire&#xD;
             sutures or surgical staples, shunts, cerebral aneurysms clips, shrapnel or other metal&#xD;
             imbedded in a patient s body (such as from war wounds or accidents or previous work in&#xD;
             metal fields or machines that may have left any metallic fragments in or near the&#xD;
             patient s eyes).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Multiple trauma or accidents in the past with non-certainty that metal objects are&#xD;
             still present in the body&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Conditions precluding entry into the scanners (e.g. morbid obesity, claustrophobia,&#xD;
             etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are breast-feeding may enroll in the study, but will not receive PET-MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to read or speak enough English to complete the clinical phenotyping&#xD;
             testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical or Psychological instability such that the subject could not reasonably be&#xD;
             expected to fulfill the study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Penetrating head injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects are not eligible for participation in the cross-sectional sub-study if any of the&#xD;
        following conditions exist:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to MRI scanning including certain metal implants or devices such as:&#xD;
             cardiac pacemaker, insulin infusion pump, implanted drug infusion device, cochlear,&#xD;
             otologic, or ear implant, transdermal medication patch (Nitroglycerine) that cannot be&#xD;
             removed for the study, body piercing(s), bone/joint pin, screw, nail, plate, wire&#xD;
             sutures or surgical staples, shunts, cerebral aneurysms clips, shrapnel or other metal&#xD;
             imbedded in a patient s body (such as from war wounds or accidents or previous work in&#xD;
             metal fields or machines that may have left any metallic fragments in or near the&#xD;
             patient s eyes).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Multiple trauma or accidents in the past with non-certainty that metal objects are&#xD;
             still present in the body&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Conditions precluding entry into the scanners (e.g. morbid obesity, claustrophobia,&#xD;
             etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to read or speak enough English to complete the clinical phenotyping&#xD;
             testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical or Psychological instability such that the subject could not reasonably be&#xD;
             expected to fulfill the study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Penetrating head injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects are not eligible to participate in the Select Exposure cohort if any of the&#xD;
        following conditions exist:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are breast-feeding may enroll in the study, but will not receive PET-MRI or&#xD;
             gadolinium.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to read or speak enough English to complete the clinical phenotyping testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical or Psychological instability such that the subject could not reasonably be&#xD;
             expected to fulfill the study requirements (such schizophrenia, uncontrolled&#xD;
             hypertension, serious heart, lung, or kidney disease, or other condiditon that would&#xD;
             make participation unsafe)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects are not eligible for participation in the healthy volunteer control group if any&#xD;
        of the following conditions exist:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to MRI scanning including certain metal implants or devices such as:&#xD;
             cardiac pacemaker, insulin infusion pump, implanted drug infusion device, cochlear,&#xD;
             otologic, or ear implant, transdermal medication patch (Nitroglycerine) that cannot be&#xD;
             removed for the study, body piercing(s), bone/joint pin, screw, nail, plate, wire&#xD;
             sutures or surgical staples, shunts, cerebral aneurysms clips, shrapnel or other metal&#xD;
             imbedded in a patient s body (such as from war wounds or accidents or previous work in&#xD;
             metal fields or machines that may have left any metallic fragments in or near the&#xD;
             patient s eyes).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to read or speak enough English to complete the clinical phenotyping&#xD;
             testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of a head injury, regardless of cause:.(Causes including: vehicle/bicycle&#xD;
             accidents, falls, sports injuries, firearm injuries, blast injuries, violent shaking,&#xD;
             etc)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight more than 250 lbs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Height greater than 6 4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any current or prior alcohol or substance abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Heavy alcohol use: The Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA)&#xD;
        defines heavy alcohol use as binge drinking on 5 or more days in the past month. SAMHSA&#xD;
        defines binge drinking as 5 or more alcoholic drinks for males or 4 or more alcoholic&#xD;
        drinks for females on the same occasion (i.e., at the same time or within a couple of hours&#xD;
        of each other) on at least 1 day in the past month.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects are not eligible for participation in the Select Exposure Matched Unaffected&#xD;
        volunteer group if any of the following conditions exist:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to read or speak enough English to complete the clinical phenotyping&#xD;
             testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any current or prior heavy alcohol or substance use.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a medical or psychological condition, such schizophrenia, uncontrolled&#xD;
             hypertension, serious heart, lung, or kidney disease, or other condition that would&#xD;
             make it difficult for to do the study tests, might make participation unsafe, or would&#xD;
             interfere with the study result&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects are not eligible for participation in the Remote Select Exposure Samples group if&#xD;
        any of the following conditions exist:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a blood disorder (such as anemia, bleeding disorders such as hemophilia, blood&#xD;
             clots, and blood cancers such as leukemia, lymphoma, and myeloma) which would make&#xD;
             participation in a blood draw dangerous, or would interfere with the study results&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a medical or psychological condition, such schizophrenia, uncontrolled&#xD;
             hypertension serious heart, lung, or kidney disease, or other condition that would&#xD;
             make it difficult to complete the study tests, might make participation unsafe, or&#xD;
             would interfere with the study result&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Leighton Chan, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andre J Van Der Merwe</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-4733</phone>
    <email>andre.vandermerwe@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Leighton Chan, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-4733</phone>
    <email>chanle@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2010-CC-0118.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 29, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 27, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 27, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 28, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Traumatic Brain Injury</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
  <keyword>Functional Level</keyword>
  <keyword>DTI</keyword>
  <keyword>Neuropsychological Assessment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Injuries, Traumatic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

