<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01137266</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NL2073208008</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01137266</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Transcutaneous Electrical Nerve Stimulation on Pain and Disability in Patients With Osteoarthritis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Transcutaneous Electrical Nerve Stimulation on Pain and Disability in Patients With Osteoarthritis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Maxima Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Philips Electronics Nederland BV</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Maxima Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the effects of transcutaneous electrical nerve&#xD;
      stimulation (TENS) on pain and mobility by comparing different stimulation sitesP:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. the location with the lowest resistance&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. the location that causes an irradiation sensation&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. a random stimulation site (but within a 10x10cm area of the irradiation site). The&#xD;
           effect is defined as the pain VAS baseline-measurement before treatment minus the pain&#xD;
           VAS repeat-measurement after the given treatment&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      SUMMARY&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rationale: In clinical practice the position of TENS electrodes appears to be critical to&#xD;
      success. It is claimed that electrodes should target areas with high neural density and where&#xD;
      nerve bundles come close to the body surface. These areas are likely to have low skin&#xD;
      resistances. Research in the field of electro-analgesia suggests areas of low skin resistance&#xD;
      are linked to TENS stimulation points, and that this lower skin resistance may reflect areas&#xD;
      with a higher density of neural tissue. When stimulated these areas are likely to generate&#xD;
      larger nerve activity and potentially a greater analgesic outcome. For this reason many&#xD;
      acupuncturist use a point finder to locate the optimal site to insert the acupuncture needle.&#xD;
      To date the relationship between the skin resistance of the areas stimulated by TENS and pain&#xD;
      relief is not known.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At present, optimal sites for electrode positioning is made ad hoc using a trial and error&#xD;
      approach. This may result in electrodes being positioned at sub-optimal sites. The Philips&#xD;
      new electronic pain relief device contains an array, or matrix, of small electrodes. Using&#xD;
      this array, the device can measure electrical skin properties. In addition, the user can&#xD;
      select which electrodes in the array are active and can adjust the intensity of those&#xD;
      electrodes so that stimulation can be targeted to a specific location. In this way it is&#xD;
      possible to investigate whether stimulating areas of low skin resistance has an effect on&#xD;
      pain relief.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With a novel matrix TENS electrode we would like to investigate the TENS outcome for&#xD;
      different electrode specifically chosen locations versus randomly chosen locations. Randomly&#xD;
      chosen locations are defined as an area of approximately 10x10 cm around the specifically&#xD;
      chosen location in which the random simulation point is chosen. The outcome of the specific&#xD;
      vs. random stimulation will be measured with as primary outcome pain and mobility and as&#xD;
      secondary outcome strength, joint range, and quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: Determine effects of transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation (TENS) on pain&#xD;
      and mobility by comparing different stimulation sites; 1) the location with the lowest&#xD;
      resistance, 2) the location that causes an irradiation sensation, 3) a random stimulation&#xD;
      site (but within a 10x10cm area of the irradiation site). The effect is defined as the pain&#xD;
      VAS baseline-measurement before treatment minus the pain VAS repeat-measurement after the&#xD;
      given treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: double-blind intervention study&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population: Patients with chronic pain arise from osteo-arthritis in one or both knees&#xD;
      Age (&gt;18y), sex and ethnic background are not relevant&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention (if applicable): Patients receive a 3 times 30 minutes TENS treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main study parameters/endpoints: The primary outcome parameters are pain (VAS) and mobility&#xD;
      (PDI and 6 min walk). Secondary outcome parameters are strength (MVC) and range-of-motion&#xD;
      (ROM) in knee extension and quality of life (SF36).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nature and extent of the burden and risks associated with participation, benefit and group&#xD;
      relatedness: There is no risk for the patients. The burden for the participants is 3 times 1&#xD;
      hour.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the effect of TENS on pain and mobility for each treatment group separately. Also determine the differences of the effect of TENS by comparing different stimulation sites;</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>outcomes of the tests are stored at the PC. If all results of all patients are ready. Results will be statistically analysed.This will be in 1 year.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>relationship between skin resistance values before stimulation with the sensations during TENS.Explore whether there is a relation between physiological or psychological characteristics of patients and outcome of TENS and user satisfaction questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>outcomes of the tests are stored at the PC. If all results of all patients are ready. Results will be statistically analysed.This will be in 1 year.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">72</enrollment>
  <condition>Osteoarthritis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>skin resistence</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>1) the location with the lowest resistance</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>irradiation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>2) the site that causes an irradiation sensation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>random</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>3) a random stimulation site.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TENS</intervention_name>
    <description>TENS</description>
    <arm_group_label>irradiation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>random</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>skin resistence</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  osteo-arthritis patients diagnosed by medical professional&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  at least 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  VAS higher than 40mm, lower than 70mm (on a 100 mm VAS scale) at the moment of the&#xD;
             investigation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pain symptoms duration longer than 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unable to comprehend instructions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unable to co-operate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  recent bleeding tissue or haemorrhage in knee&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  epilepsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  advanced cardiovascular conditions, e.g. severe angina or cardiac arrhythmias&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pacemakers or cochlear implants&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  sensory loss of the area to be treated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  devitalised skin e.g. after recent radiotherapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  local acute skin conditions e.g. eczema, dermatitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  doubtful diagnoses&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  global, multiple location pain (other than both knees)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  people who undergo currently a TENS treatment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>A Kolen, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Philips Research Eindhoven</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Maxima Medical Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Eindhoven</city>
        <state>Noord-brabant</state>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 28, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 3, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 4, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 7, 2010</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 7, 2010</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">October 8, 2010</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>A. Kolen</name_title>
    <organization>Philips Research Eindhoven</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>chronic pain osteo-arthritis in one or both knees, adults</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

