<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01130311</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AgaKhanU</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>091014MED</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>09014MED</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01130311</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Replacement of Vitamin D in Patients With Active Tuberculosis</brief_title>
  <acronym>SUCCINCT</acronym>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Placebo-Controlled, Double-Blinded, 250-Subject Clinical Trial of Vitamin D Replacement in Patients With Pulmonary Tuberculosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Aga Khan University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dow University of Health Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Aga Khan University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Tuberculosis is a global public health problem. One third of the world's population is&#xD;
      infected with tuberculosis (TB) with almost 2 million deaths per year globally. According to&#xD;
      the WHO, Pakistan ranks 8th amongst the 22 high TB burden countries, with an estimated&#xD;
      prevalence is 263 cases /100,000 populations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In spite of effective therapy for drug sensitive TB, treatment failure occurs frequently&#xD;
      leading to concerns for the emergence of multi-drug resistant (MDR) and extensively drug&#xD;
      resistant (XDR) mycobacterial strains. Therefore in the recent years, interest has been&#xD;
      generated regarding the role of adjuvant immunomodulating therapy for the treatment of TB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      WHO has classified tuberculosis by disease severity into 3 distinct categories; mild,&#xD;
      moderate and severe according to clinical presentations and host factors. Severity of disease&#xD;
      has been linked to mycobacterium genotypes and with host factors such as vitamin D deficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vitamin D is a hormone produced by the body in response to sun exposure. Independent of it's&#xD;
      effects on bone mineralization, vitamin D is recognized to have numerous immune modulating&#xD;
      effects; some specific to mycobacterium tuberculosis. Therefore vitamin D may enhance the&#xD;
      host immune responses against the pathogen. Vitamin D status can be accurately determined by&#xD;
      measuring the serum levels of 25-(OH) D3. A recent systemic review and meta-analysis explored&#xD;
      the association between low serum vitamin D and risk of active tuberculosis and concluded&#xD;
      that patients with tuberculosis have lower serum levels of vitamin D than healthy controls&#xD;
      when matched for sex, age, ethnicity, diet and geographical location.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vitamin D deficiency is not a life threatening condition. It usually is unrecognized or can&#xD;
      present with generalized 'aches and pains' due to osteomalacia. The recommended dose for&#xD;
      treatment of vitamin D deficiency is 200,000 IU/ month or 50,000 IU/ week, both given for 2&#xD;
      months or until the serum vitamin D level is &gt; 30 ng/ml. Bone mineral density changes are&#xD;
      usually completed by 10 weeks of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that by replacing vitamin D in patients with active pulmonary&#xD;
      tuberculosis, the 'Time to Recovery' can be shortened.Our aims are to determine whether&#xD;
      replacing patients with insufficient and deficient levels of vitamin D affects the clinical&#xD;
      outcome of the disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Tuberculosis Tuberculosis (TB) is a global emergency. In 2004, there were an estimated 8.9&#xD;
      million new cases and 1.7 million deaths due to the disease1. In Pakistan, pulmonary&#xD;
      tuberculosis (TB) is a major public health problem. The population of Pakistan is 160,943,000&#xD;
      with an estimated prevalence of all cases of tuberculosis at 263/100,000, an incidence of&#xD;
      smear positive pulmonary TB of 181/100,000, and a mortality of 34/100,0002.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The management of TB remains a complicated issue even with the availability of effective&#xD;
      anti-tuberculous drugs. One important aspect of this issue has been the difficulty&#xD;
      clinicians' face in measuring clinical response in these patients, especially in&#xD;
      smear-negative pulmonary and extra-pulmonary disease. Christian et al 3. have recently&#xD;
      developed and validated a simple clinical score for the evaluation of TB patients. The score&#xD;
      is based on eleven clinical variables, which were obtained from the WHO clinical manual for&#xD;
      TB. These included self-reported parameters (e.g., cough, hemoptysis, dyspnoea, chest pain&#xD;
      and night sweats), and signs comprising of anemic conjunctivae, tachycardia, positive&#xD;
      findings at lung auscultation, axillary temperature &gt;37.0˚C, body mass index (BMI) and middle&#xD;
      upper arm circumference (MUAC). Each variable contributes 1 point, except for BMI and MUAC&#xD;
      which contribute 2 points each, giving a maximum score of 13. Using this, score patients can&#xD;
      be divided into 3 severity classes, providing an easy tool for clinical follow up and&#xD;
      prognosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vitamin D Vitamin D is normally synthesized in the skin under the influence of sunlight or&#xD;
      ingested, It is readily metabo-lized in the liver to form 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D), the&#xD;
      accepted measure of vitamin D status. 25(OH)D is then further metabolized by the 1&#xD;
      hydroxylase enzyme to its biologically active metabolite, 1 , 25 dihy-droxyvitamin D (1&#xD;
      ,25[OH]2D) 4,5 . Activated vitamin D circulates with a binding protein and enters the target&#xD;
      cell to interact with its nuclear receptor. This complex then combines with the retinoic acid&#xD;
      X receptor to form a heterodimer, which in turn interacts with the Vitamin D response element&#xD;
      on the target gene. By increasing in-testinal calcium and phosphate absorption6, increasing&#xD;
      renal calcium reabsorption, and enhancing PTH-mediated bone resorption (via its effect on&#xD;
      RANKL), vitamin D has the net effect of increasing the serum cal-cium and phosphate&#xD;
      concentrations. Additionally, the vitamin D receptor element is present on multiple genes,&#xD;
      the vitamin D receptor in many organs, and 1-alpha hydroxylase activity occurs in extrarenal&#xD;
      tissues7. These local tissue effects are responsible for the non-mineral-related effects of&#xD;
      vitamin D; such as cell differentiation and proliferation and immune regulation8.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vitamin D deficiency The two most common causes of vitamin D deficiency remains decreased&#xD;
      intake of vitamin D containing food and reduced sun exposure. The major source of vitamin D&#xD;
      is exposure to sunlight, anything that diminishes the transmission or penetration of solar&#xD;
      UVB into the skin will affect the cutaneous synthesis of vitamin D3. Vita-min D deficiency&#xD;
      can therefore occur in people who live without sun exposure (including those whose skin is&#xD;
      constantly protected from the sun by protective clothing, indoor life styles and sunscreen&#xD;
      use.). In addition, very few foods naturally contain vitamin D and foods that are fortified&#xD;
      with with vitamin D are often inadequate to satisfy the vitamin D requirements. Serum levels&#xD;
      of less than 20 ng/mL (50 nmol/L) of 25-OH vitamin D are a commonly accepted cutoff for&#xD;
      vitamin D deficiency , whereas levels between 20 and 30 ng/mL (50 to 75 nmol/L), are&#xD;
      considered insufficiency9,10.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Asymptomatic or minimally symptomatic vitamin D deficiency is increasingly being recognized&#xD;
      around the world. In Pakistan, a number of small studies have identified a high prevalence of&#xD;
      vitamin D deficiency in pa-tient populations that include those presenting with hip&#xD;
      fractures, obstetric cases and those attending ambulatory care clinics. Risk factors include&#xD;
      a history of poor nutrition, lack of exposure to sunlight, and a low socioeco-nomic status.&#xD;
      Zuberi LM et al11 reported that 92% of outpatients presenting to the AKUH, were vitamin D&#xD;
      defi-cient; 62% had severe, 24% moderate and 8% had mild deficiency. Almost half of all these&#xD;
      patients (including those with severe deficiency) were asymptomatic. Two separate studies&#xD;
      from our center involving healthy, as-ymptomatic volunteers have identified a high prevalence&#xD;
      of vitamin D deficiency (unpublished data). Baig MA et al12, in a study on outpatients from&#xD;
      two public hospitals in Karachi, identified that 92% patients were vitamin D deficient and&#xD;
      that the most severe form of D deficiency was seen in patients with tuberculosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vitamin D Replacement Nutritional deficiency (25OHD &lt;20 ng/ml [50 nmol/L]) requires treatment&#xD;
      with 600,000 IU/month or 50,000 IU/week) 13. In this study we plan to give 600,000 IU/month&#xD;
      for 2 months. Repeat testing for vitamin D will be performed at 8 weeks. If the levels are&#xD;
      &lt;30ng/ml then treatment will be repeated for further 2 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vitamin D replacement is generally very safe. Toxicity, with the development of&#xD;
      hypercalciuria and hypercal-cemia occurs only at 25OHD levels above 88 ng/ml (220 nmol/L)&#xD;
      14,15 . In 1997, the National Academy of Sci-ences defined the Safe Upper Limit for vitamin D&#xD;
      as 2000 U/day14 but newer data however indicate that higher doses are safe at least over a&#xD;
      several-month period16.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The benefits of vitamin D replacement occur gradually; in one study, skeletal effects were&#xD;
      seen upto 10 months after a 5 week course of therapy17.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vitamin D and Tuberculosis Clinical studies suggest that vitamin D enhances antimycobacterial&#xD;
      immunity, and that deficiency is associated with susceptibility to active disease18,19. High&#xD;
      doses of vitamin D were widely used to treat active TB in the pre-antibiotic era. More&#xD;
      recently, case-control studies have demonstrated that a vegetarian diet (low in vitamin D) is&#xD;
      an independent risk factor for active TB in South Asians18 and that patients with TB who are&#xD;
      of Gujarati Hindu ethnic origin have significantly higher rates of vitamin D deficiency than&#xD;
      ethnically matched tuberculin-positive TB contacts. Similarly, Gibney et al, documented a&#xD;
      gradation of vitamin D levels in African immigrants to Aus-tralia, with patients with latent&#xD;
      TB having lower levels as compared to controls, while patients with active or past history of&#xD;
      active TB had levels lower than those with latent infection20. A recent systematic review and&#xD;
      meta-analysis 21explored the association between low serum vitamin D and risk of active&#xD;
      tuberculosis and con-cluded that patients with tuberculosis have lower serum levels of&#xD;
      vitamin D than healthy controls when matched for sex, age, ethnicity, diet and geographical&#xD;
      location.&#xD;
&#xD;
      1 ,25(OH)2D has no direct antimycobacterial action, but it does induce antituberculous&#xD;
      activity in vitro in both monocytes and macrophages22.Several mechanisms of action have been&#xD;
      proposed. Exogenous 1 ,25(OH)2D in-duces a superoxide burst23 and enhances phagolysosome&#xD;
      fusion in Mycobacterium tuberculosis-infected macrophages; both phenomena are mediated by&#xD;
      phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase, suggesting that this response is initiated by binding membrane&#xD;
      vitamin D receptor (VDR) 24.1 ,25(OH)2D also modulates immune responses by binding nuclear&#xD;
      VDR, where it up-regulates protective innate host responses, including induction of nitric&#xD;
      oxide synthase25.Recently, 25(OH)D has also been shown to support messenger RNA induction of&#xD;
      the antimicrobial peptide cathelicidin LL-37, which possesses antituberculous activity26.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although the association of vitamin D deficiency and tuberculosis has been documented in&#xD;
      epidemiological and clinical studies, a causal role is yet to be verified. Interestingly&#xD;
      isoniazid and rifampicin therapy has been shown to decrease vitamin D levels, raising the&#xD;
      question of whether low vitamin D levels could be a consequence of disease27. Additionally,&#xD;
      the affect of replacing vitamin D in the prevention and treatment of tuberculosis has not&#xD;
      been studied in a systematic manner. There is, therefore, a need for a randomized controlled&#xD;
      trial to evaluate the effect of vitamin D supplementation on antimycobacterial host response&#xD;
      and clinical recovery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Immune responses to Mycobacterium tuberculosis Restriction of infection by M. tuberculosis is&#xD;
      dependent on effective macrophage activation which is facilitated by the recruitment of&#xD;
      leucocytes to the site of infection. The protective role of CD4+, IFN-γ producing T cells has&#xD;
      been confirmed in both acute and chronic mycobacterial infections28. Macrophage TNFα plays a&#xD;
      critical role in granuloma formation and in restriction of disease related pathology29. TNF-α&#xD;
      and IFN-γ activate granu-loma formation by C-C family of chemokines, CCL2, CCL3, CCL4, CCL5&#xD;
      and the C-X-C chemokine family; CXCL8, CXCL9, CXCL10 and CXCL1230 .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chemokines play a critical role in determining both activation and migration patterns of&#xD;
      circulating monocytes in the blood. CXCL9 is an early predictive marker for IFNγ secreting&#xD;
      cells, and is found to be increased in re-sponse to M. tuberculosis antigen stimulation. CCL5&#xD;
      and IFNγ-induced CXCL10 also contribute to the granu-lomatous response31.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous studies have shown the utility of mycobacterial antigens such as, from RD1 antigens&#xD;
      early secreted and activated T cell (ESAT)6 in investigating specific immune responses in&#xD;
      individuals infected with M. tuber-culosis. Specific immune profiles have been shown to be&#xD;
      present in TB patients which are coordinate with their disease status32,33.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A study of household contacts of TB patients showed that the dynamics of cytokine response to&#xD;
      mycobacterial antigens driven by IL10 was central to protection against, and the development&#xD;
      of M. tuberculosis infection, and that a peak inflammatory cytokine response at 6 months was&#xD;
      present in those individuals who did not develop disease34 .&#xD;
&#xD;
      We have shown that circulating CXCL9 levels in TB patients differ according to severity of&#xD;
      disease35. In addi-tion, mycobacterial antigen induced CXCL9 responses correlate with IFNγ,&#xD;
      and that these are greater in local-ised as compared with disseminated disease36. A recent&#xD;
      study has also shown the relevance of using both CCL2 (MCP-2) and CXCL10 (IP-10) as&#xD;
      biomarkers for tuberculosis37,38 . In this study we hope to determine immune parameters in&#xD;
      patients prior to and post-vitamin D treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To measure difference in Clinical RESPONSES between test and control groups after treatment with vitamin D</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the effects of vitamin D replacement on cytokine responses</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Stimulated and unstimulated IFN-gamma responses between the two groups will be compared</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">259</enrollment>
  <condition>Tuberculosis, Pulmonary</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cholecalciferol (Vitamin D)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intramuscular injection of VITAMIN D, 600,000 UNITS WILL BE GIVEN TO THE TEST SUBJECTS AT WEEK 0 and at week 4 OF the TRIAL</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SALINE, INTRAMUSCULAR INJECTION</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>NORMAL SALINE INJECTION WILL BE GIVEN TO THE CONTROL SUBJECTS at week 0 and week 4 of the trial</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cholecalciferol</intervention_name>
    <description>Intramuscular injection of 600,000 units of Cholecalciferol for 2 doses given at week 0 and week 4</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cholecalciferol (Vitamin D)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>VITAMIN D</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Saline injection</intervention_name>
    <description>normal saline, intramuscular preperation,given in 2 doses at week 0 and week 4 of trial</description>
    <arm_group_label>SALINE, INTRAMUSCULAR INJECTION</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults (≥16 years on 1st March 2009) Males and Nonpregnant females&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active Pulmonary Tuberculosis diagnosed by Sputum Smear positivity for Acid fast&#xD;
             bacilli (AFB)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis within one week of inclusion into study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not already on antituberculous treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not receiving vitamin D replacement or supplementation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of having been treated with antimycobacterial therapy for &lt; 6 months or with &lt;&#xD;
             4 first-line anti-tuberculous drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Extra- pulmonary TB&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immune suppressed; with HIV infection, hepatic, renal failure, malignancy, diabetes&#xD;
             mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sarcoidosis, hyperparathyroidism&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Already on or requiring corticosteroids, immunosuppressive agents, thiazide diuretics&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breast feeding or pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptomatic cardiac disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Seriously ill or moribund patients with advanced respiratory impairment (cor&#xD;
             pulmonale, hypercapnia, respiratory acidosis, congestive cardiac failure)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy/sensitivity to study drugs or their formulations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant use of drugs known to interfere with vitamin D levels; phenytoin,&#xD;
             phenobarbital, carbamazepine, theophylline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability or unwillingness of subject or legal guardian/representative to give written&#xD;
             informed consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nawal Salahuddin, MBBS,FCCP</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Aga Khan University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aga Khan University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Karachi</city>
        <state>Sind</state>
        <zip>74800</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ojha Istitute of Chest Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Karachi</city>
        <state>Sind</state>
        <zip>74800</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Abbasi Shaheed Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Karachi</city>
        <state>Sind</state>
        <zip>74812</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Malir Chest Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Karachi</city>
        <state>Sind</state>
        <zip>74831</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2011</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 25, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 25, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 26, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 27, 2011</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 27, 2011</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">June 28, 2011</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Nawal Salahuddin</name_title>
    <organization>Aga Khan University</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

