<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03835949</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>4309ST101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03835949</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of TJ004309 in Combination With Atezolizumab (Tecentriq®) in Patients With Advanced or Metastatic Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1 Dose-Escalation Study of TJ004309 in Combination With Atezolizumab (Tecentriq®) in Patients With Advanced or Metastatic Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tracon Pharmaceuticals Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tracon Pharmaceuticals Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter, open label, Phase 1 dose escalation study of TJ004309 in combination&#xD;
      with standard dose atezolizumab in patients with advanced or metastatic cancer in patients&#xD;
      who are refractory to or intolerant to all available therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 16, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Tolerate Dose of TJ004309 plus Atezolizumab</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2-8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate safety and tolerability and determine a recommended Phase 2 dose of TJ004309 when combined with standard dose atezolizumab in patients with advanced or metastatic cancer. Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events as assessed by CTCAE v5.0 and coded using MedDRA 14.1.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine Phase 2 dose to TJ004309 as a single agent</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2-8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the Phase 2 dose of TJ004309 as a single agent</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Trough TJ004309 concentrations</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2-8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Trough (pre-dose and post-dose) serum TJ004309 concentrations will be measured when given as a single agent and with atezolizumab</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Trough atezolizumab concentrations</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2-8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Trough (pre-dose and post-dose) serum atezolizumab concentrations will be measured when given with TJ004309</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the Rate of TJ004309 Immunogenicity</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2-8 months</time_frame>
    <description>The number of patients who develop immunogenicity to TJ004309 (anti-product antibody development) will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the Rate of Atezolizumab Immunogenicity</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2-8 months</time_frame>
    <description>The number of patients who develop immunogenicity to atezolizumab (anti-product antibody development) will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of antitumor activity</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 2-8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Antitumor activity will be assessed by the response rate by iRECIST and RECIST 1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Solid Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TJ004309 plus Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TJ004309 will be dose escalated in a 3+3 design in combination with atezolizumab.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TJ004309</intervention_name>
    <description>Antibody to CD73</description>
    <arm_group_label>TJ004309 plus Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Atezolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Humanized monoclonal antibody to PD-L1</description>
    <arm_group_label>TJ004309 plus Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Histologically confirmed advanced or metastatic cancer in patients who are refractory&#xD;
             to or intolerant to all available therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Measurable disease by iRECIST&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Formalin fixed, paraffin-embedded (FFPE) tumor tissue that permits the preparation of&#xD;
             12 unstained slides of tumor sample- Biopsy must be excisional, incisional, or core.&#xD;
             Needle aspiration is insufficient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status ≤ 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Resolution of all acute adverse events resulting from prior cancer therapies to&#xD;
             National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE)&#xD;
             Grade ≤ 1 or baseline (except alopecia or neuropathy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Adequate organ function&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Willingness and ability to consent for self to participate in study&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Willingness and ability to comply with scheduled visits, treatment plan, laboratory&#xD;
             tests, and other study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Autoimmune disease requiring treatment within the past twelve months&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Condition requiring systemic treatment with either corticosteroids or other&#xD;
             immunosuppressive medications within 14 days prior to study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of or active interstitial lung disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prior T-cell or NK cell therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Current treatment on another therapeutic clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Receipt of systemic anticancer therapy, including investigational agents, within 28&#xD;
             days prior to study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Major surgical procedure or significant traumatic injury within 4 weeks prior to study&#xD;
             treatment, and must have fully recovered from any such procedure; and no date of&#xD;
             surgery (if applicable) or anticipated need for a major surgical procedure planned&#xD;
             within the next 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Chest radiotherapy ≤ 28 days, wide field radiotherapy ≤ 28 days (defined as &gt; 50% of&#xD;
             volume of pelvic bones or equivalent), or limited field radiation for palliation ≤ 14&#xD;
             days prior to study treatment - such patients must have recovered adequately from any&#xD;
             side effects of such therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Hypertension defined as blood pressure (BP) systolic &gt; 150 or diastolic &gt; 90 mm Hg&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Ascites or pericardial effusion that required intervention within 3 months prior to&#xD;
             study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Brain involvement with cancer, spinal cord compression, or carcinomatous meningitis,&#xD;
             or new evidence of brain or leptomeningeal disease, unless the lesion(s) have been&#xD;
             radiated or resected, are considered fully treated and inactive, are asymptomatic, and&#xD;
             no steroids have been administered for CNS disease over the 7 days prior to study&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Angina, myocardial infarction (MI), symptomatic congestive heart failure,&#xD;
             cerebrovascular accident, transient ischemic attack TIA), arterial embolism, pulmonary&#xD;
             embolism, percutaneous transluminal coronary angioplasty (PTCA), or coronary artery&#xD;
             bypass grafting (CABG) within 6 months prior to study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Thrombolytic use (except to maintain IV catheters) within 10 days prior study&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Known active viral or nonviral hepatitis or cirrhosis, except patients with Hepatitis&#xD;
             C infection and undetectable virus following treatment are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Any active infection requiring systemic treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. History of hemorrhage or hemoptysis (&gt; ½ teaspoon bright red blood) within 3 months&#xD;
             prior to study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) unless CD4+ T cell count &gt; 350 cells/μL with&#xD;
             an undetectable viral load.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Pregnancy or breastfeeding - Female patients must be surgically sterile (i.e., ≥ 6&#xD;
             weeks following surgical bilateral oophorectomy with or without hysterectomy or tubal&#xD;
             ligation) or be postmenopausal for at least one year, or must agree to use effective&#xD;
             contraception during the study and for 5 months following last dose of TJ004309. All&#xD;
             female patients of reproductive potential must have a negative pregnancy test (serum&#xD;
             or urine) within 7 days prior to study treatment. Male patients must be surgically&#xD;
             sterile or must agree to use effective contraception during the study and for 5 months&#xD;
             following last dose of TJ004309.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Patients with any severe infection within 4 weeks prior to initiation of study&#xD;
             treatment, including, but not limited to, hospitalization for complications of&#xD;
             infections should not be enrolled in the trial. Patients who required IV antibiotics&#xD;
             or were treated with antiviral medications within this 4 week period should be&#xD;
             discussed with the TRACON prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Other severe acute or chronic medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory&#xD;
             abnormality that may increase the risk associated with study participation or may&#xD;
             interfere with the interpretation of study results and, in the judgment of the&#xD;
             Investigator, would make the patient inappropriate for this study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Charles Theuer, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Medical Monitor</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The University of Alabama at Birmingham</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35294</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>HonorHealth Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Scottsdale</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85258</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City of Hope</name>
      <address>
        <city>Duarte</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77230</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.traconpharma.com</url>
    <description>TRACON Pharmaceuticals</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 5, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 7, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 11, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Second Primary</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atezolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

