<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01346163</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>809087</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01346163</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Add On Treatment for Cognitive Deficits in Schizophrenia</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase1B Study: A Placebo Controlled Study of PF-03654746 Given as Add-On Treatment of Cognitive Deficits in Schizophrenia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Pfizer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pennsylvania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will look at the impact of dosing as well as ongoing treatment with an&#xD;
      investigation medication identified as PF-03654746, on cognitive and physiologic indicators&#xD;
      of brain function. Data from this study will assist with the evaluation of the utility of&#xD;
      functional magnetic resonance imaging, arterial spin labeling (ASL), and electrophysiologic&#xD;
      measures in the detection of early signals of the effectiveness of medications developed to&#xD;
      target cognitive impairment in schizophrenia. Safety and tolerability of PF-03654746 in this&#xD;
      population will be also be evaluated.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>MATRICS Consensus Cognitive Battery</measure>
    <time_frame>13 - 15 Weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ASL perfusion and performance on neurocognitive measures</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>fMRI activation parameters and performance on neurocognitive measures.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ERP measures and performance on neurocognitive measures</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">16</enrollment>
  <condition>Schizophrenia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PF-03654746</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>H3 receptor antagonist currently being developed for the treatment of cognitive impairment associated with schizophrenia (CIAS) as well as with Alzheimer's disease.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PF 03654746</intervention_name>
    <description>All participants will receive 3 weeks of PF-03654746 and 3 weeks of placebo. PF-03654746 and placebo will be administered in a flexible titration regimen, beginning with 0.5 mg/d. If 0.5 mg/d is well tolerated, the dose will be increased to 1.0 mg/d after 5 days. If 1.0 mg/d is not well tolerated, the dose will be decreased to 0.5 mg/d, with the goal of achieving a stable dose of PF-03654746 within the first two weeks of dosing and avoiding further dose changes during the final week of dosing.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PF-03654746</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo will be used as a comparator to the active arm.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Initial Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects must be competent to provide informed consent to participate in a clinical&#xD;
             trial before any trial-related procedures can take place;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects must be willing and able to comply with scheduled visits, treatments,&#xD;
             laboratory tests and other testing and study procedures;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects who participate must be willing to remain in-patient for at least one week at&#xD;
             the beginning of each treatment period and remain in the hospital until judged by the&#xD;
             Investigator to be clinically stable and able to be discharged to outpatient status;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects must be fluent in English and able to understand all study related materials;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects must be between the ages of 18-40 (inclusive) and if Female be of&#xD;
             non-childbearing potential;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Body Mass Index (BMI) 18 to 40 kg/m2 and a total body weight of at least 50 kg (110&#xD;
             lbs);&#xD;
&#xD;
        Psychiatric Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects must have a current DSM-IV-TR diagnosis of schizophrenia of Paranoid&#xD;
             (295.30), Disorganized (295.10), Undifferentiated (295.90) or Residual Type (295.60);&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects must be receiving ongoing maintenance antipsychotic monotherapy with&#xD;
             risperidone, olanzapine, quetiapine, ziprasidone, paliperidone or aripiprazole;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects must be on a stable medication treatment regimen 2 months, including&#xD;
             concomitant psychotropic medications;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Evidence of stable control of symptoms for 3 months (eg, no hospitalizations for&#xD;
             schizophrenia, no increase in level of psychiatric care due to worsening of symptoms&#xD;
             of schizophrenia);&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. No more than moderate severity rating (4) on any individual PANSS positive symptom&#xD;
             item (P1, P3, P5, P6) or formal thought disorder (P2), with no more than two moderate&#xD;
             items in total;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Calgary Depression Scale Score less than or equal to 10;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects must have a minimal level of extrapyramidal symptoms as documented by a score&#xD;
             on the ESRS-A Global Parkinsonism scale of 3;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects must have an illness duration (from the time of diagnosis) of at least 1&#xD;
             year;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects will meet the following cognitive performance criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Performance less than the maximum cutoff (in parentheses) for at least ONE of the&#xD;
                  following MCCB tests: (i.) Letter-number span (20); (ii.) Hopkins Verbal Learning&#xD;
                  Test (HVLT) total (31); and (iii.) Continuous Performance T- test (CPT) d-prime&#xD;
                  (3.47);&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Able to complete the Baseline MCCB validly as assessed by a certified MCCB test&#xD;
                  administrator;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Standard score greater than or equal to 75 on the National Adult Reading Test&#xD;
                  (NART) or other IQ measure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Female subjects who still have child bearing potential and females who are&#xD;
             breastfeeding;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of febrile illness within 5 days prior to the first dose;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any condition possibly affecting drug absorption (eg, gastrectomy);&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects who have a positive urine drug screen which cannot be explained by prescribed&#xD;
             medications;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of regular alcohol consumption exceeding 7 drinks/week for females or 14&#xD;
             drinks/week for men (1 drink = 5 ounces (150 mL) of wine or 12 ounces (360 mL) of beer&#xD;
             or 1.5 ounces (45 mL) of hard liquor) within 6 months of screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Treatment with an investigational drug within 30 days or 5 half-lives preceding the&#xD;
             first dose of study medication;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. 12-lead ECG demonstrating QTc less than or equal to 450 msec at screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects who are using disallowed concomitant medications and who will not be able to&#xD;
             discontinue these concomitant medications prior to randomization;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects who have taken hormone replacement therapy within 28 days or have taken an&#xD;
             herbal remedy 7 days prior to the first dose of trial medication;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects with other conditions that may increase the risk associated with trial&#xD;
             participation or investigational product administration or may interfere with the&#xD;
             interpretation of trial results, and in the judgment of the Investigator, would make&#xD;
             the subject inappropriate for entry into this trial;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects with serologic evidence of acute hepatitis or chronic hepatitis and subjects&#xD;
             with known hepatitis C antibodies and elevated LFTs;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subjects with AST and/or ALT 1.5xULN at the Screening Visit;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subjects with a current DSM-IV axis I diagnosis other than schizophrenia;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subjects with a concurrent psychiatric disorder other than schizophrenia coded on Axis&#xD;
             I;&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Subjects who have previously participated in a trial using PF-03654746;&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Subjects who have DSM-IV defined psychoactive substance dependence (excluding nicotine&#xD;
             dependence) within 12 months of screening or substance abuse within 3 months prior to&#xD;
             Screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Subjects currently using illicit psychoactive substances as evidenced by positive&#xD;
             urine toxicology screen (utox positive for cannabinoids will not be exclusionary due&#xD;
             to the long elimination half life of these substances);&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Subjects with evidence or history of mental retardation;&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Subjects with significant risk of suicidal or violent behavior;&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Subjects with a history of poor compliance;&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Subjects who have received clozapine or monoamine oxidase inhibitors in the month&#xD;
             prior to randomization;&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Current treatment with haloperidol or other typical antipsychotic;&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Current treatment (within 4 weeks) with psychotropic agents known to act at the GABA-A&#xD;
             receptor, including benzodiazepines; sedative-hypnotics other than trazodone and&#xD;
             chloral hydrate; carbamazepine, gabapentin, lamotrigine, and valproic acid;&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Current treatment (within 4 weeks) with psychotropic agents known to effect cognition:&#xD;
             amphetamine; barbiturates; lithium; MAOIs; methylphenidate;&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Current treatment (within 4 weeks) with herbal preparations with possible psychotropic&#xD;
             effects (eg, St. Johns wort, kava-kava, Valerian, S-Adenosyl Methionine [SAMe]);&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Subjects with a history of seizures and or/seizure disorder, significant head&#xD;
             injury/trauma, as defined by one or more of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Loss of consciousness (LOC) for more than 1 hour;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Recurring seizures resulting from the head injury;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Clear cognitive sequelae of the injury;&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Cognitive rehabilitation following the injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. Subjects with a history of clinically significant neurological, metabolic, hepatic,&#xD;
             renal, hematological, pulmonary, cardiovascular, gastrointestinal, and/or urological&#xD;
             disorders (eg, unstable angina, decompensated congestive heart failure, CNS infection&#xD;
             or history of HIV seropositivity), which would pose a risk to the patient if they were&#xD;
             to participate in the study or that might confound the results of the study. Active&#xD;
             medical conditions that are minor or well controlled are not exclusionary if they do&#xD;
             not affect risk to the patient or the study results. For example, the following are&#xD;
             not exclusionary: a) stable and well controlled hypertension (BP normally 160/95 for&#xD;
             at least 3 months); b) asthma (no serious attacks in the past year); c) hypothyroidism&#xD;
             (T4 within normal limits for at least 1 year); and d) Type II diabetes (subjects with&#xD;
             a reported HgbA1c outside of normal limits within the last 6 months should be reviewed&#xD;
             with the study site Investigator);&#xD;
&#xD;
         28. Subject received ECT treatment within the last 6 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
         29. Prior participation in a clinical trial of any other psychotropic medication within 2&#xD;
             months;&#xD;
&#xD;
         30. Subjects with a history of treatment resistant schizophrenia;&#xD;
&#xD;
         31. Subjects with a history of Tardive dyskinesia (TD) or Neuroleptic Malignant Syndrome&#xD;
             (NMS) as determined clinically by the Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
         32. Unwilling or unable to comply with the Lifestyle guidelines described in this&#xD;
             Protocol;&#xD;
&#xD;
         33. Subjects with implanted metal;&#xD;
&#xD;
         34. Subjects with claustrophobia such that they are unable to tolerate MR scanning.&#xD;
&#xD;
         35. Subjects taking medication that inhibit CYP3A4 or CYP2D6&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Raquel P. Gur, M.D., Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Pennsylvania</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pennsylvania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.med.upenn.edu/bbl/</url>
    <description>University of Pennsylvania Department of Neuropsychiatry Home Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2011</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 20, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 29, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 2, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 29, 2011</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 29, 2011</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 2, 2011</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Raquel E. Gur, M.D., Ph.D.</name_title>
    <organization>University of Pennsylvania School of Medicine</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Schizophrenia</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognitive Impairment</keyword>
  <keyword>Electrophysiology</keyword>
  <keyword>H3 receptor antagonist</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cognitive Dysfunction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

