<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01340547</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IPM1005</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01340547</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect on QTc, Pharmacokinetics, Safety, and Preliminary Efficacy of Single-agent Palifosfamide-tris in Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Multicenter, Open-label Study of the Effect on QTc, Pharmacokinetics, Safety, and Preliminary Efficacy of Single-agent Palifosfamide-tris in Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ziopharm</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ziopharm</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label study of palifosfamide-tris administered intravenously on Days 1, 2,&#xD;
      and 3 of a 21-day cycle to subjects with advanced solid tumors. Enrolled subjects will&#xD;
      receive a placebo-control infusion on Day -1 and then commence palifosfamide-tris study&#xD;
      treatment 24 hours later on Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Time-matched, intensive ECG monitoring will occur during and following placebo and&#xD;
      palifosfamide-tris infusions on Days -1, 1, 2, 3 and 8. Generation of ECG data for study&#xD;
      analysis will be performed in a blinded fashion at a central ECG laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood and urine sampling to characterize the pharmacokinetics of palifosfamide-tris will be&#xD;
      performed on Days 1 through 8 of Cycle 1.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>June 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ECG QTc intervals of patients who receive palifosfamide-tris</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 Days -1,1, 2, 3,8</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the effect of single-agent palifosfamide-tris on QTc intervals.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood sampling to characterize the pharmacokinetics of palifosfamide-tris</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, Day 1, 2, 3, 4, 8</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the pharmacokinetic profile of single-agent palifosfamide-tris.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of palifosfamide-tris measured in amount, type, severity and relatedness of Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of time patient is on study, expected average of 5 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the safety and tolerability of single-agent palifosfamide-tris.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Preliminary efficacy of palifosfamide-tris as it pertains to cancer tumor growth</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of time patient is on study, expected average of 5 months</time_frame>
    <description>To obtain preliminary efficacy data as defined by objective response rate (ORR); progression-free survival (PFS); and durability of response in subjects with advanced solid tumors when treated with single-agent palifosfamide-tris.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Solid Tumors</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single Arm, non-blinded, non-randomized</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>palifosfamide-tris</intervention_name>
    <description>palifosfamide-tris IV infusion of 150 mg/m2 on Days 1, 2 and 3 every three weeks (21 day cycle)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>isophosphoramide mustard-tris</other_name>
    <other_name>Zymafos (TM)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Normal Saline</intervention_name>
    <description>0.9% Normal Saline 250 ml IV infusion on Cycle 1 Day -1</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female subjects, age ≥ 18 years, who have provided written informed consent&#xD;
             prior to completing any study specific procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Histologically or cytologically confirmed solid tumor that has progressed following&#xD;
             available standard therapies or for which no standard therapy exist.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Measurable or non-measurable disease by RECIST version 1.1&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Must have recovered from toxic effects of prior cancer treatment to ≤ Grade1per CTCAE&#xD;
             v4.0, with the exception of any alopecia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. ECOG Performance Status of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Adequate bone marrow, liver, and renal function, as assessed by the following&#xD;
             laboratory requirements:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Hemoglobin ≥9.0 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1,500/uL.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Platelet count ≥100,000/uL.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Total bilirubin ≤1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. ALT and AST ≤2.5 x ULN. For subjects with documented liver metastases, ALT and&#xD;
                  AST ≤5×ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. International Normalized Ratio (INR) and activated partial thromboplastin time&#xD;
                  [PTT] &lt;1.5 x ULN, if not therapeutically anticoagulated. Subjects who are being&#xD;
                  therapeutically anticoagulated with an agent such as Coumadin (warfarin sodium)&#xD;
                  or subcutaneous heparin may be included provided there is no prior evidence of&#xD;
                  underlying abnormality in coagulation parameters, screening test results are in&#xD;
                  appropriate therapeutic range, and anticoagulation regimen is stable and closely&#xD;
                  monitored.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGRF) ≥60 mL/minute/1.73 m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Male and female subjects must agree to use a highly reliable method of birth control&#xD;
             (expected failure rate less than 5% per year) from the screening visit through 28 days&#xD;
             after the last dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects who have received prior chemotherapy, radiation therapy or any&#xD;
             investigational agent within 28 days prior to the first dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Unstable or clinically significant concurrent medical condition that would, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the investigator, jeopardize the safety of a subject and/or their&#xD;
             compliance with the protocol. Examples include, but are not limited to, unstable&#xD;
             angina, congestive heart failure, recent (within 2 months of screening) myocardial&#xD;
             infarction, ongoing maintenance therapy for life-threatening ventricular arrhythmia,&#xD;
             uncontrolled asthma, HIV/AIDS without adequate anti-viral therapy, evidence of hepatic&#xD;
             pathology due to or consistent with infection with a chronic hepatitis virus,&#xD;
             uncontrolled major seizure disorder, or electrolyte imbalances.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Presence of, or history of any illness or injury to the urinary tract (renal or&#xD;
             post-renal) which may make the subject more susceptible to acute renal insufficiency&#xD;
             in the case of potential renal adverse events. Types of injury or illness might&#xD;
             include a history of polycystic renal disease, nephrectomy, renal transplant, acute or&#xD;
             chronic renal failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Active infection requiring systemic antibacterial, antifungal, or antiviral therapy&#xD;
             within 2 weeks of the first dose of study drug. Subjects with HIV who are on effective&#xD;
             anti-viral therapy or subjects with chronic herpes infections who use intermittent&#xD;
             suppressive antiviral therapy for viral outbreaks may be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Major surgery within 4 weeks prior to start of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Documented symptomatic brain metastases. Screening for brain lesions by CT or MRI is&#xD;
             not required for potential subjects; however, if there are any neurological signs or&#xD;
             symptoms consistent with brain metastases, then a brain CT or MRI should be performed&#xD;
             as clinically indicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Currently pregnant or nursing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects with implantable pacemaker or automatic implantable cardioverter&#xD;
             defibrillator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Conditions that make the screening ECG repolarization difficult to interpret, or&#xD;
             showing significant abnormalities. This includes, but is not limited to: high degree&#xD;
             AV block, pace-maker, atrial fibrillation or flutter, prolonged QTc &gt;500ms on repeat&#xD;
             measurements (e.g., 2 out of 3 ECGs), or bradycardia (defined as ≤ 50 beats/minute).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects who will be receiving medications that prolong the QT interval with a risk of&#xD;
             causing Torsades de Pointes during the time period beginning 1 week prior to and&#xD;
             during the Intensive ECG monitoring period (i.e., Cycle 1, Day -8 through Day 8).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75230</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 13, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 19, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 22, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 17, 2013</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 17, 2013</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">July 18, 2013</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Phase I</keyword>
  <keyword>Safety</keyword>
  <keyword>PK</keyword>
  <keyword>ECG QTc</keyword>
  <keyword>Efficacy</keyword>
  <keyword>Palifosfamide-tris</keyword>
  <keyword>non-randomized</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Isophosphamide mustard</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ifosfamide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

