<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05095857</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H-21056972</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05095857</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Anesthetic Ketamine as Treatment for Patients With Severe Acute Brain Injury</brief_title>
  <acronym>KETA-BID</acronym>
  <official_title>Effect of S-ketamine on Cortical Spreading Depolarisation and Cerebral Metabolic Crisis in Patients With Severe Acute Brain Injury</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Copenhagen Trial Unit, Center for Clinical Intervention Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cortical spreading depolarisations are pathological depolarisation waves that occur&#xD;
      frequently after severe acute brain injury and has been associated with poor outcome.&#xD;
      S-ketamine has been shown to inhibit cortical spreading depolarisations. The aim of the&#xD;
      present study is to examine the efficacy and safety of using S-ketamine for treatment of&#xD;
      patients with severe acute brain injury, as well as the feasibility of the trial design.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Severe acute brain injury caused by traumatic brain injury (TBI), aneurysmal subarachnoid&#xD;
      haemorrhage (aSAH) or intracerebral haemorrhage (ICH) carries a high morbidity and mortality.&#xD;
      In all these conditions, clinical neurological deterioration may occur as a consequence of&#xD;
      so-called secondary brain injury, which reduces the chance of a good outcome. Thus,&#xD;
      neurological deterioration after the initial injury is generally associated with a worse&#xD;
      outcome. Cortical spreading depolarisations (SDs) are pathological depolarisation waves that&#xD;
      occur frequently after both TBI, SAH, and ICH and have been related to poor outcome. The SDs,&#xD;
      which can be detected by electrocorticography (ECoG, using electrodes placed directly on the&#xD;
      brain cortex), propagate across the cerebral cortex and are followed by an excessive&#xD;
      upregulation of cerebral metabolism and decrease in cerebral blood flow. In vulnerable brain&#xD;
      tissue such as in patients after acute primary brain injury, this combination of&#xD;
      hypermetabolism and hypoperfusion is thought to increase the risk of ischaemia and&#xD;
      infarction. The anaesthetic drug ketamine, which is an NMDA-receptor antagonist, appears to&#xD;
      inhibit SDs both in vitro and in patient series.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The present trial is a randomised, blinded, placebo-controlled, parallel-group pilot and&#xD;
      feasibility trial, where participants with clustered SD despite physiological optimisation&#xD;
      are allocated 1:1 to infusion of S-ketamine versus matching placebo. In the present trial,&#xD;
      participants admitted to the neurointensive care unit with TBI, aSAH or ICH and undergoing&#xD;
      craniotomy or craniectomy (for clipping of an aneurysm or removal of a space-occupying&#xD;
      haematoma). Patients are monitored at the neurointensive care unit, Rigshospitalet and&#xD;
      sedated using standard sedatives. Patients will be monitored both with ECoG, intracranial&#xD;
      pressure (ICP), brain tissue oxygen tension (PbtO2), and microdialysis. Patients in whom SDs&#xD;
      occur will be subjected to a protocol of physiological optimisation targeting ICP, PbtO2,&#xD;
      blood glucose and core temperature following clinical guidelines. If clustered SDs occur&#xD;
      despite optimisation, patients are randomly allocated to infusion of either S-ketamine or&#xD;
      matching placebo (isotonic saline) at a 1:1 allocation ratio with full blinding of the&#xD;
      treatment allocation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The present trial will continue until 160 participants have been randomised. Since only&#xD;
      participants with clustered SDs are randomised, the investigators expect to include no more&#xD;
      than 400 participants for ECoG monitoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The present trial aims to examine the efficacy of S-ketamine on SDs, the safety, and the&#xD;
      feasibility of the trial design. Furthermore, surviving patients will be followed up until&#xD;
      six months after the injury, and functional outcome will be recorded by the modified Rankin&#xD;
      Scale (mRS).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of clustered SDs after randomisation</measure>
    <time_frame>During treatment with S-ketamine or placebo, a maximum of 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Efficacy of S-ketamine on clustered cortical spreading depolarisations</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of adverse events and adverse reactions</measure>
    <time_frame>During treatment with S-ketamine or placebo, a maximum of 14 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional outcome at 6 months after ictus of brain injury</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after ictus of brain injury</time_frame>
    <description>assessed using modified Rankin Scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>assessed at 6 months after ictus of brain injury</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with signs of ischaemia or infarction on computed tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI).</measure>
    <time_frame>Before discharge from NICU or the semi-intentisive care unit, expected up to be no later than day 21 postrandomisation</time_frame>
    <description>Last scan performed on clinical indication before discharge from NICU or semi-intensive care unit</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of metabolic crisis (defined as microdialysis (MD)-lactate/pyruvate ratio &gt;40, MD-glucose &lt; 0.8 μmol/L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Postrandomisation period, expected up to 21 days</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of local cerebral hypoxia (PbtO2 &lt;20 mmHg for more than 20 minutes)</measure>
    <time_frame>Postrandomisation period, expected up to 21 days</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Dosage of standard sedatives and analgesics</measure>
    <time_frame>Postrandomisation period, expected up to 21 days</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of imaging procedures (CT of the brain, CT-angiography, digital subtraction angiography, MRI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Postrandomisation period, expected up to 21 days</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of episodes of neurological worsening</measure>
    <time_frame>Postrandomisation period, expected up to 21 days</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of delayed cerebral ischemia (DCI) in participants with aSAH</measure>
    <time_frame>Postrandomisation period, expected up to 21 days</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Fraction of participants included in the trial out of all eligible participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed after 2 years or when one-third of the 160 participants have been randomised</time_frame>
    <description>Feasibility outcome</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Fraction of participants who are randomised of all included</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed after 2 years or when one-third of the 160 participants have been randomised</time_frame>
    <description>Feasibility outcome</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Subarachnoid Hemorrhage, Aneurysmal</condition>
  <condition>Intracerebral Hemorrhage</condition>
  <condition>Traumatic Brain Injury</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>S-ketamine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>S-ketamine is given as a continuous infusion started at a dose of 2.0 mg/kg/hour. The infusion rate will be re-evaluated after 24 hours, where (1) the infusion will be stopped if 24 hours ensue without SDs, (2) maintained at 2.0 mg/kg/hour if the 24-hour incidence of SDs decreases below the rate of the previous 24 hours but SD is not totally abolished, or (3) increased to 3.0 mg/kg/hour if the incidence of SD is at or above the rate of the previous 24 hours. If the infusion rate has been increased to 3.0 mg/kg/hour, the rate will be returned to 2.0 mg/kg/hour if 24 consecutive hours of ECoG show no SD.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Isotonic saline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Isotonic saline is given as placebo. It will be given as a continuous infusion started at a dose corresponding to a dose of S-ketamine of 2.0 mg/kg/hour, and follow the criteria for increasing/decreasing infusion rates as S-ketamine. The infusion rate is read from a table listing different infusion rates (ml/hour) based on participant weight and if the treatment tier corresponds to a S-ketamine dose of 2 or 3 mg/kg/hour.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>S-ketamine</intervention_name>
    <description>S-ketamines is an NMDA-receptor antagonist with sedative and analgesic properties. It will in the present trial be given in sedative doses (2-3 mg/kg/hour) in case of clustered SDs following a dosing algorithm according to SD occurrence.</description>
    <arm_group_label>S-ketamine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Esketamine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Isotonic saline (placebo)</intervention_name>
    <description>Isotonic saline has the same appearance as S-ketamine with both being clear liquids with no bubbles or other distinguishing features.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Isotonic saline</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Admitted to the NICU with a diagnosis of TBI, aneurysmal SAH or spontaneous ICH.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned for surgery with a craniotomy or craniectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected to continue sedation and mechanical ventilation after surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient and next of kin do not read or understand spoken Danish.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy to S-ketamine (the active pharmaceutical ingredient or the excipients).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immediate wake-up call planned after surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy (all female participants aged ≤ 50 years will have a blood hCG to control&#xD;
             for pregnancy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current abuse of ketamine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active anti-psychotic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Since this is an emergency trial informed consent will be obtained from a trial guardian&#xD;
        before inclusion of the participant, and informed consent will be sought from next of kin&#xD;
        as soon as possible.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Trine H Andreasen, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Trine H Andreasen, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+4535455982</phone>
    <email>trine.hjorslev.andreasen@regionh.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kirsten Møller, Professor</last_name>
    <email>Kirsten.Moeller.01@regionh.dk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Macdonald RL, Schweizer TA. Spontaneous subarachnoid haemorrhage. Lancet. 2017 Feb 11;389(10069):655-666. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(16)30668-7. Epub 2016 Sep 13. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27637674</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nieuwkamp DJ, Setz LE, Algra A, Linn FH, de Rooij NK, Rinkel GJ. Changes in case fatality of aneurysmal subarachnoid haemorrhage over time, according to age, sex, and region: a meta-analysis. Lancet Neurol. 2009 Jul;8(7):635-42. doi: 10.1016/S1474-4422(09)70126-7. Epub 2009 Jun 6.</citation>
    <PMID>19501022</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhou YT, Tong DM, Wang SD, Ye S, Xu BW, Yang CX. Acute spontaneous intracerebral hemorrhage and traumatic brain injury are the most common causes of critical illness in the ICU and have high early mortality. BMC Neurol. 2018 Aug 27;18(1):127. doi: 10.1186/s12883-018-1127-z.</citation>
    <PMID>30149796</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gross BA, Jankowitz BT, Friedlander RM. Cerebral Intraparenchymal Hemorrhage: A Review. JAMA. 2019 Apr 2;321(13):1295-1303. doi: 10.1001/jama.2019.2413. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30938800</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gruenbaum SE, Zlotnik A, Gruenbaum BF, Hersey D, Bilotta F. Pharmacologic Neuroprotection for Functional Outcomes After Traumatic Brain Injury: A Systematic Review of the Clinical Literature. CNS Drugs. 2016 Sep;30(9):791-806. doi: 10.1007/s40263-016-0355-2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27339615</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gruenbaum SE, Bilotta F. Postoperative ICU management of patients after subarachnoid hemorrhage. Curr Opin Anaesthesiol. 2014 Oct;27(5):489-93. doi: 10.1097/ACO.0000000000000111. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25115766</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Seder DB, Mayer SA. Critical care management of subarachnoid hemorrhage and ischemic stroke. Clin Chest Med. 2009 Mar;30(1):103-22, viii-ix. doi: 10.1016/j.ccm.2008.11.004. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19186283</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sheriff FG, Hinson HE. Pathophysiology and clinical management of moderate and severe traumatic brain injury in the ICU. Semin Neurol. 2015 Feb;35(1):42-9. doi: 10.1055/s-0035-1544238. Epub 2015 Feb 25. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25714866</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shah S, Kimberly WT. Today's Approach to Treating Brain Swelling in the Neuro Intensive Care Unit. Semin Neurol. 2016 Dec;36(6):502-507. Epub 2016 Dec 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27907954</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gradisek P, Osredkar J, Korsic M, Kremzar B. Multiple indicators model of long-term mortality in traumatic brain injury. Brain Inj. 2012;26(12):1472-81. doi: 10.3109/02699052.2012.694567. Epub 2012 Jun 21.</citation>
    <PMID>22721420</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Olsen MH, Orre M, Leisner ACW, Rasmussen R, Bache S, Welling KL, Eskesen V, Møller K. Delayed cerebral ischaemia in patients with aneurysmal subarachnoid haemorrhage: Functional outcome and long-term mortality. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2019 Oct;63(9):1191-1199. doi: 10.1111/aas.13412. Epub 2019 Jun 7.</citation>
    <PMID>31173342</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cordonnier C, Demchuk A, Ziai W, Anderson CS. Intracerebral haemorrhage: current approaches to acute management. Lancet. 2018 Oct 6;392(10154):1257-1268. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31878-6. Review. Erratum in: Lancet. 2019 Feb 2;393(10170):406.</citation>
    <PMID>30319113</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Budohoski KP, Guilfoyle M, Helmy A, Huuskonen T, Czosnyka M, Kirollos R, Menon DK, Pickard JD, Kirkpatrick PJ. The pathophysiology and treatment of delayed cerebral ischaemia following subarachnoid haemorrhage. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2014 Dec;85(12):1343-53. doi: 10.1136/jnnp-2014-307711. Epub 2014 May 20. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24847164</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lauritzen M, Dreier JP, Fabricius M, Hartings JA, Graf R, Strong AJ. Clinical relevance of cortical spreading depression in neurological disorders: migraine, malignant stroke, subarachnoid and intracranial hemorrhage, and traumatic brain injury. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2011 Jan;31(1):17-35. doi: 10.1038/jcbfm.2010.191. Epub 2010 Nov 3. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21045864</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hartings JA, Andaluz N, Bullock MR, Hinzman JM, Mathern B, Pahl C, Puccio A, Shutter LA, Strong AJ, Vagal A, Wilson JA, Dreier JP, Ngwenya LB, Foreman B, Pahren L, Lingsma H, Okonkwo DO. Prognostic Value of Spreading Depolarizations in Patients With Severe Traumatic Brain Injury. JAMA Neurol. 2020 Apr 1;77(4):489-499. doi: 10.1001/jamaneurol.2019.4476.</citation>
    <PMID>31886870</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Helbok R, Schiefecker AJ, Friberg C, Beer R, Kofler M, Rhomberg P, Unterberger I, Gizewski E, Hauerberg J, Möller K, Lackner P, Broessner G, Pfausler B, Ortler M, Thome C, Schmutzhard E, Fabricius M. Spreading depolarizations in patients with spontaneous intracerebral hemorrhage: Association with perihematomal edema progression. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2017 May;37(5):1871-1882. doi: 10.1177/0271678X16651269. Epub 2016 Jan 1.</citation>
    <PMID>27207168</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dreier JP, Woitzik J, Fabricius M, Bhatia R, Major S, Drenckhahn C, Lehmann TN, Sarrafzadeh A, Willumsen L, Hartings JA, Sakowitz OW, Seemann JH, Thieme A, Lauritzen M, Strong AJ. Delayed ischaemic neurological deficits after subarachnoid haemorrhage are associated with clusters of spreading depolarizations. Brain. 2006 Dec;129(Pt 12):3224-37. Epub 2006 Oct 25.</citation>
    <PMID>17067993</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ayata C, Lauritzen M. Spreading Depression, Spreading Depolarizations, and the Cerebral Vasculature. Physiol Rev. 2015 Jul;95(3):953-93. doi: 10.1152/physrev.00027.2014. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26133935</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chesnut RM, Marshall LF, Klauber MR, Blunt BA, Baldwin N, Eisenberg HM, Jane JA, Marmarou A, Foulkes MA. The role of secondary brain injury in determining outcome from severe head injury. J Trauma. 1993 Feb;34(2):216-22.</citation>
    <PMID>8459458</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Welling L, Welling MS, Teixeira MJ, Figueiredo EG. Cortical spread depolarization and ketamine: a revival of an old drug or a new era of neuroprotective drugs? World Neurosurg. 2015 Apr;83(4):396-7. doi: 10.1016/j.wneu.2015.01.006. Epub 2015 Jan 31.</citation>
    <PMID>25644895</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reinhart KM, Shuttleworth CW. Ketamine reduces deleterious consequences of spreading depolarizations. Exp Neurol. 2018 Jul;305:121-128. doi: 10.1016/j.expneurol.2018.04.007. Epub 2018 Apr 10.</citation>
    <PMID>29653188</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sakowitz OW, Kiening KL, Krajewski KL, Sarrafzadeh AS, Fabricius M, Strong AJ, Unterberg AW, Dreier JP. Preliminary evidence that ketamine inhibits spreading depolarizations in acute human brain injury. Stroke. 2009 Aug;40(8):e519-22. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.109.549303. Epub 2009 Jun 11.</citation>
    <PMID>19520992</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hertle DN, Dreier JP, Woitzik J, Hartings JA, Bullock R, Okonkwo DO, Shutter LA, Vidgeon S, Strong AJ, Kowoll C, Dohmen C, Diedler J, Veltkamp R, Bruckner T, Unterberg AW, Sakowitz OW; Cooperative Study of Brain Injury Depolarizations (COSBID). Effect of analgesics and sedatives on the occurrence of spreading depolarizations accompanying acute brain injury. Brain. 2012 Aug;135(Pt 8):2390-8. Epub 2012 Jun 19.</citation>
    <PMID>22719001</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schiefecker AJ, Beer R, Pfausler B, Lackner P, Broessner G, Unterberger I, Sohm F, Mulino M, Thome C, Humpel C, Schmutzhard E, Helbok R. Clusters of cortical spreading depolarizations in a patient with intracerebral hemorrhage: a multimodal neuromonitoring study. Neurocrit Care. 2015 Apr;22(2):293-8. doi: 10.1007/s12028-014-0050-4.</citation>
    <PMID>25142825</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hertle DN, Heer M, Santos E, Schöll M, Kowoll CM, Dohmen C, Diedler J, Veltkamp R, Graf R, Unterberg AW, Sakowitz OW. Changes in electrocorticographic beta frequency components precede spreading depolarization in patients with acute brain injury. Clin Neurophysiol. 2016 Jul;127(7):2661-7. doi: 10.1016/j.clinph.2016.04.026. Epub 2016 May 4.</citation>
    <PMID>27291885</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carlson AP, Abbas M, Alunday RL, Qeadan F, Shuttleworth CW. Spreading depolarization in acute brain injury inhibited by ketamine: a prospective, randomized, multiple crossover trial. J Neurosurg. 2018 May 25:1-7. doi: 10.3171/2017.12.JNS171665. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>29799344</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 30, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Trine Hjorslev Andreasen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD, Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cortical Spreading Depolarisation</keyword>
  <keyword>Ketamine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Injuries, Traumatic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Subarachnoid Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cerebral Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ketamine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Esketamine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

